Six,
five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
But
suck it.
I always just want to start off a
podcast by just saying suck it.
Suck at the Joe Rogan experience podcast
is brought to you by [inaudible] dot
com.
If you go to o,
n n I t dot Com and enter the code name
Rogan.
You can save yourself 10 percent off any
of our groovy supplements I'm on.
It is a company that tries to provide
you the best supplements and a strength
and fitness and health and nutrition
stuff available.
Essentially find cool shit online.
Um,
that the,
that I use in real life that I buy and
the best trends in fitness as far as
like battle ropes and kettle bells.
And we have this new thing called a
steel bill.
It's like a,
it's like,
oh look a giant fucking sandbag that you
toss around.
We're just always kind of trying to
constantly add to our things that we
make available online.
But it's this one,
it's called a steel bell.
It's like a,
it's like a bag filled with like metal
pellets and you lift it up and fucking
throw it around and shit.
Got a video for whatever use you and
then we,
you know,
we have like um,
medicine balls and shit.
I actually just started doing a lot of
that stuff with medicine ball medicine
balls and battle ropes and I've been
getting into
a lot of the workouts you would do with
the,
with the,
um,
with the one piece bathing suit over
shoulder and those kind of guys.
One piece bathing suit over your
shoulder.
Like Oh.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Well it was like a tank top shorts.
Yeah.
Like old school,
strong man type shit.
Yeah.
It does seem like it would toss us heavy
ball back and forth for awhile.
Yeah.
Um,
so any of the shit that
sell is stuff that's been shown to be
the best for whatever.
For strength and fitness for health and
nutrition.
We're just trying to sell you the
coolest shit that we can find.
Including killer bee honey,
that's the latest thing.
I have no idea if it's any better than
regular bee honey.
It's probably not a,
but it's fucking killer bee honey and
this honey.
I'm trying to drink more honey.
Actually,
it's from killer bees in.
It really took killer bees and they
stole their fucking hunting.
Have you got checked out already?
Love it.
What's wrong with your throat?
I just lose it a lot.
Like he's been losing his voice a lot
really.
But I've been taking more care of the
uh,
but um,
I'd been screaming a lot on stage over
the last six months.
Yeah,
a lot more often to customers sets.
Instead of stop screaming my other
options,
write a joke.
You could go to o n n I t dot Com.
Get some fucking killer bee honey and
drink a whole candidate.
Shit.
See if it helps you.
I will see if it gets your pussy ass
back in line.
I throw a temper tantrum once because
hunting.
What the fuck?
What happened to the girl if you go to
the other on it.
Oh,
and I take a bank.
Yeah.
He got really
good title company or something.
Other fun words.
Fuck it.
As a.
we're also brought to you by hover.
Hover.com
is a company that is owned by Ting.
Have basically a one company called two
cows.
I believe,
and it's a company that's been around
since 1994,
it's one of the largest domain name
registers in the world and hovers a part
of that and what hover is trying to do
is make you know,
just like they did with ting,
try to make you know,
an evil free domain name company.
They don't believe any heady heavy
handed selling or aggressive cross
selling.
They don't bleed and hide and
functionality or requiring extra
payments for things that should be
including with domain name management
like so they just make it really simple
and easy.
They offer 23 top level domains and they
also have it set up so that you can do
all of this through hover.com,
forward slash Rogan and if you do that,
you save 10 percent off your domain name
registrar.
Can I just add a.
They have a no charge for the who is
privacy,
which is a big deal because places like
go daddy and all these other places.
They might have a good rate,
but you're getting.
You're not getting anything extra.
That's why when you try to register
through one of those other companies,
you're going after page after page like,
no,
I don't want that.
No,
I don't want that,
you know,
I don't want that.
Was this actually gives you a know who
is privacy with no charge,
which is a,
at what I get on all my domains because
you have to give your real address and
if you don't,
they,
they will just be like,
all right,
you were taking your domain away from
you.
And then people write as like,
as like business.
Yeah.
Whatever.
People who deals with you and like,
shut up.
Why don't you have my address?
It's really scary that they make you do
that.
So what this a company that has hovered
a,
they give you that no charge the who is
privacy,
which covers that up for you.
It's just says,
you know,
this is registered to blah blah blah.
It's just like a fake thing.
So that's really good deal.
Right?
Actually,
yeah,
that's pretty,
that's pretty slick.
Um,
and it's,
uh,
like I said,
it's the same,
the,
the ethics behind the company,
the same as behind Tang.
There's trying not to rip anybody off
and you can make a lot of money not
ripping people off,
you know,
especially people are loyal.
So go,
uh,
go check it out and save 10 percent
hover.com
forward slash rogen 10 percent off your
domain name registrations,
aren't you dirty fox?
We're here with Ari Shaffir who will be
joining me Friday,
February first and Mandalay bay.
Oh yeah,
with the Great Joey Diaz at massive fuck
where the waves are.
Cue The music bitch.
Maybe.
There we go.
Sweet.
Heavenly Jesus.
We're back.
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you very much and welcome aboard.
Powerful Arash fear.
How do you do that stuff?
Brian?
Spitting down stuff.
How does he do it?
Yeah,
he's a master at using a fake turntable.
Oh Wow.
That's cool.
I like that.
And make them look like turntables to
instead of just pushing a lever or
something.
Yeah,
they're crafty.
These fucks with their ipad technology
with the things they've done.
We had that Neil degrasse Tyson guy on
the podcast yesterday.
I've been seen videos on him for a long
time,
so a lot of fun,
man.
Really,
really interesting guy.
Yeah.
What an inspirational dude.
Super Cute.
Great response for the podcast.
Except for me talking about the moon
landing,
almost universally hated.
Hated.
It was.
I want to just say that it was not my
idea to talk about that.
That's something that he wanted to talk
about in advance.
It's sort of alluded to the fact that he
was going to bring that up.
Whoops.
That's my laptop.
The she got mad at Ralph and maybe once
because were all sitting around like
late night in Vegas or something.
And Ralphie goes,
so tell me about that.
What do you think about the moon landing
and the edge of this motherfucker?
What are you going to start it?
Serious thing.
We went into the psychology of a looking
for a hidden things and how fascinating
they are too,
but we're talking about the,
the idea of that if there's a planet
there somewhere outside of Pluto that
they believe might exist to successful
theory,
what was he as.
This is a thing called the Kuiper belt
is a massive amount of asteroids that
are out there,
but they think it's very possible that
there's a large planet that's out there,
but it's so far away it has no
reflection of light from the sun and we
can't even see it,
but we're sort of guessing by some of
the things that have gone on in that
area as far as like a.
He goes,
yeah,
and so we were talking about that and I
was just commenting on how weird it is
that we have this desire to find shit
that's not there when the shit that we
know is there,
you really haven't looked into it all.
Like I've really not looked into Jupiter
that much.
You know?
I mean I kind of know that it's a gas
giant.
Got The spot on it.
Yeah.
It's,
I know that a shoemaker levy hit it,
this comment and blew up and I know that
recently they found another common
impact.
I know like little things,
but like as far as like,
like the real
know as far as like it's a fascinating
thing and all the information is readily
available and right there,
but instead I'm like,
man,
they might be hidden.
Planted out there.
The planets that are here,
I don't give a fuck about.
I don't even.
I'm so bored with the moon.
The moon didn't exist.
Then one day above you is a fucking
Mooney.
Be shitting your pants.
You'd be freaking out that the planet
was that close.
Everybody would be going nuts.
You just wouldn't.
People would just be sitting down and
parks just looking up,
staring that moon.
If it was a new thing,
it was like you'd have four parks filled
with people.
They would come and cities and gather up
and they would try to make sense of
their.
Yeah,
there's some new thing is invaded their
atmosphere.
It's floating above their planet.
That would freak people out,
but instead like,
oh yeah,
it's the moon because it's always been
there.
It's always been there and when
sometimes you look up and you see like
Saturn,
you seem like virgin was offering one
for 10 grand,
not even a crazy amount,
like 10 grand.
Would you go for it?
I would have to.
You'd have to be a few years in.
I would have to see it first.
Fuck that.
Because you know someone's not going to
make it back.
I got a matter of time.
I mean it's like we know it's a matter
of time with air flight,
you know there's some,
some plane somewhere is going down.
Oh yeah.
Just like some car somewhere is gonna
crash.
So are you willing to die in space?
That's the real question.
Are you willing to die in space?
That wouldn't be bad at diamond space.
Forget A.
because at least they sort of find your
body like maybe generations,
they're gonna.
It's gonna be a long time because the
first thing they have to do before they
do anything is the day after they're
going to do commercial space flight
where it's just the orbit,
the earth,
so they'll probably do that for a few
years.
I have stations where people can go to.
Have you seen what the things look like?
They like.
It looks like a plain sort of divergence
ship to use to go into space,
but everyone just has a seat.
Yeah,
I mean you have seats.
I don't know how many seats there are on
it.
I mean it's.
I'm sure it's more complicated than a
plane,
but it essentially looks like some sort
of a double a hold plane.
It looks weird.
It doesn't look like a spaceship.
I thought it would look like a spaceship
and you can dock with the.
With the people up there.
Yeah.
I think that's the plan for the future.
I don't know if that's what they're
going to do initially.
I think.
I think there's probably a bunch of
options on the table.
Just take him out there and then bring
them back.
Yeah.
That's a space you got to think.
How long can people deal with that?
You know what?
If you're up there with some dude who
hasn't taken us pack salt and fucking
blows a gasket,
you got to make a person proof.
Yeah,
you gotta make it person proof.
This would be a lot of good going mad.
Seeing the whole Earth Day.
I'm like,
Oh,
oh,
there's clothing.
No,
God,
I've wasted my life.
Well,
when you were in,
um,
when you're on a fan,
one of those fighter jets,
they have like a thing under your seat.
Deca pull out and inject yourself and
you go flying through the air on a
fucking parachute and you can't have
those space.
You can't have that shit.
You got to make sure that this asshole
is like,
if this thing's going down,
you don't have any say in it.
You have no control over the buttons.
It is kind of weird that like regular
flights don't have at least parachutes,
you know,
you'd think that they would.
She's underneath each seat.
You just don't kind of.
And we've got about 10 minutes.
Get everybody out here.
Thank you.
Understand how fast you're growing.
Yeah,
but I mean like a last resort,
you know,
I'd rather have that than a seat cushion
I could use as a flotation device.
I'd rather have a parachute as if like,
okay,
this shit's going down.
I'm going to try.
I don't know how to use this thing,
but I'm just going to try it.
That would make sense.
That would make sense,
but you would have to be willing to
somehow or another open up a window or a
door while that fuckers in the air
stewardess would have to do it for us.
No,
I don't think you understand what
happens to your body when you're flying
500 miles an hour and you jump out into
the air.
Like,
dude,
you got down with a trooper.
He said you got knocked out a lot.
Yeah,
you're going to get knocked unconscious.
You're not going to be able to breathe.
You're going 500 miles an hour with your
face and you're still going 500 miles an
hour when you jump out.
Okay.
You really have to wrap your head around
that because you're being protected by
this tube to the point where you're
completely unaware of the velocity.
You're flying through the fucking air
when you just get shot through it and
just let go.
Oh,
and by the way,
if you hit a bird,
you can explode.
Yeah,
yeah.
Guess what?
You wouldn't get one for awhile.
Now
the other option is pavement inside of
it.
Target that you're playing.
That's probably the best way.
That way you know you're done.
You know you don't want to fucking sort
of survive.
What happens if you.
If everyone was leaving the plane with
your flotation device,
but you forget yours and it's like,
but you're only like an aisle or two
ahead of where you started.
Do you have to go back?
Do you think there's any chance people
will let you back there?
Maybe if he'd scream I needed a
flotation device,
but that's so such a.
We needed a name for that stupid thing.
Facilitation of US flotation device,
if she can be used as a flotation
device,
should be a buoy thing.
A hell have a fucking name,
but we think that there's something with
Latin.
Yeah.
Something should ever fucking name.
Where's my flotation device?
A flotation gives me more life.
Live on the water.
There's the picture of Neil Degrasse
Tyson discusses simulation theory.
Suspiciously Asian looking person
appears behind it.
What was that?
You.
It's Brian has always said that like
when you start talking about simulation
theory in Asia and will show up.
Sounds like French and that to let you
know that you're.
That.
Yeah,
it is.
It is really all just a simulation.
It was actually somebody that somebody
photoshop that in.
No,
no,
that's actually Mike Brown who was on
that pointless podcast following this,
that he came early.
I met so many photoshop.
The writing.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Oh No.
Puppets.
Bigger issue here.
Then the Asian Person Chem trails,
floating leather letters talking about
us.
I'm Mike.
Um,
he said he was like a big time mixmax
mixing shop.
He was really cool.
He does video mixing.
So instead of doing like deejaying with
Odey,
he takes video clips and mixes like
videos and stuff
like that.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Let's throw one out.
What is a.
What is it about a.
let me find tall dicks.
Just dicks going into Dick's and
splicing.
Becoming Celtic.
Dick's to here.
We're going to Mars.
People are really.
When was this Dutch people?
Twenty,
20,
19.
Ain't gonna make it or taking volunteers
now.
Well,
that's why Neil Tyson says that's what
we need.
We need somebody else going to go there
first and that's the only way we'll go
to Mars.
You know,
like let some males pave the way.
I didn't do a good job guys.
That was his reasoning behind the idea
that,
you know,
the,
the racist to the moon was won by the
Americans.
Then it was pretty much over like the
Russians didn't even want to go to the
moon.
What's the point?
The United States already there.
Here's Mike Relm.
He remixes an old spice commercial.
How can I smell like space shows?
That's easy.
I'm going to vote and he has a whole
bunch of different ones.
Like this one,
you know what kind of stuff,
but I'm not gay,
but very sexy video.
It's really funny.
So confident man with his shirt off,
he's making silly noises with his mouth.
Oh,
Scott Pilgrim.
I don't know if you've ever seen that
movie.
It was a really great guy having sex
with a girl from behind.
What was the other thumbnail?
I don't know.
Someone's horning.
Hold on.
This is.
I don't know if you saw a whatever it's
called.
Here it is.
Scott Pilgrim
mixing ludicrous gas and
Oh,
Internet.
Check out his.
The people that people at home that are
listening or anyone in the car.
This is what he did is he spliced the
Scott Pilgrim movie with the ludicrous
music video and voices and their know
how to feel about mashup songs.
Some of them are great.
Yeah,
but it's just had originally you would
like or it's just the two of them.
Two of them coming together doesn't
bother me,
but you know what bothered me and I,
I like kid rock at that last kid rock
song was like a combination of sweet
home Alabama and something else.
You know,
know I spent doing
that a lot lately.
Yeah.
But it's just,
I didn't.
It was like,
man,
this is like,
it feels like.
It's like when vanilla ice was doing ice
ice baby,
it was like under pressure.
Was the rift,
is that under pressure riff?
At least in the mashups.
Like you can clearly tell which songs
we're using.
We're not trying to say this is our
stuff like kid rock stuff.
You don't know.
I mean I guess as a tribute and you
know,
it was a really popular songs,
so what the fuck do I know?
But I'm like man,
I would rather hear the actual songs.
Yeah.
That's how I feel sometimes with the
mashups sometimes,
but it just feels lame.
Have you ever heard good though?
Voodoo problems?
No child and 99 problems.
That's crazy.
They're sort of catchy,
but then I feel like I shouldn't like
them.
Plagiarists Nah,
they tricked you.
Sometimes it's awesome.
It's some,
some of them don't work with me.
Some of them don't say unhip.
Yeah,
I,
I wasn't into it that much until I heard
that 99 problems.
Voodoo child mix.
That shit is so good.
Fuck yeah.
It's like one of the greatest songs.
Somebody get mashed up your Song
Boutique Fernando with so many police.
Listen how good this is.
This shit works isn't actually the one
that I'm used to.
What about that?
On the Godzilla soundtrack?
This is a different person.
He did that like 15,
16 years ago.
Well,
they did it together.
Who?
There was Robert Plant.
They actually did a song together,
but it was a Zeppelin song though.
There was that all that cashmere I was
kind of.
Which was ridiculous because like you
mean if you're going to like duplicate a
song,
like you do some shit from houses of the
holy that no one remembers.
You don't come out with cashmere.
I like that.
That's a classic wrapping aerosmith.
Did that walk this way because that was
pretty fucking cool.
That was pretty cool.
Yeah.
And when run DMC did their version of
walk this way,
it was.
Aerosmith was like the idea of the video
is like them rehearsing next door.
These rappers and rappers are really
unimpressed and we can't play arm knew
this answer.
Atlanta real.
It's like one of the corniest most
hokiest videos together,
you know,
especially because like Steven Tyler
gets crazy with his mic stand.
He breaks through the wall where the
rappers are,
you know,
and then they have respect for each
other.
Like bitch,
get the fuck out of it would have
dragged him through the hole in the wall
you just made.
It looks like an old lady at his crazy
hair.
Fucking handkerchiefs on his head.
They would have beat the fuck out of
him,
man.
It's so weird to see that guy as a on
American idol
when people get old,
it's going to have.
No,
I don't,
I don't expect it.
So you don't expect.
I have not grown up even remotely other
than my responsibilities have widened
again.
So my mindset,
I mean I guess I'm at,
I'm sort of a little bit more
disciplined 15 more years,
20 more years,
but it happens to all of them.
Howard Stern.
Yeah,
but I think it's all in.
First of all,
you got to make sure that you're having
fun.
You got to make sure the friends that
are also having fun,
you gotta like keep a community of
people together.
That's what these people are all.
They're not keeping community.
People think that comes with a lot of,
um,
a lot of them,
they go solo and you know,
they just,
it's fucking them and the wife and
occasionally go on stage and just get
weird.
It's like a,
you reconsider revitive.
Something happens new again.
They get old and you know,
they always love to use that quote is
one quote that I've used.
I've used it to show me a young man.
It's on the liberal.
I'll show you a man without a heart.
Show me an old man.
It's not conservative and I'll show you
a man who has no brain.
Oh Wow.
Why?
Because he's mostly.
People are just a bunch of weak cuts.
At a certain point in time.
You got to really tell people to man up.
Uh,
I was having a conversation about
boulder today with Mrs Rogan and we were
talking about how we really loved
boulder and we even loved hippies until
we lived in boulder.
Why?
Well,
when you live around hippies,
like when they're the majority,
when.
Yeah,
when,
when there's more than a,
you know,
a small percentage of hippies when
they're around all the time acting where
it gets really annoying like there they
can be fucking annoying.
Refreshing anymore.
There's so many kids that were like
young kids that were begging for money.
Oh,
there was like,
what's,
what's the young kid?
Twenties.
Oh,
okay.
Like young just sitting there like
sitting there with like asking for money
and I don't know if it's the,
maybe I just saw too many of them and
maybe it was just really rare,
but it just seemed like in the owner,
the amount of like young people that
were like just sort of like asking for
people to help them.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
That's like that in San Francisco and
hate now.
Exactly.
And look,
there's nothing wrong with being in a
position where you need people to help
you.
We've all been there.
It's not that,
but I've never been in a position where
I'm sitting down with a fucking piece of
cardboard box open and I'm hoping
somebody gives you money,
you're not doing anything unless I'm
missing your whole past and you're
completely mentally challenged enough
and it's amazing that you're even
sitting there and that you wrote please
help.
Right,
but what's their feeling?
People just kick in and then you know,
you have money for dinner and he can
give us a dollar for parking.
Like it was.
It was.
It becomes a kind of a weird.
Becomes a kind of a weird thing where
you're like,
okay,
you guys need some discipline in your
life.
It's one thing to a peaceful and loving
and.
But the,
the real problem with the hippie life is
that it's a life of meandering,
a life of the world.
I'm sure that my next meal find its way
to me.
I don't know how I'm going to do it,
but I'm sure my next meal will find its
way to me.
I have trust in the universe and that
kind of thinking.
They were like hippies that there.
Yes,
there was quite a few.
Yeah,
we.
there was.
It was really annoying,
man.
It was a was a,
there was a lot of really cool people
don't get me wrong.
The majority were really cool,
like it's like 90 percent of them were
fucking outstanding human beings.
The people there in boulder,
but the 10 percent of these fucking
knuckle heads,
it wasn't even 10 percent.
It's just you've run into them all the
time.
For the most part it was fine,
but when it kind of knowing,
it's like when you're holding the baby
and they're asking for money and you're
like,
come on man,
get the terminator where yeah,
I'm holding a baby and you're coming up
trying to beg money.
Like I'm not really into like dealing
with you right now.
Weird guy with strings.
You making the mistake of making eye
contact a little bit.
It's like,
Oh fuck,
you're talking and everything.
Like what?
How did you get to this point where you
need money from strangers?
Like there's,
there's must be some fucking shit
decisions along the way.
Maybe I could help you with that better
than just giving you $5 towards a
homeless cup.
Once he said it was just a summer,
it was just like something to do.
Be Homeless.
You could catch from the government but
just know.
No,
not homeless,
but just the begging like,
oh,
gotta leave out other way.
Wow.
Yeah.
It's a weird thing,
man.
I think it's really important to be
surrounded by people that are also
trying to get shit done,
that people that are having fun,
people that are enjoying their lives,
people that are trying to accomplish
things.
And I don't mean in a materialistic
sense.
I mean more in a creative sense in
anything.
Like when you're like,
well you were just putting together like
you're special and you just recorded a
special like a year after your last
question.
I know that was a big deal for you,
but when you did that,
you know,
when you said that you do that,
I got inspired.
You know,
I get inspired when I hear other people
really working at something towards
something and really.
Yeah,
yeah,
absolutely.
But it becomes,
it's exciting,
you know,
I think it's super important and I think
that if you're a,
if you're not around people that are
like that,
you can get fucking dull.
You can fall apart,
you can let this push in your
outstanding person without doing
anything.
There's nothing going on in your life,
you,
you like.
Why would you think that you're going to
keep growing?
You're not challenging yourself.
You're hanging out with your wife all
the time,
you're not going anywhere and then all
of sudden you're hosted American idol
and I'm going,
what the fuck?
Yo,
Where's the journey?
Yeah,
I know what you mean though.
Yeah.
When other people are doing shit,
you're like,
oh,
I mean it's very.
Yeah,
when other people were doing things,
it's very inspirational.
It's super,
super important.
And if you don't surround yourself with
other people that are exciting and
interesting and that you can have
conversations with man,
you're going to have a shit life.
It's really that simple.
And that's people just sort of accept
that.
Do you think the people who like pair up
with people,
let's say other couples,
let's say that like to go traveling,
that'll probably help you travel,
just being next door to somebody who's
just like does nothing and then you just
have your barbecues,
your house once in a while and that's
it.
My parents lives were much better when
my stepdad was working for this friend
of his and they all lived in the same
town.
They would all do things together when
they were in Pennsylvania,
it's like their,
their life became more of like there was
a community thing going on there,
you know,
that's like,
that's very big for people.
So we,
we get loose sight of things because we
think that what's really important is a
career or you know,
getting yourself financially
established,
buying your first home,
getting some told like that's what
you're supposed to want you,
you,
it is they,
these are desirable things,
but without community their shit.
Yeah.
You can be a rich motherfucker living by
yourself,
crying your eyes out at the top of a
hill and that's real.
I talked to a real estate guy wants a
while ago and just move like it was like
an hour and a half north of La.
It's like it's you don't just for a few
years and then you can go back and like
what,
what are you talking about when you were
talking about buying a house because
it's way cheaper houses and it's like,
what?
But I have to live there.
She's not just like,
wait.
I'm like,
I'm not going to live there.
You know,
the desert.
He can get a whole acre for $180.
Okay.
I mean,
what are you doing every day that's
worth the amount of money that you would
say if you bought a home in the Nevada
desert?
Living my life.
I talked to the guy once it's a while
living in a truck stop.
Just being like a salesman of the front,
you know,
like a store.
And I was like,
how was that?
Because you got to go crazy by herself a
little bit.
I met this guy of like Vancouver or
something and he goes,
yeah,
that's why I'm not there anymore.
Well,
because it was so fucking lonely,
you wouldn't see anyone except strangers
and very briefly,
oh Jesus,
that must be crazy.
That's like a prison.
It's not like,
oh,
get away from everybody for a little
while and then it becomes your life.
Yeah.
I am of the opinion.
Especially as I get older,
that is not healthy to be away from
people.
I think you have to have some sense of
community and they're loners or any,
any,
any person that just wants to be by
themselves alone in the woods all the
time,
you know,
like no friends,
not saying hi to people.
Keep an eye on that motherfucker because
you know,
that's some uni bomber type shit.
I think it's,
I think it's this.
I think every person has a different
level of how much they need other people
around them.
Yes,
and at some point they'll just be a
curve,
like don't need anybody,
don't need anybody.
And then when somebody like 10 minutes
in the back,
there were people,
I need people with some people that can
be 10 days.
Yeah,
I'm good for two days without saying
anybody I can do that.
Really,
I like a day every now and then I'm just
decompression decompression day where I
don't have to talk to anybody.
I could just sit and chill and get some
reading done and you know,
maybe watch a documentary or something.
No,
just literally not communicated at all.
Your underwear.
It's nice.
Yeah,
those days are nice,
but they're just so rare.
But most important thing
is that you're stimulated on a regular
basis.
You know,
you gotTa,
you gotTa have people around you that
are stimulating and as soon as you get
stuck in some sort of a rut where you
don't have anything going on with your
mind or it's challenging you,
you can have slowly rot away.
You're going to fall into that Rut to,
yeah,
I bet for.
Fuck yeah.
Yeah.
You,
we need a bunch of different things.
We need to be stimulated by our
interests.
Whatever our interests are,
whether you're interested in cooking or
whether it's carpentry or whether it's
drawing or whether it's fucking golfing.
Whatever your interests are,
those dumb shits are important in your
life.
Okay?
Interests are important because
interests stimulate your mind,
interest in the job you have.
You fucking hate.
Yeah,
let's talk about it later.
So that's not your interest.
You.
Most people.
It's not.
If it is your lucky as fuck.
If you're a comedian and you know,
you actually love comedy man.
What have huge,
huge fucking blessing that is.
But you know,
for a lot of folks what they're good at
and what they make can make a living and
it's not really what the thing is.
So they,
you know,
they go bowling on the weekends so they,
go through some duck hunting but they
find something that stimulates them and
I never really,
I kind of didn't understand that even
though I was doing all those things,
it took me a long time to sort of piece
that together.
Some people do open my comedy like that
in their forties and fifties,
just first coffee shops.
Yeah.
And it's not like I'm not trying to be
successful.
It's just like doing it.
Then when you think about it,
they act as the same no matter what.
Sure.
If you're painting on your back porch
with a grandmother or painting because
your seller ship for a million dollars,
you're still just trying to make a good
painter.
Yeah.
If you're doing it the right way,
it will be exactly the same.
It's for the joy of that.
The joy of the creation.
Yeah.
I mean,
I'm like you like if I have any one flub
anywhere in a bit it will drive me
crazy.
If there's a hiccup in the jug,
there's a transition job that just seems
artificial shit will drive me crazy so I
could rush for an hour and 10 minutes
where they just loved it and I'd get off
the stage.
I'll bet that fucking on the fucking bed
sucks.
I got to fix that fucking bed and that's
all I'll think about.
You know,
I can but it's Sydney,
Australia,
but I did that for awhile.
I was like,
I got no fucking.
It was just like for months,
but those are.
But as you work through something,
right?
Yeah.
You sort of Hash them out on the stage
and I think is another thing that
happens when you're working out new
materials that you get to the point
where you said it so many times that as
your,
as you're saying it,
your brain seeks new ways to approach
it.
Oh,
because you like an isolation chamber
for your fucking material material.
It's almost like a mantra.
Like you say it so many times,
it loses its meaning.
So as you're saying,
if you find like God saying this again,
you have some new way and or it could be
this and then you all of a sudden you go
into a new direction just to entertain
yourself.
I mean how many times have you done
that?
Gone down like completely ridiculous
paths with a bit where it's like babies
with big dicks
and machine guns and they fucking.
And then like doing,
it could have a machine gun safety latch
that was one machine doesn't seem
possible,
but those kind of like ridiculous
territory of your peanuts would be
lacking and you might do one of those
and it would only work that night and it
was for that night,
but every now and then you do one of
those and then there'll be a piece in
there that becomes a new chunk.
Yeah.
You know?
That's how you
fine things.
That's how I do it way I find.
Yeah,
I do that in the writing itself through
both.
It's a.
But I,
I find I get a lot of ideas lately from
driving around with the car radio off
often do that.
I do that when I'm,
when I'm,
I don't allow myself when I'm looking
for the next storyteller show and I've
thought of one yet,
you know,
I don't let myself use the radio.
Oh,
I get it done.
I like it.
Yeah.
That's smart.
There's something about the act of
driving without a radio that your mind
has to take in all those things.
You can't tune it out.
Yeah.
I saw a study that when you're on the
phone,
even when you have an ear buds in or
whatever,
your,
your peripheral vision goes down 20
percent,
not me.
Okay,
well maybe.
But the studies show Super Douchey guy
that's invulnerable,
but yeah,
but because your mind is not focusing on
that.
My mentality,
my mentality is I see everything always.
I'll rock that test and I got a 180
degree vision of doctors.
They tested my site.
I saw to the right and left further than
any known him.
Wow,
that's amazing.
So don't worry about me with the fucking
ear buds or you're by yourself.
I'm sorry to tell you about yourself.
Super Douchey guy who never get sick.
I never get sick.
Where do you live?
In a plastic bubble.
You fucking cunt.
Got Sick.
Who are you?
Do you not eat pussy?
Every now and then you're going to get
sick.
Okay.
Things are going
go wrong already even tried cheese
sticks.
I'm not into that.
I'm totally organic.
I love that stimpson monster.
That your mushrooms.
No,
not that,
but when was like people say,
I don't,
I don't do that.
If I've never tried it,
right,
well they don't do it.
Then he goes,
I don't react well to psychedelics.
Those type of drugs because aren't
getting any mushrooms.
It goes,
which ones have you done like that?
He goes,
oh,
no,
Campbell soup.
What would you know?
Why would you know if you don't do that?
Well,
Campbell mushroom soup it fucking trip
me out.
Took him back to high school,
flying through the hallways,
but now everything was blue.
Yeah.
Well there's people that are scared and
rightly so,
you know,
for.
I don't encourage anybody to do
anything.
In the beginning I did,
when I first started doing dmt and I did
mushrooms,
I was like,
fucking do it.
You should do it.
Go do it.
But now I feel like if you're not
compelled to do it,
you shouldn't do it.
If you're not drawn into doing it,
And if you don't have a deep,
deep,
deep desire to do it,
I don't know about it might have
developed with desire.
Yeah,
I,
yeah,
maybe.
But that's up to you.
That's you.
There's books out there,
there's videos you can watch.
There's artists,
articles you can read without too much
investment
in your time and you can learn a lot of
shit about silicide man,
you can learn a lot of shit about the
history of it.
You can learn a lot of shit about the
positive benefits on personality,
so if you want to do it,
go ahead.
But I'm not talking to you about it.
It says I can't do it anymore.
It was just.
I've talked to too many Wackos,
too many,
too many loons,
too many people that are in the cult of
the mushroom and do the sacred mushrooms
going to get through all this?
Yeah.
Sometimes you're like,
all right,
easy.
I don't know what you mean by that.
Or they'll give you mushrooms.
Sometimes.
He's like,
Dude,
I'm leaving tomorrow.
I can't like.
Well right now.
I'm like,
am I doing it right now?
We're not doing mushrooms together.
Mr S FBI agent,
you would never do that.
Would you know?
It's weird to do mushrooms in front of
people with people you don't even know.
I don't even smoke weed.
Oh yeah,
I'm done.
No,
it's just too much weirdness out there,
man,
and it all came from this guy in
Cleveland that I'm positive was a comp.
What happened?
Said it was a cop.
He's asking me,
where did you get some dmt?
He was saying you don't want to get some
dmt crew cut on and like a like a
fucking.
It was like a flight jacket.
Like I was looking at the way that guys
dress and the fact that he's by himself
and I'm looking at the fact that he's a
shitty actor.
Like he was like acting when he was
talking to me.
I'm like,
what are you talking about?
He goes,
yeah,
you did that DMT,
right.
You know where to get it.
I go,
are you fucking for real?
Asking me if I know where to get illegal
drugs.
And when I said it like that loud,
he walked away.
Oh really?
Yeah,
because he got embarrassed and he walked
away.
He was like,
good cover.
You talk so good about it.
Friend to a friend.
Somebody wants something bad coming up
to me asking me if where I can probably
just a dumb person.
Oh No,
no,
no.
It wasn't stone.
That's the thing.
Do you think it was a cop?
Yeah,
I'm pretty sure it was gone.
Well.
I have pretty good instincts,
man.
I mean,
I'm guessing obviously the little edge
could grow in my imagination over time,
but I was very convinced that this guy
was fishy as fuck.
Did you wait?
You know,
when people are lying to you know,
you know someone's bullshitting you or
they're up to something.
Yeah,
there was something.
He was up to something and I've entered
into a few of those circumstances
though.
Anyway,
was like,
what am I doing this yourself?
And it's like,
oh,
well that's why when I said it loudly,
I said,
are you seriously asking me if I can get
you illegal drugs?
And then he just fucking got out of
there.
He was like,
I am.
It's just too loud.
I was saying it loud and like group of
people that were waiting in line to take
pictures and he just bolted.
Hey man,
Nuer gets dmt.
Can I get a gun from you?
A nice guy.
It's people that just really want the
information.
They don't think like that.
They're asking another human.
This guy was asking me to get him
something.
I was like,
Jesus Christ.
Dude.
Brian deese.
Macquarie with strangers.
A stranger with weird.
Have you seen the trailer,
the red band trailer for a movie?
What's already new movie?
What's the red band trailer?
The inappropriate conduct.
And what is this?
It's a sketch movie.
He's in it a lot too.
Uh,
Laurie's along with,
uh,
along with,
Lindsey Lohan,
your favorite Lindsey wetlands.
And check this out.
Adrian Brody character.
This isn't even out yet.
What happened in this Adrian Brody?
Sorry.
Now make me gag.
Pinch off the guy that brought you this
slept shop.
Oh,
I remember you telling me about this.
Okay.
Coke.
Yeah.
Chris Brown.
God,
what was that like?
Slanted.
Do Africa get the chicken to tell them
about the bathroom sector?
The sector.
Those assholes.
Okay.
Was like,
I just think I heard my dick.
That is wrong.
Can I shoot you Adrian Brody in his
finest performance since the pianist
suckling pig.
He's.
Now you're ready to blow.
I'm just going to push your stool in
real slow comedy.
How do you get through life like this?
Man,
this is crazy.
I still studied.
How does this help me drive this month?
Oh my God.
Already explained yourself.
Sketch.
Maybe I was only responsible.
The ones I did the sketches.
You did look like the world with real
people.
Racist things.
That was great,
man.
I thought you were done with amazing
racist.
She brought it back.
Yeah.
Somebody finally was able to put the
money into it to do it right.
Which one did you?
Well,
you don't want to tell us.
Don't tell us what the gags.
Where shouldn't.
Obviously there was that wine to African
black folks.
Did you apologize to them?
Tell them it was a sketch.
How did they accept it?
Not really.
There's still mad at you.
That's not mad at me.
Black folks,
black jokes and be careful with that
song.
He got
worked up to that point.
Rarely will people like,
oh,
okay,
cool.
I'm sorry.
What did you tell them?
Like how do you bring them down?
I didn't bring him down me to.
Oh,
you mean off off the emotional cliff?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You just get them to sign stuff and so
you know,
I'm really sorry.
It's just.
But they still look at you like,
yeah,
I know.
Yeah,
you can run it.
You taken a crazy chance when you're
just out there in the world running it.
A random folks.
Yeah.
Luckily most people are not murderers.
That's the boat thing.
It's in Santa Monica.
Oh,
but if I was joy ideas,
I'd say,
what the fuck is wrong with you?
What's the fuck is wrong with you dog?
I'm Monica.
I think it's coming up.
Got Chicken and a came after you dress
like a gang banger.
Was he in fact a gang banger?
Who was that guy right there?
It looks so easy and ended up UAE.
I don't know.
The guy attacks.
You look it up.
It looks like he's a Dr Dre or somewhat
dude.
It's just a plaid shirt.
He's dressed very gangsta like who's the
guy with the chicken?
Who's the other guy with you?
That was Dante.
Dante,
the comedian.
the comedian,
and he's offering them chicken dressed
like a slave masters that was going on.
Then she's free,
man.
You can't let it get in their mouth.
Wow.
That looks hilarious.
Dante get hit or just you just may even
safely on the boat.
Good for him.
He's a smart man.
Stay outside the blast range.
Just like we're going to order the
Caprio from Django unchained.
You see emily,
what'd you think?
It's pretty good.
Pretty good fucking movie.
Yeah,
he knows how to make a good goddamn
movie.
He makes things entertaining.
You know?
Even when it's off a little bit,
he's still fucking.
It's still funny shit.
Three hours,
man.
It was really fun to watch like the life
of Pi.
Everybody tells me that I've appraised
in imaging movie come out yet.
I've seen it.
I've finished leap leap in the life of
Pi that's supposed to get.
If you get a complete Karma Dharma from
broadridge,
peaceful place,
whether I'm a vegetarian and I went to
the Buddhist statues crying one Buddha
beside his life of Pi.
He lived a life of Pi lives.
It lives on a boat with a tiger for a
month.
Then it became friends,
shut the fuck up and will not go for
him.
I'm not a child.
I'm not a fucking child.
Wouldn't the tiger fish forum and they
bring them both?
I can.
I don't think the tiger willing to jump
in the water and catch things for that
guy.
I don't think they were really friends.
Bullshit movie.
You think the was.
He saw tiger on a boat,
the guy and then it's like,
oh beautiful.
Oh my God.
I got killed by a tiger that tiger off.
Even temporarily,
like he took a tuna from the tiger and
he screamed at him and slap something on
the ground.
The idea that the tiger would go for
that in a boat.
The Fuck Outta here,
man.
That's like a hamster telling you what
to do.
That's what that's like.
It's like imagine you coming home and
the hamsters telling you what to do.
You mentioned being in a boat and the
hamsters telling you that it's going to
eat and you're not going to get to eat.
You'd be like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
He'd grab that stupid thing and you'd
kill it and you eat it.
That's exactly the tiger would done
that.
Maybe we should have been two minutes
long.
Tiger season.
Look not only at the tiger was like
hiding in the boat for like a whole day.
Spoiler alert.
You're going to be on a boat for a month
with the fucking tiger.
You have to do.
I mean there's gotta be some suspension
of disbelief.
People love the book.
What did he do?
He just yelled at him because I ain't go
to use my friend.
We are one the tiger and I took griller.
We were.
We survived.
Iv is a beautiful visual movie that
Angley guys a bad black mountain.
Did he did it?
That was beautiful visual too.
I don't know that.
I think singly isn't him?
I think so.
Brian,
you have seven computers in front of
you?
Yeah.
Why don't you find that out?
What are you doing?
Surfing the web.
No.
Was looking up this crazy shit about
Adam Carolla.
I don't know if you heard about what?
What is it?
He's one of the first podcasters to get
sued by who,
for what a,
this big company that owns a bunch of
patents,
uh,
when,
after Adam Corolla and the people that
make,
uh,
some other podcasts that's pretty big
and there are suing them,
I believe something.
See how stuff works.
Dot Com.
Uh,
it's about a playlist.
So it looks like.
What's a playlist?
Do you mean?
Uh,
this company called Personal Audio Llc.
did a patent infringement lawsuit
against apple recently in one and now
they're going after podcasters.
What are they suing for using the,
using the algorithm to do a list?
Yeah.
They're not really saying much yet and
I'm Corolla hasn't sent anything yet,
but it's a Adam curl.
So I continue to say girls aren't funny.
I love the opportunity to lift others up
on it,
but it says that a personal audio is web
a website.
The company says its patents.
A pioneer techniques now commonly used
today in portable players,
smartphones,
tablets,
and other products.
And it says that,
and it lists several pants from music
playlists,
podcasting,
personalized recommendations and auto
audio messaging.
So is it like,
did he have a application that they're
saying infringed on a patent?
I know it sort of sounds like it seems
like this company has patents and
podcasting,
so I don't know what that means because
it can't just be like,
Hey,
I put an audio file up and now you're
suing,
you know,
so it has to be something about maybe he
has his own personal app and something
in that App.
Well that's why I say that because smart
phones and tablets,
that's,
that's why it looks like it.
I'm hoping you don't really need calls
to sue somebody.
You can just sue.
That's true.
And then it's out there.
Yeah.
But I'm sure that they just won a
million dollar a lawsuit against apple
so that they have going on here.
Oh.
So maybe there's some sort of
application that apple has available.
Probably some kind of playlist thing
that's involved with making the APP and
uh,
because they want.
It also says that they,
it's an involved with making the APP.
They've,
they've entered the license agreements
with Sirius Xm radio,
coby,
Samsung,
Amazon,
Motorola,
and have.
Yeah.
So it looks like there's companies that
are actually entering licensing
agreement agreements against probably
some kind of playlist thing or
something.
Huh?
That's interesting.
Yeah.
So I guess it's probably the personal
apps that are doing it.
Oh,
that's what you asked me if I have my
own APP.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
That's interesting.
I have an APP but I didn't make,
wouldn't it be the maker of the APP?
So I don't think I'm responsible for a
fan made am I can't be.
I didn't know that.
Can't.
What am I gonna do?
I'm gonna stop everybody from making.
I mean look,
it would be stupid.
Like they're making something for free
that other people can enjoy.
Why would I stop that?
That's true.
And also it makes me wonder if like
companies like Lipson who offers like
free APP.
I wonder if that makes lipson
accountable or every single one person
who does that.
Oh my God,
everyone's fucked if that's the case.
Yeah.
Well,
because it was like if,
if,
if somebody makes printing supplies,
like they haven't done anything wrong.
If you fucking cop just pirate a bunch
of shirts.
That's true.
Makes San Francisco 40 niners shirts.
Yeah,
that's true.
Yeah.
How do you doing it is?
Do you think this is a real picture of
Photoshop?
Because it's very.
Oh my God.
Oh God,
I hate that word by it.
The whole giant fucking rant on twitter
about that,
but no hit and people were saying that,
oh,
it's supposed to represent like,
you know,
not,
not having hate now it just represents
no trend represents celebrities.
They're like,
look at me.
I'm there to.
I'm cool too.
It's the dumbest idea ever that the way
to avoid hate is to draw on your face
and cover your lips with tape.
How much it's been nice to have to be
anti gay just because you're against the
fucking look of an ad campaign and why
does Amparo looks so gay in this photo?
He looks like he's wearing maker gate
them up.
They gave them on Photoshop.
Right?
Like given blush and no know.
It's just how they shot it.
Yeah.
That's an odd little thing there and let
her know,
hey,
I saw that on so many people's pages,
the table.
So many people walk in and then
everybody's like,
I want that too,
but it's not supporting the thing.
It's about a trendy DM message.
Like the way to stop pain is to put tape
over your mouth.
Like what?
What do you.
What does that represent?
Blow jobs.
What kind of image is that?
A piece of tape over your fucking mouth.
How?
How about just smiles?
How about people?
Smile.
Yeah.
What's the table with us?
That's the silence.
Sure.
There's a reason for it.
The reason is to get us to talk about it
comes out.
That means you can't have cake come out
of your mouth.
Yes,
but that is not the hateful one.
Or not saying he's not the hey buddies.
Not the hateful ones.
There's all these celebrities,
all these different people that put tape
over their fucking mouth and wrote no
hate on their face.
They're dumb or they got talked into
doing it by a chick.
That could be it too.
I wonder if anyone trying to put tape
over their mouth and put it over there
in those two and then started to
suffocate a little.
I think.
I think they would suffocate and
trendiness sort of thing before they
would run out of air,
you know,
hate and it's an h with a red eight
because it's mission eight.
Proposition eight was the,
the,
the proposition that made it illegal to
have gay marriage.
But why tape over your fucking mouth,
man,
and why you have to draw on your face.
Okay.
This beautiful,
sexy as fuck.
Ever looked back.
Really at him,
right?
He's got crew.
Palm it in his hair.
He's got the little.
I looked like a fucking novella star.
He looks awesome.
Yeah.
Well we wish them luck.
Lawsuits.
I wouldn't have sex with a guy like
that,
but I would want to hang out with them.
He's a good dude.
He's a very good deal with those.
Is You ever talked to him?
Have you ever done a show?
It was fun guy,
man.
I think I tried to get me on twitter to
promote,
especially when it comes out.
Yeah.
He said he's a fun guy to talk to.
He's a motherfucker got so much
interesting shit going on in his head
all the time.
My friend listens to him and he said he
just loves the David Allen greer
episodes because when Adam crawls,
like I got to do um,
sponsors with mount,
so no cursing and David Allen greer
refuses to comply and then you just
wasted.
He goes,
you know,
go to stamps.com
for all your content con con shit
comment.
She's like,
keep doing that.
So the way he does commercials too,
he,
this is how most people are doing it.
They,
they break up the show into like little
chunks.
They do a bunch of them,
they'll do like four of them.
They'll do them like every 15 minutes or
half hour,
whatever you're going to do,
but,
and then just say,
okay,
here,
this next segment,
this next hour is brought to you by so
and so.
That's just stops the whole flow of the
conversation.
They just start reading paper.
Yeah.
And they've asked me to do that same
thing and I,
I can't do it.
I get why.
That'd be a good one.
But then people would put that in the
beginning.
Let's keep out of the way in the
People skip right over that shit.
Yeah,
but so what?
That's fine too.
So what you know and sometimes they
don't.
And by the way the,
the ads like a lot of times we've talked
bad shit during the ads and sometimes
they're funny and yeah,
we have to get to the user code named
Rogan and Seritos shut off.
We get to all that stuff,
but at the end of the day it's fun.
So fun.
Yeah.
The show still free,
you know,
we still have to pay for bandwidth and
everything like that,
but I refuse to interrupted if your,
if your whole podcast was just the
commercial part and you're like,
you,
you Rogan Diaz and a red band.
It was like three people here.
That would still be a very entertaining
pocket.
Oh yeah.
We could.
Especially.
We still had the flashlight.
We could have missed the flesh.
I can't wait.
I get to see the site next week.
I'm so happy
you could say porn awards
bring you some.
I have a gang of him.
I told you they're just sitting in my
office.
Did you hear that?
Good news about the.
Doug.
Stan hope trial by the way.
That's fucking awesome.
The judge rules a ruling allows the
comics a duck.
Stan hope to release video accusing at
the port.
Saint Lucie,
man of molestation.
Whoa.
Court.
So I'm doug and Andy Andrews just had a
video of this guy who apparently
molested andy when he was young and he
promised Andy a car.
He had video of him doing what?
He had to a video of him accusing this
guy and the guy broke down.
He also claimed that he served him
alcohol,
shown them Porno Porno movies like,
like he,
he molested him like crazy
to be quite about.
It's not press charges when you're
getting older.
Is that what it was?
It's,
it's gonna.
It's during a recorded.
During in January ninth,
2009.
Performance of down and dirty on HBO.
And they went and got the guy and they
found him where he lived and,
and I,
I forget how they got him to do an
interview with something else.
Right Joe?
Yeah.
I don't know how they got them to do it.
Somehow or another.
Got them to a meet and do the uh,
the interview where he accused him of a
sexual predator.
Wait,
so he paid them off to not talk?
No.
They sued them somehow or another,
the guy whose videos get released to
doug and Andy saying,
don't release that.
Yeah,
I guess.
Well,
several times from 1976 to 1981.
Those are good years.
Those were good years.
A massage them twice.
Why is it a five year period?
And then when he was between 11 and 13
can't count.
That's so fucked up,
man.
So far they want to release this video,
this guy,
this guy counterfeiting and crying.
The Guy said,
uh,
you know,
you were a sexual predator.
Me.
Andy said that.
And the Guy said,
uh Huh.
And the judge just ruled in favor of
Andy and said,
you can release us.
Yes.
Wow.
There hasn't been any comment.
If he's going to release it,
stand up.
Says when and how the videos were
released.
It's up to andy that this is all andy's
deal.
I'll get out there though.
I guarantee that it'll get out there.
Wow.
I'm sure it's,
yeah,
I wonder why can't you like,
I don't want to fucking.
I'm a black male and I'm putting this
video out of him saying what he did.
It's not.
The Punch was not worse.
He's just admitting to the thing he did.
Right.
You know?
Well,
you know what,
with a lot of those guys,
it's about being exposed.
Like once you're exposed to sexual
predator,
I can't imagine that they'd got away his
whole life and got away with it.
I mean probably is already a sexual
Predator somewhere.
Wait til they find out.
You really think they got away with it
all this time.
It seems like the pretty policy that's
so fucked.
I just always assumed that if someone is
out there and molesting and they,
they try to keep doing it and then get
caught because he can't do anything now
because it's been over what,
seven years or whatever it is.
What is the statute of limitations
expires and child molesting her.
So you can just talk about it.
Thanks.
So right.
And the ball doesn't get arrested.
That's Kinda fucked.
I don't know.
I know the statute of limitations
limitations apply to everything it does
not apply to and there's federal statute
of limitations.
Is there a state statute of limitations
as well?
Like if you say,
Hey,
I killed jfk and he had proof,
they're probably still going to do
something.
How old were you?
This would be a great segment.
It's time for Brian redbands law advice.
Hey,
I'm half.
Watch that because somebody.
But it was 10 years ago.
Do you think I can tell them about it
now?
Oh yeah.
That's plenty of time.
You should brag about it to the family
and if they do anything you can sue them
and do the guy tell you he was a cop
knows they don't tell you you're a cop,
you're fine.
Get off Scott free.
They did that in breaking bad was
something early on with somebody who's
like trusted a cop and he was like,
you'll copy goes because you got to tell
them that if you already I need set.
It sold them and he goes,
you,
what are you talking about?
Yeah.
It's a weird sort of a myth that you
have to tell someone.
If they asked her,
are you a cop?
I think there was always like hookers
and movies would ask the Johns,
are you a cop?
Did you get arrested for getting a
hooker in college?
No.
Is that real?
Did you get arrested in college?
No,
it's just a joke.
Got completely drunk.
The only thing I learned in college is
avoid hookers with walkie talkies was a
joke.
It was just a joke.
Oh,
okay.
No,
that's a complete fabrication.
That was back in the days when I used to
write jokes.
Jokes.
That's a good to have to once in awhile.
Yeah.
There's a good,
like a good solid one liner to pull you
out of a ditch or to just set the stage
as long as it's like a good crisp one
could have a complete game changer.
Just like completely changed the tempo
of where the show's going.
Man,
there's a trailer for this new Kevin
Hart movie.
Kevin Hart apparently has this new
standup movie coming out and you see
like the size of the crowds he's
dealing.
Holy shuts the one with fucking pyro
techniques.
Yeah,
I did.
They didn't show any,
the PYRO,
I guess they're trying to save that as
fun.
But in the trailer they didn't show it.
No,
but I mean you're talking about like,
it looks like 18,000
people.
It looks like the UFC.
He's doing massive places.
Two crazy good for him.
Good for him.
That's great for comedy.
Anytime a guy,
people exposed to comedy.
Yeah.
And anytime a guy that's that big,
you know,
who does that?
Well,
that's just stimulates the whole sort of
a comedy movement.
Like I see that like,
wow,
like where were all these people like
five years ago when there were all these
people for any,
uh,
any other comedian.
Well,
there they were out there.
The fans are out there because nobody
had done anything that really resonated
with them.
With this guy,
you know,
they get them access to somehow.
Well he's the hot young guy,
you know,
as far as like,
uh,
especially like young black comedians.
That's why cat Williams was upset at
him.
I took over his spot.
Yeah.
Apparently,
you know,
science was the hip one.
Remember that especially did when you
had all the celebrities come up,
somebody from like little John or
somebody come up and like do a lot by
Katt Williams and in his prime is still
one of my all time favorites when he
says his especially was amazing looney
behaviors he's involved with these days,
whatever he goes off in front of a black
crowd on Michael Jackson.
Yeah.
The honest way.
The way everyone's ignoring,
like stop it.
Like as a child molester,
you would never trust him with your
child,
you know,
to a black audience.
They were like,
what?
And he just fucking set it right at them
over and over again.
It was like wow.
He,
he beat them down with it,
know,
beat them down with it.
He's.
He was hilarious.
He was fucking.
I mean maybe,
maybe still is.
Maybe this is all trolling.
Didn't.
What's his face?
Joaquin Phoenix.
Troll everybody for a year.
A year and we just saw cat and that new
movie trailer where member,
it's a documentary.
They talking about the new movie.
That's a scary movie.
Five.
Oh yeah,
there's a,
he's in a trailer where he goes,
nobody in the trailer.
Oh really?
Well that's his whole thing was just a
big troll.
Right.
It's just so we can like make a movie
about it.
Yeah.
That was the other guy's walking
phoenix.
Yeah.
That was his thing.
He was going on letterman pretending
he's nuts.
And what did he do?
He made a.
They made a whatsapp.
Yeah.
He was a rapper for awhile and he would
fall down on purpose.
No problem with that is then when
anybody like Brittany Spears shaves her
head or Katt Williams goes crazy.
Like,
Nah,
maybe it's just the publicity.
So yeah,
I mean like,
no,
these people are in a bad place.
Well,
Brittany,
experience for sure.
Yeah,
I think it's being like a hot girl
singer like that has got to be one of
the.
Especially someone who's famous.
Is that chickens?
Yeah,
it's gotta be.
The pressure's got to be unimaginable to
grow up in that pressure.
You have to go from being a mouseketeer
to be a grown.
What?
Celebrities?
Other level of fame.
Oh yes.
That worldwide.
You know,
you can't,
your bus gets mobbed.
Yeah.
You know,
and does she even have her kids?
I don't think so.
Yeah.
I think Kay feds got the kids,
like when they don't even,
they don't give you your kids.
Man.
That's not good because the state
saying,
I know noted the Richmond,
but just like,
listen,
this guy is,
he loves these guilty.
Almost always give it to the girl.
Dude,
I don't know how it's set up.
It's got to be rare though,
that take kids away from the mother,
the Scott.
It's not when they're.
Everyone's healthy,
everyone's healthy.
The kids generally stay with the mother.
They're less.
Unless there's an agreement.
Ferguson's monologue about Brittany
spears.
Yeah.
It was really nice.
Yeah,
it was very heartfelt.
You know,
there's,
there's a certain amount of us that want
to kick somebody when they're down.
They want to mock someone,
whether it's Lindsay Lohan or whether
it's anybody that's Paris Hilton or you
know,
when everyone is getting some,
you know,
everyone's shitting on someone they want
to just pile on.
They want to jump in.
And whether it's about Brittany,
Brittany Murphy,
or whether it's Brittany spears or
whether it's Liz,
will any of these girls don't like
people love a lot this week.
A small part of you was.
She was.
I mean that thing with her when,
you know,
when,
when she was falling apart and she ended
up dying and then her husband died.
Like all that shit.
Drugs,
man doing heavy opiod.
Brittany Murphy had opiates in our
system.
This dude,
there's so many people out there that
are having problems right now with
opiates.
It's which one's opiates?
Oxycontin's.
Heroin.
Morphine.
I know a lot of jokes about,
about pill sometimes.
And then when I go to the Midwest
sometimes my drug stuff,
I'm like,
ah,
you guys aren't going to get my.
And then I realized during that trip I
was like,
oh,
this is where this shit is from.
Anything else to do?
I shouldn't talk about school with
Brittany Murphy.
I'm assuming it was,
it was oxycontins.
Now that I say that,
I'm like,
no,
it like a speed thing.
But it was in the system.
I will.
Let's see what guy.
That scene where m&M fucked her in the.
In the warehouse when she just spit on
her hand and put it down there.
What a good kid.
God,
that was hot.
Was it?
Remember that?
From eight mile.
Did you beat it off so that at all?
Oh yeah.
Yeah,
I was right.
Sorry.
Multiple medications at present.
Elevated levels of hydrocodone.
That's oxy?
Yep.
Acetaminophen.
Aspirin?
Yeah.
Cold medication.
She's a cold ass honky chloro fen or m?
A L meth amphetamine.
Oh my God.
She had meth in her.
Jesus Christ.
This chick had a crazy cocktail man.
Intel inside hydrocodone.
Hydrocodone.
Okay.
And then I guess I gave her a headache
so she took some tylenol.
So we'll see the medicine in their
system.
Doesn't that sound a party?
They're going to end meth amphetamine.
I think l methamphetamine.
Is that the same?
No idea.
Brian.
You ever do from Mexico?
Let's Google it and see what pills do
the.
I don't do any pills.
I do once in a while we'll do some molly
if that's around.
Yeah.
No.
Okay.
No,
no,
no.
I want to get that.
Not adderall,
but that pill,
that other stuff.
Adderall.
Methamphetamine is a level meth
amphetamine.
And what it is is a cold medication.
It's a nasal decongestant.
Really?
Yeah.
It's a vassal,
diaster vasyl constructor,
which is the active ingredient using
some over the counter nasal
decongestants.
So she was basically,
she was taking oxys and she got sick.
Might have also been snorting the oxys
well that's,
she died from sickness.
She didn't die from the drugs.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Well,
much like Duisburg would.
He would,
by the way,
we do have someone who's got to debate
Peter Duesberg.
We have a professor of biology,
heavy duty phd dude who's down for the
program that he's a professor Tyson to
do it,
but he's going,
he's going to do it.
Um,
so,
uh,
but I think much like his assertions,
he,
he was saying he says a lot of crazy
shit about HIV that HIV only exists in
the immune system.
People that are already compromised.
And then what's really going on is those
people are partying.
Well that's what she was doing.
She was partying so hard that she was
sick as fuck.
So while she was sick as fuck,
he's taken all his nasal decongestants
and really what it was is her body was
too weak to fight off anything because
she was as red lining and on heroin.
That's what was going on.
Scary scary stuff.
But yeah,
when,
when he,
um,
when he separated himself from the pack,
Craig Ferguson did,
when he did that thing about Britney
spears,
he said just a little girl is totally
got a problem.
She's got a substance abuse problem and
were making fun of it.
Like,
it's fine.
She's a mom.
She's fucking up her life.
Tell Brittney today.
Can anyone watch Jay Leno anymore?
More than anyone watched that?
Jay Leno enjoy it.
Which age group is watching that?
I was Kimmel at 1130 now he beat a
Letterman is for show to us.
Good ratings.
Gjelina was always been nice to me.
I'll always be nice to him.
And we both liked cars.
Yeah.
But man,
well you should crazy
walking thing.
All of it is just like,
who are you playing to?
Hey,
you know the names of the people that
are like being nice folks.
Folks that when we were striking for
Sag,
I got my sag card by striking down the
commercial strike of whatever it was 12
years ago.
And uh,
he drove by and honked and like put his
hands up,
leaving his mansion in one of his 100
automobiles.
And what'd you guys any money though?
I got to pay for all this shit.
I've never seen a guy on earth that has
more cars.
That must seem like such a job after a
while.
Maintaining those cars.
No.
Doing that for 30 years.
Five days a week.
The tonight show.
Fucking loves it though.
We'll look.
I love doing this.
You know,
I mean,
this is obviously not the tonight show.
It's a lot easier.
We just call it a day.
You want to say we're not doing this.
That's what's beautiful about it,
but I love doing it.
You know what I'm saying?
For him like the tonight show that one
hour a night that he does.
It's fucking exciting.
Yeah.
He enjoys it.
He likes being a funny guy with some
funny shit to say.
He likes sitting down and interviewing
people and stories as material on stage.
Yep.
Wow.
Real stages.
Yep.
He goes to the and comedy and Magic Club
every Sunday night,
man,
every Sunday night he works out his
monologue for the week.
Yep.
Yeah.
Got a bunch of jokes.
He wrote himself,
has comics over the eat fried chicken
and they write jokes.
How do you not love the guy?
He's just doing shit that you don't
like.
He's just doing some Perry Como Shit.
You know what I mean?
He's doing some fucking,
you know,
it's just whenever he says,
what's the news today?
I'm like,
why do you care?
Why should he get a little edgy
now?
And again,
it's just,
you know,
that job is not that.
That job is almost like,
it's like you're a host,
you know,
your,
your friendly host to get to get a
couple of chuckles.
You're not there to make any big points.
You're just there to sort of get
everybody grinning and then bring out
the people that are selling books.
Bring out the guy who's got a movie
coming out,
bring out this.
Pat would get like,
I'm not into it,
but that's me.
Maybe like I said,
some people really like talking to
celebrities to today.
I got up at eight,
no,
9:00
in the morning on Sunday and drove,
drove down to bellflower to play in a
pool tournament.
How many fucking people excited to do
that?
It's a tiny fraction of the world's
population.
In fact,
if you told them they were going to do
that,
they'd be like the flood.
I don't want to go play 30 am fucking
suck at pool and I'm not going to get up
in the morning and then drive all the
way the fuck down there,
but to me it was like,
let me get up,
have a good breakfast,
try to get some coffee in me,
wake up,
get there early and Knox and balls.
As soon as you finished off in that
tournament,
went right back to another one.
Yeah,
I play it again on Monday night because
Sunday night it didn't play good.
I was not awake,
man.
My.
I think if I'm ever going to play in a
tournament in the morning,
I gotta at least do some calisthenics,
like I think maybe some jumping jacks or
something like really?
Yeah,
maybe run up a couple flights of stairs
or something because I feel like my eyes
couldn't see that good yet.
I was like,
I was like blinking a lot and my arm
wasn't loosened up.
I was just,
I was still stretching.
I'd barely,
you know,
being a week for like two hours or
whatever it fucking was when I,
when I first started playing.
So I realized that like I need more
preparation.
If you're going to do something like
toms to people on the phone,
get loose a little more around.
It's really fun though.
Stretch beforehand?
No,
but I stretched during it sometimes like
you're like one out.
So not my chance to shine.
I'll just sort of like,
you know,
put my leg on something that's,
I wear a batman outfit Bro.
And a Cape and were a Mexican mask and a
n a n a fucking coward.
Intimidate people.
If somebody came into a pool,
I'll just like that wanting to actually,
I'm going to be like,
you're not getting my action.
Do unique thing about pool is that
nobody gives a fuck about anything else
in the poolroom except can you play.
That's like all they ever care about.
It's like it's a.
it's like a place like pool halls are a
place where you have a whole group of
people that are addicted to a very
specific activity and that's hugely
important to them in that comedy.
No,
no,
no.
Like if you meet a guy in comedy and the
guy doesn't do stand up,
it never bothers you or even if he's
bad,
but like a bigger guy,
a little,
but it's not going to be like,
that bothered me for years I had to
learn how to get over that.
When I came to the store,
I learned to get over that because there
was guys that are genuinely loved and I
would see there every week and I give
them a big hug and I just have to leave
the room and they went on stage,
but I realized as a person,
he's a great guy.
He's just whatever limits him up there,
everyone's got their own struggles to
get there or whatever.
Their potential is.
Not that great.
Whatever it is,
but it's like.
But if you had a pool hall and you can't
play,
they have no respect for,
you know,
if the president was in the pool hall
and he was fucking make it shitty shots,
I just shake their head.
This motherfucker can't even get out.
It's just,
it's a weird thing when people lock onto
one obsession together and like a group
of golfers all just getting good people
and I mean it's not even always about
getting good at.
Sometimes it's just about being obsessed
with a thing like people,
people fantasy,
fantasy games,
you know,
fantasy football.
Even they'll get together and like
games.
Those people always want to tell you
about their Goddamn fucking roster.
Can't believe Erin foster.
All we did was six more yards to the
end.
And then he goes,
why would anyone,
even the people in your league aren't
entertained by this?
Did you hear about that junior,
how you say his last name,
junior sale during the sale,
the guy who committed suicide,
they,
um,
they found that he had cte had chronic
brain disease.
Yeah,
I saw the headline.
What does it,
you.
That's what it was.
It's from traumatic.
That was,
that was a football related to suicide.
Yeah.
One hundred percent.
It's so true.
Traumatic brain disorder,
they uh,
yeah,
it's bad.
It's very bad when people are
intentionally leaving the brains over to
study.
So the other football players don't have
to go through this and it's multiple.
Yeah,
I'm starting to think football.
Yeah.
Um,
you know,
I think um,
it's very important to figure out like
when this starts happening and how to
cut it off.
Like I think you can take a few hits as
a young man and I think you could take a
few knockouts in fighting.
You could get,
it could be fun your later years,
but how many Kenya?
I don't think they know.
They don't know and it varies.
That's another problem.
It's also.
I read this thing about a guy who
committed suicide,
who got knocked unconscious,
high school football player,
real friendly.
Nice.
Everyone loved them and then they sat
him out and he did this stuff that was a
stimulating to his mind.
He went to a concert,
played a bunch of video games and
committed suicide and they were like,
yeah,
you're supposed to take off from all
that.
Barely read if anything,
but like sit alone.
No loud music because he played video
games and went to stimulate his mind too
much.
It was just in his,
in his concussed mind.
Couldn't handle it.
So it just went out and killed himself.
Yeah,
he got super depressed.
They called him down for dinner and he
was like not coming down.
Hanging God Jesus is coming.
I mean,
he showed no signs of depression prior
and they were like,
this can easily be caused by concussions
until they're out of your system.
There's so much they don't understand.
Yeah.
The the kind of concussions that you
get,
and football too,
boy,
you get people running at you.
Of course when you're running that way
and they're running this way and also
it's like the ones where you don't get a
concussion and you just get wrong over
and over and over again.
You're hitting helmets with other
people.
In fact,
they say that that's the biggest issue.
It's not even the actual concussions
themselves.
It's subconcussive trauma
that accumulates.
They're saying that that's why people
who've never been knocked out in the
gym,
they.
There's been hit so many times and then
all of a sudden out of nowhere,
for whatever reason,
they're just their brain breaks and then
they can't get hit anymore and you can
hit them and they just fall down.
Like it's a weird thing that happens to
guys just.
They just lose their chin.
They completely lose their chin and
it's.
It's seen that the UFC enough to have.
Once you get knocked out once,
I don't know if it's because you're
probably a little slower and that's why
it got knocked out,
so you continue to get slower or just
your Chin is opened up.
Well,
actually talked to chocolate Dell about
this case.
I was thinking of to what Chuck said is
that first of all,
chuck was legendary for his ability to
take a punch land touchable.
Just.
He just was tough as fuck.
He would bite down on his mouthpiece and
swing at,
you know,
like Alistair overeem and him fought in
pride in the Grand Prix.
The two.
Oh,
200,
three pound Grand Prix.
I think their version of it,
they didn't call it light heavyweight.
I think they called it middleweight and
allister put it on him in that first
round man tagged him.
He didn't with some vicious shots,
but chuck Liddell just gritted down and
eventually cracked out there with an
overhand right and had them wobbled and
then jumped all over him and stopped
him.
If he was,
a lot of other guys would have went down
in that first round.
He's like,
chuck was just so tough.
You couldn't stop him.
His mind was so strong he was coming at
you and he was so determined and what he
said was that his body recognized that
his mind was going to make it take more
damage so it's body would shut off.
His consciousness would actually shut
itself off because it starts to evolve.
It had known that this guy,
this leads to damage.
When you get hit like this,
if you let this guy drive you,
he's going to keep going until the
wheels fall off and he'll,
he'll take 100 shots to the head,
just deliver one,
and then you got to deal with the
consequences of that.
So the body would shut itself off early.
So we need to be getting.
You get tagged and your brain just says
that's it.
Check please.
And just wants to shut you off.
Wow.
So if you look in like chuck's this last
fight with rich Franklin,
you know,
perfect example because he looks in
tremendous shape.
He looks fucking scary.
I mean he's really ripped.
His wife is a fitness enthusiast and she
got him like eating healthy and wearing
a like a,
a heart rate monitor and doing all this
shit that he'd never done before and
Kennedy's calories every day and eating
really healthy foods,
so he got in super good shape,
so he was down for this rich Franklin
fight,
broke rich Franklin's arm with a big
kick in the first round,
maybe rich Franklin fucked going into
that round and chuck is just going after
him and he gets clipped with a punch
that five years ago he would have ate it
like a cookie.
He would have just ate that punch and
just fucking swing done it,
but it's his brain said,
check,
please just shut them off.
And it was literally not a case of
ability and not a case of will,
but in case of his,
his just take too many shots,
so that's what happens according to him
and chuck and he would know better than
anybody.
What makes sense.
He's very honest about it.
Then once you have been exposed,
like you're just done,
you're done.
The first time probably it was already
your body and made the decision to get
knocked out of bodies,
like just go off anytime it happens,
it's bad.
Whether it's the first time or the last.
It's always bad when you get a
concussion.
There's never a good concussion,
but I think it did really varies for
some people they can get knocked out a
few times.
It'd be fine.
For other people it's like one knockout
could change their entire life and it's
all those.
You have to think about all the shit
that happened and when you were young
too,
but you don't really remember.
I mean,
how many times did you hit your head?
I hit my head a bunch of scars all over
the back of my head that aren't just my
hair transplants,
like big ass scars.
I could bring my husband child being
like one of those oversized puppies on
the linoleum floor and just like running
machine and smash get up,
run again.
I had way too much energy and that just
no direction for it at all.
I was always getting hurt.
Yeah.
I was always doing stupid shit.
You know when you're a young guy,
like if you ever seen those videos of
those young teens in Russia that are
always doing insane things like they.
They did a bungee cord,
homemade bungee cord off the roof of a
building in the middle of the winter
break.
No,
but this girl hung onto this bungee cord
that it looks like they made it with
some fucking cables.
They found.
She jumps off the fucking roof
screaming.
Wow.
And there's another one of these Russian
kids that are on a beam.
It's 900 feet above the fucking ground,
900 feet in.
This guy is walking this tightrope above
this beam and videotaping and at the
same time,
and you will shit your pants when you're
so high up.
I was a kid man before I got into
martial arts.
I did all kinds of stupid shit that I
could have done from.
I jumped on the back of a train and hung
on as a train.
Went from stop to stop.
Really man.
I hung onto a train on the outside.
Me and my friend Jimmy,
we both.
This is a newton and we hopped on a tee.
It was fucking terrifying thing was
going so fast with so stupid because
when you're a teenager,
when you're 14 years old or whatever the
fuck we were were just.
You just do it.
Just do this dumb.
You don't know the consequences are
possible consequences and you also want
to like prove to your friends you're not
scared and you want to do something
crazy,
so they'll talk about you do that with
everyone isn't doing that with their
emotions,
their heart for awhile.
Your pour yourself into.
Some girls can't do that anymore.
Your body starts to like protect itself.
Boy,
he's in love.
Like when you're 15,
yeah,
you can lose your whole identity,
but you also become a sex addict.
You know,
once you start fucking and you realize
like,
oh my God,
like this crazy feeling the flavor.
You don't.
You can never really understand quite
how good sex feels until you have sex.
However you.
I think it was.
What else?
I think the actual intercourse was like
a month before my 16th birthday.
That's.
That seems too
young to me.
Oh,
you don't know what the fuck you doing?
I was laying.
It was a late,
late bloomer.
I was 23.
Yeah,
23.
Well,
I'm,
I'm pretty sure my girlfriend was not a
virgin at the time.
I had a miscarriage at 15.
Was that a no toilet?
No,
no.
The girl was doing.
Duh.
I remember looking at it going,
wait.
She really had her miscarriage in a
toilet.
Yeah,
a gross looking what did it and if that
was just watching that and she had the
baby.
Can you imagine how different that would
be?
Oh,
your whole life.
Someone just told me something that I
have to look up because I just
remembered that about sheep.
Know about sheep that you can have sex
with a sheep and it conceives like some
sort of an embryotic fetus that always
gets a board.
It would always,
um,
a miscarriage.
She passed the third closest.
A vagina then a human.
Yeah.
I'm,
I'm not.
I'm going to find out.
Um,
is there any more weed in here?
Of course there's,
there's always weeding here.
Oh,
you got yours.
Legitly all in one.
I'm trying to find whether or not this
is true and if it's not true,
I'm going to be very upset with people
on twitter.
A lot of people were going crazy that
you said that a hydro coating is not.
People are saying it's not oxy.
Oxy,
oxy,
hydrocodone.
Vicodin.
Oh,
she had Vicodin,
so it was viking thing.
Okay.
That's not,
I don't think,
or vicodins and opiate.
All that Shit's gross.
All it is is bad or whatever.
This poor girl.
My point remains.
It's like she was.
Um,
thanks for the correction.
Vikatin opiate.
Yes.
Viking in as an opiate.
Um.
Yeah.
It's.
Yeah,
that's exactly what it was.
If I could in his hydrocodone.
Okay.
Now we know it's all opiates,
man.
So essentially it's all the shit that
we're in Afghanistan for.
Allegedly.
Have you ever done a vicodins?
Oh yeah,
tons of times.
I did vicodins once and I don't like it.
I don't like it.
Okay.
We talked about this.
We both don't like Vicodin.
That's right.
It's hydrocodone.
Hydrocodone is vicodin.
Oh really?
Yeah.
What's oxy?
Oxycodone?
Yeah.
Ahcccs.
Oxycodone.
Hydrocodone is a Vicodin oxycodone,
I guess.
Oh yeah,
I took out a bunch for like for like
after a surgery it really stops you up.
It's.
Yeah,
shit at all.
It's just you don't get shit done.
It's just.
Oh yeah,
I think it's for like,
well,
some people use it differently.
My friends have used it.
I mean I like it when I'm in pain to
cover the pain,
but then it's like I won't be doing
anything right,
but some people love fucking killing all
the pain.
One of those and a beer and it's like I
mentioned,
it's a good night.
There's no way you can impregnate a
fucking sheep and I can't even believe
I'm looking this up.
I was in the middle of the middle of
doing this.
Just make it up.
Mike.
How can I say it?
No,
no,
no.
The third closest vagina.
Someone said it to me and he's not a
dummy.
That's what was.
It was a very successful man.
Is it just whatever we put in there
fills up a sack.
Well,
there's a thing that people need to stop
doing with shit like this.
Just go google it and then tell me,
Oh,
know I heard,
don't just tell me that a sheep can get
pregnant from a fucking dude.
Son of a bitch can put this.
Apparently this is a very math because
there's a lot of these questions ever
all over this.
While humans can impregnate apes,
they cannot impregnate.
She'd gotten pregnant apes.
Wait,
what?
Backed that up?
Fuck back that up.
Okay,
let's see.
Can the human.
Well,
that's that humanity.
You know,
we played that a couple of days ago.
Um,
the uh,
the weird chimpanzee that people
suspected was a hybrid they thought of
because he walked straight up.
It had like a hairless face.
It's really,
really unusual.
They said,
no,
it was just so fucked up champ.
Just like a bunch of wacky things going
on with its,
with its genetics.
But when you looked at it,
it was really.
You've never seen seen that humanity.
Oliver's name's Oliver Post.
Face up,
Brian,
just so you can a human and I'll look
up.
Can a human in pregnant an ape?
What's his name again?
Oliver.
The commands that humanity can,
the human and pregnant and a I say no,
I say someone was wrong.
That seems like it shouldn't be allowed
by nature.
They had to work really hard to get a
donkey and a fucking horse together.
Okay.
It looks like they tried to do it in the
19 twenties.
Who did?
Well,
here's the issue to chimpanzees.
Have the United States government did.
Oh,
that's not.
That looks like Jeff Scott.
How dare you?
That's it.
That's it right there.
The gray,
the black and white one because it was a
long time ago.
Look at his face.
It's really weird.
It's got no hair on it.
That's a hard one too because it's a
closer look at the other one.
Look at that one.
The far left.
Far left up above that.
Yeah.
Looks like that.
Looks like a monkey to right.
That looks like someone put glasses.
That's not real though,
Dude.
They took.
What's her name?
Who's the black guy?
He makes other movies.
Chimps have 48 chromosomes.
No,
makes like a one movie.
What?
Tyler Perry.
Chimps have 48 chromosomes in,
humans have 46,
so it really doesn't make sense.
Apparently that they could.
They could mate.
So if a fetus,
horses and donkeys at the same amount of
chromosomes.
What about tigers and lions?
What the chromosome.
All Tigers and lions can make that
become a lagger.
Yeah.
The laggers are barren,
right?
Exactly.
Same with mule.
Talking to horse.
Yeah.
A lot of times hybrids can't breed for
some strange reason because God says no.
God says you're going to go around me so
much.
You fucked up Mr.
Rock Bass.
I wore a diaper all day on Tuesday,
son of a bitch.
How that just shit in it.
Interesting.
No,
I pissed in it.
Um,
and that felt weird.
I pooped in my and yeah,
he had his whole joke used to do about
it.
Yeah.
This is,
depends on what they make them,
like underwear looking now.
Yeah,
they're really great.
I pooped and then went to target.
Oh,
with it in there?
Yeah.
I pooped at target.
So apparently they tried to make like a,
an ape pregnant with human sperm and
tried to do it.
And the 19 twenties,
but it didn't work.
Doing using artificial insemination.
They were trying to do it.
Fox,
what if they did you know what,
if there was some real island of Doctor
Moreau shit out there.
This is half human.
Half Champ.
Yeah,
I'd be okay with that.
Would you be okay with like taking a
trip to go watch them?
Security like machine guns,
Israeli Mossad.
How about that?
Okay.
But I'm saying he's not walking around
the grounds like,
uh,
like he's parsed part owner of the place
that he's not treated like an equal as a
think of giant plexiglass wall.
Watching from watching them that way.
Not like having to hate you and hate
you.
You made a half a monkey.
Chimps are mean as fuck.
And people,
I mean is fuck fly.
He's half dog,
half human.
That was a great movie.
Yeah,
I said it again.
They kept it alive.
That's what I already have a different
makeup.
That was a remake.
Jeff Goldblum was a bad motherfucker.
He was such a bad motherfucker that you
talk about his version of the fly,
you know,
it's like you've talked about
Frankenstein.
You go all the way back to launch
Cheney,
you know y'all Boris Karloff don't go to
the new one.
Yeah,
you don't go into a fucking hero.
You go to Boris Karloff Frankenstein,
the flathead and the bolts and shit.
That's what Frankenstein's fucking looks
like.
But not with the fly.
The fly.
Go with Jeff Gold.
Not The black and white one.
He nailed it.
He was so creepy.
He was so good.
That was when he was young.
He was a shut in his life.
Yeah,
he was an animal man.
He only wanted to do his hot girlfriend.
Whatever reason.
Gina Davis,
you remember when he would,
um,
he got fucked up.
Like he was becoming more and more of
the fly.
So we started going out to places and
fucking with people and wrestling with
dudes.
He break his arm back.
He's twitching and shit and fucking like
crazy.
And he impregnated her fly thing with
member know what happened.
I don't know.
I think,
I don't think it lived.
I mean I think she probably an abortion
or something or the end of the movie
ended.
I don't remember.
I haven't seen it in like 10 years,
but I remember it was fucking awesome
movie because I was always like,
I would always watch star trek and the
beam up part,
you know Captain Kirk owns the original
and you know when Scotty beam me up and
they will all of a sudden you.
I'm like,
wow,
they're going to do that some day,
some day they're going to be able to
make you disappear and then reappear
somewhere.
Yeah,
but remember,
every now and then there'd be some fuck
ups and someone would come out dead.
They would come out with all fucked up
from the trends or the transport them to
know,
to know coordinates in route.
You just stuck in space flying around.
Yeah.
It's amazing.
I used to do those things,
but with the next generation where they
set up and let go,
always phase has already been like it's
been fired.
They're like,
oh,
disable it.
Like they were about to kill somebody on
the surface.
Right,
right,
right.
Yeah.
The,
the idea that stores,
what are they being the end of this
table.
You know,
what's really stupid about the next
generation?
No Internet.
They all had fucking.
They all had ipads.
I bads.
Yeah.
Then ipads,
ipads.
He didn't know what it was back then.
Did he go online ever?
He did something with it and I'm like
this just kind of like the remote
control for the ship.
I thought in his quarters.
In his quarters he.
Yeah,
he was a good read on stuff.
Oh,
he could read on that before the actual
ipad.
Oh Wow.
I wonder if that's what they got the
idea.
I'm just remembering this now.
I do not remember ever seeing anybody
going online,
but I guess that would be implied if
their funding was on tap.
Yeah.
Here's Picard's IPAD.
Yeah,
but that's not.
Not.
Not to email.
What year was this?
This is fucking 90.
Maybe before I understand that.
No,
no,
not 90.
Is that a book or is that an actual
extensive tablet?
A tablet.
Have we been able to access any of those
records?
We did do this stupid goggles on and
Maddy,
you're telling me you can fly to other
planets.
You making me wear this shit?
Definitely not past like 94 95 and he's
got the smart cover on the back of it.
You can tell.
That doesn't even make sense.
Well,
I've been so wise is to see that coming.
Oh,
because it's so obvious,
but do you see it at all to get to see
it?
No.
You don't see the height it very
cleverly that because they haven't
invented it yet.
Does apple owe them money?
Because it seems like they invented that
shit.
Seems like I'm stealing a bunch of shit
from people.
Have you guys noticed,
I'm starting to notice this trend that
apple since steve jobs left starting to
fuck up a little.
What do you mean?
They definitely learned new things.
They're doing the new maps.
Thanks Steve Jobs never would have never
let that stay.
He never would have let that go on his
watch and everybody.
Now it's like keeps messing up.
Like the iphone five ain't that much
better than the forest.
I like the screen size.
A little bigger screen size and you're
given a battery.
What do you expect it to have?
You give?
You're giving a better life for their
daily five is way worse.
Yes,
it is.
Hold on,
hold on,
hold on.
This is silly.
We can't say that more than twice.
You got to stop there or people will
fucking switch to the Jaguar show.
Everyone's complaining about it.
A battery life,
but it's not.
It doesn't really do anything better
than the iphone,
Florida.
It did for us.
I mean there's only so much you can do.
There's nothing.
There's no.
Don't release this brand new thing like
it's the newest.
Okay.
What you're doing though is sticking up
for apple no matter because people are
not that much better.
I enjoy a bigger screen.
I enjoy the four g lte.
I enjoy the faster internet.
I enjoy all of the better camera.
I enjoy it.
I use the phone more than I use anything
in anything more than anything I own.
I use my phone
the most.
Is that much better than the forest.
So you have the talk and capabilities
and then what else for us both support.
You get faster Internet.
Well there's a lot of capital.
Well,
the I,
I feel sucky,
still can't use it with her cover letter
cover.
You cover this cover is the shit I got
to cover that slides out so it clips
onto my pockets.
I never lose it and I can just get a
wide hole big enough.
Why'd you buy the cheap ones that you
get for like the whole wants to.
They're all messed up.
So good.
And the overwhelming consensus says that
the iphone five battery life is way
worse than the iphone four.
It seems like they're doing major
complaints.
Brought a lot of complaints online.
Oh,
people that have actually tested it and
it's supposed to have the same
battery.
Well,
the issue,
first of all,
uh,
with verizon is the lte.
When you're on the lte.
Look,
if you use any internet on the lte,
that shit will burn battery stuff.
Burns it ltd on my 10 son of a bitch.
Um,
it's okay.
It's definitely worse.
Battery life.
I guess it's a better camera.
That's doesn't inspire me as much.
Yeah,
there's like,
there's something good to it.
It's a good camera when people ask me if
they should get it,
I'm like,
yeah,
I mean you don't need it if you really
need a phone,
but don't upgrade isn't worth that much.
So here's the,
here's the actual Gizmodo,
a battery life for the iphone five,
iphone four s and for a,
it's pretty much out of here.
You,
uh,
it's a pop up,
about eight hours.
Talk for the five,
the four ss,
eight hours talk.
The four is seven.
And then for the iphone five for on the
web is eight hours.
The four es,
six hours,
uh,
and the iphone four is six hours.
And then maybe it's because it keeps
searching for the Wifi,
it's 10 to nine.
I'm telling you right now,
know exactly what it is.
Is your apartment sucks for any kind of
service?
Yeah,
but even when I'm out I,
it goes down faster,
but my apartment.
Here's the,
here's another issue.
The same with the four in the forest.
And hold on,
there's an apple update.
Have you,
or if you've been updating your phone,
do you update your address for optics?
But do you do it?
Do you have whenever that.
Okay.
Because uh,
there was an update to update,
made a significant impact on the
batteries already lives in a place I
lived there with the four.
Yeah.
But that I wouldn't notice a difference.
You are still in the same spot
connecting
to a different network or connecting to
lte instead of connecting to the older
three.
G meaning there's three g everywhere.
There's not as much lte everywhere.
If you take your phone off lte and put
it on three g,
then you'll have the similar battery
life,
but you're living in a place where it's
constantly searching for
la though.
Even when I go out though,
it does.
Uh,
I,
uh,
I have to take what I said back is
actually the Ios.
It was killing the IPAD.
I guess it is.
Okay.
No,
it is iphone five,
iphone five and ipad mini.
They were both having a problem with Ios
six point.
Oh two.
And it was a,
it was a killing the battery life that I
never changed right away.
I always let some shit sit out there for
awhile when people start complaining and
then they fix it.
And then you can get it.
I do find it amazing though.
It just seemed more fuck in the system.
I'm finding amazing.
They're constantly coming up with new
shit.
I mean,
I think it's a,
it's incredible.
And I think the iphone five,
even though it's not,
it's not perfect.
I think we're being a bunch of whiny
cons.
It's still a fucking amazing phone.
It's amazing.
I mean five years ago,
I mean,
this thing I do,
I conduct so much business from this.
I tweet,
you know,
I,
I call my management.
For us it's better,
it's faster,
it gets,
it gets like image.
Like you know what?
I really see it when people send me
images or if they said because people
will send me like a little video strip
prove I can actually improve them on my
igert.
Like go like when we're doing log into
that anymore.
We were doing some stuff with my standup
special.
They would send me some clips and I
could just put on my earphones press
that I could download three,
four megabytes on an email attachment
like that with lte and watch it.
It's way faster than just regular three
g,
it's just way faster.
Something that would take like four
times as long and I'm not even exactly
and it's a great hot spot.
Like when I have my,
like my,
my ipad mini,
like I can just sit there and turn on my
hot hotspot.
Now I have four g lte,
which is like Dsl or faster Internet on
my ipad.
So it's great for hotspotting to you.
It's the network bands is a huge deal
when it comes to getting online or when
it comes to looking at movies or even
looking at pictures.
You can't fuck with those.
Those galaxies,
those android phones,
those giant galaxies.
Their screens are fucking huge.
Huh?
They have the Samsung Galaxy s three and
the galaxy note and the galaxy.
This is the way to go the seven inch
ipad because if you're going to look at
anything,
why don't you do it on this one of the
bigger fits in your pocket,
unless you get a painter's pants back.
Maybe paid painter's pants.
Yeah.
Can I go get you a car?
I used to wear cargo pants when I did.
Fear factor when you wore cargo pants.
I remember those days when you wore
those pants.
Oh,
what the hell,
man?
Uh,
so you count on the old iphone four is
you can't go on the lte.
Huh?
The four s's go four G,
which is slowly with atnt.
Yeah.
With 18 t only with verizon four g lte.
He is faster than that.
Do you?
Um,
do they the
phone version of the IPAD mini yet?
Or?
It works.
It gets on.
So when my phone says lte and when it
says four G,
which one's moving faster?
Lte.
Shit.
That's what doesn't get that money is
potts.
Is that the deal?
Well,
not where you live in,
around Hollywood.
It's right here.
Yeah.
Why would it get it in Hollywood where
there's a billion people?
Why?
Why have good service there?
It doesn't make any sense.
It's like Anthony Bourdain is convinced
that China's going to overtake the earth
because the,
the,
their work ethic and the way they get
shit done and how quickly they get shit
done.
It's like really ever seen anything like
it.
He goes,
you could be out in the middle of a
fucking massive forest.
No people anywhere in sight.
Five bars.
It's like,
it's crazy.
You get cell phone signals everywhere
and they put up a city and like a week
trying to throw up a city and they're
just going crazy over everything.
Industrious worker ants.
What do they think?
It's like a the world of warcraft where
you just build up your area and don't
attack,
and then when you do attack it,
like what other people are so
overwhelmed by?
Well,
if he just came over here on boats would
be fucked.
If China wanted to destroy the United
States,
I'll let us do is get every Chinese
person from China come over to America
and just start walking.
What are you going to do is walk across
the entire continent.
We're going to do it.
You gonna arrest everybody.
You don't have the resources.
They would overwhelm us just by sheer
numbers.
How soon before the Chinese Americans
would say,
fuck it,
let's just torn up.
I can't tell.
They would learn.
Chinese gets some of those folks.
I wouldn't blame them with those Rosetta
stones.
Have you ever tried to use that?
You ever tried to learn a language?
Um,
if I'm downloading this stuff and
they've never listened to it many times
it's very hard.
It's very hard actually.
Speak Hebrew.
I mean,
I can understand a little bit,
but I can't.
You can't be.
You used to be fluent.
Right?
I can get by basically if you think if
you went back to Israel,
you would like,
notice how I said that.
Israel.
I didn't say Israel as Israel.
If you went back there with you,
how long would it take,
do you think?
Before you could be fluent again?
I have to leave like Jerusalem.
Oh really?
Why is that?
Because how many English speakers are in
Jerusalem?
Everybody.
Real.
Oh yeah.
And they're almost all center of town
and stuff.
Every business owner knows English.
You cannot get by without it.
We really know.
It's just,
it's silly to try not to.
Is the tourist trade over there big?
What is a fucking tourists director for
his big potter really hurts him for
that.
For him to spend some money.
People really took a plummet this most
recent.
The Intifada?
Yeah.
What does,
what does that mean?
Intifada or uprising?
The uprising.
The Palestinian.
Twelve years now.
Okay.
That and that,
that constant threat of violence.
I think it's probably recovered from
there since the beginnings of it in the
last few years,
been more peaceful.
If they could just keep a little fake
violence going on and keep people out,
it's probably a good move in terms of
like those people that would go there,
like the Christian missionary types that
settles in the settlements when they're
lucky to keep building new settlements.
Those are the Americans coming over.
Really the Americans that they're like,
yeah,
we want to help reclaim the land of
Israel.
So all those fucking Zionists.
Whoa.
I go back.
So the Americans come over and they want
to help reclaim Israel.
So they're settling.
Where in the,
um,
argued lands and whose side are they on
Israel's.
So they're coming over,
they landed and they want to live in
Israel.
And guess what?
This is part of Israel.
And the way we can show that by building
a house right here.
Oh my God,
you're next to someone else's house and
you have a watchtower and a garden.
So are they American Jews?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Oh,
so you like s sympathizers,
but you guys put up with is really
wrong.
I'm going to go over there and support
there.
There would be people that would do it
sort of like,
you know,
like that.
I'm American talent man character.
The other one guy walk out.
John Walker.
Lynn's I want to say those who went over
there and I've been obsessed with that
show.
Homeland a really seen that show.
No,
I just downloaded the first season.
It's fucking good and the sector have
been fucking better and I was not even
remotely into seeing it until I did,
but a lot of it revolves around him
being a prisoner because you hear Claire
Danes what?
Forget it.
A bitch can act or ask her.
Yeah,
she's good though.
She can act her ass off.
I loved her.
My so called life,
I never saw that because I'm a man.
Well,
I was a little boy who sided with her
and jared leto and how hard.
It wasn't high school.
Did you really side with them?
Oh yeah.
It definitely hurt.
She was awkward.
It wasn't one of the popular kids just
like me,
man.
Yeah.
Just like she knows what I'm going
through.
I hear you bro.
I fucking Lido Guy.
What about him?
He was okay because he let he let Claire
Danes be cool with them.
Wow.
Nineteen 68,000.
One a space odyssey.
Love to watch that.
It's based on.
I see his version of the future is
really interesting.
Well,
they already watched that.
They had.
I just saw it again recently.
I've only did my taxes last year.
God Damn.
Two thousand one and didn't they have a
2010 the year we make contact or
something like that was another one that
was not cool.
Brooke.
I don't think it wasn't Kubek.
No,
I think they just said,
look,
let's keep it out.
Keep it going.
Who the fuck?
Let them do that.
Hollywood like they do everything.
Fucking Twat.
Bags.
Speaking of Hollywood like they do
everything.
Steven Spielberg pushed back,
uh,
our friend,
um,
the robot apocalypse guy,
pushback annual h Wilson.
Yay.
Fucking police were supposed to do that
movie.
There were supposed to do the robot
apocalypse movie and apparently pulled
out of it.
Spielberg did.
Yeah.
You know why?
Because he doesn't want allowed
apocalypse and his movies,
his version of the world is everything
always turns out a.
okay.
Well,
I don't know if it's that.
I mean,
I think it's probably that he's tired.
The guy just got done doing lincoln.
It was a huge movie that took forever
to.
She wasn't going to do an apocalypse.
Well,
you know,
he's a science.
So science fiction,
fucking movie dude.
Robot apocalypse.
How would they get to do that and still
keep that worldview of like,
well,
I'll be okay because in the end,
the good guys probably when.
Oh,
maybe that'd be nice.
So we walk out of there feeling good
about yourself.
That's good.
So they always hated about his movies.
Well,
it's really interesting that you say
that because,
uh,
some of the choices that he made his
early is early movies you said he would
never make now.
Like,
yeah,
like in close encounters of the third
time,
you remember when Richard Dreyfus leaves
his family to go with the aliens?
He said he would never do that.
Now he would say family's more
important.
He's to stay with his family.
Yeah.
That's something a single guy would
think,
you know,
a single guy with thank fuck these wife
and kid.
Look,
I love you baby.
But you know,
you're gonna have to take care of that
kid.
I'm going off with the aliens.
Yeah,
that wouldn't.
You would be the shittiest fucking
parent to ever live at.
It's nice enough that you saw the
aliens.
Okay.
You saw him.
You know they exist.
Thank you for showing yourself to me.
But I'm going to go back to work.
I got I gonna.
What am I going to do that with you?
Why can't my kid.
I'm not.
I'm not going to fucking go fly with you
to another planet.
That's why.
Would that be good?
You wouldn't even be able to talk to
them.
It would be a fucking mess.
I mean,
thinking about the experiences that he
had with them in the movie,
it wasn't like they were a bundle of
joy.
He's so excited to go with them.
Why?
Because they have better ipads.
Different.
What is it?
18.
Gee,
we got to go.
You know,
what is it?
What?
Why would they want?
Why the fuck would you want to go and
party with aliens?
They're little knock into them.
They fall down immediately.
Probably heads crack open because
they're these giant heads coming out
used to violence at all.
They're probably super soft.
You know,
just you could accidentally break them.
I bet.
All
right.
Now all it Spielberg movies were like
happy endings.
You only wants Schindler's list,
but he did it.
He did.
It was a fucking holocaust movie and he
still talks about overcoming and meeting
all these survivors.
Yeah.
He managed to do that no matter what,
but no one left the schindler's list.
That was the great happy.
You think that saving private Ryan was
cute at the end.
It was kind of sweet at the end with a
guy who's got his family there with
them.
It's all supporting the fact that he's
spent his life.
Does he fucking goes over stuff and just
rewrite it so that he can.
I don't remember the twelfth one.
What color?
Purple twilight.
He directed this season,
but in the end he always makes
everything okay.
Even fucking the robot movie where he's
still got to go see his mom one last
time.
We'll that a robot movie like I robot or
something.
A robot.
You know what?
He's awesome making known.
The kid replaced.
Why would you make another dressing
part?
Has the other ones were awesome because
the other ones don't look.
Look at the old ones.
The old ones on the TV doesn't look so
great.
Well,
that's not true.
I just saw Jurassic Park the other day.
I thought it was fucking great.
Really?
The dentist was looked fake to you.
I remember the first time I saw them,
I was on the edge of my seat going,
this is amazing.
I saw on TV and it was like,
I didn't think they look fake at all.
You thought they looked fake.
He's too busy making real steel to who
is speaking?
We'll steal one.
Executive producer.
How dairy?
It looked good in the previous real
steel look.
Good.
I like robots at fight.
When you taught me he didn't do I am
legend.
No,
no,
no.
Who was that don't know.
Is that the guy?
Didn't momento no,
he did ai though.
That's what it was.
That was a good one.
Yeah,
that was a good one.
I mean he's,
he's a brilliant director,
but it's kind of interesting.
These guys that uh,
they get older and they just get kind of
softer.
Like George Lucas or conservative.
It's not just more conservative,
but they lose their vitality.
There's,
there's no spark inside of their work
anymore.
It's so very strange thing that happens
with some folks.
It doesn't happen to everybody.
Like with George Carlin,
it never happened.
That guy was fucking grind and get out
to the day he died.
Some guys,
it doesn't happen.
It's some guys they get better in time.
Clint Terentino's,
he's not slowing down.
That guy is fucking awesome.
That django movie was a real fucking
movie and with real crazy ass dudes
eaten by dogs.
Crazy ass fucking movie.
He's not slowing down at all,
but something happens to.
Some of them were they just becomes
pausing Lucas.
Here's the worst worst.
You'd go back and we'll watch star wars
one at the time in the error when I saw
that was a fucking masterpiece.
She's peckish now.
It's so cheesy.
Dish and you're like,
what?
How is that?
Even if I was six,
I don't think this should be Jonesville
bad or that the latest one.
Oh,
Dr.
Rayzman.
What about the earlier ones?
The other ones of those early ones are
great and when he was getting pussy and
shit,
remember when that girl and kissing each
other and now he's like an old man.
It's fucking back hurts.
Can't whip the whip.
That good
students were coming onto them.
Snakes.
It's blinking and the the on the islands
of Britain.
I love you.
Number.
Short round little Asian kid.
Yeah.
He went from being like the anymore stud
professor guy to be in someone's dad.
You know that.
That's what happened.
He lost it all.
Somewhere along the line he was like,
someone's who's,
you know,
like Harrison Ford's character was like,
now he's like someone's Dad.
It's like,
Oh,
you rascally the kids.
I'm just here to get that crystal scroll
like you back to the early one.
We had a runaway from fucking giant
boulders that were set his traps and
he's trying to get these artifacts and
the first one was great and making a new
one.
One five,
five.
I'm glad.
At least they got star wars away from
Lucas.
Yeah,
they gave it to Disney.
What are they going to do with it?
They're going to have.
Maybe rapunzel is going to be in star
wars.
That's going to have.
Well,
at least the creature could be theater
like the would be adorable.
Don't you have this idea that like,
well they can't fuck it up,
this,
this thing.
They can't mess it up completely,
but then you realize like,
no,
just property to somebody.
They can do whatever they want to.
They could ever puzzle in there.
Yeah.
Why not?
They could do whatever the fuck they
wanted and be fine.
There's nothing we could do about it.
I'm worried about Pixar lost in star
wars with flying to the galaxy and
they're just going to Indiana Jones
popping out of their fucking helmets.
You Imagine?
Yoda gets together with Mickey and
teaches.
Mickey had a fight and then it's like
the first one.
When was the,
uh,
the sword was the sorcerer in his
apprentice?
Sorcerer's apprentice.
Was that as,
um,
the Mickey Mouse one?
Oh yeah.
Sorcerer's apprentice,
I think.
Yeah.
That was that what it's called?
Fantasia.
Fantasia musical.
Yeah.
It was fucking amazing little piece of
work.
But I mean,
it's essentially,
you know,
about a magician's apprentice who fucks
up and everything goes terribly wrong.
Right?
Isn't that what it does really?
It's just like,
look at what we can do now.
Look at where we can go.
How could that be any different?
If he was hanging out with Yoda,
if he was hanging out with Yoda and it'd
be like very simple,
you know,
like he would.
Yoda would tell him,
you know,
to force,
you must,
and then he would go off and fuck up and
turn everything into a river.
It's the same.
Add Yoga or add yoga.
Yoga a Yogi man.
Dude.
Yoga is like some ancient Hindu
wrestling.
A stretches are.
Yeah.
I've heard of that.
You're holding poses.
I'm going to get rolfed tomorrow.
What does that have a bulging disc in my
back.
I have a back issue or my,
my.
I've had a back injury that have
reoccurred so many times that the disc
is starting to uh,
get inflamed and they're like slightly
protrudes.
Failing.
Yeah.
Not,
not too bad.
It's not like I don't need surgery or
anything like that,
but one of the things they do to relax
attention to areas of sin called Raul
thing,
which is supposed to be like a lot like
getting raped by pliers.
Sounds off or what do they do?
Rip Your fucking skin apart.
It tear your muscle away from your bone.
Smash it and rip it apart.
Yeah.
I suppose nothing like painful it
rebuild fl.
Rolfing.
Ruffling what's ruffling.
Rolling on the floor laughing.
Oh,
do well if you guys heard of that
letter,
the less have you heard of us or being
big.
What does that,
that sport where they get in a giant
ball and they roll with it.
Something.
Just dive in that right?
It's just two Russian guys off a fucking
cliff.
Wow,
dude.
There's a video of it by going off the
cliff.
Si Senor Brian.
I think it's called absorbing a giant
ball.
Hold on.
Guy Dies absorbing.
Let me say this,
but Wayne Coyne does,
and the flaming lips concepts.
He walked into the crowd.
As long as he doesn't do that.
Yeah,
it's scary.
It's so scary,
but it up.
Don't just share it yourself.
Yeah.
The Internet here sucks.
The fat one,
but only mobile mode only for another
month.
Speaking of Internet,
my special passive aggressive.
We have available for presale fast.
She'll dot com.
It'll be available tomorrow on for
Presale Presale,
and when does it sale?
I think February fifth.
Oh,
okay.
So they have to just hold their dicks
for two weeks.
That's 20 percent off.
We look at this fear.
Worst Marketer ever 20th.
This was supposed to be a thrilling ride
down,
a ski slope,
inflatable ball ended in tragedy for the
to Russia and men inside.
One of them died.
The other was badly injured when the
absorb,
as the transparent globe is called,
veered off course and went over a cliff
in the Caucasus mountains.
This video shows they're terrifying.
Ride.
At one point the man recording the
footage can be heard,
telling people the ball won't roll away
and that everything's gonna.
Be Okay,
but eventually the ball did roll to a
Rocky Ledge and bounced over at going
down the side of the mountain,
but it's really fast absorbing.
Started in the 19 nineties in New
Zealand at is now done around the world.
This accident has prompted the head of
Russia's emergency rescue services to
demand that safety rules for winter
sports being forced into the big move.
That's a big move.
And forest winter safety rules.
We have rules for fun in the last shy.
You can just get in bowling.
Golf cleats to mix us.
Bad Russians don't really smile.
They did say do fade or smiles.
There's a Russian.
I wouldn't have a dick and I'm okay.
You're going to have to deal with that
one.
Russian use,
Bungee cord.
Heisman Bungee Bun,
g,
G,
or a J.
e
cord off roof.
Here's the.
Oh,
you don't need to see a man.
It's a sadness.
The other one's trapped with the other
one.
Dead like he fell.
You're bouncing like that.
You're clashing heads.
He yells.
Don't say those people are going to be
fine.
Don't worry.
Look at the city,
and that's when they realized that I'm
sure has a stroke.
It's going down that cliff.
That's it.
Black.
Oh my God.
Look at it.
Hit those rocks.
Boom,
boom,
boom.
Oh my God.
Your Dad.
Shit.
One of the other had to be alive with a
friend next to him.
Still rolling down a hill and still
probably having a little bit funky
unconscious to Brian.
Look up because the last part was like,
oh yeah,
yeah.
We can look up Russian
kids with a death wish.
Bungee Russian kids with a death wish.
Bungee WII U N G E B U N G U P and
again,
get your Dick Check,
son.
His Shit's broken.
You can't hold your mud.
Get me one of those.
A coconut waters.
Oh,
coconut waters.
Jealousy to.
Oh,
well,
they're our favorite.
Bryan.
In fact,
they're so good.
They make other coconut water.
Tastes like toilet water.
I agree with that.
I can't even buy that other shit that
you get in a fucking carton.
That nonsense.
Whatever it is.
I do not like it with the Puck,
but that's my own personal.
Then I don't mind the pub.
The pub makes me feel like it's real.
Yeah,
I'm alive.
You know what I drank as a juice that I
just found out was a Jew as a juice
juice as a drink.
I drank the uh,
you know,
behind go behind the bar.
And you had the tap for orange juice.
I've been drinking that by the glass
pool thinking it was real juice.
No,
it turns out it's just some chemicals
and water.
Yeah.
He needs to.
Dude.
Tap your kid in a decade.
You're the kid that went to Mcdonald's
at that orange drink.
Orange juice.
No,
go for me guys.
I'm going healthy.
Just give me some of that other stuff.
Don't you know anything about
fermentation?
I didn't know.
Just finding this out.
This is the kids.
These are the Russian kids.
They.
They made a fake.
They made their own bungee jump.
Bungee cord tied into this bitch.
Watch this.
Put the headphones on.
Duty.
You got to hear that.
I'm not telling you.
Look it up.
Crazy.
These kids are.
They're holding onto this rope.
They tied it to a chimney slider out
through the bottoms of smashing in the
building.
They haven't controlled this.
Haven't thought this through right now.
How did they get her back up?
Wow.
I barely do.
They kind of let her down.
She's hanging.
They're hanging onto her,
so they sought slowly let her down.
They're holding it.
Yes.
Jude,
Russians are crazy.
Weight related.
Video related video.
Andrew dice clay.
What is up with this backflip fair?
I watched a dices,
a showtime special.
It was very funny.
It was very funny what's going on here,
but backflip fail.
But she's in a phone.
No backflip fail.
Let's see what goes on here.
A bridge?
Yeah,
right when she's about to do it.
A dude behind her.
Sister,
she starts her,
period.
You grow.
Your sister's hotter than you.
Oh Wow.
Look how beautiful that is.
Man.
That looks like Canada and the side.
That looks fantastic.
Oh No.
This girl's not going to do what I think
she's going to do.
Is this like off a cliff or some shit
off of bridge?
Oh No,
don't,
don't do this.
Oh my God.
Oh,
don't do this.
you fucking assholes.
Put that video up.
But she was pregnant and
she has.
She missed thing.
You know?
That's basically the bit that I do on
stage when I talk about Mr Han's,
like when someone's sent me that first
video,
this is exactly the feeling you get.
Like when?
When Brian,
remember when I'm coming to your place
and you showed me two girls,
one cup the first time it hits you in
the bone,
you can't.
You like,
what's next?
The fuck is gonna happen here and how
many times you've seen someone do
something like that and then just die.
I mean a bunch.
I've seen a bunch of people just to get
disintegrated in car accidents and flip
over Atlanta their fucking head in a
puddle of blood and raw.
I saw videos of people run over by
trucks.
I've seen everything I've seen way more
than the average person by the age of,
you know,
whatever.
100 would have seen if they lived 20
years ago.
Oh yeah.
Way More online with that.
And you've seen countless more get those
experiences.
Yeah.
Same people being beheaded them.
Oh,
I like not.
I don't like,
but they don't just chop their heads
off.
They cut them slowly off so they're
screaming and making a lot of grass.
There.
Head is getting cut off.
Well that was the most fucked up thing
about when they.
When they first caught that American
perlman or something.
Yeah.
Daniel Perlman maybe.
When they first did that to him and then
they showed them actually doing it.
No Way.
Oh my God,
look at this kid.
Oh my Lord.
Look at what he's doing now.
He's doing pushups.
He's doing chin ups,
like in space and he's doing it.
It's a thick bar.
He's hanging onto to,
oh my God,
this kid is scary and he's.
He's doing awesome self.
I'll just kid bad enough.
Fall.
Please don't tell me what.
Where is his mother?
Yeah,
this kid is crazy.
How's he up there?
He's up there.
What's the.
What's the video game?
You got to stab people swinging castles,
touching himself and landing on the bar
again and just having confidence that he
can support himself with his monkey
hands.
Andrew dice clay comes up again.
No,
the
know that you're into is special.
He yelled at a woman for laughing in the
wrong place.
She was laughing though.
What the fuck you doing?
You're ruining my daughter in the wrong
spot.
It's so ridiculous.
It's like his character to me,
especially because I know him know his
character.
Me because like if you didn't know him,
you think he's making movies like a
really a mean guy,
but he's not a mean guy at all.
He's,
he's a nice guy.
He's just.
He's just,
he's crazy.
He's crazy.
But he's not like.
He likes to fuck her.
People likes to fuck with the practical
joker,
but his comedy,
because I know him,
it's like I dunno,
it's like twice as funny.
Ridiculous on purpose.
Like we went to see him in Vegas and he
was so pickled that me and Norton and
Bobby Kelly came backstage and you just
come back to the states and Anthony
Kumina and later we were so happy to see
him and he was so happy that people came
to see him and he was like,
I don't do no,
no research.
I don't know what the fuck I'm talking
about it.
They're just making it up.
He was in the back of the kitchen,
is the comedy store talking and he got
off stage and he goes,
I said that I would slap your walnut bag
with my.
I forget what it was.
So stupid,
but they keep paying me so I'll keep
doing it.
Yeah,
he's a that,
that style of comedy.
It's just like,
to me it's no different than like,
like how many people like ACDC.
Okay.
I love ACDC.
They've got some great songs,
but some people don't like it.
Yeah,
but not only that,
but think about what they're saying.
I'm on the highway to hell.
Are you really,
really silly bitch.
It's ridiculous.
It's ridiculous shit,
but you kind of go along with them
because it's ACDC and they're saying
it's rock and it's bad ass song.
When when dice is like,
here's the.
You suck in my area.
If anybody else did that,
you would build lamer.
Yeah.
He'd be like,
Oh my God,
you're so lame.
And like,
what?
How old are you are?
Come on.
If some guy went up on one of the shows
that we have with the ice house,
some guy that you know,
Brian's cousin knows this guy was going
to be 10 minutes or he's really funny.
He goes,
goes on stage.
He's like,
here's to you suck in my.
If you know that didn't exist.
If dyson never done that,
we'd be like,
who is this lame fuck?
Here's to use sucking my dick.
Get that guy out of here.
Yeah,
but when dies does it.
It's somehow hilarious.
Hilarious.
I had that with a lot of my friends,
whether they do something that I find
funny,
other people find just so rude or it's
funny when you see a guy like Mike
holtzman character,
you immediately start laughing at when
you see and then they'll go on stage and
you'll see people not get it or not.
Not Understand that it's an act and get
like super offended.
Like we were in the front of the comedy
store and this lady came out and she
just goes,
I just want you to know that you were
really,
really funny and we really enjoyed
ourselves,
but someone needs to take the microphone
away from that man.
Okay.
Because he's not well and I don't think
indulging him.
You know what he's saying is funny and
you want to be like,
well,
I don't even have to look at it.
Is Shut your fucking mouth.
Shut your mouth.
Stupid face.
What are the crowd?
Half clear out now it's harder and he
attacked jail for being stupid.
Wasn't even that.
He was doing something about Mexicans,
long blowers.
I put a booger in somebody's drink this
week.
She left.
I tried to cut her off and like this
girl is already more.
James says right off the bat,
she's already too drunk and then she
starts to orient the audience.
See you put put a bug.
Yeah,
absolutely.
She went to the bathroom.
That place closed down to the health
violations.
People eat your boogers.
Her friends saw you were a grown man.
You in your thirties.
You haven't.
People eat your boogers.
Drink,
drink.
My blogger friends saw it was.
She's speaking to a point.
I was like,
I'm giving you the chance to do it
before me.
Do you think she just swallowed it or do
you think she felt it and was aware?
No,
I think just swallowed it.
Probably didn't know.
Probably don't know if you really fucked
up because people can understand once
you're drunk.
You don't need to keep drinking.
You be in a good place already.
You do if you have demons,
Ari?
Yeah,
I guess so.
That's the thing.
So maintain.
You're assuming that people drink to
have a good time.
A lot of people don't drink to have a
good time.
They drink to get fucked up because they
want to escape reality.
Yeah,
but that's also a good time for it.
I mean,
I guess it's escape reality,
but it's also like whatever I drank to
get drunk wasn't escaping anything.
He'd be.
He'd been to logical since.
When have you liked the average person?
When you see it running,
like in college and stuff,
you're just like,
you're allowed to drink so you do it
because it's new.
Not every college kid is running away
from their demons.
Most of them aren't.
They're just getting fucked up.
Yeah.
Most of them,
they're learning how to get fucked up,
but a lot of people are running from the
demons.
Yeah,
I guess so.
They just try to get blasted.
That's amazing.
Really drinking alone at a bar feels
more like that to me.
Does he drink alone at a bar?
I don't know.
I'm picturing that,
you know,
like grizzled,
pure Koski type character as opposed to
just like,
that's perfect pressure pressure.
So maybe it will
and get drunk during the day.
You have a problem unless you're in a
good place like Cancun on the beach.
If you wake up and have lunch and I'm
going to have a beer at lunch,
why are you drinking?
Right.
There's no reason.
Yeah,
well no.
Maybe a beer with a sandwich or
something like that,
but what if you want to get like a shot?
That's when you start.
Yeah.
My Dad said he came back from work one
day and he had some some booze at launch
on a lunch meeting and his boss kind of
smelled it on his breath and he said he
saw the look and then he was like,
that's it.
No more drinking the day time.
Yeah.
People make too many assumptions about
you.
Yeah.
You don't want that.
You don't want them to put you in that
sort of category.
Yeah.
It's a funny thing when you really think
about how responsible people actually
are with alcohol.
If you think about how available it is,
if you're over 21,
did they ever stop you from drinking?
No.
You could always drink.
Oh,
unless you've done some shit,
but if you do some shit like Lindsay
Lohan,
how to wear like an ankle bracelet that
tells you when you're drunk.
How long can they keep that on you?
They can't make that permanent.
Right?
Can they make a rule?
Were like,
look,
we'll let you roam around the street
fuck head,
but you got to wear an ankle bracelet
that tells us if you're drinking soon
enough though,
to the CSA,
you want to fly,
wear an ankle stuff for the next month.
You'll do that soon.
That's not a bad idea for people who are
fucking crazy.
You know,
if you want to control someone who just
can't handle their alcohol and you
realize you get to a certain point in
time like,
listen dude,
you've been arrested for drunk driving
twice.
You've been in five different assaults.
You've been so we're going to do stupid.
We're going to keep you from drinking.
You haven't stopped drinking,
so this is the way you can be a free
man.
You wander around,
you have a great time for tenants'
rights rule.
We find that you drink and you're
obviously not in control of your
faculties.
When you're drinking it forever,
you stupid.
Yeah.
Put a price on them for like,
yeah,
but then who's to decide whether or not
you should wear that bracelet and
freedom ain't free and that's when
fucking Alex Jones
14th is trying to put a bracelet on you
to tell you when you can have some Jack
Daniels.
How do you feel about this gun control
thing?
Um,
I feel like it's a very complex issue
and it's first of all,
the idea that anybody should be able to
have fucking military grade weapons I
think is ridiculous.
But it comes from it.
Go ahead.
And also,
I think the real issue is not the.
I mean this is a fucking cliche,
but it's not the gun.
The real issue is what would happen to a
person to make them grow up to be
someone who could be a school shooter
ready?
Oh yeah.
That's a mental health issue.
She explored 100 percent.
And by the way,
can I just say this,
Obama,
for the obamacare parts of Obamacare,
they're already put into place,
which is you have to cover mental health
if you're going to cover for everybody,
for all your means that I don't get
mental health coverage because it's not
cost effective because they can't afford
doing that.
So they cannot.
They can't let it.
They can't give it to anybody.
I find it amazing how so many people are
so adamant against people or taxpayers
paying for healthcare,
but don't express nearly the same amount
of concern about your money being used
for war.
It's really kind of shocking because the
war money,
it's like where is it even going?
It's going into another part of the
world where you're most likely never
going to visit unless you're in the
military and it's all going to tanks and
it's craziness you've seen on TV and
people are just shelling out their money
in taxes and no one cares.
But the moment someone says,
Hey,
you know,
maybe we should make it so that people
can get some help.
Hey,
pull yourself up by your own bootstraps.
Can fucking week pussy,
you know,
there's something about,
we don't need health care,
you know,
what we need is to get back to what made
America great.
And as corporations having all the
control,
you know,
they think that separations are going to
become corrupt.
They're run by people and people are
corruptible.
They will always fuck up.
You give somebody power,
there's a chance they will fuck up.
It's not even just a fucking up.
There's a weird diffusion of
responsibility thing that happens when
you are many steps removed from the
actual deed and you're involved with
many other people.
They say it's easier to rape.
A woman in a crowd was woman in front of
one.
I can see that.
It becomes like,
well,
I'm not responsible for this.
They would tell you this,
this study,
fuck,
it wasn't Pfizer,
but it was some drug company about polio
vaccines.
They were giving me these polio vaccines
to these African kids.
And um,
but they were lying to them.
It wasn't a polio vaccine was just
another drug that we're testing.
And the polio vaccine in 90 percent of
them.
And 10 percent on the game of the,
um,
the,
uh,
whatever it's called,
the sugar pill,
because that's a control group.
So the 90 percent of them took the new
drug that we're testing all died.
Well under 10 percent of them got polio.
Jesus,
because they weren't even getting the
vaccines.
They were thought they were being
tested.
Ouch.
Yeah.
And that's just what some corporation
does that make more money.
That's just a normal sort of situation.
It's over there.
Don't worry about it.
Exxon has that with a rape,
the land,
wherever they go and just buy out their
government and say new rules.
Well,
I was trying to get John Perkins on and
I'll try again.
Um,
now that we have matt stags on the case,
are you hearing us Matt?
Go get the economic hitman guy because
he's a,
he's a fascinating guy.
He used to do that for the government.
He will go and the,
Oh there's Alex Jones.
You will not take our guns.
Jon Stewart reacting to Alan.
So taking away all the guns.
But now I get it.
Now I see what's happening.
So this is what it is.
They're paranoid.
Fear of a possible dystopic future
prevents us from addressing our actual
dystopic present.
We can't even begin to
too many uses of the words that stupid.
Stop it.
I understand.
You live in New York and you're Jewish.
They got sick.
He is huge.
Cold.
During this thing,
like did he come in any way?
Just because it was such a crazy story.
Talking about Alex Jones is off the
rails.
Man.
I get it though.
With the military grade weapons.
The point was never to be able to hunt.
We're at the point was able to drive off
the government and you're not going to
do it with a fucking six pistol.
Will.
The idea is to protect yourself against
threats to this nation,
both domestic and abroad.
That's the idea is that,
you know,
they had to worry about being overtaken
from within.
That's why you have the right to bear
arms and you know,
everybody says,
well,
those book when people had muskets and
this and that,
the government's corrupt now that it was
then.
But by the way,
the government had muskets as well back
then and now the government doesn't have
any and they didn't have the ability to
arrest you for no reason.
You know,
I'm not saying that you should go and
fucking overtake the government with
forest because I definitely don't
believe that.
But what do you think is the way to get
rid of people?
I think that the issue is not people
being armed.
The issue is crazy.
People.
The issue is disenfranchised people.
The issue is people that have legitimate
mental problems.
The issue is diagnosing them.
The issue is trying to figure out how
the fuck a person becomes that
sociopathic fucking psychopathic killer.
How does that.
That's.
That's our real problem.
Because when you look at the actual
numbers of human beings and you look at
the actual numbers of human beings with
guns and then you look at the actual
numbers of crimes,
like people like to say,
oh,
England has no guns,
so they have no gun crimes.
That is absolutely true.
They have like 30 or something shootings
every year.
It's like nothing compared to the United
States.
But if you look at the overall number of
armed people in Britain to the overall
number of armed people in America,
it's really kind of shocking that we
have as few murders by guns that we do
and rose to the murders by guns,
like a good 70 percent of the assault
rifle type killings or gang related or
really high percentage of them have to
do with gang violence.
We're going to tell you that's it.
That's why up mean largely an economic
issue,
largely a poverty issue.
And then a drug dealing issue.
A couple of different aspects of our
society that are obviously sick,
you know,
the,
the illegal access to drugs,
meaning that anybody sells drugs,
that's criminal.
That's one,
that's one aspect that leads to
organized crime,
you know.
And then the other aspect of course is
poverty.
People growing up,
disenfranchise needing someone somewhere
to belong to.
They become a part of gangs and gangs
are fucking huge and they're killing
each other.
I mean it's,
it's,
it's a super common thing that they use
those types of weapons in,
in gang.
I wonder like drive bys and stuff.
Yeah.
But I look,
I don't think everybody should have
access to those guns.
That's where I parked from the average
person.
I think if you have a reason to have
those guns,
that's one thing.
But if you're.
I mean,
if you were looking for something to
protect yourself,
um,
do you really need machine guns?
I mean,
can you get by with a shotgun?
Can you get by with a rifle?
I mean,
the idea is that if somebody wanted to
go and kill a bunch of people,
it would be far harder if you had
something like a single loading rifle or
shotgun.
But then the argument of course from the
NRA people would be,
well,
if you really want to apply the language
and the declaration of independence,
the Second Amendment being that you have
the right to bear arms,
the idea means that you have the right
to protect yourself against whoever it
may be who easily could be overpowering
you.
They can have more fire power than you.
So if you have what they have and you
have a 50 caliber machine gun,
you have what they have,
they,
you're,
you're on an equal playing field and
they can't come and take your land.
The problem is they won't let you like
doesn't happen at Waco.
When they started taking a bunch of
weapons,
well they also fucking their kids.
But who knows if that's true because
that's the first thing I was there and
blew them all up.
If you want to go and get somebody to
come and become a threat to the powerful
person in government,
they're just going to wipe you out.
And that's why people in Libya and need
actual machine guns to make change.
They can't do it through voting and
we're starting to not be able to do it
through voting either.
You're right.
And I honestly,
the more I look at it,
the situation we have here with our
government not representing us,
I only really see one way around it.
Oh,
he's talking crazy talk.
This is the end of this podcast and if
you want to continue,
this conversation will be on there.
Skeptic tank available on itunes and the
part of me will be paid by Jason Team.
Um,
yeah.
Well,
I mean,
I don't know how the government has
bigger businesses.
They are,
would exceed any control if they don't
have to and they no longer have to.
Well the problem is it's eating itself.
See the access to information that the
government has now and the ability to
wire tap phones,
the ability to spy on people's lives is
now eating itself because the fucking
FBI investigated CIA,
another director of the CIA is no longer
there because they went digging into his
privacy.
That's what happened.
I mean they're,
they're spying on each other.
It's fucking spy versus spy.
Our tax dollars being spent to expose a
guy getting some pussy.
Do you think if you,
if you could go back and remove every
great leader,
every man of power.
If you're military combat,
especially military.
I mean you're talking about a in David
betray us that had been in Baltimore for
a long time.
He had seen a lot of death and you're
going to deny him some extra pussy.
Do you think that his sensual?
Yeah.
And a hot chick who's young,
that's what he got.
The whole thing was in trouble for.
Yeah,
that's what he got in trouble for.
But it also had to do somehow or another
relating it to Bengazi,
the attack on Libya where they were
woefully unprotected.
Their information failed them.
And they attack those people in the.
Killed The American,
uh,
American ambassador.
Yeah.
So there's that as well that they
believe is somehow or another connected
to it.
And they made up that story that it was
all about some movie.
Yes.
That was through.
It was really amazing.
She made up a story,
eat up a story.
These fucks.
They made up a story about this all
being inspired by a crazy bad movie,
a web movie that most likely was,
was sponsored and made by the spooks
that they made it themselves.
They really hired some actors and they
put together a Shitty fucking propaganda
movie and they made it themselves.
Not only that,
the people that were in the movie,
he said that they said certain things,
but then when they watched the movie,
other words were dubbed into their
mouths.
Oh really?
Yeah,
so the idea was that this movie was just
created as a scapegoat and then everyone
would react to that movie,
so while we can't bow down to these
Muslims or like you've got to be up at
least aware of their feelings and that
just throwing us off the real trail.
Have you ever seen that movie?
Saw pieces of it?
It's fucking unbelievably bad.
Oh yeah.
It's like,
like,
like Peter Term.
Yeah,
exactly.
Someone who's just a complete madness
just ended up here,
doesn't know what he's doing.
It's like America world police.
If it was people just got a video
camera,
isn't it Brian?
If you,
if you've seen it pull up.
Yeah,
it's like America worldly when it's like
I'm an actor,
I have to go and save the world.
Like ridiculous,
crazy cheesy dialogue,
but not funny,
you know,
not on purpose.
What they're trying to do is really make
a really,
really dumb propaganda movie to justify
the reason why these terrorists would
sent to warships over there.
Almost instantly.
I'm like,
wait,
what's happening?
Tell you what,
man is a guy who was a mob deep,
deep in the world of intelligence.
Since I've been addicted to homeland,
I understand.
Be a little bit alien to you don't know
how the system works.
I've become a fan of the CIA from doing
homeland option that showed.
Yeah,
fuck yeah.
That show literally changes my opinion
on what it must be like for the CIA to
try to thwart terrorism and it makes me
understand why they would want to take
rights away.
I still don't agree with their ability
to do so,
but I understand the kind of shit that
they probably only do you have to deal
with.
The only problem with taking their
rights away.
It's not.
If it's from a reason it's been good.
It's that let's say your,
your,
your reasons are pure.
Like I just want to go after terrorists
when there's fewer full terrorists.
Well what happens?
The next guy who was in office who might
not share your sentiment about fair,
that's an.
That's an old statement.
The man.
You're saying yes to today's not the
same man.
You're going to have to say yes to 20
years from now.
If you give someone access to your
privacy today and he's a good guy,
that doesn't mean that you know,
we can have a new Nixon or he's not
going to turn into a bad guy.
Yeah.
So y'all gonna start abusing my power.
That's an always start from scratch.
Yeah.
And didn't that happen with the
president of Egypt?
This guy gets in,
gets elected.
The Muslim Brotherhood is like,
you know,
I decided I made a dictator,
no immune to prosecution.
And they were like,
hey.
And he goes,
no,
I have to in order to be able to run a
good government.
And people are like,
no,
because what we just got away from doing
that shit.
Hilarious.
The guy tried gangster right off the
bat.
I,
you need get to be here.
He gave on it,
gave him oh great.
Foreign power.
Well he's,
you know,
he's fucked now know they're going to be
looking sideways at him forever.
I mean he was the savior who was the
new.
You can't just do that.
Of course they should kill them.
Thinking about Carolyn anymore,
no killing anymore.
Extended to stop.
They just keep going for a little while
longer.
That's the problem.
They get rid of the one guy and then
they're like,
let's get more people.
That's what they didn't like.
The French.
Right.
You know all those things too,
where you got to think all those dudes
in Libya kill every one of those dudes.
That fucking stuck sticks up his ass.
All that shit.
Yeah.
Those guys are just running around out
there that want to kill more people.
Maybe somebody killed them.
Excited.
Get all fired up.
Killed Kadafi.
I wonder if they do like public speaking
engagements like they do the clubs out
there is a dime.
I took the stick was close to table.
The time was now I shut the stick up his
ass and everybody's.
Yeah,
they throw their shoes.
Tell us.
Did he say
scheme?
He was used to cook cellular was nothing
that he wanted more.
He wish he had it everyday of his life
with a bowl of milk in the morning and
sticking his eyes.
He didn't even react.
The shoved a stick up his house.
He was in total shock,
just react that much or period at all.
Apparently he was in full shock.
Wow.
They dragged that guy out.
He couldn't believe he was out there
with the regular people.
The look on his face Qaddafi's.
That is one of the best.
Like it as far as like a peek into what
happens when a dictator gets overcome by
the rebels and you actually get to watch
it.
I've never seen that before where we saw
We were there.
Yeah,
we were there.
We knew that doesn't exist anywhere in
history and it was on a fucking cell
phone camera.
No.
Hello.
He's fucking freaking out and covered in
blood and looking for someone to come in
and rescue them and has someone ever
comes.
They're sticking sticks up his ass.
They just fucking start shooting them.
Wow.
Yeah.
They,
they,
they dragged that guy around on the roof
of a car.
It was amazing.
I mean it was like literally everything
that you would see like in a movie about
a dictator getting overthrown,
but you never saw that before.
And to see the look of terror on his
face and to know that man,
that is a story that has been playing
itself out exactly the same way over and
over.
Throughout time.
You changed dictators.
That's the way
that's the normal route.
What is that?
That phrase that the tree of liberty
must be occasionally watered with the
death of enemies and patriots under his
end patriots.
Pinterest fighting.
I think that's the quote,
but yeah,
the idea that you just need in order to
stay,
you want,
you want liberty every now and then you
gotta fuck some people up because the
normal pattern that people follow for
whatever reason is once they get into
position of being able to tell what
people what to do,
they separate them from those other
people.
Did I seen that the comedy store had it
where managers worked as a.
When I worked as a security guard,
I,
I worked for a few months as a security
guard in a concert place.
Every night we're shutting up drunks and
every night and it became us versus
them.
And I wasn't a cop.
We couldn't arrest anybody,
but I got to see and I would have to
tell people,
you can't bring your booze and he can't
bring bottles,
and he came and they would yell at me,
fuck you.
And it became us versus them and we all
banded together,
all the security guards in our
attitudes.
Least cons coming in.
Fucking assholes.
Like right away,
even though you're hired to make sure
everyone's having a good time.
Well,
you're hired to keep everybody from
bringing in booze.
Mostly our main job was we would be
there at the beginning like James Taylor
to play and all these people who just
going bring a nice bottle of wine goes
he,
James Taylor.
You can't bring bottles of wine to a
place that sells wine.
Okay.
So when you get there and we take your
wine.
So we'd have to take people's bags.
We opened them up.
Do you have anything in here that we
should know about?
No.
Did you bring any alcohol in a bottle?
What's this?
He pulled out a bottle of wine plunk.
It didn't kick them out,
but you'd put the wine in like a bucket.
So at the end of the night we'd have
giant garbage buckets with booze,
nice.
And everybody's like,
you're good,
fuck.
Then we took their boots.
Like that was the attitude of all the
people that work there.
And so if you work there like you
develop that sort of attitude too,
like everybody's like,
yeah,
relationship,
security guard or a great woods.
But granted I was 18,
19 and I recognize it as it was
happening.
And then I was like,
this is fucking,
that's the same thing as Tsa.
They're going to do the same shit.
Exactly the same shit.
And I finally realized this now with
somebody,
it's like people they excuse it always
made me troubled with Tsa while they're
fucking infringing on our rights and
looking through all my shit and make me
take my shoes off.
And all this stuff is,
is,
um,
is uh,
uh,
they're just doing their jobs.
It's not their fault individually,
but I tell him to go fuck themselves.
It's still,
they're just doing their jobs.
Well,
why is that an excuse?
You know what you're doing.
You're taking a job fucking with people
because it's the job.
You're allowed to do whatever you want.
We'll see.
I don't think because someone check
attached to it.
I don't think Tsa fucks with people for
the most part.
I have not had a single problem with
Tsa.
I have not seen a single problem with
Tsa ever
except for like when I mentioned go
through this exercise,
things they didn't test
well,
those extra things.
Which ones?
The ones that spin the penis.
Yeah,
the ones they didn't test,
but they were just like,
oh,
we'll take their word for it.
Or The guy who owns it,
what I read according to what I've read
and the that you get inside a plane is
way worse than that and it's not
something to worry about.
I would love if they just actually put
out the tests they did instead of hide
it.
It's a good idea.
Yeah.
And or allow independent testing.
It's a good idea,
but I think that what they're worried
about,
right or wrong,
I disagree with it because I think there
should be full disclosure always when it
comes to things in regard health and
radiation and shit like that,
but they don't want to release the fact
that you get a lot of radiation on a
fucking plane.
You get so much radiation on a plane
that sometimes they have to fly
different paths because they're solar
flares and you're flying in weird spots.
Yeah,
you can fly in areas where there's too
much solar activity and it's fucking
British gamma radiation closer to the
sun.
Well,
you're fucking 30,000
feet and space.
You know,
you're really high up there,
man.
Little metal tube and you're getting
blasted by gamma rays.
You're really close to,
uh,
you know,
you're close to space,
closer to space by.
What is it?
What is 30,000
people at three?
How many miles is that?
How many was it?
Five thousand miles.
Miles.
Five hundred miles is a 5,000
feet is a mile,
right?
So yeah,
you're high up there man.
So apparently that is not good for you
and they don't want people to really
dwell on that because it's,
there's radiation in all things,
there's radiation and trees,
what have you.
So what do you think?
They don't want people to dwell on it
because if you start telling people,
if some,
listen man,
next time you're on a plane,
why don't you do it for a skeptic tank,
bring a geiger counter geiger counter
and I go,
you go online on Amazon.com
and get something that is a radiation
reader and see if it works that way.
I mean I don't know if that's how it
works.
I think that's how you would do it
though.
So anyway you would,
you would get that and you know,
get a reading and then compare that
somehow or another you would have to
fucking get a reading off of one of
those x ray machines at the airport.
But they wouldn't let you do that.
But if you did,
I bet the plane would probably be at
least as radioactive if not way more.
What I've read is that it's more.
But again,
how much information is really available
out there about those folks and make
your putting ingredients on everything.
You shouldn't have to get fucking x
rayed everywhere.
It's just the it people want to blow
things up all the time and it's always
planes.
It's like when is it going to happen?
We're enough.
Cuts.
Blow up a mall where every time you go
to the mall you have to put your fucking
change in a bucket and go through and
then someone's going to be stealing
watches and shit.
They're just like,
they do a tsa every now and then you get
a rogue employee.
I hate it when they.
When they fight,
where they,
when they catch some guy as news company
will catch some guys stealing who works
for the airline and the airline is the
only reaction is they no longer work
here that have been been been
terminated.
It's like,
no,
you should fucking put print off for
trial.
Yeah,
stealing while the representing the
government should have been way worse.
They don't try and they just fucking say
they're out.
That's it.
They're out.
Just like the prettiest.
That's the worst thing that'll happen to
him or her out.
I guess they figured that the prisons
today are so fucking overcrowded and the
justice system is so understaffed and
overworked.
If I knew my only
fucking repercussions were that I don't
have this job where I get to steal
anymore just to like crazy still.
Yeah,
until you get caught and then now you
don't get to steal anymore.
Either way.
I don't want to steal some steel wire
can.
It's really funny when they get super
ghetto at the TSA station,
like someone will say something.
It was,
oh no,
no,
no.
I wasn't involved with that.
Like,
Oh,
I know you were with that guy
and the like,
don't forget that like this is their
security officers for the government,
but just he has just sort of dumb people
are just folks who that's the job of
that.
You get started.
Raise your hands.
This is what I always say.
I can't raise my hands.
Why I'm,
I'm,
I'm not under arrest.
Am I doing things that make me seem like
I'm under arrest?
So when you go through the thing,
you won't raise your hands.
Whoa.
Yeah.
And they say,
why not?
You don't trust me.
I'm like,
I don't trust the company you work for.
And the fact that you work for them.
No,
I don't trust you.
Who are you?
Some lady.
So when you go through security,
do you cause a stink,
do you say?
Usually I try to time it up.
Any Jew?
I'm not here.
I don't say it like that.
But when they had the pat me down,
like we got to patch it down.
Did you say you prefer that?
I'm like,
no,
I don't prefer that.
But if you could give me no fucking
options,
do whatever the fuck you want to talk.
Oh yeah.
Fuck them.
You could tell me.
You tell Brian to go from punch somebody
and then he does it really mean Brian,
you shouldn't have done that.
But it's like,
no,
no.
He gave me.
Rogan gave me 20 bucks.
So it was just my job.
So I was working okay.
That's a bit extreme,
but they're just going to have rights.
They're making us all feel really bad,
but they're just doing a job.
They're not.
They're just doing.
Their job is not an excuse.
Right?
Wouldn't be if there were
being violent to you,
but I think the analogy is not fair.
It's like they're not getting you there.
Just making sure you don't have bombs
and most likely you don't have bombs.
See for you,
you're like,
well,
look at me.
I'm fucking.
I'm a handsome young man.
Um,
obviously
now I'll just search your shit just
because they're just making sure you
don't have bombs.
But they are.
They're allowed.
That's the agreement that we've all
made.
We've given up a little slice of
freedom.
And so because some monkeys want to go
on one guy,
one man,
let me think about all the people that
have done fucked up shit on planes.
It's an for whatever reason,
our fear of flying,
which is very real along with the
terrorist need to send a big message by
making a huge event happen.
Planes like a perfect thing for that,
you know?
And so that's why we got to watch out.
It's like,
it's too good for it.
So we to put air marshals up there as
dudes are secretly a cops that are
hanging out with reactionary to a time
where room.
Can you spawn air marshals?
Do you ever seen one seen someone's gun
or anything like that?
Like peeking out from other shoulder
notice?
Either when I feel like fake.
They're always the ones that are always
sitting on the plane before.
You don't know why that wasn't.
Yeah.
But how,
what?
Why would they do that?
Then you would know what you think they
would go.
They would they be in first class or
they'd been way back way,
way back.
But I know a couple people that actually
sat down next to him and they talked
about them being the air marshal too.
That was a dude trying to get some
poster.
Yeah.
Really what?
I'm out here for freedom.
Where the girls told you?
Yeah.
Fighting for freedom.
I want to
see my gun zip.
Oh that's not my gun.
But you could hold that.
Just lock the door.
Just locked the door in the bathroom and
saying cockpit.
Oh that's not that easy.
What if everybody.
He locked the door,
the plane lands everybody insides debt
that went and fucking kill everybody and
then they can't take over the planet.
Everyone died anyway
when died.
Anyway,
they opened up the door and everybody,
those kills the guy spending on locking
the door.
I just shot you theory.
Full holes employed a navy seal.
I'm saying as opposed not as opposed to
the air marshal as opposed to all the
fucking things they do with that.
There was a good book called the strain,
I should say.
It was a half of a good book.
It was.
It started off really good and then it
turned to shit towards the end.
It was almost like he just wanted to
finish it.
So they just like it was.
I'm not Benito del Toro was,
who's that fucking director?
Did Pan's labyrinth or labyrinths that,
that,
that name that we're,
um,
what's that guy's name?
Guillermo Labor.
And what is elaborative?
Feminist Library.
That's one of those words that I never
say I only want.
I read a few words were you like,
I don't think I've ever asked him.
Try to throw that into a sentence like
dystopian.
I mean,
I know how to say that because it's
fairly easy,
but we'll at Berlin.
This.
What was that?
Uh,
what's that dude's name?
Guillermo del Toro.
Wiremold toe at the beginning of the
book is fucking bad ass and starts off
with a plane and I started talking to
everybody in a plane being dead.
I can't figure out what the fuck happen.
Yeah.
But the kind of puts it vampires.
They don't have big fangs.
They have like this thing was like,
no,
no.
The other one strand the strain.
It's all a book.
Was that a Michael Crighton book?
No,
I'm thinking of something else where
maybe it's not the strain.
Guillermo del Toro.
Hey Guillermo,
I,
I'm reading a book that you would
fucking love,
um,
the uh,
sex at dawn guy on your,
on your podcast as well.
Yeah.
Keep telling me that he was great.
We had,
we got them a little too high.
Really got it.
I guess that aren't used to it.
That can like a
yes,
go under.
I think me and Brian like it a little
too much.
You like it?
The strain?
Oh,
the strange name of the book.
I was right.
I think we like it a little when we see
a guy falling apart.
You like it.
This is like,
there's something about seeing that we'd
hit.
I'm like,
and you just,
you just hear that fucking sunshine on
my love song.
Doot,
doot,
doot.
Do you just see the fear grip them?
Sometimes you can't see it in people or
they're just like,
you're like,
you've been acting weird and like,
oh,
you're super stone.
That's what we did is we used to dis
will use to encourage it.
It's sort of my same year approach
to,
to uh,
mushrooms.
I used to encourage it.
I used to say come on and get high with
us.
No,
you'll be fine.
You'll be fine.
Not Everybody's going to be fun.
We're smoking if you'd like somebody
going out there.
Yeah.
I mean we've got people that like,
seem like they would be like big time
stoners.
These are all the time we were getting
is like really high grade shit.
And if they're not on a medical program,
who knows,
they might be getting weed from a
friend,
you know,
they might have like a little bit like,
hey we smoke weed every now and then.
Which,
what does that mean?
It might mean like the way I drink,
like if,
if I'm going to go out I might have a
beer or two,
but I don't sit at home and drink beer
at home,
but I'll get high and right.
You know,
my body's used to getting high.
Like I know what I'm doing when it comes
to my body goes,
I know what to do with this.
We're good.
But to a lot of people,
this is like a once a week thing.
Once every two weeks.
Things and you,
you know,
you try to keep up with
can captain silly and he passes you that
choice with a silly little.
We have like one hit,
like I'm good.
Like what are you talking like,
oh you know your limits and you go down,
you concentrate on the fucking cat.
He's going to cat on his shirt with a
suicide vest.
But I ain't got to be so high one in
Calabasas.
I fell asleep at a light red light.
It's like a man.
I think I smoked too much.
I'm like,
no,
this shit's not.
You don't have the good stuff.
It was like the strongest way to do that
shit to people now that's rude.
I err on the side of caution and I think
already what?
You weren't smoking weed back then?
Like not as much anymore.
Once in a long while.
Once every couple of months or
something.
It was,
it wrecked me.
I remember when you just completely.
Yeah,
getting hydrated every day.
I go,
well how long have you been doing that?
About a month.
A little bit.
That was really funny.
I was like,
well,
what made you,
uh,
what made you change?
I'll never forget this.
He go,
I try to have more fun.
Hi.
I'm having more fun than my fucking.
I got this gift,
big care package to you and Eddie went
into Atari.
His old place.
Yeah.
And I at the time of year,
my license.
And it was my first hire ever been to
the weed store that no one knew.
So I was in there like,
oh my God,
I'm in a store,
I should just leave,
I shouldn't like infringe on anybody's.
And then at some point he's making care
packages for you and for Eddie and the
guy behind the counter goes,
so I make one for this other guy too.
And he's like,
yeah,
yeah.
Everybody kept packages.
So I had like six,
eight different strains of weed at home.
And if I don't have to save it for
anything,
I'll go through it.
Yeah.
That guy got out of the business,
right?
Yeah,
I think he's out of the business.
I think they all get out of the
business.
Yeah.
They're trying to figure out what the
hell they're going to do in Washington
state now and in Colorado because of the
legality issues that go in there and
fucking march on Washington.
The real question is who's going to be
the first crazy fuck to open up a store
and try to sell weed because it doesn't
seem like you can sell it.
It seems like you could have it and it's
legal to have and you can grow it.
It's legal to grow like up to a certain
amount of plants.
I think they made it.
Yeah know,
like a reasonable amount,
like five or six plants or something
like that,
but what you can't do is you can't sell
it.
Selling it as an issue.
It's not legal to sell now,
which is really defeats the purpose of
the idea of legalization should be taxed
revenue man or one of them anywhere.
He should not legal your right.
One of them.
Good point.
Very good point actually.
Yeah.
It's a.
They should be able to make money off
that man.
The state should make money and it
shouldn't be something that benefits not
just the growth of your own self.
Well,
listen man,
there's a budweiser plant.
I'm in Van Nuys.
I pass by it all the time.
It's like one that Grove Budweiser on
only refreshing buds.
That's great that that Budweiser plant.
I think it's in.
Van Nuys is great for the community.
It's a big,
big.
I mean the employees,
a lot of people that require that money
for their livelihood,
right?
Employs.
Who knows how many people.
It's a huge,
huge builder,
a giant parking lot.
I can only imagine.
Nothing wrong with Budweiser.
Okay,
but why can't we'd have that same sort
of status in a community?
Like why wouldn't it be looked on the
law the way it should be like that.
It's a commodity now.
Like you can help the in the
neighborhood.
It can help.
I mean if we have the.
Oh,
there's a big weed farm here.
They employ like 700 people in this
community and know everybody's fucking
waving,
but it makes a good living.
They're selling weed.
The government gets the tax revenue from
it.
That is so possible and it's really kind
of amazing that it's taken this long
before.
Just the seeds get planted for that to
be possible because the amount of money
that a community could make off of
selling marijuana and the amount of tax
revenue,
you get it.
You could literally change agricultural
area.
She would just have to have the FDA step
in a little bit.
Make sure people aren't growing and like
really shitty conditions with Salmonella
can get out or anything like that.
Well,
they need to like look at shitty
conditions for a lot of different foods
that we ingest on a regular basis.
Mycotoxins are something that we've.
This stuff that I'm drinking this
bulletproof coffee stuff that the shit
coffee.
No,
this is.
I'm trying to not drink starbucks.
I love you.
You're very convenient.
However,
according to the Dave Asprey,
there is a very common to have
mycotoxins which are fungus,
like different types of toxic fungus
that grows on coffee.
They also grow on corn.
They grow in a bunch of different things
and he says that one of the bad feelings
that you get from drinking coffee,
it's because your body is dealing with
the fact that you just ingested a bunch
of boys and feelings from coffee.
That I get the greatest feelings ever.
Summer.
No,
I have.
I've actually gotten like sleepy after
drinking coffee before and I can never
understand what the fuck that was.
And someone said it's because you had
80.
Yeah.
That doesn't work with this stuff.
I don't get sleepy when I take this
stuff because the extra stuff is put in
there,
you know?
It's because mycotoxins occur when the
coffee beans are not processed
correctly.
That between the time of growing them
and between the time you getting them
somehow or another,
they sat in a funky place.
They develop some mold and that shit's
not good for you.
This stuff that he gets is from a single
source.
It's like the company that grows it
packages it and they take care of
everything.
They make sure that they have very non
life conditions,
you know,
whatever the fuck they use to do that.
He swears by that and now when I drink
this stuff and it also has grassfed
butter in it and you blend it and butter
and mct oil,
which is what's the grass fed butter?
Grass fed butter is butter that comes
from grass fed cows because apparently
all the cows that we're getting from
milk and all the cows that we're getting
for food for the most part,
unless you're looking for grass fed
meat,
they're eating corn and corn is not what
a cow supposed to eat.
When cows eat corn,
they get fat as fuck.
That's why they so delicious.
When they get all those layers and
marbles,
you know,
you get a nice fat steak and it's got
all that marbling,
it'll cook sop and Oh,
it's popping in juicy.
Getting hungry.
Look at.
You're excited.
Well,
that's not normal.
When a cow has is grass fed,
they have much less fat.
I mean they have like a little bit of
fat on there,
but they're far more lean and it's a
really different kind of tasting meat.
It's much healthier system.
Yes.
It actually works to burn fat it,
it builds muscle better.
It's a tremendous like,
like people were athletes swear by the
effects of grass fed meat.
It's just very expensive.
Now.
Would that help you if you just ate it
once in a while?
It was.
Got to fully switch like gluten,
we're gonna have to get completely
edited system before you start saying
that affects.
Um,
I would think that if you want to get
the utmost benefit,
you would want to take it completely out
of your system and then you could still
have cheat days,
but like it,
would it be worth somebody for somebody
once in a while when they can be like,
you know what,
give me the grass fed beef still.
Yeah.
Why don't I don't hear it every day,
but I try to eat it as much as I can.
I,
you know,
I just,
it's really inconvenient.
That's the problem.
It's hard to find,
but it's way more common than it was
just a few years ago.
People because of guys like rob wolf
because of guys like Dave Asprey,
who is a huge,
huge proponent of grass fed meat and
grass fed milk and grassfed,
uh,
the,
the butter that you get from it.
Like the butter that you get from a corn
fed cow is sick and so it's different.
Yeah.
The butter tastes different.
It's got a weird sort of a,
I dunno,
it was just a slightly different flavor
to the butter,
slightly different flavors.
It's been able to roam out fruit groves
because they're free roaming.
The meat tastes different game and the
color is different.
Yeah.
Oh really?
Yeah,
I,
I thought that was because there were
weak bitches.
I was like this little pussy ass.
They don't eat insects.
Yeah.
This,
the type of wild insects and larva and
shit that they dine on,
you know?
Yeah.
That's what apparently a changes the
color,
their flesh salmon.
So they should have that.
They're also dyed pink.
Yeah.
But no,
no,
but those are,
those are the reasons why they died and
those are the ones that are pawn fed Sam
and apparently something along those
lines.
But apparently like nutrition wise,
it's really not that much a difference.
A real like a lot of people think there
is.
But then again,
I mean I don't know exactly what you're
measuring when you.
I mean how many salmon filets get broken
down by vitamin content?
How often are they doing that?
I mean,
what,
what control group where they work in
front,
you know,
what tests that they've done on salmon.
Am I just talking out of my ass?
Ari?
Fear control of it,
right?
Yeah.
I Dunno.
I just can't think those pellets can be
as good as all those bugs they eat.
Yeah,
that's probably better.
That's an actual.
When wild salmon tastes better.
Does it tastes different?
It tastes different.
Yeah.
Saw that juicy bug juice you're getting
in there.
Delicious bug juice.
Well,
I,
you know,
a lot of people don't like the taste of
game.
You know,
a lot of people like they think that
Venice and tastes funky and I've never
had bear.
Have you ever had parents who.
Where's who sorts bear?
You've got to go somewhere.
Special Shit.
According to Steven now,
who'll be on the podcast Monday.
Hala.
Praise Odin.
A corner.
Steven Rinella.
If a bear is eating blueberries and the
spring fucking delicious.
You said when they get out of there,
right when they get out of their dens
and they start eating massive amounts of
blueberries.
Apparently they taste so good.
The bear does.
Yeah.
If you find a baptist near blueberries
and they eat a shitload of blueberries,
that's most their diet like blue flesh,
like they're fat,
they're fat is like blue,
like he saves their bear fat.
He's seems like cooks with it and shit.
Yeah.
Apparently it's unbelievably good.
Like,
but,
but it can vary.
Like if you get a bear and like New
Jersey,
like you apparently don't like to eat
brown bears.
People like to eat black bears.
Brown bears don't taste good because
brown bears are mostly predators.
So they're full of meat.
Yeah,
they're full of meat.
They're mostly,
there are a lot of them are full of fish
like grizzlies,
but a black bear.
A lot of what the is vegetables.
So when you,
when you get them and they eat like a
lot of blueberries are delicious.
But if they're eating like your garbage,
like you know,
suburban New Jersey has a real problem
with bears and just eat whatever they
can find.
Black bears get into suburban
neighborhoods like place where like Jim
Brewer lives and shit like that.
And they go and they tip over garbage
cans and they just eat all of the
people's food and they become a real
problem because once they know that they
can come into a neighborhood and eat
garbage and everybody's a little bit
through anything.
So they.
So they opened up hunting season on
them.
So when they open up hunting season,
um,
then people went out and hunted these
bands,
but they found out the bears that were
near people that tasted like shit
garbage,
you know,
they're,
they're just fucking donuts and whatever
the fuck they find in a parking lot
somewhere and never see the wild boys
were,
they were,
they had tried to lower bear into their
tent.
Yeah.
Those were like that video,
that chick doing the back flip.
I could barely watch him.
Look what the fuck do you ever see the
one where they were throwing a ham
around and these hyenas,
they're playing.
Keep away.
We're trying to.
We're trying to eat it.
They're nipping at them.
Can literally break right through your
arm.
It would just bite through your arm and
your hand would fall one side.
And the rest of your arm would go lamp
and they would take that piece out of
the middle out and it'd be gone.
And it's cool.
That's the heinous.
Now snap.
Wow.
Fuck that.
I love that.
How about the one when he got up in the
tree and the lion climbed up and got on
top of him and just started touching his
hat and didn't kill him.
Remember that Brian on the podcast.
So great.
I got so close so many times out of his
fucking mind.
Fucking mind in jacket.
He hooked himself or the nipple with a
hook and then they us for real man by
his guys are so nice.
I know.
When did that become cool to like hurt
yourself?
Scare me.
Yeah.
But why?
What,
what,
what?
America was ready for it.
I got rid of Tom Green where it's like,
oh,
we love these things,
but this is victim us.
We want to be seen enough.
Alright Ladies and gentlemen,
let's bring this bitch home.
Should fear.
Thank you very much,
my brother.
You're welcome.
I would just go ahead and say that my
special will be out February fifth ish.
50 Ish,
but you can pre order it to starting
tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
[inaudible] DOT com.
Where is it?
Chill.com.
C H I l l.com.
Ooh,
what a good one.
A good domain name.
Easy to remember.
[inaudible] DOT com.
Go to [inaudible] dot com.
Folks.
Support your boy.
Red should fear and I know that you were
very happy with this fellow.
I'm super stoked man.
I was really happy.
It was all my fans.
It's all different than comedy central
ones.
They don't tell you what to do,
what to just you do it on your own sense
of free.
It's beautiful.
We live in amazing times,
man,
for,
for artistic creativity,
for freedom,
for to be able to put your own shit out
there and to be able to do like what
we're doing right now.
You know,
we have like a legit show somehow or
another that reaches millions of people
somehow or another,
you know,
and through that platform,
you really could do what you want,
you know,
and I'll be in Edmonton at the comic
strip through in that material was
almost thought 90 percent of that
material.
So see it there for.
Yeah,
go see it there.
First you fox because he's not going to
be out on video you can download until
February fourth.
So you've got to give them time to come
up with some new shit.
I mean he just recorded it.
Okay.
Don't get a lot of you comedy nerds
skill touchy about the new material and
cut the guy some slack,
you know,
don't feel like some of your bits.
And I'm like if you saw one of my bits,
it might've been maybe one come back to
the second show and say the same thing
twice in a weekend,
which I don't,
I don't usually I have one that I'm
working on.
You fucker.
I'm a thank you to everyone for
supporting the podcast.
We appreciate the fuck out of it and I
appreciate even even the criticism.
I really do.
Without it,
I would like criticism wouldn't be as
good.
That's cool.
Thank you.
It's just people that get angry like so
many people were angry at me because of
the loon talk,
you know,
look,
you don't have to get angry.
It's stupid.
You're getting a free podcast.
There's don't need to be angry.
Oh yeah.
You like it.
You don't like it if you have something
constructive.
I really do believe that all of the
constructive criticism that I've ever
heard,
whether it was from my time time hosting
that fear factor,
whether it's from doing the UFC
commentary or whether it's from doing
comedy,
I really believe that that's made me
better at what I do.
Even some of the country shit,
it's like puts things just to know that
someone could see you that way.
Valid or not.
Uh,
so,
uh,
go check it out on twitter.
It's a r I,
s h a f f I r follow him.
He drops bits of knowledge all
throughout the day and he's a real
inspirational sort of a character.
Like the other day someone was asking
for babysit advice and he said,
call Casey Anthony the way to go,
son of a,
B,
and I'll be in Chicago with Joe Rogan.
Yeah,
that's right.
We're going to be in Chicago.
Um,
and that,
is this the 20th,
January 25th.
Wow.
That's coming up soon.
That's going to be fun as Fuck Chicago,
January 25th and then Las Vegas,
Nevada.
February first with Mad Flavor,
Aka Joey Diaz.
And uh,
just uh,
you could find that shit on ticket
master or you can go to my twitter.
You could find it up there or you can go
to Joe Rogan.net,
my newly redesigned website.
And from there you can actually buy my
new comedy special.
Oh yeah.
I guess I'm supposed to be promoting and
it's five bucks drm free.
It's the best shit I think I've ever
for.
It means you can put it on any device.
You can download a copy it I just asked.
Please don't steal it.
Don't put it on a torrent site or
anything like that.
That's your best one you've ever done?
I think so,
yeah.
I think I'm better now than I've ever
been before.
Definitely had the most experience being
a comic on this one.
I mean,
I liked my last one.
I really liked shiny,
happy jihad.
I really liked talking monkey's in
space.
Like I think everything that I've done
since I stopped doing fear factors,
my best stuff,
you know,
from that 2006 on.
Yeah,
yeah,
definitely.
But I think this is the best one at all
of them.
I just think I'm better at it,
you know?
It's just a matter of spending time and
practice reaction has been really good.
Yeah,
man,
it's been almost universal.
I'm super,
super,
super happy with it.
Some people,
there's a few complaints only that I had
talked about some of the subjects on the
podcast,
but that's impossible to avoid.
I'm doing podcasts for three hours a
day,
so when you care about this stuff you
talk about on stage,
it's going to bleed over to regular
conversations because you're not making
it up because your real feelings.
Yeah,
yeah.
No doubt.
I mean it's a.
This whole podcast connection with
standup is it was very unexpected and
start off a bit on the podcast and be
like,
oh,
let me think more of that.
You saw the first germination of an idea
all the time,
bitch,
thanks to a hover for sponsoring us as
well for the first time today.
Ladies and gentlemen,
and again,
as I said,
hover is a they,
well they promote themselves as a non
evil.
That's a,
you know,
it's a catchy word with people but a non
evil domain name company and you can go
to Rogan hover.com
or [inaudible] dot com.
Sorry,
you go to hover.com
forward slash rogen.
You get 10 percent off your domain name
registrations and if you go to
[inaudible] dot com,
that's o n n I t and use a codename
Rogan.
You save 10 percent off any and all
supplements.
All right.
You fuckers,
we love the shit out of you.
We thank you very much for,
for all the love and we'll see you soon.
Hello?
Wow.