Bad motherbutterflyer.
George is just a bad motherbutterflyer
and that's what makes him so good
old school.
Brian,
Greg,
his little bad mother butterflyer
plants makes him famous.
No,
text
me running up a little goes bad when
he's got my gamble at lunch or something
like the class clown pulling daughter.
It's hard to see no door
knocking on your door
and little speck. No,
I was still shooting. I sold nothing. Dot.
I was doing candy up the corner.
That's all I got my ass when I
was 10 years old doing dumb shit.
You got to have some sort of
a, a clean cutoff point. Brian.
We should program that into the beginning
of the first song or first a part of
the podcast.
I got clean cut off with no music because
we could probably get in trouble for
using people's music.
That was ice cube doing dumb shit
you it could be by on the iTunes.
That's where I got it. It's
possible. Brian Count. Brian Callen,
Liza fresh from Thailand. Ladies
and gentleman, freshman towers.
I played the trumpet by the way.
I just was thinking about that.
I should have taken an instrument.
Ours,
our podcast is always a
sponsored by the flashlight.
And if you go to Joe rogan.net,
there's a link.
You Click on it and if you
enter in the code Rogan,
you can masturbate at a discount.
That's butterflying awesome. You ever blast
went into one of these things? Uh, uh,
that's a sin. Anyway, Brian, Brian,
play in it clean now
that he's doing films.
Your film just got to watch the image.
It's funny when you do look at your
films for those of you guys don't know.
I think I just came back from Thailand
doing hangover two little movie. But uh,
but it's funny because when you,
and we talked about this man,
like you'd finally do the big film.
You know,
you're doing this big film and stuff and,
and you know it,
it's like you're your whole,
like your desire is to do something
that you've always watched.
You want to be the guy with
the sweaty shirt, with a gun,
tears coming down your face on a railroad
track with the wind blowing your hair
back. And it's the final confrontation.
We can have the shootout. That scene,
that scene in your fantasy takes six
days cause they're shooting half a page a
day.
That's what acting in the film as you're
just sitting around while they spray
your shirt.
Well as the sweat isn't really working,
it's not the same as the shock before.
We've got to change your shirt.
Give us a minute. That light's
not working. We've got,
can you stand to the left a
little bit bro. That's what,
that's what do on a big
film is really about.
It's fun though because he ended up
hanging out with some fun people on this.
Generally complain about doing big movies.
Dude, I want to hear that shit. Sorry.
Uh, erase sucks now. I didn't, it
didn't suck. I had a great time.
What's the best Gig in Hollywood?
Do you think it's a TV show?
Well the best Gig for,
for like as far as like comfort,
life, comfort. That's what they said.
I think there's no question that it's a
sitcom cause you work 10 minutes a week
and yeah, and, and you make a fortune.
See for me doing a doing a sitcom is,
is uh,
is cake because then I can go do stand
up on the weekends and make you know,
TV money doing that. Yeah. I
mean the best Gig in Hollywood,
the best Gig in the show business is,
is either being a rock star
or be in a standup comic.
And I'm not sure what beats what,
but you know,
there's nothing like doing stand up.
Stars can break up.
The problem is they have to rely on a
bunch of other that's exactly right. And,
and I think also, you know when you're,
when you were like a major rock star,
you've been singing the same song for 30
years. That's got to get a little tire.
Yeah. It's gotta be a weird, cause
it's totally reverse of comedians.
Cause with rock stars, nobody ever
wants to hear their new shit. You know,
nobody wants to hear the new
rolling stones songs. No,
no, no. They're like, stop,
stop. Do that. Start me up song again.
Would comedy people don't want to hear
old shit. They want to hear some new shit.
What's some new shit to
magic trick because it's,
it's like you got to surprise him.
That's when people laugh.
They're constantly could be
coming up with new material,
but isn't that a funny thing?
It's like the Rock Stars get pigeonholed
into doing all their best old creation
and we, we have to. That's why
David Lee Roth, when he got,
when they fired him from
van Halen, he goes, oh,
I know Sammy Hagar has got to
sing jump for the next 20 years.
That's the problem with rock stars about,
I'm not saying that it wouldn't
be awesome to be a rock star,
but you have to find a group of people
who agree to hang out and be cool with
each other in the midst of
like the biggest ego explosion
in humanity's history.
Rockstar. Oh, forget it. But that's the
bit, that's the top of the food chain.
There's the top of the vagina food chain
he had. There's no doubt. Fuck yet is,
are you kidding me? It's
not. To me. It's not,
I wouldn't have gone awry or rock paper,
scissors over everyone you've
ever met in your butterflying life.
Even when he's a rock star with
that huge head, it doesn't matter.
That doesn't matter. He's got that.
He's got the jobs are rock stars.
Everyone knows he's banging
everybody and it doesn't matter.
It's not even them town. He's the
Alpha male butterflying savage. Why?
Cause he's a rockstar son.
Singing songs that make
them emotionally satisfied.
These making them orgasm emotionally,
saying all the right shit with the right
tone, the right amount of sensitivity.
Amazing what guys will do to get checks.
How as a player of epic proportions,
truly respect. Did he show? He shows up.
He shows up in a black tight tank top.
He's the only guy I can get away with
that. How is he black? Top tank top.
What champion?
I'd get punched in the face,
but John Mayer plays
guitar and girls swoon.
My man is just swinging Dick
and given out bubble gum.
Have you seen him do comedy?
It's also about six four I think too.
I Hate Everest guy. Handsome
Brian. If you seen it to comedy,
he's done comedy at the comedy store.
I've heard he's done comedy as well. Yeah,
I can't. Yeah. Some guys, look,
there's a pecking order, you know,
I'm the best silver back.
That's all there is to it.
I'm in the tree thrown fruit
while he's taken all my girls.
Speaking of which all I could think of
when I saw this video was you the the,
have you seen those videos
of the heartbeat eagles and
Venezuela? Oh yes I have.
Holy Sean's a take goats. Yeah.
And that let it drop forever. No,
the Harpy Eagles do that.
But the big thing they do is get monkeys,
monkeys and sloths.
Venezuela basically butterflying kill anything.
They're the biggest ego. The biggest
legal there are enormous. And this is,
there's a documentary on Youtube.
It is the shit.
And I've thought of you immediately
cause you and I are both retards when it
comes to animal. He never had more too.
If you heard about his butterflying lions,
we never had these conversations with
anybody more than with you because you and
I just sync up. We both kick it to the
next level of retard. I can't get enough.
I can't get an that guy cause cause that,
that you remember the conversation
we had about those lions,
the super lines in Africa that
heat the water buffalo. Yeah,
the giant lines talking
about Brown because,
and I were in like retard
fever pitch right there.
Well they used to always think of males.
The females are bigger than males.
They're chunking muscle
lions both like holy butterfly,
this is butterflying insane. And
you just get, so that's why,
that's why I got so obsessed with those
champs, those huge 400 pounds champs,
those lion eater chess. They found
leopard meet in their faces. What?
Oh and by the way,
they how?
Apparently and they fished with their
own bare hands and they are all gray.
You know that. No, I did not
know that. Great chimps. The
older ones, they're gray.
Look, let's just like in that movie Congo
and let me explain something to you.
When you buy a champ for anybody who
wants to buy a champion, I one call.
Here's the problem.
You don't,
you don't want something with seven times
the upper body strength of a grown man
with a three year old's brain.
It's prone to rage. Okay.
Cause they go for the face
and the genitals. Yeah. Yeah.
That's what they do. They,
the guy at the San Diego Zoo go, no. A
chimp says solve everything with violence.
They go for the, the face and the genitals
cause they don't want you to breathe.
So they're, they're pretty vindictive.
That's great. They really are like a,
it's like a 500 pound man. Right.
That's what they say. Well let me,
let me give you an example. They took
140 pound female in the Bronx Zoo.
A long time. 140 pounds. Okay.
Now MailChimp's get up to about 200
pounds is 140 pound female adolescent.
They taught her that the more
she pulled with one hand,
they strapped her to a chair,
the more she pulled with one hand the she
had the sweeter or the fruit that give
her, it's supposed to at an
apple, they give our mango,
she pulled 1200 pounds with one hand.
She rode 1200 pounds with one hand.
Now think about that for a second.
Do To who are doing the upright
row with three 50 they're crazy.
They're monsters. They're huge. 1200
pounds. Her, her tensile strength,
they did a tensile strength. And
whether it's, did they test your grip?
So the 160 pound man has, I'm
a hundred and God, what was it?
It was like 300 pounds or four,
actually a 200 pounds of tensile strength.
She had 1200 pounds of tensile strength
strength as well. She could squeeze,
you know, a ball. I don't know.
We are so butterflying weak policies or such.
I was less,
she would fight with Shitty pussies.
I spent three weeks in Indonesia
rehabilitating orangutans. Okay.
I was around,
I'm sorry.
It's pronounced orangutan to hear a
butterflying really smart you guys. Holy Shit.
Personal. The forest in
Indonesia. You guys learn a lot.
This is about education. Show Tony
about the education. Yo. Yeah,
but meanwhile they're ridiculously
strong. That's insane man. It's crazy.
Back to Bangkok and that's
140 pound female. Uh, correct.
So a 200 pound male butterflying chart.
How about a 400 pound male
other than the huge ones?
That's why they call him lion
killers. Correct. The, the, the,
the most recent expeditions actually
caught one eating a leopard.
They don't know if it killed it,
but they observed them eating
it and they're very elusive man.
They've actually never, I guess they've
only seen like a couple in the wild. Yeah,
they've only seen a few in the
wild and they sleep on the ground.
They nest on the ground just
like gorillas. Who wouldn't,
they don't give a butterfly.
Exactly. Good luck everybody.
It's crazy cause it's only a very,
very small part of the Congo and that,
that part is all filled with civil
war right now. It's very dangerous.
So it's really hard to explore
these guys and to get to them,
you got to go straight through rain
forest on foot. It's solely penetrable.
Penetrable it's insane. And once you're
in there, man, dude, good butterflying luck.
Good luck with poisonous spiders.
Insects you out from the ear out.
They will climb into your ears and eat
your butterflying brains. Millions of them.
Streams of Ai. It's got to
feel good. Elephants, man.
Have you heard of the spiders that are
like that big that are over in like a
rack right now that can't like
camel spiders. I've seen him.
I lived in Saudi Arabia.
People those on fear factor.
That's butterflyed up though.
So they eat. I'm like, no,
don't say biking numbs you.
Well I would never be on that show.
You got to grab them the right way.
Hazing what people do for like the aim.
I lead a camel spider and gets stung
in my face. Yeah, getting stung on the,
on the roof of my mouth can't be weak.
There was a lot of shit we did with bugs.
It was ridiculous.
Scorpions with made people lie and a
thing is corporate and just get jacked by
Scorpions and they got to
Tom and stuff. Yeah. Oh
yeah. Those big black ones
that were really scary.
Those are apparently are not as dangerous.
Really dangerous ones with the small
brown ones. Some of the small brown ones,
but the big black ones, it's like a bee
sting. What were those fluorescent ones?
They were like green caterpillars that
just burst every time you meet somebody
would chew on them. Like they're
Lewis, huge tomato hornworms.
Those things are crazy.
Fluorescent Green and it's so,
if you're really trippy here in the wild,
if you're in the wild,
is there any bug you can't eat? Is
there? I'm sure there's a lot of them.
The one when bugs are really bright,
bright, and colorful most of the time.
That's a big warning.
Yeah.
It's a big warning that
there's some poison in this
motherbutterflyer. Like, you know,
look at this bitch pet back the butterfly up.
Yeah, you don't see me. It's both of us.
There's suicide bombers.
You eat them and that's really what it is,
is to discourage predation.
Nature's porn star.
You don't want to eat caterpillars.
Apparently. Those are those.
They're really bright and pretty,
or Hornets, caterpillars, my whole,
all those butterflying things were just
so lucky. They're small. Fuck,
won't you imagine if Hornets
were giant like a horse?
It was a size of a butterflying horse dude.
You alluded him.
Never evolved to this point. I guess
they would just come down and just Jack,
you bite your butterflying head off
and eat your body. Yeah, they did.
They would just do that.
It would just do that and would
be nothing you can do about it.
It never developed to the point where
if, if those animals existed, let's,
we learned how to ride
them. No. Are we high rate?
We're just going to be fine as butterfly.
If it wasn't for that Goddamn asteroid
that killed all the dinosaurs, do it.
It never, we would never
have gotten to this position.
We had to start from scratch and then
have a, a new race with the mammals.
I tried to get to the
top of the food chain.
If there was giant flying butterflying hornets,
the size of horses,
we would've never made it this far.
I don't know.
You'd have to go walk
around with a flame thrower.
I don't know if that would work. I don't
know if that works on a regular morning.
Those things are no joke. Yeah
man. They would find that you,
if they find you like in a a big
butterflying swarm of them found you.
They found out where the people are.
You ever watched that video there,
these gigantic Hornets and the Japanese?
Do you want to do mine?
I don't want to go into that 50
times butterflying you might have,
I mean the sixth Japanese,
Yellow Hornets,
they're the biggest member of the Horn
of family that came in and killed 30,000
bees in a period of three hours.
Is that what you mean?
That video heads off ladies and
gents already thousand bees.
It would would be the youtube search
for that Japanese Hornets Kisco.
He'll go to go to hornets versus
B versus B. As you gotta see this,
and imagine if they were big
and by the way, these things,
they have close up on this thing and
you watch these bees doing whatever they
can. And the only time, this is what
it was so creepy, those Japanese worn,
it's what they'll do is they'll send a
scout out and when the scouts sees the
hive it drops like a hormone,
like a,
like a scent trail on the hive
and then goes flying back to its,
you know its nest and then,
and then,
and then the troops come out and
they come out and then they just,
they just eat the bees, how, what they
do. But sometimes what the bees get,
they get lucky. And what they'll
do sometimes is they will actually,
when they get, when the Hornets walking
around like it's doing right now,
sometimes the bees will jump on it and
they can't sting it cause it's too,
it's a armors too thick.
What they do is they start flapping
their wings around it and they create so
much heat around the horn at that the
horn, it dies because it's too hot.
And that's the only time if you can kill
the scout before he goes back, your,
your, your colony will survive. If
you don't, then you're all dead.
Holy Shit. Yeah. Look
how big, how big it is.
You have to see this spaceship and just
wrap your head around what the butterfly's
going on.
We,
I think we discount the insane complexity
of the insect world because there's so
little. That's right. But if
they were big, yeah. Well,
buck a trip, this would be,
they're, they're sold
incredibly organized. It's
ridiculous. We're just so lucky.
They're little. The defenders
greatly outnumbered the Hornets.
It could have easily yet turned out
that these things were birds, you know,
giant birds.
Well did they tear doctors and things?
We had the dinosaurs were essentially
the birds have their closest relatives.
They set us.
So there's an interesting theory that
I've read recently about dinosaurs that
they believe that the size of dinosaurs
is so ineffective given our current,
uh, atmosphere that they think that
it's possibly evidence that there was a
different atmosphere on earth when
a different like dogs density to the
atmosphere on earth and
they were cold blooded.
It would probably have to be warmer
than it was. Right. You know? Um,
like crocodiles, I mean if you, you
need to see that documentary called,
there'll be here be dragons where you
got those crops that actually bite a
Willdabeast around the mid section and
take a man butterflying video when they're
within the Willdabeast walks up to the
palm there drinking and it just explodes
out of the pond. That's right.
And that, that's a, that's a,
I don't know how many thousands of pounds,
but that, that is, that's a dinosaur.
That's as close to a dinosaur as you get.
It's incredible that that thing is still
alive. They keep living and by the way,
they keep growing.
There's this condition with a reptile
like that where they will just keep
growing more.
They get bigger,
they get where they eat cows and there's
a certain sinister quality to the
crocodile that makes it look more
sinister than an alligator even,
you know, it's, it's called a longer,
sharper snout and alligators have that
got that round kind of rounder snout and
they tend to eat fish
and smaller animals too,
but they butterflying eat
people and only pay him to,
the guy got killed who was a on a
running from the cops. He crashed.
His car is like a Dui in Florida.
Really? Running from the cops,
jumped out of his car,
jumps into the water just as he jumps
into the wall and the alligator grabs him
and butterflys him up right in front of the
car. Is that true? Yeah. I was in the,
I was in Marco Island doing standup and
there's an area in Marco island off of
Naples that has the biggest saltwater
crocodile preserve American crocodiles.
And there are signs all over. Don't go
swimming. Do not get out of your boat.
Don't be careful when you're fishing.
All that stuff.
It their crocodiles anywhere
in the area. I'm not, Oh shit.
No, no. We're not going hiking.
Well all you have to do is tap them on
the snout and they're walking with it the
butterfly out of here.
Fucking time. That's the,
that's the biggest lie when I talk
about when a, when a shark attacks,
you hit him in the nose, they kill
sea lines with their mouths tried.
It's like hitting the Chevy on that on,
on the mouth when it's coming at you at
30 miles an hour. And on the hood of the,
on the hood, they're not worried
about stuff that bumps their nose.
They're going to butterfly you
up. That's just some bribes.
That's great rights. What? That guy
that rides great whites. It's a guy who,
Brian's great wines from South Africa
who he was snorkeling with eight great
whites in the water and then
wrote a 22 footer shut the fun.
Speaking of which David Blaine butterflying,
I don't know if I can say this cause he,
I think it's going to be part of a show,
but um,
he does a thing with the great
whites is pretty crazy to do.
You just give it away. I
can't even believe you did,
but it's not, it's nothing.
It wasn't it you, I'm not giving
anything away, but he does something.
He showed me some pretty cool stuff.
I'll drop big names on this podcast
if I want the whole animal world, man,
we so take it for granted because we've
pretty much isolated ourselves from it
with cities.
And you know,
that's the first thing that really
struck me when I was living in Colorado.
Who was hell, you're connected
to the wild world there on your,
you cannot remove the
wild world from Colorado.
Like when you're driving through town in
Evergreen, there's these photos of, uh,
like elk herds that w Mosey through town,
hundreds of elk thousand
pound wild animals,
wild cattle basically. Right?
That's what they're like.
And they're moving through the butterflying
forest and walking down the mainstream,
clogging up traffic. I mean, it's
a trip. I was in Ohio one time,
I was swimming and uh,
um,
I watched these poor purposes
like I could, I could not,
I could hear them because they were
probably 50 feet away and they just passed
me.
Not Dolphins,
but those huge purple porpoises
just and one I'm surface
and breathe through. It's a, and
I just felt so insignificant.
It was like a locomotive,
like it just a bunch of locomotives
just gliding through. It was crazy.
So I called to them,
I'll do the trip about dolphins is
that they're so intelligent and they,
and they have wars with each other
and you can see it when you're,
you're looking at them. There's like
there's some weird connection when you're,
when you're communicating with a dolphin,
when you look,
if you're buy a boat and they're jumping
up and looking at you like when they're
trying to play with you and have fun
with you, like one there's like you,
you connecting to them somehow or another
cause like I think what's interesting
about the more intelligent the
animal, for example, chimpanzees,
even even certain birds
but especially dolphins,
the more organized and more
violent they are with each other.
Like a dolphins will
wage war on other door,
Dolphin pods and kill entire pods.
And they didn't know that until they
created this documentary on it where they
actually have they sent out like warring
parties. It's exactly like chimps.
If chimps have one area of a forest and
there's another family of chimps and
another area,
they'll send mails out that we'll look
for other males when the other and kill
him.
It's crazy. Yeah. We're not the only ones
that do Warren animal kick. Not at all.
Not at all. That's why I've
always said to people, man,
you gotta be really careful about
wanting the butterflying aliens to land.
Just look at the history of what every
smart thing has done to everything.
Not as smart all over earth.
Every single opportunity nature
has had to express itself.
The, the stronger, smarter
things. Fuck the weaker thing.
That's the argument against technology
in some ways for a lot of computer
scientists,
when you start creating computers that
are smarter than we are and they start
making computers smarter than they are,
which is,
and then they'd start developing what's
called will, uh, that the question is,
are they going to have a respect
for the biological heritage?
Yeah. I mean, look all over. The what?
The intelligent animals that we know.
Chimpanzees eat monkeys. All
right. Killer whales eat dolphins.
They kill and eat dolphins,
man,
and we do whatever the butterfly we want
to do to everything underneath us.
Why would it,
what are we expecting the aliens to be
so evolved that they're past the whole
rule of nature that expresses itself
over and over again wherever we are.
Everything that's intelligent takes
advantage of everything that's not as
intelligent. Absolutely.
It's just the way it was.
Not as strong or not as power and human
beings do it to other human beings. It.
Dot. Yeah. You know,
why wouldn't we expect the aliens to just
be coming down here and just butterfly with
us? I think it's a will to power. I think
it exists. I don't know. I'll be ready.
Brian,
what would you do if the aliens landed?
What would you do if it all turned
out to be real and that we have been
monitored from space by
invisible Aircrafts that
well, it depends what, how they come.
Like if they just slowly land and go like,
Hey, I'm an alien. I just landed, I would
probably be like, hey, what's going on?
You know? But if they just like blow
up, it'd be funny if they were really,
they were really had to come back
to, hey guys, what's going on?
Where the aliens Auntie,
nothing will,
you know,
they got to a point where they realized
they had to step in because we were
butterflying up the resources of this world
so bad that they had to reveal them
again. It would have to be
their body language, you know?
If they're like just coming
up to me going like, hey,
we're going to have to step in
here. You guys are like, okay,
I guess you could do I try it
again. Try it out, go for it.
I'd ask him to just
think about jet travel.
I'm going to take less time
to travel across the country.
You don't want it to take less time. It's
good right now. It's only a day, dude.
Relax everybody. Let's not butterflying
start teleport in each other.
Halfway from here to there.
Thailand was like 27 hours.
I don't know what that was.
Was there like weird,
like just things everywhere you went
around there. Yeah. Bangkok's interests
saint because it's like
this very, very, um, hot,
hot tropical city with a lot of
pollution and a lot of people,
it's just chaos.
But what's interesting,
and if you're in the underage sex for 60
bucks, then you know, more power to you.
But I'm not into that stuff or
I am, but I feel so guilty. Uh,
no, no. But I played, uh, you
know, the owner of a strip club.
So we shot a lot of those scenes in, in
the sex district, the red light district,
which is you play a new
person and you were, yeah,
I mean, I, I'm wearing a
wig. He and I, it's very
much the same.
Anytime Phyllis loves that character.
And I shouldn't say much more than that,
but, but, um, it, it was so much fun, man.
And I think,
I really think it's gonna be hilarious.
I think it's going to be just as funny as
far as awesome. Yeah. I mean it was so,
they just so went for it in every aspect.
I think they're going to
do the same with this man.
I was so impressed with just watching
the credits were butterflying fast.
God and Paul Giamatti is in reality.
He's just hilarious.
And he was the deal with that Chinese guy.
That's not really his penis.
I can CGI, you should have
him on the podcast by the way.
He's a great guy and he loves you. But
I, I'm actually talked to him about you,
but um, uh, that is, I'm not
going to make a comment on that.
I'm not sure if that's his actual,
I'm a big fan of him too and I, yeah,
I've seen him talk about it that he,
that really was, it was such a good guy.
Is He? Oh, he's a great last one.
He's a real doctor practitioner,
a practicing doctor. Holy
Shit in Calabasas, I think
that's where it was. And he,
he's,
he's a straight up doctor and then started
just taking acting classes and doing
stand up and he's just
hilarious and fearless and he
just hasn't stopped working
and he was so grateful for where he's
at and he can't believe it. He's like,
I keep all of this, but he's
fearless man. He doesn't care.
He'll take his clothes off. He's just,
you know, just funny, funny, funny.
So how did he, how did he break out
of being a doctor? He was just like,
I don't really like
man a doctor that much.
When he was acting and doing all these
movies, he was still, he had a practice.
He was still doing like, you know, yeah,
he's his wife as a practicing
doctor to holy shit.
How many people are like that? They just
wanted to do something else with their,
butterflying never went for it.
He said they got stuck when it turned
it around that much. Most people, man,
I know. And then a guy like
that who actually says, I'm
going to, you know what?
Thanks a lot for medical school debt.
I'm going to be an actor. You know, why?
What are you talking about?
You got to practice now I'm going to,
I'm going to chuck this in and I'm going
to become a movie star. He's good man.
He'll be working forever. Forever. He's
your go to guy for sure. He's hilarious.
And he's really fun to work with.
That's the other thing I'm starting to,
I was like the guys that work a
lot like Giamatti and those guys,
they're just really good people.
Right? Just a blast. They just,
they're just very giving, you know,
they're just, they listened to you,
they react to you. They just, they're,
they're just happy to be there and
not cynical about it. Kevin James, um,
I did his movies,
zookeeper and his whole staff,
like everybody who was working on the
movie is so friendly. Oh, they're great.
Like so nice. And everyone is like
really appreciative of everyone.
It's just a nice fun working environment
and it's like seamless because of that.
And I'm Kevin's that way. Kevin's
a regular guy comes, right?
It all comes down from him, but it's
like, it makes things so much better.
You know,
you really like when you're working with
people that appreciate what's happening
and appreciate what they're doing and
appreciate each other, you know, fun,
positive environment. It's
called perspective. That's
why reading like history,
instead of being like,
not talking about intellectual,
but just getting a sense
of what came before you
and how most people throughout all of
history lived short, miserable lives,
lives because they didn't have
access to, I dunno, uh, antibiotics,
vaccines, uh, cat scans, all the things
that let us go beyond Abazi running water.
I mean, it just goes on and on and so, you
know, you'd lose three of you are like,
Lincoln lost his kid to a
fever. You know, how many,
how many famous people
have lost their children,
three of their children at a time to,
you know,
things like diptheria and stuff we
don't even, we haven't even heard of.
And so when you have a perspective of
how lucky you are as just somebody with
WHO's never missed a meal,
for example, or who are,
doesn't have to do anything to
get what they want, you know,
just stay warm and stay safe and have
representative government. There are,
there's nothing to complain
about. Nothing man. Well,
there's certainly something to complain
about because got to evolve and get
better.
She can be satisfied with the way it is.
That's what it's completely butterflyed up.
I want to know about all this crazy
wikileak shit. You know, it's uh, uh, the,
the, the, yeah and, and the
debate. Here's an interesting,
well before you say anything,
there's an interesting story that came
up from the New York or rolling stone
magazine said if the New York Times
had received the same information,
which is basically all wikileaks did,
would, would we be prosecuting them?
That's the fundamental question is this,
you had a private who made
all this information available
and the private was in
direct violation of military
code that that when you,
when you join the mill and
take an oath and what that,
that private could be tried for treason
because what he did is he took sensitive
information, not top secret but
secret information and he let it end.
He just basically deliberately leaked it.
Now I agree with Julian, Julian Assange,
he, if it's proven in court, and this
is probably going to be the defense,
the defense is platform. If
Julian Assan just said, look,
I was given this information and I
provided a platform for that information,
not unlike the, and this is exactly what
the New York Times did they provide.
Now the New York Times,
what they did was they actually,
they actually edited out certain names
of people that could be put into harm's
way if it was found out that they were
helping the enemy in those countries.
So in other words, if the CIA has
certain people we pay to get information,
as soon as their names are put out on
the Internet, they are, they can be,
their lives can be a danger because the
host country or the country that they
belong to or that they're
betraying or whatever,
they would put them in jail or kill
them or whatever it might be. So,
so that's where,
that's where the dilemma really,
because we're really comes when you just
dump a bunch of information out, uh, it,
it can have representation
to the names of operatives.
The New York Times did the wikileaks did
know Julianne songs just took all that
Info and just let it out really.
So he let out names of operatives at
different countries and he even gave,
he even gave a social security numbers
and addresses of soldiers and stuff like
that. And the problem with
that is that, you know,
there's one side of the
argument that says, look,
there's got to be transparency and
if you're, if you're an operative,
if you work for the CIA, there's always
that risk, you're going to be compromised.
Okay, that's one idea. But
the other issue is how,
why we're all for transparency.
I certainly am.
I'm for transparency of government. That's
important. You don't want to give any,
any agency in government too much
power because like any human beings,
just about natural human instincts,
they just become their own gang
and they get as much power.
And that's what's the brilliance of
the founding fathers was creating all
different departments that are
competing against each other.
The State Department has their agenda and
they're always trying to undermine the
department of Defense.
Department of Defense has its own
problems with the executive and it just,
and that's a beautiful thing because it,
it,
it doesn't let anybody have too much
power. But, but at the end of the day,
if you're going to take just a bunch
of Info and just dump it in some ways I
think it has, it's first of
all, it's spiteful and I'm
not sure what the point is.
If you want transparency,
that's one thing,
but if you're going to be
that irresponsible and put
people's lives at stake who
are trying to do a good word,
personal information and they're trying
to do good work out there. You know,
when I was in Afghanistan,
those guys,
most of those soldiers I was around were
building hospitals and schools say what
you will about the war and say we'll
about the motives and things, but and,
and there's an intelligent debate to
be had about the United States and not
getting involved in other countries
affairs. We've heard these things,
but the point becomes what are you trying
to accomplish when you dump all that
information out there and what one of
the repercussions might very well be that
government agencies have a tough time
getting information from valuable sources
overseas,
whether it's in cases of espionage or
whether it's case of national security.
A lot of people now are going to go,
I don't want to talk to you, dude,
I talked to you and I might get leaked
because you have no guarantee that you
can keep these correspondence secret.
It's one thing to embarrass politicians.
It's one thing that Vladimir Putin is
called a guy who doesn't have as much
control over as government. All right,
we'll get over that diplomatically.
It's another thing when very valuable
sources of information for the United
States all of a sudden are compromised.
And then field operatives who are
trying to make the world a safer place,
all of a sudden have very tough time
recruiting anybody because nobody wants
people to, like I tell you a secret man
and my name now is all of a sudden on, on,
you know, uh, in the New York
Times, no thanks. Or it's on,
it's on the web and on a website and my,
and the people that I'm betraying,
that's the first thing.
That's the first place they look and
they come to my house and kill me and my
family. Nah, sorry. Find
another guy. I'm not, I'm not
working for you. So that, that,
that that becomes an issue and
there are a lot of other issues.
I think that we haven't really even,
we'll see what this, what this means,
that these things take time.
The ripple effect takes some time.
Do you think that there's
any way that the private,
the guy who leaked the information,
the guy who you know in effect,
committed treason,
does any way that you could argue that
if he thought that there were agregious
offenses that were being
ignored and swept under the rug,
that it would actually be
unpatriotic to not report them?
It's a very good question.
It's a question that was raised with the
Pentagon papers. It's a question where,
when, when it's tricky,
right? Well sometimes the,
your government is saying that we're not
bombing Cambodia and you start finding
out that we're doing, we're doing
exactly that in violation of it might be,
you know, this is the whistleblower
is a whistleblower at debate.
It all depends on whistleblowers always
going to have to take responsibility for
the fact that there are people in the
government that needs to betrayed,
that are going to call him a scumbag
and tried to prosecute him. I do think,
I think that's a very,
very good question.
I do think that sometimes you are
in a position where you are privy to
information that is either unjust,
illegal or um,
but there are channels, there are also
channels and our government to go through.
Uh, sometimes you think to yourself the
press might be the last resort. There,
there are other legal channels
that the military provides. Um,
and uh, it's a good question. Uh,
it's a really good question, man.
I do think that you have a responsibility
as a human being when you see grave
injustice. I don't think in
this case that was the case.
I don't think this private, um, saw
anything grossly injustice back.
Do you think he's just, he just,
it was impulsive. Like what do you,
why do you think he did? Uh, you
know, I butterfly that's him. That's him.
Let's ask him. Just ask him like hold
or drinking coconut water.
Listen, you don't want to
give her a heads. See Two oh,
coconut water. I love
it. No, what is that?
It's a really hard to find coconut
water. I like that. It's clear there's a,
there's a Amy and Brian's too
that can be found on that.
Why is this hard to find? I don't know.
It's just really popular or it's just,
it's 100% natural, new and tonics.
Sorry about that. Ladies and gentlemen,
we were in the middle of fascinating
butterflying conversations. Like God damn,
phone has to ring. But that's a, that's
a really good question. And whenever,
you know, um, you know, an institution
of power, it's tricky, right? It's like,
you know, look what is this this nation
founded on the nation is founded on,
here's a very good question.
Here's a very good question.
What does that founded on true?
If we go back to 2003 and you had very,
very good information that there
were no weapons of mass destruction.
For example, if you had top secret
information that, um, that, that,
for example,
we've had,
we have no evidence whatsoever that there
are any weapons of mass destruction,
yet an entire nation is being
sold a bill of goods red.
Let's just take that as an example.
Okay. And you knew for sure,
because by the way, in 2002, nobody
had any idea. Nobody was really saying,
even on the National Security Council,
on the United Nations Security Council,
nobody was saying Saddam Hussein didn't
have weapons of mass destruction.
They were saying, where are they?
That's what they were saying.
We all assumed he had met in the weapons
of mass destruction because he'd used
them on the Kurds in the nineties
poison gas, not just poison gas,
but germ warfare as well. So we had, we
had documented evidence and you're not,
and, and the United States,
United Nations corroborated this.
It wasn't just US intelligence,
but we had documented evidence that he
had used and killed a large number of
Kurdish men, women, and children
with, with these horrible weapons. So,
so in 2002, when you say, when,
when Bush was saying, look,
this guy has the fourth
largest army in the world. Um,
he's acted very responsibly. Started three
wars, two with Iran, one with Kuwait,
uh, which resulted in a million
people, the dead on both sides.
This guy miscalculates all the time.
You tell me what's,
what's to stop them from dropping a weapon
of mass destruction into an enemy of
ours? Hands anonymously, like okayed.
Okay. It was a very, it was a, that was a,
that was a debate that they talked
about in the war room. Bush says,
you know what? The guy's got
weapons of mass destruction.
Let's make a play. Let's,
let's, let's bring it up in the, to the,
to the United Nations and we're going to
war. If this guy doesn't cough them up.
Now let me ask you something.
If you're,
what are, you talked
about? What is going on?
Hold, please hold. Ladies and gentlemen,
I hope you're taking notes because
I don't know what I'm talking about.
Story is haunted dude.
Do you think coconut water is gonna
become so big that they're just going to
like, they're like coconuts
are going to become rare,
like we're going to eat all the
coconuts off the planet? No,
I don't because I don't think
it's that popular. What if,
because I mean is that
something that we could run out?
I don't know what happened there folks.
I have my volume turned off.
There's obviously a
butterflying ghost in my house.
Sit in the office late and gentlemen,
the government,
the government is letting me know I
can turn up your volume anytime I want.
It's the comedy store, abortions,
ghosts, but he's traveling.
But here, here's the final
point. Here's the point.
The point and we'll move on is if you,
if you were in a position and you work,
you are a field operative.
You are a CIA guy who were in a panic
on and whatever and you knew for a fact
that there were no weapons
of mass destruction or at
least there was no evidence.
But to divulge that information would be
to compromise certain national security
secrets. Would you do it? My,
my feeling would be that you should do
it might be like feeling would be that if
you're going to stop a war from
happening cause there's no evidence,
then maybe you should say something that
you're a butterflying George Clooney moves
you guys.
You're a god Damn George Clooney movie.
I don't have enough hair to be George
butterflying you can to to give you some shit.
They put some stuff in. You know
what? They dust my head. Bruce Willis,
important way. Bruce was shaved his
head. He doesn't give a butterfly dude.
You could do it man.
This is the movie.
This is the breakout hit gas
less gentlemen. Your stop it.
You're going to stop the war. He's
the guy that talks too much. He's old.
It's an alternate world,
an alternate version of our life.
If you had stopped the war,
if you had known there was no
weapons of mass instruction,
you get on TV and you change the world,
they believe you,
and then it shows what we're really like
now in 2010 or 1111 but it used to that.
That's what's funny is if
you had all the answers,
you had all the secrets and how would,
when people really listen to think
you're an idiot. Shut up stupid. Right?
Well that's what Judah
thought about Jesus, man.
That's what they thought about Jesus.
Unless you can provide produce miracles
right there and then even then they're
like, that's a trick. There's
something fascinating about this.
Looking back to a time when
someone had it all butterflying nailed,
we've always done it. It's weird. It's
nostalgia for the, what is that called,
the good old days.
Do you think that Dan is,
because there's been a bunch of different
versions of civilization that things
have crashed and gotten terrible
and then gotten better and crashing,
gotten terrible,
so they've always looked back to when
things were great before it crashed.
It's like almost like an
ethic. It's almost like the
way we think, well, you know,
like, uh, they were talking
about it, uh, this, this
fundamentalist Islamic movement.
It's a very new thing in Islam and this,
this extreme extremes who believed that,
you know,
they always look back when Mohammed
created Islam and that was the golden age
and it was where everything was perfect
and stuff like that. And it just,
I think that some,
I maybe it's,
I think sometimes people will know what
started it. What started the, the most,
the most extreme movement now?
Well,
a lot of it came from what they
w hobby sect of Islam, which, uh,
was in Saudi Arabia and
continues to be in Saudi Arabia.
It's a puritanical form of Islam.
But, um, this is a long debate.
I don't want to say anything to you but,
but I mean certainly I think one of the,
one of the,
one of the things that caused
Islamic fundamentalism was I think,
I think Islamic fundamentalism, like
anything else, it's an idea that was,
that was born out of a bunch of men who
basically felt lost and insignificant
and needed something to make
themselves feel. Um, uh,
I guess cohesive and important. And you
know, whenever you look back in this,
this is what I was trying to
say about when you look back,
usually when people look
back on the good old days,
I think it's a natural reaction.
It's usually because you're connected
to something that's trying to revive
something. You're trying to
revive something. And when
you look back at, you know,
whenever you talk about,
well back in the day with Connie,
here's with martial arts a lot back in
the day those Kung Fu masters cause walk
on water.
They could fly through the air.
I think it's like kind of like before
things were contaminated that when they
first came out they were
pure and throughout the
ages they become compromised
and contaminated.
That's a human thing we do instead of
realizing the things actually evolve and
get better usually, uh, we, we like to
look at like when things first came,
when they were first born,
if there's a purity to it and we got to
get back to that purity because we've
lost our way. And I think
that's why people look back
on history and kind of say,
boy, back in the day when, when,
when the mailman came and the Milkman
came and it was just so great and you have
to walk the streets without
anybody killing you are
murdering you and it's all,
it's all a lie. It's all, it's all
horse shit in my opinion. It's all like,
you know, looking back on
the good old days when you
know, things weren't so good,
things are actually really
inconvenient and really difficult.
You didn't have things like,
you know,
the Internet and access to
information immediately. Sure.
It comes with its own problems. But
we live for the most part. Most of us,
even in the past 30 years,
live a much better life.
And I'll give you two examples. I
mean, China and remember China was,
was an Russia for that matter.
And most of those countries couldn't,
they couldn't leave their own country.
Those were communist countries
with very strong central authority.
Is it controlled everything you did?
Uh,
Latin America was all
military dictatorships. Now
they're all democracies.
So I mean, you know, when people look
back on the old days, I'm always like,
I dunno man. You know, you haven't
been studying history too much because
it wasn't all the old days can
suck my dick. Correct that correct.
Even old cars suck. I like just an
old car when I used to widdle. Yeah.
An old car with a carburetor. It got like
a block, a gallon at always broke down.
They look awesome. They sound stupid.
Right? They just so ridiculously dumb.
The drive, and they were
really, really dangerous. They
didn't have airbags. I mean,
you went through those windshields,
man,
you lost your head and those
breaks were bunks on those breaks.
Barely stopped those cars.
Big stupid drum brakes in the back.
We were just driving around in death
machines right now we have abs brakes,
we got computers,
we got everything.
It's amazing that people survived having
those stupid cards didn't most of the
time you had kids riding in the front
seat with those lashed out butterflying hey put
on your lap belt everybody. I'm in the
backseat. I don't need my seat belt.
And you're driving around in this
huge rectangle of metal. Forget it.
Barely loosely connected to stupid tires
that are screeching around every corner
and goes my transmission he cars,
they would take a turn and you would hear
their tire squeal cause they're barely
hanging onto the road with this shitty
pizza you get in an accident and all you
got to run into is steel and
glass. Not even, not even like,
not even that crushed glass.
It's just like that big shards of
glass cars today are the defy physics.
You know, don't really, but they
feel like they do Ralph Nader.
You can thank him for that. He was the
spearhead for all that. Ralph Nader.
That's not do for Shit. How
about that? Ralph Nader was like,
cars are dangerous and I'm going
to do something about it. He,
a lot of people got pissed off by that
guy when he was running for president.
I said that's,
that sort of revealed who he really is.
Well, yeah, because he
took away, he took votes.
Crucial votes away from
the Democrats though.
Yeah. There was that idea and there was
also the idea that, well, what else?
Who gives a butterfly about politics?
Politics.
Motherbutterflyer's saying the Ralph Nader
is the one responsible for it all.
Well, Ralph Nader is, Ralph Nader was
the guy who said, you know, these,
these cars are,
I think he started a thing called unsafe
at any speed or something. And uh,
I think that's what it was.
I might be wrong, but Ralph
Nader basically said, look,
we've got a lot of people dying needlessly
and it's ridiculous getting paralyzed
and stuff because cars are not safe.
They're dangerous.
And there's a way we have the
technology to make cars safer. You know,
letting Mercedes Benz invented the airbag.
Okay.
Let told everybody.
So, so it's Brody Stevens. Was
He over there? Yes, he was. Yes,
he was late and gentlemen,
Brody Stevens going crazy over there.
Brody Stevens going crazy.
Did he bring his dog?
Uh, he did not bring, the
dog did not bring a stop,
but I was going to say that I want to
buy a Mercedes next because I found that
Mercedes invented the airbag and
gave it to every other car company.
They gave it to them because they realized
that was the moral and ethical thing
to do.
So you're going to buy a Mercedes because
of that or because you want to go big
pimpin sons.
I want to go big.
Pimpin would you buy like one of those
big sled like Mercedes or would you buy
like the little two door? I want to be, I
don't know, man. That's a good question.
Maybe I want to buy.
I should butterflying know what you want to
buy something that drives well you give a
butterfly about that or do you
think that when you don't care,
how about safety for me now
I want to try it out. Yeah.
That's the best safety and
comfort. Yeah. I like an SUV,
so if somebody hits me, I'm not
dying. They want to, I want a horse.
I think horses are sexy.
Talk to me about what I want.
Plenty horse store this horses
in my neighborhood near the dam.
I'm driving and I swore to God,
I'm not speeding.
I am not even remotely spitting.
I am a leisurely driving down the street
and there's a lady in front of me with
the horse and a, I'm
nowhere near them. Okay,
I'm hundred yards away and
the horse starts freaking,
just does a like a little freak move,
like a little freak move and the butterflying
lady with the horse and her friend look
at me and just start doing this thing.
Waking up and down
and I swear to you,
making the horse is more of,
you're not even going 25 miles an hour.
I'm not,
I'm not even going so slow.
I'm just relaxing.
I'm just driving and this horse just sees
a car coming and it starts bucking and
these gigantic man like arms cause to
everyone and women who are into horses.
They're all the same. First
of all, they're all blonde.
They all have cinder block heads and
they all have these squat football player
bodies and they're butterflying stupid boots,
funniest leather boots that go up to
their knees to butterfly you shared there
weren't going to like pimps up hoes down.
She was mad at,
I swear to God I was nowhere near this
horse. If I had done a douchey thing,
I'm a big fan of animals, but I'd done a
douchey thing. I would, I would admit it.
I put, it was ridiculous. It was
just me driving and all of a sudden
fund money.
Funniest horror story I just heard
a couple of days ago, my buddy,
what had they found this,
he's fine now,
but they found a benign tumor
growing out of his spinal cord.
He had back problems. She here so he's
like, what's going on? And he's been,
he was a pro athletes up and they
went and they go, dude, you got to,
you got a tumor growing out of your spine.
He has since had it removed and it was a
really successful operation and stopped
by these team of really good time. But
anyway, so he's, he's all bunched up.
He's like a tumor in my day. Like,
yeah, we have to take it out.
It's very delicate procedure.
You could have some paralysis and
he's dealing with all this knee,
doesn't know what to do. He's
like, oh, this is terrible.
So he's driving in Marina del Ray and
he's down this alleyway and he's like kind
of in a daze. Like, what am I going
to do? I've got to, this is crazy.
Thank God I have health insurance,
but I don't know what I'm going to do.
They've got to cut into my spinal cord
and he's just completely out of it.
Out of nowhere, out of nowhere as he's
like contemplating his own mortality,
he just sees and these huge eyes
and nostrils and this horse,
this massive horse runs ed his
car and he it on the slant.
He's going really slow anyways
down and now he stops the horse,
jumps over his car,
breaks the windshield,
but Denzler does $3,000 worth of
damage on his new car and then run runs
over the roof. Good, good,
good, good, good, good. So if
he does, he, he's good. Good,
good.
She crushed and she'll
run over as bar runs.
It was a police horse
that had gotten spooked.
It got spooked by somebody
who threw a firecracker and,
and all of a sudden the horse
ones and he sees like 16
cops like,
oh come running around the corner and
now they're running at him and he's like,
what the butterfly is going on? And they
just do see the horse. He goes,
look at my butterflying car. And now he's
like trying to get them to pay for his,
you know,
his basically his car is pretty butterflying
crazy that they're were and animals.
Yeah. 2011 it's for
crowd control. Come on.
Why are you riding animals?
Christmases in Lord of the Rings Brahms
everyday because I live in a
question and district and so there's,
this horse is coming over my patio
like scaring my dog all the time.
I mean I live in like horse
world. It's crazy. I didn't get,
how do you get on the mounted police?
Is that a promotion or is that a demotion
that you get made fun of by the other
guys on the motorcycles and
write for dudes? It's really
uncomfortable for girls.
Apparently riding horses
can give you Oregon.
You can blind it upright and
listened. I had, I had sex with this.
I had sex with this horse girl
in London. Tough Lips. Ah, it was
good in the stable by the way.
The smell of horses and leather
and my Dick. Holy Shit, Alexei,
smell that all together.
I smelled the VA should offer a few of
my ticks and I was like, Hey, and saddle,
that
ghost is living in my by Brian Calla.
It sounds like, uh, sounds like a
butterflying Cologne. I said, dude, 50 cents.
Got a quote and that's what
you need. Horses. Smell that.
You smell that Horse Hay and Dick.
It's my new Cologne called Horse Hay Day.
Hope you don't mind sponsoring.
We spotted the Joe Rogan podcast.
Might be the only Cologne I'd be
willing to. Where you want to smile?
You want to smell it?
Horse. He would wear,
I would wear that shit and I spell
out there. My natural chimpanzee,
I'd Spell Dick was three I's.
Dig with a hyphen.
Then at the end of it probably Jake
gently touch the tip of your penis through
your pants.
Talking about dementia.
That's my favorite,
you know, question district. I live in it.
There's these people that have
those little ponies and it's like,
and I'm just like, who are these people
that buy these minimum opponents?
Prance around yet. Yet he's a little
horse. It just walk around with, oh,
they're show ponies.
That's what they're really affectionate.
Those little things and there are great,
butterfly, whoa. What? Hey, wait a minute. Hey,
we've been through this before.
Have you ever thought about getting one?
Joe's what I'm asking because I've
loved it. If you had a little show. No,
there's a guy across the street
from me that's got a horse stall.
You can get one that's kind of a trip
walk by his house and this is China animal
in his yard. I love the ride.
You ride them. They're just going
to be there,
a pet them and they eat.
That's the weirdest thing. They just
wander around. They don't do shit.
If it's like dogs, I
have a yard, dogs are,
they're always out there playing and
chasing a squirrel or something and it's
like fill a cart. They're having a good
time out there. But if you have a horse,
they just stand there. It looked
for something neat and just move.
Move a little over here.
You could butterfly them, Jo. Brian,
you know you don't butterfly courses.
Did you watch the video we played
yesterday? Horses. Fuck you pal. You know,
butterfly them. You are the
conversation killer. My brother.
The mouth can butterfly you dude.
There's some good,
could you imagine sticking your Dick
in a horse? Have you ever felt it?
It's soft as an ass. Does fat
like a baby's butt? Have you ever,
it would be perfect. Yeah.
You mean the lips? Yeah,
those turpines says flat grass
stain teeth got ahold of your,
snapped it off it like a base.
It likes carrots, tickets,
teeth out. Oh, shut the butterfly up bro. I be
great. We could crush you just to bone.
Even without teeth out
teeth that would crush you.
It was my mother got bitten by a horse.
Okay. My mother got bit right. Right,
right in the shoulder by a horse
and the fun bit and she was like,
it was the worst thing she'd ever had.
A what for what reason? Horses by you.
If a horse doesn't like you or
horses fearing scared of territorial,
they'll bite you with those horse
teeth and butterfly you up. Correct.
Oh, last time I was on a horses because
I got bucked and I haven't been on one
sentence and that was one of
the most scariest things ever.
Getting butterflying a horse. It's
freaking out and just bucking you off.
Flying in the CROC or I'm riding
since I grew up riding horses,
I'm still scared of him. Fuck, butterfly.
Big giant animals that you ride since
2011 just stupid. I'm just kidding.
I hate horses. That was the best,
the best that my buddy, my buddy Bob,
that that real tough dude. I always tell
you about it. I went to him, I said,
he does everything you need rides, bulls
and stuff like that and I've seen him,
I have video of him riding a bull lock,
both knock both his teeth out and
he was like, whatever stayed on it,
stayed on in any way.
Didn't get off. He plays,
he plays that poker thing
where you play poker in a bowl.
They let a bull out and the last guy
to get up though, butterfly plays that.
He's always the last guy up. I have
video of that. He's the last guy up.
The other guys don't,
everybody's like runs and he's like,
he gets up casually like eh, whatever like
that. And I said to him one time, I go,
I go, can you a ride a horse? He looked
at me, I guess I'll break a horse bro.
I break old. Dead serious.
Like he was insulted.
I asked him if he could ride when he
butterflying break a wild horse. I know.
How would you do that? He goes, I butterflying
ride it until it butterflying listens to me.
That's how I get, that's how I do that.
I was like, you're a butterflying bad ass
work. Well, the horse just
gives up and becomes your,
now you have to break that. You break a
horse on a line, you, you, you have it.
You teach it at a run in a circle and you,
you have it on a line.
So if they get a wild horse, they really
can break a wild horse. If someone can,
you could lasso a wild.
Yeah, but there's a technique to it. You
have to unity have you don't get on it.
At first you, you tether
it, you tether it to a,
like a mine and you and you
and you teach it how to run.
How does it not just stomp the butterfly out
of you? It does. A lot of times they will,
but you got to, you have a whip
and you keep them in. I mean,
it's somebody who really knows what
they're doing. You got to whip it.
Did people still do that in this day and
age? You still try to tame wild horses?
Well, you have to break a horse.
Wears a wild horse these days.
Where are you finding no,
I wouldn't find packs of wild horses
and hang out with the trip courses are
indigenous, I believe originally
in the Gobi desert of um,
of Nepal. I mean, I'm of a, of Mongolia.
So that's where horses, yeah, that would,
that's where the wild asses came from
and all that. So I believe that the,
the original, the original horse, um,
that's where they were originally, uh,
from the steps of Asia. So did they come
over here on boats? They came over here.
They think when the, I
need to know Zach. Zach,
in fact,
um,
the native Americans didn't ride
horses from what I understand at first,
those were brought over by Spaniards,
by the Spaniards. And so, um,
well that's how the
whole deal with the ink,
the ink is thought they were gods
because they were riding horses.
They were pretty amazing.
Where God's like, they had
no idea what the butterfly was up.
You imagine you see somebody riding a
huge horse, an animal you'd never seen.
He'd be like, what the butterfly is that?
That's why I always try. When I ride,
I was riding naked just so that they,
so I looked like a Centaur.
You do look like a sentence. Yeah.
I never know where to put my balls.
I just rested on its butterflying backbone when
I need side first guy to ride a horse.
Must have been a bad mother butterflyer. That's
what I mean. How about the first guy?
I decided,
you know what?
I'm going to write a butterflying book dares
mates who dares me throw eight. No,
let's go further.
Throw a testicle,
cinch on that butterflying bull and tie my
risk to it and I'm going to butterflying see
how long I can stay on it.
They tie.
You got to tie your risks
of that butterflying thing.
That's why when they fall off and they
get caught and they're being flopped
around like a ragdoll and stomp.
Yeah. Have you ever seen him get stock
guys die that way? No. Why didn't
you have to tie yourself on?
Why do you have to find,
can you just hold on?
I don't know what a piece of it like
part of the macho thing you got to tell
yourself mom, cause that's how you
stay on the bull on. You can't hold on.
You know when it's moving like
that buddy of mine, listen to this.
You want to hear some crazy shit.
I forget what branch of,
whether it's a rangers or what
branch of the special certain forces,
whatever you have to do.
He was talking about when he bailed out
of the system and this was what they
were going to have these guys do,
they were going to tie them together.
They hog tie them and throw them in the
water and then you die and then bring
you back and they bring you back.
The navy seals that that's
what the seal teams doing what?
That's his butterfly dude.
They want you to be willing to drown and
be convinced that your boys are going
to go in there and dive in.
Once the bubbles stop by the way,
okay and no sooner the bubbles
stop. You go in, pull the guy out.
He's drowned.
You've pumped them out and rescue him
and give him CPR and bring them back to
life. They did the seal team, seal teams,
the seal team six apparently to wrap
your brain around that, but dude,
and that was it for him.
This is where I'm drawing the line.
I did not know you guys were going to
go here and I've never known that there
was, we were doing today. No bench press.
No running. You're going to die and
we're going to bring you back. Trust me.
Fuck Outta here. Fuck. I'll wake up
with you making out. Nah. Oh my God.
Could you imagine what must be
going through your head who,
we'll just dive in there. Hogtied
and drown. It's always that way.
It's back in the, I remember back in
the day they'd send you out with a,
with a line in the Masai Mara, the Masa
and in Kenya and the bound to they,
they'd send you out with a spear and
go, Hey, guess what you're doing.
You want to be a man?
Go kill a butterflying line with a spear.
And they said the real men would get the
line to charge him and is in line with
charge and jump. You let it
fall on the spear. Uh, yeah.
Jesus Christ or what if
you miss your butterflying dad.
I was at the MGM and it was last weekend
for the UFC and they have lions in the
middle of the casino.
Dude,
there's this big glass room and
there's this gigantic apex Predator.
It's and it's got a wall and it's whacking
the ball around and little kids are
sitting there staring at it, going
look and pointing did what I was doing.
I remember I was doing mad TV and I was
on the set and they brought a 525 pound
male lions on a chain and
if it was the lion they had,
they had done the drawing of line,
came over and they were wondering
why I wouldn't go near it.
I was up on the landing and they're
like, dude, it's tame. I was like,
butterflying shut up.
DNA kicks in and it looks at me like I'm
a gazelle. We're not a butterflying thing.
It's team. What does that mean?
It's 525 pounds to kitty cat.
It's still got its instincts full
intact and your hold your food.
It's one, maybe two generations
removed from the butterflying job,
man. What are you going to do?
Make yourself hard to swallow?
Now you sure that he's absolutely
exercise to the fullest so that he's not a
little uptight and tense. Right? Right.
Maybe he's having a bad traveling.
Might be freaking him out. That's
like elephants. That's like elephants.
Elephants kill their handlers, their
mock boots all the time. Elephants,
it's really interesting when you like,
cause when you're,
when you talk about breaking an animal,
they have to break an
elephant and it's awful.
They tie a a small elephant to like
steaks and they basically beat it.
I saw this thing, this
a documentary. They,
they'll break an elephant spirit problem
is that now you're riding your elephant
and the Ma,
it's in India.
It's like kind of a religious
thing and I think in Thailand they,
they will bathe it. They live with it.
They spend all their time, they feed it,
they bay that they clean it, and they
get very attached to their elephants.
That an elephant one day just decides,
you know what?
This is ridiculous.
You are a parasite on my back and I
don't butterflying feel like doing what you're
doing. So I'm going to
have, and they rage,
they'll go off and erase race and
when they get their handler, they,
a lot of times we'll just keep,
they'll,
they'll stomp them till he's jelly and
pull them apart with their tosca holding
arms off and shit. And you're not doing
a goddamn thing until he's done. Wow.
Making mincemeat for real out of you.
You know?
That's why no chimps, no
butterflying elephants. That's
the theme of this podcast.
Help me if a dog's
target humans in some
parts of the world too,
especially if they've lost
loved ones to come through,
they come through villages.
If they've lost loved ones to poachers,
they develop an attitude
and they developed a hatred
for humans and then they go
and attack and smash people's houses,
just smashed their houses and pull them
out. They're so big. And so powerful.
Your House is nothing. They just walk
right through your house. I mean,
literally just kicked down your front
door. Popey blowout, stabbed him to death.
It's crazy. They don't give a butterfly. No,
it's an algorithm. It's just so strange.
Even you think about Africa and the
quantity of gigantic things that can kill
you there. India too. You know, back
in the day, a lot of people tied.
There's the cobras.
A lot of people die that
way in the rural areas.
It's amazing when you look in Africa,
I mean it's one of the reasons why,
you know, like African culture, you know,
if you look at the rest of the world,
like all the inventions that have
come out, all these different places,
the most dangerous countries,
Africa,
and that's the place where like the
least amount of inventions, right?
It's like you don't have
time. No. You know, if you're,
if you're living in Africa,
you're actually growing up and
developing in Africa. You got butterflyed man.
You got dropped off in some place.
You're born in an area that's
filled with monsters. Aren't they?
More advanced and other monsters like
Kipling's woodworking and stuff like that.
I mean,
living their lives.
There was an awesome documentary
on the Congo and these, uh,
talked about these fishermen that,
that uh,
the literally from the
time that they're young,
they hang off trees and is it
a raging river underneath them?
And they've developed this
intricate system of, uh,
of nets that they create themselves.
They make their own rope using twine from
trees and shit like that. And they're,
they're hanging from these butterflying trees
over this raging river and it looks
like if they fall in their butterflyed, if the
very least you're going to get smashed,
you may very well drown.
I mean,
this is like some serious rapids and
they're scooping fish up as they do it in
the handing the nets up and
it's really butterflying complex.
And if you look at it
and said, well, you know,
they're very sophisticated for living
in this environment because if it was me
in that environment, how the butterfly am I
going to get a fish and this raging crazy?
See,
I'm not going to figure that shit out.
But it lived at the Masa in Africa.
And he told me that these dudes can tell
you the difference between like a blade
of grass and,
and what it means and what kind of animal
pass through and why that animal chose
that play of grass to eat.
And he said they're there.
They have an encyclopedic
knowledge of their environment.
And it's like anything else. Human beings
adapt and, and you know, they use their,
their minds for what is relevant to
their survival and their, their, um,
their flourishing.
They're probably,
it's a trippy thing. These are
tribal guys that a higher, uh, well,
Americans rather hired them to go and hunt
and they, uh, they take him to Africa.
Like there's, you know, there's
certain guy, game hunters yeah.
That want one of everything. They're like,
Ooh, last time I got a zebra, you know,
like they're shooting zebra.
She just stood that,
I never want to say that trophy hunting.
It's a strange to me. Very weird. Yeah.
I don't, I on one hand, you know,
it can be argued that hunting
actually pays to, uh, when,
when you pay for a hunting tags,
it pays to keep everything
healthy. Yeah. Because,
because if you manage the
environment, you put, if you put,
if there's a, if there's a profit
in your environment, so if you,
if you're making money off of,
off of hunting,
it's in everybody's interest
to preserve that. The,
you don't want to kill the
goose with the Golden Egg.
You want to keep the goose alive.
It goes towards money goes towards
management and conservation.
And that's a really tricky thing when
it comes to hunting. Even in America,
like I've had,
I've talked to so many people but hunting
and they have this crazy butterflying like
almost, you know, Disney
movie view of, of what,
what me eating meat is and what, you know,
meet where meat comes from. You know,
like, man, you don't want to do that.
You don't want to take some deer's life.
You want to do that. Like, do
you want understand leather
shoes? But first of all,
do you not understand that you have to,
do you understand that unless you want
a nation filled with mountain lions,
right? You have to kill the deer. Okay?
Cause otherwise you're
going to have no predators.
And then they're going to be sick. They're
going to starve to death everywhere.
They're going to be hitting
them with cars. They're gonna
die, miserable, horrible,
vicious deaths. You got to
call her. Yeah, you have to,
because otherwise they'll just,
I mean, it's a natural balance.
And in the way we've set up civilization,
we're not allowing any
predators around us, you know,
which is a pretty smart thing, right? So
because of that, you know, if you're not,
you've done a predators and
you have all these deer,
you have to butterflying shoot some of
ours. You've got to manage it. People,
they don't want me to mention the venison
is good. It's delicious, it's delicious.
Did the crazy idea that you're
not supposed to do that.
[inaudible] it's such a strange argument,
you know,
are these these butterflying deer gonna
live forever and cure cancer?
Like what are you talking about? Stupid.
You're going to die eventually anyway,
by the way, let's be honest. Their food, I
mean kind of the food. Yeah. Food shipped.
Beautiful. Yes, they are definitely
beautiful. I'm not saying eat all of them,
but you should shoot a few every year
there's a reason they're animals.
They're animals of of flight
because predators like a
minimalist look. Delicious.
Yeah. Did you punch a deer if it
wasn't an attack, you back, dude,
these are dangerous. Deers. Fuck
human talk. You back. Would you?
Why would I do that? I don't know why.
Don't want to hit it. I've had it.
You would have had if you had a
pet deer that would get you laid.
How you guys close? Want to pet my deer?
Every single girl in the world like
tamed it. Do you have a way with animals?
Do you remember that movie? Beastmaster?
Yes,
I do.
With dude who was like sculpted abs
and no shirts and he's just ready.
He's just in tune with all the animals of
all time. Ran a show of all time there.
I said
I butterflying lived the beastmaster.
What was his deal?
How was he selling tool with the animals
blow. I butterflying, I took his class.
I'll tell you,
we don't have time right now.
I took his workshop doctor due to what
workshop hit the beastmaster work.
She had a workshop. No doctor Doolittle.
You had me really excited. I was like,
I've got to go to this
workshop based mastery.
Well I had those two goddamn parents so
that was pretty much and two dogs and a
snake. What an asshole. I was. You've had
a bunch of crazy and my thirties I did
well. You know what man, if I could
have a children look a gigantic reserve,
how can my backyard, I know we've
talked about that before. A building,
some very thick wall managing it like
a zoo environment just to have a huge
chimpanzee I closed.
That's going to protect me.
Like I just want something on my next
to me all the time that just might,
you know, turn that may have
hard times. How would, how would,
how would a GSP do against
the chimp if you muzzle,
if you muscle that he couldn't bite you
with those butterflying, those mouth tasks.
Crush it. It would crush your bones.
They're talking to, dude, I was, I was in,
I was in the San Diego Zoo and I was
watching the mountain gorillas wrestle.
They're the best wrestlers on the plant.
Strong,
but they're also wrestlers that they
grow up wrestling did the babies,
all they do is wrestle all day and
they do good moves like Granby roles.
Real drags, real real is to
arm, arm drags, Granby roles.
I mean guillotines it's amazing. It's
incredible. Wow. I was literally,
I'm telling you I'm not kidding when I
say it, like ankle picks. Crazy shit.
Feigns docs. It's at the San
Diego Zoo. Go there, there, there,
and you can go right up still to the
glass and then there's the silver back.
Could just sits with his back to everybody
and you just look at this. 600 pounds,
six foot one gorilla, six
one 600 pounds. No Fat,
ladies and gentlemen. No fat
on it. He 600 pounds. Six one.
That's two of Brock Lesnar's.
Okay. I would love to watch them.
All he needs is Broccoli.
That's all he eats is butterflying grass.
Grass and bamboo sheets and shins.
Isn't that incredible, that,
that big and that strong and it's mostly
to keep everybody the butterfly away. Yeah.
Just let me butterflying eat.
Oh just let me sit here and
have some butterflying vegetables.
They were trying to figure out how strong
a mountain gorillas and they couldn't
figure it out,
but there was this log that took
like seven men to move cause they,
it was part of the exhibit
and the mountain gorilla
had a little tantrum and it
flung the log. It flung, it didn't
just throw it but full, you know,
when you fling something
it means it's really light.
Like don't fling that bottle at me.
It really is a trip that they're so
strong and all they do is eat vegetables.
Like what happened to the gorilla that
made it not want to just pick some animal
up and start eating at one day?
I don't know.
It's a weird to cause they're just
total her before is, you know. Yeah,
pretty much right there. I don't
think they eat any meat. Chimps,
chimps eat a lot of it. A lot of meat
chance organized hunting parties. Yeah.
I think we've talked about this
before on the show. You and I have,
I'm not sure if we have,
because it's a subject I can just don't
ever get tired of that so I never do.
I can't, I can go on
forever. Talking about,
Chad was talking about butterflying
hunting chimps all day.
Did I tell you went to a fake Fogo de
Chao the other day? A fake, a fake one.
It's called like Samba at universal
and forget a child if you've been there
where it's like all you can eat meat,
like there's come and
bring shit to Haas Korea.
So I sat there for half hour and the
only thing I got was a guy with a sausage
come over.
So I'm like getting kind of pissed and
I've told this the waitress like four
times. Like all right, I went to
Bacone, I want some kind of meat.
Have been here for 30
minutes. Right, right.
So then they get one come over with one
piece of meat and slice it off and send
it goes boom,
boom.
And all these dancers come out like these
Brazilian dancers and all them people
run away and you're just sitting there
watching this show for like 10 minutes
and then you come back and then it was,
it was the most like obvious,
like we only want you to eat a teeny
piece of meat and then we're going to go
over here and really like
I love,
I love a little dancing
with my meat better.
I was at a restaurant once when
they started doing that and I just,
I just was like, no, I don't want to
to pull me out of my chair. I'm like,
no thank you.
I'll take dancers any day over the
accordion and the guitar and that, that,
that sing.
Oh, it's going to let you know
when you're walking in the door.
I was in the Dominican Republic
with my family, by the way,
family vacations or the worst,
but anyway. Yeah, but I was
way rather have someone played music than
someone tried to pull you out of your
chair
dance. That's what this chick was
doing. Just like, come on. It was just,
it was just trying to step
up and down trying to,
it was just trying to confuse you so
you don't realize that you're not eating
meat. Say that you would get stuff and
then you get this headache stuffed because
there you're eating salad bars.
Okay.
I want you to notice to check 30
minutes once a month. I really love,
I just like Brazilian. Why don't you come
down for the UFC? UFC isn't August. Um,
I've seen him there. Okay. We're going.
Really? Yeah, we're going to Brazil. I'm,
I'm in there saying that now.
It's a,
yeah. I don't think the
card has been put in place.
Check through it cause it's quite
a ways away. It's an August.
I'm off to figure out who they're
going to fall over. Leave.
I'm pretty sure it's locked in. It's
coffee. Better in Brazil. Coffee. Yeah.
Brazil stone. Really known
for their coffee. No, no, no.
I always thought so because Columbia,
Hawaii,
Hawaii is the best coffee
resilience with big asses. Yes.
And toxo plasma.
That's the place where people were
infected by that cap of 66% of the people.
What you don't know about
this. Oh my brother. Got It.
You talked about it
yesterday unfortunately,
but I've been bringing up again because
you're going to freak the butterfly out.
I noted there is a,
there is a parasite called toxo plasma
and it's a cat parasite and it infects
rats.
And what it does to rats is it gets the
rats and rewires their sexual system and
has them attracted to
the smell of cat piss.
So these rats start going weird cat piss
is and like literally a testy swelled a
whole deal.
The cats eat them and now the cat has
this parasite and that's how it travels
from cat to rat. And it gets to
humans and it gets to humans.
If they touch cat shit or they touch it
when it's in the field and when it gets
in your system,
it does two things for women.
It makes them more sexually promiscuous
and it makes it more submissive.
And for men it makes it
more arrogant assholes.
And they even have correlated
it to successful soccer teams.
When you have the countries cause it
makes you so aggressive and so reckless.
And you look at countries
that are successful
in the World Cup also have very high
rates of Toxoplasma and their population.
I need to get some time.
Want to know you don't want it because
it slows your reaction time to either was
a doctor on, on, um, uh, there's a youtube
video. I really forget the guy's name.
I'll have to go over it again.
But it was a guy who was a
toxoplasma researcher who, uh,
used to work in the emergency room and
he found that when they tested people who
were motorcycle accident victims,
a disproportionate amount of them
were toxoplasma infecting wow.
And it made him reckless.
It makes you reckless and it may even
saw your reaction time. That's crazy.
It's really strange. But
it's a, it's a, you know,
it's a real brain altering parasite
that's affected 50 million Americans.
I just want to see what,
in 30 years when we've really kind of
got a lot of this biochemical chemistry
down and how our body's reacting kind
of pills they're going to come up with.
Are they going to be able to eradicate
something like this so you can figure out
a way to send nanobots in
there to kill all the question,
what the butterfly would they do?
How would you kill something that becomes
a brain parasite whenever people ask
these questions, you know what I'm
saying to myself? People say, well,
you know we're going to and we're
going to come up with different things,
but there's always going to be playing
all death and there's always going to be
these issues and new diseases
and new mutations and stuff.
Nobody's time is finite.
You just have to accept that.
I mean make use of it what you can
and keep it as healthy as possible,
but you must accept that it's fine. I know
I'm always working out though. My, my,
my buddy who's a writer and
doesn't do a lot of stuff,
but he's a kind of intellectual guy
and he's always looking at me and I'm
working out and I'm trying,
I'm doing my dead list and I'm
doing all this stuff and he's like,
look at the little man trying to stop
the clock trying to slow the clock tab.
Right. That's true. But you know what
man, it does one thing for me for sure.
It makes me like a blow stress
out and makes me see the world.
It makes me feel better.
I loud, I didn't exercise.
I know everybody thinks it's a vanity
thing and a lot of it is vanity. You know,
there's a lot of guys what you know,
you want to look good,
you want to look better,
you don't want to,
you don't want to be sexually
sexually discussed. Wow.
So talk about like in it part of my
standup now I'm just talking about how I
really also think it's,
it's genetic.
It's also like you want
to do a couple of things.
One you want to look like you got
to, you know, guys, bench press.
There's no reason to really deep bench.
Isn't that kind of a useless exercise?
You never really do the best
of scapes. Yeah, yeah it is.
But I'm just saying that usually you're
not in a situation where you have to hip
escape and I'm mad, but I'm going to
hip escape but at least three days.
But it's good.
But it's just a breeding instinct.
We want to fluff our
feathers so girls know,
see that we've got that going and we
want to look like we can fight the tiger
man want to look like we're, we're,
we're, you know, that's why guys butterflying,
you know,
you've got to look like you.
You're the bench is not really that
important, but it flawless. You know,
it's like your peacock here.
It's like, it's like birds, man.
She's really funny when you see some
dudes look completely disproportionate.
These weird bodies with chicks,
strippers, like a big chest.
I read it and Muslims fit this bro.
There was this one dude at the gym.
He had this giant chest and giant arms.
Okay.
And then he used to wear sweatpants.
Okay. You never saw his legs,
but there's no way they could match his
upper bodies I'm provided was massive
and his neck was like a small man's are.
That's a terrible thing goes this man
woe, woe. Always got to look at the neck.
You've got to look at the neck and the
legs. Actually first, crazy wobbly.
I was like, this is the weirdest
combination of I like this guy.
Just decided to just everyday do
the same goddamn exercises. Yeah,
flies just packed.
Deck blew up his body,
but there's probably a complete
disconnect between all three systems.
I bet his body works terrible.
It's probably so confused
as to why it's so heavy.
I was five. That's why you, when
you roll with a guy like that,
a lot of times he's a bodybuilder and
he feels like you can move them so well
and then you get some due to just as kind
of a thick neck and kind of like a big
base and just big legs and all
of sudden he's tank. You're like,
why can't even move you?
While the would a lot of people do that
or like bodybuilder type strength guys
ignore the legs and the back.
Those are the most important
things for your movement,
your legs and all the way up through your
upper back. You know, your, your core,
like your ability to stay and keep your
own position and the ability to resist
being pushed around and your
ability to push off your legs.
That's the most important thing.
So when guys are always like
doing like bench presses and shit,
like you're concentrating on the dumbest
shit you're concentrating on most of
the least important shit.
I was asked you, um,
obviously I'm a huge UFC fan and that
you talk about this a lot so I don't want
to talk about it too much.
But um,
one thing I always notice when I
watch it with a lot of my friends,
we always talk about how detailed your
knowledge is about the fight game and,
and you know,
you've always been a fighter and you
boxed and you did a lot of taekwondo and
you did and he wrestled and Jujitsu and
you continue to. But how much has your,
um,
your understanding of fighting evolved?
Do you think it's evolved a lot or have
you always kind of had it? Yeah, well,
you just watching the fights,
it, it evolves because you
see more things, you know,
you see more. I don't just watch
UFC always watched like k one,
like I'm a big fan of a k one kickboxing
and Muay Thai watching Brian and the
Jelly, the Jelly, the jelly is good too.
But I don't know what you're talking
about. Don't you, you, when Jelly,
I don't know what you're talking
about, split, but don't you think it's,
but are you surprised that you're watching
really great wrestlers like Maynard
and uh, and, and um, uh, what's
his name? Frank. I under, yeah.
And watching to a top flight
college collegiate wrestlers box.
Now it's like becoming,
it looks like it's becoming,
it's almost like I'm starting to
see why boxing even came about.
It kind of like evolved into
boxing ultimately, you know?
Well, I don't think so.
I think what it is with those two guys
is they're both really good wrestlers.
It's really hard to take each other down.
So it's almost like,
and they want to stand and bang because
you know it, it starts to become like a,
you know, a thing, you know,
he's going to meet me in the center of
the octagon and we're just going to swing
leather, you know, you know, hey, if
he wants to stay on with me, you know,
there's a lot of that. So there's,
the guys want to knock guys out.
It's the best feeling in the world,
I'm sure.
And you guys want to submit guys too.
And I think both guys are
really difficult to take down.
And so when you're really difficult
to take each other down, it's like,
what are we going to do? We're going to
try to take each other down over here.
No one wants to go to the crowd
anyway. It's exhausting. He'd rather,
you know what I mean? The
quickest way to win, I mean,
if you can't catch a submission,
obviously won by knockout and gray.
Maynard had some heavy, heavy hands
as you saw in that fight. Dude,
I've never seen anybody hit so
many times in the first round.
Get hurt so many times and come back and
win the next round. It was incredible.
Incredible.
Maynard is a beast man.
He rocked him with a left hook and
then just started like beaten on a man.
I mean it was, do you see anybody else
seen them as high as one 90 he gets big.
It's big. He's a really thick
kid. He's very, very muscular.
I know he's got those classical
all the way down on his hips.
He's one of those guys that like when
he cuts, wait, he really, you know,
he has to die it for a long time.
Like he has to know in advance
when he's fighting, has to die.
It get his body fat real low and
then slowly dehydrate himself.
He said they have it down to a science.
So when he gets in the octagon,
he's not one 55 he's probably one 65
one seven nine somewhere around that.
And he's a, he's big. He's very
heavy. So super strong, you know.
And I couldn't believe that Frankie
Edgar butterflying take those shots, man.
It was crazy. He's, he's just incredible.
He just kept going and he would not quit.
It was several opportunities
for him to quit. Well,
he was just getting bombed on that.
If he wanted to give it up,
he could have just given it up. He
never for a minute quit. I'd be,
it was so impressive to see how he
or manner did against Jose Aldo.
You taught them well, they're going
to, apparently they got a rematch,
which I think a these
guys going to rematch,
which I think is going to be fantastic.
You know, I think when you got to fight,
that's that close to God. It was so
close. There's so many arguments. Like,
you know, what was the first
rounds at a ten eight round was a,
some guys have said it could have
been a tense seven. You know,
obviously I'm not a judge. I don't, I
don't really score the fights that way.
But I think, you know, if I,
if I looked at it, you know,
you looked at it like as far as rounds
one and you know, butterfly it's close.
It's real close. Right. The
big thing is the first round.
How much damage did you give
Maynard in the first round?
Because a lot of the other
rounds are like, man,
there's a few of them
that were really close,
just incredible that Acre could come
back like that. It's incredible.
It's in grant. What's your calling? The
uh, Maynard adjusted really well too,
cause he almost punched himself
out in the, in this first round.
And I saw that I was having a hard time,
but then the third round he got loose
again. So he came right back. So you know,
when you've been wrestling since you
were that young and you've been learning
how to suck weight and you,
and you have to train that hard,
they're sewed mentally tough.
You know,
I the most mentally tough and I went to
Dan Gables intensive wrestling camp and
I was in high school and they train
us so bad. It's so hard. I, I,
that's when I decided I'm not wrestling
in college, so he was just a nightmare.
I'm not doing this.
And Dan Gable guys famous for that.
Well you know Dan Gable also has like two
hip replacements and two to fact knees.
Yeah, that's crazy. He really literally
wore his body down to the bone.
Well he does that with his Rassler's um,
apparently it's a mental thing.
Like he'll, he'll just wear you
down to the point where, you know,
the real interesting argument about
that as the eastern Europeans,
they don't do it though.
There's like a bunch of mother butterflyers.
I swear to God it just looks the other
phone. I have two phones in my office.
Shit. That's what happens
when you're a billionaire.
You know when you're a kid and your mom
told you to don't crack your knuckles,
it makes your fist bigger. What's that?
Do you remember when you were a kid?
Your mom told you not to crack your
knuckles cause it'll make her knuckles
bigger. Did you ever hear that as great?
Yeah. I always thought like, Oh yeah,
my crack my knuckles. So I have a bigger
fish and I could punch people better.
I think I just started cracking all my
knuckles to think that's how I'm building
my body's muscle up and I forgot that.
That doesn't really work. Like, Oh man,
I'm just glad I'm not a, I don't have
to fight for a living and that's it.
Hard life.
I respect those guys are phone problems.
I swear to God I disconnected
bolt of them. Yeah.
Get rid of your home phones. Who
uses home phone? What's your call?
What's your call on up here?
There's no cellular service.
What's your call on silver bells.
[inaudible] Anderson is
an interesting fight.
You know Vitor is a really dangerous guy.
Like as far as like a box on his,
yeah, his hands. He's really dangerous.
So fast. You started rich Franklin fight,
quickie took out. Franklin's crazy.
If he unloads on you like that and catches
you, he comes with a swarm of punches.
Man. I know. The only problem with
vittores had this in the past.
He just had a harder time in like the
second and third rounds maintain the same
intensity. But uh, and he's
had some mental issues, but
he had to like a really,
a lot of like real
serious personal issues.
Like his sister was kidnapped
and murdered. Yeah. A lot
of hard stuff happening.
First thing they ever go through it. And
then he's such a sweet person, you know,
you have to make a living
so you have to fight.
So you're forced to take fights when
you're not in a good state. And,
and I'm not making any
excuses for the guy,
but traditionally if you watch his fights,
he's very,
very strong in the beginning of the
fight issues that he has is in second and
third rounds.
Yeah.
So at one 85 the idea is that he killed
those issues because it was before it
was that he was carrying her on too much
muscle and now he's much leaner at one
85 which was his natural way,
isn't it?
He's probably a bit bigger than
that in real life, you know,
probably closer to 200 pounds.
But you know when he's in lean shape,
like ready for a fight. Yeah, I
suppose he's so ridiculously athletic.
He always was super fast.
Like his, his reflexes are,
it's very good. Yeah. You know he's had,
he's had some issues in the past
like Alistair Overeem submitted them,
but you know, the reality is a lot of that
was probably fatigue. If you're tired,
man, you leave your neck out there
and a guy like Al Star jumps on it.
It doesn't matter who you
are. No it doesn't. You know,
if you're finding them and may find you're
not adequately, physically prepared,
it's, you're going to do some
students show, it's why to me MMA is,
is the greatest sport because
it requires everything.
It requires like literally
not just your courage and,
and you have to be in top physical
shape, but you know, anything can happen.
The margin for error is so slim.
You make one mistake,
you get tired and even the training
that you have to go through to become a
really good boxer,
to become a really good wrestler,
to become and to stay
in really good shape.
That's just a full time job all the
time. Yeah. And what happens is you,
you mean you, you have to decide where
you're going to dedicate your time.
Is it going to be in a
strength and conditioning?
Is it going to be to work in your skills?
Cause you only have a certain amount of
hours in a day and a certain amount of
resources in your physical
body, you know. Exactly.
You're going to burn yourself out to
the point where you can't recover and,
and there's no money in it. I mean,
the other thing, especially in the,
and this job man,
it's like worked at high levels.
There is though at the high levels
there's rock star money. You know,
like George Saint Pierre is balling.
That guy's making ridiculous raising money
and Brock Lesnar made ridiculous one.
Yeah. I mean anybody who can sell tickets,
chocolate dealt ridiculous money. Yeah.
But it's the guys who can
sell, you know, paper views.
They can write the guys who can,
you know,
get a piece of the action guys who were,
who are legit starts with what
the UFC has done that so smart,
you know that a lot of people have
said about is they've made the name UFC
bigger than any fight. That's the smartest
thing to do and went to ever done.
That's the whole thing is that the
brand name is bigger than any fight.
And the good thing about that is that
everyone in the organization that's,
you know, it's in there, they can get
them to fight each other, you know,
and when you have like outside of, there's
like a bunch of different promotions.
The argument for that against that
rather is what's going on with Floyd
Mayweather and Manny Pacquiao.
They just won't butterflying find each other.
It's like Floyd Mayweather just doesn't
want to find them and just keep it off.
And you know, I want
drug test thing. I want,
I want to take his blood 10 minutes
before the fight, which is butterflying,
I mean they just, they're convinced
many packages. I was on steroids.
But then you look at his last fight, he
was 20 butterflying pounds. It's so crazy.
The Margarita Margarita Margarita was
an animal and it's a big comeback fight
for him and walks around at one
75 whatever big dude and, and,
and has never actually been heard,
I don't think Margarito and outlined that
and pack out just he figures your game
out mostly by the way, stopped them. So
I shouldn't say he has never been hurt.
That's not true.
I forgot about that fight.
That was the fight where I can't
believe I forgot about the butterflyers.
That was a fight where you get exposed
for having plaster in his gloves.
So that was, that was actually
the codified. No, no, no.
Oh, sugar. Shane Mosley. Yes,
absolutely.
That's why he came out
like almost projected and
humiliated and he was suspended
right out and sugar Shane
Mosley beat the butterflying shit.
And that was a fight where
a lot of people were saying,
well one of the reasons why,
I bet he got his ass kicked.
He probably felt super guilty though.
They got caught with his hand in the
cookie jar that he had been doing that to
people for a long time. A lot of people
suspected, oh sure. He like broke up code.
He broke up a lot of guys. It really,
really dangerous man. Frankly,
to be honest with you,
I would have banned him for life for that.
I mean it's kind of ridiculous that the
only got a year band. He's outrageous.
If they could prove that
he had done it more evil,
even just proving that you did it once.
I also think I also personally think
anybody who does that and lets their
trainer does do that.
I didn't the whole campus scumbag and
then it's just a scumbag, shitty plaster.
In 2010 you putting plaster and
you're ramped worst. Wow. You know,
but meanwhile what I said Mack Manny
Pacquiao 20 pounds butterflying light or lights
him up like a Christmas tree.
Nobody's come close to this guy. He's,
he's just probably the
greatest fighter ever.
I really think he's greatest boxer ever.
It's one in eight different
weight divisions. I mean,
how do you argue against that? Right.
I mean, if you see what he does to all,
to all these different fires, he's a
politician too. Oh, and by the way,
when he fights all of his country,
all of the Philippines stops to watch
crime goes down. No pressure, Manny.
And he goes in there like,
hey, what's up everybody? Hi,
how he's waving due to in the stands
before he even tried to hype up this fight
by talking about, you know how his
training camp hasn't been going so good.
Like you watched the Hbo 24 Seven Man,
he's so distracted, Manson distracted.
Meanwhile he gets in there,
I got this thing that dude's just
watching the fireworks go off.
He's standing in front
of that little butterflying,
that butterflying little lightning
bolts fly lefted right.
And is he seeing little sparks in
front of his eyes every 10 seconds?
He's like Roberto Duran when he
was younger, but, but way better.
Like he's so touches his belt.
He comes in and does that weird.
He loves fighting to men even
though he has so much to lose,
he still loves fighting
and he's a born fighter.
That's what I think is that
the hardest thing is when you,
when you become that biggest celebrity
and you have that many fans and you get
into a ring,
you have a lot to lose and
the great champions can
somehow put that out of their
heads and he seems like he makes him
elevate. It makes him better. You know?
He seems like the weight of these people
behind them just make some better.
Some people are, you know, some people
would talk trash, it doesn't work.
So I'm other people do like chill Sona
and obviously talking trash away does,
it helps them. It works
for him. I don't know.
Well the thing about Manny Pacquiao too
is that he seems to be doing everything
perfectly. He like, he seems
to be a really nice guy.
Yeah. It didn't. You tell me.
He also plays a pool, like I'm going
to be, well level plays better than me.
No one thing that doesn't
fashional level pool, that's crazy.
He's not good at is singing apparently.
Well yeah, he plays Karaoke and shit,
but give them some time.
I'll probably get good at that too.
If you really want it to,
we'll be with you by an Italian.
I'm going up shit about his thinking.
He'll probably higher voice coaches
and just become one of the badass opera
singers of our generation.
Never be able to deny him.
He's just a bad motherbutterflyer paid versus
old Tyson. Who would you go with? Wow.
Coming from, he's a tiny guy. No, but
if it was, if they were the same size,
that was the most interesting thing
about Tyson when he was young is that he
moved like a man much smaller than him.
You watched like the Mike
Tyson Marvis Frazier fight.
That is one of the most
disturbing boxing matches ever.
Cause Marvis knew what was going to
happen. We knew it was going to happen.
Tyson knew it was going to happen. The
announcers knew it was going to happen.
You know, they were all talking
about it. This is, you know,
a lot of people saying this is a
mismatch and then Tyson just comes rare,
renowned him moving
like, like in, in frames.
You're not even seeing all
of his movements because
he's moving so God damn fast
and all of a sudden he's hurling these
left hooks in your direction and you feel
your rib cage imploding and
before you even react to it,
another one's hit you on
the other side of the head.
He was having trouble finding sparring
partners cause he was crushing people too
badly. He moves so fast. That was the
thing. He didn't move like Ali where he,
you know, would move with fancy footwork
and dance around Joe Frazier style.
You know, but, but, but different
because with both hands, you know,
he would throw rights and laughs
with equal abandoned, you know,
whereas Joe Frazier was a big left
hooker and he had a diesel right hand,
but it was nothing like Tyson's, Tyson's
famous for that right hook to the body.
Right uppercut combination. He was
a butterflying, for one brief moment,
one brief period of history,
he changed that whole sport.
He changed watching boxing,
watching boxing was never
watching an execution. Okay.
It wouldn't,
Marvin Hagler was fighting good guys.
Like when he was fighting John the beats
Mugabi. It was like a big fight, right?
Everybody got excited about it. Like,
Holy Shit, I'm [inaudible] punch it.
And it was a fight to macaby knocked
out Terry Norris Mugabe is a bad
motherbutterflyer. Mugabe's get
serious power. You know,
this could be the fight for Hagler
Mike Tyson's fights were executions.
It's like, here's Bruce
Seldon, here's Mike Tyson.
Look at Bruce Selvans knees shake.
You know,
all of a sudden Tyson's charging after
him. Boom. The fights over. Well,
you know what they said is that
uh, Don king used to set up monitors
and he'd have a highlight reel of Tyson
knocking dudes out and when
you are going to fight him,
he would always step the monitors up.
So the fighter in the MGM,
when it would have to walk through that,
oh my God, Don king was nuts that way.
And so you'd be fighting and you'd
just see these highlight reels of him.
I just crushed it in slow motion. That
makes sense. It's the monitor attached.
Fantastic. You got to go fight Mike Tyson.
Some of those guys were so intimidated.
That's a huge,
I met him one time in Vegas at Dyson
and you just get put on weight,
but he's so thick, like his
hand is so thick. His, his,
his hips in his head,
everything is just so wide.
You're like [inaudible] just
a different human being.
I never grew while he's locked.
He was just so compact and fast.
He was a new model heavyweights
and six feet tall. Me To me,
like if you would've picked
the prototype of what I,
what I like just the ultimate
like top of the food chain dude.
That's what I'd like to look like. I
always wear black shorts and black shoes.
Do you remember when he came out of prison
and he was super yolked like he came
into prison,
that prison,
all he was doing was push ups and sit ups
and tat tips and getting tattooed with
butterflying are controversial.
Pete's Rashers Take Kong mouth.
They don't kill about 40 million
people crazies. The Arthur Ashe Tattoo.
It's like, all right dude, I got ya. Okay
grace. He's a fantastic mother butterflyer.
Che Guevara.
He's got take tattooed on him today.
It doesn't mean Che and Oh yeah,
he's a fascinating motherbutterflyer, man.
For that brief moment. Look, I said
that he changed the whole sport,
changed the whole sport and he lost
his trainer. Right, right. Well,
I lost a bunch of things. There was a
bunch of things that happen, you know,
fame happened and it also,
it's almost impossible to keep up the
level of Rpms that he was operating at.
You know,
when he was at the very top of his game,
when he was like challenging for the
heavyweight title and it was training,
you know, getting up at five o'clock
in the morning every time, running.
What's once,
you know,
once girls start coming into the picture
and money starts coming in the picture,
and he said to Todd Phillips recently and
the hangover two, and he goes, he goes,
I'm that, Todd told me this
story. And it was funny,
we were talking about the power of
women and how, you know, it never,
no matter how much money you make
and stuff and they're all women,
well it's kind of in a rush,
you know, and, and uh, and,
and Mike Tyson said to tiny goes, man,
I've heard it all. I've had, I've had, um,
I've had money, I've had fame. Uh,
but if God invented anything better
than poor thethe keeping it for himself.
Yeah.
Oh, he's keeping it for himself.
That's brilliant. Oh my God.
That might be the wisest thing anyone's
ever said. All right man. That's genius.
That should be in a book somewhere.
Someone folks, someone put that,
put that as your Avatar is your
signature at the bottom. You know,
you want to do that free screen
name. You need that. God Damn, that's
did you said that guide that we talked
about yesterday, I don't know if you saw,
those are not Brian.
There's this homeless guy that has
this really awesome radio voice and uh,
he was a bum on the side of the road
and this guy just filmed them and like,
you know, it like here, you know,
here's some money and the guides
of wide thank you very much.
And it was just like the most
creepiest video. Anyways,
a day after like he's really
probably play it for Brian's. Right?
It's really quick.
Oh, sorry. I wish I, I've always
wanted to have, you can do butterfly Outta,
you can do any voice to
tell people that I want,
I want a voice like this is just natural.
It's just got a lot of gravel in it.
Just a sexy kind of like a lumberjack was
just a guy who keeps you real calm and
get you a real horn.
It when he talks how old he is,
your maker either love master 17 years
old. He looked at it, but a 20 to me.
All right,
right. Sorry. Crepey sorry. I'll
wait. No, that's not it. Great.
And now this place is flooded,
dude. I always tell people there's
two, two funniest moments now.
The funniest moments ever.
One of them was in the hotel,
you and me and Eddie Bravo and Larry and
a couple other dudes and we were really
super banked and you went into your
Brazilian Jujitsu rapist character.
Oh my God, Dude. I remember laughing
until I literally couldn't breathe.
Like I've said, this is, this is the
funniest moment I've ever had in my life.
There's that moment. And the other moment
is Joey Diaz on the Alex Jones show.
Those to me, I haven't seen
that. You have to say it.
It's the most ridiculous thing ever. Joe,
you know Alex Jones show is all kept.
Trails are taking up our sky.
Kate bio chips, they're doing it,
they're putting it
inside children's cereal.
Ladies and gentlemen with the elitist,
they want to lower the population
and vaccines and you know,
it's all like crazy. We need
to buy gold. He gets nutty.
Joey DNS comes on because Alex is my
friend and I've known Alex for like 10
years and he's right about
a lot of things. I mean,
he's really right about
a lot of things here.
And I think the only way to chase
things down the way that guy does,
you gotta be a little loony. So he's
a little loony, but he's a great guy.
Alex Jones is a great guy, but he's
got this conspiracy theories theory,
a right wing kind of a radio show.
And Joey comes on it and we go onto
the internet break. But grind Q,
that shit up. We go into the homeless
guy. You, I played the homeless guy.
First Day.
I'm gonna make you work for your dollar.
Say something with that great radio voice
when you're listening to nothing but
the best of oldies. You're listening to
magic 98.9 all right, you can take it.
You so much.
That's how I use it. So that guy got a
job that was so anyways, yesterday that,
that,
that video hit today.
The was it the colts gave him a
house and a job working for him.
Is it the cult? I think, yeah,
the Cleveland Colts or whoever
the Cleveland Cleveland is.
It's great. If I didn't find out what is,
cause it's give them props with Kevin.
Here's the Cleveland Cavaliers.
Cavaliers,
the calves I should have
or a basketball team.
So they picked him up as the
announcer. Yeah, they pick, well,
they offered Williams a full time job
doing voiceover work for the team and a
free home in Cleveland
to the is a motherbutterflyer.
Love it. I love it. In one day
that guy, he's got a house,
there's all all together.
It's beautiful and it's a great story.
Brilliant PR move for life.
Friend was giggling and showed
me this thing and I looked at it.
It was a man I was trading himself and I
was like, yeah, I've seen a few of those.
I was like, great. That's what,
I don't need the internet.
I watched one where a guy, um, tied
off his balls with rubber bands,
detailed every single aspect of the
balls dying and him cutting off the balls
with a serrated knife. I didn't see
that. I saw the hatchet job. Oh, crime.
Any crime, any crime. Money. There's a lot
of crazy motherbutterflyers out there, dude.
God Damn.
I wonder if this home is shit's going to
catch on and all these homeless people
are going to start trying to do voices.
So now there's,
this can be tons of homeless people coming
up. You going, hey, how's it going? Hey,
can I have someone?
I think there'll be like a slow like
incubation period before it hits the
homeless people because most of
them don't have any internet.
So it's going to take like six months
of somebody trying to drag them into a
library. Mcgee, go see this cause it
heroin. If it's not, I'm not going. Huh.
And then not January, this
guy got a job. We need a neck.
This is like a Fred Flintstone.
Unless they start eating to Barney
rubble and let's they start reading their
toilet paper, you know, I'm like, oh no.
Do you remember Fred Flintstone and
Barney rubble? They're always like,
there's always scams to
coming up with things.
They always had some new skins come up
with an eye. We're going to start a band.
You remember, he was always like
trying to figure out his shit.
And his wife was always cock blocking and
holding them down. My Buddy, my buddy,
uh, it has Asperger's syndrome really?
And he's 50 and he's really smart,
but he's also completely crazy. And we
were driving and he's 15. It looks to me,
he goes, he goes, I'm thinking about
something. I go, what? He goes,
I think we should start a band. And I go,
wow, that's a really good idea. Johnny,
is he driving a, you drive?
I'm driving. He goes, thank God
you gotta do you think
so? I go, I do think so.
The only issue is that I don't think
either one of us sings or plays an
instrument. So what would we
do? He goes, well, you know,
you're a charismatic so you could figure
something out, you know, and I would,
I do sing, I do sing. Um, I, I've
always had music inside of me. I go,
okay, but if you saying, that's
good, I don't, I'm a shower singer,
so what would I do? And
he was like, you know,
like just the tambourine and plus you
could just be the leader of the band.
I was like, you're the greatest
human being old time at.
I'll do that in a heartbeat.
So anyway,
anybody who wants to join me and Johnny's
band, please, please give me a call.
Can they get a hold of you on Twitter?
Are you going to have auditions
for the band? You know, I
would, I, you know, for me,
I just, it's funny, I wish I
played an instrument. I don't,
I never had the patients.
What's,
what fascinates me is why some
people choose certain instruments.
Like the guitar, I get it, you get laid
the piano and the drums, but the Tuba,
that's the dumbest butterflying instrument.
Like there's not even a,
there's not even a song.
Really. Yeah. You just,
you need a huge brass band
and you only play like
boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
You know, there's no really
like full songs for the two.
But we're like, um, what
else does a couple of the
accordion, certain things that
people have a calling for that are,
that fascinated me. I always
just slow, what was that movie?
The Spike Lee movie about jazz
with Denzel Washington movie.
What was that quote?
Better Blues Blues.
And I still love watching like,
like the part where Denzel Washington
would take out his trumpet and he would
clean it.
It was like a ritual and then he would
go through all his practice routines.
Like he was so disciplined
about his practice. Tropics,
we try to get at them and be like, I've
got a practice, I got to find a, yeah,
you know,
Wynton Marsalis talks about that he's
considered by many to be the greatest jazz
trumpeter, you know, in
the world. And as he,
the dude that was on the tonight
show or was it his brother?
His brother Brandford.
But um,
but witness is considered a real real
maestro. Like, like in the, in the,
in the, in the same pantheon is
like, Yo, yo ma or even even, uh,
Louie Armstrong. I mean, so he's just
completely dedicated to the [inaudible].
By the time he was 19,
he was on a physical technical level with
the trumpet that was so far superseded
anybody in the field. Almost,
and, and they also say,
and I've heard this from people
like Harry Connick Jr and stuff,
we say that he does things on a trumpet.
You're not physically supposed to
be able to do like your fingers.
I'm supposed to be able to do that stuff.
Yeah.
And cause he can just move them so fast.
Such dexterity and the
things that he does, but
talks a lot about, um, you know, just,
just what practice means and the kind
of thing that I believe he's still blows
on a read an hour a day, you know,
which is like a beginners thing. But,
but he says if, you
know, the daily practice,
the daily adherence to practice is what,
what changes everything.
And not only that,
he also talks about like when you do a
performance and you come off and you've
got a high and if you killed it, that
energy, a lot of people go, well,
I'm going to have a couple of drinks and
celebrate actually what a guy like that
we'll do is go, I've got all
this new, all this new energy.
And he goes and shuts himself in the room.
And practices even more with that
new found sort of rush, that energy.
And you know,
he talks about the difference between
being truly great and truly original and
being like everybody else is or those
kinds of, those kinds of things.
You know,
like pushing yourself to that level.
Everybody has their own process of course,
but nobody practices as much as he does.
Yeah. The discipline, the adherence
discipline is so attractive. You know,
in my mind it's like, so what I
would like to be doing, you know,
I stay as disciplined as I can,
but I'm so butterflying pulsive there's so
many different things entering into my
interest all the time had,
pardon me, says, well,
that's where some of my
creative creativity comes from,
is this fascination with a
constant need for, you know,
all this new information and new
things and yeah, but it's also,
it's also a distraction.
Yeah. It's massive. And I
also think that in some ways,
like I always think that you get to a
certain point in your life where you,
in a way,
no,
everything that you need to know to
create something perfect and beautiful.
But it's, it's new. Current Shit is
the most fascinating thing to me.
I mean every,
the crazy thing about what's going on
the Internet now is every God damn day
you get Twitter messages and a
message board messages on my, my,
on the Rogan board where it's all these
new incredible scientific discoveries,
all these new weird things that
are happening around the world,
like the thousand butterflying thousands of
birds that have died and fallen from the
sky and Arkansas and everybody's going,
what the butterfly is going on?
You know and heard that's viral just
because they're filming angry birds right
now. What that says viral videos for
the angry birds movie. Are you serious?
I think that that's, that's a
rumor that's going on, right?
There's no way you're going to
kill thousands. What happened?
They actually think what happened was
that's like the fireworks jail for
fireworks. 10 years actually roused
them from their sleep and they rent,
they couldn't see and ran
into like different chimneys
and everything. They just,
they get it, they stay, they flew.
Well that doesn't make sense because
there's thousands of them and they're over
fields and shit. The thousands of them
got scared and fell from the sky deck.
That doesn't sound right.
It sounds like bird flu or something.
Maybe it sounds like they
butterflying poison them or something.
That sounds more like, yeah,
there's probably some, you
know, loud or something.
And there's the conspiracy theory angle.
There's a bunch of people that are
trying to pawn it off on this one guy.
I should, I should know this man's name,
so I'm going to look it up right now.
But this guy just got killed and he was,
um,
a chemical weapons expert and he was
tortured and murdered and a real thing.
Yeah.
And they think there's some sort of a
connection to it that the guy turned up
missing. And, um, he
turned up missing and, uh,
I think in Delaware and they found them
in a landfill. He had been murdered. Yeah.
And they believe that this
guy, um, was, you know,
here he is top you as
official. Yeah. He, um, it's,
it's really kind of creepy,
man.
Their stories are very bizarre
because this guy was like, uh, he,
he worked under George Herbert Walker
Bush as well, and he's an expert in, um,
and um, um, uh,
weapons and biological weapons and
chemical weapons. It's crazy shit, man.
And, uh, the, the course of
conspiracy angle is that a,
they were testing something and killed
all these birds off and he might have
protested a freaked out
or, you know, I, I've been,
I spent a lot of time
reading the history and I,
one of the things I like about doing
that as opposed to even looking at where
we're headed is how, how
little, how much change,
but also how little changes a lot of ways.
And the man's name is John P.
Wheeler for anybody who wants to look into
the story, John a Joe Chen, p wheeler,
w h e l, e r. And just
type that into Google.
And I'm sure a bunch of different
stories will come up on the sky.
This is the same thing that somebody
printed to all the websites in with like I
s or anything.
Some of them are the ones that are legit,
legit ones that aren't claiming
any sort of conspiracy.
Those are interesting because would
they talked about is the fact that this
guy's television was turned on full blast
and it freaked out his neighbors cause
he was a really kind of a quiet
guy and it was an older guy.
They didn't understand why it's television
was ty co was like blasting like that.
Well television really loud is one of
the ways they hide the sounds of torture.
So they found this guy's house,
um,
and there was a yellow police tape in
his kitchen and they pulled up floor
boards and they roped off the chair.
So the idea is that it is very possible
that they might have talked to this guy
before the killed them and they might
have tortured him in his own house and
then they killed him and then it took him
to a dump. Yeah. It's, you know, it's,
it's interesting when a guy has that sort
of a backgrounds, you know, so, you know,
and like I said, I know, I'm not saying
by the conspiracy theory, I'm saying,
you know,
first of all,
it's creepy that this guy got butterflying
tortured and murdered or at least the very
least murdered the torture part. It's
speculation at this point, but it's a,
it's an interesting little thing.
I don't know if it has anything to
do with all these, uh, this guy.
You can pretty much connect anyone from
that store to that store if you really
had to type without not, we're just
guesswork. Yeah, sure. Yeah. Yeah.
Me Basically we were just
making pieces of fiction.
We don't really know if he's connected
to it, but the idea is oh two,
that's what I want to talk about.
In Abu Dhabi this year,
they made it rain 52 times. Did you
know that they made it round seating?
Silver got like a strict payment doing,
they've been doing cloud seeding system.
They probably made it right in there more
than $52 and they've been doing cloud
seeding for many, many years. But this,
this is something that they've
come public about and that,
that Abu Dhabi better at using,
they're using it as a weekly strategy.
They're like, I mean, 52 times. That's
like once a week. Man, that's crazy.
If they just choose to space it out
like that, they want to make it greener.
They're very ambitious.
Yeah. How crazy is that?
They're happening where they're getting
the drawing in their water from.
It wasn't there before that apparently
there's moisture in the air and
especially where they live there,
they're near a lot of ocean and there's
moisture in the air and you have to coax
it out. But I mean, what are
the repercussions? What are
the repercussions of that?
I mean, what is the, I mean, how safe is
it to be spraying shit in the air? Well,
they've been doing it for many years. I
mean, they've always done cloud seeding.
I don't know how effective it is and I
don't know how good they've gotten on it.
But, um, I know that that's been around
for since at least the seventies.
I think they're getting better at it.
Yeah.
This Abu Dhabi thing was fascinating
because I've never heard it discussed on
like cnn.com or you know,
any major in major news website.
But that's what they were
talking about is very, is, is,
is I guess from what I've read
becoming really ambitious,
they really want to become sort
of the new Arab, that center of,
for the new Arab world. You know,
there's sort of the, the beacon of light,
if you will, for a different way of
doing things. They got crazy paper, dude.
They got crazy paper. They go crazy
paper. But, but live in like that man,
make an artificial butterflying rain showers.
Holy Shit. That's crazy. You know,
it's just, you always wonder,
does that, is it good?
Is that going to affect
something somewhere else? Uh, is,
is forcing it to rain somewhere else
for saying like a butterflying hurricane to,
to grow over here on the other side.
I mean,
isn't the sky all somehow
or another connected,
isn't the environment connecting
sell? I don't think that, no,
I don't think that a localized, you know,
rain seeding of cloud seeding. It's over.
How big of an area do you get away
with it? But that's the thing.
I don't think it's a, I don't think you
can do it over a large area and so on.
It's hard to do.
I think so.
I don't know if they figured out how to
do it all the time and obviously they
have, they've done it 52 times.
That's pretty consistent.
If they just decided to do that, that
would be such a trip. If Allston,
we went over
to two, I would dominate. It was
like West Palm Beach, Florida.
It's butterflying dead and shit.
Everything's wedded. We're headed.
We are becoming more and more in control
of our environment or at least trying
to be. But then again, we're
also losing some control of it.
If you buy into the whole global warming,
you know,
that's the story of the Annunaki.
That's the story from the Sumerian text.
The reason why human beings were invented,
the whole,
the Zechariah sitch and craziness,
you know about all this.
The story was that these alien beings
from another planet came to earth because
they had ruined their atmosphere with
their technological race and so in,
in they ruin their atmosphere and they
needed gold particles to suspend in their
atmosphere to protect them from radiation.
And the sun's chill with that.
That's pretty well.
And that they had done exactly what we're
about to do right now. And the, the, uh,
it's the most ridiculous thing ever.
It's called the 12th planet
and he wrote it back in 1970.
But what's fascinating is the idea of
suspending particles in the atmosphere
that had never been discussed
until like the year 2000.
And they had like a global
symposium on, on, you know,
protecting the earth from environmental
hazards, like losing the ozone layer,
losing our atmosphere.
And that was one of the suggestions
for suspend reflective particles in the
atmosphere. That's pretty wild.
Yeah. That you could do that.
You could fill the sky with
silver and gold particles. Well,
gold to the s the crazy thing about
gold is a tiny little piece of gold can
spread out so far. Gold dust is so
fine. It's like incredible moving.
The other issues that you're,
you're actually, they just
created bacteria strains,
um, from a computer. In other words, they,
they cross pollinated DNA
and created lifeforms,
bacteria farms that had never existed
on earth that it's called synthetic
biology. This guy, Craig
venter and his team,
if you go to ted.com you can see
his lecture and when when they,
for the first time on a printer,
they print it out essentially
the structure for a
completely new life form and,
and would that has far
reaching implications in
the sense that for the first
time human beings might very well be
able to control their own evolution and
certainly create new life forms are
going to be such a butterflying mess.
It's going to be create,
it comes with great promise,
but also peril manifesting in fire.
Yeah, no shit. With your paper
monster, what the butterfly you're doing?
You're going to make a new life forms
with your computer. How nuts is that butterfly,
things are getting weird.
I think it's going to get,
I think it's going to get to a point where
we won't really be able to figure out
like, you know, like I was thinking,
I'm reading this, you guys, if you ever,
if you ever just take, take three
months and do it in two months, it,
I'm reading blood Meridian Cormac
McCarthy's a masterpiece. It's,
it's considered by,
when they reviewed it in 85 they said
this is one of the great feats of language
in the past 50 years. It's, it's the,
it's the, and it's about a novel.
It's a novel and it's about the sort of
the settling of the west and it follows
these, this track, this group of 19. So,
um, um, men who are hunting
Indians, what's it called? Scouts.
It's a brutal book.
What's it called?
It's called Blood Meridian blood
and Maria and, and you know,
we all know what happened.
A lot of people may not,
but what happened to the native Americans,
and it's just,
it's the same old story of one group
comes in with guns and they basically
decimate, you know, not just what disease
but with bullets. And everything else.
But um, God, I forgot what I was going
to say, but it was about, um, oh yeah.
What I was gonna say is that if you
look at what happened as they started
settling the west is that the,
the,
the Europeans were killing
not just all the buffalo,
they were killing all the
other animals as well.
They got really efficient at it
because this, they lay the railroad,
they would shoot buffalo and in the course
and then they would place the bodies
with strychnine.
Now why would you do that?
Because all the other animals with feed
on the buffalo and they would die with
stuff,
the strychnine.
So then you could scan them and send all
those pelts to Europe and to the east
and to the east coast and stuff, whether
it was big money. So in of course,
a 20 years,
probably 500 million animals died.
If you look at the old paintings
and pictures of the, of the,
of the Great Plains in
America, they looked like the
Serengeti and, and of course,
the 20 years, literally we killed all
the buffalo and so many other animals.
Not just the wolf that fed on the Buffalo,
we killed him, but everything else. And,
and um,
so what happened for a lot of the native
Americans was their entire mythology,
entire mythology there.
Religions were wrapped up with their
environment and the animals around them.
And in 20 years they were all gone.
Forget the fact that they were starved
to death. But they're, they're very,
they're very mythology.
They're very religion.
What would the cornerstone to their
culture was eradicated and you really
wonder, you know, what,
what psychologically they were going
through as they saw this true holocaust
sorta unfold for them. You
know, it's in its historic,
when you think about right heel short
of a time period, that is right.
And I always think,
are we going to come up with a certain
kind of technology that does the same to
us? That's the question. I mean nothing.
Nothing says that our culture and our
way of life and our even lives are
guaranteed by anything. I mean if you're
very religious, you believe it is.
But for people who tend to have more
of a scientific bent or have a, Oh,
take a real look at history, it's
very possible that, you know,
there are threats out there eventually
maybe of our own design that could render
us extinct or abs.
Yeah.
The idea is that light keeps going
in a direction of more complexity.
Things getting more and more complicated.
In the issue with the Indians was you're
dealing with, okay. American Indians,
native Americans, we're dealing with
people that were so butterflying crazy.
They were willing to get in boats and go
across the ocean and across the country
to a place to live. Yeah. You know,
and then just trek out on their own
to the middle of the butterflying country.
There's giant continent that was literally
filled with people that were living
like the rest, the rest of the world.
They were living like a much, much,
much more modern. I mean,
American Indians before that
we did, before we had
introduced or the, the uh,
Spanish or other had introduced
horses to them. I mean,
they were like no manic tp living
Arrow shooting motherbutterflyers, you know.
I mean it was really crazy.
It's like they were living just like the
people that they find today in the the
Amazon rain forest,
there's still finding people like that.
Today they found a bunch of new
tribes. There's like, I got, I got,
I can't remember the number,
but they have this fascinating photo of
one that they found that's near the Peru
and Brazil border and their
skin is covered with ink.
They're covered with red ink and two of
them are red and one of them looks like
like a black color and they're just
covered with like this crazy war paint and
they're holding bows and they're
pointing arrows at the airplanes.
The airplanes take pictures of them.
These are undiscovered,
untouched tribes that's are completely
isolated from the rest of the world.
It's wild. So that's really
what American Indians were like.
Native Americans were like,
and unfortunately,
whatever the butterfly humanity
is doing here on this planet,
what we're trying to do is be
more better, faster, bigger.
What the butterfly are you get out of my
way. More. Better, faster, bigger.
How about a butterflying metal box that rolls
on metal train tracks and it goes 300
butterflying miles an hour and it cuts
across the whole country. I mean,
we just more better, faster,
more, better, faster.
Live in teepees is just getting
in the way. It was like,
what are you talking about? Sacred
ground. Sacred ground. Sacred ground.
Mine says money. Okay, we got to kill
you. We're going to kill these people.
We gotta kill him. I got tell him we got
a calendar they want and not reasonable.
It's the same old story of
history is full of that stuff.
That history is full of one group that
comes into another group and says,
you guys are in the way, man. You got
to either leave or die. I mean, yeah,
it's absolutely wrong. I mean,
not no one has justifying it.
It's absolutely heinous.
It's absolutely disgusting,
but objectively stepping away from the
old whole idea of emotions and humanity
and people in genocide and all that stuff.
If you look at it as like, you know,
in a direction that humanities,
that's inevitable.
The point is the DA unimaginable
can happen to people. And,
and it happens to huge groups of people,
whether it's Russia,
the Russian Ukrainians in the 1930s,
under Stalin or the Jews under Hitler and,
and, and you know, in the, uh,
later thirties and up to 45,
the unimaginable. The, the, the,
the unspeakable can happen
to millions of people.
Millions people can perish in a period
of make the argument people make the
argument. But that was then, and now the
age of information, the South Hospital.
Now look at the, we have not
changed that much human beings.
The one difference I will
say about history, thank God,
is that it becomes harder for bad men to
get away with things for a long period
of time because there are a
lot of people watching and,
and that's a very good thing. You
know, you're always going to have,
if you have an incentive
structure that gives,
there are always people in society who
are willing to do what others won't do.
And,
and those people always flourish in chaos.
They always flourish in war when
Russia fell apart. That's right.
It's the people that are willing
to do what others won't do that.
That always rise to the top in in a
situation where there's no rule of law and
Sandra,
that's the enemy and that's not good.
That's not good.
That's why you have to fight
for representative government.
You have to fight for all the things
the founding fathers Taco talked about
because it keeps bad men in check and so
whenever you start blaming individuals,
it's like kind of blaming the way of
the world. We're always going to have.
You're always going to have bad people.
You want a system that keeps
them somewhat neutered.
That's very important and
people don't challenge.
People don't understand the the,
the logic of countries and met.
It's all stupid man.
It's all stupid.
I want to show you a video and the
video is the hodge on the mosque.
I know all about the hush,
the hodge on Mecca and watching all
those people mill around the post and go,
listen,
if it's just you and your scantly
connected group of friends and you,
you have some sort of a conflict with
a group that's as connected as these
motherbutterflyers,
you know,
they're willing to do a lot of crazy
shit and you're willing to die.
There's something quite
beautiful about the hot, amazing.
And the Hodges is beautiful because in,
in,
in the notion as you were two sheets
and whether you're a prince or a pauper,
you're in the same group.
You were a two sheets.
When you go on your pilgrimage to Mecca
and every Muslim has to do at once in
their life, at least you go, you go and
you, you fast from sunup to sundown.
And usually if you're strict, I don't
even think you're allowed to drink water,
but the notion is we're all
equal under the eyes of God.
So it's a very egalitarian movement.
So when they make their
pilgrimage to Mecca,
they were two sheets and they
are, they are, they are we in?
So you can be right next to some of these
worth $1 billion and you have nothing
but under the eyes of God when you're
there, you guys are all the same.
You're all eating the same foods,
you're all behaving the same way.
And it was this notion that Muhammad
came up with was this notion that, look,
we need, you always have to
go and, and, and basically we,
there's got to be somewhat of a, a
communal, a communal pilgrimage, uh,
humbling pilgrimage to show each
other that we're all the same.
It was kind of a unifying thing,
movement,
very important and ritualistic
things like, absolutely. Absolutely.
What does that box supposed to represent?
The big square building that I believe
is where Muhammad was buried. Mohammed,
I believe it was born in Medina and he
died in Mecca and Medina and Mecca. And I,
I'm sorry if you're a Muslim and I'm
getting them mixed, uh, switched around.
But Medina and Mecca are the most,
um,
they are the most
religious places in Islam.
There are truly the most religious places.
Notice on when you pray,
you pray toward Mecca.
So when you go to hotels or things in,
in the Arab world,
Muslim world,
a lot of times they have
arrows pointing to Mecca.
Is there a lot of prep iPhone APP? So
he not there. There may very well be.
I'd be surprised that there was,
there has to be [inaudible] if
there's not out there developers,
you know what the butterfly to do? You need to
make a mecca iPhone APP. I need to know.
I'll pay my respects towards
sparco butterfly listen. So he was,
he was buried there. Yes.
That's incredible. So He's
under that box somewhere.
His right. I believe that's, I believe
that's the stone he was, he was the,
I believe, and I just read about this
and I'm sorry that I don't know it,
but I believe that the stone was where
Mohammed received a message from sort of
an angel about the Koran.
Because remember that the Muslims always
believed that there was one person that
spoke through God and that was Muhammad.
And their proof was that he was an
illiterate shepard who over the course of
seven years wrote, the Suna wrote,
wrote essentially the, the Quran.
The Quran being a essentially
a bunch of poems. It's,
it's written in verse and it's quite
beautiful. It's quite, it's a, it's very,
very intricate and with these incredible
and stories and stuff, and they said,
how could one man write all this
in seven years? He was inspired.
He never learned how to write,
read or write,
but he would obviously had some kind
of a revelation or an inspiration.
And so that was what that was where
Muhammad really made his name.
And not only did he do that, but mom
had also was the guy who said, look,
this is a bunch of tribes, a bunch
of Pagan tribes. I'm going to,
I'm going to unite the people of Saudi
Arabia. I'm going to unite these people,
these nomads.
I'm going to stop them from fighting
each other and I'm going to create one
group of people under one banner
of heaven. And that was the notion.
It's amazing how butterflying radical they
are to the gotten to the point where you
can't even draw Muhammad or,
yeah,
it's a shame.
It's a shame because historically Islam
was actually always a religion that was
so open to interpretation and in fact
we look, look, look at Indonesia,
Indonesia for until very recently and
even still was always, it's always,
it's been a Muslim country for many, many,
many years and has always been a very,
very open and tolerant society.
Remember that the Jews who were persecuted
and killed by the Christians always
went to Muslim countries first.
Muslims were the ones that
actually protected the Jews
because they were people
of the book.
The Quran upholds every story in the
Old Testament and believes that the Old
Testament to be gospel.
It's more of a rebuttal to
the new testament with the
notion that Jesus Christ,
that it considers to be a great prophet.
The notion that Christians say that Jesus
Christ is actually God is where they
take issue,
and that was where the big rift was.
But remember that Islam was always a place
for the most part, Islamic countries,
like the Ottoman empire was a place
where where the Jews took refuge in.
So that's why this, this, this
rift between Jews and Muslims.
Over the founding of the state of Israel
in 1948 that's where all of this came
from. And that's what's so
unfortunate about all that. Well,
at one point in time, the, the,
the Muslim religion or Muslim people
responsible for an incredible amount of
adventures to absolutely.
We'll look and say it's the omen
scientifically advanced. I mean,
you're talking about the
Ottoman Empire for God's sake.
It wasn't what it is today
and what happened that, that,
that butterflyed everything up and got it
to the point where it is today where
there's so much, you know, it's like
so many things degrade, you know, and,
and get to a point where it's not
what, you know, I would argue,
I would argue that, and I'm
not a political scientist
and I don't know anything.
I'm just a goddamn actor, but, but I,
but I did live there for eight
years of my life and I would that
the Middle East biggest problem
is not it. I think, I think,
I believe that Islamic fundamentalism was,
came out of the fact that the 22
governments in the Middle East are not
democracies,
that they've always been monarchies and
dictatorships and those monarchies and
dictatorships kept people in poverty.
When you keep people in poverty and you
have a bunch of men that have no jobs
and nothing to make themselves
feel good about themselves,
they're going to turn to something man,
and they're going to turn to something
like a religion because it makes them,
and they're going to, and, and men do this
kind of thing. They'd say, Hey, again,
we have historical evidence for
that where people say, look,
there are Christian fundamentalists.
They're Jewish fundamentalists. You can,
you can, you, they're all over the place.
But, but, uh, somehow along the way,
uh, this became a perverted
notion of Islam where, you know,
I'm going to solve my problems with
violence. I'm going to blow myself up.
I'm going to go to heaven.
This is all very new man and I
and and religious fundamentalism.
It's fairly new. It's, it's a, it's
a 20th century invention. I've heard
a lot of people,
and I don't know if this is accurate,
but I've heard it from more than one
source where people were connecting the
mujahideen and their fight against the
Soviet Union and their work with the CIA
creating a bunch of,
a bunch of different new things that
happened in the Muslim religion, like,
like suicide bombers and
the suicide bombers actually notion of
jihad really because the suicide bombers,
where did they were the first suicide
bombers we were reading about it worthy.
Tommy. All Tigers actually in Sri
Lanka. They, that's who those were.
That was in the 90s, the early
nineties. I mean the Tamil Tigers,
where were the ones that were actually
blowing themselves up and nobody had ever
heard of that? We couldn't believe it. You
didn't, you'd never heard of any Muslim?
Absolutely not. Absolutely not. And
what are they? The Sri Lanka guys,
are they Muslims? What are
the, uh, the Tamil Tigers,
I believe a lot of them are Hindu in fact,
and now it's not.
Hindus were the first suicide
bombing. Yeah. So they were
not, they were not, uh, um,
Muslims 90 and the,
and,
and the Tamil Tigers were,
were fierce group of people trying.
They've been crushed, but they,
they, uh, uh, they were trying,
they were trying to fight for their own
independence, their own notion of, of,
you know, what they want. But,
um, so, so a lot of this stuff,
if you look at the inspiration behind
it, it's, it's pretty bizarre. You know,
groups watch other groups and you know,
what's the crazy bad ass,
you know, listen, I mean, suicide
bombing is not in Vietnam.
And you had people who
would, a lot of, like,
women would take your hand grenade
and jumping into a helicopter and blow
themselves up and everybody in the
helicopter. So that's just a human thing.
I mean, yes. Yes. So, um, there
were a lot of cases of that.
A lot of kids.
The Viet Cong were a tough group of
people who were willing to do whatever it
took to get to hard to tell
occupied, like, that must be
so crazy. It is. You know,
you're just a normal person living your
life in a hut somewhere and chillin and
I'm going a good time.
Then all of a sudden they're soldiers
coming in and metal boxes for some reason
you don't understand.
They're pointing guns at you and scream,
aren't you? It's like Afghanistan,
man. The Mujahideen was, you know, the,
the good example because
they were basically when the Soviets
came in, first of all, Afghanistan,
it's never been a country.
You've got to understand,
it's always been a group of tribes. You
had to put, you had the push stones,
you have the techniques,
you have the Hazera and they
all have always competed
against each other. I mean,
where did you live when you were there?
I lived in Saudi Arabia and Lebanon, uh,
in the Arab world. But no, no.
But my mother had been there twice and my
father had been there twice. I thought,
I'm sorry. I thought you were saying
you lived in. No, I've been to,
it was kind of like you do, you did.
Oh, it's doing stand. Yeah. Yeah.
But that doesn't mean it. Now when
you're living in these, these, um,
how many countries did you live in?
I was born in the Philippines.
I then moved to India where I live in
Bombay and Calcutta, which is now Mumbai,
Bombay.
And then I moved to Lebanon and then I
moved to Pakistan and then I moved back
to Lebanon work.
It would be so in love with it now.
How do you think I get so much? I get
laid then. I thought you were married. Oh,
sorry. Yeah. And uh, I forgot
about that part, but um, but
then I, then I moved to, uh,
uh, Lebanon again in the war broke out
and we got stuck in the war and I lived in
the heart of the end for six months.
Holy Shit.
We really couldn't get out of the country.
Oh my God.
I used to hear machine gun and it was
crazy. You know what you're worried about?
The holiday and getting overtaken was
too young to worry about that stuff.
You know, I was, um, gosh,
I was a, I think 11 or 12,
and then I was, we were evacuated to
Greece and I lived in Greece and then I,
and then I went to Saudi Arabia. And then
when, by the time I was 14, I'd, I'd,
I'd never lived in the states and I came
to the states. That's incredible. Yeah.
Yeah.
It was pretty wild.
We had a very different perspective
growing up and no Shit, Huh? Yeah.
And the world and the world, uh, and,
and what happens to the world, um,
makes a difference to you, you know,
like this, this Pakistanian governor,
you know,
in Pakistan there's called the blasphemy
law and the law is if you insult Islam,
you will be put to death.
Now when you say insult Islam,
there are a lot of ways to
interpret that and people use it,
manipulate it to get rid of their
neighbors and things like that. And this,
this governor of the
Punjab, which is, um, uh,
an area of a large area of
Pakistan basically said, um,
I'm sorry if it's putting, I don't know,
it's Punjab. I thought that was India,
but anyway, but he was a big oven and he
said, um, he was trying to get rid of it.
You've tried to repeal it.
It was trying to, you know,
he was a champion of women's rights and
things like that and I sort of a face of
the more modern notion of,
you know,
not only Islam but with Pakistan
and uh, he was assassinated. Uh,
one of his elite guards filled in with
23 bullets because this recent, yeah,
really recently, very recently, I just
thought to myself, I thought, man,
this stuff is not dead.
We still are in living in a world of
ignorance and of people who are willing to
solve problems through violence.
How about this crazy motherbutterflyer in
North Korea? Man, oh, Kim Jong, Il,
he's the biggest day holding the
history of the world. However,
he wins biggest asshole of all time.
He's just a dick.
The crazy thing about the Koreans is
that North Korea and South Korea war with
each other basically, and they looked
exactly the same. It's crazy shit.
So bizarre. You're talking about
it. That's a monarchy. North Korea,
that's a forum.
They yawned while 2 million
of their people starve to
death in the 90s they just
did. The elite was like pass the
salt. That's amazing. There's just no,
no power to revolt. And there's
a massive amount of patriotism.
It's not just patriotism,
it's a religion.
I mean the North Koreans believe
that the dear leader is a deity man.
They've done a good job of getting that.
Isn't that the same in Thailand?
They'll have a know Thailand
is actually amazing. Yes.
Thailand's king has s there's this,
he has a sort of, he's a semi deity.
But what's really amazing about Thailand
is that they've never been colonized
and, and it's because they've always
been really good at compromising.
They've always kind of been really good
at figuring out a way to kind of just be
the place where you come from. A
little R and r butterfly war man. That's,
that's in Laos. And Cambodia
and Vietnam, US, Eh,
we'll just align ourselves with the
u s cause it's easier and you know,
you can come over and have a good time.
And we got pretty girls and they're
just a really sweet people. Man.
It's amazing to have such a bad
ass fighting style. You know,
most people believe the best
standup fighting style in the world.
Moitai maybe man, they're
just, uh, they're there for,
for a group of people that are so butterflying
nice to you and so welcoming and it's
such a safe place, man. You walk
around, you never worry. You know, I,
you just drive around and
you're like, there's no crime.
You never worry about it.
Just a lot of really pretty girls that
you can, you know, date if you want.
But you know, you're in that. But I'm a,
I'm an actor guys, so just say, you know,
I was always doing my scenes.
Did you practice Tai while
you're there? Yes, I did.
One thing I wanted to do
do is go to a Paquette and a,
there's a tiger Moitai thing and do like,
I just don't know if it's safe enough
to bring my whole family down there.
I check here it is.
I know a lot of western nurse who
lived down there who loved it. Yeah.
It just seems very trippy risk.
I just want to do it so good to me.
Everything's a risk.
And I think it'd be,
it'd be amazing for your kids to see
a different part of the world. Yeah.
Murder and shit. Six flags. It's
pretty scary to some wild monkeys.
I think the US is way,
way more dangerous in some ways and a
lot of countries to visit and stuff like
that.
Tell me that about, um, uh, I was
talking about going to Mexico,
like they were going to Mexico on Cabo
San Lucas or one of those places and I
was like, uh, yeah, but I
mean, butterfly man, don't you worry
about, oh, Puerto Vallarta.
I was like,
you don't worry about like
all the violence that's
going on in Mexico. They go,
well, you know, there's violence in
America to, you know, go to Detroit,
you probably won't get caught up
in it. I'm like, yeah, okay, maybe,
but I know where Detroit is also those
drug cartels from what I hear are
actually starting to target tourists.
Like yeah,
they're starting to target tourist areas
because they're trying to get resorts
to pay them off because they extort
money from a bunch of different ways.
One of the things they do is kidnapped
people that are trying to uh,
get to America and then
they go back to the,
they killed a lot of people from
Guatemala and El Salvador. They just,
and these people were just people that
were trying to migrate to America.
Well they asked for money I guess,
and I said
no, and they just don't ask for a lot of
money and they said we're going to kill
them.
And they do it all the time.
And apparently some people pay and some
people don't. And the people that pay,
they get that money and they let the
people free would they kill a bunch of
butterflying people? Man, it's
really, really scary.
So bad and you see the videos of these
12 year old kids that they've hired for
assassins and the, you know,
they've completely butterfly these
kids heads. Really? Yeah.
And some of them were American kids.
They've hired the drug cartels have hard
and one of them got arrested recently
and you know the cell phone video footage
of him torturing people and it got
onto the internet.
It's,
it's horrendous stuff in and they
tortured people before they killed them,
you know, and this 12 year old kid
and you know, I mean they still evil,
they're taking violence
to a whole new level.
If you look at like what's going on
in the world and all this, you know,
the idea that we're over in Afghanistan
so that we don't have to fight it over
here. Hey, how about what
is right connected to us?
How about some shit you can drive to take
as Mexico you can butterflying drive to and
that puny ass butterflying wall,
that's really not going to stop
anybody from coming over to races.
But bigger question is, would you legalize
drugs? And doesn't that make sense?
The only problem is it's gotten to a
certain point where I think you have to
squash the problem before you
legalize drugs because the,
the cartels are so butterflying big. You
have to somehow, and it's working,
they're not doing it. So it's
a war. It's gotta be a war.
The drug cartels are gigantic
now, man, look, what do I know?
I'm talking out of my ass.
But the whole situation came about
for sure because drugs aren't leaving.
The problem with it being a war is that
the drug cartels are very much in sync
with the power structure with
the government itself. Sure.
It's all in the self apparently is a lot
of the kind of Mexican company itself
is propped up by the drug trade.
So holy. So if that's the case,
then how do you de legitimize, how'd
you figure out a way to make it work?
Do you legalize they're talking about
legalizing drugs in Mexico itself.
We criminalized everything in
Mexico. LSD, mushrooms. Oh yeah.
I mean knew you're not supposed
to sell it, but if you have it,
you don't go to jail.
As long as there's a demand.
And the risk of pedaling
that demand is that high.
You're going to have people who are bad
ass motherbutterflyers wanting to do whatever
it takes to get that money.
Scary.
I mean it's every role should have
learned about that in this country with
prohibition 1920s I,
you know,
we're lucky that marijuana has the
calming effect that it has because if it,
if it wasn't, you know, the whole
stoner culture and around behind it,
if that's why.
That's why I've always been,
I've just marveled at the fact that you
made alcohol, legal and weed illegal,
that it's like goes back to that reefer
madness ignorance. It's like, you know,
you're out of your butterflying bull.
It's also an issue of it's
been illegal for so long.
If they'd come out and say there's no
reason for it to have ever been illegal
now,
then you open up a whole can of worms
that just brought up the biggest and best
argument for any, for,
for a smaller government.
Whenever you pass a law, and I'm not
saying some laws don't need to be passed,
but you gotta remember one thing,
you pass any kind of law,
any kind of legislation, say what you
want about the Obama health care thing.
I don't know enough about it.
I'm not going to make a stand on it,
but just know that when you have a huge
government program and you pass laws
around that program,
what happens is a cottage industry grows
up around that law and a lot of people
develop an interest in economic
interest. Again, keeping that law act of,
that's why whenever you start
a government program, when it,
you started giving money to somebody or
whatever it might be, it doesn't go away.
And the Democrats themselves had passed
just something because it will never go
away and you'll be able to add
to it and, and that's, that is,
it's not about being right or left.
It's,
you better keep that in mind because
George Washington himself said,
men will invent laws to take their
own freedom away from themselves.
That's how people are,
you know,
you want to make the world
a really butterflying safe place.
You want to legislate everything. I don't
want to live in a country like that.
Fuck you. I want to take my own
personal responsibility for things.
Abso-Fucking-Lutely you know, and the,
the, the real problem with these, uh,
government, you know, when government
grows is that it very rarely shrinks.
It doesn't drink. It's expansive.
It's ever expansive in its course.
If it does two things, it takes taxes and
it passes laws. Do you need that? Yes.
The question is, what does w w w it's
about proportion. How much is too much?
That's the question.
This country was founded on the notion
that government is a necessary evil.
It doesn't mean you don't have it,
but stop telling me that government
and equalizing the playing field and
socially engineering equality is
what makes this country great. No,
it's butterflying not. The creates
so much resentment and
whenever you have, you know,
social engineering and, and you, you'd do
it for, you know, like you're like, well,
I think that affirmative
action is a wonderful idea.
I think the idea that you know,
you want to balance everything out
and give black people a chance to,
but whenever you have it set
up for one, I'm like, guys,
testing for the fire department
or something like that.
We're a black candidate doesn't have to
score as high as the worst thing is that
that is the worst thing for any black
person or anybody else. It's true.
It is assuming and suggesting to a black
person that they can compete mentally.
What does that do to
someone's self esteem?
What does it do to someone's self worth?
That is the most,
that is an a is the most insulting. That's
the most racist thing I can think of.
In fact, it's, well, it's ridiculous.
Did black people need us to lower the
playing field when it came to sports and
music? Look what they did with jazz.
Look what they've done with sports.
Jazz is the highest American art form.
Expression is primarily
at black expression.
Did blacks need government
programs for that? No.
They're just as capable of thinking
what the hell find out and they believe.
They do believe that it's an
issue that they should have, uh,
as much as close to an equal number
of people representative as they do in
society. If it's 10%, it's
close to as they can, but not
look for it when it's not.
The argument is op is equal. Equality
of opportunity. Oh, you know,
we know that that what people who are
in the affirmative action camp and I
understand it, they're saying,
look, we're looking for,
we're chronic trying to create an equal
opportunity for people and I understand
that and you do. It is an
uneven playing field. It is.
But the question is
what do you do about it?
And you better be very careful when
government comes in with solutions.
I think the best solution if
possible is to go in real early,
go in and have programs for
kids that are developing in,
in single family households or single
parent households where they're not
getting any attention and
they're not getting any love.
They're not getting any guidance and their
mom has to work and are doing that at
Harlan, apparently been very
successful. That would be the way.
There was a guy in Harlem who said,
we've got to get these kids before
they even get to kindergarten.
That's the movement.
And he did,
and he created a program that followed
them from kindergarten all the way
through college, and it's been, it's
called the Harlem Renaissance Project.
That's brilliant. That's brilliant.
And it's been amazing. Apparently.
That's really what it takes. I mean, well,
you start with someone
when they're 20 man, Mike,
God so much that you don't do
that. And you have, for example,
let's just take the black issue.
If you have a disproportionate number
of black men in jail, for example,
the problem with that is people
think it's not their problem.
You're wasting a huge segment of
your population. You're, you're,
you're not tapping into incredible,
incredible potential that you could be.
And so the question becomes what you're
right. I think you have to get it when,
when, when a boy is 14 he's
already lost in some ways. I mean,
it's very hard.
It's very hard to,
to kind of figure out how to deal
with that damage. Martial arts,
who's the best way,
whatever or whatever is the thing about
martial arts is you have to overcome.
You overcome great, scary things over and
over and over again. And in doing that,
uh,
develops character and builds character
and you almost want to make up for the
fact that, you know, you were
butterflyed up when you got into this.
You want to show a big
gap. You know, Josh,
Josh Waitzkin who was the chess
prodigy. He has a school. Uh, he does,
he has a school where he teaches
children math. No, I'm sorry, music,
chess and martial arts. And uh, and,
and what he does through those
three school, through those three,
through those three
venues, he, she, he didn't,
he's not teaching you even the martial
arts and music and the chest is secondary.
Most importantly is you're learning how
to learn. And, and he always says that,
that he wrote a book about, yeah,
it's a great book. He wrote,
I recommend everybody called
the art of learning special.
My friend Nathan and my friend Nathan
got me in contact with them and we've
exchanged emails back and forth.
And I want to, he's a great guy.
Him and train with him and when I'm
in New York I want to get them on the
podcast too. If I met him,
I met him in New York,
I had a lunch with them and the people
don't know. He's the guy who came up with,
I mean it was rather, excuse me, the,
the movie searching for Bobby Fisher
was based on his life, him as a child,
chess prodigy. And he went from
that to going into Kung Fu.
He became the king who's hands to
Time Push Hans Kung Fu champion,
which is a heavy stuff they
do, it's throws and, and, and,
and he was the first Westerner in China
to win it twice, two times in a row.
And now he's going to, for the Monday
I was I guess a phene with Jujitsu.
Now he trains with Marcella Garcia and he,
he developed this website called mg,
inaction mg and action.com mg being
Marcella Garcia. I believe that's the URL.
Check it. Marsia Garcia or Marcella Garcia
and action if you want to look at it,
if you're a Jujitsu fan. And what
the, uh, what the website is,
is he's broken down Jujitsu
moves just in study them.
The way he would do chess because
chess is so disciplined, you know,
just so we were talking about the Trump
and I mean chess players,
crap practice constantly and they go over
moves and they go over strategies and
the, you know, they have maps out
in their head. Well what would he,
this guy has done is put all
that same discipline to Jujitsu.
And so he has Marcel Garcia, his entire
repertoire of techniques and you know,
all sorts of different
sweeps and you know,
arm bars and all these different
things and in chains and how they go.
And he has like this website where you
can just sign up and you can learn.
I mean basically like you and your
friends, you know, if you wanted to,
you could sign up for it,
get an Internet connection,
get a laptop and have like a mat and
your living room and you and your buddy
could learn Jujitsu friends from school.
Man, it's butterflying amazing, man. Yeah,
I mean, it's amazing. And for
for people that studied Jujitsu,
it's fascinating because he'll go
over the finer nuances of a technique.
You're like, butterfly, that's
what I've been doing wrong.
Because a lot of Jujitsu
is leverage and it's not.
Most of it's not about strength,
it's about being in the proper position
and much smaller people can defeat much
larger people because of the technique,
but it's like little subtle things that
techniques sometimes you miss and so
these videos are like real
masters like Marcella Garcia.
This is like a Sarah Garcia. I
asked, I asked Josh, I was like,
what's it like to roll with them? Do
you ever get him? You ever catch him?
And he's like, no, I never get him.
No. He's on another level, man.
He moves so fast that what it is.
He's so good. He's still sharp,
so sharp. You can't have
any room for error. See,
with a lot of Jujitsu it's like how much
room for error you're going to give me.
Are you going to leave
openings for under hooks?
Are you going to slip to your back? Are
you going to, you know, let me sweep you.
Are you going to give up cause you don't
want to fight anymore and go to your
back and tried to get
them in on your guard.
It's like there's like a little
battle going on. Like say,
how much do you have left in the tank?
Well,
when you get to a level
like Marcella Garcia,
instead of all that
nonsense in your brain,
it's this super tuned killing
machine that moves so fast.
You can't even like, literally, he's
not even thinking about his movements.
He's drilled them to the point where
they're so pinpoint and precise action.
It's all reaction idea of getting to
your back. And then before you know it,
his hooks are in. He's got his arm across
your neck. It's happened in Millis, Josh,
Josh Waitzkin. Cause that
chunking where, where,
what he's seen so much that he
can start thinking in chunks,
like he can think in systems and
you're thinking move to move.
And He's thinking in a
system like he's thinking in,
in literally like six move chunks.
Uh,
and he's also watching you and can, are
already predict what you're going to do.
And because he's been doing it so long,
he gets into your mind.
So he's watching you like,
do these clunky,
here I come, I'm going to do
this. And he goes, I've seen that.
I've seen that a thousand
times and I'm going to do this,
but I'm already going
to do this after that.
And so it's like Josh said that when he
would play chess with guys who weren't
as advanced as he,
he seen the whole board.
And the reason he's seeing six or seven
moves ahead of time is because he's able
to chunk is chunking. He's seeing
things in, in, uh, I dunno,
I guess that's what he called it. He
just called it like, I'm five, move
six, move, um, uh, blocks of time.
That's one of the things about Eddie
style or the way Eddie teaches Eddie
teachers, instead of just teaching a
move, he teaches a whole chain of moves.
I killed,
teach a certain paths to get to a certain
position and then to there and then
always to a finish. But it's like
four or five moves in advance.
And sometimes there's, there's alternate
endings or alternate branches. Like,
what happens if you lose this arm?
Now you've got to go to
this and then you know,
so in your mind when you're rolling
and you get to certain specific areas,
you have this already, Matt, he's
already mapped it out for you. Well,
it's like the way he teaches. Wow. Yeah.
I think it's a really smart way to do it.
There's a lot of that with my love. Megan
Love making love making. Tell me more.
You get an echo.
Did you, you channeling Craig
Shoemaker, is that what I'm doing?
A careful to love master
or any of his stuff? No,
old school.
Speaking of standard,
what are you up for?
Three hours. We've been,
we've been talking for three hours and
I got that long. We didn't start on,
it's like three 30,
but it might've been our best
podcast ever. Thank you to all the people
that are listening. Thank you very much.
We really appreciate it.
We appreciate all the kind words on
Twitter and all that good shit. And, um,
you know, we love doing it
and I'm glad you guys enjoy
it. And it's, uh, there's a,
you know,
I'm,
I'm getting in contact with a fascinating
group of human beings through Twitter,
through the message board,
through Facebook. Yeah.
There's a few douchebags slipped through
the cracks, but for the most part,
there's a lot of really
interesting people. And you
know, I said that about, uh,
what are you playing in the
background? Crazy. Hm. What does that,
that's butterflying grants. It sounds
terrible. Stop that. Shuts the bangles.
Walk like an Egyptian isn't. Yeah,
stop it Brian. Just stop it. Cut It.
Loose pride. Anyway, thank you everybody.
We appreciate it all very much and we
enjoyed doing it and uh, you know, um,
I'm a very lucky person and I'm very lucky
to have people like Brian Cowen in my
life because, uh, you know, it's a,
it makes life very interesting to have
interesting friends and I know that
there's a lot of people out there that
you don't have a lot of cool people to
talk to. And, uh,
I appreciate everything you get down to
the podcast and it resonates with me,
Brian and my friend.
Thank you very much.
Thanks for having me. Always an honor.
Always an honor to be with you, my friend.
You're the best man. Your favorite
guest of all time. Thank you sir.
Sorry everybody else that's
thanks to the fleshlight. Uh,
go to Joe rogan.net and click the link
and put in Rogan is your code and you get
15% off your masturbation.
Okay.
It's a discount and you'll
blow giant loads inside this
rubber vagina. Yeah. Love
it. So did you ever use your phone?
I haven't used it, man. Really?
The music now lies you masturbated
since that night? No. No.
Save your seat in the Christian,
uh, save a seat. Yeah.
And what's the most times you've heard,
well,
how many days of roads there were
saved your seat? I used to do it a lot.
I used to do, when I was doing taekwondo,
I was like, that's cool. I might take.
My new teacher told me that that's,
you know, so I'd like try to do it,
but I was like 21 I just
be like butterflying two hours.
[inaudible] that's my weakest muscle ever.
The holding the load back,
muscle weakness, muscle. It's so
hard. Still still. I want to butterflying,
I still wake up with a hard
on every morning they say
he's supposed to go tantra,
squeeze it.
You look,
you never talked about that in inner area
and keep your can keep your Tanto I'm
blowing heavy loads
and I'm screaming filthy, filthy
when I do it and on that. No,
I'm not [inaudible] gentlemen.
Thank you. February 4th
Mandalay Bay theater. Me,
Ari, Shaffir, Joey Diaz,
the show of the year.
We're butterflying fired up for it.
Some tickets are still available.
They're going quick.
So get in on it where we're
excited about it. I'm,
I've never been to this theater, but
it's big and it's awesome. And it's the,
the day before the UFC,
which is February 5th so there's
going to be a lot of freaks in town.
It's going to be crazy.
I predict a lot of skull tee shirts.
A lot of butterflying flaming foil. Brian
red band. Follow him on Twitter.
Ladies and gentlemen, he's trying to get
over 21,000. What do you have right now,
dude?
Like
10,000, 10,000 Ladies
and gentlemen, we can,
we can get him over 21 and
Brian Count on Twitter.
It's Bryan with a y because it's, it's,
you know, it's just, it's interesting.
It's this, right? I'm gonna Start, I'm
gonna start being on Twitter, Mario.
Are you do tweet at all? Tweet like,
like your act, you tweeted like,
like you do on stage.
I just tweet like whenever I,
if I come with something funny, I'll tweet
it. That's it. There's nothing about me.
That's interesting.
I'm not going to say anything and it's,
what are you talking about man? You're
one of the most interesting friends. Well,
thank you. Don't be down at
yourself brother. Um, so one,
can anybody see you
next when you stand up?
I'm starting a news TV show called
Death Valley on MTV. Uh, I and I,
it's a shot like cost, but
we kill werewolves, vampires
and zombies in the valley.
And I play the chief of police who's a
complete retard and a complete pervert.
And it's a really fun part
and it's called Death Valley.
And it could be really funny.
It's a comedy. It's comedy,
but totally gory and really violent.
Really? Yeah. It's really funny.
Under the Werewolf's look, do they look
cool? Amazing man. The pilot looks,
looked amazing. They picked up 12
episodes on MTV. I'll send you,
I'll give you my, that sounds awesome.
Yeah, that's right up my alley.
It's going to be really cool. And you
play a crazy sheriff chief of police.
He's an, and he's always happy. He always
has a hand. Squeezer really tight shirts.
He's a butterflying loser. And so
you're happy with it? Yeah,
I looked like I muscular don not
so sad and it's a good time, man.
It's a good time. It starts on MTV. When,
when does it start airing a, it starts,
uh, well we start shooting a January 31st.
I'm not sure what the air date is. Okay.
A couple in the Canon and start airing.
Okay. But you, you shot a pilot already.
You'll show me that.
Yeah,
it was for you bitches got the inside
scoop funny and silly and you know,
we'll see what, all right, we'll be
back next week. We're trying to get
Gilbert and Gilbert. We might, we might,
uh, yeah, we still got his calm. Yeah,
he's one of my favorite comedians.
Touring inspirational. Very,
very funny guy and just a
cool dude. And he's um, uh,
he's in town this week when he tried to
get him in and we might do another one
this week. We might do another one
Friday maybe. So, uh, other than that,
thank you very much everybody.
That's it.
Just mad love to all my bitches hollow
and uh, see you guys soon. Soon.
Eventually you're not going anywhere.
We're going to keep this shit rolling.
We're going to keep this shit
rolling on bitches. Oh Shit.
Right now. Well, people
watching right now, there's
1200 people. Hello my friends.
That's usually where we get live. And then
afterwards it's always a, you know, 20,
30,000 or something
like that. And then iTunes
a lot more than that though.
Itunes is where most of the people is
to really, we're still talking to you.
People like you're not there. I love
it, but sure. Then I love you. Goodbye.