Let's do the countdown is false
calendar.
You go four,
three,
two,
one.
And we're live.
What's up my brother quick.
I know how it goes.
I like it.
Very efficient.
I could just start,
just start.
Boom.
Make it happen.
Like it.
So things are getting weird real quick
when you're thinking about this,
this uh,
orange fella.
I mean I got to say for me it's the best
time ever to start a news service and we
started a daily show about a month
before and it just is like,
wow.
And you do want it on vice,
on your channel?
No,
it's with HBO.
It's a daily news show on HBO.
It's like we were doing so well on
weekly.
I don't know about shit.
Why didn't I know about this?
We did our weekly show,
right?
And that was doing well.
So they gave us a daily show and they
were going to just put it on HBO now and
go.
But then it was doing.
So they put us on,
on the air,
on TV.
So it's every night.
This is the best possible compliment for
your show.
Your show is like,
what?
I would expect someone who's never done
a show before to do,
if you just gave them a fuck load of
money,
that's probably.
That's exactly hosts who have really
never hosted anything before and gave
them a fuck load of money that the whole
thing feels so [inaudible].
The wrong word to use is unprofessional
but polished.
Unpolished,
unfakeable.
There you go.
That's unpolished is no one talking like
this.
There's no Brian Williams.
We didn't know what we were doing and
when we started.
Perfect.
The,
the criticisms came.
My favorite was from the New York Times
was it's just a bunch of hipsters and
skinny jeans and tattoos,
high fiving in war zones.
And I was like,
if,
if you aren't criticizing the news are
criticizing the truth or the facts of
the stories.
You're just criticizing that.
We have tattoos and we don't look like
you.
We want.
Yeah,
fuck you.
Perfect.
So that was our first season and yeah,
ever since I wouldn't they celebrate
that.
That's really interesting.
It's really interesting to see a bunch
of young Weirdos in war zones.
You know,
there was one that you guys did.
I don't remember the location it was,
but one of the reporters was out there
and he had a flak jacket on and he was
surrounded by all these rebels in there,
in these bombed out buildings and you
hear,
you hear things going off in the
distance and he's like kind of calmly
explaining,
okay,
so what's going on is they're there,
they're bombing the location very close
to us and they over there and he's like
pointing at.
I'm like,
hopefully better understand that guys,
I think it was Ben Anderson,
I just,
we just did a thing on the resurgence of
the Taliban in Afghanistan and how it's
basically going back to the same borders
that it was pre-invasion and that he's
under fire the whole time and he's just
like,
you know,
and he just goes down on one knee and he
keeps talking,
unfazed.
And as they're driving back there,
they're clearing out these cds and
they're just pulling it with a rope and,
and,
and like pulling out.
The IED is with a rope and he's just
standing there calmly knowing they don't
blow up.
No,
he's calmly like talking to the camera
as all this shit is happening and you're
like,
this guy's fucking special dude on
antidepressants.
He,
I asked him about it one time and he
goes,
you know,
I have this thing where there's like a
32nd lag between like some guy that you
want to die and he's got a 32nd lag
between when he realizes that and so he,
he,
he comes across as just to have like,
you know,
an unflappable.
But wow,
it's a genetic thing.
He's also fucking the best word during
list out there.
So it didn't fall on his head as a
youth.
Is there something missing?
Is there a broken part and he's just,
he's built for the job,
for the job.
Well,
I'd like to see that in this day and
age.
I mean we're dealing with this weird
time where the president of United
States points to CNN and says,
I'm not talking to you,
your fake news.
And then the meme comes,
you know what?
The sunglasses fall down,
but the thug life with him and you,
you do get a lot of fake news though.
Yeah,
getting a lot of these unsubstantiated
reports about him with prostitutes in
urine and they're talking about it on
the fucking news,
which is unprecedented.
There's fake news on both sides.
That's the problem and there's so much
of it that it's,
it's,
it's almost impossible to wade through
it all.
Yeah.
And you know,
for us when after the election everybody
came to me and said,
what should we do?
And I said we got to just be logical
fact based,
middle of the road press record,
nonpolitical,
nonpartisan.
None of this shit.
We just go out there and do it.
The problem is,
you know,
we view ourself as centrists and sort of
press record all that stuff,
but if the world takes a sort of giant
leap to the right with,
you know,
fake news and all this crazy shit
happening,
then you're sitting there sort of going,
well all of a sudden we were putting
this position.
Like for me,
I always,
I always bring it up and say like,
I'm an environmentalist because there's
a boogeyman.
They're like,
we all get fucked.
If the environment gets fucked.
And there's,
there's a boogeyman that we can that we
can sort of go against and it's good for
everybody,
you know,
whatever.
And the problem is,
is,
I dunno when environmentalism became a
left thing.
It should be for anyone who's saying
anyone who's smart and you know,
I spend time like going back to war,
like when you spend a lot of time in war
zones,
the one thing when you talk to people in
those war zones is wharf is fucked.
It's not fun.
It's not heroic.
It's not like a manly shot in the
catheter bags and you're fucked up and
you have your head's missing.
Your ass is missing,
your balls are.
And so it's,
when you go to these things you never
want to go back kind of thing.
You know,
when you talk about the environment,
when you talk to the scientists,
they're all like,
well,
of course it's a global scientific
consensus.
Of course it is.
And then I did this piece this year on
in season five.
It's going to be the first piece.
And I'm like,
I literally don't understand what the
fuck is happening here.
Because if you talk to every scientist
now,
they're terrible at getting information
scientists,
but they're like,
well,
that's not my fucking job.
My job is to do science.
I don't fucking know.
So,
but you know,
there's this global scientific consensus
of,
you know,
global warming,
97 percent,
which never happens in any science,
right?
Ever.
But there's all this,
I'm a doubt not all over the world,
but it a lot in America still.
So we looked at it,
we said,
why,
what the fuck is happening here?
And there's now three age,
three attorney,
attorneys general with 20 other in
support have come out for this lawsuit
now against Exxon Ceo of Exxon is now
our secretary of state rex tillerson.
And so the,
what happened was they knew in the
seventies and eighties that fossil fuel,
um,
uh,
you know,
burning fossil fuels,
carbon in the air,
carbon emission caused global warming
and was a factor for global warming.
And then they realized this is going to
be bad for business.
So in the eighties and nineties and now
they spend billions of dollars on,
on,
you know,
discrediting the science.
That's the whole thing.
Well,
there's no consensus,
there's no consensus.
Uh,
that's the,
that's the thing.
And they spend billions of dollars to do
it.
There is a consensus.
Does he told him I did.
Amazing.
And so highlights that.
Yeah,
exactly.
And a lot of people,
it's the same people.
What that highlights is it's the exact
same scientist and the exact same people
and groups and uh,
more like smoking spokespeople and went
after cigarettes,
cigarettes,
it.
Well,
in some cases the same scientist,
they said,
oh,
well it's exact same thing.
It's questioned the science.
It's,
you know,
well there's not,
we can't really figure out smoking.
Lung cancer could be anything and do it
loudly and concisely with quick
sentences where they're very well
prepared and they did the exact same
thing with global warming.
And that's why when you come here and
you talk to people and say,
you know,
look,
we have to do this,
we have to know science isn't settled.
Fuck you.
And you're like,
it's like back in the day when your
mouth would open and a cigarette would
come out and say,
smoking is good for you.
Or whatever.
It's like an oil can comes out.
You're like,
no,
the science isn't settled yet.
This whole argument that the science
isn't settled yet.
Like you said,
it's being perpetrated by the people
that can profit on the science not being
settled here and that gets really scary
because people being fucking do and it
gets scary is it makes it real
convenient for right wing people who
just classically think and vote and
behave right wing to just adopt that
thinking and then and thing and you're
like,
it's not a fucking left thing like
you're a hundred like to go ahead.
It's an everybody who likes to go
outside thing.
It's like everybody likes to hunt thing.
Everyone likes to swim.
Thing is everyone like that served a
drink.
Fucking water,
right?
I mean,
did you see this?
There was a new report that came out
today about the infrastructure in terms
of the water supply,
the pipes that we have that the water's
being carried with rotting out your
place in this country.
It will cost a trillion dollars,
but they're saying that flint,
but what
happened in flint could happen in a lot
of the pope.
It's just old infrastructure.
It needs to be replaced,
you know,
and here it is national.
Flint's America's one point 2 million
miles of deteriorating lead pipes and
they'll cost $1,000,000,000,000
to fix it.
One thing that I like about trump is
that he has been saying that he wants to
address the infrastructure and he wants
to put people to work fixing all the
problems that exist and creating jobs by
fixing all these types of.
Which is another famous presidents at
the same thing.
Which one?
FDR.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Oh,
he's a good guy,
right?
Very good one.
It's hard to say who's a good one.
We only liked the ones that get shot.
I had like a whole bit about that,
but we like Kennedy and like Lincoln.
Well,
it's interesting
because the president,
if you really look at it traditionally,
you know,
there,
there are big power is right now is when
you do appointees or when you get a
judge through or when you do an
appointee,
you know,
you,
you put your cabinet together,
then the cabinet as power and the
president goes on to opening bridges and
flying around the world and shaking
hands and kissing babies.
And I think that that's what,
you know,
what we said is we're not going to,
as a news agency,
look at the bloombastic or the,
uh,
the titillating headlines or they,
oh my God,
he said that we're going to look after a
policy.
We're going to look at what is the EPA
with a guy who runs the EPA,
who tried to sue the EPA and shut it
down.
What is the energy?
What is the Department of Energy look
like with Rick Perry?
Who as when he ran for president,
said I would,
I would shut down the Department of
Energy.
What does that look with him actually
running it or sessions?
Who Actually,
uh,
is now the attorney general who sued the
government many times against climate
change reform or rex Tillerson,
you know,
who ran the largest fossil fuel
companies will now being secretary of
state.
So we're looking more at just policy
what policy changes because of this
cabinet,
etc.
Etc.
YEah,
it's really weird.
It's like
everybody thought this was going to be
this sort of,
uh,
get rid of political correctness,
stop all these whiny crybaby liberals.
And then once he got into office,
a lot of the same people that I talked
to that were kind of in supportive.
I'm just kind of stepped back and went
whoa.
Like alreadY,
like right away,
keystone pipeline,
the dakota access,
abortion,
abortion.
I mean they're,
they're cutting,
they're cutting insurance,
pay a payment,
paying of abor.
How would you say that?
The funding of abortion.
It's like you can't get an abortion with
insurance anymore.
Yeah.
is that what they have?
They passed that has that been passed?
Which is uh,
you know,
obviously for some people that don't
like abortions,
it's a very touchy subject,
which ironically,
the same people who love war.
It's very strange.
I don't want you killing babies.
They don't mind killing people.
Once they're full,
they can go fuck themselves,
especially if they live in some other
spot and he's really fucking building
wall.
It wasn't just rhetoric.
Yeah,
I mean it's,
it's,
he's a guy who got elected on a
populist,
uh,
platforms.
So he's going to do some of those
things.
It's going to be interesting.
I mean,
I think two things about it.
I don't really think so much about trump
as much as two things.
I think a,
it shows a sort of generational divide,
you know,
it's not just trump [inaudible] you
looked,
you saw in brexit,
you're seeing it in France,
you saw natalie,
you're seeing it,
you know,
in many countries around the world where
you have the largest cohort,
the largest demographic is gen y,
but the socioeconomic and political
power is mostly still controlled by the
boomers.
So you have this sort of generational
divide.
And what happened in America was,
you know,
the,
the gen y was more an fractured,
you know,
we talked a little bit,
but there's a fractured because of
bernie sanders and hillary and people
just didn't like hillary.
And so,
and by the way she's,
you know,
an older generation as well.
And then trump was the sort of baby
boomers like living in the gated
community saying we don't want all that
bad shit to happen.
I understand why people don't want to
believe environmental change because
it's scary and it's bad.
And it's like,
fuck,
I don't want to believe in that,
so I'm not going to believe in that.
And so I think,
but you have this generational divide
and now what you have is just sort of
this backlash of kids going like in
brexit,
they're like,
what the fuck?
You guys vote to fucking leave europe
and now fucked,
you know,
hold on a second.
And now I think you're going to get
that.
So I think it's,
it's sort of a global thing and I think
it's also young people are,
are,
are getting upset and also they're
learning.
You should have fucking voted.
Yeah,
I,
I've,
I've talked to quite a few people that
were pissed off that didn't vote.
Yeah.
Like,
well that's kind of weird.
And they were like,
well,
California is going to hillary anyway.
Uh,
okay.
Sorta.
Yeah.
Well that's the problem.
Like,
you know,
California legalized recreational
marijuana and a sessions.
Yeah.
He doesn't know.
He doesn't want it.
He literally is on record saying they
good people don't smoke marijuana.
What about drink scotch?
People drink scotch.
What about cigars?
And good people smoke cigars,
jeff.
And as I work and I think that that's,
you know,
if you look at it every,
I think young people know what side of
history they want to be on.
like we're all,
like,
we all know it's going to be legalized.
We all know what's going to be there.
It's going to be like say three years,
maybe five years,
and then all this shit,
all those people in jail don't have to
be in jail.
All this money,
all this tax money could go and look at
what happened in Colorado.
All the cartels and all the,
all this stuff.
It's just like it's going to happen.
So anybody who comes along and says,
nope,
fuck that.
You're like,
well,
you're on the wrong side of history,
brother.
Well,
he's lifted up.
What trump has said is that he's going
to leave it up to the states,
so if he leaves it up to the states,
it's just going to go across the country
and then what are they going to do
federally and once it becomes state
legal everywhere,
and then the federal government still
says it's illegal.
What did they do then?
I mean,
did they change then because they have
to change a lot because of the money
they have to change law because in
Colorado it's legal but you can't bank
it,
you know,
it's a fucking mess.
SubmAssive armored cars and guys with
guns.
I know a lot of guys who are former
seals and and you know guys who worked
for blackwater and now they're fucking
holding guns at at we chops because they
got a million dollars in cash in the
bank,
which is bad enough with one state,
but when it's 20 states,
fucking places in that state,
think about one state.
How many marks do you have weren't
running around and it all has to be
cashed,
but to grow your own shit in Colorado
too.
That's the other thing.
You're not buying it from somebody.
You have to grow it if you're selling
it.
So they're creating a dangerous
situation and people have already been
robbed.
Correct.
And you know,
the whole thing.
To me it was really disappointing when
the dea didn't change the classification
from schedule one in august,
like they,
they had the opportunity.
All the evidence was there.
They know the evidence is there and they
fucking lied about it.
And this is under obama also.
The problem with that is because it's
scheduled,
you can't do research on cancer,
you know,
all of those cbd stuff that you know
that's coming out now.
It's not psychoactive,
which is so important for people who
have issues like arthritis,
and I had joe valtellIna here was a
former kickboxing champion.
He's a commentator now for glory.
He told me that he was locked in a room
after one of his concussions from his
last fight,
locked in a room in the dark for three
weeks because you couldn't even see the
light on the power button on a cell
phone to charge a cell phone like the
little red light where it shows you that
that would give him a headache.
And so cbd oil cured and it's not
illegal.
And that's the thing is again,
what side of history do beyond like we
know all of this stuff.
We know where it's going,
why the fuck are we slowing down now?
Well,
it's a bunch of old people.
That's really what it is.
It's a bunch of old people who don't get
high and you know,
and they're scared of it and instead of
looking at it pragmatically,
objectively looking at the science,
they're looking at it like some goddamn
19 fifties episode of dragnet.
You know,
joe frIday's coming in for losers.
It's frustrated.
Are you a loser mickey?
That's,
that's really what's going on.
It's,
it's very strange.
Yeah.
We did this story,
uh,
you know,
the kings of cannabis,
these guys,
they're like the seed hunters.
They fly around the world and they find
like the best seed strains and then they
go back to holland and they make like
they wanted the cannabis cup like six,
eight years in a row that,
you know,
they did white widow,
the cannabis cup real quick.
I was one of the fucking judges.
We've know these guys are two dutch
guys.
These guys not only did it once,
I'm going to do it again.
It's a farce.
Okay?
This is what they give you.
They give you,
you know how those old ladies to take
pills,
like if you're a,
like someone else to take your arthritis
medication and you have like seven days,
monday,
tuesday,
wednesday,
thursday,
those little things.
They give you one of those.
Each one of those things has weed and
you just start fucking smoking.
You're going to watch one,
three races.
You have no idea.
The first of hits you're on and you just
fucking hammer in it and then
everybody's talking in this ridiculous
jargon.
They're like,
oh,
this is really tasty.
They're a fucking super annoying and
stinky.
And talking about the cannabis community
had this weird conversation with this
one dude who won.
When the fuck knows,
I don't even know who I voted for.
I have no idea.
I was so high afterwards.
I was having out of body experiences
because people were giving me cookies
and candies.
It was one of,
if not the highest,
one of the highest I've ever been in my
life.
Maybe the highest because we were at
this place on melrose.
It was a,
um,
a head shop and in the back they had
this pop thing and um,
it was just filled with fucking people
in this.
No ventilation,
just filled with pot smoker.
and this is an amsterdam los angeles.
They did it in La and they're passing
around bongs and pipes and cookies and
cakes and they had security there to
make sure no one would come and they had
it all blocked off and they did a smart
job like the way they handled it,
but as far as like actually judging
what's the best pot,
the fuck outta here.
No one has any idea.
It's like giving you seven glasses of
whiskey and then telling you to drink
some wine.
What wine do you like,
shane?
That's generally how it is.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's how most of our podcasts are now.
Men.
I judged it and it was.
I don't remember what I judged.
I don't remember what the pot was like.
I was.
I was a poor judge and everybody else
has a poor judge too,
but I'm being honest about it.
There you go.
If you wanted a judge,
can't.
You wanted to have a real cannabis cup.
You would give someone a strain for a
week and then give them another strain
for a week and have make them keep a
journal and then make them send in that
journal like,
this is my experience on this is how
much I smoke,
this is what it felt like.
Body high,
head,
strong.
Some of that shit.
It's like,
it's my stuff.
It's getting to a strange place now for
sure.
Because what's interesting to me is when
people who don't smoke it,
smoke it,
then I get to see because we're,
our tolerance is so high because we
smoke it.
I smoke it almost every Day.
At least five days a week.
I probably smoke weed.
So when I see people that tried for the
first time and you see that terrified
look in their eye when they're
confronted with their own mortality and
they feel the earth spinning and they're
like,
jesus,
I've got a question for you.
Mr.
Smoker?
Okay.
Because my problem is I'm an ex smoker,
not smoker.
I'm uh,
currently I'm an ex smoker,
smoker.
And so smoking always makes me want to
smoke cigarettes a,
b.
So I do like a,
you know,
they have all the different things now,
the one,
the one I like is uh,
is this high cbd sort of,
uh,
but it's,
it gets you.
Hi honey.
Oh yeah.
And it's fucking awesome.
Whatever you need I can get.
but the thing is,
I've got a question because I was
thinking about this yesterday because I,
I'm,
I'm like reading all about,
you know,
how it stops cancer.
ThIs is great for this and great for
that and stuff.
So I'm like,
fuck yeah,
but isn't smoking it's still bad for
you?
No,
apparently not.
In that it's actually scientists.
Zack,
it actually acts as an expectorant on
your lungs.
It's actually good for people that have
emphysema.
issues with their lungs,
which is really strange.
Asthma,
really good for asthma.
Smoking weed.
Yeah.
Crazy.
It doesn't seem to make sense.
No,
it more much better though because
smoking is still kind of harsh,
but the effect of the cannabis smoke,
cannabis smoke is not toxic the same way
as cigarette smoke is.
And one of the reasons why cigarette
smoke is toxic is not just the tobacco,
which is 599 fucking chemicals or
whatever the hell it is.
Now,
marijuana users have good lungs for
transplanting.
So if you get high walk off a building,
whoops man.
Yeah,
you're.
Your lungs are good,
but you don't have to smoke it.
Here's,
here's what I'm down with these fucking
things that I got charged and right
here,
these vape pens,
some of them suck because some of them,
the ones that look like like an
e-cigarette,
those suck.
They don't have enough juice.
They're not powerful enough.
You want one that has a really good
pull.
There you go.
That's good because these are you high
like getting high,
getting high.
Whereas the other ones,
he got to keep hitting them over and
over and over and over again to get
high.
These mother fuckers get hot because
that batteries,
fat cells,
fat,
that battery is as much fat are the
other ones when you get the ones that
are skinny like this.
The other problem with the ones that are
skinny,
ms.you
get a lot of duds.
They make it.
A lot of them in China,
sorry China,
but a lot of them suck band,
like my friend gina who sells me
everything,
he gave me three.
No four pens and three of them were
duds.
Nearly three out of four were duds.
If it was all legal than exactly what
your quality control to control.
Yeah.
They were packaged to see the whole deal
is that are packaged ready and when
you're getting these ones that are
prepackaged,
like you throw them away when they're
done,
it's very wasteful.
So this you just get this little
cartridge.
You slide the cartridge into this big
fat battery thing and there were no
scared.
Was scared it a good boy.
It's a good time,
man.
It's a good time for that and it's a
good time for people to do.
The problem is the research is still.
Federal research is still impossible.
Doing real,
real hardcore research on large scale
research nationwide and we should be
going anything that shows some promise
re cancer.
We should be going whole hog after in
the fact that we're not as just
ridiculous.
I'm worried that he has such trump such
incredible connections to money and
that,
you know,
all the good parts that's going to come
from that,
like his no nonsense approach to
infrastructure,
wanting to rebuild a lot of things,
put a lot of people to work because of
that and a lot of benefit from that.
WHat scares me is that money connection
with the pharmaceutical companies who
have just gone way,
way out of their way to try to stifle
marijuana research at every possible
turn and legalization at every possible
turn and it's criminal.
What would they do is awful,
you know,
the.
Because when you make something illegal,
it's not just making something illegal,
which is why I had,
I had to like drill this into the head
of a friend of mine who was pro hillary
and uh,
you know,
he's asking me why I'm upset with her.
And I said,
look dude,
there's a fucking email that was leaked.
The wiki leaks email that said she's
against marijuana in every sense of the
word.
This was a,
she was making a promise to some
organization,
I don't remember who it was,
but they were asking her,
what is our stance on marijuana?
She's againsT it in every sense of the
word.
How could you be?
That's like saying I'm against peanut
butter in every sense of the word.
You know,
like what are you a monster?
You want people to go to jail for peanut
butter.
You know,
like the problem is,
it's not just that you don't like it,
which I'm fine with.
The problem is you could make people get
locked in a cage.
That's a crime.
It's a crime.
We know this is an oculus.
I of just hit it.
We're having a conversation.
There's no problems.
This is not some devil weed.
It's not going to ruin lives.
I pay taxes,
I have a family.
Everything's fine.
I wake up when the alarm goes off,
so we're when fed bullshit.
And when someone who In the position of
running for president,
like hilary says something crazy like
that,
she's against marijuana legalization in
every sense of the word.
That means some people are going to go
to jail.
That means people are going to get shot.
That means more mexican drug gangs are
going to ship more illegal product over
here.
The church is being done.
No research is being done.
People are going to die from cancer that
don't have to die.
People are going to get diseases.
They don't have it.
This is my problem because again,
it's what side of history do you want to
be on and I think that most people who
grew up the way we did it or seen people
are just saying what the fuck?
Exactly.
Exactly,
and as you said,
there's five different positive aspects
for it and by the way,
we all know where it's going.
If it doesn't go in that direction,
we're going to have a fucking revolution
and they need to understand that what
you saw with that women's march when the
day after trump was inaugurated,
when you see millions of people,
there's a million people in la,
they expected 80,000,
970,000
fucking people showed up.
Whitney coming sent me some pictures
when she was there.
I was like,
holy shit,
this is crazy.
That kind of movement,
it's not just connected to women's
rights and it certainly is at that that
day,
but it's a mindset.
It's a mindset of protesting and
fighting what they think is wrong and
it's going to spread across the board.
So we're in a weird fucking bipolar
situation.
This country bipolar situation,
the country in a lot of ways.
You know,
there's a lot of you fucking liberal
crybabies bunch of loops.
This is the whole thing is that you,
you know,
I did a special on,
on dysfunctions picture from whitney
cummings,
instagram.
Geez,
that's a lot of people will actually.
It's good because,
you know,
I think americans had forgotten how to
sort of protest americans had forgotten
that this is part of democracy and all
this stuff.
We've been sort of,
You know,
talk radioing our,
our,
uh,
our anger,
you know,
in quiet and you know,
and I think it's good to go out and
protest if you believe in it.
A,
b,
If you,
if you sort of look at what's happening
politically,
you know,
I did a thing on a house divided.
And what's interesting is if you ever do
anything on Israel and the palestinian
pro palestinian people go after you.
If you ever been on palestine,
the israeli people go after everybody.
Like you can never do anything right.
It's the same thing when you do sort of,
you know,
politics here.
And we were,
you know,
we,
we thought we were incredibly even
handed.
We gave republicans the same amount of
time as the democrats and the democrats
were like,
well,
you made the republicans look too good.
And,
but the thing is,
is when you look at it,
you say,
you know,
it's,
it's so broken that they used to be just
like a pendulum swings,
pendulum swings.
But now what's going to happen is that
trump gets in,
he's going to undo a lot of the last
eight years than the dams.
When it swings to them,
we'll undo what he undid.
So it's not doing nothing.
Now it's going backwards.
And so you're sitting there saying,
there's a lot of shit that we got to
solve and we can't solve it if we just
keep going backwards politically.
And I think that's why there's so much
frustration is because you're sitting
there going,
let's unwind what they did for the past
eight years and then someone else can
get in and unwind.
But we unwound.
We have a real problem as human beings
in getting into that team mentality.
There is so many of us on the left that
have so many.
We,
we,
we agree with so many things at the
right stands for like.
And there's so many on the right that
agree with so many on the left,
you know,
I mean I'm more left than I am,
right.
But I'm pretty fucking right.
I'm riding on a lot of shit.
Like gun control
and your,
your,
your essential trust,
which is hopefully what most people
should be.
That they can see the logic in both
sides.
Yeah.
The problem is when you get too far to
the left or too far to the right,
it's crazy.
And what?
WhaT's worrisome?
And it just,
you know,
farther look in France,
France elect a socialist,
you know,
pm.
and then all of a sudden the front
nationale who were a joke become the
leaders in the next election.
Yeah.
From nationality or like,
you know,
super.
Right,
right,
right.
And so you sit there and say,
okay,
well everyone's moving far apart.
It's best when we're all just fucking
working together.
The economy's doing well,
we're all getting it done.
And so you know,
we're sitting in,
in the sort of logical middle.
That's the problem with going too far to
any side.
And that's like you can be on either
side on,
on issues and all this stuff.
But if you go too far and you're to sort
of dogmatic on either side,
that's when it gets scary
and it gets scary.
Quick.
Get scary real quick.
As soon as one incident happens and it
gets scary.
And France,
imagine scary in this country,
will you have more guns than you have
human beings.
That's it.
You know?
And that's what people will latch with
the gun problem.
It's not a gun problem,
it's a human being problem.
And if we address it as a gun problem,
you're gonna make that human being
problem even worse because you're going
to take people's guns and you got to
make them more angry or any kind of
legislation that fights against their
rights that they think are there by the
founding fathers,
you're going to have a giant problem.
And when people think that you could
just pull it away from them,
we're just going to take away the guns.
Fuck it.
There's nothing they can do.
Jesus christ,
there is definitely something they can
do.
And you've got to be really fucking
careful starting that war.
It goes back to messaging and you're
saying like a lot of people are saying
no the sciences out because they've
spent billions of dollars to do that.
The thing is,
is when you are playing such far right,
far left partisan politics,
then you have people saying,
oh,
uh,
obamacare,
he's a socialist.
He's trying to take over the government.
He's trying to do this.
He's trying to do that and sort of
blowing it up.
Why?
Because that creates the tea party,
Which you know,
comes in.
And then they have power and then the
tea party by the way,
as to go back to their constituents and
say,
we're going to repeal it,
we're going to do this,
we're going to be deliver.
And it just becomes a.
Everything goes to the atomic level.
And so that when you actually go into,
into,
you know,
into congress or into the executive or
into the senate,
and you try to get anything done,
you can't because you've promised that
you're not gonna do anything.
You're not going to have any sort of
partisan.
A relation.
Bipartisan bipartisan
relations.
yeah.
It's fucked up,
man.
It's,
and it's stupid.
And it exists because we have two
parties.
When you make to people we make.
One of them were red and you make one of
them were blue.
They start wanting to fight each other.
It's,
it's a stupid thing.
Great.
You're also,
it doesn't matter if you're in or out,
you're always empower because there's
only two.
So you're always going to be this sort
of opposition.
Yeah.
And that influenced the problem is like
this is what people have to realize a
lot of your opinions.
And my opinions too,
I'm not really my opinions,
their opinions that I've decided are
good that I've heard from other people
and a lot of our patterns of behaviors
from accents to the way we approach
culture,
the way we think about women,
the way we think about religion.
A lot of that is learned.
Okay.
And we have these two deeply ingrained
patterns in this country.
We have the democrats and we have the
republicans and the republicans are
these no nonsense get business done and
the democrats are,
you know,
we always think of all these people are
all cry babies and they're all wishy
washy and they're bleeding hearts.
And,
and that this is like ingrained in sort
of ingrained in our system,
these two different patterns of behavior
if they're severely problematic because
you could exhibit a lot of traits on
each sides and still be a very good
person or a lot of ideas on each side
and still be a very good.
If you look at.
I remember one,
uh,
you
know,
looking at sort of the clinton
administration,
he took the largest deficit in history,
made it the largest,
a surplus in history,
a strong government.
Basically the tenants of the republican
party w gets in trading is large,
the surplus and the largest deficit in
expands the government,
et cetera.
But nobody said boo,
like when you're like,
hold on a second,
we just switched these things.
No one wants to criticize their side.
It's like,
it's like sports teams.
If it's exactly.
You pick your sports team when you're
six,
you pick your political party because
your parents do generally.
Yeah.
And,
and,
and where you are.
And then that's it.
I don't give a shit out as a democrat to
your dad in a lot of places is like
coming out gay.
Yeah,
I bet it's probably because they're just
fucking democrats because were ashamed.
You're a fucking democrat.
You're going to vote for bernie sanders.
He only wants to do this family.
Bernie sanders wants to give all your
money to black lives matter.
We actually did a show up as part of our
news thing of we had people going back
for thanksgiving and it was the parents
who voted for trump versus the kids who
voted for either hillary or didn't vote
or whatever,
and they were just fighting and crying
and freaking out and like,
you know,
all this stuff and why did,
why,
why did we get to this level of
dysfunction?
I mean,
it's a,
it's a problem when you have two sides,
you know,
it would.
It's very difficult for to sports teams
to meet and say if they meet in neutral
territory like vegas and the fans get
along,
they're not going to get along.
People are fools.
we have tribal instincts.
We have instincts built into the.
When we were small bands of 50 people
that could barely stay alive and we were
often wiped out often.
So your genealogy,
your family line,
all your history of when you love could
be easily dead.
And so that was my questIon because it
seems to me what I'm getting the feeling
now,
like humanity when they have a big thing
like a war or something,
it's just like we're all getting
together and we're all going to fucking
do this together and we're going to
science and we're going to work hard and
we're going to do all this.
And we're like fuck.
And then when you know,
this has been the largest or longest
period of peace and prosperity the
world's ever known.
yeah.
Right now we see things in Syria though.
I'm talking about sort of these are sort
of isolated conflict,
but overall globally.
And what do we do?
We're sort of eatIng ourselves know
we're looking inwards and just sent out,
fuck,
I hate that guy.
Right?
That with,
in their parties,
they eat themselves.
That,
that you,
you pick teams inside your team.
Sure.
Did baner black lives matter is now mad
at the women.
The women that put on that women's march
and the transgender community is mad at
the women who are the pussy hats.
Well guess they're saying that being a
woman does not just mean you have a
pussy,
you have a tea party came in and ousted
canter and baner because they had the
audacity to even go meet with the
president or the democrats.
I mean people are just like,
well that's your fucking job is to go
there and talk
and make shit happen.
Fuck naomi.
Anyway,
we can go on forever.
But I think,
you know,
both you and I are sort of coming to the
same point that you can put any name you
want on it,
what you're,
what you're coming to as a sort of
dysfunctional relationship.
That's not going to end anytime soon.
but I'm hoping,
and this is totally possible that
generation y,
like you're talking about generation x,
all these people that are growing up
right now and just sort of waking up as
adults,
like realizing like half those people
that are wandering through the streets.
When you looked aT the women's march
have those people are,
you know,
in their twenties.
They're young folks that are just kind
of realizing like,
hey,
I'm a fucking adult.
I can go out and organize,
I can get something done,
I can do.
I am really hoping that this message
will get out,
that it is high time.
We abandoned this fucking goofy system
and that we demand a better system for
running 350 million people and one
figurehead and all of his cronies that
he's stuffs into some office and has
massive influence over all of us.
I think it's a giant problem.
It's a giant problem and to keep those
people rotating back and forth from left
to right and it's not doing anybody any
good,
but I think what's ironic about that is
I think you'd have a lot of people agree
with you on both sides.
I think we need like a cOuncil of
elders,
like we're.
We've been talking about this lately a
lot like having a counselor of really
fucking smart people.
You know?
Who would have on though,
would you have to cancel if you had a
council of eight people?
Who would you put on a people you don't
want seven because it's probably like
titanic or something.
Some lucky,
weird number that.
I mean,
you'd need a good,
you'd need a good a doctor like just for
health stuff.
I like the dark dot mukherjee who wrote
the emperor of all maladies,
uh,
any about sanjay gupta.
Like that guy.
Like I used to hate them and then I like
to,
I like siddhartha.
I think he's a,
he's a real genius when it comes to
stuff like that.
I think you need a good tech person
because I think elon musk,
he's in ilan musk.
I'm a big fan of.
I'm a big fan of elon as well.
You know what he can do on his own.
It was just fucking amazing.
American tunnel.
he's tired.
Are you tired of the traffic in la?
Digging a giant tunnel.
I love elon musk.
elon musk.
I like the fact that like batteries,
you know?
Yeah.
The thing that was solar didn't work
because the fucking storage didn't work,
so he's like,
fuck it,
I'm going to make them.
And he took the tesla battery thing into
a powerhouse.
The best battery in the world.
You're like,
you know what else I liked about him?
He married an actress twice with no
prenup.
You married the same actress twice.
You know what that means?
That means he drinks and it fucks.
He drinks and he fucks because it's the
only way you make those goddamn
decisions.
You married that same actress twice with
no pre lump.
If he did that,
he's an animal.
He's,
he's a savage.
He's in.
He's like,
I love you.
I don't give a fuck about a prenup.
Oh,
you came inside of her.
They fucking high five.
That's my kind of guy.
And he's making batteries.
Make them fucking good.
Battery charging stations everywhere.
You got to put him in.
Okay.
So we've got elon musk,
we got sanjay.
Meet your guy.
Siddhartha mukherjee.
But you need it.
You need a good common sense like,
do we have al gore,
al gore?
You know the criticism because of that
movie,
like a lot of people.
I think he's thinking I'm an
environmentalist,
but I think he's too far too far over
there.
I think you need to sort of,
if it was me,
you want someone,
you know who I like.
I like,
there's a guy named um,
Eric Schmidt and he's the chief or one
of the head nasa scientists and these
guys are just super smart dudes,
right?
Man and women actually because the head
signed the chief scientist at nasa.
I met his mom.
She's fantastic as well,
but you just need like a common sense
person who just goes in there with no
rhetoric or no politics or anything.
Just saying,
look,
we have to reduce emissions by 80
percent if we don't,
we all die.
So here's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna,
get a lot of batteries and we're going
to put the things on because the
batteries can finally do it now.
And this is what we're going to do.
You need someone to do that because it
gets when it gets hyper politicized and
stuff and everything gets lost in the
bullshit.
You just need a common sensical person
who just says,
this is what needs to happen because
this is what the science says.
The log jams that you must have,
like at a big corporation,
say if you worked for under armour,
like the log jams,
he must have.
You want to get something done.
It probably monumental.
it's probably a million people.
You try and talk about this and you have
to have design meetings and sit down and
try new fabric.
All this fucking socks.
Let me try thIs.
I was saying that I just imagined that
in,
in politics,
in the country and trillions of dollars
involved.
All these people.
Do you watch house of cards?
Yeah,
me too.
Love it.
I wish it was like that.
A lot of it maybe is.
Well,
I was watching actually,
ironically I was watching the lbj a
documentary and what was interesting
about that was that here's this guy
who's basically a political mechanic,
you know who's sitting there and
everybody wants something.
Everybody you know is trying to get this
and try to.
And basically it's completely fucked and
you can't get anything done.
And the only thing that came across
there was he got everything done by
lying to everybody by just saying you.
I'm going to give you what you want and
I'm going to give you what you want.
And then just sort of figuring it out at
the end.
And it was,
I was just watching it.
It was fantastic because you're like,
that's probably the last era when you
could actually get shit done.
And he was,
he was like,
I mean,
who knows because it's,
it was a movie,
but You know,
he was,
he was just sort of,
you know,
he was lIke the last of the,
because I look at Frank Underwood and I
always call him like he was a political
mechanic.
He was the guy who could go get the
votes and you could drum up the boats
and you could do it.
You know,
he reminds me actually talking about the
lead figure,
a kevin spacey,
kevin spacey,
house of cards.
He kinda,
without the sort of psychopath,
sociopath thing.
He reminds me of speaker boehner,
speaker boehner was that kind of got
like,
how many votes do we need?
How do we get it in?
What do we trade off like they get an
aircraft carrier plant in pittsburgh or
whatever we get at this thing,
you know,
but it doesn't happen anymore.
Those kinds of guys don't happen
anymore,
but why not?
I don't fucking know.
Well,
is that preferable to what we've got
now?
I mean,
what?
Well,
because shit would actually get done.
I don't think she gets done now.
In fact,
they go backwards.
So to go back to the council of elders,
something needs to happen where there's
some sort of change because it it like
it's not going to fix itself,
right?
No one's going to fucking fail.
In fact,
in Washington now they're saying the
biggest thing is the supreme court
nomination because everything's so
fucked and everybody realizes that that
everything will have to go up to the
supreme court and be decided there
because it will not be decided in the
senate and congress or an executive.
That's how fucked it is,
is that we're going.
That's what's really important because
we gonna have to sue each other on
everything we want to do.
Oh,
okay.
I got another member of our council of
elders,
neil degrasse tyson must be in their
mustang.
He has to be in America.
Yeah.
Who else?
There's a guy that I would take two if
you're looking at that kind of thing.
This guy,
uh,
um,
taylor wilson.
I did a thing.
He,
he,
he built the fusion reactor in his
garage when he was 14.
Yeah.
I heard that story.
And so I interviewed him.
What did they,
how did they find?
They found that the reactor,
like there was some sort of a reading
they were getting.
No,
he was,
he was taking a energy off the grid and
that's what it was,
right?
Yeah.
But then the government sort of took him
and now he's,
he's,
he's got his own lab and so he's a
fantastic guy.
They found him.
Right?
Like there was some crazy power drain or
something.
I mean,
I shouldn't talk because I don't know
the actual story,
but I remember they were like,
well,
I mean they know and because he was
getting the materials and all this
stuff,
taylor's nukes.
I was actually,
he was actually,
when he was 14,
he was getting,
he was plotting uranium mines.
He figured out if you put like,
you know,
a white bottle with a thing and it says
you're a,
you could plot the and he would go get
uranium,
refine their uranium on his own,
into yellow cake and then make this,
this fusion reactor.
What kind of cancer doeS he have?
But he's,
you know,
he's got,
he's got all sorts of gear on when he
does that.
All you need is a bunch of,
you know,
he's,
he's an expert,
but anyway,
he's 14.
But the whole thing with them that,
well now he's 23 but not.
But the thing is is he's into dark
matter,
dark energy and he's going around the
hydraulic collider and seren and I'm
just like this kid,
you know,
I think,
I don't know if we've talked about this,
but yeah,
look at him.
So he came up with the girl.
The reason why the,
when he was younger,
the reason why I liked him so much as he
came up with a failsafe reactor,
little tiny one,
and he's like with all the sort of the,
the,
the old um,
power plants.
No,
yeah,
they're,
they're spent waste and the weapons that
we have to store,
which we can store it for more than a
hundred years,
but they need to be stored for 10,000
years.
He can take little pea size bits of
that,
put it into fail safe reactor that sort
of drains into a salt thing,
whatever and it,
and it can't be whatever.
It's fail safe and,
but they are small,
but they do like 50,000
houses or 100,000
houses and just by using the fuel that
we already have that we can store,
we can power the world for the next
10,000
years.
Oh jesus chrIst.
So when I hear this,
and this is his thing,
and by the way he's being backed by ilan
and all the big names and whatever.
But the thing is,
is I'm like,
I want that kid on my side.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
I want that kid to sit there and say,
how about we don't like eric schmidt's
going to say not Eric Schmidt.
What's his name?
Shit.
Eric schmidt is a glue.
It's anyway,
somebody schmidt from nasa,
Dr.
Schmidt is going to say is going to say,
hey,
we need to reduce,
you know,
emissions by 80 percent of all going to
die.
And then taylor goes,
got it.
You know,
we do these,
these,
uh,
these little reactors and we,
when we eat up all the old,
uh,
warheads and we're done.
Yeah,
they can turn them into batteries that
last for the,
pull that up.
They turned them into batteries made out
of diamonds.
That lasts for thousands of years.
And so you just,
you just want somebody to say,
god,
here's what its overall it out.
Boom.
What's always made sense to me that If
we were putting carbon out in the
atmosphere and carbons valuable for
construction and a lot of different
things,
there's got to be a way.
BIofuels,
like so if you want to do bio fuels,
it's all,
it's all carbon you need to ceo to,
to,
to inject into the biofuels and you're
like refined to carbon out of the
goddamn atmosphere when they make
biodiesel with corn and shit like that.
The,
there's a,
there's the one that you use.
Algae.
The algae.
Yeah.
Diamonds turn nuclear waste into nuclear
battery go jesus christ.
See if you can pull up taylor's a
reactor thing.
It's,
it's fast.
I would kind of solve all of our
problem.
I mean,
it really would mean that we no longer
got to react.
It's like his reactor that uses a,
spent a,
he did a ted talk on it anyway.
Um,
so we need him because whenever I'm
around him I feel better about humanity
because I'm like,
this is just so devastating and,
and I don't know how to fix it.
He goes,
well,
the science is there.
You can do it tomorrow.
You just got to duh,
dah duh duh,
duh.
And you're like,
oh,
how do we get that done?
We've got to keep that 23 year old kid
away from pussy us.
We gotta do we got to keep them
productive,
you know,
because some girl that wrecked elon
musk,
that same type of guy.
Well,
he loves doing strong.
We all know he's,
he's good.
Some of them.
Who else we lose the good ones.
Who have these nikola tesla.
You need like a philosopher king,
kind of like big picture.
Sam harris,
globalist,
globalist.
I want sam harris on the bar.
So sam harris,
he must be council of elders.
A lot of people right now on reddit,
on twitter.
It's interesting.
Who is,
who is someone that's just got a big
picture,
understands everything that's going to
sort of smooth out everything.
It's really hard to find people like
that.
It's really hard to find people that um,
it's really hard to find people that are
open to the facts,
that are willing to change their mind,
aren't attached their ideas and willing
to look at every side of things before
they form an opinion.
Most people don't have the time to do
that.
That's part of the issue.
Part of the issue I think when anyone
who went to talking about anything
related to the environment or politics
or gender or race or anything is there
is only so much fucking time in the
world so it's so much easier to form
this prejudice opinion or this
predetermined opinion on everything
across the board,
which is why I like being on the right
is so popular.
It's so easy to dismiss it,
but he's a bunch of babies and shit on
them,
you know,
and it's much easier to shit on.
Things tend to say here's a solution
much.
That's why I like taylor.
I'm like,
this fucking kid.
Like he can just,
he's just like,
not only is the science there,
we can do this,
this,
this and this.
And I'm like,
well why don't we do that?
And he goes,
politics,
money,
this,
that could have a baby drill.
start drilling into.
It's interesting though,
it's interesting that we cannot think
between the two of us have someone who
could just be,
you know,
someone is just unbelievable and people
could just go,
okay,
I get it.
You know,
someone is really wise.
Someone,
they don't necessarily have to be smart
and,
and also just like they can,
they can convey,
you know,
this is what we're doing,
this is why we're here because you need
a communicator because you know,
taylor and elan are not going to be
communicating,
you know,
batteries and,
and the,
and the physics behind,
you know,
the little piece and the thing when,
I mean you need someone to say,
this is what we're doing,
this is why we're doing it.
This is why everybody in the world,
like who is the best,
most believable politician in the last
50 years?
Who,
who is going to be that person?
Jimmy carter globally,
globally.
It's funny about jimmy carter because
I've never met anyone as sort of quick,
you know,
he's so,
he's like,
I don't know how you'd use it for an
hour or so many so fast.
And he's got the stats.
He's got twitter and he's just,
he,
he looks and he sounds like the perfect
president.
He was destroyed when he was empowered.
Like he was just vilified.
So you're like,
he was a great smart guy.
He,
he should have been like a secretary
general,
you understand that you don't know about
president.
He was um,
as a,
as his character,
like how he,
how he presents himself.
He was not like a firm leader character,
you know,
he was a kind gentleman from Georgia
peanut fall and a smart,
smart gen,
genuinely genuinely smart dude.
And with a good moral center.
He was worked and he was working towards
the end by the reagan administration
when they were coming in the reagan
campaign because they were the first
campaign to ever use the rights
connection to christianity.
This is the first time they had
organized the hardcore religious base
even though,
you know,
he was a pastor.
I know,
it's kind of crazy.
It's kind kinda crazy.
And the republicans connected themselves
to these crazy like televangelists jerry
falwell and.
Yeah,
exactly.
Have you got elected?
Because he could,
he could get the evangelical base.
So they worked him there.
They worked him there.
And ronald reagan was an actor.
He was a much better public speaker.
He was strong.
He had slicked back hair like god damn
comic book from the fifties.
I mean,
he was,
yeah,
because he was,
he was like the president and in many
cases is the queen of england.
It's a,
it's a ceremonial thing and that's,
that's why I'm saying you need a
communicator who can sort of get things
across and,
but people will believe,
like nobody really believed carter and
half the country didn't believe reagan
or they believed him after he was gone,
you know,
because everyone's like,
that's convenient to love reagan now.
But I remember,
and you remember when we were kids,
he was like,
that's what punk rock started in America
was because right.
And got in.
We all went fucking New York hardcore
and all that shit.
But,
you know,
I just,
it's,
it's a shame that we cannot think.
It doesn't have to be american.
What about like in the world,
isn't there somebody in the world and
the fucking world hard pressed,
hard pressed to find a prominent public
figure that really stands out.
That's pretty interesting.
That's oprah.
No,
no,
I'm just kidding.
Um,
yeah man,
it's uh,
it's.
Oh,
the other thing that carter got fucked
on was the hostages.
They had negotiated the release of the
hostages to make sure that it was done
once reagan was in office and not before
that,
and they had kept those fucking american
citizens over there.
They,
I mean this is a proven conspiracy.
They kept those american citizens over
there longer than they had to be because
they wanted to make sure that it will
all look good.
You had,
you had that happened,
which was not good.
You also had,
I mean there's also an economic timing
issue and you had this oil crisis and
you had a recession.
You have all these bad things happening
and you're like,
well that's carter's fault,
and it was also when they ruined
american cars.
There you go.
They all turned to shit.
American cars in 19 sixties up until the
early seventies were fucking awesome.
They're the best looking cars and to
this day they're like the biggest
collector.
Cars like barracudas and corvettes and
all those old cars.
As soon as that gas crisis hit,
man,
those cars turned to shit.
While also same thing.
Every time there's a gas crisis,
so that's when the japanese cars became
popular.
That's when it's the exact same thing,
you know the suv where the highest
sellers before the last oil crisis or
when the went through the roof and then
that's when the prius,
they couldn't,
they couldn't make them fast enough.
It was exactly the same thing that
happened in the late seventies.
So I think anyway,
it was a princess is a
far better car.
Then the 19 eighties,
the dislike taken.
They took one of the best cars ever.
Like the from steve mcqueen bullet.
Remember that?
Fuck yeah.
That was a 68.
I think it was [inaudible] 68 mustang
got damn was a gorgeous piece of metal
and they turned that into these 19
eighties things that he likes.
Like,
what the fuck happened?
What did you do?
I look at a lot of stuff and say,
what the fuck?
What the fuck?
Like the late seventies mustang.
Find like,
uh,
that's,
that's the shit.
Come on man.
That's.
Oh,
I thought was steve mcqueen.
60 eight fastback.
I like,
I like to block one.
I like them all.
I love them.
This one of the,
something about american muscle cars
from the sixties and the early
seventies.
Mustang there.
Yeah,
that's it.
Fucking steve mcqueen baby.
Look at that goddamn parker.
So you go from that.
Now type up 1980 mustang prepared to
throw out to get ready to puke.
Here we go.
Oh my god.
What in the fuck is that hunk of shit.
Fuck how the fuck.
NoBody wants that car.
That car is worth three cents.
Nobody wants that fucking car.
I think I actually like,
uh,
you know,
people who like logan's run and all that
stuff like those old,
uh,
a seventies futurists,
they would like to know even,
um,
even those dummies,
they just made some terrible fucking
cars in the 19,
late seventies and put that away.
You're making me throw up there you go.
Oh they,
they,
they can't.
Something happens.
It's interesting.
So on our council of elders,
we don't have one politician.
Okay.
So now we can have one of those.
So we got those people are good doctors.
We got some good scientists,
we got a tech guy,
we got some visionaries.
Well,
we need more than one tech need.
Probably gonna need some tech guy to
balance out.
Ilan,
ilan might get a little wacky,
start sending people to mars and shit.
Now here's the other thing is,
is a council of elders for the world or
for the country,
because then you also need some military
dudes to say when we can we,
we like the one thing that you know,
that,
that is sort of whatever a true truism
is that you have to,
you have to preach that sort of.
There is no democracy without safety.
Right?
Right.
That's true.
And you and you have to have guaranteed
sort of protection.
And if you look at europe,
it's quite interesting because when
they,
when they sort of said,
okay,
we've got,
you know,
we were going to protect this area and
we're going to.
There was an economic benefit for this
area.
You had all the little groups start to
say like scotland or the basque
country's or catalonia or you know,
all these different say,
well we want to split off,
right?
Because it's more democratic to have
smaller sort of runnable countries that.
And they're like,
well we want to have our own thing
because we'll be part of this bigger
thing,
but we want to be more democratic and I
think that's quite because you have
these super national political entities
that sort of guarantee safety and
economic security and then therefore
it's much more democratic.
So you sort of sit there and say,
okay,
well if that's the case then you have to
have that guarantee security.
So,
so how do you do that?
Well this is the ultimate goal and this
is going to take several generations and
all nations treat each other now because
we are so big and we are so connected.
Treat each other now as one,
one organism,
one gigantic super organism,
the human race and all this country
bullshit.
Let difficult to be back and we'll have
an insanely it almost impossible to do
it.
Look,
I'm saying
unless there's a w,
where was I going to go back to?
It was like we're great at like war.
Like when there's a world fuck we got to
go get them.
You know what if or let's say,
so I view it like this.
But like,
let's say there's a fucking asteroid
coming towards us,
like we're going to put all over the
global,
you know,
like a movie.
We're going to put everybody,
the smartest guys,
the russian guys,
chinese guys and us and everybody's
going to go off and do this thing.
So if that's the case,
and I always say humans aren't going to
move unless we have a gun to her head,
but at some point what happens is,
let's say greenland,
a big chunk about four feet.
Miami goes away and everybody goes,
oh shit,
now we got to do something.
At that point,
everybody goes,
okay,
you know,
because if,
if miami goes away,
shanghai goes away.
So then shang shanghai goes away.
It goes away.
And so if you're sitting there,
you go,
okay,
everybody's going to get together and
say shit,
the oceans rise and we got to do
something.
We gotta do something right now.
But there's always gonna be people that
are ignoring that and profiting.
Somebody else can take care of it.
Let's start drilling and they're going
to do that.
They're going to do that short.
Don't you think though,
that if mumbai goes away,
miami goes away in New York,
goes away,
whatever,
and all the seed,
the big seat next to the cease cities go
away.
Now this is interesting because when we
were shooting this a doc on on sea level
rise,
one of the things that's damning to oil
companies is they're like,
wow,
I didn't know science has not decided.
We didn't fucking know while this was
happening.
They raised spending hundreds of
millions of dollars more billions of
dollars.
They raised all their oil platforms by
eight feet.
Ooh,
why?
Because they didn't want them getting
sunk because jesus,
the outside prediction so that they have
to last 80 years for insurance,
you know,
for the life of things.
So the outside prediction For 100 years
was eight feet.
That's four feet,
three feet to four feet,
and then the outside is eight feet.
So they're like,
okay,
well just do eight feet.
So they know.
So they know if you don't raise
something and pay hundreds of dollars to
raise it eight feet by eight feet,
why not four feet?
Why not three feet wide,
12 feet in any case?
So you this.
The thing is is you sit there and say,
okay,
eight feet at four feet,
miami's gone.
New york's gone.
Shane at eight feet were all sitting
there.
Okay.
It probably gets to paint canyon fucking
eight feet.
It probably gets.
So at that point humanity goes,
holy shit,
we need taylor,
we need ilan.
And we did a.
And so that's an interesting point.
I think that ultimately what is gonna
happen and it may take 100 years,
it may take 500 years.
I think ultimately we're going to reach
a technologically driven state of
evolution that bypasses our biological
evolution.
So I've got an answer to that.
I agree.
Half the world will do that.
Maybe the other half the world goes the
opposite way.
Maybe that's what's happening now,
but it's not happening now with cell
phones.
Cell phones have gone all over the world
and if this,
if we can achieve a technology that
allows people to understand each other
in a,
in a way that's way more way,
way deeper and more intimate than just
getting to know somebody.
They talked to you,
you talked to me,
you know,
like we,
you and I have been friends for a long
time now and every time I see a give you
a big hug,
I know,
I see shane.
I'm going to give him a hug.
I associate you with my friend.
It's happiness.
We have a lot of great talks.
We get drunk together and that's all
built in,
but it takes a while to establish that,
right?
It takes a while to make a bond between
two people who enjoy each other's
company.
I think we could all this whole world
could be a bunch of friends.
It sounds crazy,
but it can be done,
will be done in small groups.
It can be done in this room.
It can be done in this town.
I think it can be done.
If we're facing extinction,
I don't think it can be done otherwise
because I.
What I see happening to go back to if we
don't have war,
like global war we have,
we have this eating ourselves.
So again,
if you look at the world,
you have half the world roughly saying
technology can fix us.
We're going to go to mars,
we're gonna have little pellets of
things which are going to feed 50
houses.
We're going to do this,
and then you have the other half of the
world that saying fuck reading.
You know,
fuck technology.
We're going back to another time.
And not just not just the muslim world.
You have lots of different groups in
africa.
You have lots of different groups in and
obviously the middle east you have
different groups who are saying fuck
that.
We're not doing that.
And so they're moving away from it.
So you have this sort of duopoly in the
world of people who are going one way
and the people who are going the other
way.
And I don't think that unless you have a
common goal,
which is by the way,
we're all going to die unless we do
this,
that everybody does it and it's like
star trek and star trek,
they did this thing where,
where everybody from the world is
finally together and then we're all
working together for this great thing
which is exploring space,
but they needed that whole,
you know,
focus that goal and I think we need that
focus and that go,
which is why,
again,
to go back to war zones,
when you go to war zones says,
oh shit,
we shouldn't be fucking dropping bombs
on each other.
And then when you go and talk to
scientists,
they go,
oh,
it's coming and it's coming fucked.
And now,
yeah.
And that I'm not like this crazy dude or
whatever.
I'm just a regular dude going,
oh shit,
it's because I talk to these scientists
were like,
we just did this thing in Russia where,
uh,
I don't know if you know about this,
but the permafrost,
if you heard about the permafrost,
yes.
All the carbon in the permafrost is
released.
It's going to be released as melting and
so it releases carbon,
it actually releases methane,
which is 20 times worse than carbon and
there's more carbon in the permafrost
than all of the carbon that we've
released since the industrial revolution
started because it's a bunch of dead
thinGs that have died up there for
millions of years.
Correct.
And all that's going to get warmed up.
And it's gonna be a bunch of stinky dead
bodies and animal shit.
Do you want to know two interesting
things about that?
Well,
I got two interesting things about that.
One is we went up to lakes in both
Russia and the arctic and you pop a hole
in the lake and you put a.
You put a like a torch in and it shoots
out like a,
like an oil flare.
Oh my god.
Oh,
I've seen that because there's methane
in the lake,
in the water and it just shooting out
like an oil flair.
And you're like,
what the fuck?
A b.
This is gonna sound crazy.
But it's actually fucking true in that.
So we go to siberia and we hang out with
this dude who's been living in the
permafrost,
he's like the world's biggest expert on
permafrost and it's scientists,
scientists,
and there's all these slumps,
like they have the biggest slump in,
in,
in the world,
in a slump.
So it's where the permafrost melts in.
The permafrost is like frozen ground,
like dirt and shit.
It's also frozen water.
And so when it melts,
the water goes away and the ground which
has left sort of slump and it goes down
like 20 or 30 feet.
And so you just had these all over
siberia.
You have these huge,
like two,
three,
four mile wide,
just like craters,
you know.
And so he's there and he's like the sort
of foremost expert.
And what's interesting about is he goes,
look in the ice age,
here's what happened.
There were not that many humans,
but there were millions upon millions of
animals and they were like elk.
And there were,
you know,
caribou and all this shit.
And the wooly mammoth.
You know what they did,
they ate all the fucking shrubs and the
trees and shit.
Which actually,
you know,
made the ground freeze much deeper
because there's a lot of things like
dark sort of,
you know,
brings in a heat and it takes the
installation away.
All theSe stuffs,
the foliage is not,
the sun beats directly down to earth.
And so.
So anyways,
he no because no,
because the trees bringing the heat and
hold it in the act,
it freezes more in the winter and then
therefore stays colder in any case.
So he's like,
look,
here's what we have to do.
We have to put millions of caribou and
millions of horses and millions of elk
can stop up in siberia.
But he goes,
that's yeah,
that'll get you 60 percent of the way
there.
The only thing that'll get us really
there is the fucking woolly mammoth.
Now this is not a joke.
What?
So ironically they found a woolly
mammoth,
perfectly preserved in the permafrost.
Like it fell into a fucking lake and
froze and never a thought out thought.
So when they,
then they opened it up,
it still had red cells living cells.
So you know they're doing this is we
have,
we shot this and I was watching this
with my mouth on the ground.
They're cloning the wooly mAmmoths.
Skin found well preserved and permafrost
gives new hope.
a trump look up the trunk.
Look up the show.
They have a trunk.
They have a full jesus look at it,
look it up there,
the image,
but they have a full truck look up.
Woolly mammoth trunk.
Wow.
Because they have this full trunk that,
that,
that there.
That's.
No,
no.
They have a trunk.
Like I have a full trunk.
In any case,
they're trying to clone using tusk,
tusk.
They go,
oh,
you're a trunk.
Why did it pull up tusk hunters for the
first thing.
ThAt's weird.
They're trying to say anyway,
so they're cloning either with the south
koreans.
They're cloning mammoths in the hopes
that they're just going to put all these
clones of mammoths up there and it's
going to freeze.
The permafrost is just make more shit
and more dead animals,
which makes more methane.
I'm so confused.
Well,
the amount that they would make versus
the amount of methane that's going to be
released from the permafrost,
which has been collecting this shit for
fucking millions of years because
diminimous.
So the idea is they're going to beat the
fuck out of all the vegetation that will
cool the area down.
Correct.
Wow.
Why don't they just make ice cubes and
just dumped them out of helicopters?
It seems like just as good evaluator.
It'll make fucking.
There's another guy we need for our
council is this fucking crazy russian
dude who's just up there saying,
fuck it.
Let's get some mammoths to fix us.
I wonder.
And that'll get you 60 percent of the
way there,
but still 40 percent fucked.
No,
with us we Get 90 percent.
Oh,
so the 60 percent.
Sixty percent.
There you go.
There's the trunk.
wow.
That is so crazy.
She,
yeah,
they have a good chance of successfully
colonial.
They have south koreans and the russians
and the russians are moving very fast on
this because they realized that if
permafrost melts,
they're screwed.
So do they keep this thing in a frozen
room?
They do,
we filmed it,
we filmed them trying to clone it.
Wow.
What a crazy time to be alive.
So amazed.
Because what's amazing about that is
like,
oh,
we're fucked.
The permafrost to melt.
We're all doomed.
And then you're like,
but we can get some fucking woolly
mammoths and mammoths.
You need to make saber tooth tigers to
just for the fuck of it.
Well,
there could be an argument there because
you're like,
well,
who's going to eat the mammoth?
Because we actually talked to nasa and
said,
is this guy crazy?
As he liked don quixote tilting at
windmills and he said actually the
environmental or the organic solution
rather than dropping ice cubes,
that all coverage is the best solution
because it used to be that 40,000
years ago this shit regulated itself and
this is when the planet was cold.
Now it's too fucking hot.
So this is a way to get back to being
cold.
So it actually makes sense.
So we need that guy really that he's on
our council.
We need some people from other countries
that they're gonna get mad at us
because,
uh,
well maybe we shouldn't.
Maybe we should have our fucking country
figure this out.
It's too.
It's too much.
We'll spend into fix the world.
I think you need.
You need,
you need other people.
Can we need some checks?
Go on,
go get some checks on their chicks are
going to get pissed.
They're already march.
And dude,
we need checks in calgary.
Who do we got?
Nobody.
Unfortunately,
oprah.
Oprah.
Maybe you know what oprah is good at.
You know what?
You just hit the nail on the head
because she's great at sort of regular
whether she's.
No,
she's great at,
at getting a message across.
She's great at saying,
hey,
this is the thing and this is why it's
happening.
So taylor goes,
oh shit,
you know,
we've got this,
uh,
this a reactor that we can do that cost
10 bucks.
And then she goes,
okay,
this is why we're doing it.
Okay.
So who else?
What other checks?
Oprah is very good.
I like that as our,
as our politicians get mad when you call
them chicks yet,
so that's still okay.
When,
when do I become a pig?
forgotten.
I'm just not good.
It's not good to call them chicks.
No.
Why is it good to call joe Biden to
dude?
He's a good dude.
Is not all right.
Yeah,
he's a good dude.
So why isn't it okay to call hillary
clinton?
Well,
She's a fiery check.
I think it's good when you're calling
people like,
you know,
with their buddies and tHeir friends.
What about getting into.
We call women chicks,
but.
But I think we need another
international.
We need an international person.
I end hirsi ali.
Alright,
that's good.
There you go.
Yeah.
She would be amazing with foreign
relations and understanding people of
our religious ideologies.
Okay.
Who else?
Sitting down the super liberals get mad
at you for that is not hilarious.
Have you read any criticisms of her
know?
So people that just go so far left,
they spun around and their noses up the
rights ass.
There's so confused.
That's the one thing is we're the,
the left goes so far left and the right
and the rest goes so far as calls it
out,
you know,
it's like,
it's like tHis black lives matter going
after the women's march thing.
Like everybody relax one hand though.
I got to Admit though,
I read the thing and I was like,
why would they complain about people
supporting this women's march?
Why would they complain about something
good?
And then the other part of me went,
well,
imagine if you were them manage.
If you were them,
you're protesting against people getting
shot and killed by cops and you're
trying to make a movement out of that
and you don't get near the kind of
traction.
Nowhere near the kind of positive press.
Then the other part of me goes back to
the women's march and go,
you know what's crazy about the women's
march?
Not a single fucking arrest all across
the country.
That's good vibes,
which has done pretty.
Were wearing pink hats with cat ears.
They're called pussy hats.
Get it.
So they have these fucking cats were
wearing.
our cops rather were wearing them and
women were taking pictures because,
you know,
you sit there and you say,
okay,
look,
you know,
people can do this and we can do it
peacefully and we can it rationally and
we're all at the end of the day.
We're all in the same boat,
but he was talking the street.
Do you think there's enough people that
aren't racist that you could pull
something like that off?
Do you think it's more common to be
racist than it is to be sexist?
You know,
I will say the universe does things a,
uh,
for a reason I think.
And I had a,
I have two amazing daughters and it
changed my life and it changed the way I
view the world and it changed the way I
see things and it's why I look at that
march and I said,
that's a great thing.
And uh,
you know,
it,
it definitely,
you know,
it alters how you think about things for
sure.
It also alters how you think about the
future,
because a lot of people are like,
fuck,
level orange is not going to fucking do
anything in mind.
When you have kids,
all of a sudden you're like,
shit,
I want my kid to go swimming.
You don't want a kid to go in a
nightmare.
The only one.
And I don't want to.
We're adults.
You know,
we gotta we gotta pick up her own shit
here.
In any case,
I think it's a good idea.
I think,
uh,
we should,
we will submit our,
a council of elders idea to the world
via the internet and see if we get a
billion votes,
then I think everybody has to adopt it.
And then,
uh,
and then we get to sort of be special
advisors.
I seriously think this could actually
happen one day.
It might not happen in our lives,
you know,
who's a good politician that people like
and would fucking follow a good vibe.
Ron paul,
joe biden,
uh,
maybe you know,
joe biden.
We used to have joe biden night at
stitches comedy club back in boston
where we would plagiarize each other's
material because joe biden got busted
speeches when he was running for
president eight.
Really?
Everybody's kinda forgot about that.
He seems like a fairly decent dude,
although a little odd.
Yeah.
You want,
you want a little bit odd.
But you know what,
whenever vice president,
you're like,
oh,
it has to do with fucking smile.
Like,
you know,
they don't have to.
They,
you know,
nobody blamed for anything.
Volumes are mainly like,
to me it's kind of a favorite one.
I think that made him.
If the mems had come out before the
election,
he could have won that with,
uh,
the,
my favorite one was biden throwing his
head back,
laughing is that he goes,
and then I said to hillary,
you did the same thing.
Monica did,
you blew it.
And then then obama says,
you know,
she kills people,
right?
Yeah.
It's that picture,
that picture.
And then they use that with a bunch of
them.
I'm so glad.
So fuck.
Oh my god.
Oh good.
All right.
It's uh,
it's interesting.
But I think that what I'm saying about
technology is I think we're way more
connected as human beings than we ever
have been before and I think a lot of
this crazy super social justice warrior
progressive shit that you're seeing
today where it's getting so far,
far,
far outreaches of it are so out of hand.
I think all of this is possible and all
of this is because of this new found
opportunity.
We have to communicate with each other
that just previously just.
I've got a question for you.
Okay.
So you look at.
I agree with you like we have this
ability to connect all day everyday and
it's going to be yours.
It's going to get crazier and we are,
aren't connect more and more connected.
Is this is just the beginning.
Have you seen this?
Augmented reality,
but yes.
Yes.
Like you see that and you're like,
oh,
what we have now is,
I mean rudimentary and that's two years
old,
three years old.
And once people start submitting to some
sort of a lens in there,
I mean that's kinda goddamn happened.
People are already gettIng lenses in the
riser,
repair their vision.
I have friends that have lenses.
I have a above.
My friend steve,
he just got two friends,
steve that had had had eye operations,
but my friend steve just got to fucking
artificial lens.
It had a rip cornea and they put an
artificial lens over a piece on it.
Look insane.
Yeah,
I mean he's not even like a martial
artist anything.
He's just a regular guy that an eye
problem and they're starting to do this
on people and it's going to accelerate.
They're doing all sorts of crazy shit
now,
but when you see augmented reality,
so augmented,
I don't know if everybody knows what it
is,
but now,
right now it's glass is and once you get
over the fact,
which is weird that it's like holograms
inside your eyeball.
Yeah,
like they,
they put them in now.
I'm like,
I'm a fucking like germaphobe freaking.
oh shit,
that's going to give me cancer the
fucking eyeball.
But apparently it's not.
But in any case,
after you get over that fear,
you're like,
oh,
you put these things on it,
this room,
right?
And you're like,
oh,
there's a tv and you're watching tv in
your room.
Okay,
great.
And they're like putting.
It's only a tv because your brain is
used to it being a tv.
when you get used to it will just flip a
button and you're on the 50 yard line,
you know,
it can be anything.
It can be any size.
Yeah,
you can do the art and the room,
you know,
now that's for tv watching it.
It was developed for like a media thing,
like it could be movies or tv,
but they're like,
oh,
be your phone.
It can be your computer,
it can be everything.
So everything is going to be in your
glasses,
a camera,
everything.
You control it with this little thing
and it's you.
You're going to be,
you know,
your,
all,
your media is there,
your phone is there,
your computers there,
everything's there.
and it's just this connectivity that's
always there.
It's always on.
It's fucking crazy.
Now there's all kinds of ethical things.
And how's that going to change humanity,
all that stuff,
but who cares is going to happen because
the technology's there and fucking
better than a phone.
Now once that connectivity happens,
to go back to your point is there's a
power in there for positivity and all
this stuff.
But if you look at,
for example,
social media,
you know,
one of the things that is destroying
twitter is they can't keep like the,
and,
and by the way,
the fake news on facebook and all this
stuff,
they can't police it is to mom people is
too many people,
too much shit.
And it's like bad people.
It's just people to.
And everybody's got an opinion.
And by the way,
when you're across the table,
the reason why we eat,
the reason why we have feast,
the reason why we do all this shit just
because when you're eating together,
you form social bonds and all this shit
and you're like,
oh,
I'm not going to kill you because we had
a beer together,
whatever.
But when you don't.
And it's just this anonymous,
I can say and do whatever the fuck I
want.
It just becomes like crazy and it
becomes fun for people there.
Bob,
fIfty five to two a asshole and then
they decided to fuck with,
you know,
if it's fun for them,
it's a little game,
you know,
it was,
I was listening to this radio lab pot.
No,
it was an article I was reading.
That's what it was.
And it was about this,
a guy who had been stalked online by his
friend's son and uh,
they were,
I mean,
it got to the point where this guy was
just,
they were doing all,
he was doing all sorts of horrible shit
and sending them a horrible evil
messages.
They were terrified.
They were all having horrible anxiety.
And it turned out that it was his
friend's son and he called the fbi,
found for fun.
He didn't think about what he broke down
crying when they confronted him and it
was,
it was awful.
But it was like,
wow,
there's lIke some sort of weird,
perverse thing that people enjoy doing
just fucking with someone as a game.
And that all takes place because of that
lack of social interaction.
The problem with that is,
is as those tools,
let's say augmented reality get more and
more powerful than that sort of,
unless it's.
Unless we look at that aspect of it,
we're all fucked.
Maybe,
maybe not though you know it's going to
be you and I are going to be able to
have this conversation where we're
nowhere near each other exactly the same
way that we're having it written.
Now we're going to be able to look at
each other in the eye and have like this
kind of a conversation and you are going
to represent you,
you.
There's going to be some sort of A video
version of you that I will not be able
to distinguish from you and you'll be
sItting there right now and it won't be
much different other than physical
contact.
There's an interesting point though,
which is when humans are hungry and
thirsty,
our immediate reaction is no,
and when we're fed and when we're a bit
boozed up,
the reaction is yes,
which is why everyone says let's have a
business lunch or a business dinner.
Right?
And also if you look at how we socialize
with the family,
how we socialize with each other,
if you actually look back at your
history and say,
oh,
I'm that guy buddy or my family,
whatever.
If you look back at the majority of the
positive memories that you have,
they're generally at thanksgiving with
the family or christmas with this or we
got drunk with this guy or we at burgers
late at night or whatever it is because
that's,
you get these sort of endorphin rushes.
And I,
oh,
we're bonding.
So I think once you take that out,
and I.
It's interesting because I was taught
someone the other day,
I was saying the more gets
sophisticated,
the more you kind of have to fly because
it's to have that meeting.
Like we have the night and call,
you know,
but now you have to fly and you have to
have the meal and you have to have to.
Because if you're doing a big deal with
somebody and you don't do that,
even though it doesn't make any sense at
all,
it's become a thing.
Everyone's flying way more.
But ironically,
because of the technology is seen as non
effect,
so there's that in the world of
business.
yeah,
no kidding.
Wow.
I didn't see that coming,
but it totally makes sense.
Yeah,
it completely makes sense.
I feel much different about people when
I meet them.
Yeah.
You know,
and,
and not meeting him even for awhile.
Even being in communication for a long
time without meeting them,
they sort of disassociate.
It doesn't feel the same.
Correct.
Yeah,
it makes sense.
Totally does.
Because we,
that's how we interacted forever.
I wonder if that same feeling will
happen when you're dealing with someone
in a three d form,
like a hologram that's
indistinguishable.
Interesting.
And it's coming rapidly.
Yeah.
I mean the technology is here now,
it's just how quick can they make it
into like a thing that everybody can
buy.
Yeah.
How quick can they and what would,
what form will it take?
Because we're just extrapolating from
what they have right now.
Who knows what form it's going to be
available.
Google already has their contact lens
thing and nobody thought this whole
thing was going to happen in the first
place.
This augmented reality,
this wasn't something discussed 20 years
ago,
it was always virtual reality.
It wasn't,
yeah,
it wasn't reality and it might just
skip,
might just go to augmented,
it could go to something even crazier
than that.
It can go to some sort of a,
some sort of a recreation of life that
is,
is imparted into your brain.
Yeah.
Literally a hologram that's an
individualized hologram on the inside of
your eye.
Yeah.
It's like projecting on your eyelid or
on your eyeball.
Yeah,
but what I'm thinking is something even
crazier now when you close your eyes and
you're transported,
you know,
like what was that movie with arnold
work?
Total recall style because he just shot
into this new place that seems to me to
not be far off.
I just see.
I see where they're going as far as
their ability to send signals from brain
to brain through an annoyance.
You know,
what is being worked on and
theoretically possiBle what they.
So interstellar space.
Travel is hard and impossible because
people will die before they get to where
they're supposed to be going and all
this stuff.
So theoretically what we can do is we
can,
you know,
have clones in other places and you
download your,
your brain into a,
like a computer,
you send that brain to another computer
through laser beam traveling at the
speed of light,
and then it gets downloaded into the
clothing on the other side of the thing.
Now that's obviously highly theoretical.
What's going to happen?
You're going to have a whole country
filled with Donald Trump,
like 1 billion.
Trump's,
he's just gonna fucking keep recreating
themselves over and over and over again.
And you're going to be.
People are going to make more than one
version of themselves going to be walls
everywhere.
That's going to be a real problem.
You come home,
there's 15 of you in your house,
you know,
and they all want to watch the game and
scream the same things.
And then you're competing to see who
says,
this is another interesting thing.
This is another interesting thing
because technology,
when we go back to sanity versus
insanity.
So for example,
right now we have crispr technology
where you can edit the genome,
right?
Right.
And go in and log.
So you can go in and say,
well I don't want to edit out the cancer
thing and like when you were going to
have a kid and then you can say,
well hey,
they're not going to have downs.
You're like,
fuck yeah,
that sounds good,
but you know,
putting cancer and make n six,
four and you know this and that,
the other thing put out,
take out the.
Right.
And so because of that,
we said,
okay,
well we're not gonna what I'm gonna do
that because we're playing god know
stuff.
But they have places in China already
where they're,
where they're going to do that.
Now if you extrapolate because they're
already experimenting on human fetus.
But if you extrapolate and you say,
okay,
they start doing this and everybody
comes out genius plus iq and seven feet
tall and super strong and whatever.
It's kind of an arms race.
Yes.
And you're going to say,
whoa,
gatica be damned like we were going to
have to compete.
And,
and that's when you don't see like,
oh,
this technology where like when your
logical said,
well we can't mess with this because
it's funny because they,
they,
they do things like,
oh,
they were checking in on how
butterflies,
he called her and they used crispr to
change like one thing and then all of a
sudden the butterfly,
a monarch butterfly just became all
white and like their,
you know,
things shrunk when her kids were like,
you're playing god and you're like,
one thing makes all this other shit
happened.
And so,
but that's happening now.
That's happening today.
They're actually doing it.
Yeah.
And what if they deal with wooly
mammoths?
TheY say,
you know what?
We could whack this all the way up to
$100 super mammoth.
And they started making superman mous
with three decks.
It's going to be real strange 100 years.
Really.
We're not going to be able to say,
well,
you and I are probably less science can.
I don't even know that the live.
Well,
that's the other thing is they're saying
now with advances in medicine that the
kids being born today are going to live
into their hundreds.
Yeah,
I've heard that they're going to live to
be 150 years old.
That's going to be really common,
but the thing is that's just saying that
today they might come up with something
five years from now that makes people go
back like reverse aging.
That's entirely possible.
I mean,
it's just a process.
It's a biological process.
If you can stay alive long Enough for
them to figure that out,
how to turn it back and you know,
that's the real playing god,
turn you back,
go back to when you were younger and
then you're going to have to.
You're going to be a younger.
You dealing with a new super race that's
been developed
where everyone is 300 pounds of solid
muscle and every olympic wrestler.
Yeah.
Every olympic wrestling match between
two enormous gorillas.
There's no more fighting ai sort of war
against the terminator bots.
It's going to be incredibly strange.
What is that?
Aging is reversible,
at least in human cells and live mice.
Changes to gene activity that occur with
age can be turned back.
A new study shows jesus christ.
Longevity can be turned back.
I'll tell you what's going to happen.
Old ladies going to be out getting dick
like crazy.
That's going to be happening.
They're going to,
they're going to turn 20 and then
they're going to be on a rampage.
They're going to just hit the clubs and
fuck everybody.
Well,
I got to tell you,
you know this,
that your evolutionary clock stops at
40.
Like it just at 40.
You don't,
you don't continue on to,
oh,
we're going to try this and we're going
to ourselves.
We'll keep on making new shit.
It just stops.
And if you could,
if you could go in and said,
I'm going to go to the clinic and keep
my envelope.
EvolutionAry clock ticking.
What'd you do it?
Well,
anything that made me feel better.
Yeah,
that's how I feel.
I mean,
you know,
people said,
well that's really selfish and you'll
stay around forever and use up all the
resources.
Uh,
that's not up to you bitch in here.
Here's the other problem with that.
Like when throw 500 years ago,
everybody died at 20,
you know,
nobody fucking lived to be today.
Like being 49 was impossible back then.
It was incredibly tiny,
tiny,
tiny people that didn't eat that much.
So yeah,
I would do it.
Yeah,
I would do it selfishly or would I do
it?
I would do it just because it would be a
better experience.
Like if they all of a sudden gave you
something and you felt your immune
system work better,
your,
you know,
your body fat was lower,
you had more vitality,
you've got more things done,
you more energetic and you don't have to
lose any experience.
You don't have to loSe any understanding
of the world.
You don't lose your facultIes.
Yeah.
Why wouldn't I do it?
So that's the famous to students.
The thing with technology is that,
is that there's going to,
they're going to try to hold it back,
but it's just going to get.
They're going to get it back.
I don't think they can hold it back.
Yeah.
Well,
I think the China factor is huge because
I think if China really does start doing
that with crispr and make these super
athletes and superhumans and make people
that are just infinitely smarter than
what we have today,
that that also plays into my idea of
technology induced evolution.
I think symbiotically introduced where
it's like human beings interacting with
technology,
but I think also that technology being
applied to our biological being,
all that stuff is going to happen.
Did you ever read neuromancer?
Oh god,
why did I,
why does that was a while.
Basically he,
he,
he's was that love prophesied?
No,
it's a lookup neuromancer.
It's a canadian guy,
but he's,
he's a William Gibson gibson.
There you go.
Eighty four,
84.
Wow.
Um,
but basically he,
he,
he sort of foresaw all of stuff
happening
and sort of,
by the way,
it's interesting because he gets
credited with a lot of the tech stuff
because a lot of people who were in
college read em and then use those Ideas
to invent the things that are coming out
now.
That's cool.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
What a science.
I wonder what drugs he took.
Probably good ones,
huh?
But if you've ever read it,
you're like,
holy shit.
Like he,
he,
he called it all.
I feel like I read it,
but I think I read it like right out of
high school.
yeah,
it's been so long distant ones,
but I love the fact that these people
who are creative people you know,
are the ones that have come up with a
lot of these ideas.
There was a thing of reading she wells
and all the different things that hg
wells predicted and the people will say,
actually that's not so crazy,
but well that's how things get started.
It's just they can't do it,
you know,
like,
well all the shit we're talking about
now,
you know,
you just,
you and I talking about potential
technologies,
those thoughts like between people at
uni that are not technologically savvy
at all.
Those thoughts can get into the mind of
someone who is and then they can project
that idea in their own way and start
working on it.
Those are going to be a huge revolution,
and then they'll say,
joe and jane,
the council of elders,
we made it to imagine if it all boils
down,
civilization in the future,
after the mad max days,
and it'll pull us down to this
conversation.
We'll try and wild stallions.
How's that?
How's it like the.
Whilst I agree with you was thinking
about it.
It's a bill and ted's excellent
adventure.
Jesus.
They saved the world.
Bill and ted's excellent adventure.
Yeah.
Um,
do we have enough people?
We didn't.
We only picked one woman.
We need more than women.
Who else?
I like Martha Stewart.
I enjoy her on that.
Snoop dogg show.
She's a hell of a woman she had.
She also doesn't give a shit.
Put her in coach.
Yeah,
she's good.
She's good.
She doesn't give a shit.
I like people don't give a shit.
People just through the fucking papers
over there.
That's it.
He just fucking elected Martha Stewart.
This guy's an asshole.
I'm not listening to this podcast
anymore.
I liked Martha Stewart because she's
been to jail.
Yes,
she's fucking down.
I always say like it held her mud.
If you,
if you,
if you've done shit and seeing things,
then you're much better a ruler than
somebody who's never done anything.
I like her.
Yeah.
So by that,
by that logic,
who else?
Who else has done shit and seen things
that you'd like to throw in the mix?
Hmm.
I mean,
it's hard because you're searching.
Your database is for.
There's a lot of different people out
there who are sort of admirable.
Again,
I mean there was a lock.
Yeah,
we'd have to really.
We'd have to really sit down if someone
was going to really formulate something
along those lines,
you'd have to really think it through.
Yeah.
But not impossible and,
and a better solution than this fucking
mess.
Presidential masses.
Ridiculous.
You know,
and it's also is gonna sound fucked up,
but I don't think everybody should be
allowed to vote.
I think you should have to prove in some
way that you have an understanding of
what you're saying in order to be able
to vote.
The problem with that of course is who
the hell gets to decide that that's the
problem.
But if you have someone who's mentally
deranged and they just haven't committed
a crime yet and you,
you read what they have to say about
lIfe and about people and they're racist
and sexist,
but he's lIke,
here's the problem with that.
Right?
And,
and I agree with you,
but it's also problematic because here's
the problem that's happening.
It's happening all over the world,
but let's say In America,
because everybody's up in arms about
trump and there's protests and all this
stuff and all the media is going,
can you fucking believe this guy?
and you only realize that that's what
the rest of the country was saying.
Every time obama opened his mouth.
And so you sit there and say,
hold on a second here.
Half the country believes that,
you know,
people crazy.
People in California and New York voted.
And then now I in Texas and Oklahoma
have to fucking suffer on the other.
Half of the people were saying,
hold on a second.
These people in Oklahoma and Texas and
Ohio voted and now I have to fucking,
you know,
listen to all this shit.
And so that therein lies the rub.
Because to go back to it,
you say,
okay,
if he hear me out,
if you had your security and economic
security,
uh,
like solidified was there,
wouldn't it be more democratic to just
say,
okay,
Texas is Texas and California.
That's what it used to be.
Anyways.
The United States was the states rights
and all this stuff because the minute
that happened to California,
it's like,
fuck it.
That just split off.
We want our pot.
You know what I mean?
Well,
it would be interesting because you were
talking about with other countries,
having smaller,
more manageable groups is more
democratic democratic.
It's not a democratic,
not a bad idea in the current state that
we exist in.
Not a bad idea to run things.
If it's dysfunctional,
in fact,
it's worse than dysfunctional.
You're just going back to undo what they
just did.
Why wouldn't you just say,
fuck it.
California is going to go off and do our
own thing in Texas.
Going to do its thing in Oklahoma is
going to do its thing.
And by the way,
if you don't like it in Oklahoma,
you can move to California.
And how about less reliance,
much,
much less reliance on a federal
government because it's not necessarily.
It doesn't work.
Yeah.
And it doesn't work,
but state government does.
So it works better because it's smaller
and more and more democratic.
Yeah.
I mean it's sort of tribes,
as long as we can keep from going to war
with each other,
you know,
but that's what you have to do.
If you guarantee that economic security
and you guarantee that,
that sort of political and military and
security,
then it kind of makes a ton of sense to
just say,
well,
if we're like minded people in New York
or la or like,
okay,
California,
what's the stat?
It's like California would be the eighth
economy in the world.
Six,
six,
six largest economy in the world.
Believe that paul shows a third of
california's favor,
a cal exit from the us and awakened
trump's election victory.
And they were just fucking shitting on
Texas by the way,
years ago for this.
Either way I favor it because I live
here.
It's god's country,
but all the tech people here smart,
all the food is here right?
Right.
All the money's here.
It's one of the biggest here.
Kanye west is here and have all of the
kardashians and fact,
and you can sit here and say it's more
democratic.
We can have our.
We'd have cbd.
Fuck it.
Let's just.
Let's.
Let's do the experiments to Italy and
France can live close to each other.
Why can't California,
Nevada be different countries?
Right?
It's basically the same thing.
Fucking same thing.
Goddammit.
We'd like to start today.
The California.
I guess it's already started.
It's already started.
We didn't even have to do.
We'll run though me and you will run.
What do you want to ticket?
What do you want to be?
A lot of California.
I'll be vice president.
You can be credit going to be fucking
president.
Every president,
I'll be like,
oh,
we biden.
I don't even want to be a vice
president.
I'll have a sort of legacy.
Will be on the council of elders.
We're going to have.
I think california's the only one cook
enough to actually say,
fuck it.
We're going to leave my.
Let me tell you something.
We might win in this new era.
In this new era where you can't,
you can't be president,
you're canadian,
you're american.
Now we have to change the laws,
but if you're going to have to battle
our.
No,
but it's immediately going to
California,
California.
We'll,
we'll,
we'll allow it.
We'll wait as a couple.
You can be governor of California.
Obviously arnold.
I could be governor and then switch it
over or.
Yeah.
Well,
when it becomes a country,
then we say,
well fuck all this being born here.
It's stupid.
You have nothing to do with where you're
born.
Doesn't have anything to do with it.
You didn't ask to be born in Canada.
If you did,
if you could take it back.
Would you be born here in god's country?
If you could take it back,
if you could denounce your canadian
birth?
No.
I'll tell you why I show you my first
want you to.
Because.
Because I think the.
I think the american experience
ironically is an immigrant experience.
I am literally the american dream.
You are.
I came here as an american to me.
I came here as an immigrant.
I killed it.
I love it.
I love it here.
I love California.
I'm like stroking.
Awesome.
I say it to everybody and everyone shits
on me.
I'm like,
fuck you.
And,
and,
and uh,
but look,
growing up in Canada,
I'm going to say it.
Great country,
clean,
great schools,
nicer.
Nice people are really nice.
Great.
So I look,
but what I believe 20 percent less
douche bags probably,
I think,
but I believe that it doesn't fucking
matter where you're born,
like,
good,
cool.
Like,
you know what,
if you're good and you're smart and
whatever you,
you rise to the top.
You're hard working.
You know,
this was a country built by immigrants
and then all of a sudden they're saying,
well,
they were the good ones.
Now there's bad ones.
Yeah.
And even better because
you were born in Canada,
you can't be president,
which is a shit job in the first place.
So it makes you the ultimate american.
Hey,
I'd love to be president,
fix this mess,
but I can't do it.
Can't do it.
I was born in the wrong piece of dirt.
I can't do it.
You literally could fucking drive in a
couple of hours from where you were into
America.
Yeah,
I mean,
it's ridiculous.
I mean it's like I am connected to
Delaware in some way.
We're both in the same country.
Well,
you were,
you were.
Living in Canada is way fucking closer
to the United States than me to
Delaware.
It's all the same shit.
It's all the same land mass.
And they go,
god damn it.
We're stupid.
Yes,
but you're a more american than me,
man.
You are an actual immigrant.
I was just lucky.
I got lucky that my grandparents,
parents,
my great grandparents were like,
fuck Italy.
And they moved over with my grandparents
were little and Ireland too.
Same thing.
My grandfather,
great grandfather on my father's side,
same thing.
They all just said,
fuck this place.
And they brought their kids over and uh,
they had to figure out this new thing.
It was a new thing.
Yeah.
It wasn't wide open.
I mean,
it's still kind of a new thing.
We'll look at the history.
Well,
look at it though,
like the tech world,
everyone's coming from everywhere to
silicone to hear silicone beach.
Everyone's coming and you're like,
that's a fucking great thing.
It is a great because you're getting all
the best and smartest people coming here
and giving us their knowledge and you're
like,
why is that?
Man?
That's fucking great.
You know it's really interesting too is
they're almost universally leaning left
if you look at all of these powerful
tech giants,
whether it's even like social media
companies like facebook and apple and
they,
they almost predominantly lean left
despite the fact that they're worth
billions of fucking dollars and their
main driving force in our account.
I think that this is,
this is my,
my problem because I don't know if
they're leaning left necessarily.
They're backing things that are
perceived as left leaning like that.
Like for example,
if you have a fucking brain and you've
talked to scientists and you've and
you've read and you're like,
oh shit,
we're up against the wall.
Like I say,
humans won't do anything until the
fucking guns to that.
The guns to the fucking head.
Right?
And so if you talk to any of these
people,
it's like,
okay,
yes,
I fucking,
how do we fucking fix this?
The fact that that's laughed or liberal,
that's stupid.
Right?
And,
and I don't understand it.
The other thing is you go onto like pot
for example,
we all know where it's going.
Or if you want to talk about,
like for example,
the women's march on civil rights.
We all know where we're fucking going.
Yeah.
If you grew up as we did in the fucking
modern age civil rights.
Okay.
We're not fucking going backwards.
Right?
How the fuck.
That became a fucking left thing too.
It's crazy.
I mean,
how is it not a right thing as it should
be?
One thing we will all meet in the
middle,
one thing where we meet 100 percent in
the middle and go,
look,
there can't be racism anymore.
We gotta get.
This doesn't make any fucking sense.
It's too old.
It's too stupid.
It's just an archaic monkey way of
thinking.
It's back to our primal tribal fact that
it's still on the fucking table.
Is this stupid?
Yeah,
it's fucking stupid.
I feel the same way about gay rights.
I feel the exact same way.
If you have a real problem with gay
neighbor,
these,
these folks that lived down the street,
they have a kid,
they adopted a kid,
they have a fucking dog.
They walk by.
They're the nicest fucking people in the
world.
I feel like the fuck.
Do you care family?
What the fuck do you care?
Why would anybody care?
Civil rights,
gay rights,
women's rights part of it.
We all know where we're going.
Exactly.
We all know where we're going,
so why the fuck are we having these
fights and fucking is because people on
one look at mean you were talking about
earlier,
the black lives matter.
People upset at the women's rights
movement.
The trans community upset the women
wearing vaginas.
People are crazy for a fractious,
fractious,
yes,
that's a good word.
I ever used it,
but I'm and start fucking thrown it
around him and I think that this is why
we need some sanity and you need some
common sense and saying,
look,
people,
we all know where we're getting this
stuff,
fighting each other.
We need psychedelic drugs.
That's really what we need.
I mean,
this sounds stupid,
but mushrooms and ptsd as well also mtma
and ptsd and I wasa securing a lot of
people smoking and alcoholism.
Um,
and a heroin.
Yeah.
And that's,
a lot of that is also because they,
they need to get iowasca because
dimethyltryptamine,
the active compound of it is illegal in
the United States even though your body
produces it and go.
There's actually a clinics in Mexico
again,
which is an amazing one for heroin.
Rewires the mind if you have someone
who,
you know as an opiod addiction,
my friend aggregate has a,
my friend ed clay,
he runs a center down in Mexico and he
started it out because he had a problem
with them.
He kicked them by using ibogaine and now
he's like,
we did a story on it and,
and it's incredibly successful.
The guy who we follow through that,
he's still clean.
It's been incredibly.
I mean,
I don't understand why,
if,
if things work,
why we just can't say.
Okay.
Yeah.
Um,
well,
because again,
that's not on our team.
Our team is clean and jesus and bibles
and football and we're not taking trucks
like a bunch of god damn dirty hippy,
but it's so you want bernie sanders and
you want drugs and it's also.
It's also a big pharma.
Yeah,
that too.
It was a lot of money.
Well,
they need to get high too.
That's part of the problem.
Part of the problem is all these fucking
people that have already made a fuckload
of money and they're trying to protect
those investments.
They are involved in these gigantic
organizations,
these corporations.
It becomes this diffusion of
responsibility situation where you have
all of these people acting in the
benefit of the group or for the benefit
of the group.
Not thinking about everybody as
individuals and justifying what they do
by the fact that,
hey,
this is just business.
This is how it's done.
This how it's always done.
There's enough fucking profit or
rhetoric,
there's enough and if you're in a
business and you're only way to make
profit is by eating babies and he go,
well look,
my country,
we've been eating babies over here for a
long time and we're not going to just
stop eating babies.
No,
you have to stop eating babies.
We know it's not good now and I feel the
same way about fucking seaworld.
They need to stop having dolphins and
whales and orcas in captivity.
Cut the shit.
Can't do that anymore.
Like it's the same.
It's.
There's a lot of things that we know are
bad,
but we allow them to go on because
they've gone on for a long time and I
think that's.
I mean that's across the board.
There's a lot and those.
All of those,
they're being exposed now.
It's one of the more interesting things
about this time is that because of all
the.
All the information that's out now about
opiate addictions,
that's the reason why doctors prescribed
less and less now.
That's the reason why they're under more
and more scrutiny.
It's not because of the doctors wanting
to stop,
stop.
It's because our information got out
drug in the last 10 years and it's
because guys like you and advice got
fentanyl.
Yeah.
What?
I know a guy who just died of it.
Yeah,
I know.
A a martial arts guy.
Just fucking crazy.
It's great.
It's,
it's way more powerful than heroin,
right?
Way more.
400 times more powerful.
That's crazy.
God damn it.
Fuck fucking looked at.
Oxies went not strong enough,
bro.
This stuff's for pussies.
Well,
the thing with fentanyl is you can take
like one grain of it and then cut it
into so and so.
It's just to go back to your point,
it's pure profit,
but the fact of the thing is people are
dying like motherfuckers on it.
Yeah.
And you're like,
holy shit.
And people didn't know that they were
addicted to fentanyl until they went in
to try to get treated.
And they're like,
oh shit,
you're not addicted to heroin.
You're addicted to fentanyl,
which is even harder to kick.
God damn it.
And it's synthetic and it's something
that human beings have created and
created over the last 10 years.
Right?
And there's not a lot of data on it as
far as like,
it's for like a,
you know,
operating on rhinoceros.
I mean it's,
it's super fucking straw.
It's super strong were assholes,
but to like the opioid overdoses are
going through the roof.
It's never been higher.
A deaths have never been higher and
we're just sitting there going,
well,
we're making this stuff.
Like we can stop making it.
Whoever is making that stuff is a
monster.
If you're making that stuff,
you are a monster.
Whatever company that's making them.
The fact that the government hasn't
stepped in trump immediately steps in
and fucking stops the protests and the
dakota pipeline and start that back up
again and he doesn't do anything about
fentanyl.
One hundred percent on that.
That's what numbers of deaths.
Jamie,
pull up the numbers of deaths and you
know,
maybe it's not on his table.
Maybe people aren't bringing it to him,
but goddamn shit.
Huge.
It's a huge,
huge problem that the opioid addictions
are going through the roof and death.
Let's guess,
how many people a year do you think die
from fentanyl in the United States?
Well,
it just started,
they just started being able to track
it,
but I would say 50,000.
Oh,
I was going to say 19,000.
I don't know why I said I would say
50,000.
Okay.
I'm going low.
He's going.
Hi jamie.
What are the numbers?
Drum roll please.
Readily pal.
Yet that's because the god damned
pharmaceutical companies are fucking
around with the man.
Let's just see opioid overdoses in 2016.
What?
No,
no,
no.
We need to specifically find out.
Oh,
well,
let's just go.
Let's just see what that is.
It'll see.
It'll give us ballpark.
That's going to be a lot for opioid
overdoses in the United States.
I'm going with $75,000.
When you say,
I don't know,
you don't get you gotta?
Yes.
Can't say I don't know.
I went,
okay.
Okay,
so we're fine.
Because you gotta think like,
oh that's overdose deaths.
Deaths.
That's a lot.
Like that's a ton.
Right?
But I bet it's probably accurate.
I mean you think about the $350 million
people and I think there's something
like $39 million that are on.
Oh,
it's something insane.
Insane.
The number of people that are on
painkillers.
It's fucking bananas.
What do we got here?
Do,
do,
do 50,
$2,000.
Bam.
You're a monster.
You fucking nailed it.
Look at you.
Well I got 52.
I got a.
Hold on.
I had 50,000
on drugs.
Drug over those 15 opioids driving this
epidemic with 20,000.
Oh,
so I was right.
There you go.
That's 20 slash 15 slash 16 I believe.
He was like,
yeah,
it was close to 75.
I think.
Jesus christ.
So it ramped up that much.
It's going.
God,
I believe it's doubled in the past three
years in 2016.
Is that maybe it's not open.
It's probably not out yet.
They're still counting up.
The body's.
She's fucked up.
Fucking crazy.
It's just crazy.
And um,
find out this,
um,
what are the number?
They don't give you the number of people
that are on them,
but they'll give you the number of
prescriptions for 2015 and 16 for
opiates.
No,
I think you get that number.
I think it's $39 million.
Jesus.
I think that's what I had read,
that there was $39 million
prescriptions,
which is one out of 10,
but it's not really because like,
like how many times did they refill it?
Right.
Is it that,
is it,
when you say someone has a prescription,
are you saying you had your,
it's prescribed to you or are you saying
I write you a new prescription when it
runs at 39 million people on opioids is.
I mean that's a large country.
Yeah it is,
but that's one out of 10.
It's more than one out of 10.
If it's,
um,
if it's,
if it's per person.
Yeah,
I don't think it is per person.
No,
I think it's per prescription.
So like,
like you might be able to have five
prescriptions over the course of a year,
you know,
but then again they don't
know because a lot of it is illegal.
That's the majority of the problem.
Yeah.
I mean I would,
I would gather that probably half of it
is illegal at least because.
Because you got illegal stuff,
pills coming in from all over the world
and Mexico and then people.
So the story we did on it was they get
addicted to oxy,
then they can't afford it because our
are more expensive than heroin.
I don't know how the fuck that happened,
I guess whatever.
And then they're doing heroin because
it's cheaper than fentanyl because it's
cheaper still and stronger.
And there's that whole thing of like
when someone dies of a heroin overdose,
everyone goes to their dealer and buys
from them because oh,
then it's really strong.
So that's another reason why fentanyl is
going through the roof.
Isn't that amazing?
It's such a bizarre state that we're in
when it comes to that.
And then there's all sorts of other
prescription pills that people are
taking you.
How many people are addicted to xanax?
You know,
not a lot of them are dropping like
flies,
but it's a huge issue.
And all these wives
is that.
I meet in these,
like these wealthy communities,
all these people and there like so many
fucking people are on xanax.
They're laughing about.
I'll just have a xanax on the glass of
wine,
like how many of you fuckers are on
xanax?
Some lady was at the comedy or at the
improv the other night and she was so
comfortable.
Heckling.
She was in the front row.
She's an older lady and she was a little
drunk.
She's tipsy,
but she was so comfortable hecklin and
chat it up and I go,
let me guess.
I go,
you had a glass of wine and xanax and
she fucking got up and high fived me.
She was laughing.
Yes,
yes,
you're right.
And I go,
do you take that all the time?
She's like,
all the time.
I can't get along without it.
Wasn't there a stat I remember this,
that and hopefully we can pull it way
too much work.
Right.
He's confused.
But there was a stat that like 50
percent of the country was on
pharmaceutical,
some sort of like xanax or this or that
or whatever.
Booze and the other 50 percent was on,
you know,
pot or coke or this or that.
Which kind of makes sense.
Yeah.
And so you're like,
basically,
you know,
it reminded me,
reminded me of,
um,
like platoon when,
when elias is dudes were all smoking pot
and they were like the freaks and then
the other dudes were drinking whiskey
and beer and whatever,
and it's like,
it's sort of like,
those are your tribes.
Like the freaks and the crazy guys were
smoking the weed and the good know
hardcore guy,
whatever his name was,
the tom berenger character.
They were the wild Turkey drinkers.
And,
but if you just look at it,
you're like,
well,
everybody in the country in some form or
another is taken some,
right?
Yeah.
But if not,
then they're going to aa meetings and
smoking cigarettes and drinking coffee
them.
That's really what's going on,
man.
You know,
what do we got here?
Jamie got some stats.
Fifty two american,
that's even 52 million americans use
prescription drugs for nonmedical
reasons of these once in their lifetime.
So that means people that are
recreationally taking,
yeah.
Uh,
probably no painkillers.
Death by overdose is including involving
prescription painkillers quadrupled.
Wow,
that's incredible.
More than six point $5.
Million people above the age of 11 used
prescription drugs for nonmedical
reasons in 2013 more than cocaine.
Cocaine number looks unbelievably low.
I think that's New York on a friday
night.
Santa monica.
There's a liar's total number of retail
drug prescriptions in 2015.
It's 4 billion.
Sixty $5 million.
One hundred 75,000.
Sixty four.
Holy shit.
We are fucking.
We've been evaded.
You're a good researcher.
He's a bad mother.
Good.
We've been in vico.
Look how.
Look at Alabama who come in strong
families at the top.
It's just.
Oh,
I see.
Oh yeah,
California though.
Oh my god.
Four hundred $58 million.
We're taking it.
we're taking it out here in Florida is
just.
We're number one New York.
That's hilarious at flora's number two
because it's way less people in Florida
and you're just above New York.
Wow.
Wow,
dude.
We're.
There's way less people in Florida.
Ohio is way up there for ohio's.
You grew up their kid.
You know what's up?
You got to get fucked up.
You fucked up.
You want to get through where?
We're in Ohio,
columbus,
Ohio.
a lot of punk bands from there,
a reason why it's fucking blue gray and
all through winter go outside.
It's no goddamn clouds,
just a dark roast or no sun.
Just darkness and gloomy and heroin and
pills.
Pills.
Yeah man,
it's not good and I don't know how to
get that out of the system.
That's like a.
That's like having a computer virus and
you bring it to the computer guy and
he's like,
oh jesus.
It's in everYthing.
That's also another reason why we're all
fucked up.
We said everybody's just,
you know,
drugging themseLves and oh,
fucking opioids in new.
And the cynics will say,
well you're,
you're a fucking pot hood talking about
that and you're a pothead.
What's the difference,
bro?
That's pot stupid.
First of all.
Second of.
well,
it doesn't,
doesn't do anything bad to you.
It's already been established.
Obviously know no one's trying to stop
whiskey.
No one's trying to stop wine.
Not trying to stop people from taking
things that are manageable.
There is nothing manageable about
fentanyl.
If you're rolling the dice with death
every time you're doing something that's
not good.
And also,
if you're getting addicted like that and
you just can't,
you can't do anything about it,
then that's just stupid and it's way
harder to kick.
He said,
yeah,
I mean it's,
it's much stronger.
So obviously needed that,
like,
who approved that,
what was it was for animals.
And then they said,
oh,
we can just cut this.
And it's sort of like super strong
heroin.
It's like pcp,
right?
Pcp was a,
an animal tranquilizer.
I know,
but it's just amazing that someone
greenlit that,
that they look at goal on paper seems to
be an order.
Let's go roll it out.
Well,
how many.
This is my thing,
how many hippopotamuses and rhinos are
we traCking because somebody must've
looked at at some point and said,
fuck,
this is a lot of hippopotamus.
Is getting their livers removed here in,
uh,
in New York city.
Jesus christ.
Yeah.
Well,
once those woolly mammoths start fucking
roman through Russia and chew and
everything,
we needed it.
I'd have to shoot him with darts.
Going to have to try and check them out,
make sure they're not doing anything
weird.
We need the mammoths,
we need the mammoth.
Make sure that all evolving.
Honest.
Yeah,
we're times man.
Really,
really,
really weird times and more weird I
think than any other time in human
history for sure.
And you know,
if we believe in moore's law then it's
going to just go like you're saying,
we have this technology now.
We can't even like it Used to be like,
oh,
50 years from now we'll write about five
years from now,
we don't know what the fuck's going to
happen.
All this shit is just like,
well,
we can,
you know,
map the genome and now we can edit the
genome.
Now we can reverSe aging.
NOw we can do this now.
And you'Re jusT sitting there going,
holy shit.
This is hAppening in real time.
So quicklY.
And,
and,
and because of that and the sort of the
speed is ramping up.
I kinda like it though,
because you knoW,
I do a lot of medical research and I'm
like,
um,
you know,
one of the reasons why I'm not drinking
here is because I got to go for my
annual physical and I'm going to go in
and not have too much booze or whatever
my body.
But what's interesting about it is they
map your shit and they check out your
shit and they say,
well this is going to happen or that can
happen,
whatever else.
but you sitting there and you go,
in five years,
you're going to have aggressive
therapies if not cures for many forms of
cancer.
So you're just sitting there going,
please,
for fuck's sakes,
just just get me another fucking 10
years.
Yeah.
So that I can get to this sort of stage.
And I think a Lot of people with a lot
of diseases that hitherto have been
incurable are sitting there going,
come on,
come on.
Like,
you know,
beCause it's just,
it's,
it's going exponentially.
And when you can map the genome,
then you can figure this out and we can
rewire that fucking thing.
And,
well,
there's also more understanding about
nutrition now than ever before and the
causes of all these illnesses and a big
part of that is inflammation,
gut,
gut health,
gut health.
And that pertains to a lot of it
pertains to your diet,
you know,
and uh,
also the overprescription of
antibiotics.
I was listening.
Posture is your bio.
Yeah.
I was listening to this podcast today
where they were discussing,
this one was discussing having a.
She had some sort of a,
an illness and they gave her too.
Oh,
she had an ear infection and they gave
her two big doses of antibiotics and she
was fucked up for a decade.
Just her.
She just had constant pain,
chronic pain,
all these illnesses and injuries.
And then finally she went to a
homeopathic doctor and the doctor sorted
out with probiotics and she'd bullshit.
She was saying like the woman,
her name was like snowflake and her
child was moon child,
don't have the exact card,
was not started.
It was a great,
great,
great doctor called dr lipman.
He's an internist.
And what happened was I had a stomach
eating flesh eating stomach parasite.
Oh jesus and dysentery.
You've got an Afghanistan.
I came back and I was in trouble.
I was,
went to the sort of tropical disease
center and they're like,
holy shit,
we have to get this out.
Uh,
and so what did it look like?
Well,
I took super strong,
super,
super strong antibiotics and afterwards
I was like,
I'm fucked up.
Like I'm,
I'm seriously fucked up here.
I can't get out of bed.
Like I messed up and this guy goes like
this internist.
You got to go see him.
So it goes to him and he's just like,
you need a ton of pro box,
you need to rebuild your bio.
Right?
And so I did,
I just took a ton of probiotics and he
put me on the shit whenever I was a new
man.
Right?
Because,
because all your immune system,
everything is there like the now they
found out.
So you know,
what was happening was cdf and crohn's
disease and all these things were
happening because there was super bugs
and hospitals because they were over
prescribing antibiotics,
antibiotics.
And so they started doing a fecal
transplants,
have healthy shit.
I tried to explain that to someone they
thought I was joking and read.
Does your bio,
and by the way it was incurable before
people are dying.
And then they do a fecal transplant and
they're cured.
Why?
Because it replenishes your biome,
right?
And you're completely destroying it with
antibiotics.
We did a piece on it,
the post antibiotic world where they
just stopped working.
And if you don't come up with shit like
fecal transplants,
you're fucking dead.
So I went through that and I've got to
say,
you know,
fucking let's spend some money on that.
Look at this.
Autism symptoms improve after fecal
transplant.
Small study finds.
That's.
Yeah,
they're finding out that it has
something to do with a autistic,
um,
parkinson's and alzheimer's.
Yeah.
But the severity of autism symptoms and
all the traits that they exhibit that
something has to do with their gut
biome.
And if you can make the gut biome
healthy,
radically improve parkinson's and
alzheimer's starts in,
your gut,
moves up,
starts to plaque.
And that's another thing that apparently
has a giant effect on people with autism
is medical marijuana,
medical marijuana,
especially edible marijuana.
I have a friend and he moved to
Washington state particularly because of
that,
because when they made it legal and
another friend who is a kid who's also
autistic,
moved to Colorado for that reason,
get it easily and people with cancer.
We have a storY of all these parents who
are like bible thumpers who found the
only thing that worked with cbd and
they're like,
fuck it,
we're moving from Texas and wherever to
to Washington and Colorado because it's
the only thing that helps my kid.
And Here's my message to them.
If you believe in god,
you got to believe that god made
marijuana.
You know it's man that decided it was
bad for you.
It's not god.
It's not logic.
It's definitely not science.
There's just some bullshit propaganda
that got stuck to it in the 19 thirties
and we're still trying to shake it off.
That's really what's going on.
It Has nothing to do with what's right
or what not to do.
A lot of fun in the thirties.
They didn't want booze.
It was right after that.
Actually.
It was right after they had gotten
through the prohibition that they
decided to go after marijuana and that's
really what had happened at all.
It all happened because of William
Randolph hearst.
You know the whole story behind it?
Oh god dammit.
I've told it a tHousand times,
so I'll give you the abbreviated
version.
William randolph hearst owned hearst
publications,
newspapers.
He also owned paper mills and they came
out with this machine called the
decorticator.
That allowed them to much more
effectively process hemp fiber.
A machine.
That process did hemp,
makes us superior paper and makes
superior cloth.
It makes appear you can eat it.
The hemp seeds and nutritious as
essential medial central fatty acids,
all the amino acids.
It's this amazing plant.
It's like an alien planet,
and he decides to demonize it because he
doesn't want to convert his wood,
his trees that he's turning into paper.
He doesn't want to convert it to him and
spend millions of dollars.
So instead he starts publishing stories
about mexicans and blacks that are
taking this new drug called marijuana
and raping white women.
This drug,
marijuana wasn't even the name for
cannabis.
They when they made cannabis outlaw,
when they made it illegal,
when they made marijuana illegal,
they didn't even know they were making
hemp illegal.
They didn't know because the general
public did not know it was the same
thing because this word marijuana was
never associated with a hamp or with
cannabis.
Marijuana was a wild mexican tobacco,
totally unrelated to cannabis.
They called it marijuana so that they
could demonize it and that's when they
funded reefer madness and all those
crazy propaganda movies and posters and
we are still to this day trying to shake
off what William Randolph hearst and
harry anslinger did in the 19 thirties.
It's a very interesting anecdote that
sort of is very pertinent to what's
happening today where you can just make
up a story about something and then it's
fucking.
It's the truth.
It's really perfect.
It's the perfect way to connect it to.
I mean,
we're still dealing with that problem
from almost 100 years ago.
It was crazy.
It's bananas and it's a.
It could happen again.
You know what we're looking at right now
is not a rigid,
completely rock solid civilization.
All it would take is one asteroidal
impact,
one killing of the power grid,
one mean what something happens to
media.
Shower happens and it kills off 30
percent of the population and permafrost
permafrost.
That could happen and there's so many
things that could go wrong.
Yellowstone,
they have thousands of earthquakes in
yellowstone every year.
It's a giant called dara volcano that at
one point in time blew up and killed
everything on the continent.
Every six to 800,000
years it goes and when it goes,
that's a wrap.
Babies in the last time it went 600,000
years ago and we have thousands of
earthquakes every year in yellowstone.
You go there and you watch steam
shooting out of the ground because the
fucking boiling magma is so close to the
surface that the rivers and streams in
the underground water runs into it,
heats it up and shoots it up in the sky
on a regular basis.
It's fucking bananas.
What I love about that is everyone who
goes and says,
look that that's fucking awesome.
Yeah,
it's really cool,
but it's.
It's totally possible that that fucking
thing with very little notice could blow
and if it blows,
we were dead because it's too.
Or too close to it,
which it's in Montana.
That's not far enough away.
I mean maybe some people in the east
coast to survive,
but they're going to go into nuclear
winter and it's going to fuck up
everybody all over the world,
but that's why,
speaking about technology that you know,
if you ever talked to,
for example,
our guy on our council of elders,
ilan musk,
he's like,
why would be,
why are we a single planetary species?
Why wouldn't we just hedge our bets and
have by planetary species?
Because if something does go wrong,
at least you've got your data and your
culture and your people and whatever,
and why wouldn't you do that?
If you could do that?
When they put it that way,
you're like,
sort of makes sense because everyone's
like,
oh,
you want to live on mars was crazy
nurse.
There's no evidence that We can live
there though.
The real problem is we can't really stay
in that atmosphere for very long,
but I mean they can make fucking.
Yeah,
but even that we're still dealing with a
lesser gravity.
It's gonna have massive health
consequences for the people that decided
to move there.
Got it.
But I'm just saying that's their
argument.
We should argue multiplanetary species.
It's a good argument and it's also
arguable that with all this crispr
technology,
they might be able to figure out some
sort of a medical solution for people
that do move to a,
you know,
the moon has one sixth earth gravity,
there might be some way that they could
figure out a way to colonize the moon
and you know,
develop some sort of a new technology.
Have crazy shit about permafrost
terraforming and shit.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Creating an atmosphere.
Why don't they do that here?
You have to use nukes to do it in march.
Oh,
that's right.
They have to nuke the Polls.
Right.
They knew couple.
Wonderful.
What a good idea.
Jesus christ.
Anytime your.
That sounds like something a little kid
would come up with.
How are you going to solve this?
What we're going to draw up some fucking
nuclear bombs on the roof.
It's going to make the thing make an
atmosphere too many.
Matt damon.
I alWays.
What I always just think about that is
know they get the equation wrong and
then some like,
oh fuck it.
It throws the,
you know,
the gravitational pull off by four
centimeters,
which you and then you're like,
oh shit.
Yeah,
yeah.
That should have been a carry the two.
And then aliens land on it and take it
over.
As soon as the air comes up.
Those like the actual alien from the
movie alien with the big fucking head.
Those things,
they just camp out right over there and
start building spaceships and plan their
attack problems.
Shane smith,
I don't know if we're gonna solve them
by moving them or do you see that?
Uh,
thAt the last movie,
they're a rival?
Yeah.
no,
I didn't.
I liked it.
I heard it was great.
I heard it was really good.
I haven't seen it yet.
I'm going to see it though.
I liked it.
I thought it was good.
Don't you spoil her?
okay.
I'm not gonna.
I know you wanted to.
Right?
I gotta go man.
Get outta here,
man.
I love this fun.
Always.
Always,
always.
We did a sober one,
said we couldn't do it.
I'll come back a midseason and I'll.
I'll be on the piss again.
Oh,
jesus.
I'm hoping that mayo gives me a clean
bill so that I can come back.
You'll look great.
I'm sure you're fine.
clever.
Amazing.
Gentlemen,
I love you to.
Shane smith was great.