Freak bitches.
I observed the food day of surgery an
entire day.
Like I saw eight operations when I was a
freshman in high school.
I had the illusion that I would be a
doctor,
be a doctor,
and then my uncle was a doctor.
He sent me up at the,
a Mayo Clinic in Jacksonville and so I
meet this guy and I was pretty big kid
so they're like,
what college do you go to?
And I was like,
no,
I'm in school.
And they're like,
okay,
you ready to see this?
Like they thought it was a little more
and the first one we see is a woman who
spread eagle.
She's 80 and the removing assist from
her vagina.
And here's the thing,
he goes,
so he comes over because he comes over
to me and I'm with my dad and he goes,
hey,
don't make any jokes while you're in
here.
And I go,
what are you talking about?
He goes,
she's awake.
So if you're like,
oh,
look at her old plus.
Okay.
No,
but the best way they go in Gnarly,
they fucking open up.
The cyst is the size of a softball,
so the guy's like,
this is the biggest we've ever seen.
Has the,
has another nurse go get a camera,
starts documentaries like this is going
to be in a journal.
This is incredible.
Then they rupture it.
Shooting out of there.
Have you ever seen onto Dr Pimple
popper.com?
Oh,
headphones.
Headphones.
Dr.
Purple Lady on Instagram and I'm
obsessed with her page and she's got
like millions of followers to because
she.
All she does is her youtube videos or
instagram videos or I'll just her
popping cysts.
And it is strangely strangely.
So she cut Dr Sandra Lee.
Hello,
Sandra.
Um,
millions of millions of views on
instagram.
Millions of views on youtube.
Oh No,
not yet.
Wait,
wait till you see it.
You're not going to bark yet.
So right now she's cutting into this
woman's back who has what looks like,
like a small frog growing her back.
So she's like cutting the top of it off.
Cutting a chunk of the meeting was
really good at cutting it yet.
Yeah.
Because she wants to,
uh,
remove it in one chunk.
Like sometimes she can get them Hawaii.
She's opening it up right now with these
scissors.
This is not the most satisfying because
this right now we're just looking at
surgery.
You okay?
Steve?
I don't like it.
Why is it just says she's snipping.
Oh,
why you gotta be so nasty,
Joe.
I have seen so many people get cut and
knocked unconscious and beat up.
I'm not averse to looking at ces.
Now look how nasty this is.
Once you start scoring,
and here we go.
Here we go.
Come on,
come on.
Oh,
thank you.
there you go.
Oh God,
what a person's body to vomit.
No way back.
Is that a back cyst?
What is that?
Sorry to tell them.
What is the cyst is just nasty.
Just nasty shit.
I don't know.
What it says is.
That was,
huh?
I think it's dead skin.
I read about one of these recently
because they're always watching.
Well,
why don't you just google it?
I did.
Oh,
I can't.
well,
we'll find out.
We did so much speculation.
We did a podcast this weekend without,
without Jamie on the computer and we're
asking questions and no one ever
answered the questions we just said it
was like 100 percent misinformation.
I heard.
I heard it was like this.
Do you want to look?
Hey Jamie.
I think we're all good.
That was great.
Thanks.
I'm just going to get to the end of it.
She really,
some of them are fucking unbelievable.
Push them now.
Looks like trash.
Trash in your body yet.
Five minutes left on this video.
I'm going to do a damn thing to me.
You just had a baby.
Should be like durable now with the
whole.
Yeah.
It's crazy how big that hole is.
Like that's a god damn gaping holes.
The stuff coming out.
That's the gnarly parts or why she had
to do it that obviously I'm not a
doctor,
I'm not criticizing her technique,
but I wonder why you have to take a
chunk out of the skin and less instead
of like making like a little hatch.
Like you remember those?
Um,
you know,
like old school pajamas,
scape dude.
Yeah.
That's a small fish.
Oh,
for the love of Mommy,
get that last part out,
that sack that that it's all holding in
and then what's left over after I heard
that they don't actually know what
causes cysts.
How comforting.
I don't know.
Anything.
You just growing up.
Golf ball size,
bag of pus on years from now.
We don't know.
And people grow in weird spots too.
They don't even know why.
Yeah,
go weird.
Spots are going to top your head and
shit.
They over grow and they're not
cancerous.
Find a member.
Woo Membrane the membrane.
This membrane,
the membrane in the body,
a membranous sack or cab cavity of
abnormal character containing fluid.
A tough protective capsule.
And closing the larva.
Parasitic worm.
No.
So yeah,
I guess it's a.
A cavity containing fluid and they used
the word fluid super loosely.
Fluid pus.
It's fluid.
It's like a whipped cream,
like pissy nastiness.
That's not good.
Nah,
no blood on your vagina too.
That's.
I imagine this ladies.
I still remember it.
It was on her badge,
on the outer part so everybody could see
or inside it was inside,
but then they,
they,
they had her in some way where they
could push back and you could see it
coming out of the side coming like on
the wall in a speculum,
like they opened her up.
Wow.
That's gnarly.
Wonder if it really had fluid though.
I do remember that.
It wasn't like this.
It really was like a stream coming out.
I hate.
I hate to be disrespectful,
but do you think it made her pussy
tighter?
I think so.
It seems like a wood.
It's a really good question.
Yeah.
I don't see how,
unless you had it in your mouth and be
sure tough to swallow.
So imagine if you got it in your box.
It was.
I think that's how they said snug it up.
David discovered it because her husband
was tight.
He's like,
Oh shit,
baby.
That,
that,
that 85 percent.