The Gay folks took over the rainbow
for three to,
will it work today,
Jamie?
Yes. Hello Nicholas. Hey Joe. How
are you man? Great to meet you.
It's really good to meet you too.
Ah,
I became aware of you like many people
did with the infamous Halloween costume
incident at Yale. Uh, where, uh,
explain that for people who don't know
what happened cause it was kind of a
crazy scene. It went national.
Yes, it was a moment when, uh,
around the country,
many students were struggling with
how to balance the conflicting, um,
sort of needs a little bit closer to your
face. They are conflicting needs. Uh,
uh, how on the one hand to create an
environment at schools where people,
everyone sort of felt welcome
as we've democratized, uh,
admissions to our American universities
is I think we should have people from
all walks of life have started moving
into these institutions claiming them for
their own,
which I think is appropriate.
But at the same time these institutions
had wonderful heritage is of commitment
to free expression and open debate and um,
and reason as a principal for
resolving our differences.
And US and some of those values came
into tension. And so around the country,
there was a lot of heat about this.
And I happened to walk into
a propeller, uh, myself and,
and wound up, um, in some
challenging circumstances.
And, um, you know, I, I, it was not,
it was not the worst thing that's
ever happened to me, but, you know,
it was sitting in the top 10, uh,
challenging moments I've had in my life,
let's say. Yeah, that's a very lawyer,
like way of describing
exactly what happened.
I mean, the thing is, I, you know, I,
I, I, you know, I struggle. I mean,
you can tell the story if you want
and then I can correct things.
But here's the thing,
it's,
it's my job to be a teacher and I have
taken responsibility for teaching young
people.
And it is the case that many
people lost their minds.
I mean, lost their senses. And, and, and
the faculty too, incidentally. I mean,
you know, there, it's one thing
to talk about people in there,
in college age people, but then, you know,
the faculty also didn't necessarily
do what they should've done, but, um,
but the thing is, is that,
you know, my commitment,
my commitment is to,
is to teaching more generally.
And I don't want to be defined by that
event. I don't want that to become a,
the most important thing about me,
you know,
have this book or this book that we're
going to talk about that is an important
thing in my life.
Instantiates my values.
It talks about what I think is
important about the world. So,
so I'm trying to be balanced about it.
Just, it's one thing that happened.
I did my best. It's in
the past. So let me,
let me help out here because you're
being so nice about the whole thing. Um,
so people know what we're talking about.
There was a,
an incident that was on someone's
cell phone where you were standing
here, people, it was an hour of footage,
five or six different angles.
So a clip went viral,
but I want to emphasize that there were
many people filming that day and an hour
or more of the two or three hours
I was out there as available.
But I'm glad that you had the
courage to do that though,
to stand out there and talk to those kids.
But some of them were clearly,
there's something that happens when people
become extremely self indulgent when
they know that they have
this platform and they, uh,
have someone who is in a
position of authority and
they get to hamstring them in
front of the public.
And that's what I felt was going on to,
is my understanding of human nature.
I knew what she was doing,
what she was doing by shouting
and screaming, this is our
fucking home. You know,
w, you know, we were supposed
to be safe here. I was like,
oh, I see what's going on.
She's throwing up the flag of virtue for
all of her friends to see how amazing
she was. So she's putting
on a show. People do that.
It's, it's, it's human nature.
You handled it admirably.
You stood there and you,
you just listened to her and you never
yelled back and you never raise your
voice and you remained calm.
But that sort of environment
where the children,
and I want to say children,
they're basically adults,
but acting like children.
This is one of the ironies that
the people that age, you know,
can fight in wars and lose their lives.
And so I think it's a,
it's a difficult challenge because on the
one hand it's right and appropriate to
hold people responsible for their actions.
Certainly if you're 20 years old,
you're an adult, you're still
growing, you're still changing,
you're still learning.
I'm not the same man I was when I was 20
but you have to be responsible for your
behavior. Yes. I don't think you get
a total pass either. It's hard now.
You do not get a total pass.
And you know,
for folks who don't have a 20 year old
in their life and don't remember what it
was like, you know, you're not a
fully formed thing yet. You're,
you're filled with chaos,
emotions and hormones and yes.
And then you're at school and you're
probably a way from the instructions of
your parents for the first time and you
know you're cutting loose and trying out
new new ways of communicating that
way. It's, it's a lot of, it's a mess.
But most people felt
horrified watching that,
that you were subjected to that
when you're being very reasonable.
And also what it all came about was your
wife had sent out an email saying like,
hey,
maybe it should be okay for someone
to wear a fucked up Halloween costume.
You know, maybe it's okay to, for someone
to dress up like crazy horse. We have,
well we'll actually, just
to be clear, what Erica was
saying in that note was not,
this is very important intellectual
distinction. I think we've,
we've lost a lot of nuance in our
political lives in general in our country
right now.
And also in the,
in the nuance and the way we think about
difficult topics. So Erica was saying
was not that necessarily the people,
she was not taking a position on any
particular costumes like this is okay.
In fact,
many of the costumes that would have
offended the students would offend her.
But she was saying was that she didn't
think the university should be telling
students what to wear.
And she was asking the students,
do you students really
at this age at Yale,
do you really want the university to be
sending you guidance on what to where?
Perhaps you should think about
that. You're adults, you're smart,
you're in an environment that
privileges free expression.
Do you really want to grab the power
to an institution to tell you how to
communicate?
And people then a thought
that she was saying that, uh,
that she was defending a particular course
of action. What she was saying was, um,
you, uh, she was saying,
do you students really want to surrender
that kind of control over your own
lives to older adults? And apparently
many students did actually. They wanted,
they did. They did. So I
don't believe they did.
I think they wanted absolute enforcement
of what they thought to be wrong or
right. Yes. Yes. I think that's
right. So they, they, they,
uh, they did the many but not
all of the students. I mean,
let's, let's also be very clear
and in part of the motivation in,
in Erica a writing that
note was that, uh, many, uh,
many of her students and in fact
many hundreds of other students felt
infantilized by this policy.
And there had been a big
buildup prior to that event,
including an article in the New York
Times about these Halloween costume
policies around the country and
weren't they kind of ridiculous.
And so there was a, there was a kind of
a, a ferment where people were saying,
wait a minute, do we really need
adults to be told in this institution,
especially given its commitments
to open expression, uh,
what to wear.
And keep in mind that there could be
many ways in which a costume that offends
you might not, might,
I might not know why.
So let's say you had been abused by a
priest and you were that one of the rules
said you shouldn't, a mock religion
for example, was what one of the Pr,
one of the provisions. So, so a
a university wide email went out,
signed by 13 people saying,
um, you know, don't, don't, uh,
don't mock people's deeply
held faith traditions. Well,
what if for the sake of argument,
you had been abused by a priest and you
want it in Halloween to dress up as a
Catholic priest, for
example. Uh, you know,
holding a doll and someone
else who had a different,
who was Catholic was very
deeply offended by that. Well,
who should adjudicate
that? Like, you know,
is it the role of the institution
to come down and say, yes,
you can express yourself
this way. No, you cannot.
And so the argument was
let the young people learn,
let them sort it out themselves.
Let them learn by talking to each other,
expressing themselves, saying,
you know, that hurts my feelings.
Here's why it hurts my feelings. And
the other person say, oh, I understand,
or I don't understand, I
reject that reason. And,
and sort of buy into a kind of commitment
to free and open expression that
actually I think ultimately serves the
objectives of righteous social progress.
If we really want to do better in our
society or in any society in my view,
we have to create an environment where
we can talk to each other, grant,
good faith, uh, listen carefully,
make subtle distinctions and,
and free people up to express what
they're thinking so we can have a real
marketplace of ideas. That's, you
know, my commitment or my belief.
Well that's a wonderful belief. I
love it. I mean that's really a,
I couldn't agree with you more,
more enthusiastically.
That's really,
that sounds like the best possible
environment for growing up and learning.
As long as you have someone to sort of
moderate or someone to mediate if things
go sideways.
Yes.
Or I don't think you necessarily
need a third party mediator,
but you do need a shared understanding of,
of a core liberal principles.
And these principles do include,
as I mentioned earlier, I kind of
commitment to free and open expression,
a commitment to debate,
a commitment to reason.
So how are you and I going to come to
a better understanding of what is true
about the world we could
fight, right? And then the,
the stronger person would decide
what's right. We could vote.
Doesn't seem quite right either.
You know,
a 350 cardinals voted that Galileo was
wrong. That didn't make Galileo wrong.
Or we could use principles of reason,
an inquiry to try to appreciate
the world together, right?
We're looking out at the world and
saying, that's confusing. You know,
does the sun,
does the earth revolve around the sun or
does the sun revolve around the earth?
Or that's confusing. Should a
king have monarch, you know,
should a king has ultimate authority in
a state or is that not how we want to
organize a state? So we, you and I look
at the world and debate and think about,
okay,
and we exchange reasons and we use
evidence and ways of understanding and
studying the world. That to me is
the only way to truth. Actually. Now,
some people will think that
religion is a way to truth, right?
They think that the truth is, you
know, has god given. For example,
now I am very sympathetic
to religious belief systems,
but I don't think that's a way
to truth that it's a way to,
some truths actually it's a way
to some some wisdom, but anyway,
so that's what our
universities and our society,
our universities are officially committed
to that the mottos of our universities
are all about free inquiry and pursuit
of knowledge and our country is committed
to that in our bill of rights,
right.
We have a commitment to free and
open expression, freedom of assembly,
freedom of religion and so forth and,
and those ground rules then in my view,
make it possible for us to
have a better society and,
and there's more academic. Well, I'm sure
we will get into it. No, I'm sure we will.
Again, I couldn't agree
with you more. Yeah. I
just think we need more
reasonable conversations and
the screaming and shouting
people down and less toxic
mob action. Yes. Yes.
The mob action is very weird because I
don't remember it well from the like from
the Vietnam war protests
to what's going on today.
There was this long gap where you didn't
hear about university shutting down
speech.
This is fairly new.
This is within the last half decade or so.
Well let's not yet. Yes, yes.
I mean they're always there.
There's always an undercurrent
of tension about this at,
at universities and in our
society at large. Uh, you know,
let's not forget the McCarthy era where
you had the right wing was, you know,
really interested in
shutting down communists.
Like if you were a professor or an
artist who had far left political views,
you were screwed and that's what's wrong.
Or even if you would want
went to a communist meeting,
find out what it was
all about. Yes. Just to,
yes, yes. In fact,
that's a great example because that's
like right now I see a lot of people being
criticized for following online
people they disagree with,
which is nuts. Crazy. So I just,
because I follow someone doesn't mean
I agree with what they're saying.
I'm interested to learn. What are
they saying? I'm friends with people.
I don't agree with me too. I'm friends
with so many people that go to agree with.
I have a friend, I have, I have friends
across the political spectrum from the,
I don't have any monarch. Yes. Among
my president reservoir or Monica.
But I have friends with
the far right to far left.
I have a friend who really
believes he's sold libertarian.
He thinks there should be
private ownership of roads.
Uh, whoa. Yeah. I mean,
yeah, I think that's ridiculous.
And we debate. He, you know,
must be white is actually
my wife says she would just once like
to meet a poor libertarian female
libertarian. Yes. No. Yeah. That's
a ridiculous position. I think so.
Private roads get the fuck
out of it. Yeah. Okay. But so
here's the thing, but okay,
how are we going to
persuade this man that he's,
he also thinks somewhat
less controversially.
It's harder decision. He also
thinks that you, you shouldn't be,
you should be able to sell your
book, your organs. You know,
we should have a market and
kidneys, uh, that you, you know,
you right now you're alive. Yeah. You can
give away one of your kidneys, but yeah,
you can, we allow you to give it
away. But we don't allow you to
sell it. Wasn't there an instance,
Jamie, that you were telling me about,
about a young guy who was sold
as kidney to get an iPhone?
Does that in another country,
another country? Yes. Yes.
And wound up having an infection and
lost his second kidney as well. Yes.
And then would need to be under yes.
These things. Yeah. And these things,
these things happen in the, but in
the United States, it's prohibited.
You can't do that. You also can't
sell your blood in the United States.
There's a reason for that.
Yes. And that's a good reason.
A good public health reason.
Yeah.
Because people who want to sell
their blood are usually fun.
Correct.
And so it's not a safe,
the blood supply is in countries where
you were people terribly altruistically
doing it. Exactly, yes. But the kidney is
a harder case anyway. He believes that he,
he, he, anyway, so I love debating him
and I learned from it. Like recently,
he said to me and I, and I think
I have a better answer. He said,
he doesn't understand
why blackmail is illegal,
but a point is it goes hand or kiss,
anarchists and Libertarians,
all of them need their asses
kicked there. Really do. Exactly.
But the, these are like, and I
think 80 kind of extreme ideology,
but the point is we can learn,
there is some wisdom almost anywhere,
right? And, and the problem comes
from excess expression. You know, the,
the, the problem comes from, um, you
know, there's, there's, there, there,
there the problem comes,
you know,
when we take things to extremes
and we get to, you know,
private ownership of roads.
But anyway, and by the way,
if you're an anarchist or a libertarian,
I'm kidding.
I don't really pitch when you get your
ass kicked. I'm just joking around.
But it is a mob after,
it's a position that I always feel like
to be remedied with psychedelic drugs.
It could be, yes. Almost always
could be. Like, I get, you know,
I just, I get where they're coming from.
I understand personal responsibility.
The idea that the free market
should decide, get all that,
but we are ready except that there's some
things that we agree on that we should
all chip in to pay for. Like, like roads.
Yeah. Or like assessment abilities.
Well yeah, are like assessment
of drug purity for example.
So the very rich could set up
a laboratory in their basement.
So whenever a doctor
prescribes a medication,
they could see if the drugs are safe
and pure. The rest of us pay taxes.
Now we say we're all going to pitch in
together and we're going to have the FDA
and they are going to certify drug purity
so that when I go to my pharmacist and
by a drug,
the pharmaceutical companies and killing
me by shotty manufacturing practices.
Yes.
So I think that's right.
We get together and as a free
society and we do these things,
we want a non-corrupt judiciary.
Right?
We don't want people to be able to
bribe judges. Shore. Exactly. Yeah.
So there are certain foundational elements
of our civilization of our society,
which are crucial to our wellbeing.
And one of them is the capacity to openly
debate ideas and to expose ourselves
to ideas across the gamut. And I'm not
just talking about political ideas,
I'm talking about scientific ideas.
So how are we going to win the
battle against anti-vaxxers?
Like how are we going to persuade people
who believe that vaccines killed people
for which there is no scientific
evidence that they're wrong.
We could imprison them like
that's force. Uh, we could vote,
which is sort of what we're
doing. We're saying, okay,
well you're a minority group who believes
these things so we're not going to
allow you to control policy.
Or we could try to win the battle of
ideas and persuade them. Ultimately,
that's the only path in my view that
gets us to where we want to be. Yeah.
And
just an honest assessment
of the actual data,
like what we really know and understanding
how the scientists come to these
conclusions.
But the problem is these echo chambers
where people get involved with online
that magnify all of these
beliefs and you get radicalized.
I mean, I've seen true people get
involved in these Facebook groups.
He's anti-vaxxer faces or
Facebook groups or you know, all,
all sorts of different things.
I mean that's how these
flat earth people get going.
They start listening only to people
that are involved in this circle.
They don't have a greater understanding
of the science involved in,
did you just see,
I just saw online their sec a cruise
to the flat or cruise for a flat earth.
I don't know if you saw it too.
The ice wall. Yeah, the ice wall.
Ooh,
that's a new wrinkle.
Cause the old flat earthers used to think
that the water was shown falling off
the disc of the earth. You know, like the
edge of the earth. They was just a disc.
Now the new theory that
there's an ice wall, actually,
it's kind of not falsifiable B,
that is to say you,
you could get on a cruise and sail to the
edge of the earth and you would find a
wall of ice there. So you
Antarctica. So you'd think,
Huh, it's flat. In other words,
they,
they have redefined their theory too to
make it so that you can't disprove it.
Right. You don't get to
an edge, there's no edge.
There's an ice wall is
what they're saying. No.
And Are you aware of Hashtag
spaces fake? No, I'm not.
I have to say it right
and not expose myself to that space.
There's a bunch of people that believe
that space is fake, but it's not real.
But there's no real space and
that there's like lights up there.
Oh and that this is some
sort of a plan by Satan.
It's a lot of, it's very
biblical. It's really interesting.
A lot of the flat earth
stop is very biblical.
That's it has to do with the firmament.
And they use descriptions and
depictions from the Bible. Oh yeah.
It's super bizarre.
And what's really bizarre is when you
listened to the youtube videos or these
discussions that are done by people
that use words that are real,
they string them together correctly.
They have like full sentences,
they appear to be articulate.
It's very confusing if you're a dummy,
if you listen to those ego like wow, this
guy's making a lot of sense. He's not.
But it sounds like he's making a lot of
sense cause he's using all these words
that are correctly,
users know oms he saying it articulately.
There's like everything seems like
like, oh my God, this man is exposing.
He's exposing the reality. But it's
not. It's just fucking nonsense.
And if you don't know any better,
and that's all you listened to,
that's where your head will go.
The same with the Anti Vaccine Movement.
If you only listened to
these anti-vaxxers, they're
making so much sense like,
oh my God, it's giving everybody
uh, all sorts of ailments.
And they have a theory of how it does
that, which is not, it's uses as you say,
scientific words,
but it's actually not correct.
Do you know it does this, which then
does that, which then does that,
they lay out a kind of causal chain,
which is false.
And then there's a problem of nuance
in perspective because there's so many
people that get vaccinated.
There's hundreds of millions
of people in this country,
billions of people worldwide.
And then there are instances,
rare occurrences where people have
real issues with vaccinations.
Well, there are some where they
have real issues. So for example,
there's some vaccines which are known to
cause certain neurological conditions,
rarely went out of a million or
one out of 100,000 vaccinations.
More commonly is a situation in which
you have vaccination is so common.
Everyone is getting vaccinated and often
that occurs near to an occurrence of
some other rare condition. And people
associate the two they think, oh,
because of the vaccine, this happened.
No, it's a coincidence either or. Yes,
there's both in the, and
there's also, you know,
if it's one out of a million and
you have 300 million, exactly.
You have 3 million.
1 million people with an
issue is a big deal. Yeah.
With 300 million people. Yes. You,
you easily could have
300 really big cases,
you know,
300 cases where if something died from
vaccines and then you bring those in
front of people and say, Oh my God.
And then there's this one and this one,
this one, and there's 298 more.
And you're like, Holy Shit,
all these people are dying from vaccines.
As you know,
it doesn't feel good if it's your child,
but when we look at the
greater perspective of humanity
and you say, well listen,
you don't want to bring back smallpox.
You don't want your child to get measles.
Babies can get measles when they
can't even be vaccinated for it.
This is one of the reasons why we need
to vaccinate children is to make sure
they don't get measles is a serious
fucking problem and a serious problem that
scientists have labored for untold
decades to try to try off of our
civilization. That we can
actually stop these diseases. Yes.
And save children's lives.
I had a woman yesterday who is an expert.
She's a medical historian and
expert in Victorian era surgery. Uh,
Lindsey Fitzharris and she wrote this
great book called the butchering art and
in it there's all these images.
Should she, one of them,
she brought up of what smallpox
actually looks like when people get it,
it's horrible. It just
covers people's bodies. Yes,
you've eradicated this like
painful and you die from it.
It's actually gone.
Yes.
We don't get it into in this country
as funny where credible, it's credible.
But that's obviously neither here
nor there. So this book a blueprint,
the evolutionary origins of a good
society. When did you start this?
About nine or 10 years ago. Uh, and I,
at the time in my lab we were
doing research on friendship.
We were doing research on, on why people
have friends. It's actually, it's not,
it's not difficult to provide an account
for why we have sex with each other. Uh,
many animals, most animals are,
well, I don't know if it's most,
but animals either reproduce sexually
or asexually and most animals,
I'm trying to remember now what the
relative proportions anyway, mama
say most,
most animals reproduce sexually.
And it's not hard to provide
an account for how, um,
for why we, why sex originated,
why we reproduce sexually.
It's not hard to provide an account for.
Why we are choosy in our mates are why
we are careful in who we have sex with.
But human beings don't just mate with
each other. We befriend each other.
We form longterm non reproductive unions
to other individuals to whom we're not
related. Why that's very
rare in the animal kingdom.
Very few creatures do this. We do it.
Certain other primates, elephants,
certain whales and that's mostly it.
So the question is why.
So I became very interested in my lab
and trying to understand the deep origins
of friendship. Why would natural selection
have equipped us with his capacity?
And that set the stage then for an
exploring all kinds of other things in our
lives, like why we love each other.
For example, why do we, why do we,
when we have a sex with a person,
we tend to become attached to them.
We develop emotional sentiment about them.
That's not an essential to having sex yet.
We do that.
And then I became interested in other
kinds of good things like not into just
love and friendship,
but cooperation and teaching.
Teaching is another crazy thing.
We take it for granted that we teach
each other. But think about this.
Most animals are able to learn.
So a little fish in the ocean learns
that if it swims to the light,
it finds more food there. So the fish
then learns to, to, to be tropic,
to move towards the light. Uh,
and that's individual learning.
Some animals, uh, developed
what's called social learning.
Social learning is really efficient.
So if I put my hand in the fire,
I learned that I burned myself. I pull
my hand out, I've learned something,
I paid a price and I learned something.
I could observe you putting your hand
in the fire. You pay all the price.
But I gained most of the knowledge. It's
almost as good. I learned, oh people,
you shouldn't put your hand in the fire
saw that Joe put his hand in the fire.
So social learning is super
efficient learning from others,
but we take it to an even further level.
We don't just passively observe other EH,
other animals of our own species and
learn from them. We teach each other.
That is very rare in the animal kingdom
where one animal sets out to teach and
other animal something. So
the book is a, is, is, uh,
is about the evolutionary
origins of a good society.
It's also a kind of a response to kind
of push back to a long tradition in the
sciences of attention to the bad
parts of our nature. You know, uh,
scientists in my view have for too
long been looking at the origins of,
of murder and tribalism and
selfishness and mendacity.
Um,
but,
but I think the bright side
has been denied the attention
it deserves because we
have also evolved to love and to befriend
each other and to be kind to each
other and to cooperate and to teach
each other and all these good things.
And I'll shut up and
please don't know. And, uh,
and here's the thing. Here's the
sort of one way to think about this.
This must have been the case that the
benefits of a connected life outweighed
the costs.
We would not be living socially.
If my exposure to you
harmed me and Annette.
Other words, if I came near
you and you were violent to me,
you killed me or you
gave me misinformation,
you told me lies about the world than my
connection to you would ultimately harm
me, that I should be better off
living as an isolated animal.
So animals that come together
to live socially there,
the benefits of that
must outweigh the costs.
My living us living as a group.
So all this attention to the ways
in which our interactions are bad,
that we kill each other, that
we steal from each other,
that we lie to each other,
that we have tribalism and all of these
traits which we do every century is
replete with horrors. I'm not like
Pangloss like I don't think like,
you know, Pollyanna like, oh,
everything's great. That's not me.
But what is me is a kind of optimistic
focus on the good parts of our,
of human nature and the recognition
that those good parts must in toto
overwhelmed the bad parts.
While they certainly have to,
there's so many human beings. I mean
it's obvious that this is working. Yes,
we have propagated where everywhere
on every single patch of land that's
occupiable. In fact, you're,
you're exactly right. The argument,
and that's discussed in the book,
the way we have achieved the kind
of social conquest of the earth,
the way our species is,
is as spread out to occupy every niche,
which is also very rare. Most animals
live in one, you know, grizzlies live in,
in this part of the world. They don't
live in Amazonia. And, uh, you know,
polar bears live in this part of the
world. They don't live in, in Arizona,
et Cetera. So, so, uh, but
our species lives everywhere.
And the way we have come to be able
to do that is by the capacity to have
culture, to teach and learn from
each other, to accumulate knowledge.
So in the book I talk about lots of this,
a famous set of stories called the
last European explorer files about how
European explorers are lost. They lose
their supplies, they wind up dying.
And um,
but they're in an environment in which
other people thrive and survive because
they have learned to how to live there.
So we've spread out around
the world and then don't,
there's a chapter in the book at
the beginning about shipwrecks. So,
so I have this, should I go on
chaplain? Yeah, I have this,
I have this. Uh, so, so
what I'd like to do is,
what I tried to set out to do in the
beginning of the book is I say, look,
it's clear that our genes shaped the
structure and function of our bodies.
It is increasingly clear that our genes
also straight shape the and function of
our minds, our behaviors,
whether you are risk averse, uh,
how intelligent you are. Uh, uh,
whether you, uh, have wanderlust, uh,
these properties are properties
that depend in part on your genes.
But it's also clear to me,
and that's what the book argues,
is that our genes shape not just the
structure and function of our bodies,
not just the structure
and function of our minds,
but also the structure and
function of our societies.
And to really prove that what we would
need is something known as the forbidden
experiment.
And the forbidden experiment
is an experiment in which
we took a group of babies
who had never been taught anything,
who are a cultural,
had no culture and stranded them on an
island and left them on their own to see
what kind of society they would
make when they grew up. You know,
how would they organize
themselves socially?
Is there kind of an innate society that
human beings are prewired to make in an
essence? Now, obviously
that's unethical and cruel,
but actually monarchs for thousands of
years of contemplated this experiment.
So Heraclitus writes in about how one of
the ancient Egyptian Pharaohs wanted to
know what kind of language would,
what was a natural language we had in
us that we would speak if we were not
taught language.
So this pharaoh,
it is said took two babies and gave them
to a mute Shepard Terez to see how did
the children's speak when they
grew up and uh, and, and, and uh,
the emperor Akbar attempted this,
there was a couple of European
kings at attempted this.
Obviously we can't actually do this.
So what I do in the book is I look at a
series of other approximations of that.
And one chapter is devoted to looking
at shipwrecks groups of men typically,
but sometimes men and women who,
between 1500 and 1900,
there were 9,000 shipwrecks, many more
thousands of ships were lost at sea.
And in 20 of those cases we
found 20 cases where, uh,
at least 19 people were stranded for
at least two months. And, uh, you know,
here's the, there's a kind of, um, here's
a map of the, uh, I'm going to, well,
here's one crew I can tell you about, but
here's a map of the, of the shipwrecks.
Like these are the,
Oh wow.
The all over the world
where they occurred and, uh,
when they occurred and how many people
there were. And uh, and so then I, uh,
I got all the original
accounts from the sailors,
from the people on the wrecks and all
contemporary archeological excavations of
those wrecks were where they
had been excavated. And, um,
and try to understand what kind of
society did these isolated cruise actually
wind up making. And there was some
amazing stories that were, uh,
that I found in there.
So the stayed for at least two months.
How many of them actually
established a real civilization?
How many, well, forever,
no, no one was stuck forever. Uh, most
of those crews were eventually, in fact,
all of those crews had at least one
survivor because if they had all died,
then I wouldn't be able
to know about them.
But there's a one famous case
in which these sailors, uh,
were stranded in near Australia,
I think somewhere in the Pacific.
And they managed to catch a big petrol,
one of those huge birds that, you know,
like a condor. And uh, and they, they,
they put a little note in a little tiny
bottle and they tied it to its feet.
And this petro flew thousands of miles
and landed in Australia and was found
with a note indicating where
the ice stranded sailors were.
And a ship was sent to go find
the men and the got there,
but they had all died. They were all gone.
So they use this, this, uh, this bird.
So the bird, well, no, they didn't
eat the bird. They push. No.
I think if you had that choice,
you would communicate rather than eat Joe.
I think. Yes. Yeah. For a little bit.
Well until the very end as yes, yes. But,
uh, they starved to death. We don't know.
Nobody knows.
But the point is that we have to,
for me to be able to describe what
happened, we needed at least one survivor.
Often. There were many cases
where everyone survived. I mean,
there was one pair of cases that I was
amazing to me in 1846 in south Auckland
islands, just north of Antarctica,
south of New Zealand. Uh, the, uh,
the Grafton was racked on the
southern part of the island.
I can't remember how big the island was.
It's in the book and maybe let's say 90
miles long or something or 20 miles long
thing. It's 20 miles long on the
southern part of the island. Uh,
five men are wrecked on the Grafton and,
uh,
on the northern part of the island,
the Invico rex,
19 men are wrecked on the INVICO.
Uh,
all the graft and cruise survives the,
and both feet.
Both crews were on the
island at the same time.
They never encountered each other. They're
struggling for survival. It's like an,
like an experiment. Like who's going to
win? Tempted to say fear factor. Yeah.
And uh, and, and the question is who's
going to survive and how and why.
Everyone in the graft and crew survives,
and 16 of the 19 men on the, uh,
on the INVICO crew die. And there's also
cannibalism in that crew. So it's a,
it's a very, it's a very different
outcome for various reasons.
So anyway,
so the point is that in the book I
start with a series of stories about how
people come together to make,
attempt to make new civilizations.
I use the example of
unintentional communities with,
uh, with shipwrecks. I have,
I looked at it, intentional communities
like communes and um, and uh,
kibbutzes in Israel and a 1970s
communes in the United States,
a 19th century communes in
the United States. Actually
going back to Roman times,
there've always been groups of people
who've said, society's fucked up.
I'm going to go. And we're going
to make it again. You know,
we're going to start a fresh.
Um,
I look at settlements in Antarctica
of scientists. I look at the Pitcairn,
you know, the mutiny on the bounty. I
look at the Shackleton expedition. Many,
many cases of stranded,
isolated groups of people trying
to make a new social order.
And then I also use data from
experiments we do in my lab.
We have this software where tens of
thousands of people have come and played
these games.
We,
we can create these temporary artificial
societies of real people where people
come and spend an hour or two and we
would as God like wake an engineer,
the society,
we can have a lot of inequality or little
inequality or various other features.
And then we can observe what happens.
And I look at all of that data,
all those stories and say,
look,
there is a deep and fundamental way
that no matter what human beings,
uh, make a society their underlying
fundamental principles about society,
which are as innate as the fact
that you have two kidneys. You know,
most people, almost everyone
or your pancreas makes insulin.
But they're very different all
throughout the world. Right?
I mean there's totalitarian
society, no nose, no.
So here's the point. No, yes. So
here's what, here's the argument.
You look around the world and the
way the example I give is that yes,
there's huge cultural variation
around the world. Just like you said,
to tell turn societies.
There's people have different foods and
they have different ways of dressing and
there's enormous cultural variation
and it's marvelous and interesting and
obvious to anybody. But I think we're
missing the forest from the trees. To me,
this is like you and I are sitting on a
plane and we look at a hill that's 300
feet and 900 feet and we say
those are very different hills.
But actually if he took a step back,
we would see that we're on,
we were on a plateau and
one was a mountain that was
10,300 feet and another was
a mountain that was 10,900 feet.
And actually there,
there are these much more deep and
fundamental plate tectonic forces that are
creating these two mountains
that are very similar.
But we are just focused
on the superficial top.
So the argument in the book is
that everywhere in the world,
people have friendship. People love
their partners, people cooperate,
people teach each other.
These are fundamental common
principals shared by everyone.
Even though there's also a
lot of variation, even in
a place like North Korea.
Yes. Now North Korea, that that state,
so totalitarian states apply huge
cultural pressure to suppress this innate
tendency. It's like,
it's like a religious,
you need a lot of belief in God to
suppress your innate desire to have sex.
Right? Right. So you can have a
belief system that's very powerful,
that kind of prevents you,
squashes what would otherwise be a kind
of in escapable inclination you have.
So totalitarian regimes,
and this is discussed in the book too,
they are very threatened
by the institution of the
family. They're threatened.
You need to owe your loyalty to the state,
not to your family,
not to your friends. And so they have a
series of institutions that, you know,
everyone has comrade, everyone
called Conrad for example, or, or,
uh, uh, there are a lot of, a lot of
times, well I won't, I don't want to,
I don't know if I want to speak
at the state level. Let me,
let me take it down a notch to communes.
So if you think about communes,
if you're going to make a commune of
people and you want them to feel real
loyalty to the commune,
one way you can do that is you want to,
uh,
reduce the commitment people have
to their partners, let's say their,
their mates in, in order to do that,
you can go to one of two extremes.
Either you can prohibit sex, like
the shakers and you say, okay,
no one is going to have sex with anyone
because we're all in a commune and we
all love each other and we're not going
to have a special love for particular
people.
Or You could go to the other extreme and
you can have polyamory say everyone's
going to have sex with everyone else.
Once again,
you see that subverts the special
relationship that people might form with
particular individuals.
And so both of those strategies,
even though they're opposite,
are attempting to do the same thing,
which is to break down real relationships,
face to face,
relationship between individuals so
that you can have a commitment to this
higher group. And that's what totalitarian
states also face the same dilemma.
And that's also why,
incidentally,
a lot of the states try to re reduce
gender differences, right? They like,
you know, the Mao jacket, the men and
women all were wearing the similar,
similar kind of attire for instance.
Uh,
because they want to have people see
themselves as interchangeable and not as
individuals and relationships,
not be particular.
Did you study cults a little bit?
Um,
not a lot. Uh, there's some talk a
little bit in the book about cults,
but I don't really need to get to cults
in order to make the arguments that I'm
making. No, I mean not even just
to make arguments,
just to compare because
that is essentially like in
particularly the Rajneesh
called Oregon, the wild, wild west
or wild wild country documentary.
On Netflix. Did you see that?
No, I haven't. It's fantastic.
They essentially took over an entire town
and started busing and homeless people
to vote.
Oh, I read about that.
I know about this. Yes.
It's really quite amazing.
And what they did was really weird.
You know what I mean? For there's moments
in the documentary you're like, wow,
maybe they're on to something,
and then of course it goes completely
sideways and they wind up poisoning people
and it's chaos.
But I am absolutely fascinated by those
types of environments where people do
decide they're going to branch
off from regular. They don't,
they're unsatisfied with
regular civilization.
They're gonna all move to some location.
Yes. That's a, that's a primitive and
ancient impulse. Like I was saying,
people have been doing that
for since time and memorial.
It's how America got started.
Yes, yes, yes. It's, screw this.
I'm going over there to start again. But
again and again, when people do that,
they keep expressing some of these
fundamental beliefs. It's, yes, yes.
It's like saying yes. Anyway,
go on. No, please. No, no, no.
I don't have anything to add. I
mean, I just was what you said,
but yes, that's right. I mean, I'm,
I'm always fascinated by people that
are unhappy with the current state of
affairs. They don't like the
way society feels to them.
They don't feel like they belong and
they want to try somewhere else. I mean,
and what was really interesting to me
is the last time someone did this as a
country, as far as I know,
is the United States. There
really is. It's about, I mean,
it's also very unique that this is one
of the weirdest countries in the world in
terms of our ability to freely
express ourselves and more guns.
Well, the thing about America, that's it,
it's like the American
experiment would have,
is about the fact that
anyone can be an American.
My parents immigrated from Greece. Uh,
I was raised in this country, you know,
uh,
I,
to be an American means to buy into a
certain set of principles like the bill of
rights and many other countries
are very xenophobic. You know, you,
you can't become a Japanese.
It's, you can't be,
you can't be nationalized in Japan.
I mean you can,
but it's extremely difficult and rare.
Uh, so it's a very homogeneous country.
Switzerland is another country.
It's very difficult to become Swiss.
You can't be nationalized
as a Swiss. I mean, you can,
but it's extremely difficult and rare. So,
um, but the United States, you know, we,
we say you are an American. If you from
all of the whole world, you're welcome.
Bring us your tired. Your, you know, the
famous saying on the foot on the, your,
I forgot the saying,
it's very poetic on the bottom of the,
of the Statue of Liberty. You're
wretched. You're, you're for Lauren,
whatever it is. Uh, and
you can come to this,
these shores and make
your life a new. And, um,
and all you need to do to
be an American is to, um,
buy into a commitment to constitutional
governance, democratic rule,
Bill of rights and these principles.
Now we should note that there were
millions of people that were brought as
slaves and voluntarily to these shores.
We don't always realize our best virtues.
We allow people to come,
but like the Irish and treat them as
second class citizens or the Italians or
the Greeks even. Um, you know,
we, we don't always do that, but,
but the idea that you're putting on
the table, which I think is correct,
is that you can be an American. This
is a special, unusual experiment.
You can't reinvent yourself
quite that way. And to my
knowledge, in any other, uh,
colony or country,
that's why it's one of the weirdest
things that this is a country where
anti-immigrant sentiments
are running rampant. Yes.
One of the entire foundation,
the country is based on immigration.
Yes. The only way people got here,
if you're not a native American,
it was taken from the native Americans.
And everyone's since then is an immigrant
or a descendant of an immigrant.
That's correct. In the native Americans,
they came 20,000. Yes. It's crazy.
Yes. The whole thing's
crazy. Yes. It's, it's just,
and it's such a unique environment
for expression. I mean,
there's really no other country
that has as free expression.
Even the Brits don't. That's right.
And Canada certainly does. Correct.
And they're our neighbors.
Yes, it's uh, it's just, it's a
very unusual thing.
And this unusual thing is the most
recent incarnation of a country.
Yes, yes. I think that's right.
And I think there are, you know,
then this ties in with a whole set of
ideas about American exceptionalism.
You know, are we, how
different are we, uh,
what is the source of our wealth?
What is the height of our
civilization? You know, I'm, I'm,
I am distressed by some of the direction
our country is going in at the moment,
but I think the, you know, I
think in the long arc of history,
I think the United States stands for
many of the best principals in the world.
And I'm prepared to defend
those principles. I am too.
And I think what you were saying with
your libertarian friend and you know,
someone who may be an anarchist
or whatever, and then there's,
there's room for all these weird opinions.
They might not be correct and they will
all be represented is just gigantic soup
of human beings.
It's 300 plus million.
It's just the idea that America is like
a white nationalists in Charlottesville.
This is what's wrong with America. No,
what's wrong with America is volume.
You know,
you're,
you're going to have certain ridiculous
ideas and awful ideas that are amplified
in this volume is incredible.
Massive humans. Yes. I think a large,
I think that's right. I think
our size, uh, contributes to, uh,
or makes a kind of heterogeneity
of ideas more easy. Uh, you know,
if we were tiny country, although
even in small democracies, you know,
like you go to European countries
that are tiny, uh, Spain for example.
I mean it's not tiny, but it's
tiny compared to us. Uh, you know,
there's a lot of difference of beliefs
from far left to far. Right. But I think,
I think the key aspect, which you're
talking about earlier, which again,
you're highlighting,
which I agree with,
is that we want an environment in which
people can, the ground rules are clear.
So, you know, you can't, there's no
physical contact allowed. Right. So we do,
we draw a bright line distinction
between words and deeds.
So I completely reject the idea that
words are violent. Violent. Yeah, totally.
Yeah. I totally reject that. Uh, and, and
because we have different words for it,
the two different things,
totally different. I mean,
we, we, so ground was our,
you know, I can't touch
you, but I can speak, uh,
other ground rules are that we
are committed to open expression.
A good ground rule would be that we grant
positive intent. We grant good intent.
That is to say, I tried to put what
you're saying in the most favorable light.
First I think about it. I say, okay,
now wait a minute. What is he saying?
What does he mean by that? He,
Mike's, uh, now you may be an idiot.
A person may be an idiot. They
may be viral, they may be violent,
they may be wrong. You know, all
of those things are also possible,
but that's not the first Goto. Um, so
anyway, if we set those ground rules,
I think, I believe strongly that
in the marketplace of ideas,
the truth will out, um, and,
and righteousness will out.
That's, that's what I think.
Maybe I'm wrong. Maybe in fact, what
we need is a benevolent dictator who,
you know, comes down and
tells us what to think and do,
but that's not the world
I want to live in. Yeah.
The benevolent dictator idea
is what does that come from?
Like why is it just because it's,
that's really been the only way the
society is actually functioned for most of
the past. Fantasize, right. Every,
I mean Plato talks about this,
I mean people look around and they
think situation is not so great.
I really wished it was a strong man
that would come down and fix it. Um,
this is the inclination towards
Trump. I think in some part, yes,
Trumpism is a little bit about this
fantasy that, that we will, um,
you know, that that the way out is to
have a kind of imposition from above.
And I think that's very
dangerous actually.
And we were talking about earlier in
college campuses, it's the same principle,
right?
Like the idea that big daddy's going to
come down and tell us what to do and fix
the situation I think is
undemocratic in the end.
And painting it has to follow the
rules of these children. What I mean,
this is part of the issue with
the idea of words equal violence.
I mean this is not a well thought through
idea and this is an idea that is world
rewards can lead to violence.
Sure. Words can be painful.
They can hurt your feelings. Yes, that
can be unpleasant. All of that is true,
but words are different than violence.
They just are. And so I think we need to,
you know, and in fact as John
Height and uh, and uh, uh,
Greg Louisiana argue,
we actually might want to create there
other reasons to draw the distinction
between words and violence and
to cultivate an appreciation
for that distinction.
And that is by allowing people to speak,
we may actually reduce violence because
we can identify who has these crazy
ideas. We know who. So if you're, if, if,
if I believe that someone hates people
like me and I created an environment in
which we allow him to say
he hates people like me,
I think it's horrible that
he hates people like me.
I'm not defending that he hates people
like me, but we might now know who he is,
right as I stay away from
him, you know? Uh, so,
so that's their argument that look,
you in height make that,
that actually this is a
potentially additional
additional benefit of creating a
free and open marketplace of ideas is we
identify where the crazy is, you know,
here are all these people were
talking about the anti-vaxxers.
I'd like to know who are the people that
hold these beliefs because as a public
health expert,
and I was a hospice doctor for many years,
I took care of patients for a long time.
Anyway,
I was very am still interested in a lot
of our projects around the world are
public health projects. In order to
be able to lead people to wisdom,
you have to know where, where's the
ignorance? Right? Well, if it's secret,
you don't know it.
So that's another benefit of fostering
this climate of open expression. Yeah.
And the,
the solution to these bad ideas is for
someone to come up and give a better
idea.
Yes.
Someone to debate or to expand what's
wrong with it and to do it in a reasonable
manner. When people start shouting
and screaming and pulling fire alarms,
like it's this side,
the idea of silencing people from speaking
that somehow know that this is going
to help. This is a, this is
also part of d platforming. Yes.
When people call for deep, deep
planning, I think that's wrong.
Even based on just a reasonable
people with differing opinions.
It's raw. It's crazy. There's a tach
will, Peter Tatchell, there's a, uh,
a gay rights activist in, um, in England
who went to prison for his rights, was,
had been imprisoned in foreign countries
for defending a gay rights and he was d
platformed in England
a couple of years ago.
Now here's the problem with d platforming.
So first of all,
it is totally right and
appropriate to protest.
So if someone is speaking something
you don't want, I will strongly defend,
protest, stand outside, yell
and scream, hold banners up,
whatever.
You can't interfere with the right of
the speaker to express themselves first
point.
But even more important.
The reason we don't want that is not
so much because we're interested in the
right of the speaker.
It's because we're interested
in the rights of the listeners,
the people who are want to listen to that
person have a right to listen to that
person in a free society.
So when we prevent them, the
harm were causing is not,
it's not that I'm silencing you,
I'm,
I am interfering with the ability of all
the people who want to hear you to hear
you. It's their rights that matter
too. So if we it the D platforming,
it's not about, oh, so and so was unable
to speak at such and such a place.
It's the fact that all the people that
want it to hear so and so we're deprived
of their opportunity to do so.
So I think the answer to words,
we do not like the answer to speech.
We do not like is more speech.
It's not silencing. Yeah.
And there's also the, uh,
the obvious situation. You put someone
in, when you do attempt to silence them,
you put them under duress and
their message changes you,
you make someone more combative.
And yes,
this has often been the argument for
why Trump became president in the first
place is that people were tired
of the argument on the other side.
I mean,
I'm not a political scientist and I
followed that literature a little bit. Uh,
I think there is a strong argument
that that is one of the factors that
contributed to Trump's a success.
Let's keep in mind however,
that the majority of Americans voted
for Hillary Clinton. Um, and, and,
uh, he's a majority of
Americans didn't vote correct,
but of the people who voted yes, that's
right. That's another whole problem. Um,
but 63 or so million, uh, I, anyway,
about 3 million more people voted for
Hillary Clinton than voted for Donald
Trump nationally. So, um, so,
uh, I forgot how we got onto him.
What were you saying? When we're talking
about people wanting to silence people?
So one of the things,
correctness and the rebounding of that
is that reinforcing of someone who comes
along who's the polar opposite of
that? Yes, I would agree with that.
And I think that that's another,
you know,
that sort of is a variant of the
argument we were discussing earlier,
which is that you,
one of the advantages of creating a
free and open society is that you allow,
you know, live and let live
and uh, then you don't, you
don't, you, you tend to, um,
you avoid creating kind of
suppressed animosities or you,
you can help to avoid it to open
communication is so critical and it's also
critical to have reasonable,
polite conversation.
Like people can oppose each
other info in their idea,
but you should be able to express how
and why you oppose that idea without it
being this sort of personal yes.
Vendetta. Yes, I agree with that. I mean,
you know, I think we have to accept that
there will be, people will get angry.
I mean that's part of having
an open society and I think
we need to get a person.
Yes. And I think we need to accept
that some people, not everyone will,
will engage in discourse the way you
and I might want to engage in that
discourse.
Um,
but I do agree with you completely
that ideally we would have a kind of
civilized conversation that allowed
us to learn, um, and to grow.
And I think ultimately that
as we've been saying is,
is better for our society as well.
Well,
I think we should acknowledge
that people are going to be upset,
but we should also applaud people for
not being upset. I think there's a,
there's a higher value to people being
able to communicate reasonably. Yes,
I agree.
I don't think that that's
reinforced enough and I don't
think that's appreciated
enough.
I can play up high.
Don't you want to get any disagreement
from me on that? Yes. Yeah. I mean I just,
I just think we, this is
something that we can do. Yes.
And we can get better at it. Well, I
think it's like martial arts training,
you know, I think that it
is self discipline is not
an easy thing Joe. And, um,
like anything else worth doing in life,
like basically anything
worth doing takes effort.
It's tempting the Goto
strategy that many people have.
So I think it's important to note that
free speech is difficult and is not an
easy thing. It's a natural inclination
to want to silence your opponents,
but it's wrong it and it's harmful and
it's actually harmful to you to do that.
So, um, so,
so I think we need to have an
educational system that cultivates,
cultivates that,
that cultivates the capacity to tolerate
an idea that you don't like to think
about that idea and then to
respond to that idea. Um, so, so,
but I, so, so I guess what
I'm saying, it's, it's a, it
does require some training.
It doesn't come naturally, unfortunately,
you know, but it should be reinforced.
Yes.
I think there's a way to do that and
there's a way to appreciate that and as a
way to call that out
when you see it and just,
I think the world needs more of it.
And if we can figure out a way to do that,
we will find that we are differences
are not nearly as egregious.
They're the not nearly as disgusting
as well, like to think that, well,
that's exactly what I argue
with blueprint, that there's
such, you know, like,
you know,
when you go to a foreign country initially
you're overwhelmed by the different
food
and the different smells and the
different architecture and anyone who's
traveled even to a different state has
had this experience. And yet actually,
once you get to know the people, you see
that they're very human. They're like us,
they love their partners and they hang
out with their friends and they work
together to build a
civilization and a society.
And they have schools and they teach
and they learn and they do all of these
basic things that are a fundamental
part of our common humanity. And,
and this is what I talk about in blueprint
at length. You know, like I, I, uh,
you know, I just, I think it's,
I think there's a kind of, um,
there's a kind of flawed
beauty to the world that, ah,
captivates me and it's a little bit on
the, there's a synthetic tradition in, in,
in Japan and a philosophy called Wabi.
Sabi. Do you know Wabi Sabi? Sabi is, no,
probably know about it, but you may not
know the word, so I've heard it, you know,
like how,
like the western aesthetic for pottery
is like these perfectly symmetrical,
beautifully glazed, you know, pots.
But there's a tradition in Japan of
slightly imperfect pots, you know,
like a crackpot or a pot
that's slightly misshapen.
It's very difficult to masters to
make these pots. And it's, it's,
it's called Wabi Sabi and it's about,
it's about how imperfections are
kind of beauty of imperfection,
a kind of flawed beauty, um, like
a hot girl with a gap in her teeth.
Yes.
I suppose,
yes. I suppose that could be
an example of that, that, um,
or you know, Elle Macpherson,
you know, famously had that
little, uh, uh, was it her,
I forgot, which was the famous model
that had Sydney Crawford. Yeah.
I had that famous a mole on her face
and glassy. So it's a flawed beauty. So,
so here's the point.
It's not hard to look around the world
and see the violence and the murderer in
the warfare and the incompetent leadership
and all of these awful things about
our species,
but we're really a fucking
unbelievable species actually,
who do amazing things when you compare
us to other species and there's a kind of
flawed beauty to us and I think that it's,
it's wrong to be seduced to the dark side.
You know,
it's wrong to like only focus on those,
on the bad stuff.
I also think it's a kind of moral
and philosophical laziness, right?
If we allow ourselves to just
think that, oh, you know,
people are awful.
It kind of relieves us of any
duty to be good and to work,
to make the world better. It's a kind
of, you know, surrender to the dark side.
I think that's wrong. And the book shows
exactly how and why that's wrong and,
and how we,
how natural selection has shaped all
these wonderful qualities which are shared
the world over.
So you go to the foreign country,
you're initially perplexed by their crazy
practices and then slowly but surely
you find our common humanity.
And I anyway,
I find that it's pleasing, at least
to me, that perspective, you know,
that's one of the cool things
about travel, right? You,
you broaden your perspective and your
understanding of what it means to be a
person.
Go to these
different environments and
yourself too. Yeah, yeah.
They're different and they're
different foods or different art.
They're different architecture. And you
go, oh, this is also possible to yes,
people can live like this.
Yes.
And do you even begin to see why
they live like that? You know,
like you initially you go to Greece
and you have resin flavored wine,
you have it at Siena and you wondering
why would these crazy Greeks put pine
resin in there ruining
perfectly good white wine.
And then after awhile you start to say,
Hey, actually this is pretty good. Uh,
you know,
this is not a crazy thing after all.
And you acquired case run resident
and there were walls. Yes. You know,
the first time, the first time
I had scotch whiskey, I, I,
uh, I didn't know what I thought about
it. And now I love whiskey. Right.
It's an acquired taste. So the first
time you drink something like that,
you think, you know, yes. They put resin,
they put pine resin in their white wine.
They chill it.
I should've brought you some,
maybe I'll send you on an acquired taste.
Ouzo Koolaid.
It's delicious from the beginning.
Yeah. I just right out of the cold.
And this is sweet. Good. Yes, yes, yes.
We'll have to convince anybody.
Yes, that's right. That's right.
Some things that's right.
Some things are just good right
out of the budget is good. Yes.
Kool aid is just good. Yeah. I mean, I
don't recommend you drink it all the time.
It's full of sugar. It's terrible for
you. But damn, that's tough. It's like,
it's like a, it's like fried
foods, you know? Yeah, sure. Yummy.
A lot of them French fries. Yes. I mean,
come on man, salt and catch up. You guys
know I'm a, I'm not sure about
what I should mention, but anyway,
I love Popeye's fried chicken. I do
as well. I love it so bad. It's awful.
And my wife, my wife is unlikely to
listen to this full podcast so or I'll,
I'll skip over this part so she doesn't
hear this part but and my sister will be
listening probably and so she will
laugh when she gets to this part because
whenever I see a Popeye's I just pull
over and indulge myself and then I
terrible. Terrible. It's Hafez
is good. But you know what?
If you really want to indulge and
you like chicken Roscoe's in La,
I have it. No, you don't know. Oh, I
don't know. Ascos chicken and waffles.
Oh Dude. I tried to go there and
get in waffle family. We tried.
Don't you make that tried to go there
the other day with my family and a half.
Wait on the same place on day chicken
and waffles course on the same plate.
What are you a communist? Yeah,
man, it's La Tierra above them too.
And butter. Yeah. You
mean the chewiness? Yes.
It perfectly.
It's damn delicious in my mind.
Yet from another pant I,
I make maple syrup.
I live in Vermont and I make Maple Syrup.
I tap my own trees and wow.
What a freak. I have a,
I have a, yeah, exactly.
Giving people a hard time for waffles
and chicken again. Show me the colonel.
The colonel is a liar. He does
not have it. Get out of here.
It's not even the colonel.
The colonel is norm Macdonald.
Norman said temporary like promotion
or something. This is nonsense. Yeah,
but they do, oh my gosh. I got a waffle.
The syrup goes on top of the chicken that
chicken and waffles and chicken tastes
like cat litter compared to Roscoe's.
Also sweet chick La.
He could try to get this outta
here. Uh, so, uh, it's tough.
Can go fuck off Roscoe's
chicken and waffles.
You get the Greens to the Collard
Greens. That's fine. Damn good.
That's fine.
But that's a waste of maple syrup.
Take it from the man who makes it to put
it on chicken. Chicken is good. I'm sure.
Sweet. It's nozzles place. I get it. I
love it. I've been there. It's great.
Roscoe's okay, I'll have a look. Fuck off.
There's a reason why there's an hour
and a half wait on a Sunday. Okay.
How long you in town for a just a day.
Maybe I'll be back though.
I'll be back over there
right after the show.
Maybe I'll go there for a
little one on Gower. Okay.
Ooh Man. It's good. All right.
Maybe I'll try that. It's so good.
And it's also one of those places.
It's been there forever.
We used to get it.
I found out about it from 19
1994 when I was doing news radio.
95 ish, I guess. Have you been in La
since you left the Massachusetts? No,
I went to New York for a couple
of years then I moved down here,
moved down here in [inaudible] 94 okay,
so you've been here a long time. Yeah.
And when I was on news radio,
they got it for like,
you can order lunch and someone ordered
Roscoe's chicken and I was like,
what is this like waffles? And it was
just like you waffles and chicken there.
It looks that's,
that's,
that's doesn't look as good
as it looks when you're there.
When you're there and you smell it.
It's damn good doing a,
Roscoe is commercial here
but an incredible, I'm a fan.
That's an incredible combination of items.
It's so good. And afterwards you
better have nothing to do man.
Food Coma Son.
Anyway,
how do we get to that?
W W I dunno fry,
you may lose syrup stories
going to different countries,
different countries in opening
your mind. So you read it. Yeah.
So you are counteracting my resin
flavored white wine with these maple syrup
syrup. Well, I'm a, I'm a
giant fan of spicy food.
I love spicy foods. I really,
really enjoyed Thailand. Uh,
I really enjoyed their style of cooking
and they're kind of food and it's just
one of those people who, who eats
those Scofield units on the, uh,
on the hot peppers. Like, you know like
how hot, you know? No, I just like spicy,
not high hot and they're like
Habanero. I liked it. I like put,
it's pretty spicy compared
to the average person,
but I have friends that put
me to shame. Yeah, like a,
I have a buddy of mine from that I used
to do for your factor with my friend
Tommy Hirsch.
Go shout out to Tommy and I used to eat.
I ate chili with him and I
couldn't feel how hard he can go.
I'm like, this is crazy. Yes.
I think people just have a different
inherent like it's almost like built into
their bodies both. I think it's
both. Some people are better able,
it's like some are faster
runners than others,
but it's also training so you get to,
you eat alone,
you slowly work your way up
to being able to tolerate.
Unlike those really super hot peppers.
I, I find it a very unpleasant,
I have a friend just like
you who really is into it,
like really seeks out the hotness.
I also think it's a bit like addiction,
like you tolerate like, like as you
get used to like the less hot stuff,
now you need more and more stuff in
order to get the same. It's not exactly,
some people think it's a high by the way,
but there's a little high to it.
Some people say that I, I mean,
I, again, it's not for me.
I cook meat with Jalapenos.
I slice it up and I'll have like a piece
of the meat with the Jalapenos to get,
especially elk with Jalapenos
and sensational. So good. Yes.
Yeah. But my kids always make
fun of me because I'm bald.
So my whole head is covered with sweat
and they'd come over and wipe my hands
like, you're so gross. And
then how old are your kids?
The youngest ones are eight and 10. And
you have, you have, uh, how many? Three.
I have three daughters. All daughters,
two year old, a 10 year old and an eight.
You'll live longer, uh, with daughters.
If you, if you, if you plot, uh,
Dad's survival on the y axis and fraction
of female children on the x axis,
a survival is slightly longer for men
who have higher fraction of daughters,
his children because boys drive you
to your fucking grave cause they're so
goddamn crazy. There's lots of theories
as to why it happens. But I think,
and that is in fact one of them, it's
framed a bit more scientifically. Well by,
it's the basic theory. My 10 year old
is a maniac, my 10 year old daughters.
And I just imagine if she was a boy,
I'd be terrified that she knows
just lighting things on fire.
Blowing up buildings. Yes. Yeah.
Boys are a problem. That can be,
I mean, I think, yeah, I mean I
think, um, you know, I think it's,
um, I think, um,
well, I mean we could get onto the whole
gender issue. I'm not sure we want to,
but I think boys are responsible. It,
let's talk about chimpanzees. It's easier.
Okay.
Mail chimp's a do most of the violence,
but 95% of the violence in murders
are committed by male chimpanzees.
And most of the victims are males.
And um, you know, I think it's,
there's no doubt that,
um,
biology plays a very important role in
male proclivity to violence, for example.
So instead of trouble. Yeah. So the boys
can be a problem that way. And Yeah,
and I think the many ways in which s a
society are of cultural traits that we
invent,
their purpose is to shape and guide
those tendencies to violence to kind of
mitigate them. But we don't just need,
again, going back to the books or observe,
please do. We don't just need, uh, we
don't just use culture for that purpose.
There are, there's an argument
in the book that we humans have,
have domesticated ourselves.
So if you look at,
if you compare a dogs to wolves and
domesticated cats to wild cats from which
they descended,
or a Guinea pigs to the wild Guinea
pigs from which they descended or,
or horses to, uh, to the wild horses, to
which they sent a few again and again,
you compare these couplets,
these pears,
you find that the domesticated version
of these animals that are much more
placid, much more peaceful, they
also tend to have floppy ears.
They have for,
so Guinea pigs and dogs and
cows all have splotchy black,
white and Brown for why is that?
The animals from which they evolved didn't
have those, the kind of splotchiness.
So,
uh,
and they become much more peaceful
if you compare a human beings and,
but they had a, uh, the, the, those
animals were domesticated by humans.
Like I deliberately allowed
the reproduction of this
member of the litter and
not that member because this
member was, was, was nicer.
And so across time we evolve a more a
domesticated version of the ancestral
species. So we get, we get my miniature
Dachsund from a wolf, like the wound,
like the kind of things that were
photographed out in your studio here.
Crazy transition.
Uh,
now if you look at humans
and you compare us to, uh,
to the,
the non to our ancestors or to
other primates for all the world,
it looks like we have been domesticated.
We are more peaceful and placid.
We have sex outside.
Non Reproductive sex is another thing.
So these domesticated
animals we'll have sex, uh,
even when it's not time to
reproduce. Uh, we, uh, we, um,
uh, we, our tails, we don't have tails
anymore, but our tails have get shortened.
There are all these features that we have,
these,
these behavioral qualities and these
physical properties that we have are,
are we get a feminization of our faces.
Our jaws become smaller.
Like if you look at,
you compare these domesticated animals
to their non domesticated ancestors,
the domestic version are less violence.
So we lose a lot of the traits
that physical and, and, uh, um,
psychological traits
associated with violence.
But there was no one that domesticated
us. So the theory is, the question is how,
how did that happen? And one of the
theories that's discussed in, in, uh,
in blueprint and that's advanced by
other scientists, this is not my work,
is that we self domesticated.
And that what happened over the centuries,
over the millennia,
over millions of years,
is that weaker individuals
into our groups.
When one individual became too autocratic
and too violent and too powerful,
they banded together and kill that guy.
And so over time we were killing the
more violent members of our species,
weeding out those people, and therefore
the gene pool changed across time.
And we self domesticated.
We are more peaceful today than we
would have been because we domesticated
ourselves.
And this is one of the arguments that's
also made to help explain the origins of
goodness actually,
and the origins of cooperation because
it would take a few good diesel to kill
the bad person that's running everything
that's evil. Correct. It's exactly right.
Recreational sex does occur in Bonobos,
which is really weird,
isn't it? Because they're so
similar to regular chimps. Yes,
but they're not the same species.
They also have homosexual sex. Uh,
they use sex to make,
you know,
so, uh, it, it's, yeah, they're
very licentious a species.
That's exactly right. And, and, and,
and Bonobos are felt to be a self
domesticated chimpanzee. So the similar,
so bonobos are to chimps as uh,
as let's say dogs are to wolves and,
but there was the dogs,
we domesticate it. The Banabos
self domesticated as the theory.
Do they know why or how? Well,
the theory is that they did it.
Like we were saying by weeding out killing
the more of aggressive members it was,
what we know must have happened is that
the nicer guys must have been able to
have more offspring.
So the gene pool changed over time because
of the differential success of the,
of the, of the nicer guys. Now people have
looked at this even in human societies,
they've looked,
for instance,
there's a study I talk about in the book
of different pathways to reproductive
success amongst that Samani which is a
group in Amazonia and other societies are
similar.
So you can either be like big and strong
or you can be charismatic and have
useful knowledge in both ways.
You have more children. Mm.
Um, so there are these competing ways, uh,
in our species of enhancing
your reproductive fitness.
Are you aware of [inaudible]
work with, um, baboons?
That's a fascinating case, right? Because
they were studying baboons in Africa.
They would eat from human garbage,
and a bunch of them got sick and died.
And it turns out that the most violent
and ruthless of them got sick and died.
And it changed the entire culture of the
baboons tribe. I don't know that story.
That's an interesting one.
Little sterling grooming each other and
being kind to each other. Oh my God. Yeah.
That's a good example.
But there was an accidental,
it was an accident is an accident. And
you had, it lasted for generations. Yes.
And when he returned to study them,
he found that they were still this
different kind of contrite about this a
little bit. Yeah. I'm doing a shitty
job. I'm sure I'm explaining it, but I'm,
I know, I think could have the
fascinate. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yes. He's very impressive.
And a, I know the, I, I, I'm,
uh, now that you're reminding me,
I'm a little familiar with
that particular study.
I did know that it started with
garbage, however, that Janet,
it was a coincidental x extermination of
the more violent members of the troop.
Yes.
Yeah.
So they were removed from the gene pool
and it changed the entire culture to the
point where generations later they were
still using this more peaceful ways.
Full. Yeah, yeah, yeah. More kind.
Well, it didn't just change the culture.
It may have changed the culture,
but it appears we're arguing
the two of changing gene pool,
second evolutionary pressure that's
been applied. So you have, you know,
big dogs and small dogs.
You don't allow the big ones to reproduce.
You just reproduce the small ones. Yeah.
You get small dogs in the end. Well,
I've had dogs my whole life.
And one of the things that you do kind of,
I right now have a golden
retriever. Uh, we have, uh,
we, yeah, we have a white lab.
Yeah. A yellow lab. And, uh, I've
had a bunch of different dogs.
Mastiffs and pit bulls and
German shepherds, no small,
we have a docksin too.
You don't have small dogs.
My oldest daughter has a tiny Chihuahua.
It's a pays off. Sorry that he's the
best. They just bark all the time now.
He doesn't bark that much. He
barks a little bit, but he's,
he's really smart and
he's actually a Mutt.
He's Chihuahua and Australian shepherd,
but he's like that big, it's tiny,
tiny little thing and
he's the best. But um, um,
my point being is that you can see
if you get a dog from a breeder,
you really can see how they can
cultivate certain types of behavior.
Like a good example of my mass
tiff who passed away this year,
he came from this guy who bred dogs
for films and for a police training.
And uh, he was the most calm, most
chilled out dog I've ever had in my life.
He was a giant dog.
He's 140 pounds, but he,
you could have them take him anywhere and
trust him with a baby. And he was like,
hello.
Like everything was like totally
he but this guy purposely,
anytime a dog showed any aggression
towards people or any aggression towards
dogs,
he wouldn't let them breed.
So how can anyone not hear
the stories like that or no?
Stories like that and not then also
think that genes play a role in human
behavior. You have children. Yes.
You realize when you have children
you see it like, okay, this is not,
I didn't do this. This is,
this comes from me. Yes.
There's certain traits that my children
have that I watch and I go, okay,
this is not, this is teach them.
They just started, they were born,
this is what got my fucked up brain.
You know, there's something in there.
They're not seeing that.
Like they don't see how crazy I am in
terms of like how hard I work, things,
how obsessive I get with things
they're just doing and it's very weird.
It's very weird because
you see, oh well, okay,
well how much of this shit that's in me
is like how much of me is me deciding to
be this person and how much of me has no
choice? About half and half. I would say.
Overall on average across traits,
how much do you think gets passed
down through genetics in terms of
inclinations? Like like the
nature of physicians? Yeah,
about half on average. So for
example, about half the Wii,
you know how religious you are or
how risk averse you are. Like I can,
I can about half the variation in how if
you look at a group of people and some
are more risk averse than others,
about about half of that has to do with
their jeans and half has to do with how
they were raised or what environments
they grew up in. So you know,
there's a kind of innateness to many of
our qualities and you can shape them.
You know, for example, you can't,
you couldn't make me a musician.
Unfortunately I have almost no musical
talent. I can dance I think. I mean,
I think others would even say that I can
do that. Uh, but um, does not just like,
I think I can dance, but I can't. Uh, but
I, I have no musical ability whatsoever.
I would say I'm tone deaf and, and you
know, I can appreciate music I like,
but I can't produce it.
There's no way you could train me,
I don't think to be a
musician. Um, but, um,
so some of it is inborn and some of it is,
is a,
is taught for all of these qualities.
Yes.
It's a fascinating thing to watch it
emerge from a child, isn't it? Yes.
As a parent you see where it comes from.
Although we have adopted, like, I, um,
my mother had three biological children
and I have two adopted siblings that
come from actually a multiracial family.
I have a black sister
and a Chinese brother.
And My mother was an incredible human
being. She died when I was a 25.
She was 47. Uh, and, uh, we have been
foster parents, my wife and I, and,
and so,
and might,
we have lots of adopted kids in the
extended family in addition to biological
kids. And so you can see, you
can see the play of genes.
You could see the extent to which the,
the,
the kind of inherited traits that
these people that we all have.
And you'll see the shaping by
how you're raised and you know,
so both are important. And this is
incidentally why if you ever have anyone,
it's not,
it's not nature or nurture.
It's both always almost in
every single trait actually.
Well that's the case of so
many things in this life.
We want everything to be
binaries. Yes. It's, it's nuts.
It's a total,
we were talking earlier,
it's a total loss of nuance and
an inability to see any gray and,
and, and some people think, and I think
that's what you were talking about,
some people think that we are
hardwired to like dichotomies to see,
you know,
male and female and an up and down
and good and evil and left and right.
And to simplify the world by finding it.
And that we like it,
that it soothing to us to think that
the world can be divided into two
categories,
but in fact,
many times not always like
up and down is sort of clear,
but many times it can't.
They're shades of gray and it's harder.
That's harder to live in the
gray. Yes. I completely agree.
And that's why I've always been a po.
I mean,
I think it's an incredibly
foolish to deny that,
but people find comfort in denying
they find comfort in main tribal.
You find confidence in them. Yeah. US
versus them. This is the classic. Yes,
yes, yes. It's, it's a, it's a
simplified view of the world and it's,
it's foolish and dangerous
actually. Yeah. Um,
now sometimes you're at war with an enemy,
you know,
it's me or him and uh,
or us or them,
there are circumstances in which
it's a different survival. Yes.
Or survival in that mode. Yeah.
I get it. But, um, but you know,
but I think the a kind of worldview
which says we are good, they are evil.
Um, as we've been saying in different
kind of ways in different parts of our
conversation is I think foolish and
wrong and ultimately self-injurious.
Actually. Um, so we used
to have a, you know,
you've done martial arts, I spent
years training and showed ICAN karate.
It's very traditional Japanese style,
which I loved.
I'm sure you've had the same thing.
You actually are grateful for your up to
your opponent. You Mount your opponent,
you say thank you to your opponent,
right? Sure. Component is necessary for
you to learn. Oh yeah. I
mean this is the whole point,
not just your opponent training partners.
You don't want people to be able
to beat you. Yes. You get better.
That's exactly right. So, um, so this
is, you know, I think that the kind of,
that aspect of that kind of training
is, um, is a life lesson as well, right?
The capacity to see that in
the same happens with ideas.
How to my ideas get better.
How do I discover in my laboratory new
knowledge I discovered against opposition,
right? Someone says, you're
wrong about that. It's not
true. And I'm like, Oh yeah,
let me prove it to you.
Here's what,
I'm going to go back and do more
experiments and come back to you with more
arguments and more data and show you that
actually I'm right about this or not.
You go back to your lab and you're like,
oh shit, they were right. We were wrong.
So that's the way you uncover truth,
right?
It's the way you get to bore perfection.
It's the kind of ying and Yang actually.
So, uh, so, so yes, I think that, um,
I think that this, this, this, this,
the simplification of the world,
um, to think of, you know,
I'm good and your evil is, um,
really misunderstands that in many,
not all,
but in many circumstances and
misunderstands what's happening.
And also it brings back this problem that
human beings have always had with ego
and this need to be right.
And that identifying yourself in each
individual discussion and debate and
battle and needing to triumph.
And even though you desire to be correct,
you have to understand when you are not.
And you have to appreciate someone who
shows you that you are incorrect because
they are allowing you to grow your nest,
a finished product.
There's no way you can be.
Yes.
I think that's why I like arguing with
people I disagree with because that's
when I learned more stuff. Right.
If I talk to people I agree with,
I don't learn as much. So you get together
with our private roads do that dude.
And some other dudes I have saw is I
just came from his house and uh, he also,
he's crazy.
But anyway,
he'll laugh. He will listen to this and
this and he'll be laughing right now.
Does he do for a living? He's
a financier. No fucking way.
God Damn. That's cliche. Yes,
exactly. That's hilarious. Is
So, um, it is hilarious.
Anyway, pro gun mercenary.
Yeah.
Fries. Yeah, we saw that
coming. That's really funny.
The um,
oh,
what was the hold on I was going to say
something to you about you arguing with
people you disagree with. Um, hold
on. I lost the train of thought.
I had said before we talked about my
friend. Uh, you learn from them. Anyway.
I lost the train there, but no worries.
Yeah. Um, so, uh, yeah, I mean that's,
that's another issue that I've faced with
this podcast where people get upset at
me for having people on that have
opinions that they disagree with.
That's nuts. Yeah. They
think that you, you're,
you're doing a disservice by
providing a platform that's not that,
that's phrase they keep saying platform,
giving them a platform.
I think you have power, uh,
which you should use wisely.
I have power. I should use,
like we all have some power and some
parts of our lives and I think it is okay
to say you have some
power. You do. You know,
you have lots of millions of
listeners, people respect you. Um,
lots of people are both presidents,
CEOs, they're people of power.
But the idea that by talking to someone,
you are somehow abusing that power.
That's, that's crazy to me. In fact,
quite the opposite.
I think that you are shining
bright light of day onto a ideas.
Let people discuss them. Look, let's,
it's also quite schizophrenia. I mean,
have you ever seen one, the
schizophrenia person draws these, uh,
connections where they have one person
and that person met this other person and
that person used to work with this other
person and that person met Hitler. Yeah.
So, you know, Hitler, yes. Know
you've ever seen those. And yes,
it's really similar in
the same sort of a way.
It's this weird sort of a thing where
you're not allowed to even communicate or
be in contact with someone who is
in this apoe. And it's a myth. It's,
it's very childlike. Yes.
This, this perspective.
And it's very by an area and my friend
in your Susie's friend. Exactly.
So fucking stupid. Yes. I would
agree with that. And it's a,
it's a really common thing today that you,
you're seeing people are
trying to reinforce this
idea in and push it on other
folks. Well, I think one
thing, you know, like I think,
um, I think that, um, like
we were talking about,
I think that exposing ourselves
to a breadth of ideas to
people we disagree with.
I, you know, I think and,
and creating an environment
in which people can express
themselves. Um, you know,
it is good. You're not going to get
any arguments from me against on that,
on that point.
No. Um, and I, I just think
it's better for everybody.
Like we were talking about before,
when you meet someone who
can give you a lesson and,
and express something in a way that makes
you reconsider your own ideas that you
hold sacred. I mean, I'll
give you an example. Apple,
when I, when I, I met
my wife 30 years ago, I,
I wasn't pro death penalty,
but I was,
I would say I would say have neutral
to the death penalty. I would be like,
you know, ted Bundy, the
state can put him to death
and I had all the kind of conventional
reasons or I didn't really care.
He's a vile person. He killed all
these people. He tortured them.
If the families will get any
relief or whatever, that's fine.
I had some concerns because I was this
statistician about a conviction of the
innocent and I support the
innocence project and I am
very concerned with police
brutality. I have for years
been advocating the racializing,
the police brutality is
vile and, and uh, uh,
port and must be firmly
resisted. Uh, I think that, um,
I think the,
the,
the prosecutorial misconduct way people
are prosecutors lie and put people in
prison. Uh, you know, there've been many,
many cases of people on death row who
were innocent that should offend our
conscience.
So even back then I had some concerns
about the death penalty because I, um,
because I, I recognize that,
you know, we can't be perfect.
We're going to convict some innocent
people and also let some guilty people go
free. That's not as bad as killing
the putting to death. He innocent,
but they're both bad. So I had that
concern about the death penalty,
but otherwise I was like, it's okay.
My opinions have totally changed.
I'm completely opposed to the
death penalty now for many reasons.
Not just the statistical reason,
but also I think it's immoral.
I don't think the state should put into,
I think we can rip deprive you of liberty.
I think we can make sure
you're not a threat to society.
We can block you up for the rest
of your life. But I think we,
the state should not be taking
people's lives in that way.
There's something extraordinarily
strange about locking someone up.
It's very strange. Well, we have a
carceral state. I mean, you know,
we lock up a higher we have is,
we are fraction of people incarcerated
I think is the same as Stalinist Russia
and we have very long prison sentences,
which are nuts.
You don't need them for deterrence,
for nonviolent drug,
especially for non all nonviolent
offenses should have much shorter prison
doesn't, we should have more. We should
have higher certainty of punishment.
Higher fraction of people
who have actually committed
crimes should be punished.
But I think we should,
we could cut in half or less the,
the duration of the census. I
think you'll be able to, uh,
deter criminals from doing things with
a three month sentence if they are very
confident that they will be
convicted if they're caught.
Whereas now we have a system where
most are not convicted like this Jesse
smallest thing, which is just
ridiculous in the news. And, uh, uh,
and which therefore the, and only
a tiny fraction are convicted and,
but they're giving huge lung sentences.
It's like they're paying the
sentence for everyone that didn't,
it doesn't make any sense. And it, it's
expensive at ties up our prison system.
Actually, can I go to
tell you the story? True.
So it was a situation a few years
ago when there's a very famous, um,
uh, director and writer by the name of
David Simon, who I consider a friend.
He did the wire, he was a show runner
for a bunch of other very famous, uh,
wonderful, uh, TV programs.
Now he started his career actually
as a reporter in a, in Baltimore.
He was a beat reporter and then
went on to become a writer,
did the wire and so forth.
And he told the story, uh,
actually at Yale to students about how
he had just come back from a summit.
President Obama was still president where
he was trying to help the students to
see that you could find common ground
with your political opponents and that you
need to listen to them and talk to them
in order to, to find that ground, uh, if,
and so he told the following
story, he said, I had,
I just came back from Camp David where,
uh,
there was a meeting about how to
reduce incarceration in our society.
And he said the Koch brothers were there
and the students all hissed and Newt
Gingrich was there and the students,
all hissed and a bunch of
liberal people were there.
And the students were really happy
about that. And then they said, well,
why did you go, how could you associate
yourself with those evil people?
And he said, look, you said
the, the conservatives want to reduce
incarceration because it's expensive.
The liberals want to reduce
incarceration because it's unjust.
And the libertarians want to
reduce incarceration because
the state shouldn't be
depriving people of Liberty.
And I can find common ground with
these people and reduce incarceration.
Why would I not talk to them? And the
students didn't seem to understand that.
They were like,
they couldn't get it.
That's why they shouldn't
be able to vote to be 33,
25. I mean, and so I don't know
how we got onto this, you know,
like talking to you is so much fun because
it's like we're all over the place.
But, um, how did I get it?
Come up with this example we were talking
about talking to her political enemies.
Was it or something else?
We're talking about people telling
you that you shouldn't associate yes.
People that have varying opinions.
Yes, yes. And you know, Oh and no.
We were talking about an incarceration
and prison sensors and so forth.
So we have a horrible problem in our
society with, with incarceration.
A larger fraction of our
populace is incarcerated.
We deprive after you paid your debt to
society, we often have these, these, uh,
we deprive you of your right to vote,
which I think is wrong.
You've paid your debt to society.
You should be able to reenter society.
That's exactly, yes. Exactly.
You were in prison for 10 years.
That's enough. You don't, now you, we
want you to feel a part of society.
Can we want to welcome you back
if we have that vision of justice?
How about the registered sex offender?
That's a serious problem. Especially for,
uh, crimes. You know, the, these crazy
cases which offend my conscience.
I know a guy who got
charged as a registered sex
offender because he urinated
outside. Yeah. That's not caught in the
south urinating outside. That's nuts.
That's just a prosecutorial abuse.
Or you know,
you have these Romeo and
Juliet laws, which are not in
every state now. Thank God,
alas, last, they are not in
every state. Uh, you know,
you have a 16 year old boy
and a 14 year old girl.
There have to be exceptions for that
kind of sexual practice. You know,
they're exchanging a
sexually explicit images.
They should not be considered sex
offenders for the rest of their lives.
That's nuts. So, um, so
yeah, so all of those things.
So the,
but the problem is not only do we have
a huge fraction of people in prison,
we have extremely long prison sentences
compared to any many European countries
for the same crime and a, it's
costly. It's unjust, it's ineffective.
I think. I think we should change the
policies on this and maybe we will.
There's also the idea of
reforming them. It's, it's,
they're not using all the
tools within their disposal.
They're not really giving
a good attempted it.
And I just don't think it does anything
other than make their life hell for a
short period of time,
which we're hoping we hope deters
them from doing future crime. Well,
they're different. There's the justice,
there's deterrent there. Safety, right?
Like so violent criminals that we put
in jail. Uh, we need to do that. I mean,
I'm not interested in being
killed by somebody who, you know,
could it killed someone else. She should
have busy in jail, uh, for a while,
20 years.
So I'm at a time from larder.
Yeah, for murder. I think
20 years is enough. Well,
a European,
a European standards are
about 20 years actually.
And there are different things like
if you want to deprive them, if your,
if your vision is they're being
punished for the killing of a life,
therefore they've surrendered their life.
It's sort of eye for an eye
kind of justice. You would,
they would be the rest of
their lives. And you know, I,
we can debate whether that's
reasonable or not. If you,
if you want to provide
a public safety reason,
people often age out of their violence.
So a lot of men,
typically these were talking mostly about
men who do these things. Uh, you know,
by the time they're in
their forties or 50s,
they're much less violent to stoss
declines. They get older and wiser. Uh,
they're not interested in, in criminal,
in that kind of criminal behavior.
Many of them are not.
So that does,
that suggests you don't need
life sentences for murder.
And I think it also depends and we
have gradations of murder. You know,
we have like the impulsive stuff that
intent matters of planfulness matters,
that depravity matters. All of
these things are, are factors.
And I don't think we should have a one
size fits all incarceration for murder.
Yes. That's my opinion. What do you think?
I think it depends entirely
on the circumstances.
If two men are engaged in some sort of
a dispute and one winds up killing the
other one,
that's a big difference between that
and someone breaking into your house and
killing your daughter. Yes. A correct.
And I also think even in that, like I,
I really am opposed to these stand
your ground laws. I think those are,
if you have the opportunity to avoid
conflict and to avoid you or not,
uh, it, I would prefer as a state
to require that you walk away,
even if it makes you feel embarrassed,
uh,
then give you the right to kill
someone for offending you in those,
those videos of the,
of the guys in that shot,
the guy on his knees in the parking lot
in the, I forgot what state it was like,
uh, not long. A year or two ago. They got
into an altercation and the parking lot.
Like, if I have words with someone, an
apartment shot guy on his knee. Yes.
There was no threat to him.
And he was,
he was not prosecuted on the stand
your ground argument, which is nuts.
Why was the guy on his knees?
He was, I forgot, I said,
don't shoot me or something.
Oh, Jesus. So it was, it was crazy. He
didn't get prosecuted. I don't think so.
We can look up the facts.
There were several cases.
There were several cases like
this, but you know, like,
I remember when I was doing,
showed a con karate,
my Sensei Kazumi Tabata,
this was years ago, uh,
the 30 years ago now. And he
told us the following story. He,
he said there was a Sensei
in this village in Japan,
and the students were coming to the
Dojo. And, uh, there was the, the,
the best student that, you know,
and then all the other students,
and they were walking through the village
and they passed the approach to horse
that was on the street from the rear,
and it startled the horse.
And as the horse reared up and
kicked its leg, the, the, uh,
the best student instantly
did a kind of a avoidance,
kind of twisted his body and avoided
the kick and the, and the, and the, uh,
the horse,
his leg went right in front of him and
all the other students were amazed at his
ability and they get to the
Dojo and they tell the Sensei,
this is my sensei telling me this story,
telling all of us this story. And they,
those students get to this, the
Dojo. And they tell that the Sensei,
the story marveling at the,
at the ability of this master student
to definitely avoid the strike and the
Sensei's very angry and he
don't understand why, why
is he so angry? He said,
if he were a really good student of mine,
he would have walked on the
other side of the street.
He would have avoided
the horse altogether.
So the real wisdom is to avoid avoidance
of conflict in the first place.
There's no reason to seek out conflict.
And so on the stand your ground laws,
you know, if the choices ether you just
avoid the conflict, you know, someone,
someone swore at you or called you an
asshole or was an unreasonable jerk that
doesn't give you the right to
kill them. Right. Um, so anyway,
I don't know how we got onto this as well.
How are we going to the penalty
for, for murder. Exactly. Exactly.
So, so, so different
gradations. Yeah. Yeah.
I just don't know how much of a
deterrent it is locking people up.
I just, I, I'm not sure,
I'm not really sure if that actually
stops people from doing things.
I think it stops some people. I think
there've been academic research on this.
I just don't think there's any real
rehabilitation other than personal choice.
I mean, I think the, the,
the real rehabilitation comes from someone
making a personal choice to never be
that person. That Dan again. Yes.
For most of them you're, you're,
you're being locked up with a bunch
of hardened criminals and you, your,
that's your,
your community.
But you're not suggesting we have a
society in which when you commit violent
acts, we do nothing. No, I'm
not. No, I'm not. No, I'm,
I'm suggesting you're struggling with this
is what you're saying. Yeah. The, yeah.
The concept of nuances. Yes. This is,
this is a applied here
better than anywhere else.
I think I got the impression looking at
your face a moment ago when I told my
sort of sweet Sensei, Japanese karate
story, that you didn't agree necessarily.
We know that's a very wise way
of looking at it. Yeah. Don't,
don't be near a fucking horse that
wants a kick. You very smart. Yeah.
Get out of there. I'm a big believer
in avoiding conflict. Yeah. I'm, I'm,
I'm the first guy to conflict, not
intellectual conflict. Right, exactly.
Physical words and violence are
different access routes and very,
extremely different. Yeah. I mean,
intellectual conflict at that is actually
important and you learn from it. Yes.
Very rarely do you learn too much. Right.
I mean, you learned don't do that again,
that's going to learn from physical
conflicts. This don't do that again. Yes.
I was just, it's just, you know what,
what happens in nature with
animals happens with people.
If you let them get to that level and
it's scratched down to the, you know,
remove that thin film of society
with rocks.
Yes, there we are violent. But I keep
coming back to what I argue in blueprint.
You know, we, I have those, those
tendencies, but equally we have
tendencies to be kind and friendly and uh,
and it's, we have to create
the environment to, uh,
to foster those. I have a,
there's sense in which,
and I talk about this in the book,
there's a sense in which as
we create those environments,
we actually change ourselves as a species.
There's this a set of ideas that's
known as gene culture coevolution.
And the idea is that we create certain
kinds of cultural environments,
those kind of cultural
environments advantage certain
ones of us making those of
us that are born with
certain abilities better off,
which then leads to those
environments being created even more.
Let me give you some,
an example of that.
The most famous example of this is
something known as lactase persistence.
So many people, not about half the
world can adults can drink milk.
The other half cannot. They
get lactose intolerant. Well,
why can you drink milk as an adult? Have
you ever thought about that? Like why?
Why are you capable of drinking milk
as an adult? In our ancestral state,
actually up until about 10,000 years ago,
only babies could address to digest
milk because only babies had milk.
Babies would suckle at their mother's
breasts and have milk and then they'd be
weaned and then they would never drink
milk again. There'd be no milk to drink.
There was therefore no reason for any
adult to be able to digest lactose,
which is the principle sugar in milk
because there was no lactose in your diet.
You didn't encounter milk,
so human beings were able to digest
lactose when they were babies.
They lost that capacity.
All human beings,
when they got to about two or three
or four or five, when they wean,
they no longer were able to just melt.
So the enzymes in their body,
we're programmed as it were to
only work when they were infants.
Well about between three and 9,000 years
ago in multiple places in Africa and in
Europe,
human beings suddenly domesticate animals.
We domesticate milk producing animals like
cattle and sheep and goats and camels,
and now all of a sudden there's a
supply of milk around us because of our
cultural innovation,
because of the thing we invented,
we created the domestic breeds.
Now we have milk.
Now therefore those among us who are
mutants who were born with the ability to
have our lactase, the enzyme that
digest lactose persist into adulthood.
This is known as lactase persistence.
Those of us who had that would have a
survival advantage because we could have
another source of calories that the
rest of the people in our group couldn't
consume.
They couldn't drink milk like we could
and we had a source of unspoiled water
during times of drought.
We could drink milk.
Everyone else had to drink this filthy
water that they didn't have access to,
so those among us who had these qualities
could reproduce better, survive headed,
have survival advantage. It turns out
that this has happened several times.
This is when well documented.
The genetics of this has all been worked
out several times and last three to
9,000 years because of Acumen,
cultural product.
We have evolved to be a slightly different
genetically and it doesn't stop with
cows.
I think that when we invent
cities about over 5,000 years ago,
we, so we, we, we invent
agriculture about 10,000 years ago.
It's debated exactly
when we invent cities,
but between five and 10,000 years ago
we start having fixed settlements.
Earlier you and I were talking about
population density and having to live with
other people, which is not our ancestral
state, not packed, not with other people.
We always lived as a group, as socially.
I think that as we invent cities,
people with different kinds of brains
are better able to survive in cities.
So now that we've invented cities where
advantaging people with certain kinds of
brains and therefore I think in a
thousand or 2000 or 5,000 years,
just like the milk example,
there'll be different people as a result
of something we humans manufactured
that we made. And I could keep giving you
examples of this. There's a, in the book,
I have an example, another example of
a, they're called the sea nomads. They,
they live in the Philippines.
These are people who don't live on land.
They live on houseboats that sail around
the Pacific for thousands of years.
They've had this lifestyle and
they die for their food dive.
So they forage on the seabed.
They are the world's best free divers.
They spend hours per day underwater.
They can hold their breath longer than
anyone else. Uh, and they, they do do it.
Nothing except with
weights and wooden goggles.
They dive down into the seabed
and forage and they hunt.
They hunt underwater with spears.
Okay.
They hunt underwater would spirits.
It's mind boggling. Wow. And uh,
but they, uh, have evolved,
have different spleens and
different oxygen metabolism
than you and I. So those,
among them that could survive the dives,
fed their families, made more babies.
And now we think this happened 2000
years ago. There are different,
the ones that couldn't died.
So their invention of a
seafaring way of life,
their invention of a way of living at sea,
the boats technology,
the,
the spear fishing technology,
the intervention of those
technologies creates an environment,
cultural environment around them,
which modifies natural
selection and changes the kind
of genes that those people
have.
These are,
these are discussed in blueprint and
there are many examples of how I want to
see an image of these
goggles. Yeah. If you Google,
if you Google, um, that's
our little slit goggles.
If you Google see nomad Goggle, you may
come up with it and let me give you,
what are they using for a lens? There's
no lens. Yeah, they're little slits.
So what's the point? Uh, I didn't
look at the technology at that level,
but let me just find lens than it
doesn't protect your eyes. I think it,
I think it, uh, it may reduce
glare underwater, you know,
by having you look through slits, it's
got some something on, I can see it,
Huh? Uh, well, no,
because they didn't have glass or maybe
they might take a piece of it. Well,
the one this kids holding up,
it's got something. Let me see.
That's a lots of actual, no,
that's a modern scuba diving mask.
Yeah. He may have made it from wood, but
the ancient one. Yeah. This is the Zhao.
But uh, so if you look
at, so look at that.
Can you find what's I'm looking Goggle,
I mean it'll be hard to find.
Maybe no one's put it on and now of
course they have modern technology so they
can uh, they can, uh, that's, those
are totally monitored plastic. Yes.
But they used to have these
wooden goggles anyway.
They adopted or adapted
rather to this new lifestyle.
Sort of like genetically adapt.
Yes.
Like the [inaudible] have developed
disability to not get frostbite and to not
get numb fingers and cold weather.
I did not know that example,
but that would be an example of that.
Yeah. This is an example from a,
believe they were talking
about it from Alaska that they,
they did genetic testing on these people
and they did different facets. Yes, yes,
yes, yes, yes. That would be another
example of just exactly that example.
I didn't put that one in the
book, but yes. Yeah, we're
incredibly flexible, right?
Yes. Well we have flex two kinds
of flexibility, so, so think about,
think about like when we settled the
Tibetan plateau, when human being settled,
the Tibetan plateau,
there were different challenges up there.
It's cold up there and there's not a
lot of oxygen up there. Now we could,
genetic evolution is not fast in us.
We didn't become furry, you know,
like one way to cope with a cold is to
become furry again. We didn't do that.
Why?
Because we had clothing.
We had cultural means of
coping with this situation.
So for the coal to cope with a cold,
we used culture.
There was no cultural means to
cope with the low oxygen up there.
They didn't have bottled
oxygen 5,000 years ago.
There was no way to produce oxygen.
They couldn't,
they didn't have the
chemistry to produce auction.
So the auction to cope with the
low oxygen tent pressure up there,
low oxygen tension up there.
They've evolved genetically so that the
people who live in the, in the Himalayas,
they actually have different kinds
of hemoglobin compared to you and me,
better able to extract
oxygen from the environment.
So they're two different challenges
that are coped with in different ways.
One is cope with culturally by cultural
evolution. One is coped with genetically,
which is much slower,
which genetic evolution and it's the
cultural evolution is the cultural traits
that natural.
So natural selection equips us with a
capacity to accumulate knowledge and to
teach each other stuff.
And given that rare ability,
as we discussed earlier,
we're able to spread out across the
planet and live in all these dissimilar
environments. We use our cultural
ability to dominate the planet basically.
Now, when you were, when
you were creating this,
will you actually thinking of it as a
blueprint that someone would follow?
Uh, yes and no. I wasn't thinking of it
that way, but having finished the book,
I do think that there are,
like I don't,
in the book I talk a little bit in
the book about implications for, uh,
of these ideas for, for
artificial intelligence.
Like, as we create robots, uh,
as we, even as we create sex robots
or autonomous vehicles or, uh,
forms of bots online,
how should those bots be programs
so as not to injure our society.
So there are some policy implications
I discuss in the book, but I,
I wasn't thinking of this as a,
as a, as a, as a a prescription.
Like this is the way to live a good life.
But partly because as I,
as I argue in the book,
you know,
we don't need to affirmatively
seek a good life.
We have been endowed by natural selection
with the capacity to make a good life,
uh, full of these qualities.
So this blueprint is,
I want to use the word God given it
doesn't come from God, but it's God given,
you know, it comes from somewhere else.
It comes from natural selection that we,
um, that we do this. So I, yeah.
How much time have you put into
artificial intelligence and a lot,
and we do a lot of work in my lab on Ai.
What about sex robots?
Like what rules should
they give for sex robots?
And how much could that damage
interpersonal relations? Yes,
that's a great question. That's
exactly the right question in my view.
So our concern with sex robots from a
liberty point of view should not in the
slightest. B, whether
you enjoy a sex robot,
it's your business you'd buyer bought,
do what you want. I really don't. I see.
I find it would be hard pressed
to to object. The problem
is with set. Well let's,
let's back up from the less provocative,
but let's come back at six but I looked
like a simpler example. First let's talk.
Let's talk about your children
talking to Alexa. Okay,
so the person who designs Alexa wants
to make your child's experience easy and
pleasant and as part of the programming
of Alexa because they want to make Alexa
the obedient servant of your child,
it doesn't require a child to say,
please Alexa,
would you play the music for me?
Your child can be as rude as she wants to.
Alexa and Alexa will do what she wants.
What you should be concerned about,
however, is not your child's
interaction with Alexa.
When you should be concerned about
is what your child is learning from
interacting with Alexa,
that then she takes to the playground.
So now she's rude to other children.
So Alexa is corroding our social fabric.
Alexa,
in this example is making
children rude to each other.
So our concern is not so much
do we make and do we make,
you know, like Asimov's
laws of robotics, do we we,
it's not that we want to program the
robot so that their don't harm you.
It's true.
The first law,
we don't want the robot to through an act
of commission or omission harmer allow
human to come to be harmed.
It's that we're concerned about how the
robot and interacting with you might
cause you to harm others.
The robot,
the robotic intelligence creates these
externalities, these cascade effects.
So in the Alexa example,
we might want to regulate the programming
of devices that speak to children,
not because we want to
deprive your daughter,
have the right to speak how she wants,
but because we recognize that that robot
is going to cause your daughter to be
rude to other people. Is it really?
Do you really think, yes, the Alexa,
what's the weather that that
would make your attorney?
But surely I think it will contribute. So
that's a, it's an example. It's not like,
I'm not arguing that Alexis should become,
or nately think it's so novel to kids
that they know it's not a person.
I don't think it really,
all right.
But we're using these
examples to build the thing.
So let's talk about the sex robot.
Okay.
So some people believe that actually
the emergence of sex robots,
which will surely appear in the
next 10 or 20 years, um, will, um,
will be a fantastic boon.
They think that, um,
you will people be able to experiment,
uh,
you'll be able to experiment with
same sex relationships. For example,
a group sex. Uh, you might learn to be a,
a better lover so he could practice with
the robots and therefore you'd be more
experienced when you were having
sex with a real human. So they,
you can't get venereal diseases from a
sex robots. You can't hurt their feelings.
Uh,
so people think that the argument based
on ethical grounds is that this would be
terrific. Uh, that this will be a benefit.
Other people have the opposite opinion.
Other people think that actually
having sex with robots first of all is
symbolically and, and, um, conceptually
vile. They think that, you know, it,
it, it, it takes sex and converts
it into a kind of a machine,
literally a machine like
a, you know, function. Uh,
and they furthermore think
that it would result in,
you ha in one having a kind of anonymous
or impersonal interactions with human
subsequently that you'll be in trained,
you know, to let's say want an obedient,
uh, you know, partner, uh, for
example, I don't have a stand on this.
Like I don't know which way it's going
out. And in a way I don't have to get,
make a stand on it.
Because what I'm interested in recognizing
is that when we talk about having,
allowing people to have sex with
sex robots not allowing there,
it's going to happen.
The focus of our concern should be not
what is your experience in your bedroom
when you have sex with a sex robot?
Our concern is a state like my interest,
I have no stake or control over
what you're doing over there,
but my interest is in,
in once you have had that experience,
how does that change how you
interact with other people? Right.
And there I think just like
anything else like you can,
you can make all the garbage
you want in your house,
but if you start polluting the
environment, you're harming me.
So now I have a reason for intervening
in your activities on your land.
You can't pollute your own land if
that pollution runs off onto my land.
And so the similar argument can be
made or look at autonomous vehicles.
Here's an example.
Right now we have all roads,
almost all roads have just human drivers
and in 20 or 30 years almost all roads
will probably have only nonhuman drivers.
Machines will drive and those autonomous
vehicles probably can be yoked
together. They can communicate with
each other so that you'll have like,
like trains of cars moving and synchrony.
Like each of them will be communicating
with the other nearby cars and you'll
have laminar flow where all these vehicles
are smoothly moving and joining the
highway and leaving the highway and
communicating on a citywide scale,
slowing traffic down miles away because
they anticipate with AI that there'll be
a jam here if they don't do that. And,
and I think that'll be actually great.
I'm actually looking
forward to autonomous.
I mean I still like to take my
car to the speedway but you know,
dried it itself with stick,
which I like, but you know,
but in between we're going to have a
world of what I call hybrid systems of
human driven cars and autonomous
vehicles coexisting in an on a plane,
on an even plane.
And we need to be worried about that
because these autonomous vehicles when we
interact with them are going to change
how we interact with each other.
For example,
do we program the autonomous vehicle
to drive at a constant steady speed?
If you're the designer of
the car, you might say, Gee,
I don't want this car to crash a,
I want the car to drive in a very
predictable fashion and that that's what's
best for the occupants of the car.
That's what's gonna allow
me to sell more vehicles.
But it may be the case that actually
when people are in contact with such a
vehicle, they get lulled into
a false sense of security. Oh,
that'd vehicle never does anything new.
I don't need to pay so much
attention to the car in front of me.
I just miss drive, you
know, at a steady clip.
And then they veer off and they go to a
part of the highway where they're just
human drivers and now having been
lulled into a false sense of security,
they cause more collisions
is not paying attention.
So that autonomous vehicle has changed
how I drive in a way that harms other
people.
So maybe the programming of the vehicle
should be to occasionally do erratic
things too. Like suddenly slow
down or speed up a little bit,
obliging me to stay vigilant
and pay attention as I'm
interacting with that car.
So that then when I go to
another part of the highway,
when I interact with just humans, I have
retained that vigilance. Once again,
the lesson here is,
is that it's not just about the one
on one interaction between the robotic
artificial intelligence
and the human being.
It's about how the robot's affect us.
And in my lab,
we do many experiments in social systems
where we take a group of people and we
drop online,
we drop a Bot or in the laboratory we
have a physical robot and we watch how the
presence of the robot doesn't just
modify how the human interacts with the
robot, but how the humans interact with
each other. So if we put a robot right,
they're looking at us with its
third, I would, we, uh, you know,
would it change how you and I talked
to each other, make us different.
That's the experiments we're doing.
Well,
clearly in the sex robot realm, that's
going to be a problem. I mean we,
we see the difference between
humans that have porn addictions.
Yeah, that's a good example. Yeah.
Porn addictions when people do they
developed is very impersonal way of
communicating with people and they,
they think about sex and
the objectification of
the opposite sex in a very
different reasons. Very different
way. It flavors the way you,
it flavors your expectations. Yes.
Yes. And it makes it difficult.
It can make it difficult for you to have
normal sexual relationships if you come
to see if your expectations are, are, uh,
guided by porn and that is going to
be radically magnified by some sort of
artificial life form that you create
that's indistinguishable. Yes. Have,
you can have an indistinguishable
sex partner that is, you know,
some incredibly beautiful woman. Yes.
That is a robot. And then you are,
man, let's go, man, women would be quite
happy to change their spouses for robots.
I wonder if women are going to be as
intuit as men because I think women divine
desire,
more emotional intimacy
and I think, I mean, uh,
on a, on a scale than
men do. I, I think, um,
I think the jury is still
out on, you know, what,
what the relative balance between men
and women, we might be surprised that uh,
that will be repeated nails,
especially given x societal expectations
and women can form those and,
and I'll be giving her a chance
to not a lot of men can be sure.
So it could go both ways.
I don't,
I'm not prepared to make a prediction
who's going to be better off in the gender
debate with the emergence of sex robots,
but they'll maybe you way you suggest,
I don't know what we're also in this
weird transition genetically where they're
doing genetic expert experiments on
humans and with the advent of Crispr and
emerging technologies,
I was talking about that in the book too.
Entirely possible that there's not
going to be any frumpy bodies anymore.
That that's hundreds of years away.
But yes, I think so. I wonder, I mean,
I don't know if it is,
I think if they start cracking them out
in China and they start giving birth to
eight foot tall superman,
yes. 12 inch dicks. Yes. We're
going to have a real issue.
Yes. Uh, we will, uh, yes,
that's the least of it. Uh, yes.
Uh,
like God,
I mean it's a million tiredly possible
in the future they're going to have that
and then we're going to
have likely cumins yes.
I think that is likely the
debate is how far in the future.
So I don't think we're going to start
by using these technologies to cure a
monogenic diseases. So, you know,
like thalassemia for example,
so a diseases or certain
immune deficiencies,
disease where a single
gene is defective and uh,
and those will be the initial targets.
But once we start with that,
eventually I think there will be people
who will want to genetically engineer
other people, uh, their
offspring for example,
and a modified them in
the ways that you suggest,
maybe not 12 inch Dick's
but maybe you know,
ability to run fast or something
else. Far Smarter. I mean, yes.
Isn't that one of these side effects
that they showed with the, um,
genetic manipulation of these Chinese
babies to eliminate HIV there?
That they made them smarter? No, I don't
know if they made them smarter there.
What's clear from the most recent findings
I've seen from that case is that a,
unsurprisingly,
as anyone could predict,
the technology is not good enough to
restrict the mutations to one particular
region of the genome.
So there were other changes in the
genome and these children that occurred
elsewhere rather than the targeted region,
which was to increase their immunity to
HIV. And we don't know what those are,
but those could kill those kids quickly.
We could make them better in some ways,
we have no way of knowing yet,
but I think the conclusion was that it
increased their intelligence. I don't,
I think it's,
I have not seen results and I think it
would be premature find that it would
because every mature to come to that
because they're [inaudible]. Yeah.
There the problem is also
sensational Click Bait, which is,
that's what you want to click,
you know,
not just that they did the HIV and they
made them smarter is going to get like
40% more clicks versus,
yeah,
wolf 40% yeah. That mean that's,
that's just the nature of humans,
right? Yes. Um, just declare clear. I
talk about the crisper example in, in uh,
in blueprint. I actually talk about
these, how these technologies, again,
my lens on it is how these technologies
are going to change how we interact with
each other.
And it goes back to the example we were
talking about at the beginning when we
invented cities.
That was a technology that changed
how we interacted with each other.
So human beings for a very long time,
they've been inventing
when we invented weapons,
that was a technology that changed
how we interact with each other.
So we have previously
done this kind of thing.
We've invented a technology that changed
how we interact with each other and I'm
very interested in in the and discuss
some of those implications. Yeah.
I'm incredibly interested
in this because I,
I love to study history and I love to
study like how crazy the world was four
thousand five thousand years ago,
a thousand years ago,
what it's going to be like in the future.
I just think our understanding of the
consequences of our actions are so
different than anybody has ever had
before. We have just such a, a broader,
first of all,
we have examples from all over the world
now that we can study very closely,
which I don't think really was available
to that many people up until recently.
You mean?
I'm sorry.
You're saying the examples are more
numerous or a capacity to discern them is
higher. Our capacity to discern them and
just our in depth understanding of these
various cultures all over the world.
Like,
like what you've been telling you
today about these divers and others,
we just have so much more data and so
much more of an understanding than ever
before. Yes, I love the idea that we are,
I mean I believe that this is probably
the best time ever to be alive and I
think that it's probably,
I think that's true.
I think there's certainly
a lot of terrible things
that are wrong in the world
today also true.
But I think that there's less of that and
more good and compare that too before.
No, I think that's right. And,
but one of the arguments that I make is
this is a kind of Steven pinker argument
that you're outlining, which is, you
know, with the emergence of, I mean,
people are living longer than they
ever have on the whole planet.
Fewer people in starvation.
We have less violence. I mean,
every indicator of human wellbeing is up.
Uh,
and it's partly due, are largely due in
the recent last thousand years to the, uh,
to the emergence of the
enlightenment and a, the Phyllis,
the philosophy and the science that was
guided that emerged about 300 years ago
and 200 and some odd years ago and
culminating in the present and continuing.
So I think,
I think this is not just the kind of
so-called weekish view of history.
It's not just a progressive
sort of fantasy.
I think it's the case that
these philosophical and
moves that our species made
in the last few hundred years has
improved our wellbeing. However,
as we've been discussing today,
it's not just historical forces that are
tending towards making us better off a
deeper and more ancient and more
powerful force is also at work,
which is natural selection.
It's evolutionary and not just historical
forces that are relevant to our
wellbeing.
And we don't just need to
look to philosophers to find
the path to a good life.
Natural selection has equipped us with
these capacities for love and friendship
and cooperation and teaching and all
these good things we've been discussing
that also tend to a good life. So,
so yes, I totally, we would do,
we're better off today than we've ever
been on average across the world. However,
it's not just that,
that's contributing to our wellbeing.
This natural selection is literally why
we are in this state now and why we were
hoping this trend will continue.
We will be in this better place 50 years
from now, 100 years from now. Well,
natural selection doesn't
work over those time scales.
So those are historical forces. But the
point is we are set up for success. Yes.
Um, you know, we are equipped with these,
uh, you know, you're given five fingers,
which make it pos and an opposable thumb,
which allows you to manipulate tools.
So natural selection has
given you an opposable thumb.
Culture lets you use a computer.
Do you worry about the circumventing
of this natural process by artificial
intelligence that artificial intelligence
is going to introduce some new,
incredibly powerful factor into this
whole chain of events that by having sex
robots and sex or, or,
or, or, um, robot workers,
yes. Things becoming automated.
Yes. This I, I'm concerned. I mean,
this is,
I,
I'm very concerned about how technology
is going to affect our economy. These,
again, these concerns were not the
first generation to face these concerns.
There were similar concerns with the
industrial revolution that workers were
being put out of work when machines were
invented. Nevertheless, work persisted.
People still had jobs to do. Um, there was
a disruption. There's no doubt about it.
I think Google and the information
revolution and these types of robotic
automation are disruptive.
They're going to affect how we allocate
labor and capital and data in our
society.
There's no doubt about all of that.
I thought you were alluding to just
to check if you were to the debate,
which I don't know the
answer to on whether AI will,
are we going to face like a terminator
type existence where you know the
machine's rise up and kill us all or not
and you know very smart people on both
sides of that debate. And I read them
all and like I would like, he's right.
And then there'd be the guy
that has the opposite, but
I'm like, no, no, he's right.
And then it goes back and forth.
I don't know who's writing it goes back
to nuance, right? Yes, it is nuanced,
but it's hard to know whether, again,
we're not talking over our lifetimes,
right over hundreds of years,
you know?
Is there a time a thousand years from
now when the human beings will say,
what the hell were our ancestors doing
inventing artificial intelligence that
they're wiping us out?
I don't know the answer to that question.
I think there's an issue also with the,
the concept of artificial,
like artificial life,
artificial intelligence. It's,
I think it's going to be life because
it's is going to be a life that we've
created.
And I don't think it's artificial.
I just think it's a
different kind of life.
I think that we're thinking of
biologically based life of sex
reproduction in terms of the way we've
always known it as being the only way
that life exists.
But if we can create something and
that something decides to do things,
it's sound create, live on its own.
Yeah. It's silicon based life form.
Like why not?
Why,
why does life have to be something
that only exists through the, you know,
multiplication of cells. Yes. That's
very charitable of you. And uh,
it's, people make that claim. Uh,
some people think that, you know,
those machines in the distant future,
we'll look back at us as like one stage
of evolution that culminated in them
that we're some, I've always said that
we are some sort of an electronic, uh,
Caterpillar that doesn't know that it's
going to give birth to a butterfly.
We're making a cocoon.
We don't even know what it's doing.
That's a great metaphor.
I have a hard time accepting that
because you're a person. Yes, it's,
it gets my interest,
but we're so flawed.
All these things that we've
outlined all the pipes with us,
those would go away with
artificial intelligence.
It's a deep philosophical question,
Joe.
I would think it's inevitable and I
think if the single celled organisms are
sitting around wondering what
the future was going to be like,
where are we going to be replaced? Will
they make antibiotics and kill us? Yes.
What's gas? They aren't going
to kill us. I mean this is,
I mean we are so fluff
denigrate the ocean.
We do pull the fish out of it and do
fuck up the air, do commit genocide.
There's all these things that are real,
but the artificial life won't have
those problems because it won't be
emotionally based, won't be
biologically based. It'll just exist.
That's a really good story.
We're so flawed. Why not?
Oh, we're very flawed. We are flawed, but
like I said, we have a fun activity at it.
I'm not going to read a very flat though.
We are fly. I think it's beautiful.
Beautiful too. But I think vultures
probably think they're beautiful too.
That's why they breed with each
other. Well, they are beautiful, but,
but the point is I think we
have a flop beauty. I like,
I'm going to stick to my principles
that we are, despite our flaws worth it.
There is something wonderful about us.
And I think that that wonderful creative
quality is the reason why we created
artificial life in the first place.
It's like this, this creation.
We've had that impetus. You know,
if you look at a lot of the, um,
the art, whether it's the
Egyptian, you know, the, the, the,
the pyramids a or other kinds
of, um, artistic expression,
we seem to have had a desire
to transcend death, you know,
to make things that sure that looked like
us but weren't alive forever actually.
So, I mean, I think in that regard,
I think you're quite right that, um,
it's not going to stop. That tendency is
not gonna stop now. You're, you're very,
as I said,
positive take on the claim and your
analogy to single celled organisms,
which are just, you know, but a fleeting,
not a fleeting, they're still there,
but a phase in our evolution,
you know,
is something I'm going to have to be
thinking about because it's disturbing,
honestly. Well, it's an
objective perspective.
If I took myself out of the human race,
which I really can't,
but if I tried to fake it, I would say,
oh, I see what's going on here. Yeah.
These domains is,
yes,
these dummies are buying iPhones
and new Mac books because they,
they know that this is what's going
to help the production of newer,
more superior technologies. The
more we consume. It's also based,
I think in a lot of ways our insane
desire for materialism is fueling this and
it could be an inherent property of the
human species that it is designed to
create this artificial life and that
literally is what it's here for.
And much like an ant is creating an ant
hill and doesn't exactly have some sort
of a future plan.
It's kids and it's four o one k plan that
what we're doing is like this inherent
property of being a human being, our
curiosity, our wanderlust, our design,
our culture things.
Yeah.
All these things are built in because
if you follow them far enough down the
line a hundred years, 200 years, it
inevitably leads to artificial life. Yes.
I think, uh, I think that's possible. Um,
and of course we're not going
to be alive to test that idea.
Their son will maybe with CRISPR and
all this crazy shit that's coming down.
I'll come on. I know there's nothing's
gonna happen in the pace of innovation.
People always had been say,
if you go back every decade,
people say just around the corner,
just around the corner,
these things that are take forever.
They're very hard.
Biological systems are very hard to
engineer. Um, I don't, and you know,
of course the people who do
that kind of work will often,
I think a lot of them engage in snake
oil. You know, they want to fund.
There was sure,
but I think it's entirely possible that
there's a 20 year old listening to this
podcast will be 150 yes. That's
possible. Maybe a lot more than that.
I think there's, I think it's entirely
possible that 30 year olds today,
it could be 150, but I think there's,
you give another 10 years of research,
you give maybe 10 years more.
I think it's entirely, well,
there's a famous bad about this. You may
know they feel Schonski I'll stood bet.
Yes. Where they bet that uh,
about 10 or 20 years ago,
they bet that there was a person born
that then that year who would live to be
150. And on one side you had one
guy who said no, they, they, they,
they bet $1 billion and
they endowed it with, uh,
they opened up a bank account.
They put in, you know,
they're using compound interest
to get to that sum of money.
And they obliged can nerds. Yes. And
they obliged and they have lives.
They're a clear bag.
Yeah. And they, and they,
and they designated the National Academy
of Sciences or some entity like that,
that would, um, that would
adjudicate the baton 150 years. And,
uh,
and they,
they specify the kinds of documentation
that might be needed and they allowed
for in the future. They may be other
ways of ascertaining how old someone
is and those can be used.
And that's the bet. Uh, so I,
you might be right about
that. Like, you know,
there are humans that live naturally to
be 120. We have that capacity. Actually,
here's an interesting idea.
Why do we die at all?
Why is natural selection ever
given us an immortal species?
Have you ever thought
about that? Yeah. Yeah.
I have never reached a conclusion, but
I, I was figured you live long enough.
We'll, especially up until recent
history, only long enough to recognize it.
It was all crazy hustle.
That's a fourth philosophical, I'm
looking for a scientific answer. Here's,
here's one answer for why we're not
immortal. So if you think about it,
why would natural selection not have
created a creature that lived forever,
right? Would that be? Why did, why should
we die? Okay, so here's the one answer.
It's not know for sure if this is the
answer, but this is a good answer.
Imagine there to two different
kinds of things that can kill you.
Intrinsic Causes,
an extrinsic causes,
so things inside your body that
result in you dying, defects,
diseases and so forth, or things
outside your body, like accidents,
lightening strikes, trees fall,
and you just die and so forth
because it's impossible to eliminate
all extrinsic causes because some people
are going to die from accidents.
It would be inefficient from the
point of view of evolution to evolve,
to be immortal because we would have
all this capacity to be immortal.
We would have these body's
capable of a mortality,
which let's say would be
evolutionarily demanding,
like to evolve anything like
an I or a brain or strong,
any, any quality. Lactase,
right? We, like we talked
about earlier, you,
you don't have lactase persistence
into adulthood because it's not needed.
So evolution doesn't waste anything.
There'd be no reason for that.
So there'd be no that would
be there would uh, there, uh,
there would be no reason the argument
goes to evolve in mortality because
inevitably some people would be
killed eventually by accidents anyway.
So unless you can create a world
in which there are no accidents,
there are no extrinsic causes of death,
it would be inefficient from an
evolutionary point of view to evolve in
mortality. So death, the
reason we die naturally,
some people think is that the reason we
dynamically is that there are unnatural
causes of death in the world,
like accidents.
If we could eliminate the unnatural
causes so that nowhere, no,
no time ever where we ever killed by
trees falling or lightening strikes or
things like that,
then actually over time we would
evolve to live indefinitely.
This is the theory. It's
crazy idea. It is fascinating.
But do you think that nature had
that sort of sort of foresight?
He was not a foresight,
but that's how natural selection works.
Think about like if I suddenly magically
transformed your body at great expense
to make you capable of immortality.
And then two days from now you're hit
by a bus. I've wasted all that effort.
But if you only done it to one person,
you wasted that effort.
If you did did it to other people,
you have the potential to
create an incredibly wise
person with a thousand years
of life and experience and education die.
He also had die.
So everyone eventually would die from
these extrinsic causes. So personal law,
well, no, that's, that's, that's
their assumption in the model.
If it's not perhaps if in
fact there are no extremes,
if in fact there is a world in which
you're never struck by lightning,
never hit by a bus, never
a tree branch, then uh,
then the theory is that we would
have evolved to be a mortal.
So it's almost like the law,
the life that you live,
you're inevitably going to get
killed by extrinsic causes. Yes.
If you extend that life to a thousand
years and it's absolutely going to happen,
therefore why bother?
That's just living in a bubble.
Just terrified of the world on
rocks. Lamberg and gentry. Yeah,
but you can't transport,
you can't take this theory.
And this model and apply to an
individual and an individual life.
It's about how our species evolved. It's
not about how you should live your life.
I mean it's also true. I don't think
you should live your life afraid.
I think that's a difficult, I think
that's a sad life. To live a life afraid.
It takes practice to be unafraid of,
you'd be more afraid if you could live
a thousand years without an accident.
You know? Cause if like if you're
one of those crazy rock climber,
dude's like Alex Honnold and he's crazy.
He's crazy. I love him though. He's told,
have you talked? Have you met him?
Yeah, I've had him on a couple of times.
Oh my God, he's awesome. I'm sure he
has his Amygdala. Of course he's a,
Migdal is fucked up. You know this, right?
He has no fear. Now he does have fear.
You're wrong. Oh really?
Absolutely. As fear.
He just understands his capacity
and his ability you think is rashly,
says I can do this,
therefore I should not be afraid cause
I read that he takes scanned his brain
and that his, his fear
centers are different than
the rest of us is what I read.
Maybe that's wrong.
I don't know.
Did he tell you he didn't
say anything about that? No,
I think he's using his patient.
I don't know about that.
He said basically that the experience,
he just stays mellow and calm and then
if things go wrong it's really bad.
Like you don't want to be freaking
out. Yes. It's so diverse.
You don't panic when you're underwater
and you lose your way. Right.
There was a consumes oxygen a lot mazing
story that my friend Donald Cerrone,
he's a UFC fighter told
about being trapped in a cave
and despegar watering out
when it was running out of oxygen.
Yeah. Horrible, crazy scary story.
And you have to, those guys are
also different. Either they,
either they're born that way
or they learn to be that way.
You have to keep calm because when
you and I lose our cool and start
hyperventilating,
our auction consumption skyrockets.
And that's the opposite of what
you need to do in that situation.
Actually what he talked about,
you know,
like trying to stay calm and battling
the demons not going to die like this.
Yeah. What an incredible story. Yeah.
The Alex Honnold thing I hear is
something, I watched the movie,
what it talks to him. He got an MRI and
they said that, what did it say? Yeah,
he's a, Migdal is different,
but what did it say?
How does it say the kids
Amygdala isn't firing. Yes. Okay.
But isn't that possible that that's
just through development of constant,
it is also possible calm while you
were in life threatening situations.
It's possible like to see fighters
brains measured in that regard.
I would like to see soldiers, well,
special forces guys. I think that's right.
And the guys a special force guys.
It's like the capacity to shoot back when
you're being shot at keeping your calm
moving positions, you know, and so forth.
Those are all very important to
abilities, not panicking. Uh,
but and it is also the case
that some people, for example,
the most famous study in this regard
was a study of London taxi drivers.
London taxi drivers can go from any point
in the city to any other point in the
city.
It's called the knowledge.
They have a mental map of the
whole city and it's freakish.
It takes years to be able to know how to
navigate the city with the thousands of
Nate,
tens of thousands of street names and
they can do it by like dead reckoning.
They a scan.
This was a paper about 10 years ago.
They brain scan these guys and they had,
I forgot what region of the brain,
but they had through learning it is
felt modify that region of the brain.
So it's possible. Holland is like you
say, that he learned to be this way.
That is a big deal isn't firing because
he trained himself but I handled,
handled, handled. I'm sorry handled
is this way because he learns well,
but it's more likely I think that he's
like Usain bolt that was born with the
credibly,
a high preponderance of fast twitch
fibers in his leg so he can run like the
wind and he trains as
well. You have both, right.
Good athletes require both innate ability
plus training and I think a Honnold is
probably like that.
He was probably born with an Amygdala.
It doesn't fire so much and
he's an amazing, uh, you know,
climber is purely speculative,
right? Like the, and they also,
the nature versus nurture would
apply to chess players as well.
I would like to see their brain scan like
w uh, Gary Kasparov. I know Gary. Yes.
I would love to see that. I
got a brain scan. Yes. Yeah.
He's an interesting guy to hit.
What I'll say. The article goes way
more into depth and night. Well,
I just showed you about,
okay. Just that sentence. She,
she's at the doctor who studied it was
specifically looks at people that go
under high stress and look
for those kinds of things.
She's been doing that since 2005, I
guess. And she goes, it's pages long.
This whole thing about his brain,
but it is unusual, but it also,
the amount of time, think about
people that are in high stress.
High stress is one thing.
This kid is in a life threatening
absolute fatality situation.
Mistake his death every
day. I know all day. I know.
I mean, he lives in a van and just
climbs. Yes. That's what he does.
It's really fascinating. Yes, it is. It
is. It's amazing. Honestly. It's amazing.
So I mean, I don't know. I'd
never met him. I admire him
very much. And I love this.
Like we said at the beginning, it's very
important to have skills of any kind.
So his skills are
amazing. Uh, admire music,
musical skills in carpentry skills
and martial arts skills and skills and
medical. I admire skills, you know, I
think it's in its worth cultivating. Yeah.
It's worth cultivating those skills.
So you find out more about
yourself through acquiring
these skills and knowledge
and information and just abilities.
Yes.
You learn and you also learn about
how to acquire skills. Yes. Yes,
I think that's right. And I think,
uh, and I think it's also a kind of,
you also find oftentimes that the,
the practice of acquiring the skill
teaches you other things that can then be
used in other areas. Yeah. So even
if you like, you know, like, uh,
like you make the effort to learn the
violin or to learn Chinese for example,
or whatever, you know, some effort, you,
that self discipline then
can be translated into even
just something that you're
not so good at it,
but it's still useful to have that.
That's the mia moto massage. He quote the
book from the Book of five rings once,
you know, the way broadly you see it in
all things. Yes. Yeah. That's very good.
Yeah. I remember at my mind is lashing
back to, we're talking about mortality.
Do you remember that scene at
a, at Helms Helms deep when, uh,
in the Lord of the rings when,
um, uh, they're protecting,
you know, the, the, uh,
the key to the castle and the
elves come and help the humans.
Do you know the movie? Probably
know the, yeah. And I was,
I was very sad when these elves were
killed because if they hadn't been killed
by extrinsic forces, they would
have lived a long time. Uh,
they would have been immortal. So it's
like a, especially sad loss. Anyway,
I had wanted to mention that earlier
when we were talking about that thing.
So now what was the saying again?
You just said about once, you know,
the way broadly you'll see it in all
things. Yes, that's right. Yeah. Yeah.
It was just about acquiring excellence
in something that you understand what it
takes to acquire excellence in something
and you can apply that to other things
as well. It's the same process, just a
different path. Yes, that's right. Well,
listen, Nicholas, thank you so much
for being here. Thank you so much.
I can't wait to read this book.
I'm going on vacation,
so I'm going to read this
with me. All right. And, uh,
some of the stories at the beginning,
I really did. Thank you so much,
so much for having me. Shit.
I've been really grateful.
Thanks man. Thanks so much.
Bye everybody.