The powerful Dom Arrera is here.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I am typing that shit as I talk to you.
That's why I seem like I'm slow.
But I wrote,
damn,
I rera see that.
Damn I that I very character.
Why did he get off at the soda?
Like I told him pill.
John,
my rarer is uh,
one of my favorite human
beings on the planet,
but he also drives a car
from many decades ago.
Has No,
it is an antique.
Now I'll tell you what,
that car,
would it be worth a lot of money to like
a young upcoming comic if they found
out they could get ahold of Don.
My rare is Lexis.
Well,
you know it was,
I called it the share cause I was on
tour with Sherra and I got all this extra
cash and it's summer.
So I go in and buy a car.
I said a guy,
I'll give you 40,
$40,000.
He goes,
I can't do that.
And I said,
all right,
it goes,
wait,
come back.
I said,
that's what I'm going to give you.
I can just got a brand new Honda.
I don't need Alexis.
I just want one cause it's cool.
Then went let me talk to my friends and
he comes back because you know I like
you.
I'd go,
we just met me.
That's amazing.
I wonder are what quick
wonderful relationship.
This is.
Then I got the car.
I paid cash.
Yeah,
that's a,
that's a war horse of a fucking car,
but Don Maria has no goddamn
navigation system in that thing,
but it looks beautiful.
I listened to the ground like it's
like an Indian scout dumped them.
I'm feeling the wheels beneath my feet.
All radio.
That's an evil work and fix it.
I had my radio break once and it fucking,
I thought up more shit that day.
Then and then any other day I like I
should break my radio all the time.
The biggest drag or that car
is it only has a tape deck.
Oh no it does.
It's really hard to get tapes.
I went into a place and they have no
tapes left.
That is Goddamn hilarious.
You have a tape deck,
but all these other cars I've got it.
I've got a brand new Cadillac
for leasing and all that.
Something went wrong with him.
This one,
nothing stops it.
Well,
you know those Lexus's
or fucking bulletproof.
You want us as bulletproof time?
I remember.
Oh and and it get yourself
some bulletproof coffee.
Mix it up with fresh butter that comes
from grass fed cows and the only way to
go on some MCT oil.
Could you repeat that
because I didn't get that.
This
is a complicated advertisement.
Okay.
onnit.com o n n I t would you need to do
is get some shroom tech sport and your
lifetime Herrera said what?
Shroom tech support.
Oh yeah.
Shouldn't text book.
I just read out.
You need to get some,
I'll give you some alpha Bray too.
I actually have a gift pack for you Jamie.
This is own little boxes in
their little gold on it boxes.
I have getting gifts for everybody that
magic podcasts now we give them an honor
gift pack and in the honor gift pack
that has all sorts of groupie shit
including Buffalo Jerky made
with real cranberry hungry.
No,
no,
no.
Hepped up on.
None of these things will get you higher,
but a,
the Alpha brain will definitely,
hopefully,
if it works for you,
it works for almost everybody.
But I believe people,
when they say it has no effect on him.
I absolutely believe them.
I don't know how you're
fucking dumb marks.
I don't even understand how mind works.
But I do know that
every single ingredient,
if you go to onnit.com
there's a whole page.
It's a based on the science behind all
of these supplements and all of it has
been shown to increase memory
or a aid and test scores.
It's,
they're all just essentially nutrients
that help cognitive function.
It's a very controversial thing
and because it's controversial,
we want to treat this thing like as
evenly and as honestly and as morally as
possible.
It's kind of hard to do
when you run a business,
but the idea behind on it is
a real genuine and honest one.
And it's to try to sell you
the best shit possible at,
at a very reasonable price and make
it so that no one feels ripped off.
And one of the ways we do that is we have
a 90 day 100% money back guarantee on
the first 30 pills of
whether it's Alpha brain,
a shroom tech.
If you try it,
you,
you know,
you use it,
you don't feel like it was,
it had an effect on you
get your money back,
you're going to have
to return the product.
No one's trying to rip you off,
but we're,
what we are doing is selling you the
best shit possible that we actually use
ourselves.
I actually use Alpha brain,
shroom tech,
new mood.
I use these daily hemp force.
I eat that shit daily.
I use all this stuff
unless you use a lot of it.
Yeah,
it was a battle rope workout.
Anyway,
go to [inaudible] dot com using code
any Rogan and save yourself 10% off.
Have you been playing that fucking game?
We played actually play it.
I play it on the toilet.
I have an Ipad,
uh,
now my toilet that I used an old iPad.
So there's an image I'd
like to get out of my head.
Yeah.
Well,
I,
um,
if you play it on the toilet,
I mean you've gotta be real
careful of those legs getting,
yeah.
I'm more concerned about the
hemorrhoid that it created.
That's how I got it.
I hemorrhoid you have hemorrhoids.
It comes from forcing things.
Is that what hammer was
sitting on the toilet too long?
I,
I sit on the toilet like all the time,
but his social life.
Huh?
It's comfortable.
It's warm.
Not have a lot of lettuce in his diet.
I'm sure.
No rough.
She shits or a struggle so much.
Each one's a battle.
Tell me about it a lot.
I,
I poop all the time.
Do you?
Yeah.
This try,
this coffee is just like
two poops waiting to happen.
Well that's good.
The one you're not pooping,
you've got a real problem.
Right?
I was watching this show
the other day and uh,
oh,
is Anthony Bourdain's show and
it was on a Philadelphia and uh,
he was,
uh,
it's,
um,
his other show,
you know,
he's got those two different shows.
Uh,
the one of them is called the
layover and it was that one and a,
one of the things in Philadelphia,
they went to this museum where they
had this guy would a gigantic colon and
sometimes it would be like
six to 10 days in between.
Shifts is getting shit for like
six days as colon was enormous.
It was disgusting.
So don't let that happen.
But they find out that
he had enormous colon.
Um,
well he was,
he was distended like as he was alive,
he looked disgusting.
They like,
it was really horrendous looking.
And um,
they uh,
they saved it in this museum.
It's a museum of all like
fucked up body anomalies.
I have a friend who used
to think it was manly,
not the pay and they would drink beer.
He drink like a 10 pack
of beer and hey listen,
this is crazy.
He got a distended bladder from it and it,
it has no resiliency to now
he has to use a catheter.
So every time it's so fucking sad.
Broke his bladder.
He didn't break it.
He distended it.
So it's so scratched out,
but it can't hold water again.
So he just has to use a call mark.
He imagined himself all the fucking
things that happened to us in life.
He did it to himself,
you know,
was he thought he was like Spartacus,
not pay it and that made them strong.
Wow.
That's uh,
that's kind of an
interesting approach to life.
Just talking about backfire.
I think I should have beat
that has nothing to do with
don would playing blades
slinger while you're on the toilet.
I see that kerosene games is one of our
new sponsors and they have this new game
called blade runner or blade slinger.
I keep it same blade runner,
two combination.
It's played slinger,
goddammit.
Um,
it's pretty dope.
The,
the graphics are amazing.
It's that is,
that's the actual graphics of the game.
I mean it is really well done and it's
not a game that's ported over from a
computer.
They designed them
specifically for the IPAD,
iPhone interface,
the way it works with no buttons and
touchscreen and everything like that.
So everything works intuitively with that.
It's a fun fucking game.
And it's,
it's a really good deal too.
It's only 299 to 99 and,
and it's a,
it's,
it's fun to apply and kerosene games,
um,
their,
their whole gold,
their whole mission is to make the
coolest video games available specifically
for mobile devices.
So that's what they're working on.
Who does the main character looked like?
It looks like you Jamie.
Get at it.
It looks like you bitch.
One of the Jamie,
Jamie,
Jamie employee number two.
Oh,
okay.
Anyway,
blade slinger.
Um,
go get it on.
on the IPAD.
You can get it on the iPhone and uh,
they're working on a version
of it for android apparently.
But a do not says Eta January,
February high end,
android devices as well.
Back to galaxy s three.
The galaxy has three from 10,
if you've been playing with it.
Yeah,
I love it.
The,
the map,
I tell you,
man,
there's,
there's only,
there's a few things that android
has going for it for sure.
Especially the galaxy s three
and one is the Google maps.
Like just having Google maps back,
the original application that's
not on the iPhone anymore.
It's so nice.
And on the Google or
the the galaxy s three,
the screen's so big and you had like,
Oh nice maps,
big screen.
It's,
but you know,
I'm still playing with it.
I don't know if it's just because I'm
so used to the iPhone for the last five
years using the same operating system or
if it's just like everything is set up
so nice.
It's very,
very intuitive.
On the iPhone I find like although
a android phones I really like,
um,
they can be a bit like windows or once
you know where the fuck everything is,
yeah,
everything's cool.
But before then it's like,
yeah,
why is it here?
I would never see this
doing are the fuck is that.
I definitely would never go,
hey mom,
get a,
get an android over an iPhone.
Because it is like,
like,
oh,
you have to figure that
shit out this defrag.
Well you would if you wanted
her to call you and need you.
Right.
You're like real needy.
You would tell him to
get an android phone.
That's true.
Just so you have to give
her advice all the time.
Yeah.
Anyway,
my advice to you go
getting played slinger.
Yeah.
Get it for the IPAD.
Um,
and uh,
support this cool game company.
Kerosene games because they support
the podcast and it's only two 99.
My advice to you is you
don't need segways Mr. Yeah.
I'm a master at this shit come naturally.
They flow right.
Next week is when I am releasing
my standup special next Tuesday,
the 18th.
So,
uh,
I finally got it all together.
Uh,
I know it took a long ass time.
It took a lot longer than I
thought it was going to take,
but thanks everybody for your patience
and even the people that asked about it.
No one was being douchey about it,
but it was,
yeah,
I agree.
I mean I recorded it in April.
It's finally coming out.
Is this the just the standup special
or is there any extra bonus feature?
Some other shit too,
but as of right now,
like it's just a standup special material
and a release that you did last night.
If some of that in that.
No,
that's all new stuff.
I thought that was
fucking killer last night.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
You've got dry.
Really new stuff.
You got the fucking
crime and no vagina joke.
That's groundbreaking.
Well,
thanks man.
Last night was fun as Fuck Don.
My rare is here.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the end of the commercials.
Use the code a Brogan
and go fuck yourself,
Tom.
I rera is here.
God dammit set up a bit old school.
I can't believe I found the place.
One of the greats,
God dammit,
the Joe Rogan experience.
Try by day Joe Rogan podcast all day.
If a one hour into the podcast,
Brian becomes a bundle of energy
and super duper talkative.
It may or may not be because he got
ahold of some provigil provigil.
Provigil may or may not be.
What's that?
Some stuff that keeps you awake?
I was told to tell me that
the way he looked at me like,
oh boy,
I don't need that.
Like that's one of the worst
things you could ever do to me,
Jo.
Yeah,
that's the thing about Comedians,
man.
We'd love to get us sleep on.
Well,
I mean speed would kill me.
Yeah.
I like down.
So I like tranquilizers.
If I was going to do any drug,
I would do heroin.
But what,
from what they say,
it feels like Robert Schimmel told me
he accidentally took Adderall once.
He,
uh,
I guess it was someone he thought it was
one of his pills after he had his heart
condition.
He had cancer and cancer,
cancer and he had a
heart condition as well.
Right.
It was having a hard problems,
you know,
um,
whatever he was on,
whatever medication he is on,
he accidentally take someone else's
Adderall while he was worried.
But his doctor said he would help,
would be okay.
You know,
like you said,
you like what is the,
what's the pill that you took?
How many milligrams?
You're going to be fine.
It's just going to take a while.
Just go get them.
He's done.
So he let run it around his house.
He's be organized.
His office,
he said he organized all of his notes
and put them in alphabetical order,
like doing shit that he
would never do without it.
It makes you think like,
man,
if you could,
uh,
if you could manage that correctly,
if you were a confident that you
could manage that Adderall stuff,
it seems like you get a
lot of shit done on that.
It coffee gets me high.
Oh,
it definitely does.
Yeah.
I mean that's what it looks.
Especially Starbucks.
I mean,
that's why this stuff is a everywhere.
Everybody's addicted to this stuff.
That was that last night I had two
drinks and I couldn't interview you.
You get an Mba.
We were fun.
It was fun.
It's fun.
But I was,
I had to think,
you know,
usually,
I mean with you it's like just flows.
But I'm telling you the two
drinks affecting me ever since.
I said I stopped drinking.
I started,
I said,
I thought you stopped drinking.
I did.
I Sat,
but I do.
I stopped drinking and then I have a
couple drinks every night almost to
celebrate my sobriety and that's,
that's what happens.
I get higher because
I don't drink as much.
And I had those two Irish coffees.
I was,
I was fucking,
how many days a week are you
back to drinking a seven?
I actually didn't,
I didn't drink on Monday.
And I told my God,
my God daughter who lives with me,
I go in,
I quit drinking again.
She said,
uh,
it's only Tuesday.
You drink Sunday.
I was like,
I'm over the whole day.
So yeah,
that's a tough one.
Yeah.
He only stopped drinking on hangovers.
You,
you did really well
for several months.
Three months.
And then what happened?
I Dunno,
it just checking those keys.
Dumb.
Sorry,
those keys are on that table.
I'm,
no one will forget.
You just missed it.
I missed it.
I missed the fun.
And you know,
one of the girls that left
factory friend of mine,
she said to me,
she called me like basically a pussy,
right?
Right on my Juliet.
And she says,
uh Oh,
what are you?
Are you going to have a
couple drinks with me tonight?
Are you going to show me a
chip for how long gets bitch?
You quit drinking.
You know what I mean?
Like what a friend,
another friend I played ping pong
with and he goes and he'll go,
he'll put a Martini and then my nose.
Doesn't that look good?
Like I have just the opposite
of supportive friends.
I have Fred to try and get me to drink.
It's like a reverse intervention.
Why do they do that?
I don't know.
Just for fun.
I mean if it didn't bloat me.
And do you get hangovers?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Okay.
And last all day now for me and
he started like the whole day,
like I'll have a hangover at
like 10 o'clock at night and go,
all right,
I guess I'm ready.
Drinks just to get rid of
you.
Gotta you gotta really over hydrate.
That's the key.
When you kicked it on,
water's good.
It's very good for that.
When,
when you,
when you feel that headache,
that's,
that's mostly dehydration.
I don't get a headache.
I get nervous.
You get nervous,
like anxiety,
heart palpitations.
No,
just like,
I don't know.
Well you realize you're
killing your body slower.
Yeah.
You know,
that's the feeling.
Like you realize your impending doom.
That's a danger.
Be a comedian too.
Cause you can fucking live the life
of a degenerate and then be fine by 10
o'clock at night.
And let's be honest about,
I mean,
how much,
how much sobriety is required in our jobs.
You know,
I,
you can go on,
have fucked up and have a great set.
I can go on drunk and not even
remember to set and just go on wrote.
I mean,
I hate to do that,
but if I have,
I've done so much
standup that I could get.
I literally,
I don't even really from a Hammock,
I never,
um,
I remember watching
people when I was younger,
phone it in and we've all seen guys
phone it in where they're not really
engaging in what they're saying
and not really thinking about it.
And I don't like to do that.
It's weird.
It's weird when you see it,
you know,
it's weird when you see it.
And it's weird when it happens to you too,
and maybe sometimes it doesn't
always happen to you on PR,
like especially starting out
and developing like along
the way you kind of like
realize like,
well that's set went great.
What did I do different?
And this set didn't go as good.
What did I do wrong?
But I remember Rah Ray
Romano got offset it.
Uh,
we,
I worked with him at Jimmy's comedy alley.
[inaudible] said,
I love that place.
Yeah.
I middled for Ray Romano back in the day.
It was awesome.
He was a great guy too.
What does a great guy,
he's such a sweetheart.
He hates to follow anybody's drunk,
but he was great about it though.
He was so funny,
man.
He was so goddamn good.
But anyway,
he got off stage.
I mean,
he just crushed for 45 minutes.
I absolutely destroyed.
And then he got off to a job wound that
was about the most autopilot I've ever
been.
Really just walked right through that one.
It's like he just,
he goes,
I totally found it in and
they fucking bought it.
Hook,
line and sinker.
It was hilarious.
Benefit with him for Peter Boyles,
uh,
you know,
his wife started a cancer fund,
the research thing,
and Ray,
uh,
you know,
it comes up to me.
It's so funny.
Our lives,
he goes,
can I ask you a question?
May sound a little awkward.
I go,
why?
He goes,
did you talk about your balls at all?
Like,
I want to know why it goes,
Oh,
I've got a ball bit I wanted to do,
but I don't want to talk
about balls again if you did.
Thanks for checking in with me.
Right.
I appreciate it.
Yeah.
God,
did you ever have that with guys?
Like they say,
oh,
sorry,
I didn't know that you talked to
that and you know,
yeah,
of course.
I don't give a fuck.
Do you give a fuck?
I didn't like,
no,
I don't care if I tell you what I took.
I did a bit that Johnny Sanchez did
and I knew that I had to have heard it
subconsciously because I swear
to God and Johnny knows me.
He knows I wouldn't take it,
but it was too specific was about
Mesopotamia and Persia and Babylonia.
Like it had too many rings
to it that I thought John,
he goes,
no,
do it.
Like go,
I'm not going to do it.
Cause I know I had to like I could've
been sitting upstairs the laugh factory,
not even paying attention.
Heard it in my mind.
You know what I mean?
That's the dangerous somebody didn't
cause sometimes it's not malicious.
Sometimes it's that weird thing where
you're working with a guy and they have a
bit that's on the same
subject as your bed,
but it's a different bit like all the
sudden your friend has a time machine bit
but old out of nowhere.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You're like,
okay,
yeah.
Well that's not my bed.
Yeah.
Yours is a def.
Definitely a different bit,
but you're going to do a time machine
bit right before I do a time machine bit
that's,
yeah,
I've seen that on the road where
you have the Middle Act to do,
I'm going to lack the next night.
All of a sudden has same subject matter.
He wrote anything on your material,
uh,
guys who,
open for you when they're doing that shit.
It's so gross,
so transparent,
you know,
and I hate to tell people what to do,
before the subject matter.
I feel like so,
but you can't,
you cannot,
it's just to you,
you know,
when someone's got
actual bits and you know,
when someone is just trying to step
on a step on the subject matter,
it's a weird thing that people do when
they get competitive with the other acts
that they're working with.
And it just ruins the whole vibe.
Like if you go on the road with people
and everybody's having a good time and
everybody wants everybody else to do well,
that's like a great feeling when you're
working with a guy and he wants you to
eat it.
And so he's trying to like bury you.
He's trying to do shit to burry you.
That's a weird feeling.
Even imagine that way.
I won't guy that did that to me.
Yeah.
And a New Jersey and he just kept
trying to fuck me and I could tell,
you know what I mean?
It's just,
yeah,
that's the area for it.
I had,
mine was in Philly,
my worst case examples in Philly.
I had this whole bit about Madonna and
this dude did the bit in front of me and
use Janet Jackson.
Oh,
like did the exact same bit.
I mean it was the same number.
You called her a whore in it.
No,
a tall,
beautiful human being.
Oh,
okay.
We're called the wrong bit.
No,
it was,
uh,
it was just about watching the videos.
A stupid joke.
I don't even remember
the exact wording of it.
And watching a video on Madonna video
while my girlfriend was in the room and
having to feel dumb questions.
Like if you had to choose our enemy,
I'm like,
Jack,
I want you to be honest.
And they choke.
It's like I would fuck her in front
of you over your mother's house on the
kitchen table with her
ass and your corn flakes.
So it was a stupid joke,
but this dude had the exact same
joke the next day with Janet Jackson.
I'm like,
well that's crazy.
Like you just stole that joke.
And it was,
I didn't know,
you know,
back in the day,
I didn't really know exactly how it,
how you dealt with that.
I had enough material
that it didn't matter.
I didn't have to do it.
It was like already phasing that bit out.
But I thought it was crazy.
This guy had like two or three bits.
All of the sudden they were on the
same subjects and one of them was like
basically the same exact
joke and just reworded it.
Did you ever throw something away and
somebody picks it up and runs with it?
I had like a thing where I was talking
about I'm not a racist unless I'm in
traffic,
then I become a racist,
you know,
it's gotta be a fucking
Chink in front of me.
I know it's gotta be a chink broad.
Right.
And I drive with,
see it is,
it's like,
why would you ever throw that away?
Well,
I,
Gee,
I don't know.
But anyway,
there's an act at the,
at the,
uh,
plant factor now.
His whole first five minutes is
about that in a racist and traffic.
So,
wow.
And he heard you talk about this.
He had to hear it.
That's,
that's really pathetic.
Pathetically like motivated.
I've seen guys do that.
I've seen guys take a bit that someone
else said in a conversation and all of a
sudden they,
well,
what they don't understand
is that a lot of times,
like when you say
something in conversation,
you might have already
said it on stage or you,
you know,
if you have like a point
of view on something,
it might be something you've already
been working on for a long time.
And if you lay out the
premise like that to a guy,
like that's,
it's just as bad as stealing material.
Right?
But you know,
some things you can't steal.
Like when you were doing the
two bits about your daughter,
it's so vivid.
Like you can see that that's a,
I mean,
yeah,
but you know,
I'm not going to tell you that.
That's what makes it so funny,
but it's like perfectly executed in the
sense that you see her and you see you
and hear you.
You know,
not,
not just the banana thing,
but the second thing is fucking hilarious
because it brings you in to something
that's,
that's what people hopefully can't
steal is your essence and your,
your own,
your own life.
You know,
if somebody starts talking
about my cousin Johnny,
I know they stole from me.
I know they can fuck
around and dance around.
Yeah.
Shit but,
but this is a weird thing with being
influenced by people versus stealing from
people because yeah,
we're all influence is like
we didn't get here on our own.
None of us get her on her own.
I think what we would,
everybody is always concerned with
though is like the honesty of where these
ideas are coming from.
Like you're taking
ideas from other people.
The whole vibe of what you're doing is
completely different because they're like
the vibe of a standup comedian.
Like what I love about say a guy like you
when you're on stage and you're killin
is I know that this is your
mind putting all this together.
I know this is like any individual's
point of view and expression and I lock
into it and have a great
time with your thoughts.
But as soon as I think that you're
just parroting someone else's words,
as soon as I think that this isn't
something that you've absorbed,
this isn't a part of you as a human,
this is,
these aren't your actual thoughts.
These aren't your actual conclusions.
Right.
This is just you saying some shit.
Well then you lose,
you lose a big chunk of
that connection then.
Then you,
then we have a bullshit relationship.
There's no soul to it.
I was watching a guy last week and he
really was stuck in the 80s and really
stuck,
you know,
for witness without being able
to budge and he was just doing,
he had nothing,
had any heart too.
It was just like,
it Kinda like Rodney did.
It's so extreme that it was funny.
You knew that it was a character.
You knew it was jokes and it was funny
because his character is so brilliant.
This guy was trying to
act like it was him,
but it was jokey jokes.
Do you know what I mean?
It was bizarre and I thought,
okay,
would you put that away?
What happened is a video of me
and I was like 20 years old.
This is so crazy.
Somebody just like,
I just remember
Dama rare from full frontal comedy.
So I'm like,
I wonder if I can find that
clip and I just hold it up.
Show on full random.
Aye
did it with dumb.
I've never seen this before.
Oh,
it's terrible.
Don't you dare still leans
forward when he screamed.
Flexibility.
Waste.
Oh Wow.
This is crazy.
I love it.
Is Do you know Joe?
I don't know.
It's probably terrible though.
Whatever it is.
And something involved with a penis.
Don't turn it Brian.
Stop it.
Do not.
Last thing I want to hear is my oldest
fuck outta here with that here a minute.
One minute and go to Google.
Go Youtube it yourself.
I don't listen to myself,
man.
The last thing,
even my special,
like I didn't listen
to it until last week.
I would like a a day to,
uh,
to edit it and I watched it
for the first time that night.
Yeah.
I don't like watching myself.
I don't either.
I like,
I do it for the purposes
of working on material.
Like I'll listen to the recordings and
I do learn shit when I watch myself.
Like what,
what I think is more effective,
like what pauses are more effective
or moves and more effective,
like,
and you can incorporate what you,
you figure it out from watching yourself.
But it's like,
it takes away from a lot of the
fun of the improvisation of it all.
Yeah.
I don't want to watch myself.
Do you mind if we watch?
No.
Well you might step it out for a minute.
I cannot wait to watch it.
I just,
I'd never seen that before.
You kill up in Montreal.
Dom and I became friends because,
uh,
we did.
Uh,
we did,
what was it called?
What was,
it might've been called the danger zone.
Danger zone from the danger
zone or something like that.
Uh,
it was in Montreal at the club Soda.
Yeah.
And that was the first
time I met you with it.
Yeah.
That was my first like real TV credit,
I think.
I think I did.
He did MTV half hour comedy
hour before that and then I,
but I didn't really care about
that one cause I couldn't swear.
You know,
so I want to do a real one.
That was like my first real set and
then dom and I met again an Amsterdam
billiards and that's when we fell in love.
Yet we found out that we played pool.
Dom and I played pool.
We were regulars at a set of
established that will remain unnamed.
Look at that guy,
young chap from 19 it's
like I got a wig on it.
Look at the fucking moves.
He's got stomach three
it'd be 64 inches long.
I don't even remember that.
Right about this guy.
He got hit by two trains in one day.
Listen,
listen,
we don't have to do that to you.
Isn't it weird like seeing a
recorded version of yourself?
I was like 50 pounds lighter
with the big head of hair.
Dom Irrera listen.
Well we need to do is get
you a podcast first of all.
I got a podcast.
Yeah,
been on it.
I know,
I know.
Listen,
let me finish.
When you have a podcast,
what I'm saying is we need to get you
a podcast that just deals with you not
drinking.
All right,
I'll podcasts where you just,
you get all or any,
any like momentum you have,
any motivation that you have to drink,
any like release a podcast about it.
Release a podcast about why you want to
go have a drink or why you don't want to
have a drink.
And I think people would be absolutely
fascinated by the struggle of it all.
Cause you're very open about it.
You're very honest about it.
Every time you've come on the podcast
when you haven't drank and you were
telling me how great your
field and then now you're like,
Eh,
it's too fucking fun shit.
I'll be your cohost.
And I try not to judge told the,
you know,
like in a young Frankenstein when
gene wilder says no matter what,
I say don't do not open that door.
And he walks in to talk to the monster.
Remember that?
Yeah.
Well,
I said to Noel last night
at the laugh factory said,
do not give me a drink,
another drink.
Are there any circumstances?
I come back 10 minutes later
I'll take another drink.
He goes,
I don't know what to do.
You just told me that to give it to.
I said,
forget about what?
don't you gotta listen to me.
I'm a drunk.
You can't.
Um,
um,
I mean you can't keep like seesaw on like
that and I think maybe doing a podcast
would be a good catharsis.
Well,
a good sort of a method to try to
stay sober if you really want to.
I mean,
if you don't want to look,
I would never try to go to Stan
hope and tell him a sober up.
She hasn't.
Why can't imagine him sober?
He doesn't want to do it.
If he wanted any.
And if you wanted to do it,
he could do it.
He can do it anytime he wanted to.
He could.
He could do it tomorrow if you want it to.
He couldn't.
Mitch Hedberg was the one
I tried to reach out to.
Really?
Yeah.
Because he,
you know,
he was killing him,
so obviously,
but I mean,
you know,
I didn't know he was doing heroin well.
I was worried.
I think statistically
heroin safer than alcohol.
Really?
Yeah.
I think,
um,
I think alcohol is a,
it's a really dangerous shit.
We just don't think it's
dangerous because it's everywhere.
It crushes your immune system,
but it also makes you feel great too.
I've got a couple of whiskeys,
senior sweet home.
Alabama comes on me.
I think that's the secret is
going back to beer for me.
I think I need to just go,
I used to only drink beer then I just
got on this Jack Daniels kick out of
nowhere and I'm just like,
why am I drinking so much jack?
I could through almost
75% of bottled and no,
I think gunfighter in the old west.
Yeah.
I drink like whiskey now.
Me Too.
That was that about,
I like it.
It makes me feel like I'm alive.
I love that feeling down your throat.
Whoa.
Yeah.
I had a shot last weekend before
I went on stage and Seattle.
I did that.
A parlor live,
if you have to do that place up there,
it's quick right club.
They uh,
that area of Seattle,
Washington,
it's called Bellevue to a suburb
is fucking beautiful out there.
It's so beautiful.
Northwest.
It's incredible.
And it's so like,
it's all like,
it's very like high end
stores and Nice area.
I guess that's where like
Microsoft is or something to,
Huh?
Shit.
Load of that paper up there.
Mercer island making that big paper.
What's Mercer Island?
That's an island up there.
My girlfriend from college lives.
Yeah.
Really?
She lives on an island.
I still go out there
and give it one feeling.
Put a theme,
that graph offer for college.
It's still slam it to,
I know she imagined.
She looks much older than me now.
That's,
you know,
it's sad.
We get so program like no
matter what I look like,
I,
I still,
I can't get a fucking hard on
unless the chicks young and hot,
I'm done.
I thought,
you know what I mean,
I'm fucking done.
People would call you shallow.
I have to go to another country.
I am shallow,
shallow,
like I don't care.
You know,
I don't care what it girls accomplished.
I care about her looks.
I don't care what you got.
What a phd in philosophy.
Talk to me baby.
I'm hard as a rock.
You not sexually right.
Not Sexually.
I mean I,
I'd be interested in the person.
Yeah,
there's that quote.
Um,
fuck who said that quote,
goddammit.
I forget who it was,
but he said,
um,
all I need from a woman
is to be attracted to her.
Everything else I get from him,
man.
I think it was George Harrison.
Really?
Yeah,
I think it was George Harrison said that.
I think I've always
attributed to George Harrison,
but it did Google and I couldn't find it,
but I remember reading
it somewhere really,
really a pretty positive.
It's him.
It's as a whole bit about it.
He has a whole bit about,
um,
like a that like if you really
wanted to hang out with somebody,
you know,
if he was on a deserted island,
he would want it to be a woman.
Cause cause he gets fucking
bored of talking to her.
You know he's not compatible like yeah.
If you want to be attracted to a
woman like unfortunately for the male
reproductive system and we get our bodies
get triggered by young fertile women.
It's an amazing hell interesting.
They'd become like a leave so
stupid and I find it riveting.
Fuck,
he never said an original
thing in your life.
It's just so crazy that are,
our bodies are like programmed
to that where rationally your,
your consciousness,
the idea is like if we're going to evolve,
your consciousness should be able to
look at that and go I have nothing in
common with his 23 year olds drive.
What I need to be doing is dating at 50
year old woman like myself and you know,
and go out and enjoy our
last year's together.
Let's go get a beer.
But you if you,
you know,
the problem is like if you were
still in the sex and he's still,
your body unfortunately wants that.
It does shape body.
Dick does not lie.
It did.
It's like you feel so shallow and heart.
The I seriously am shallow.
I mean,
I pride myself on my shallow,
shallow in a year or whatever it is.
Michelle,
this lack of depth with this,
the girls that are easy on the eyes
are never easy on the heart though.
Oh,
beautiful.
You are
good reads you the eyes.
I say unto Thee Brian,
year before our balls,
the fucking lecturer frick you.
No,
you're fucking toilet seat.
Beauty on the eyes.
I love it.
Okay.
So have you been in starting to come out?
Have you been in love twice today?
No.
I mean real love where you
live and eat and sleep.
Yeah.
I fall,
I fall deeper in love
really fast actually.
So that's,
yeah.
You don't,
no,
no I don't.
I mean I have been like Kinda
married four times in my life,
but only you get married once,
but yeah,
Dom's been in some situations before.
He's had some struggle.
Well,
the CRA,
the one extra person.
Horrible.
Craziest.
I can't even do that.
That the whole thing with the
house and all that other number.
How many of them had green cards?
Yeah,
yeah.
How many had green cards?
Time?
They were all,
uh,
citizens.
I was proud to say
not of the United States,
but do you feel bad for like a
chick that has to date a comedian?
Like for the most part,
like why would you want to
date crazy fucking comedian?
Because comedians are like some of
the brightest people I've ever met.
So I think that,
see that's the difference.
We're just going back to,
they find that attractive.
You can get women because they are,
uh,
they're just shallow in
a different way there.
They,
you know,
they,
they couldn't be with a
guy who just a good guy,
they have to laugh,
you know,
especially like,
like these models.
I remember working at the river cafe
when I was parking cars and the models,
nobody asks them out because
there were too fucking hot.
Right.
So they were alone all the time,
you know,
and like they,
nobody was attracted to them or no,
I guess people were afraid of them,
you know,
they just didn't want to get shot down.
They didn't think they were.
Yeah.
Have you ever been in that
situation before where girls,
you just felt like a girl was too good
for you and you couldn't even try?
I,
I'm that thick.
No,
never.
Even when you were in Denver,
you know,
I tried everything and I've gotten girls
way out of my league just being funny
and honesty.
Well,
you've been a comedian
for so fucking long to,
it's like you probably
don't know her weight.
You probably don't remember what it's
like to just be a out there in the free
world.
But I was,
I was like better looking then I was
better as I got less good looking,
my,
I got richer and more famous.
Right.
You know what I mean?
So it kind of balanced off,
you know what I'm saying?
If you go to like a third world country,
you'll press the Fuckos Kailand I'm big,
big dial in.
I think with the kids.
I enjoy it though.
I mean,
I,
I w you know what,
we've talked about this
a long time ago and I,
you know about how hard it is as a
comedian and especially when you go on the
road and you know,
cause I try not to do
anything with the waitresses,
waitstaff,
seriously.
I,
so I'd rather have like a,
you know,
if I'm going to be with somebody,
I'd rather it be like a,
uh,
some nut from the box in the supermarket.
It comes to the show.
But the,
for them,
like it's a thrill to get a guy
like Tom Herrera cause like,
oh this crazy ass holes coming into town.
You get to toss their world
upside down for a couple of days,
give her a kiss on the cheek and,
and you don't name drop,
you don't Brag and name drop.
They love that.
They love when you don't.
How come you didn't tell me that?
Well I don't think come up,
you know what I mean?
Like it's a very,
it's an interesting kind of trick
because you really like Whoa,
withholding the bragging to make you look,
you know,
humble brags seriously.
If you ever seen humble brags on Twitter.
It's a really funny,
I'm in the humble brag book.
You're in the book.
I said something like,
are you serious?
Just published his book
and somebody's like,
dude,
you're in this book.
That's hilarious.
What is that though?
Is that a website or not?
It's like a Twitter tag.
Humblebrag when someone
says something like,
wow,
I can't believe I got
nominated for this today.
I totally didn't expect this.
You know what I mean?
Well,
yeah,
you just letting everybody know you
got nominated with your like fake self
deprecating booze shit.
I hear this right here.
It says,
uh,
so Thursday I met John Mayer.
Friday I met 50 cent this rate at this
rate tonight I'm smoking weed with Jim
Morrison and Terry Shiloh.
That was at a homeless on a hump.
Their kindness.
I truly don't get what this means.
What does it has the cadence,
what does it say?
It has the cadence.
It's cut off whoever took this picture,
but it really doesn't stack up well.
Whoever wrote that dumb,
you're dumb person.
You don't,
you don't understand what he's saying.
He's a regular guy who
met some famous people.
You fuck,
I truly,
during Tet with this with me,
it means you're a cunt.
Yeah.
I met John when you're doing comedy,
which was we was doing comedy
at the store for a while.
John Mayer.
Yeah.
You asked me about Connie Mcshane.
Paul's,
yeah,
that's right.
Yeah.
Louis C K scary.
We used to do is thing in Montreal.
It was so fucking funny where
I literally used to love it.
Oh Shit.
That's,
is that your phone?
Your phone is the Beatles,
but he got a bad song.
I was like,
damn,
dom Irrera sorry.
He's got one of them old flip phones to,
Oh,
I got an iPhone.
I got the first $5.
It has no navigation up in that car.
Has No idea where he's going.
I had to text him directions.
God helped the people that were behind
him as he was reading that shit.
People are twittering,
tweeting.
Oh,
there you have it set up so
that when people tweet to you,
it goes to your phone.
I don't know that it's not good.
Daughter did it worse.
Do you want to change that right now?
Because these fucking animals just found
that shit out to kill your battery.
Better.
Shut your phone off son
or change your settings.
Yeah.
Shut that shit off.
Cause when it's going to explode,
when it comes back on,
they just found out they could get you.
People just found out they could reach
you with just a tweet.
Do you understand that?
That's insane.
You can't let them do that.
You know when I first got your
phone will explode about Israel.
No,
you just got back,
right?
I didn't go,
but I didn't go.
Everybody in my family this,
you know when it peaked,
right?
Remember when it peaked like the,
the danger and they said they didn't up.
There's going to be a war and then
they started the bombs hit Tel Aviv and
Jerusalem for the first time in 40 years.
I remember that.
Yes.
Okay.
So I had to make a decision and
Jeremy Hotz was coming with me,
terrific comedian,
cannon and a w.
I said,
look,
I'm going to pull out because my
whole family doesn't want me to go.
All my friends don't want me to go.
And the guy says,
but give me three days.
I said,
what does is fiddler
on the roof three days?
Like you're going to,
what are you going to
talk to the Palestinians?
You know,
the promoter.
So he says,
give me three days.
And I said,
look,
he goes,
don't watch the news.
It will poison you.
I said,
that's like saying that hurricanes come
and don't watch the weather channel.
It's depressing.
Anyway,
so I canceled and it'd be
giving them enough time.
There was an article in the,
in the Jerusalem Post
about how like we were,
we didn't care about victims
from terror of terrorism,
you know,
it's just the opposite.
I was the only took the
gig because they were,
it was helping people,
you know what I mean?
The article about you don't care about
it added me and Jeremy and the guy who
promoted it,
I'm not going to name him,
but he didn't,
he posted it four times,
you know,
and then he said,
he didn't realize about you.
Write it down on a piece of
paper and slide it over here.
And I'll name him.
No,
I don't want to do that.
It's not worth it.
Well,
okay,
let's not name him then,
but it's not about any asshole that,
that it's mad at you cause you
didn't want to go to a war.
Yeah,
until my brother is a
colonel in the marines.
My brother Joe,
he's,
he's almost a general,
he's done that hand.
The house,
the house combat crazy shit.
I told you that.
Yeah.
He told me,
he goes,
hold on a second.
He looked something up on the
computer hotspots in the world.
He goes,
I take a rain check on this one.
And he told me not to go.
He told you not to know.
And he said it because
my other brothers said,
all right,
you're caring.
Brothers says one thing,
let's call the crazy brother.
And the crazy one said,
don't go.
Yeah.
You know what the issue is dumb.
It's like so far everything has been,
the casualties have been capped,
like at least mildly in check.
But it doesn't mean that someone
can't do something fucking crazy.
And it might not happen.
And it might be,
you know,
a few people die here and few people
respond and die here and might be the way
it's coming on or might be an event.
Right.
I'm totally sympathetic
to these people too.
It's not like I do care and sterilely
situations for refrigerator.
No.
And I was afraid of not getting bombed.
That's so random.
I was afraid of the airport
getting bombed and stucked yeah.
Getting stuck there and you
have to think about that,
cause it's not like I can go
to Damascus can catch a flight.
It's not like,
you know,
if you're in Europe and they're an
airline goes on Air France goes on strike,
you just drive to Spain.
Yeah.
But it ain't like that in the Middle East.
It's not like that at all.
And that is one of the that people use.
If they're attacking a city,
they'll attack the airport.
So they keep us goods the,
anyways,
yeah,
that's what they do.
It's this is,
it's a very,
very volatile situation.
And you could have gone over there
and you could have been fine.
Oh,
he could have got over there
and you could have died.
Yeah.
It's like that's reality in
those parts of the world.
It's like we have this sort
of a ridiculous notion that,
uh,
because we're safe over here because a
wood that we don't really have to think
about that shit too.
Well,
the world is smaller now.
There was a time when it did mean a lot.
Like,
you know,
the fact that we were isolated over here,
away from Europe and Asia,
you know,
as far as fighting.
That's why,
you know what I mean?
There was a time when it now
everything's so instantaneous.
They would,
they could get inside people.
Terrorists could do something
here if they want to do,
I'm one's been watching homeland.
I haven't seen him live.
Good fucking show.
You know,
I was with one of the leads last week
and then not to be a name dropper because
I don't even remember his name.
Russell Peters.
We were going to have the dinner and uh,
to be an excellent,
Peter's knows everyone famous.
He's fucking hilarious
is and having a party.
Here's my number.
Mix Master man.
Come up.
He's the only one that
brought a posse to my podcast.
They said,
Russell,
you bring,
bringing a fucking posse.
Brings posses everywhere.
Nice House too.
Can I plugged that podcast?
Dom Rare live from the laugh factory.
Let's talk about doing another podcast.
Let's talk about doing
a sobriety chronicles.
I'm telling you,
it'd be hilarious and it would be
a method to keep you from drinking.
I know you don't want to drink because
I know how you felt when you weren't
drinking.
When we're talking,
we're playing pool,
you're like,
I feel better.
I feel I'm just nice to not feel like
shit and I'm able to up quicker and ping
pong.
I'm sure you can tell much better.
I felt dumb.
You don't have to drink to have
a good time with these clubs,
you know?
And uh,
I'm,
I'm not saying that you
should try pot because,
uh,
you,
you don't need to even change your state
of consciousness if you don't want to.
I can.
I still do Xanax.
You tell me why one.
No,
no,
it wasn't good at that stuff.
I'll tell you Joe,
I don't know though.
You're listen,
I'm sure I don't need that.
It's hanging out the club
to impossible not to drink.
I tried every day.
I'm at a comment,
hey,
you just see everyone else drinking.
I'm laughing and having fun
though when you're on the road.
I went to the laugh factory
last night and I had some water.
Yeah,
you can go up and have fun,
man.
You don't need to.
All right,
so this is my life.
I'm in Australia.
I'm at the Sydney Opera House,
right?
One week,
the next week I met Mr Magoo bees.
Joe Cass and I'm alone.
But the girls are nice.
I'm having a drink with the money.
You know,
what do I do?
I go back to my,
well,
sometimes it's fun.
Look,
I'm not saying you shouldn't drink.
I love drink.
Yeah,
but I,
I agree with,
but I don't do it every day.
But you're in a lot fucking
better shape than me.
You know,
you can drink.
I shouldn't drink.
Well,
even me,
I feel it.
I feel it when I drank and I
feel the difference in my body.
It's just not good for you.
It's not smart.
And I don't,
I don't have an issue with it.
I can take it or leave it.
I like it.
Look with a meal.
I like some wine with a meal,
but I can take it or leave it.
What I,
what I think is important though is when
you can't take something or leave it,
when you have to take it,
that's sort of a situation
where you've got a really wore,
well,
what is this thing doing to me?
Is this thing that I
can't take as helping me?
Do I feel better or is it
fucking with my whole life?
And for you,
I think it fucks with your whole life,
you know?
And I agree and I love you and I,
I love seeing that you were sober,
you know,
and you know,
I'm not captain save a hoe.
I mean,
you do whatever the fuck you want to do.
You know how I am.
I give people advice if they want it.
And I,
you and I have had this,
uh,
this conversation many,
many times and it never really told
you what you should do or shouldn't do.
I sort of just let you talk and you know,
and asked you questions and,
but if,
if you wanted my advice,
my advice would say,
you gotta stop drinking.
It's not good for you.
How they look great.
But it's,
uh,
it's one of those things like some people
can have a drink every now and again
and some people can't do that and all of
a sudden it creeps up and becomes your
whole day.
Yeah.
Well it doesn't become,
but it does.
It's definitely creep back up.
But for you,
you were doing like drinks
in the morning like,
oh,
that was awhile ago.
Yeah.
But that's,
that became your whole day,
right?
No,
not my whole day.
I mean,
I would do a drink in
the morning on a plane,
but I wasn't sitting at home having a
shots before I get out of bed that night.
You know,
not like last weekend kind of thing.
Will you drinking alone?
Yeah.
Oh,
I love it.
Why are you sitting on a toilet?
I mean,
look,
people
that liked to drink and like,
this is annoying man
lift to go and beat him.
So good.
Good drink.
Um,
I just,
I didn't know what you,
I know you're,
when you're reaching out a little bit,
and I know when you keep
mentioning this stuff,
it's not because it's
not fucking with you.
Yeah.
You know?
Well,
you know,
we go to that pool hall,
I don't need to drink.
Right.
I'm fine.
You know,
just racking a boss for you,
I guess.
Be a good shame.
Well,
you,
um,
you know,
started playing better too.
Yeah.
Everything works better.
So I go look drunk.
It's fun.
I enjoy it.
I enjoy it,
but it's got,
damn,
it's bad on the bottom.
Nobody ever says something like,
Hey,
you look good.
What are you drinking again?
Really got it together.
But it's not,
you know,
they say like a glass of wine every
night and it's not even bad for it.
And matter of fact,
it might be beneficial,
an ounce of alcohol,
whether it's in a beer wine or it's
supposed to be good for your circulation.
Well,
you know,
people used to drink wine with food
because they thought it prevented food
poisoning,
prevented travelers
poison travelers sickness.
They would call it because back then
when they were traveling around those
assholes with drinking wine out of like
animal skins and showing like that they
made like these flasks
out of animal skins.
That's how they drank their wines.
I rationalized too because I go,
I only had two drinks but they're two
martinis are like eight shots each of them
and there are two jumbo drinks to imagine
how hard it must have been carried
food back then.
I mean they probably
all got food sickness,
you know,
because Oh my God,
how long was meat stay good.
A couple of hours after he killed it.
I mean,
how many of you have a day?
What do you have?
And it's 80 degrees outside.
Do you have two days?
I know that's a question you have about,
uh,
people bitching about it.
The plane being in a half hour late,
right.
And comedians say like,
Oh,
you actually trying to write a bit about
it because the idea of taking a year to
go across the country and you know,
getting stuck at the Donner
pass because it's snow.
How fucking crate.
Imagine like,
where are you going?
I got to go to bed.
I've got a Gig at San Francisco when?
Oh,
next June.
In a year.
Oh,
really?
You better get some rest.
You know what I mean?
It's like,
yeah,
we just take it like,
fuck the half hour late,
son of a bitch.
Well,
you want to really wrap your
head around a crazy number.
Here's the,
here's the craziest number between the,
uh,
v Invention of the airplane and the
dropping of an atomic bomb from the
airplane.
It was less than 50 years.
Wow.
Talk about a life change in that.
Yeah.
Hitler fucked up.
Hitler fucked up shit.
It never really needed the Jews.
They want it for us.
Bernard von Braun.
Yeah.
Well,
yeah.
Oppenheimer,
right?
He was the guy that created it.
Wernher von Braun was the NASA guy.
What was his name?
The guy that did the atom bomb?
No,
that's Oppenheimer.
Wernher von Braun was,
um,
the guy who supposedly got us on the moon,
son of a bitch.
He's the guy from operation paperclip.
The,
uh,
all the best Nazi scientists from,
or Jewish.
We're Jewish,
weren't they?
At first they came over there.
I Dunno if they were not a,
but all the best.
Nazi scientists were a sort of a
distributed between Russia and the United
States after World War II.
And,
uh,
America started,
you know,
they,
they started with Wernher von Braun.
They got Wernher von Braun and all these
different Nazi dudes under operation
paperclip,
but they were all like legit Nazis.
That's one of the dark secrets
of the American space program.
There was,
it was run by Nazis.
Wernher von Braun was a legit Nazi,
like if he was alive today,
the Simon Wiesenthal Center said they
would prosecute him for crimes against
humanity.
Wow.
Apparently he had a rocket factory in
Berlin and there was this guy who did this
documentary on m and a,
the Moon landings,
and he interviewed,
uh,
people that worked in the rocket factory.
This guy had tattoos from being the
concentration camp and he talked about how
wonderful I'm Brown.
Like they would hang the five slowest
Jews in front of the rocket factory every
day.
I think it was like really dark,
dark education lunch.
It's not,
I mean,
that's beyond hate in humanity.
It's like that regime,
that Nazi regime there,
that ruthlessness also yielded
some incredible science.
I mean the scientific achievements,
it just in the rocketry and engine
engine building and you know,
the,
the shit that they were able to do.
And then Russia scoop some of them
up and we scooped some of them up.
And that's where the autonomy
it was invented here.
Yeah.
Manhattan project.
That was Oppenheimer.
It was that he a,
I mean,
it sounds pretty Jewish.
Is Oppenheimer Jewish.
It must be right,
of course.
Of course.
Let's not forget that the
best speaking to Jews,
I'm Christmas Eve.
I'm doing it.
Do what?
His synagogue,
the synagogue and a,
uh,
the laugh factory has a show,
a Jewish show.
Oh really?
Yeah.
I love that.
Nice.
Um,
you have where you have
a Gig on New Year's Eve,
where yet?
Um,
at the,
uh,
good nights in North Carolina.
Oh,
that's right.
Yeah.
Which I'm really looking
forward to not only the club,
uh,
but my family's down there and Mike,
I got a lot of friends in Raleigh
so I'm looking to see if he was Jewish.
It does not say,
dammit.
We showed this on a podcast before.
That is not to experiment
with the dog head.
Yeah.
They had electrical impulses into the dog.
Hadn't made it move after
is detached from the body.
Oh yeah,
they did some banking look
that looks real right there.
Yeah.
That dog is alive.
Do they did some crazy shit.
The Nazis did some crazy shit and they
were really obsessed with the cult.
That's,
that's really weird.
I wonder how much of it is uh,
you know,
um,
sort of revisionist bullshit that
like these reality TV shows try to,
uh,
to do these sort of half
documentary type shows.
Like I love,
um,
ancient aliens a fun show,
but the reality is they
get a lot of shit wrong.
Like they're not trying to be like
super duper accurate about some of their
stuff.
And so like when they
say something like that,
the,
that the,
the Nazis were really into the call.
I really wish I knew how
much into the cult they were.
That was a theme of like
Indiana Jones and the template.
You know,
remember the old Raiders of the lost Ark
when they found the Ark of the covenant
that was supposed to be the Nazis
were after all this a culture.
Yeah.
Apparently they had like a reputation.
I really,
we should educate myself on that.
Find out how,
how deep that was and what
the fuck that was all about.
But this guy,
uh,
Oppenheimer,
one of the creepiest,
you look at it that now.
Yeah.
When he,
uh,
when,
when he blew up the,
the nuclear bomb,
he,
uh,
he quoted the Bhagavad Gita is
this ancient Hindu religious text.
It said,
now I am become death.
The destroyer of worlds.
Wow.
Could you imagine standing next to a dude?
No.
So fucking smart that he
created an atomic bomb,
like his inventions let gave birth of
the atomic bomb and then you're standing
next to him why it blows up and
he quotes that kind of shit.
Like he's happy about it.
He's not happy.
He wasn't happy at all.
He thought it was a terrible term.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Well a lot of these guys that are
scientists that the real issue is,
and becoming a scientist,
you're,
you're pursuing knowledge.
You're pursuing the,
the,
the measurement of a,
of a,
of different experiments.
And,
and,
and you're,
you're trying to invent
and create with technology,
but at a certain point in time,
you must know that if you
continue down this path,
it's going to lead to insane
amounts of people dying.
And in your mind,
it's a battle now,
but it,
cause it's because as a scientist,
as a,
a person is trying to achieve a goal,
you wanted to see if you can
be the first person to do this.
You want to see if you can be the first
person to split an atom inside of bomb
and lead.
To this incredible explosion of energy.
You want to be,
you want to do that,
but then you have to realize like,
wow,
if I do do that,
what the fuck am I really doing?
Like I'm,
I am,
I am the only way this can get done.
And then there's the argument,
well,
if you don't do it,
the Nazis are going to do it.
We have to do it argument.
That's what the argument was.
And so this guy was caught in there
and he got there first and when he said
that,
you know,
that that became one of the creepiest
quotes ever a attributed to anybody that's
responsible for anything
like really monumental.
I had read that a lot of the scientists
we got were Jews who left Nazi Germany
when they could get out.
I bet there was that too.
I'm sure there was that as well.
I mean,
that's Einstein.
Yeah.
Um,
but I think,
um,
the rocketry program in particular,
the NASA got a lot of,
uh,
they were,
they were still a lot of no Germans.
There were never Nazis.
It was a operation paperclip and meeting.
And how many of them were Nazis because
their families were forced into that
because there were stuck there.
How many of were Nazis because they
were really fucking psychopath creeps.
Who knows how many of them are
actually responsible for murder?
I don't know.
I would love to know what
he was saying though.
Cause you got to admit the
guy was a riveting performer.
Hitler,
charismatic speaker.
I mean I thought,
do you ever see pictures of cruise chef?
Yes.
When he took his shoe off and bang,
Hey,
well Barry you fuck takes
their shoe or for the Yulin?
Yeah.
Do you remember that fear that we had?
You know there was a oh yeah.
Of,
of being in a nuclear war with Russia.
Sure.
And it was on,
it was all the time.
We always felt it like that was a,
like in the eighties Dan was like,
especially because there
was no internet back then,
we didn't know what the
fuck was really going on.
Button.
The red,
the red phone picking it,
you know,
the president had that power.
But you would get your news like from,
you know,
either newspapers or the news shows
that that's where you got your news.
I wonder if it ever came
close to a nuclear war.
Well,
they say that,
uh,
the Bay of pigs,
they say the bay of Pigs,
it got pretty close.
Yeah.
Jerry here about their Russian sleep
experiment that they did back in the,
uh,
I want to say the 1940s,
they wanted to keep five prisoners awake.
I meant the Cuban missile crisis,
not a bay of pigs,
but no,
what did they do?
They wanted to keep a five people wait,
they took five prisoners
and they said like,
Hey,
uh,
we went to do some experiments on
here and then we'll let you go.
So for a,
I think the first five
days everyone was kind of,
you know,
fine,
and then it went from them like
screaming like four hours at a time.
Like get me Outta here.
And like they had microphones in this,
like in this pen,
it was like,
you know,
a sealed kind of thing that had no
windows and they had microphones.
So they could record everybody,
what they we talked about and stuff,
and they started going crazy.
They start screaming and everything
and they were pumping this room,
fill,
there's some gas and test gas
that they were trying to exclude.
It could keep soldiers
up for 10 days at a time,
you know?
Uh,
and so then all the
people started screaming.
Then they were quiet.
Then all the scientists were like,
I think the microphones aren't working
when they're not making any noises at
all.
And so they go in there and uh,
they're all,
the people are just very calm.
They didn't want to leave
anymore and stuff like that.
And then when they experiment,
it's over.
They wouldn't leave.
Like they were like fighting.
They,
they wanted to stay in this chamber.
They started,
people started like,
I guess people started like killing
themselves because they didn't want to go,
like ripping their throats
out and stuff like that.
Yeah.
And there's,
there's a video on youtube called,
what is the exact name of
the Russian sleep experiment?
It's on,
it's on youtube and there's a bigger,
I think it's what the
microphones recorded.
I'm,
I'm remembering this now,
but I think I might've in my own
head incorporated it into that.
Do you remember that movie
in the mouth of madness?
No.
It was a movie about a dude who
was an author went fucking crazy.
And I think I attributed
some of the aspects of his,
the,
the book had some weird power over
people when they read the book that gets
sucked into this crazy world.
Like the world around them would change.
Really fascinating book.
Um,
I forget who wrote it.
I want to say it,
Stephen King,
but it's not the mouth of madness.
Yeah.
Uh,
there's a website called
creepy Pasta Wiki or whatever,
just typing the Russian sleep experiment.
There's the whole story and he goes,
he breaks it down per hour.
And then like how,
how people just,
they started going crazy and,
and uh,
the,
uh,
the movie moving the mouth of mantises,
it's a John Carpenter movie.
Creepy ass movie.
It's a really good movie.
But,
uh,
I,
for some reason I incorporated that.
I guess that is like a real news story.
I incorporated that in my memory.
That's just goes to show you how
like memories can be faulty as,
you know,
I incorporated that
reality into a fake memory.
I guess some one of the people were
hurt and they tried to give him an
anesthesia and the guy was like,
I must remain awake.
You know,
I must stay awake.
Like they,
whoa.
Uh,
yeah.
It's interesting though.
I read it if,
when you get a chance to
read this whole thing,
are you sure this is not fiction?
I always thought it was real.
I've heard that there's
people that questioned it,
uh,
because of the,
based on the youtube video,
because the youtube video
is just the microphone.
So I think a lot of people are like,
and that's not real.
It's somebody just bullshitting,
you know?
Cause at one point they do start
screaming and running around and stuff,
but I don't,
I don't,
I,
you know,
I never really researched it.
Uh,
it's something,
uh,
that I heard a long time ago.
Hmm.
But yeah,
I'm sure Internet will tell
me if it's real or not.
So if it's on the Internet,
it's gotta be true.
Right?
Yeah.
I wanna I wanna I wanna
find out if this is true.
Should I go to Snopes?
Is the Russian experiment
sleep experiment?
True?
Huh?
Yeah.
I need to find this out
because we can't keep,
it helps to make sure.
It's interesting though,
right?
Right.
This information p people get
so aggro with correcting us.
Joe,
you're F you're spreading false knowledge.
I try so hard to get shit right.
When did get mad because
I called the Hamp,
uh,
a cousin of marijuana.
[inaudible] says it's a cousin,
like everywhere online,
everywhere you read just Google cousin,
I think marijuana from him.
He be see has it?
It's a strain.
It's a different strain and
it's the male of the species.
And I understand that.
And this guy was saying that I
was spreading dish information.
It's like people like are like jumping up,
trying to catch you
saying something wrong.
So when we have something like this,
yeah,
this is a way,
a nice way to say thanks folks.
Okay.
And if something's wrong,
say hey,
I think maybe there's a dispute
about the definition of this.
Or Hey,
maybe you didn't know.
But even though everybody
calls it a cousin,
it's something else.
Or Hey,
maybe,
you know,
just be nice folks.
Don't be all conti.
I have to stop with the disinformation.
Like you're doing it on purpose.
I have two friends that are lawyers and
one of them always ends the argument by
going,
you're wrong.
Oh God.
So that shuts it all down.
Those that,
those guys are just so gross.
You can't,
you have a conversation,
you weak bitch,
have a conversation with someone who
has a completely different point of view
from you and take it in.
That's why I don't talk politics because
I've never seen anybody go at the end
of the political discussion.
You know what?
You got a good point.
I think I'm going to change my mind you,
there's an issue with a lot of men
socially when it comes to arguing about
things and that issue is
they're trying to win.
Yeah.
You know,
they're not just,
they're not comfortable with themselves
enough to just be themselves.
Right.
They're trying to establish societal
dominance is trying to establish a social
dominance.
I,
uh,
you know,
I have a friend,
okay.
Just
very nice person.
Um,
who has a husband the name over,
I won't,
who has a husband and a,
when I'm forced to interact with the sky,
it always becomes this weird thing where
he tries to like brag about something
or,
yeah.
And it's,
it's this weird social thing.
Yeah.
And it might be like,
he'll try to crack a subtle
joke at you or you know what,
but whatever it is,
it's this weird like uncomfortable,
like posturing thing that goes on.
Yeah.
And so when I'm,
I'm,
I'm around him,
I always like treat it
like a research subject.
I was like,
wait,
what?
Did you know what,
what throws it off exactly.
You know,
what do we have to do to,
uh,
to get them to stop doing shit?
I just,
what should I do this time?
Should I just agree with them?
We'll go off for sure.
Amazing.
I say,
no,
you,
there are a really amazing guy.
Your wife is so fortunate,
you know,
change my life,
make them really uncomfortable.
We hang out together more.
Cause I think I can learn from you.
There's just something about you.
And what'd he do?
Progressive,
you know,
mock them or do you,
do you call them out on it?
I wouldn't call them out.
I think it's like the guy
who was the Israel thing.
When I found out that he had
posted this thing four times,
I called him up and I says,
you know,
really look forward to
working with you again.
I understand you're coming in today.
If you need a,
I could send the car
for her at the airport.
Or if I kept myself totally
just being fucking evil,
I was,
you know,
but instead of like,
don't fuck you.
And then he's got that recorded.
It's like,
hey man,
thank you for doing that.
I appreciate it.
The exposure in Israel,
it's,
look,
it's indefensible.
The fact this guy wanted you to fly into
a war zone is fucking nuts to tell some
jokey jokes,
guys,
an asshole.
You know,
he didn't like the fact that it would
give us deposit back or whatever the fuck
went wrong.
But guess what,
Dude?
That's part of what goes on when you're
dealing with shit in a war zone and it's
not the fucking entertainers fault.
They don't want to fly
into a fucking war zone.
And the guy,
the writer apologized and he said,
we gotta be careful not to get
comedians that they're skittish.
So in other words,
you know,
I'm sorry for what I said,
but these guys are pussies.
Skiddish skiddish yeah.
You know,
I don't think you used the word
skittish when there's bombs,
he's skittish around bomb.
If there's actual bombs going off,
attacks from getting shot at,
is it a real war?
Oh,
it's a real war.
Ha.
And you're,
yeah,
I think you might be a little harsh.
Skiddish you'd judgemental cunt face.
Where does this guy live?
That shit.
Which one?
The guy who booked this shit.
Oh,
here.
He lives here.
Oh yeah.
It isn't live this and go over there.
He goes over,
but he doesn't live here.
How dare he?
Everyone's saying that Russian ships fake.
Yeah.
Probably 2009 it was just like this
viral thing that went around a,
it's a fictional piece of work that
appears to have started spreading a viral
fashion sometime in 2009 meanwhile,
we were just contributing information.
Brian.
Alicia,
that's good.
It's a nice story.
That was really creepy.
Creepy.
I remember from a while ago and I just,
you know,
remember reading and going,
huh,
that's crazy.
Just to
cool a p.
It's not even a hoax.
Apparently it was just a piece of fiction.
Yeah.
I liked this.
Prevented,
prevented all provigil.
Yeah,
I could feel it.
I feel like wide awake.
Yeah.
It's gonna.
It's gonna kick in even later pulses.
Your pulse elevated.
No,
we,
we learned about this shit from powerful
Dave Asprey and powerful Tim Ferris.
It's an,
I just feel awake.
I will say no more.
Yeah,
but those guys can be,
if it works.
No,
that's the,
one of the cool things about having this
podcast is that I get to hang out and
talk to all these like dudes
way off the beaten path.
It would never get to
communicate with like,
uh,
this Guy Dave Asprey who's just see,
I would guess you would call
him like a human performance.
And he runs a,
a,
a tech company.
But on top of that,
he also like has this a website that
he puts out all this information about
health and fitness and he does
these brain hacking things and all,
you had to find him just,
um,
minimum line man met him
through a communicating online,
you know,
people recommended has worked and they
checked him out and we had the guy in
here.
He's a guy,
he's fucking super creepy genius.
It was one of those crazy,
um,
podcasts while like after it's over,
like you've got to go back with a piece
of paper and write down shit and Google
things.
And yeah,
it was a crazy podcast.
I learned a lot of stuff and like how,
what are the odds of getting a
chance to talk to a guy like that?
If you didn't have a podcast like this,
how would you get someone to sit down
with you for three hours and talk about
shit?
Yeah.
You know,
I'm,
I'm always amazed by the mind.
And I used to teach school.
I taught fourth grade and I was amazed
at how kids had different intelligence
and how,
like,
I remember I was really bad in math,
but I knew every,
the batting average of every,
the top 10 players in American national
league without even thinking about it.
I knew that er,
they earned run average of the pictures
and that incredible the way your mind
accepts things.
And then I was like
fucking retarded in math.
Yeah.
I always loved that I could,
I knew like Marvin Hagler record.
Yeah.
You know,
I knew,
uh,
who we lost to,
what the decision was.
You know,
I knew a Durand's record,
you know,
I could read you back like how,
where,
where he had his first loss when he beat
can be Canon to get the title to watch
that whole fight the other night.
Yeah,
I did.
I pack.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That was a,
that was crazy.
It was crazy the way he walked into it.
Huh?
You can't let that and you can't
make that instantaneous mistake.
And boxing you'd done?
I think he's got his attention
very stretched as well.
There's a bunch of issues if pack.
Yeah,
I think,
I think one of the big
issues is that he's like,
I don't think we can even wrap our
heads around how famous that guy is.
Oh,
in the Philippines,
he's like a God,
he's gonna be president.
He could be president of the Philippines.
So there's that and he being
a congressman over there,
well who knows what kind of crazy
fucking pressure that guys under,
who knows?
I don't understand.
Then on top of that,
he's trying to chain train and then
on top of that he's super famous,
so he's got to constantly do,
be doing media things,
constantly be doing interviews,
was constantly talking to people and
then on top of that he has a family.
Like that's a lot of shit.
I don't,
I don't know.
I mean,
I don't know if you could really do that.
I think you could do it for a little while
because you were so good at boxing to
begin with.
But I think he's at a point where his
skills have started to slip because of the
fact that he's not putting the same amount
of focus into it as it was because to
me the strategy and then on top of that
he's had a lot of wars and he's had a
lot of crazy fights.
Yeah.
I mean he wasn't getting hit too
much in other fights but man these,
these God mark has fights.
Mark has just has his number.
Some guys just have a,
I think he was winning up to that point.
Yes,
yes I did.
But he did get knocked down and he
got knocked down with one punch and a,
that was the first time.
The first time he got knocked down you've
got knocked down like in like was like
the fourth maybe and then he
got knocked out in the sixth.
I understand him to go.
That's the cleanest punch I've ever seen.
Quick guy take like a guy that kind of
lightening speed cause he really looked
into it flush,
flush it.
You couldn't hit a guy anyhow.
Perfect.
Any more.
Perfect mark has just
drilled it down the middle.
Brilliant placement and when
you see the impact of it,
we were,
we were watching it in a Dana White's
dressing room and when you see the impact
of Paki Owl's head fly back,
you will like if they fell down face
first and then you see him fall down face
first.
We all just like leapt up who?
I was like who saw that comment because
Pacquiao was moving in on him like he
had heard.
Mark has got a little bit too cocky.
I looked up khaki cause I would love to
hit somebody like that without fear of
getting hit back.
Well that's what I've always said.
Like people say like give,
what did you food man.
Which food in the mu first of all
everybody wants to beat people up.
No one wants to fight.
Okay.
Everybody that says things like that,
you don't know what a fight is.
A fight as he gets to do that to you.
Too stupid,
but you know it's not a matter of who
vote could keep gay as I just go in there
and kick his butt.
Then people who can also kick
ass going to kick your ass.
You understand that,
right?
Like you,
you have to be ready for the craziest
fucking competition known to man.
That's what professional fighter.
Yeah.
Trains is a fighter.
You can't just go kick ass.
Okay.
It does.
It was funny,
but people that talk about this guy,
he used to sell fucking
throw it through a wall.
First of all,
when's the last time you were in a fight?
Second Grade.
You know what I mean?
Like these guys,
they talk about fighting all the time.
I'm fucking killed.
I'll break your fucking head.
You never did anything.
There's a fighting Koolaid,
a whole series of,
hey koolaid.
There's a whole series of dudes I've
met throughout my life who have told me
that they can't lose
because of their mentality.
It's this thing that guys will tell you,
this fucking guy,
it was a year ago,
I told me,
he goes,
I'll tell you why man.
If I dedicated myself to MMA,
if I dedicated myself,
I would dominate.
Cause Dude,
my mentality is I cannot
lose getting hit here,
here and this nervous.
Yeah,
you can leave.
And I have to sit there when a guy says
something like that and just non going,
yeah,
well good luck with that mentality
but you don't understand my mentality.
I cannot lose when I get that in my
head and just make sure you don't fight
anybody and they always invade your
space when they're telling you this and
you're like okay.
Do you ever get people challenging you?
No,
no,
no.
I'm like super friendly,
you know,
very standoffish at all am I
know you're great with paypal.
But if uh,
if someone like,
like those kind of guys,
if you know,
if you challenged them,
if you want to like getting
in an altercation with a dude,
you can say something and
they will probably hit you.
Yeah.
There's a lot of people that are just
running around looking for someone to hit.
I told you that ray man,
see any story,
right?
What?
What happened?
He came to see me at the Improv with his
wife and his kids and then when I got
off he came out to talk to
me and this guy comes up and
he goes,
hey ray,
boom,
boom man.
Sini and it's great,
you know,
it gets all excited.
He goes,
hey ray,
can you hit me?
And he goes,
why?
I go,
look man.
He goes,
yeah,
I want to see what it feels like
to get hit by professional box.
It just like hit me and you know,
I gotta look man,
he can't hit and raise the nicest
fucking guy and where he can't hit you.
Right?
And the guy goes,
oh,
come on.
He goes,
all right,
well can I hit you?
Then I go,
well you get the fuck out of here.
Can I hit you then what the fuck?
I know.
Can I hit you then?
Can I give you a shot just
to show you how strong I am?
I'm just on the arm.
I had a guy asked me if
he could carry me once.
I think it would carry me.
Okay.
You inside?
He put his jacket down over the puddle.
He take a picture with me.
He wanted to hold me when
that's how he said it too.
He's like,
no the fuck is wrong with you man.
Big giant dude.
He was this big,
he looked like it was a
native American long hair,
long dark hair.
Scary as fuck.
Juicy fruit cause he had
no problem with that guy.
Take a while.
Can I carry you?
Come on.
Crazy like it.
Probably like six,
eight six,
nine big giant dude.
Wanted to pick people up and pictures
does thing.
Strange Fetish but understandable.
Well you know when that's
got,
you know it's a funny
thing when people like,
you know,
they're like super proud of like a
physical attribute that there were,
you know,
sort of born with like being
like really crazy tall,
tall.
I am.
I'm just three fucking tall
being tall and all and like,
it's a strange thing.
You know,
I spent,
I guess suspect guys,
a big decks,
have that tail happy.
We do happy that they got a big Dick.
But listen man,
you could have easily been born with a
micro Dick's that you laugh out online.
Back to didn't ask for that deck
and you didn't ask for your Dick.
You got lucky.
What is that you're showing in the corner?
People are saying that you are,
uh,
undercover Russian spy
or something like that.
How's that?
So I'm showing the KGB logo,
why they stay undercover west,
the fucking spine
storage show.
Yeah.
It's fun to watch live feedback.
Joe Doesn't like it.
Well,
the problem is they'll,
they will entertain your thoughts
with a lot of negative shit.
Yeah.
You know,
and you,
you're inviting.
I mean,
every now and then it might be fun,
but you were inviting too many,
uh,
too many options.
People really think
you're arrest alien or,
or all that shit.
Like they're really,
people believe that you're part of the,
yeah,
the Illuminati.
I'm sure there's some,
look,
there's a lot of people that are what
you call paranoid schizophrenia x and
that's legit.
And that's not like a small
percentage of our population.
You know,
there's like,
I know several,
I know,
I know many people that have
like legit mental illnesses.
I think it's super common.
Yeah.
So if you're a person with a
legit mental illness and you know,
you see someone on television,
you can get completely convinced that
they're involved in some sort of civic
society to hold you down.
I know a dude who's losing his mind,
but that one dude we know who was
losing his mind thinks that everybody's
working for the fucking CIA.
People being mind controlled and shit.
Like,
what are you like,
stop,
settle the fuck down.
It's much,
there's much less conspiracy afoot than
people would like to see fit there.
Then people would like to,
uh,
like to believe.
Have you ever been contacted
by any of these groups?
Like,
like Scientologists are Illuminati
ontology.
They seem to,
they have a lot of money and
then they protect their people.
Well,
we have to rework some of your rules,
but I think we'll be fine.
Yeah.
But I guess if you,
not saying that religion did,
they,
did they believe in God or they
believe they're a group about assets.
They're very successful.
If you look at what Scientology has done,
they're,
they're amazing at making money
and it managing their business,
their business of Scientology and amazing
at acquiring really expensive real
estate.
I think they're like a big real
estate holder in Los Angeles.
They own like some really
big fucking buildings,
a lot of like really expensive stuff.
So they're smart.
That was all on Hubbard,
right?
Yeah.
Well he's the guy who started it
has been dead for a long time.
Do they think that,
uh,
did they believe in a god
or they believe their God,
they believe aliens.
They believe some crazy shit
written by l Ron Hubbard.
That's what's really weird about it.
It's like they believe some,
it seems to me that some people just need
a structure that needs some stuff that
tells them all the answers.
Every question that they have is answered,
whether it logical or not.
Some people just need that base covered
and they'll take that base from time
tology of tea.
They'll take that base from Buddhism
or they'll take that base from
Christianity,
they'll take that base from
whoever gets there first.
Whoever gets there first,
whoever's in the right position
who resonates with them the most,
they'll accept that.
And for something like Scientology,
one of the good things about Scientology
as opposed to a lot of the other
religions is there's a lot of like
pretty interesting principles that they,
that they masked with in terms of
managing your consciousness in terms of
positive thinking and accepting um,
uh,
positive things in your
life and acting change.
Like then there's like a lot of like,
uh,
like that's why dianetics
were so successful.
Like dianetics when they sold it on TV,
you didn't know that you were becoming
a part of some sort of crazy religious
cult.
The thought that you were
buying a self help book.
And uh,
I bought a bunch of self help books,
man.
I bought Tony Robbins Shit.
I listened to his books on tape.
Yeah.
When I was a,
when I was poor as fuck,
living in revere.
Um,
I used to live in cities.
Yeah.
That's hilarious.
I was well struggling comedian,
I was listening to Anthony Robbins tapes
and just thinking about like how to
make things happen.
Like he's like really good motivator,
you know,
and the,
the dianetics thing,
I thought it was this very similar,
that's what I thought it was.
And then when I got it,
when I,
um,
when I got the book they sent me
invitations to go to like the Scientology
center and all this different Shit.
They sent me them almost every month.
They were relentless for years.
Like if you are lost,
they reach out and they just get you,
it's like this is pre internet.
Okay.
Cause this is like 1994.
So it was fascinating to me because
I didn't understand what it was.
I didn't,
we had no internet.
Okay.
We'll wrap your head around that.
People.
So when I,
if someone asked me what Scientology was,
I had to like literally go to a store.
I had a bio book,
I had read it myself.
So in reading this dianetics book and
then getting all these emails from these
males,
actual physical mail sent to
my mailbox from this group,
I was like,
what the fuck is this?
So then it piqued my curiosity and then
I really looked into when I was like,
wow,
this is a,
this is amazing.
This is a cult and this is
ever going to get any of that.
No,
no.
I never went to like
a meeting or anything,
but I did sit down with a dude and he
did that a stress test thing on me.
What they did.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But that was way later.
That was like a couple of years ago.
Well,
you definitely needed,
it.
Didn't like the outcome
of that test was like,
you need to become a scientologist.
It was pretty,
pretty clear.
Um,
it was,
it's the most ridiculous device ever.
Um,
I'm sitting there and I don't think,
I wish that we had,
um,
uh,
Kara Santa Maria on who she could
explain us the science behind it and how
woefully lacking it is and real science.
But it gives,
you really does.
But anyway,
um,
this,
they would sit down with you and you
hold on to this e meter and even ask you
questions.
And I don't remember the
nature of the questions,
but I just remember it
being so ridiculous.
And I remember asking like,
how many different things can affect this?
You know,
what about intent does
intent if effect it,
what if I get angry?
Does that affect it?
So then I tried to just like think
of answers like in a fucked up way.
So like really raised my craziness up.
Oh No,
I,
I I I I'm not exactly sure cause
it was really high when I did this.
Um,
but so it wasn't that long ago.
It wasn't,
it was a couple years ago.
It was,
um,
I was filming,
game show in my head.
Okay.
We were down there cause so that was,
uh,
that was pre before fear factor came out.
So it was a couple of years ago,
at least three years ago.
Anyway,
point being,
I'm standing there with these
fucking tin cans and my hands,
like holding onto this thing and this guy
who is reading out of this book like a
Prozac Zombie,
I mean,
he's like,
he's,
he's a weird,
disconnected dude and he's
reading me these things.
He definitely doesn't know who I am.
Uh,
you know,
he's never watched fear factor
or anything before he's,
he was 100%.
Like,
he,
uh,
asked me my name a couple of times.
He forgot it.
He had to ask me it again.
But the,
um,
the way he was like taking me through.
Do you feel,
uh,
what,
how do you feel when you
feel about your childhood?
Hmm.
I'm like,
great.
It's pretty good.
Good childhood.
I'm here.
I'm healthy.
Okay.
How do you feel about your education?
Like if you're asking me these weird
questions when I'm holding onto the floor,
I don't know.
I don't understand it.
And they were trying to like show that
you have a certain amount of stress in
your life and what they would recommend
is that you look into dianetics and then
you look into dianetics and then boom,
you're,
you're a scientologist.
And what,
you know,
Scientology can too for a lot of people
is provide them with a framework,
provide them with like a scaffolding.
It gives him like a way to
like move forward and that,
that that's legit for everybody.
For what it's Christianity or anything.
When you give someone a framework,
sometimes it just looked,
all they need is a step by
step instruction of how to
get through life or how to
move through,
you know,
to the next stage how to,
how to go get a job,
how to get their shit together.
Like people need like instructional,
even even wack ones,
you know,
he's in Wac,
ones that have aliens
in them and like what?
All that other stuff,
the [inaudible] and the volcanoes
and what does the story do?
Anything that we can play
a quick south park like,
yeah,
let's do that.
Let's do that.
Because this is the why.
Why fuck around when the
masters already nailed it.
Okay.
Hold on.
Let me get this,
get this.
I can tell you what stresses you Joe.
What the reason.
Lack of integrity.
Yeah.
Anything.
He's stealing material
people that bullshit.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Let's,
let's listen to this.
Let's see if we can,
there was a reason for people getting sab
75 billion years ago.
Back then,
that was a galactic federation,
which was ruled over by the Lord Walk,
walk,
walk.
Galaxy was overpopulated and so he
rounded up the hop as aliens from all
different plans and the hospitals.
The graphic it says,
this is what Scientology
was actually right,
believe which looked like DC
Hayes except the croc cruisers.
They took the frozen alien bodies to
harm and dump them into the volcanoes of
Hawaii.
The aliens were no longer have chosen
the souls of those aliens.
However they've gone and all
bloated up towards the sky.
But the evil Lord Zino had repaired for
this Paul Paul Walker shows to return.
And so we built giant
full catchers in the sky,
the rain watching to see what he wishes
he knew about all the phones were forced
to watch days of brainwashing material.
What's trick them into
believing a false reality.
Vito,
good release behavior,
which roamed the earth.
English reading the fog of
confusion at the dawn of Man.
The is finally found bodies
which you can grab onto.
They attached themselves.
All man con is still to this
day talking all our fears.
Yeah.
That's where our fears,
our confusions in our problems come from,
from the Seatons were so fucking smart,
aren't they?
Oh,
those guys
are the best.
I love south firing.
Have you ever met those guys?
You Know Eric laughing?
Have,
do they,
have you ever been to the laugh factory
or do they come in there and what's the
guy's name?
Trey Parker and Matt Stone.
Trey Parker.
I met somewhere along the line.
Oh that's cool.
But I think he was
producing a long time ago,
maybe on Fox or something.
They're writing.
So you used to open up for share.
Did you ever mess around with shared?
Did you ever get a part of that,
that everyone like mess around with share?
You mean like sexually?
Yeah.
Or Know
No.
Wear her outfit with the,
but I remember one night we were
working at the Mirage and I would,
you know,
and when we work in like casinos,
we would see each other like I don't
have an arena or there'd be a break after
it,
you know,
so I would never see her cause she'd
be putting on one over wigs and her
eyelashes,
Shit.
And she goes to me,
uh,
as we're walking,
we're walking by and she goes,
I can't believe you did
a just over a hedge joke,
my grandmothers here.
I said,
I can't believe that your
grandfather gets to see your ass.
Later on that night were downstairs
party in her room and her
grandmother says like,
almost like it was a sitcom.
She goes,
I love that bit you did about the hedge.
All right.
She goes,
you know what the fuck?
She was cool.
Very cool.
You know,
it's so weird how people are,
like friend of mine is working with her,
they're doing a gig in
Russia soon and she,
you know,
I mean she's very fucking talented,
obviously she accomplished whether you
like her or not and she's insecure about
her voice,
you know,
and I'm,
I'm,
I'm fuck,
I suck,
but I love to sing.
I'm singing with him
or all my fucking arm.
Then it's secure.
I don't,
but of course she's famous,
you know,
as a singer.
But it's just so weird how people can be
insecure and we know this from any part
of show business,
you know,
the needy comedian would you think?
Yeah.
It's the worst and unfortunately this
is a lot of us that I really liked it or
like that they want to come
up and see is this good?
Is this okay?
Yeah.
Like,
come on man.
Get out of here with that shit.
Go up there dude.
It's funny because the way we do stand up,
all of us together,
it's kind of the same way
when we all get together.
We have these shows,
whether it's a are your
Dunkin or or Joey or whatever.
We're just hanging out and then
one of us will go on stage,
meaning we,
you've done these shows with us.
Of course another one would go onstage,
but every now and then we'll bring
someone new into the mix and then they're
like I said,
he could match it up with this,
which I did.
What are you doing?
Go Up.
Go up there.
Come on man.
Joey was both of them.
Both of them were on
that show list and I did.
They left I think before you came in.
I just,
I met Ari upstairs.
They were both,
they're both fucking really funny,
but Joey was fucking high as it could.
I can't.
His eyes were like clothes.
There's I'm so fucking
item and they almost fell.
I tell you,
it must fell off to big boy.
Big Boy.
That's not good.
If he falls off that stage,
that's not a fall backwards near the way.
He's good,
but he would have killed
the shingles up front.
He can.
You can break things.
I wish I was.
I was watching those
when you were doing some of those bits
and said they couldn't fucking help but
laugh,
you know when you did
the the the last bit,
but you know.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They,
I loved watching him.
I love watching people who can't help
laugh even though they think I've seen
people shake their head and laugh.
I go,
no,
you can't disapprove and left 11 when
you're out with coworkers and because you
don't want those other ladies
in your office to how you know,
like you're all on the
corporate ladder together.
You don't want them to have a turn it on.
Yeah.
We went there and you see this
one every fucking blow job jokes.
She's laughing her ass off.
But before you came in I asked him
something that you really shouldn't ask
women.
We shouldn't ask him.
I said,
which one are you?
Which one of you ladies do you think is
the hottest and also the at least hot.
And then one of them was their
boss and go leave her out of it.
Then she's the boss.
But just like,
I mean,
obviously one of you is in a
different league than the others.
I mean,
I could,
I could see and they were like fucking
laughing and at least one of them is
thinking,
I wonder if it's me,
you know?
Wow.
That's funny.
Yeah.
I think they liked you tomorrow.
I love fucking with people.
I love interacting.
Yeah,
we're,
we're doing a show,
Joan,
if you ever want to come in,
I don't want to be a
fucking a plugged machine,
but it's going to be called
busting balls with dom.
Rarer and,
and we encourage interaction
with the crowd and how they say,
no talking during the show.
I want you to fucking talk.
I want you to break balls then we have,
yeah.
And then we'll,
we'll have a,
uh,
also an interview and we can bust each
other's balls where we can be fucking
goofy,
you know,
so it's essentially not heckling
because you're actually encouraging the
interaction.
It's not heckling,
you know,
it's not like a regular comedy show.
No,
that's second.
It's going to confuse the shit out
of your regular comedy club people.
But I'll say it at the beginning,
you know,
but then they're gonna want,
they're gonna want that
kind of Damo rarer action.
I'm gonna.
I don't want that,
that,
that spontaneous shit.
I don't mind.
You don't mind.
You know,
I don't like when it bits get interrupted.
I don't mind talking to people.
I love talking to you
don't get interrupted.
People have to,
you give sometimes.
Sometimes you do.
You know this drunk man drops for a while.
That's part of our business and they,
and they also want to like
have an interaction with you.
You ever have people call out your bits?
Like you're not doing enough that,
yeah,
they'll say do that,
but you know,
can't fuck.
It's really hard to do
a bit when someone asks,
you can do it cause
it's so and spontaneous.
It's also really hard to do a bit when
you know that they already know it.
Yeah.
It's like,
you know,
it's not not the same as a song.
It's weird because it was for dice.
Right.
You know when dice was at his peak.
That's one of the things is everybody
would like say the joke with them.
What's in the bowl.
You can also his audiences.
God lives in fear was that I am a part of,
I was probably in the audience.
I want to see dice in Vegas.
I had a good old time.
He tried to bad mouth me on the show.
No,
he didn't pay it and you
were covering for me,
you and Eleanor.
I hear.
I hear things.
Listen,
you guys kind of hug it out.
Hug it out as
too old school gangsters.
Dice,
dice friends at one time.
Yeah,
I know you were.
Yeah.
He's a good guy.
I like him.
He's not a good guy.
Good guy to me.
He's a good guy to you.
He's not a good guy.
I'm a good guy.
You're a great guy.
I'm good.
You're a great,
if I had to choose between the two of you,
take you.
Me Too.
You guys are all getting
in trouble now you guys.
I do.
I just wished the deicing died.
Let's dom,
dom.
I to be my friend,
my good friend since
like 1990 I love dice.
I'm a fuge fan of his.
I grew up being inspired by like dice,
but I liked him better.
I'm not just saying that,
but it just gets done.
Dom is my very good friend.
We,
we'd diamond,
I play pool every week.
I can't go without dom said the
sex have sex with dom or Andy.
Andy Roddick.
Andrew dice clay.
Yeah.
Oh,
I would dice as much harder than me.
Beautiful guys.
Softer and club.
More of a challenge.
The whole dice down.
Yeah.
I think it'd be cleaner.
That's what you could shoot as well.
For me.
It's gotta be some support in it.
I want to be fucking that dude.
It's got to be a bit of a struggle.
I think I couldn't do it.
I couldn't get a hard
on seeing the hairy ass.
You say that,
but what if that became your thing?
Well,
how's it going to become my thing?
You know,
if there's one skyrocket orgasm,
because apparently a big dude like that
can really clench down on his ass cheeks
and anybody getting hungry.
And when you score it,
you squirt like you've never scored it
before and then you just make a decision.
Okay,
you should write poetry month.
You've got away with words,
Labelle fuck game.
You know,
I've tried,
I tried to get over to Karma bit.
It's tough for me with the Italian
thing what him and I just hold grudges,
you know?
Yeah.
But I only have three.
There's only three comedians I hate.
Who are the other two?
Uh,
Craig Shoemaker and Bobby Collins.
Wow.
I can't believe you got that out of me.
I don't know.
Shoemaker.
I've only met him once.
Fucking asshole.
What's wrong with shoemaker?
Uh,
he's just a bragging cunt and
I said it with all due respect,
Joe.
He's just a,
you know.
All right.
I'll give you an example.
Okay.
I'm trying to clean up my Karma,
right?
A couple of years ago they said,
do you mind if,
um,
you know,
I draw well in Atlantic city,
so I'm going to do the regatta.
And they said he might've
shoemaker up was for you.
Now he was getting $7,500 to open.
So,
you know,
I was getting good money,
right?
So I said,
you know what?
Fuck it.
Go clean up the Karma.
Let them open.
Right?
That's 45 minutes
instead of 25 to fuck me.
And you know what he said at the end,
he goes,
I'll never work with you again.
And I said,
why is that?
And I'm thinking,
you don't got a chance
to work with me again.
He goes,
because I can't believe
you could follow me.
What a fucking ego.
What a jerk.
He was upset.
He was upset because I him,
he thought he buried me.
So was it like a Jew?
Was he like sort of jokingly,
uh,
jokingly praising,
you know,
he's just such a deck.
He wasn't joking at all.
He just really thought nobody could follow
him cause he got a standing ovation.
So I walked out,
I got like a fucking guy up for me.
It got a standing ovation
when I'm not going,
what am I supposed to fly around the room?
You know,
I mean,
and then,
but they were there to see me.
So,
you know,
it was,
it was not hard.
Really hard to bury someone when
people are there to see you.
I know he was just,
and I didn't even get laid into him.
Like what an ancillary was
telling him about the time.
Well,
I mean,
imagine just doing 20 minutes over
when you're opening for somebody.
Just money and fucking run.
Yeah.
Why did he do that to Jack Him?
No,
because I just didn't want
to communicate with him.
I didn't want to fucking have a talk out
with them and because I don't want to
be friends with them.
Right.
So that was it.
You were trying to clean up your Karma
and I blow it and then I blow Bobby
Collins at fucking Dick face.
Do you know him?
You know him,
Bobby Collins Shit.
I don't know him very well.
I know you never show.
He's the exact,
yeah,
I said to you,
he doesn't have a fucking honest bone.
His body,
so fucking phony.
He's the kind of guy,
he'll go,
this guy Frankie who used to
work at the comedy connection.
Frankie Baby,
look at you lost weight.
Frankie goes,
damn,
I look like I'm going to fucking explode.
I gained the a hundred pants.
I saw this phony fuck.
But that's the kind of guy he was.
So he demanded to,
uh,
we were working together at Staten Island
and I don't give a fuck about going on
first.
I don't give a fuck.
I just want to get the money,
have a good time,
get out of there.
And I was supposed to headline this
show and it said it in the contract.
So the Bobby Collins was
throwing a fit about,
he's throwing a fit about who was
going to close the show to watch it.
Pixie from Paul.
I'm looking at phony fucking smiling.
Hi Guys.
I'm a white boon.
So anyway,
he,
uh,
he calls up,
he wants to close,
cause he went to sell
merchandise after the show.
So the producer calls me,
they say quo Donald,
he's a good guy.
Oh fucking,
I don't care.
So she calls me and she goes,
you know,
do you mind if he closes?
I go,
look,
I'm a headliner.
I headline that.
You see what it says in the contract?
She goes,
oh,
I understand.
You're right.
I go,
I don't give a fuck.
I'm kidding you.
I said,
I'll do a meet and greet at the
beginning and then get out of there.
I don't care if they're going to pay me,
I'll do my best.
Anyway,
after that month later,
Mike Ivy,
my friend,
my black friend from Mississippi,
Tove Lo,
you know Nikki,
I love you brother.
And he goes,
uh,
Nikki,
all God asks you a question where you
opened them for Bobby Collins and Staten
Island.
I'm like,
what do you think?
Right?
So he goes,
no.
I said,
well,
it's not even worth
talking about is anyway.
I see Bobby at the common struggle.
Bobby,
you're fucking pathetic.
Dommy baby.
I see you.
Just pathetic.
And then I walked away and I was it.
So that,
that's so much for cleaning up my Karma.
This isn't on the air,
is it?
I don't think so.
Okay.
The cons are closed a
spring 2007 CFA season,
the laughter arts festival.
What does that,
what does the CFA
college of Staten Island,
that's where you guys were.
Oh,
that's funny.
It's great.
You can look at Schiller.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well I'm sorry you had those bad
experiences with those two guys.
But I mean I bet your ironed it out
by just out in them on the road.
You never had the guys just come up to
you like for some things you've said on
podcasts yet,
cause you,
you've been very outspoken with like,
you know,
I'm on the edge,
but I love most people,
very honest guy.
If you tell me,
you know that someone's been a con to you,
I always believe you.
Yeah.
I mean I would never,
I tried to like patch things
up and then I was wrong.
I was right.
I wish I was wrong,
you know what I mean?
I wished that I,
it was worked and,
but it didn't work out at me.
You know how many guys and these guys,
Oh,
do we do the thing about
Louis C k the shitty?
No,
you started it.
I was just talking about people I love,
I don't know what happened.
You know,
you and Louie and,
uh,
Bill Berg,
best best comics in the world.
Fucking that Taj and Louis used
to come into Montreal and uh,
okay,
so he'd be in the audience and the
character was [inaudible] ship balls.
That's the grossest,
and so I'd be hosting the show.
I go,
excuse me,
I think we've got a
celebrity in the audience.
And he put his hand over his head and go,
no,
I go,
is that you conti?
Is that you?
And he goes,
I said,
Connie Mcshane,
pause everybody.
Right everybody.
Yay.
Cause we had plants all over
the room and then he kinda,
he happens to have a guitar by a seat.
I go,
Connie,
how about a song?
No,
I can't play it.
Con t con t the whole crowds go and then
he comes up and does his fucking salt.
Oh,
he used to cry laughing.
That's Alaria.
I never seen Louie happier.
He loved doing the
character Cunty Mc Shit.
I Dunno if we had a middle name.
You know,
I,
I've said this before,
I'm gonna say it again,
but Stan Hope said this and
I never agreed with him more.
He goes,
I could quit doing comedy,
but I couldn't,
couldn't quit hanging out with standups.
Yeah.
So just to have that kind of experience,
be able to tell that story.
Oh yeah.
It's fucking fun.
That's actually your job.
That's what you do for work.
I do.
For a living.
Yeah.
I mean what we did last night,
that's,
that was our job.
We,
dom and I worked together last
night at the laugh factory.
Right.
We worked work and we're hanging out.
Just laughing.
And I remember so hosted some
shows thinking this is what I do.
I was,
there's one of you ever hear about the
guy who sticks to Roman candle up his ass
and,
and they light it and then it
flares and they play any works.
It's random too.
There's no business like show business.
Really?
Yeah.
Can you look him up?
You got to see this as one of
the funniest fucking thing.
Lights of Roman [inaudible]
sticks it in his hair.
Oh my God.
He pulls large pieces of
furniture out of his ass.
Remember that from a Jerky boys.
I'm also known,
so I'll have to,
dude,
I listen to some jerky boys the
other day and was fucking hilarious.
I forgot how funny the shit was.
How do those guys stopped doing that?
What happened there was so good because
the rules change with telephone calls
and people remember that.
Then they changed it where
you can only do it in Vegas.
You can only do it in Nevada.
Like make prank calls cause
all kinds of legal shit.
Plus people started getting,
getting onto it because they,
you know,
they're becoming famous.
That's why I wonder what the impractical
jokers you ever see that show?
Uh,
I haven't seen it.
Check it out.
It's really good.
Funny.
Yeah.
Excellent.
Did you hear about those practical jokers
that committed suicide in Australia?
What,
what happened?
Do you know?
Yeah,
so there was a hospital,
the WHO,
who is there or the queen or the
princess or what's the duchess,
the duchess,
whatever.
All right.
Some royalty was there.
And so,
uh,
this radio station had this prank
where they're going to act like the,
the mom.
So I guess the Queen,
uh,
and they were controlled.
And so they operate or like they
called up and they were like,
oh no,
I would like to speak to my daughter,
I don't eat or whatever.
And the operator just
let her through like,
Oh yes,
one second please.
Instead of like,
you know,
like how do I know this
is the right person?
And stuff like that.
And then,
uh,
they did this prank on the radio
station and I guess as you know,
because of the royal keeps trade
crown and she killed herself,
had herself,
if my,
my,
my granddaughter Kate
is my grand daughter,
Kate there please,
or she wasn't 30 said they
like immediately the people
on the phone really did
immediately give up information
about her condition.
Like they started just
rattling off the information.
They didn't like double check at all.
They weren't even remotely suspicious.
Talk about fucking up your day though.
Huh?
I mean,
everybody,
everybody loses.
Yeah,
the girl's dead.
The,
the,
the hospital security's a question now.
And these people lose their jobs.
They just meant to get a laugh.
Yeah.
Morrissey is really interesting.
You know,
Marcy,
the the singer,
he's blaming the,
um,
he's blaming Kate Middleton for the death
cause he's saying the arrogance of the
British royals is staggering
and that's why we're,
uh,
and why it's allowed.
I really don't know.
So He's,
he's saying that
the recent story about
the nurse killing herself,
there's no blame placed on Kate Middleton
who was at the hospital for as far as
I can see.
No reason.
She feels no shame about
the death of this woman.
She's saying nothing about
the death of this poor woman.
Boy.
Morrissey needs a fucking hug.
What a depressed guy.
What does that mean?
How does he know what
another person feels?
How can he say like,
she feels nothing.
How,
how can you,
how can you really say that?
Um,
what is,
what is someone say when someone
commits suicide over a prank?
Like that?
Yeah,
but you can't say she feels no shame.
She's saying nothing.
How did,
does she,
is she supposed to say
something publicly about that?
I mean,
what,
what obligations do you have to,
she has,
yeah,
she has nothing to do with it.
What obligations does she have to
comment on something that's obviously a
horrific thing.
And you know,
to blame her,
that's so ridiculous.
Silly Morrissey,
the idea of the royal
family is crazy though,
that the fact that you could give a fuck,
CNN had it on,
it was the,
the problems in Gaza.
Okay.
And CNN was talking about the dangers of
Gaza showed like some night vision with
a bomb going off and shit like that.
And then they said,
and you know,
Royal Kate,
whatever the fuck her name is,
is pregnant,
there will be another baby baby.
But you know,
next to it.
Yeah,
I know.
It's,
and it stands cause itself.
It's crazy.
Joe.
I was in uh,
Canada and when the Queen Mother
died at 102 I had a bit about her,
you know,
about it,
like she looked 101,
this whole thing she got
on the treadmill thing.
But uh,
I,
when I did it in Montreal,
it got an applause.
It's interesting how
people react to royalty.
When I did it in Ottawa,
which is more mixed Montreals mostly
French and a French and English,
but they're not,
they're not under the auspices
of the crown by any stretch.
Ottawa,
it a little bit,
you know,
laugh,
mild applause,
Toronto and nothing.
Nothing.
Not a fucking sound.
Yeah,
it did.
An American would have the arrogance
to come up and do something against the
Queen and that funny,
like the same fucking job,
just a couple of hundred miles
west boom.
Now it's very weird when you see people
that are really like it taken into the
royal family thing.
The oils like leave the royals,
they live their lives
that they read about them,
like as if their thoughts are more,
more important.
And yeah,
I was,
I'm making fun of the Queen when I was,
uh,
when I was in England one time,
I forgot which town were around,
but it wasn't like London,
London.
They probably would have
laughed their asses off,
but these people were like,
oh yeah,
you gotta Watch Manchester.
While I don't remember what town it was.
It wasn't Manchester.
Maybe it was new castle,
maybe was Newcastle.
Anyway,
wherever I was,
um,
I had this,
uh,
this whole bit about how people like try
to pretend that like that this queen,
this woman was like really like a queen.
Like you know that Princess Diana
really was actually a princess.
Like,
no,
that's just a person.
Like,
and she's a woman who didn't
even have a job and you know,
and,
and she tried,
she had a woman with children who
tried to kill herself like three times,
you know,
and I'm like,
how many people would be in
that same position and Leno and,
and be incredibly fortunate and feel
so happy that they have all this money.
How many poor people
would love to be married?
Wealth?
And she was like,
oh no,
the tiers code,
the crumpets a stale,
where's the razor?
I cannot possibly go on the tabloids
showed you a photo of my backside quickly
drained the pool that
will die from the roof.
This is horrid.
Horrid.
Life cannot go on.
And I have like a whole series of those
fucking things and they didn't know how
to react.
Oh yeah,
they started,
they still like,
you could see people like,
oh,
oh that's cause you're American too.
But they got,
they went with it.
They went with it.
Eventually,
eventually I beat,
I beat them down with
it cause it's just like,
come on.
It sucks when everybody dies.
It's like this is not a,
you don't need royals.
You don't need the ancestors of the
people who suppressed your ancestors and
give them some special favors.
This is crazy.
You know,
that's like,
but they're holding on to
that shit somehow or another.
And they've gone from being these,
uh,
these horrible dictators,
which they used to be to these weird
sort of benevolent people wave and hold
some strange position of,
of,
of like a,
a like a social example,
you know,
example of the perfect etiquette,
the perfect behavior.
Yeah.
I mean at least the pope was elected.
Not that,
you know,
not that his wealth that
shouldn't be in question two,
but they were just born into it.
It's craziness.
And then marrying into it
is even more hilarious.
They're over such as prejudice.
It's fucking nuts.
And everybody's following it.
I mean it's like so dumb.
Who was the one that gave
up the crown because he,
he,
he wanted to marry somebody remembered
that one of the guys gave up the crown.
Can you imagine how fucking hot that
bed to give up the fucking cram?
Yeah.
Well I bet in England
like being a royal is,
what do you think it's better though?
England or like in like Saudi Arabia or
something like that and like a Middle
Eastern country and uh,
you say that though,
but those Saudi Arabian
guys rocket way better.
Yeah.
They,
the Middle Eastern guys,
they rock it the right way
when they want to go balls out.
Yeah,
they do it.
I would pay girls hundreds of thousands
of dollars to be sex slaves and then
they have definitely,
cause you're not judged as much.
Nobody is rocking it.
Like those young chic
dudes that have those like,
like that one guy,
the sultan of Brunei,
that guy,
he's the guy that has like the famous
parties where he will fly out like the
hottest women.
Apparently it was like a dirty
secret for the longest time.
Pre-Internet.
He would get like the all the hottest
penthouse paths actresses and shit that
like,
you know,
weren't doing so well because you could
go over there and you could make like an
insect.
I'll give her a call and I'm not joking.
Yeah.
And I got a Gig with those
guys and they sent me a watch.
There was worth like 20 grand.
It's like ridiculous.
And they were asking me about Italian
batch were just so fucking funny from
Saudis that they knew
like Joey bag of donuts.
That's fun.
It's old shit.
That's hilarious.
There's those guys have so
much money that this guy,
the salt,
no Brunei apparently has
a disco in his house,
makes his own discount,
which is beautiful.
Unbelievably lavishly appointed disco
gold gilded work on the ceiling and
magnificent and just filled with tens.
She's tens everywhere and this guy just
goes out there and slides amongst them.
It has a cocktail mingles mixes with
the next group or they're all trying to
impress him and they're
all trying to compete.
And it was him and a few of his friends,
I guess.
I think it just fucking bang them.
Just walk every night and every night
he's fishing in this stock pond.
I mean,
it's really the,
nobody's ever been such a
baller because he's not,
he's not actually enslaving anybody.
He's paying them significant
amounts of money.
Okay?
He's not corrupting their morals.
They're willing to do this.
Okay.
There's nothing wrong with the exchange
because the amount of money to make an
is really fucking staggering.
But when you really stop and think about
like how many guys have ever done it
like that?
The Sultan of Brunei is
probably doing it the nicest.
Wherever everybody else who did it,
they did it with armies.
You know,
every,
every other guy that's
like lived like that,
they did it with swords and you know,
conquering towns and keeping
chicks in cages and shit.
This guy just pays him stupid
amounts of money based on oil money.
Wow.
That sounds like fun.
I mean,
I think pre Prince Charles is kind of
sad because he's at the point now where
he's like,
he loves his mother,
but you know,
mom,
could you die already?
So it can be King Charles
to be king before I'm 70 do
you know if she lives to a
hundred you know what the
fuck's going to happen to him?
Yeah.
She might outlive live him.
Yeah,
it's possible.
Oh sure.
You know who's under more stress?
No,
she's probably just nice and slow all day.
He's running around doing shit,
trying to fucking make ends meet.
Trying to put food on the table.
Dot.
My rarer.
They're poor prince.
What does that guy do all day?
[inaudible] you know,
she still play snooker.
Did you look something up?
Yeah,
but holes and fireworks and I just got
really lost and I found an old article
from 91 where you were with
Ellen doing comedy and,
and Miami or something like that.
Do you ever Bang her
Ellen degeneres?
Yeah.
Oh,
Hey,
talk to this week.
Sorry.
I gotta take a leak.
No,
I never bagged down now.
I Love Ellen.
I know.
No,
I worked with her,
uh,
that worked at her in Miami too.
If it's something,
it looks like it was 91
that you worked with her.
I know I worked with her.
Would see I need to
Atlantic city 92 for Hbo,
one night stand maybe.
Oh,
okay.
She's,
I didn't remember it all and do it.
I mean,
I know she did one,
but I didn't know she did it,
uh,
the same night as me.
Maybe she did,
but a great standup.
Ellen.
Yeah.
And did you ever know anyone that dated
her or was she always kind of like a
lesbian until the,
I didn't know,
you know,
I didn't know she was lesbian,
but I,
I,
I certainly approve of it.
Yeah.
Who was your gang like,
like,
you know,
when you were starting out?
Shecky Greene.
Yeah.
Bob Hope.
Really?
No,
can't come off that fucking old.
Who is my gang?
Uh,
well I think a comic strip.
It was like Seinfeld and Paul Riser
and Mark Schiff and these guys.
Uh,
and at the Improv,
uh,
with John Mendoza,
Carol Siskin and enough,
you know,
those guys.
But they were good friends and uh,
I would say was the most
famous that came out of that,
that channel.
He was a little bit before me.
I was,
I was acting still.
And Jerry was a standup already.
I paid to see don my rarer
before I ever did comedy.
Yeah.
If I,
if I,
um,
had done comedy,
I'd only done it like maybe once or twice.
Awesome.
Nick's right.
Yeah.
The funny was a place,
Joe,
not only did I say
[inaudible] Dahmer at next,
I paid two nights in a row because dom
could make in one night and his plane was
delayed or something like that.
And Denis Leary,
uh,
went up and that's how I
found out about Denis leary.
And Denis leary became my
favorite comedian for six months.
But I,
uh,
I paid,
we had some good shows on there
where before we were ever friends.
Yeah.
That place is a classic place.
So these people,
um,
did they get fired or did they quit?
Uh,
they,
they said that they were going
to leave the radio show until,
uh,
you know,
kind of tell a ship blows over.
It's a tough place to rebound to cause
such a small country if not in size,
but in population.
I don't think you can blame that.
Know the guy.
They're just trying to be funny.
If somebody would kill them.
So they thought that they would like have
a conversation with somebody who would
it be silly?
I mean,
they've done that before
with other people.
You know,
they did one of those with Sarah Pailin.
Remember those Canadian guys?
They called and they told Sarah Palin,
Sarah Palin,
yeah,
nobody killed anybody,
and so they were okay,
but that this is not okay
because the lady kills herself.
That's it.
That's right.
It's craziness,
man.
You can't blame these people.
You can say,
hey,
you shouldn't do prank calls anymore,
but I,
I don't think these people
should even be fired.
It's really what they
did was not a bad thing.
It was a silly thing,
but it's not a bad thing.
The woman was in the hospital
because she wasn't feeling well.
It wasn't like,
you know,
like there had been some horrible
accident and they were keeping medical
attention from her that was going to
save her life and it led to her death.
There was no obstruction
of health services.
It was just a silly thing.
You can't blame these
people for a fucking site.
I mean,
you don't know it's going
to backfire that much.
It's a bunch of pussies.
But Marcy,
Ooh,
how annoying.
Mustak IB.
Apparently Morrissey is a super vegan
and not only is he a vegetarian,
but he won't let anyone on his
crew eat any animals either.
So the crew guys will like get together,
they'll meet and one guy's room and
they order a bunch of Burgers for room
service and they hide and
one guy watches the door.
I'm not bullshit and I'm not bullshitting.
And they have to,
uh,
they have to have a fucking backup plan
if Marcy comes and finds him in the
room.
I love the honey bit,
by the way,
but never thought of that.
You never thought of that?
Yeah.
If he can start supposed to eat honey,
they're silly bitches.
No,
I'm sorry that I mentioned those
guys names because you said,
you know,
I forget how powerful this show is now.
Everybody's going to know who they are.
Well made them more famous.
Oh,
well.
Oh boy.
Do you have any response to
dom Irrera calling you a cunt?
I,
Tom and I,
we just need to get to get out
of the phone to kill this kid.
He says this,
we bust balls.
Hey,
I was kidding.
Bus Balls.
I was speaking of busting,
I was listening to a,
did you listen to or have you
been listening to ONA at all?
I know because they don't have
only a satellite in my old car.
You got it.
I have a tape deck.
Why don't you get in your new car?
It was your new car.
Satellite Ready?
Yeah.
Just what do
they do it,
it's really funny lately.
Well it's always funny,
but lately they had on Joe Piscopo.
Hmm.
Oh Wow.
And uh,
they,
you know,
they were busting Joe Pisco
boasts balls on the air.
It was fucking,
that was like muscle man think they,
well,
they,
what they did was they played some shit
from like the 1990s when he was in love
with this girl and he had like some
show and like he sang for like,
you really sang to her.
And now,
apparently 20 years later,
um,
he,
he's uh,
got it with these,
they've got restraining orders
against each other for domestic abuse.
They both have restraining orders
and,
and you know,
he's got,
he became like Joe Piscopo.
It became like this weird
sort of a caricature of who
he used to make fun of it.
Like that whole,
I'm from Jersey,
well now it's like he's
really weird become that.
Yeah.
And he tells like these
joke episcopal shows,
his live shows places and you fills
up these really small places and he's,
you know,
kinda scratching by and try to it.
And it's weird like hearing him get
fucked with by Opie and Anthony.
It was like really painful.
Like they were.
Why would he,
why would he do the show?
Cause it gets,
it gets people paying attention
to them when people go see him.
Even as a goof.
I mean,
look,
I would go see it if I knew
that he was going to be in town.
I would go see it.
Even if I'm,
I will go see a lot of things that I,
I'm pretty sure I'm going to suck.
You know,
if it's going to be an
inexperienced comedically though,
you could sit through it.
I don't think it's comedy.
I think he's like singing thank,
he's like singing songs.
I think.
I don't,
I don't really think he's doing comedy.
I think he's doing like a lot of Sinatra
songs and shit like that really did
stand up.
He did character pressures
of the sports caster.
I'm an entertainer.
I'm a triple threat,
but having him,
he does Sinatra.
Who else does he do there?
The artists.
The comedian.
What does it say?
The comedian,
the performer.
Is that his website?
Bruce Springsteen to snatch a
Gella take you to in the audience.
I know a thrill ride.
Every lane follow up.
Yeah,
seat belts.
I think he's mostly doing
like impressions and Shit.
Yeah,
that's the thing.
It's like a,
it's like an entertaining show.
Look,
look at him there.
Yeah.
Don't mind me.
I'm over here.
Yes.
If you don't want to subscribe to serious,
I'm sure you listen to some of the clips
online like the people take them fans
do and they uh,
they put them on youtube because
our show is still on here.
He was one of the reasons I started
this probably goes down here.
I don't know all the time man.
The reasons I started doing standup,
that was hilarious because he was so bad.
I was getting hired for
Saturday night live and they,
cause Eddie Murphy like Joe,
the only two people that kept,
I got hired by shine that lap.
They change producers and Eddie Murphy
like Joe,
they were friends and they
kept Joe because of Eddie.
And you know,
Joe was fine on the show
it on him and put him down.
But uh,
I thought to myself,
fuck this,
I can do that.
I could do stand up,
you know,
I became a standard cause I didn't want
to deal with the fucking agents and Shit
and you know,
policy or was this 1980.
Wow.
So that's when you started standing up
best at the Improv and sad passed right
away because I was already
a polished performer,
not to be a jerk,
but I had done so much acting and Improv
that stand up all I was really okay.
I just had no act and I couldn't
understand how standards had to repeat
themselves to,
to hone it.
That was the tough part for me,
you know,
so pissed Capone never
did a stand up and he did,
but he used to do this thing
where he'd come in and like,
you know,
you could see right through
it and then he'd go,
hey everybody,
I just stopped in to say hello.
Right.
And they'd be clapping,
you know,
like in other words,
I'm saying hello,
which is good enough.
Now if I happen to be funny,
great,
but don't expect me to be funny
because once I didn't live,
oh see that's what he would say.
Hello.
Famous.
How famous was he?
At one point I was really famous.
He was famous enough to
be on Saturday night live,
you know,
like that.
He was a pretty big name.
I know who he is.
I mean,
I knew who he is when
I was in high school,
so he must be,
he must have been really famous.
That was the 80s.
I wasn't one that was 80 for 80 on
that was a few years after that.
I don't remember what
happened to him after that.
Uh,
he's always a nice guy,
you know,
I mean,
I just,
uh,
I don't think standup was his thing.
He was listening to Ona town apartments.
So brutal.
Well,
he's from a different era,
you know,
he's,
we're a Sinatra era kind of.
Yeah.
And then even though
he's younger than that,
reading his tweets about it,
you know,
like,
like trying to like sort of
justify it and everything.
It's just like,
he's like,
he sacrifices himself so
he can get that attention,
but that is really the only
attention that he's getting really.
If you stop and think about it without,
without that kind of stuff,
without opie and Anthony,
they mean they really
are helping them out.
And Jim Norton actually
like put it on his,
uh,
his tweet,
like,
oh,
go see you.
I'm like,
he's such a good guy.
He's a great guy.
He really is.
He's my favorite performer.
He is because he's so unabashed
and unapologetic about it.
He talks about like Midi pussies.
He's like,
you could see like it's a little
hands get sweaty and his pod,
he starts squirming,
gets him getting dumped on that.
That makes,
that even makes me uncomfortable.
Yeah,
he's a,
he's not playing it clean.
He's done some wild shit.
Yeah.
Literally I was say I was
doing a Jimmy Fallon show,
uh,
about a month ago and my friend,
you know,
some people have no tact and I love Jim,
but you know,
nobody really wants to look like Jim.
Not,
you know,
not that they weren't so
looked like me either.
But she says to the guy who's a club club
owner of governors and brokerage where
I was playing,
you know,
you're out in the island cause
you look like Jim Norton.
He goes,
no,
I know.
I go,
she goes,
yeah,
you do.
You remind me him and I
go join and let it go.
Nobody wants it.
If you're going to say
he looked like somebody,
say you look like Tom Hanks or,
or not Tom Hanks,
Tom Cruise or whatever.
Somebody who's supposed
to be good looking.
You don't see Jim Norton.
You know how rude I know.
You know.
I wouldn't want,
you know,
to somebody saying,
well you look like dot Merera.
You're a spitting image of him.
Nice.
A little puffy,
overweight.
I like that.
Look,
when you see those pictures
of you back in the day dot.
Merera the video that we had on earlier,
does it make you want to
go hit that treadmill?
Yeah.
It doesn't mean there's Jim
that was a cover of one of his,
one of his cds I think,
or his book.
I think his book,
he's funny.
He's a juvenile jail.
The problem is they have a
Deli platter right at the end.
I do.
You know what I do?
I do exercise.
Yes.
The thing when I go to like get
my annual treadmill tests and all,
I'm fine.
I'm great in great shape.
It's just the eating and drinking so much,
you know,
and the hours,
the comedian lifestyle,
my friend too.
Happy.
Yeah.
What did Christopher Hitchens say when he,
uh,
he got cancer and died.
He said he burnt the candle at both ends.
But what a,
what a lovely glow it made.
I don't burn it at both ends cause I,
I get plenty of rest,
so that's okay.
I'm not saying it's okay,
but it's better than not rest.
And to take care of your health at all.
Do you like you would take
vitamins or do you eat healthy?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Do you know what we just read yesterday
that pizza was an antique carcinogen
because the effect,
I hope this is true,
the effect of the melted cheese on
cooked tomatoes with somehow like sofic
esophagus cancer,
it was like damn 50%
and a bunch of things.
Uh,
you know,
if you can find that it was great
cause it's like liberated us.
I know there's a,
a,
there's a nutrient and
cook tomatoes that uh,
apparently only,
eh,
it's only in cook tomatoes
that it has a certain effect.
Whereas it lycopene.
Yeah,
you got a,
um,
you have to cook it to get lycopene
and lycopene is how you turn into a
werewolf.
Doesn't sound like it.
Lichen Lycopene,
you hear me?
You follow me?
Like lupus.
I Dunno.
I'm talking about werewolves down.
Herrera.
Lycopene is a apparently,
um,
it's uh,
reduces the risk of breast,
prostate,
colon and other cancers.
Hmm.
A powerful antioxidant.
Pi Foot.
Christ swipe down.
He has lived so long,
by my way.
Am I right
on that?
A little gravy on this.
Take some humble you.
I made gobbly guts field.
That's when you know they're legit.
When they call it gravy.
My grandmother always called it gravy.
Get him some gravy.
Get degraded.
The only time we called the sauce was,
uh,
was like,
I'm
totally different thing like gravy
and also was like Turkey gravy.
You know,
that kind of it.
But great.
We were,
but red sauce was great.
Yeah.
It was never sauce.
You never called the red sauce
and you never had white sauce.
Get the fuck out of here.
With that.
What are you a Prima Donna?
What do you want to,
olive oil would call it a fucking massage.
You,
while you have that,
you can get that.
Look at this sexy fish right here.
Jesus Christ.
Sexy bastard.
Look at you.
Look up.
Kills who you are.
I said I love my cat.
You know those people
that always have to write.
All right.
[inaudible] material for great.
Wait til I leave.
I'm great and you're being very
disrespectful to have a cat.
Do you?
Do you still love your cat?
I'm not going to lead me into a bit.
Well,
if you want to talk to Brian,
he will be at the American comedy
company tonight in San Diego.
Right?
You feeling good for that trip?
You feel better and I can
feel like I could drive.
Definitely stay there tonight though.
Make sure you stay over there.
Don't try to drive back tonight now.
Don't do that then.
Good luck with the show.
Thanks.
Fine.
And we are
Tony Hinchcliffe.
Hassan's a fucking hilarious
up and coming standup comedian.
We've had him on a bunch of the
death squad shows at the Ice House.
He's hilarious.
Really good dude too.
Sarah.
Sianna also very funny also.
Very cool.
We've also had her on the
ice house chronicles as well,
and I'm now who's hilarious comic.
And if you use the coupon code end of
the days right now at American comedy
code,
you get two for one tickets
for the first 10 people.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
that's an excellent show tonight.
San Diego,
San Diego is really a,
there's quite a few uh,
comedy,
uh,
opportunities now.
There's two good clubs,
there's a,
the American comedy club and there's a,
an American comedy company.
And then there's Matt House.
My house I heard is awesome and you know,
I liked the little,
well,
and I did a theater though.
The comedy store.
Yeah.
I don't remember the theater's name,
but I did a theater there.
Um,
but it was whatever it was.
It was fucking awesome.
They gas place beautiful.
So happy then they're fucking,
San Diego is great.
I mean,
it's a little weird because you're
right next to Mexico and uh,
um,
you get a lot of people that come
over from Tijuana to watch the show.
Really that,
that was cool as fuck.
I met a lot of people from Tijuana
and they would tell me like,
where we're taking pictures together.
Hey man,
we came from Tijuana.
I'm like,
Damn,
you could just come over.
Like I was under the impression
that it was like really difficult.
You couldn't just like go out for a
night in San Diego if you live in Tiawana
like they wouldn't let you
because they would think,
why would you come back?
You know?
But no,
these dudes,
they were like legit.
They had passports the whole deal
and then they win a that's cool.
Yeah.
[inaudible] guys are coming at night.
The radio,
that was the Balboa theatre.
It was pretty awesome.
But yeah,
you can.
Uh,
did he get Viagara here?
You don't want that Mexican for too.
It might not be real.
I got bill burr on the
show tomorrow night.
It's a busting balls with Dom Herrera
at the laugh factory had a clock.
And so this is your show that people are
allowed to come in and they're allowed
to like yell out and say
things and what times of start?
Eight o'clock to eight
o'clock and it's bill.
Who else?
I Dunno who else on the show.
I just want to make sure I nail the bill.
Oh,
okay.
Because that sounds
like it'd be really fun.
That's tomorrow night.
Thursday night.
Well am I go by and watch that as a,
as a spectator,
if you want to say we don't want to spot,
you know,
it's open to you.
I need to start hanging out there.
It seems like everyone
is hanging out there now.
Well we went there last night.
Last night was great.
We can definitely make
that place do better.
And he was like,
you need a lot,
you know,
like the crowds are small.
Like for the sunset strip.
I mean we'd be packed the Ice House.
Yeah.
And that's,
I don't know,
the fuck got Pasadena.
They had been,
no,
you were going to be on at five o'clock.
That's what I'm saying.
Like we could have a,
we could have promoted that.
Yeah.
Tiffany Henderson is
always there and she's,
and she's,
you know,
she's one of the only people that went
through that camp that I still call me,
man.
She was hot then.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
Yeah.
Well,
it's a great club effect is great.
If we get another date,
Jamie,
so he can't talk to us anymore to figure
out a way we got to do my podcast with
just me.
Yes.
Yes we do.
Yeah,
please.
Yeah.
What we're doing next week.
Last week,
I got a couple of days off next week.
Next week's the end of the world tour.
It's only one day.
It's not really a tour.
That's the end of the world
show with a mad flavor.
Aka Planet Rock,
Aka Joey Diaz and Doug Stan hope
and great show honey honey band.
We're going to have them on the podcast.
Next money honey.
Honey,
honey,
honey band.
They will be here or ice house.
Probably do it at his house.
His house.
We'll do it at the ice house
cause we got the good Internet.
Um,
you ever do Tampa?
Yes.
I've done Tampa.
Bobby jewels.
I did know,
I did all the Improv,
the improvement side splitters.
My folks used to live out there.
They still live in Clearwater where
all the scientists Scientologists are.
That's where the Phillies train.
If it matters,
maybe they're Scientologists too.
Maybe that's why they do so well.
I'm doing that in January
with his Knoxville club,
which is funny because I can't draw a
fucking person in Nashville and Knoxville.
He sold out Nashville.
Tricky.
Why would I sell that Knoxville?
But Nashville is a particularly
tricky apparently for comedy.
Yeah.
I don't know why.
Yeah,
this,
there are cities where it's tough.
You know,
it's,
it's hard to,
you know,
they don't have,
they don't have a comedy community and
it seems like it wouldn't really make
sense.
I mean,
he gets,
it doesn't feel like it held up on music.
You know?
It's such a music town.
I get,
I mean,
if you're like a really big name
at southern that they like you,
they like the southern accent.
Yeah.
And guys like Louie,
who's like a example of a southern act.
It's like Rodney Carrington,
Jeff Fox,
where Jeff Fox goes,
guys.
Larry the cable guy or to Kevin.
He's a white crosses,
a lot of lines.
It then the Larry the cable guy.
Oh yeah.
They love him up in Michigan.
And because he's so blue collar,
you know,
it's so funny.
If he doesn't talk like
that at all at all.
And I love him and it's like if some
people have gotten insulted because he
doesn't talk like that,
I you will lead me on bar,
Sir.
I'm just here to make some money.
Yeah.
He uh,
I met him at a Montreal
comedy festival way,
way back in the day.
Yeah.
Really Nice Guy,
man.
Him and Todd,
she used to hanging out at the West
Palm Club coach called comedy corner and
that's where we got to
know those two guys.
And then,
do you know Josh Wolfe?
I don't.
Josh Wolfe is a open for Larry,
the cable guy and he was
showing me photos of it,
of being in football
arena.
Oh my God.
It's like 50,000 people to see Larry.
He knew it was so funny.
He was.
He was,
he was such a normal act as himself.
Yeah.
He wasn't bad,
but it wasn't good as Larry the cable guy,
he looked into something brilliant.
Yeah.
And he's great at it.
He's great.
He's so fucking badly.
He found that character
muscle fitness with Joe Piscopo on.
It looks like his head is
in planted on a muscle,
men's body.
It doesn't look right while he's
in fucking killer shape back then,
he's probably Royden.
Oh yeah.
Joe Piscopo.
Johnny dangerously girls like trying to
take him down and he's holding onto her
hand.
What kind of a fucking w what?
What does that statement,
why is she behind him?
She should be holding
them in front of them.
It looks like they Photoshop the cock out.
It's a weird thing.
It's always a smooth over his deck.
Those were darker days.
People didn't have as
many Cox in their life.
Anybody who was on the Internet.
That's my golden rule.
The Internet.
If you have a photo on
the Internet somewhere,
someone has Photoshop
to dick in your mouth.
It's just the fact there's
no getting around that.
I think that's better for everybody.
I was watching this show.
There was talking.
It was that you ever watch that Morgan
Freeman show through the wormhole?
No.
He narrates it.
Oh yes.
It's like a Cya discovery or one of those.
Yeah,
it blows.
It's mind blowing if you
haven't DVR did folks,
it's a must DVR.
Especially when you,
you know,
like if you're looking for something
really freaky to watch two o'clock in the
morning and they were talking about the
fact that just by virtue of the laws of
probability this,
uh,
I think that's what they were citing.
That because of the fact that the universe
may be infinite and what that means
is that,
you know,
we have a,
an idea that the universe is like
14 billion years old and it started,
there's a lot of people,
a lot of these physicists that actually
think that instead of it being finite,
like you can measure the
distance of the Internet,
that it might be infinite.
And if it is,
and I have no idea,
I don't understand any of it.
I don't understand how it
can be 14 billion years old.
I don't understand how
it could have 14 billion.
I don't understand how it could
have not existed in an existed.
I really don't understand it.
But what I do know is that what this guy
was saying was that if the universe is
infinite,
that means there's not just one but
several versions of you exactly out there
just because of the laws of that.
The fact that there's so many variables,
it's like it's like a they,
what they showed is they showed
this giant pattern of rocks,
like this huge pile of rocks and they
were showing that if you get a like this,
there's like one blue rock,
one white rock,
one black rock,
like in this order right next to each
other in this massive pile of rocks,
you're going to have this
occur x amount of times.
It's just inevitable.
It just will occur.
And he walks around and he picks it
out and then they were starting to talk
about the,
the distance of infinity and
the idea of the infinite.
And the idea that if that is the case,
there is so many possibilities
that every like one,
you know,
x amount of trillion light years,
there will be another
dom.
Irrera.
Exactly.
Well,
I hope you lost weight.
You know what,
I could just stop.
You know what?
I can't fathom 186,000 miles a second.
I believe the speed of light is,
and they say light years and then
they say a trillion light years.
That's fucking unfathomed.
I think it was several
trillion light years.
It was,
I mean,
hundred million light years
or something like that.
Uh,
I can't,
my mind can't.
We can't 93 million miles as a son.
I can understand that.
93 million.
I can deal with that.
You know,
the Earth is 24,000
miles around 93 million.
All right.
The Sun,
but fucking trillion light years.
Well,
what's really fucked up,
Homie,
me universe is that if the
WWE universe is infinite,
when you get to 1 trillion light years,
you're not even like
1000000th of 1% done here.
Like it never ends.
So it doesn't matter.
It's like,
it will go on literally forever.
So how can we get cocky?
I don't know.
How could we help people?
I think,
you know what's helped
people get cocky cities,
I think lights,
you know,
like light pollution,
security.
Yeah.
I think those old cave men,
people like they had a great reverence
to the sky because like at nighttime the
shit was overwhelming.
Like you would have Sunday time and then
at nighttime they were had to be nights
back when there was no
pollution whatsoever.
Especially high altitude people where
they must've just seen have low.
Yeah,
it's got to be lit up.
Everything.
So the,
the reverence that they must've had
for their journey on this biological
spaceship,
this organic spaceship
hurling through the galaxy.
I mean it must've been
far greater than ours now.
So like as we develop more and more
technology that allows us to do more and
more things that make us almost superhuman
in our abilities as far as like our
ability to,
to send information and receive
information and get questions answered,
learn things,
transmit data,
photos and videos.
It's like unprecedented.
Like it's nothing has ever
even been close to this before.
And when you see that,
like it really makes you wonder,
it really makes you wonder.
It really makes you wonder if like while
we're doing that and then while we're
blocking out all this sun with all
this light and you get all this light
pollution and then we have all this
actual pollution where we don't see the
mountains.
You know that weird feeling that you
get in la where you can't see the
mountains.
Then one day it rains and all of a sudden
you see fucking mountains everywhere
coming down such that there's a
snow cap mountain and you're like,
wait a minute,
what the fuck put that up.
But it's like think about that the the
areas where human beings are at their
biggest,
the areas where they're at
their most overpopulated,
that's you also at your most
disconnected from nature.
You're most disconnected from the view
of space because of the light pollution
you most disconnected from the view of
the mountains because of the pollution.
It's really fascinating cause that that
sort of mindset comes out of the lack of
reverence for nature.
The Moron mindset of the city.
Like that's like the,
the lack of respect for the fact
that this amazing deal with nature.
Crazy because it all,
it all happens in this
big and it's easy to do.
Like if you live in Manhattan and you
take the subway to work and you fucking
buy your food at this grocery store
on the block and your apartments,
I looked up,
why bother?
What do you give a fuck
if food's there you go,
you pay it,
you go to your job,
you get your money,
you pay for your groceries.
Why even pay attention to
where it's being farmed?
Weight.
Even paying attention to pesticides,
agenda.
They can genetically modified foods or
who has to go to war to control what part
of the world?
Why?
Why give a fuck?
That's the weird sort of an arrogance.
It develops and some
place where you don't,
you,
you're not connected to it.
It's like we're,
we're developing things in these cities
where we're escaping the connection of
nature and like creating it ourselves.
You know,
people that have those indoor greenhouses
and shit cause something bad ass about
it.
But it's something crazy like why you,
why you got all this food and under
lamps and stuff and like in a,
in a basement,
you know,
like that's,
I have a friend who would grow
vegetables in his basement.
I'm like,
what's wrong with the dirt?
But you should the dirt.
What are you do it?
Well,
some of it is this because
they can't connect.
They can't
raise things in the winter.
That kind of Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Oh definitely.
Yeah.
But agriculture to me and
you and kill the climate.
Yeah.
One day I watched those,
uh,
those Alaska shows where people are like
preserving all their food and getting
ready for the,
the cold to put the
fucking crazy in there.
How did those guys,
the Eskimos and all,
why,
why would you ask him?
Why would you stop there?
The end,
do it.
Whoever the do it,
what do they call it?
I'm not the idiot.
Well,
where it came from was,
um,
the people that came
down the Bering strait,
the same people that,
uh,
that populated North America
before the Europeans,
they walked.
Yeah.
But when you start,
when you keep walking until
you got a little warmer.
Yeah,
I would say so.
But you know,
they might've found like a good
check that doesn't mind the cold.
And they started fucking,
they had some kids and they couldn't
move to the kid got older and they said,
listen,
I know how to catch seal.
It's just stay here.
Yeah,
we got to make fires every night.
But so why?
We'll make a fire rather
than make it glues.
It's beautiful.
Well,
there's a place in Siberia called
the Thai Gow and there's this guy,
you mean you ever see that
documentary grizzly man?
No.
He ever heard of Werner
Herzog documentary and he's,
he got a bunch of really
good documentaries.
He's famous for his documentary.
That most recent one was about the,
you see that one about the cave paintings,
the cave paintings in France,
that really ancient,
incredible cave paintings.
But anyway,
this Herzog guy,
he's a really good documentary and he
had this thing about people that live in
Siberia and it was like happy
people life on the taiga.
And it's all about these people
that just fucking trap and fish.
And that's,
there's still their culture.
That's all they do.
And they trap and that pays for
like chainsaws and shit like that.
So that,
you know,
the tools are essential tools.
And then from that they,
um,
they,
they just fish and trap and
hunt all year that is there,
that that's their entire existence.
And apparently there's
like no mental problems.
Everybody,
like people are fairly
healthy is skincare to them,
that it's life is clear and um,
they,
they actually enjoy it.
Like they were all getting together
and they were talking about how,
what good fun hunting,
what do you want to do tomorrow?
Let's go fishing.
They fished and they hunt.
It's a good idea.
And they have to store up
a certain amount of meat.
So from that show I started getting
obsessed with all these other Alaska shows
and uh,
the show mountain men were these dude,
this one dude's living in North Carolina,
another dude's living in Montana
and other dude was living in Alaska.
But the guy living in Alaska,
it's live in the craziest fucking life
because this guy is a trapper and he
flies on a little plane hours into the
wilderness hours and then lands and he
has the same spotty lands every year.
He's got this clearance that he's made
and he has a trail that he's made and he
is a trap trail.
So he takes this trail with
a snowmobile and leaves,
traps all along the way,
and then comes back every
day or every couple days,
whatever,
and collects the dead animals and
he stays up there from months.
No people believe just by
himself in a fucking log cabin.
It's Khorasan like you watching
this guy's life and you go,
whoa.
That's where your fucking coat comes from.
Like that is something that's
a crazy lifestyle choice.
That's a correct whoever he'll go with,
stand up comedy.
It's gotta be the hardest
thing in the world.
I'm thinking liquid his life.
I'm obsessed with these shows,
man.
I'm set.
I'm obsessed with the idea
of subsistence living,
living off the land,
these people living off the land.
It's amazing.
And Alaska.
The last frontier is the best one because
they got really intelligent people.
That's a new discovery channel show.
They have these really smart fucking
people like you're hearing them talk and
like these are not
uneducated people there.
They're smart people that have lived
several generations up there in Alaska.
They're family was a escaping a war torn
Europe and so they moved to Alaska to
be homesteaders.
They got like this giant piece of land
starting to growing cattle out there.
So crazy fucking reality
that these people live.
But again,
they seem pretty fucking happy man.
You've been up there?
No,
never been to Alaska.
It's supposed to be amazing though.
It's supposed to be some Ma.
It's real game changing shit.
Like when you say like the the wilderness
up there that it's a state so far away
they say eagles are everywhere there.
Have you ever seen like any of those
videos of eagles like swarming,
like the where the fishermen go?
I'd never seen a swarm of eagles.
It's crazy.
I'll pull up a video,
I'll,
I'll get her out.
Death we'd okay.
Yeah.
It looked for m three g Carter while you,
yeah,
I have mine.
I have it here.
I should lock it in.
Uh,
but anyway,
the,
the um,
what do you,
what are you going to Google?
What's the exact term?
Swarm of eagles.
Butthole.
Yeah.
No swamp vehicles.
Salmon,
Alaska.
They,
they,
they swore,
I mean you,
you can't believe it though.
You're talking about like
30 or 40 bald eagles.
They're sitting on this lawn.
It's incredible.
It's really a,
one of those things that if
you didn't see it on the video,
you would think it'd be fake.
But apparently people
that go up there and say,
that's really what they're like up there.
There's a shitload of eagles,
but you still can't kill him.
Kill him.
Nichold a shitload.
Not like a gaggle
flock.
I don't think that was it,
Brian.
It was a,
here,
I'll,
I'll go vote real quick.
It's
crazy to watch.
Eagles.
Alaska
Eagles is called a swarm.
He goes on lawn.
Let's see.
Yeah,
but eagles on lawn.
Oh,
how bad are you a Google sign?
You just go eagles on law and first
video over 30 bald eagles in the
backyard.
It's these people.
They just got back from fishing.
And so they take these,
uh,
these salmons and,
the salmon bodies and they
throw the body to the,
uh,
the fish after they filleted it and like,
they're feeding the eagles.
It's fucking crazy,
man.
Where do you see all these fucking things?
Right?
Pick that one up there on that roof.
Let's go find some bald eagles.
Look at this.
Look at that.
They have a whole yard and all
of the roof was behind the yard.
Six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
They swarmed on you.
They could fuck you up.
Oh yeah.
Egos really could,
man.
Look at all of them.
It's amazing.
Those are bald eagles.
I never saw anything like that.
It's crazy.
Well,
people in Alaska,
man,
you get a see shit like this.
Yeah,
you do live in the frozen.
We'll new wilderness,
but you get to see shit like this.
This is a trip.
Now.
This is a protector it up in the last,
Oh yes,
they arm and they're protected everywhere,
but this is a part of your reality.
If you live up there,
look at this reality.
Your reality is you're surrounded
by bald eagles and mountains,
and especially like
right now in the summer,
it must be awesome.
The thing is like,
look at these kids walking up.
Wow.
I would not let my kid
go near a fucking eagle.
I would have a shotgun
and trained on those pugs
because eagles have
carried off babies before.
Yeah,
that's true,
right?
Oh yeah.
All these executives to just take these
children and he is an old picture of an
eagle trying to carry off a child.
There's a video of a
eagles killing wolves.
You got to see that.
Look at these fucking,
that kid has no idea how
different his life is.
Yeah.
Well,
they don't have any idea how weird it is.
See a gang of eagles in your backyard.
30 Eagles.
I thought there were solitary animals.
I didn't know they flew together.
I think there's so much salmon in
Alaska that when the salmon is running,
apparently they'd go bananas and they
just all get together and say fuck it.
Ari Shaffir did stand up in Alaska and
went salmon fishing and he said it's the
craziest thing he's ever done in his life.
He said it was amazing.
I shouldn't say it's the craziest
thing he's ever done in his life,
cause I wouldn't be,
that wouldn't be true.
But he said it was amazing and they would
eat raw salmon right from the side of
the boat.
That would just slap the salmon down,
cut it open,
take chunks out of it and just eat it.
That's correct.
He said it was delicious.
It sounds like the greatest Sushi
could ever eat in your life.
You think that's gross,
but yeah,
you had Sushi.
I know.
I just don't like the faces.
Faces.
Oh,
the faces.
You don't like the being
responsible for the death.
Have you ever killed a fish?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
We haven't gone fishing and all that shit.
But you always feel bad.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Yeah,
not me.
Not Fish.
I don't really feel bad about fish at all.
I mean,
I don't want them to be tortured,
but I will eat the shit out of them.
And if I catch,
if you hook them button in their mouth,
they already starting to torture.
Oh,
someone sounds like if Hagen,
no history person for if a fish
people for ethical treatment of fish.
I like to think of it pit,
if that's the cracks you have about
people that only their pescatarians.
Yeah.
It's like,
how do you know a fish doesn't
have fucking bad feelings?
Someone said this to my wife.
She said,
uh,
she said,
fish don't raise their babies.
I went,
whoa.
She was truly,
even dolphins.
Dolphins aren't fish.
Oh yeah,
they're mammals.
But she said no.
There's dolphins that are fish to whites.
There's dolphins,
Mahi,
Mahi.
Actually they call them dolphin fish.
Yeah,
I know what you're talking about.
that's fine.
Because I read that in a magazine once
when I was just starting to fish and I
was like,
why people fish for dolphins?
That's crazy.
It's not the same dog.
It's not the,
it's actually a fish that
the flipper type don't know.
Yeah.
It's not really called
a dolphin very often.
It's mostly called Mahima.
Good.
Occasionally on the break,
Casey,
man,
you don't give a fuck.
Dot.
Merera silly,
silly.
He's owed on the age.
All right,
Brian has got to get the fuck outta here.
We gotta send this boys.
It was fun.
I'll tell you son of a B all the
way down to San Diego tonight.
American Comedy Company,
eight o'clock show folks,
Tony Hinchcliffe,
Sarah,
Tiana,
Jason Tebow,
Billy Ball now.
And what is the,
uh,
the way they can save some money and if
you go to American comedy Co and to buy
your tickets,
if you use the coupon code,
end of end of days,
I believe it is.
Let me just double check the end of days.
We'll give you [inaudible]
for one,
uh,
tickets.
That's what we're talking about.
Folks were talking about end of days.
So if it is all over,
what do you want to do it tonight?
You want to stay home and watch TV or
go out and get your fucking freak on.
Okay,
go ahead and get your freak on.
It's gonna be fun.
Should be fun.
Uh,
all right.
we will be back Sunday
at four in the afternoon.
It very odd show with a very odd gentlemen
that will be Dennis Mckenna and uh,
that will be a,
that's going to be really interesting.
I'm very curious to talk to him.
Uh,
it should be incredibly fascinating
if you don't know who he is.
He's the brother of one of the most
famous psychedelic adventures of all time.
Dennis can a Terence Mckenna,
his brother and a Terence Mckenna is
responsible for probably some of the most
influential works on,
on,
on psychedelics ever
the most influential points of view.
And Dennis was with him through a lot
of that stuff and he's got a book on it
now.
Um,
a strange name to the book Brotherhood
of the screaming abyss or something like
that.
Sweet Dolphin kisses.
I don't think that's in there.
Hold on,
let me,
uh,
Dennis Mckenna book.
I want to make sure I
dom Irrera on Twitter
and as dom I r r e r a
at Don Maria.
This is what's important.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the two Rs is first and
please come to see me.
A good night's let me pack
the place on New Year's Eve.
I'm happy to go back to North Carolina.
Yeah,
that's a good club,
Charlie.
Good Nights.
We did rally recently.
Raleigh's fun man.
Brotherhood of the screaming your best.
That's the book.
If you want to read that
book before the interview,
it might be interesting to give you a
little perspective if you're down with it.
Uh,
but,
uh,
Dennis is a brilliant,
brilliant guy and uh,
he's an,
I don't even know how to say this.
Ethno pharmacologist and,
and a,
and an author and a well known
psychedelics proponent should be,
uh,
should be fascinating.
He's a brother to well known
psychedelics proponent.
I don't know if he's a proponent himself.
He's probably a bit Hedgie.
He's a scientific man.
This comes in.
I'm just a Gamer.
Joe.
Not sure why you want me to come here.
Sprung guy.
Um,
and uh,
again,
uh,
next week,
after,
uh,
Dennis,
which is on Sunday.
Monday we got honey,
honey and uh,
someone Tuesday.
Uh,
I forgot what.
We'll figure it out.
All right.
You dirty fucks.
Listen,
you guys have been fantastic.
Thanks everybody.
Thanks to uh,
um,
uh,
on at.com.
Yeah,
them too.
thanks to a bleed slinger plates.
Yeah.
It's a great grains from kerosene games.
It's available on the iTunes store.
Yeah.
It's only two 99.
And I'm cursing games,
which is our,
yeah.
How do you go wrong?
They're signing it,
losing money by not buying it.
So they're,
they're,
they're the,
the latest sponsor of this podcast and
kerosene games are committed to making
all of their games.
Uh,
originally for iPad and I
phones and now they're in the,
in the middle of a developing it
for the high end android devices.
That'll be January and February.
But it's a cool game.
It's great graphics.
It's again,
designed for the IPAD.
It's not ported over.
They're designed for it and it's only two
99 and they're supporting the podcast.
So go,
go check that shit out.
Throw,
throw three bucks the way,
pick yourself up a dope ass
game if you're into some,
because it's entertaining time killing.
And next Tuesday the 18th,
I am leasing my standup comedy special
and that will be live on Joe rogan.net
and borrowing from the Great
Louis C K it will be five bucks.
It'll be the same thing you'd be
able to download at a bunch of gray.
Yeah.
So please don't steal it.
Just go.
I paid a lot of money to make it.
Um,
but other than that,
uh,
thanks.
Thanks for everybody and thanks
for everybody to be here for you,
my friends.
And we'll see you all on Sunday,
right here from
the middle of nowhere,
which is the bottom of everywhere.
Exactly where it's just
the top of the beyond
the middle of the Infiniti.
Dot.
Merera I'll see you tomorrow.
Rocky.
Come coming back to Duke.
A busting balls with them or I will
come back to hang out with you,
dom Arrera wherever we shall go together
we shall be like Tuesday nights.
Dot.
Rare is almost always
at the laugh factory.
The night's going to switch,
but it's Thursday night for this week,
this week,
Thursday night and close with them.
Or he'll switch to build.
Thursday's a great night.
That's a good night out.
And that's probably go into a Thursday.
A lot of pros like to go out on Thursday.
Yeah,
you can get some fun times on Thursdays.
All right.
Get dirty fucks.
Thanks man.
Follow red ban on Twitter.
Red Ban.
Um,
he'd go to higher primate
higher-primate.com and
check out my tee shirts.
It's my,
a psychedelic monk and tee shirts.
I don't know how many of them are still
available and we sold a shit load of
them.
I over underestimate how
many people are buying them,
but we're getting all new ones in and uh,
we're getting,
uh,
we're going to be
affiliated with on it now,
so we'll have our distribution far easier.
Yeah.
I'm not much of a businessman,
folks.
All right.
You fucks.
We've got a lot of good shit coming up
and thanks for being here through all of
this.
We appreciate the shit out of you and uh,
we love you long time.
All right,
bye.
See you later.
[inaudible].