And where are you writing notes?
Yes.
What are you writing notes about?
Just things that would be cool if we
talk about.
What are you organized to do that?
Man,
I just know you don't like me looking at
my computer so.
Well,
trying to go analog.
Yeah.
I think both of us would be better off
in these things if we just said it's so
easy to just start reading computers,
especially when you read and shit that's
on the Internet.
Just to get when one person's talking to
start thinking about the next thing
you're going to read about instead of
just talking,
you know,
there's just too much.
It's too much coming at us.
It's like obsessive.
I like to obsessive Lee,
like fact check though and like make
sure I'm saying the right thing.
So you
get trumped later.
Yeah.
You uh,
you have to with this stuff.
But I mean don't think it's like harder
to form an opinion now than it's ever
been before.
Oh yeah.
It's insane.
I mean just looking back at old videos,
I'm like,
oh that's a different day.
You know,
I,
I should probably delete this now if
you,
you know,
like the,
the amount of data that you take in
today as opposed to just 20 years ago.
Like when I,
when I see something,
anything that's happened and I read a
story about something,
I got to throw it through like 10
filters.
I kind of like,
is this real?
This is bullshit.
Like who,
who's making this?
What is this?
Then you have to trust,
you know,
like every time someone sends you some
how,
what articles on.
That's what I always do with Eddie
Bravo.
Every Eddie Bravo hit me up with some
crazy shit.
I go,
okay,
what before you get too excited.
What website was this world?
Truther organization West.
You know,
like there's some nutty fucking articles
that are written that aren't real.
It's hard to figure out what the fuck is
really going on with some things.
Yeah.
And they're so tricky now to like go be
like NBC News Dot Com Dot Com.
You know,
I'd just like to.com.
There's fucking weird ones man.
Like I saw one the other day that I
think was a scam,
it was for some,
some fucking brain pill and it lead you
to some NBC looking website.
And I was like,
what is this?
That's what I'm talking about.
Followed this rabbit hole of,
okay,
what happens when you click that?
Okay,
what's going on over here?
Yeah,
it's like a fake cnn where it's just
like.
And it has like a,
like an article about this brain pill
and you're reading it as if CNN wrote
this article it,
there's a lot of those brain pilled
things too in the soylent soylent.
Uh,
it's like that all.
It's like a full meal.
Yeah.
And they,
they released these bars the other day
or recently and all these people are
going to the hospital and like they,
they,
they sent it to the lab trying to figure
out what it is.
Is this a fact check thing?
This is true.
And so they just recalled all these
protein bars,
like the whole thing.
And
it's like this one guy couldn't stop
throwing up and you have to go far just
from these pills.
Are these uh,
food bars?
Oh my God,
what's in these fucking things?
I don't know.
But the old soylent is people thing.
You think they would change their name?
Fucking giant line in a science fiction
movie.
A movie.
I know.
So I let green is paypal.
That's what they said,
right?
Wasn't that the line was in the movie?
Yeah.
Speaking of bullies,
but not really.
This is not happening already.
Should fear show premieres tonight?
Midnight.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm in.
He,
I know he's got a lot of funny fucking
people on the season.
It's a great show.
If you haven't seen it before,
it's really one of the best shows on
television because it's,
it's really funny.
People like Joey Diaz and I mean he's
had stan hope bond.
I know Rawlins is on the season.
Henry rollins notice I said rollins.
It's like when people used to pretend
they knew Eddie Murphy,
they just call him Eddie.
You know,
me and Eddie were tight.
We're just type me.
Uh,
you know,
just hang out together.
You know what,
you don't want to say his last name.
Like Eddie who?
Murphy Pro Murphy.
I'm trying to think.
Is there anyone that you.
I mean if you really were hanging out
with them,
like,
like sharing a pizza or you know,
would you call him by his last name?
Rawlins?
No,
I definitely wouldn't.
Not.
That would be so,
so like,
hey,
rogen.
I'd be like,
Oh man,
yeah,
that's.
But actually no,
that's not bad.
It depends on the length of the name.
Right?
Like if your name,
if you have a long crazy name,
like a fatal or a million Ngo,
if you like.
Hey,
a million inco,
like my name's faith or pitch,
just call me fader.
That's when you get a nickname real
quick.
Yeah.
You have to get a nickname.
You know?
What about Jerry Seinfeld?
You would probably say Mr Seinfeld,
right?
Or I would say Mr Seinfeld.
I said Mr Ventura,
when I met Jesse Ventura,
I called him Sir.
I always try to show,
especially to like older guys that I
like.
I was trying to show them a lot of
respect.
Yeah.
If I met Seinfeld for sure,
I'd called him Mr Seinfeld,
Jerry Seinfeld,
but if you're sharing a pizza like
watching a movie,
Mr Seinfeld,
let me ask you this.
It will be weird.
That's weird.
That's weird,
but let me tell me like some young kid
who's seen you online for all these
years,
hasn't done that to you.
Oh yeah.
We went in.
Friends call me red bad.
It's gross.
Like what the fuck?
My name is Brian.
People introduce me as red.
It's gross.
You're like a rapper.
You have a name?
Yeah.
Did you know,
did we already say this?
Did you know red man?
The rapper?
Yeah.
Has a group called death death squad
squad.
That's like simulation shit.
Holy Shit.
I had no idea.
It's like parallel universe.
It's fucking weird.
That's so bizarre.
It's so bizarre and totally independent
of each other and just think.
Think of like how many different
variables that are in between.
Is there a red baron deaf squad?
Redman deaf squad.
Larry is dude always go.
Eric sermon from epmd.
Dude,
he's like one of the best rappers of all
time and he's got like a weird speech
thing going on.
Right?
I don't know him.
EPMD dude.
I used to love epmd.
You don't know epmd.
I definitely know the name,
but that's a generation just above my
dude old school hip hop.
What's the main song?
I probably know the songs.
They probably just don't really have in
listening to their shit in a long time.
I used to be a giant fan.
Strictly business.
Yes.
There we go.
We'll go to like a uh,
an album strictly business was great.
You got to chose great business.
They still got my space.
How about safety profile?
Here's something that people forget.
Big Daddy Kane.
Follow the leader.
Yeah,
dude,
what was that?
Eric B and Rakim?
Eric B.
and Rakim was follow the leader.
Big Daddy Kane.
Goddamn big.
Daddy cane had a bunch of giant hits.
I met him when I was a kid.
My cousin loved him and he went to his
show in Florida.
Let's see what his.
What would the big daddy cane hits where
ain't no half stuff and I get the job
done.
Yeah.
He had a lot of great shit.
Taste the chocolate album.
He had a great style to like a great
smooth,
quick style of rapping.
I wish we could play some of this.
Hate is yanked off mother fucking juice.
It's too bad,
but it educate yourself folks.
Go get it.
Get Ahold of some big daddy kane.
Go listen to Kool Moe dee.
I go to work.
You gotta.
Think back then.
Rap was only a few years old.
That's what's even cooler about it.
Like if you listen to Kool Moe dee,
I go to work.
Let me take a guess because I listened
to that when I was a kid.
If I had a guest.
That's a song from the eighties,
right?
Yeah,
I would say that 1989.
Yeah.
Okay,
so I went to school.
I went to a a middle school in Jamaica
Plain Massachusetts when I was 13 years
old and I remember that's when that hip
hop hip it to the hippity hop.
That's when that was going on.
That's when the sugar hill gang had just
come out with the first rap music ever
that I had ever rather.
I mean,
there might've been some before,
but that was the first mainstream rap
that I was exposed to as a kid.
So that was 1980 I think.
Come on.
This is good shit.
Yeah.
Come on man.
Kool moe dee.
Look at the glasses.
That's great.
Now is this.
How does not get us kicked off Youtube?
Okay.
Let's hope Kool moe dee doesn't fuck.
Which I was trying to give you props
dude.
When ll cool J.
uh,
you know,
don't call it a comeback.
Came out.
I had a Ford Taurus and I had like the
best base ever,
but that time period of music was
exciting because it.
Dude,
ll cool J is a bad mother fucker,
but people don't like to give ll cool j
too much props because he's too good
looking and he's two years old.
Yeah.
He's always eating ice cream like it.
He's jacked.
He's built like a superhero.
It was a beautiful man,
somber form.
The summer in Columbus.
He was at.
He headlined a big festival and there
was a ton of the ladies that were just
rapping all his old songs,
like getting excited for the night,
like just walking up thing in the
phenomenon.
And did he.
Did he play the old stuff?
Yeah.
Even at one point I stopped.
The show is like,
right,
well you guys want some new shit.
You went to old shit and there was like,
oh shit.
That's crazy.
Wow.
Mama said,
knock you out.
I mean,
come on dude,
come on Song doesn't Jack you up when
you're on the elliptical machine.
It's a great fucking song and it's so
loud.
And going back to Cali,
Cali,
come on man.
He's got some great songs,
great songs.
Her Bikini small heels tall.
She said she likes the ocean.
She chooses to really listen to that.
I haven't heard that fucking song rules.
And again,
I mean think ll cool j one.
When was that?
When was going back to Cali?
That was probably the nineties.
Yeah,
80.
Same.
Same time period,
right?
Eighty nine.
80 seven.
What about um,
uh,
go to work that what we just said that
it's 89,
right?
Yeah.
So what about,
uh,
going back to Cali
88,
89,
right.
I was a middle school.
80 nine.
That's insane.
Yeah.
I was just about to graduate high
school.
No,
I graduated high school.
80 five.
80 nine was.
I thought that's so weird.
My brain works.
I think of graduating high school.
80 eight,
87 released January 27th,
1988.
[inaudible] 88.
I think of a graduating high school and
the day I started comedy I superimpose
those times,
like literally are you think of those
are the two milestones of my youth for
sure.
Graduating high school,
1985 and then starting comedy 1988.
Those are the big milestones.
So sometimes I confabulated them.
Is that the word?
No,
might not be the right word.
Stepped out of my lane again.
Do you have one of those word of the
day?
Like calendars and everyday you,
you,
you look at it?
No,
no.
I just try to find a good word that fits
my friend has one of those and every day
she tries to use a new word and I'm just
like the word,
isn't it?
What is this?
Okay.
In Psychiatry,
psychiatry.
Confabulation is a disturbance of memory
defined as the production of fabricated,
distorted or misinterpreted memories
about oneself or the world without
conscious intention to deceive.
Never used it.
Right.
How do they use it again?
What did I write that I confabulated
them,
but I know that I'm wrong once I say it.
Okay.
So it was a disturbance of memory?
Yeah.
So it's right.
Confabulation.
Okay.
Yeah,
I did.
Um,
I think about it man.
Think about those like the date you
graduated high school.
Did you ever have nightmares that you
had to go back?
That you didn't take tests?
I slept through most of high school,
like the whole,
the whole school I was sleeping so it
was all a dream to me.
I actually probably slept honestly,
40 percent of high school.
Why?
Because I only liked art class and
that's all I liked.
I hated everything else except English.
I liked English class because I liked
like stories and writing crazy shit.
I have to bring this up because I
brought her up on the podcast before
there was a guy,
I think I told you that,
um,
when I was in high school that I had a,
an art teacher that was just a Douche
bag.
He just was not nice and he was like
really negative and he must have been
depressed.
I mean,
the guy,
he was just wasn't a happy guy and um,
he made me stop doing art because I
didn't want to be in his class.
I was like,
he was just,
he,
I liked frank frazetta illustrations and
I like comic book illustrations.
That's what I was really into learning
how to do and this guy was just like
pissing on dreams,
you know,
just saying like,
you'll never be able to do that.
You're going to have to be able to do
advertisements for magazines that's most
likely where you're going to work.
He was just super negative,
but there was one guy in the class that
was the most talented guy by far.
His name's John Devor and I talked about
on the podcast and John reached out to
me,
Oh fuck,
John Got Ahold of me and um,
he told me that he fucking quit that
guy's class.
That guy failed him.
And I'm like,
and this guy was insanely talented.
He was like,
this is like,
I was always pretty good,
but there was always,
it was another guy in our class.
It was better than me too.
His name was Kevin.
He was a football player who's a big,
stocky fucking dude.
And his brother was on the football
team.
Got Damn.
I wish I could remember his last name,
but those were the two guys.
I was like number three.
Those are two guys who they were.
And it was all this.
We all did the same style of was all
comic book,
illustration Type Shit.
And devor could draw like he was the
most versatile.
He could draw like things like he could
draw a beautiful things like huge,
huge or rose or you could draw a
monster.
I can only draw monsters how to draw and
look like shit,
but I draw a fucked up,
you know,
Werewolf's for something like that.
And so that was into that kind of stuff
and in all three of us were into like
that sort of comic book style aren't.
And this fucking teacher just,
she,
I mean he rather uh,
got the most talented guy in the class
and gave them an f.
yeah.
When he told me that I went what I think
he said give him an f that's fucked up.
And that teacher went in,
exists in today's world because you
would have filmed him,
you would have put on Youtube.
But when it became a news story,
it would have been like checking the
teachers is like another big thing where
it is.
But it's when a teacher has tenure,
it can be really difficult in certain
schools,
you know,
I know they have that problem with that
in certain universities.
Teachers have tenure,
like you really can't fire them.
And once they know they can't be fired.
Like if they can be like really,
really radical and some crazy fucking
ideas and teach your kids some shit that
you don't agree with that no one agrees
with and if they get into a university
and they get into the system and your
kid winds up in their class,
I mean some really crazy teachers out
there and there's this guy in Toronto
who is a professor and they are
demanding that he take a sensitivity
courses and all kinds of crazy shit and
they're calling him transphobic because
you won't use the 28 different gender
pronouns that are available today.
Like 30 fucking gender pronouns.
So talking to him.
They're calling him transphobic and
gender binary gender believer and this
guy is a lashing out.
Instead of backing off,
he's decided to make more and more
educational youtube videos about what's
wrong with this kind of censorship
because he was.
He saying is,
and I agree with this,
if you look at a lot of like what's
going on with like maybe what people
would call a social justice warrior or
people want to shut people down from
being able to say something.
What's going on,
it's like there's this need to control
and there's a.
there's like a need to control other
people and to push your idea on other
people whether or not they agree with
you or not.
That mirrors the same thing that happens
with religions.
It's like you might be right or you
might not be right.
There might be an argument against what
you're saying that you might have to
consider like in that one when people
get an idea one way in their head,
they don't want to consider any other
possibilities and when you see these
kids rallying against this professor,
it's never been more evident because
this professor is brilliant and what
he's saying is nonemotional and he's
talking about the problems with how
these things are defined and one of the
things is he brought up this DVD that
one of the teachers of this course was
making about how to.
How to make sure that you're not
subconsciously biased or subconsciously
a prejudiced and the dvds were like 700
bucks or something like that for a DVD
series.
Yeah.
Well this guy outlines all of this in
his.
In his video,
in this youtube video,
and he's like,
this is craziness like gold.
This is that.
This doesn't make sense.
It's never been proven to work.
Like in the idea that there's
subconscious biases that you're accusing
someone of being guilty before you're
ever even talking to them about
something.
I get it like you don't even know.
Saying a subconscious bias is a very
strange thing.
Like,
boy,
how do you know if you have that?
It's subconscious like you can't even
like you're,
you're,
you're making people think they're
guilty.
Even if they're not.
Like if you say you have a subconscious
bias,
that's one of the things that people do
when they're super,
super liberal in order to prevent from
other people think and they have a
subconscious bias.
They go way out of their way to show no
bias whatsoever and even favor something
that people would be biased against.
Like there's super and a gay marriage.
I love seeing gay couples.
It's amazing.
Do you love seeing heterosexual couples
to like,
or do you just freak out over gay
people?
Like what's going on?
You know,
I like seeing people in love to,
but I really don't.
You like seeing all of them.
I like seeing the whole batch.
It's nice.
It's very exhausting nowadays.
Like April in love,
just everything.
Like the how you're supposed to act,
what you're supposed to say.
Ridiculous.
There was a last night I was at this bar
and this,
I thought it was sitting next to a,
a taller woman and then she looked up,
she looked over and it was obviously a
post,
you know,
like a transformation and a transgender
woman,
you fuck,
you have to say the right word,
but you have to say the right word.
She transformed.
Uh,
anyways,
so,
but then the whole time she.
Right,
right.
She kept on looking at me as if that
person was way taller and so if it was a
guy it would be a big giant guy just
staring at me.
So either way I feel I felt like freaked
out about it,
you know,
so I might not allowed to be freaked out
because she's a woman now that some guys
staring at me.
Woman.
Yeah.
Well everyone's staring at you.
You're allowed to get freaked out over
anyone staring at you.
I mean,
if a little kid was staring at you like
mad dog,
New News,
10,
you're like,
oh my God,
am I have to fuck this?
Ten year old up anybody staring at you?
It's not good.
I didn't know how to act as.
It was weird though.
Stand your ground.
You have ground.
Can you get your back up?
Get your particles up.
It's weird.
If you don't want to vote for Hillary
this election.
People kind of think that you hate women
essentially.
I don't know that it's
essentially just fools.
Just fools.
There's people that are.
What's the.
It's an obvious target,
right?
You don't vote for because you hate
women.
You just.
You don't understand what a milestone
this is,
man.
You don't care because you don't fucking
care.
Okay?
You know what you're worried about,
man.
You worried about going to the gym and
being a Bro.
Okay,
so why don't you do that?
I want you to go to gym and be a bro and
leave the fucking voting to people who
care.
You know,
those super like aggro,
progressive type people.
Like I remember I was in a bar once in
New York and I was having a conversation
with this,
uh,
this girl who was a waitress and the
bartender got so aggro bro on me and it
was a,
it was about the,
it was the Oj Simpson case where like Oj
Simpson had been accused of domestic
violence before,
like before the murder.
It was something like that,
something along those lines and our
member,
all I asked was,
I said,
that's interesting.
I said he was accused of being,
but he was acquitted and the,
and the guy just totally ego brought me
in.
He goes,
listen man,
when a woman says that something
happened,
it fucking happened.
Okay.
Until you know better.
It happened.
Like,
but didn't you just say he was
acquitted?
Like I think he probably murdered his ex
wife and that dude.
But didn't you say that he was
acquitted?
Like you can't,
like you can't,
you can't attack that in there.
If he was acquitted,
we don't really know what happened
unless you were there.
We know that a court of law found that
he wasn't guilty of it.
Is that because he had a lot of money?
Is it.
Did it.
Did he never go to trial for that?
Was it just something that somebody
accused him of dropping and then drop
the charges?
What was it?
But he didn't want to hear none of that
dude.
He wanted to come strong with the ECO
bro.
He just puffed up.
I didn't even respond to them.
I remember going to look at this silly
fuck.
This is ridiculous.
He got so aggro with me.
Did you watch that make and made in
America the ESPN 30 for 30 on the trial
yet?
No.
It's available on demand.
I'm.
They probably leave it up there for
awhile.
It's still.
As far as I recall,
I looked it up.
It's the only place you can find that
show.
The actual photos from the crime scene.
Photos of autopsy.
Photos of,
of Ab Nicole with like a slashing her
throat can see Ron Goldman to.
They don't show up when they hear it on
TV,
so if you're watching it and you can try
to catch it there,
because I tried to show it to my friend
that,
uh,
the other day I was like,
wait,
right here,
it's going to come up.
And then it didn't take the,
cut it out.
It's literally only on,
on demand if you want to see it.
Wow.
There's not,
you can't even find them online anymore.
I don't know how they kept it off the
web,
but it's amazing how some things can be
kept off the web pretty easy nowadays.
Like it's like,
I forget what it was recently where
they did just the best job.
Oh,
those photos of uh,
the SNL girl.
Oh yeah.
And uh,
those were just gone,
like every link dead,
like there was not one place to find it.
It was really well done.
And it's weird.
How did you hear four chance closing?
Uh,
they're,
they're going bankrupt and it costs
money to run for town a lot.
And the servers mostly lead must get
mad.
Mad.
Crazy traffic,
right?
Yeah,
it's weird.
All our websites are dying.
Remember style project and always used
to talk to that dude on the phone.
Jay Style even dig.
I don't think I've been a dig in so
long.
I don't even know if that's still
gigs there.
Yeah,
yeah.
I go to dig all the time.
Yeah,
you get crazy stories.
Dig is like one of the one stop shops of
getting interesting shit online.
For me,
I'm like,
what the fuck is going on in the world?
I'll go to dig and dig will be about
some new scientific adventure next to
you know,
some new fucking paleo logical fine next
to some new technological discovery next
to Nino,
new cell phones,
new cars.
Like it's all kinds of crazy stories
come out.
It seems like when Kevin left I kind of
just stopped going.
I started using reddit more and Fark.
All those are great,
but to me it's a super easy one.
Stop.
What's the weird shit?
You know?
And always like weird,
interesting things.
They'll,
they'll aggregate these stories from all
these other different websites and stuff
too.
It's a,
it's like it's easy to go to someone
who's already done the collecting for
you,
you know,
like the,
I,
I believe in supporting collectors
because I don't,
I don't have the time to do that.
You're going out and finding all these
cool stories about space and you're
putting them up in one spot that's very
valuable because it's like a Dj there,
like a Dj for stories because they're
not just covering any fucking story
because if they covered any fucking
story it would be boring as shit.
You know?
There's a lot of stories that are going
on.
They're just like,
oh,
that's not that good.
But they figured out like,
what's the juiciest shit?
Like what's the more interesting shit?
What's the,
this,
what's the debt?
And they shuffle it all in together and
you always can get something fascinating
out of it.
It's very addictive man.
Like looking on the Internet for those
stories,
like weird,
crazy fucking scientific discoveries and
it's,
it's very addictive.
I went deep jewelry that I just like
when you get deep into a subject and
then you start watching videos and start
learning more.
And then if anyone asks happens to ask
you that question,
you'd be like,
oh,
I know everything.
Like I,
I went deep on toaster ovens.
So if you need any information with
toaster ovens,
I know all the recent news on toaster
ovens,
but I went so deep I just laid in bed
for two hours watching reviews of
toaster ovens.
And Dude,
you're the go to toaster oven guy.
Tell everybody do you have a toaster
oven?
It's great.
They're great.
I've never had one.
You know what?
They're really good forman.
English muffins with like a tuna fish on
them.
And a little cheese.
Why that bitch?
Damn.
He just made a face like he's disgusted.
How dare you?
Yeah.
Martin,
you can put a chicken in it,
but you know,
you don't believe in a tuna melt with
the English muffin.
No.
You would need a tune them out.
Tune has got a stench to it that someone
doesn't need.
Post.
Someone doesn't meet you.
Like when you have fraud.
What is the fresh?
My,
my,
my.
Yeah.
Yes.
So like that.
And I know it's different from what it
starkist and a little pouch or whatever.
Obviously way different tuna.
But to me when it's out in the open and
someone who's just cooked it,
it just fills up the room with a fucking
stench.
That's why you have mustard and Mayo.
Hm?
I don't know how to describe it.
Smells like the ocean.
Real weird.
Yeah.
That doesn't bother me.
No Shit though.
You don't want a bunch of weird shit
with your food guy.
Eddie Bravo has got an onion thing.
If he gets unused something he'll
fucking throw up.
Really?
Yeah.
Hates onions.
Hates him.
Why?
Stepfather was a dick and his stepfather
used to make them eat.
So Vj and still to this day,
she's onions.
He wants to fucking throw up.
Wait.
Who wants being made to eat?
So Vj,
vj is great.
Hey Man,
I wasn't there.
What the pot.
I don't know what went down,
but that is my boy.
Yeah.
They just can't eat.
He can't eat any onions.
He like.
He,
if he gets on until fucking puke.
Tau is a.
She is Korean.
So she eats all this,
fucked up Kimchi,
do.
She eats eyeballs,
she loves eating fish eyeballs.
She'll just go up to a fish and pull up
the eyeball and eat it.
I'm like,
what are you born?
And she had this like,
her mom is sick.
So she went to go visit her mom and so
she opens up this thing and she got.
She's like,
mom,
I got you everything.
And it was like every thing that you
wouldn't want to eat like a pig,
you're a pig feet like cow noses.
Like it was just like a smorgasbord.
There was one,
not one thing that I would eat in,
in this whole tray.
And it was like a Delicatessen to Whoa,
where did the balloon?
That's Philippines.
They love that stuff.
We used to serve that on fear factor as
a,
like a hard thing to do.
And my Filipino friends because in pool,
like a lot of the best pool players in
the world are Filipino.
So I played pool a lot.
I was always around Filipino guys and
while I was doing fear factor,
I played a lot of pool.
This fucking dudes.
They were like,
I'll eat that shit tomorrow.
Like bring somebody.
Didn't you got any leftover?
They wanted to eat it.
I was like,
we made people eat that stuff is if you
don't know what we're talking about,
it's a fetus to duck fetus that's in.
It's like it's cooked in the yolk.
It's really kind of fucked up.
It's kind of gruesome and it looks like
a duck.
Like the picture.
I remember it looked like a baby duck
that you'd just eat a baby duck.
Yeah.
I didn't know until I was like fucking
39 years old or something.
I mean,
I don't know how old I was when I found
out that uh,
of
a chicken egg doesn't become a chicken.
Like I never thought of it.
I never even thought of it.
Like,
of course it can't become a chicken.
That's just like,
I thought he had to describe them quick
for the chicken,
eat them.
Don't get if you got them
early,
but if you sat on them then you're going
to have to take care of that God damn
chicken because it checks going to be
born.
And that's what I thought I felt you
like you had to eat the eggs quick
because they were just going to become
chickens.
Because in my mind,
and this is as a dopey child,
I felt like once something's out of the
body,
well it's obviously,
it's just that's how they do it.
They,
they lay their eggs and then the things
come out of the eggs.
It's out of the body.
It must have given birth.
Like in my mind it has to be.
It's an egg.
It's in a shell.
It gave birth.
So I didn't understand that.
No,
it has to be a fertilized egg.
Oh.
So what happens then within all that
shit that's in the egg,
all that shit becomes a little.
A little bird.
But birds are such hose.
They're so goddamn prolific that they
drop an egg every day.
I know I might have birds that I have
chickens to drop an egg every day.
That means everyday they,
they want to be shitting out a baby.
As your cholesterol or anything gone up
since he got these chickens is a
gigantic myth.
Dietary cholesterol
strong according to the most recent
science,
according to people that are way smarter
than me.
Okay.
And I know there's some disputes on this
amongst people that are plant based,
people that believe that you can get
everything that you,
uh,
you need from vegetables.
But um,
I think dietary cholesterol is less
significant than sedentary lifestyle.
Less like genetics are a huge factor in
having high cholesterol.
And then there's also,
I've come to learn about ldl cholesterol
and hdl cholesterol and that having a
higher levels of each other can balance
each other out.
And it's not necessarily the level of
cholesterol they're concerned with.
It's the type of cholesterol.
So it's,
it's not food,
it's not like dietary cholesterol is
actually important for developing
hormones.
It's actually an important factor in,
in your,
your body having the proper nutrients to
rebuild itself.
Like dietary cholesterol is actually
good for you.
We've been fucked.
We've been fucked by these food
industries.
There was an article today from Arab
Technica and how do you say that?
Ars Technica where they were talking
about the sugar industry,
the Soda Industry,
paying off people to lie about the
negative health effects of sugar,
of sugar in these sodas.
W when we forget this,
so this were created as a desert.
You're not supposed to drink it as a
beverage.
Really.
It's,
yeah,
it was supposed to be like,
oh,
after dinner maybe we can all split a
coca cola.
Big Soda is
buying off health orgs to keep profits
in Americans.
Fat Top Producers Back 90 six national
organizations defeated $29.
Proposed regulations.
Whoa.
And now I switched to Arnold Palmer's a
few years ago,
an ice teas.
Rest in peace.
Arnold Palmer.
But uh,
uh,
I don't know if that's better though,
because the sugar of the lemonade
probably not,
but it's,
it's prob half a glass.
Well,
it depends on how much,
how many grams,
you know,
really you would think there's some,
there's a new soda that they sweetened
with Stevia.
Wonder if it's any good.
It's gross.
I saw somebody was drinking it.
That's a very health conscious.
The other day I looked at them drinking
it.
I tried to.
What is it,
the trader Joe's or the whole foods?
A Stevia Cola and it tastes like RC RC
Cola.
Nate Diaz.
Nate Diaz was drinking it.
Nate had it on his.
Uh,
I think that.
Is it.
This is it called Xavia.
Nate had it on his instagram page.
That's.
Look,
I like Stevie and coughing.
I like it.
It's different than soda,
different than sugar,
but at least I know it's not fucking
man.
You know,
starbucks just finally got Stevia and
almond milk within the last month.
There he goes.
Yeah.
And you know,
if,
you know nate,
nate is super health conscious.
He eats real clean.
They,
uh,
once they really got deep into like
triathlons and stuff like that,
that's when they really,
like.
Nick was the first one.
He really met a bunch of people that ate
really clean,
all these racers and then you realize
like,
oh,
okay,
like organic foods,
way better for you.
Oh,
there's,
oh,
okay.
You know,
don't eat pastas and breads.
And then they,
I think he cut out everything except for
fish.
I think it was like no land animals he
was doing for awhile.
But he might even be full vegan now and
his brother's gone back and forth.
Sometimes they take in fish and I know
that they were eating eggs.
Jake shields eat eggs,
you know,
like a lot of those guys hanging out
together and they have a real similar
diet.
But um,
the um,
those guys,
if they're drinking something like that,
like that cvs shit guarantee.
It's not bad for you.
Steve is just not bad for you.
Right?
Like,
I've never seen any negative effects of
Steve.
I thought there was that because I
remember I was really big in the Stevia.
And then there was an article that came
out about something that I was like,
Yo,
I'm just going back to sugar.
I'm just sick of this.
My only sugar that I really take now is
like,
I get some sugar in my ice coffee
instead of putting sweeteners in there.
I just put it in your.
So you get an unsweetened and dump it
in.
Yeah,
just a little bit man.
But I don't know how bad that is.
And I've cut down starbucks now.
I used to do it every day,
like one of these every day.
Now.
I did it like twice a week.
I think they're saying more and more
that it's just not good unless it's in
the food naturally like sugar and when
it's connected to all the fiber
and all the vitamins and nutrients in
like an like an orange or something like
that.
Like you know,
there's some juicy oranges that you get
that are probably better than any
dessert you ever have,
but isn't there like a factor in
desserts that you know you're not
supposed to be eating that shit.
They know the thing I missed the most
and it's hard to get out here in
California or at least I,
unless you go to like a,
like a market or like a outdoor.
When those is a peach or,
or a nectarine or a plum.
That's actually nice.
And were you in Ohio?
You would just bite these humongous
peaches and they just melt in your mouth
out here.
They're like hard as a rock and then you
might,
you just have to kind of wait for them
to get like mushy one day and go,
okay,
now it's mushy.
Mushy is not the same as
catch them and season.
Yeah.
I think.
Look,
it's dry as fuck out here.
I bet a lot of like fruit trees and
shit.
I mean we're good.
We're good for almonds,
man.
This is what California is good for.
Almonds.
Oh,
here's some shit I found out.
Okay.
When I was at the home ranch that to
hone ranch,
they have pistachio trees,
but they graphed the pistachio leaves
and branches onto another sturdier tree,
like an avocado.
Cool.
And so you've got like a pistachio tree
growing out of an avocado tree.
That's awesome.
And the dude was telling me,
I was like,
what?
They can do that.
Did you know they could do that?
I think they,
they do a lot of things like that in
farming nowadays.
Like
how did I not know that?
I mean I knew about grafting,
like limbs onto other plants,
but I would've thought it was the same
plant.
Like you would graft your tomato branch
onto another tomato.
What the fuck man?
How do they do that?
Uh,
it's kind of,
I don't know.
Again,
I would say they probably like a.
What is this Jamie hand drawn diagram?
It looks like it says right here,
like figure one cut.
You know what this looks like whenever
dudes get abducted by aliens and then
they come back.
What was it like?
Well,
let me draw it for you.
This is the first one.
The first one I come to,
I'm on the table.
The second one,
the table said,
stop,
go back.
Go back.
Well,
you're doing the second one that's
stable,
starts to vibrate and then the alien
comes in from overhead and now all I
could see was his head and the lights in
the ceiling.
And then an examining machine came down,
see the Arrow down into exactly what it
looks like.
And then I became one with the galaxy.
See?
There's the alien and then the galaxy.
He reaches the next level,
the next level of the game.
That's what I see.
I say Dick and a butthole and it's
getting probed on that last one.
Uh,
I don't see a Dick if you.
Dick looks like that.
Dr.
Doctor.
Quite sure with Dick it's a,
it looks like a nail.
That's a tea cup o' tea cut stem.
And then they're implanting.
It says a bud gets implanted in there.
Oh Wow.
Then the bud grows into out of the stem.
Wow.
That's crazy.
So they,
they implant the button there and then
they cut it.
Is that what they're saying?
This is cutting the bud.
Just trying to do some other pictures
where you could kind of see that.
But like this is a little more of a
bizarre.
Is that man,
they make a tree grow inside another
tree.
I did not know that they can frank and
tree but I should've known.
Right.
Because it makes sense.
Did they,
did they uh,
talk about the drought and like how
pistachios are supposedly going to
double in price in the next year because
we had such a drought this year and I
guess pistachios are just about to go
crazy.
Sky High.
So by now I know that's a really good
point and I know it's important for
agriculture in California,
but I want to go get it.
Cause smog.
Oh you fuck what if you buy a bag a day
that's like,
dude,
it's $2 more a day and pistachios,
I'm fucked.
It's also a good of how much.
What percentage of your fucking budget
goes to pistachios ever in your life?
Like if you had to even consume a moment
of your time thinking about this as a
possibility.
Like what about the stock price is going
up.
Like I love it.
What's your favorite three things that
you buy?
Well,
if I gave you an opportunity to give up
pistachios for the rest of your life,
do you think you would struggle now?
Don't be no issue.
Go Mad.
Walnuts.
The Brazil nuts.
I'm interesting.
Complex flavors.
Yeah,
I mean there'd be no problem.
You eat peanuts,
you'd be like cashews.
I'm down with cashews.
Don't need.
Where do you buy walnuts?
Like full walnuts.
Like I tried to buy like walnuts,
not like chopped up walnuts.
It's like I'm talking about the ones in
the shower.
You crack on with this stupid crackers.
Good question.
I guess the supermarket,
right?
I looked.
They don't have walnuts.
Walnuts.
Nobody gives a fuck about Walmart's
anymore.
People realize like mixed nuts.
Walnuts give me that almond motherfucker
to crack that.
Especially.
Yeah,
like how many people buy nutcrackers
these days?
If you're not cracking clause,
like lobster claws or crab claws.
Right?
You're not buying a fucking nut.
Cracker was the last time he cracked a
nut.
Cracking any nuts.
I have a netcracker collection at home.
It's one of those things.
You just leave in Ohio.
Just like the dance one where you like
to handle that?
Yeah,
those are real.
That's what people don't know.
Like the nutcracker.
When I was a kid,
I was always like,
why they call it the nutcracker when
it's just a bunch of wooden toys.
Like why is that the nutcracker?
And realized,
oh,
those are actual nutcrackers.
[inaudible] was,
boy,
we cracked on notes.
We didn't just go and buy Aum.
Aum shilled and packaged by Mexicans.
I also had a box of wooden ducks.
Remember when that was a popular thing
where you'd have like a stupid people
will when we were kids like,
here have a wooden fucking dumped.
You're too stupid to play with anything
that moves you.
Piece of shit.
Just take this fucking wouldn't duck and
pretend it's real.
Yeah.
Have duck fights.
I don't give a shit.
I'm over here starving to death and
there was duck.
There was something that was ultra
realistic like that,
the green head and everything.
And then there was ones that we were
just all brown that weren't painted and
stuff,
but I have like 20 of them.
That's hilarious.
Did you got wooden ducks?
Oh,
the role or wants a baby?
Do you know what I'm talking about
though?
Was that a thing or is that just an arm?
Like a,
like a stupid redneck thing or
something?
I'm sure there's like wouldn't stupid
wooden toys it.
I remember when I was a boy,
she.
Here's the argument though,
is the argument that it gave us more
room for creativity when we were kids
because we're playing with these stupid
toys that really didn't do much,
so we had to do it all in our own head
instead of being overwhelmed by a video
game.
You know what I'm saying?
That.
Yeah,
that's.
Oh,
that's a decoy,
bro.
That's actually like a,
a well done decoy.
Like what that is.
They use those when they hunt ducks,
they put that shit in the water.
Well,
this had like a.
well maybe they did,
but this had like real feathers and
yeah,
that misstep.
We.
You'd put it on your fireplace.
Okay,
well,
so that's because people use them for
decoration.
No,
no,
no.
Some of them are beautiful.
What they started out.
See,
when you call it a decoy,
it's just because it's the exact same
shape as a decoy might not ever see the
water,
but what those were.
Originally it was people trying to make
ducks that looked exactly like a duck so
you could float it on the pond and the
ducks would fly over and go,
oh,
these ducks are just hanging out here.
This is a cool spot.
And they land and you blast them.
I mean,
that's a duck.
Dynasty is all about that as a show and
an empire built on duck slaughter,
trickery and fuckery.
That's what they should rename duck
dynasty trickery and fuckery because
they're tricking those ducks and is
blowing them out of the sky.
But um,
because people got really good at it,
they started doing as art.
Like some of them are just art,
like people like grandma type people
have on their mantle piece.
And I love this.
I love this.
I Love What it represents to pee in a
fall.
Yeah,
I got a lot of them if you want it.
No,
I'm not.
I'm not into that.
It's funny because my mom is like,
Brian,
I don't want.
I want to throw away all this shit.
And I was like,
mom,
you have a basement.
It's like,
why bother throwing it away?
It's not,
you don't need more room,
you know,
it's like you barely even go in your
basement and she's just telling me all
this shit that I have there that
completely forgot.
Like I have a brand new laser,
this player back home.
I have laser,
laser district.
Funny that some things get to a certain
point,
like if you hang onto that laser disc,
maybe it'll be one day like that Tuba
with a needle on it that you dropped
down on the records,
you know,
because that shit is dope now.
If you had one of those,
if you had one of those old school like
19.
Oh,
three Tuba things,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
It's like it was non mechanical or
electrical.
You turn the handle.
I think so the record player with the
speaker shout.
Yeah,
there was.
There was like a,
like the needle was attached to like a
thing that looked like a musical
instrument.
Right?
Graph.
Yeah.
Phonograph.
It's called the phonograph.
Yeah.
Is there a video of that thing?
For sure.
That pull up a video of the thing.
I haven't even thought of that thing.
And do you watch antique roadshow?
I'll be like,
in 10 years.
No,
I,
I just,
I forgot those things were real at one
point in time.
It's like one of those things where you
go back to like the history of stuff and
you go,
oh yeah,
this is even showing.
Uh,
I,
I tried to tell you about this before.
This is what they used before.
A records that Edison cylinder,
right?
That's right.
You did tell him about this Mrs.
just a metal like,
yeah,
it's like a kid's toy nowadays.
Yeah.
But God,
that'd be so valuable if you had that in
your house.
Like if you had that in your mom's house
and you,
you,
you've fished that out one day and be
like,
Holy Shit,
if it's an edison on it,
dude,
that laser disk recorder.
As goofy as it seems now,
there's gonna come a time where it's not
goofy anymore.
Right now it's going to make a comeback
and be like watching.
We're going to make a comeback,
but it's going to be interesting.
It's going to be like,
Whoa,
look at this fucking thing from 1999
where they had these silver discs
earlier this year,
July the last few car got made right
until they've started making them again
because someone's going to realize that
can make a shitload of money,
but no weird.
About five years ago I bought a VCR just
because I was like,
you know what this is,
this is on its way out and I have tons
of vhs tapes so I'm just going to buy
$29 on Amazon.
So I bought one and it's so light
nowadays.
The technology is so basic.
It's like you could just pick,
pick on like one finger easily,
you know?
Yeah.
It's ridiculous how light it is.
It feels cheap.
The only one on Amazon now costs a 180
bucks.
Whoa.
Fuck you.
As a DVD player,
you got to get one of those both.
Yeah.
Well maybe it's telling you.
Is it the other one that dvr now?
Just like what is the price?
What is a good price for like a vhs
player?
It used to be like 50,
$60.
They got down to like 29 to $39,
but look at these companies that make
them like,
who I've heard of that.
So,
um,
did you hear about that thing that they
were doing?
I've been paying more attention to this
now.
I'm trying to figure out what a lot of
this was.
There was a story,
um,
that uh,
Eddie Bravo actually told them about it
first were the Pentagon was making fake
al Qaeda videos and faked like isis
videos.
And um,
there was this documentary about this.
Um,
we're not a documentary but this video
online about the company that was
involved in making these things.
It's crazy,
dude.
It's crazy story.
Come in for a meeting like,
who am I meeting with Kevin seat.
Okay,
you got the job,
you're going to Iraq.
They fucking ship this guy off.
It's a really interesting,
like this guy talking about being
recruited to create these propaganda
films for the US government and what
they were was seat.
Everybody goes,
oh my God,
the US government's line to us.
Yeah,
definitely not good to have these videos
that we think are al Qaeda but are
actually CIA that are or whoever it is
that's doing these things as propaganda
from.
But what's interesting is what they did
with it.
So there's a,
there was a thing called realplayer.
You Remember Real player?
Yeah.
They only streamed it through real
player so people would go to it,
they would stream it and it would get
their Ip and they would know where they
were and so they would know where people
who were all grouping up in these like
radical factions,
radical groups,
and they would be able to isolate them
to a certain extent because of that or
at least isolate their location,
you know,
so,
but which is really interesting.
Right.
It's really interesting because that's
another thing that someone was telling
me and this I had never considered this
fucking who fucking said this.
I want to say it's on the message board,
but they were talking about all the
different factions that were sort of put
together to become isis and that they
weren't even really necessarily against
or together with each other.
You know,
there was Boko Haram,
there's the Taliban,
al Qaeda,
there's ice,
there's all these different people,
but they just sort of lump all these
groups in together like we're fighting
those fuckers everybody.
And we think of him as an organized
group,
like they got together and said,
you know what,
we've got to get together and organize a
group and put together our powers and
no,
they didn't.
They basically on each other sides,
like the whole,
the whole thing is like a,
just a giant group of people that don't
like us foreign policy and we sort of
call them whatever we want to call them.
Some of them are isis and some of them
are al Qaeda and some of them are
Taliban and some of them are what they
used to be the Mujahideen.
It's crazy.
Right.
Did you watch the debates?
The funniest thing on twitter is the
Hashtag Muslims reporting.
Uh,
whatever trump says,
like the Muslims need to report things.
So there's a Hashtag of just Muslims
reporting things.
Like it's.
But it's all shit.
Like,
like a fart in a little poop came out
and listened to recordings.
You know,
God,
it's hilarious.
Or so they just took over that Hashtag.
Yeah,
they actually made it because it is
pretty ridiculous.
That's when he said that.
So now they're just taking advantage of
it to make it funny and it's.
It's hilarious to Rio,
a Muslim report stuff.
Hashtag
dude.
It doesn't even seem real.
It really doesn't.
I'm watched the debate and I was like,
this is.
It's so strange to watch that this is
their choice.
This is our choice of who gets to be
president.
It's like,
how did we.
What happened here?
I got really freaked out when he was
hovering over,
like,
I don't know what triggered something in
me,
but I said,
get,
get away from her later taught.
Big powerful man.
Yeah.
He's a big looming,
powerful,
successful,
rich man.
Scares off everybody,
you know,
I Kim hovering over her and that debate
was just.
The whole thing was bizarre.
It's really bizarre what
talking to people that watch the same
program as you with completely different
hockey,
like in fights with family members over
and like,
did you not?
What I watched,
I've been tuning the Fox News nonstop.
That's all been watching.
It's so interesting to see how people
just fucking form teams,
man,
they just form teams.
They go right or they go left,
but they form a team and then they write
shit that doesn't necessarily make
sense,
but it fits within the narrative of
their team winning and they duke it out
back and forth with each other.
There's a bunch of people that we're
talking with big smiles about how great
trump came away from that debate.
He had one good line.
You'd be in jail.
Oh yeah,
that was a good line.
Yeah,
because you'd be in jail.
That was a good line.
He got her there.
I mean that was a fucking nice quick
one.
Got,
ain't got out.
Boom,
knockout,
blow.
But the debate itself,
man.
And then when he kept on saying like,
Hey,
you know,
she's uh,
she did her time interrupting while
interrupting.
He interrupted more and took more time
to answer questions.
It was like,
what road is,
is he living in a strange guy?
Politics.
I hate both of them,
but uh,
it's really interesting seeing how
grocery bill,
I feel bad for billy Bush.
Like I think,
I think a lot's going to come out on him
now that he's under the microscope.
Let me ask you this.
Why does there have to be moderators?
Wouldn't it be better to watch the two
of them sit down and talk?
This is what I think.
Get Hillary Clinton and Donald Trump.
Sit them in a room together across a
nice table like this.
Put a camera on the bolt them and let,
let them have a conversation.
Let's find out what they're really all
about.
You know,
because everyone's doing their
broadcasting to you.
Everyone's broadcasting to you,
including me right now,
which is very ironic,
but everyone,
that's what they're doing.
They're broadcasting,
but don't just think Donald Trump would
overpower for her.
So she can't even talk as you will learn
a lot about him.
If he does that well,
we'll learn a lot about him.
If he does that and I bet she'll be able
to manipulate that and make him look
really bad.
Look,
I think you get them together,
the moderators asking him to answer
questions,
telling her the time is up and all this
different jazz.
That's an added element.
Why am I not talking to her?
Okay.
I'm not.
I can't.
Well,
I'm not there.
Okay.
Well,
why doesn't he talk to her?
Let's find out what they think about
each other.
Let's let,
let them.
Why I'm.
Why are you going to do it better than
me?
Tell me.
You know,
why does it have to be fucking bitter
dire enemies every time to people are
running for the same position kit.
They've recognized that without
competition,
you know,
this is allegedly not the best we can
do.
Right?
I think most people think,
well,
we probably could find a few scientists
or doctors or whatever that might do a
better job in those two.
Running the country,
but whatever.
Just put that aside.
It's not the best.
Do you think is the best?
There's no way,
right?
No Way.
Why don't
just doesn't seem real.
Even discussing it.
I like lose my train of thought because
I'm like,
I can't believe we're actually sitting
here talking about this,
but whatever people do,
man,
they get on a team and they fucking wave
that flag and it's the team of the right
of the team of the left is a few people
that sort of dangling between the
middles,
so like if you had big giant piles of
ants and then there was like a little
trail in between those piles of ants
that was like kinda thinned out and then
the,
the pile would be on the lefthand side
and the pile of being the right hand
side.
There's a few people that are in the
middle.
There's a few people that are walking
back and forth in the middle.
They don't know which way to go,
but the vast majority,
they kill a fucking pile and they decide
fucking circular movement or they,
you know,
they decide whatever it is,
whatever they decide,
you know,
fourth amendment,
freedom of speech,
whatever it is they ride with.
Yep.
It's like apple,
pc,
Samsung,
like is that whole thing?
Just gender rights.
What do you think the chances this
happens again in 20,
20 are the same.
I don't know if she wins a big Kanye
versus trump in 2020.
It's going to be worse.
It's not getting better cognac when you
could.
When I can't take it.
He could win.
I can you imagine having years of Kanye
like trump shit.
Trump.
Eight years in a row.
All right.
I would throw my tv out.
Could have a new election every year.
You keep winning.
Just so people could say president
Kanye.
Hey Man.
Is it that bad?
I mean,
what do we,
what are we getting into right now?
This is bananas.
It doesn't seem right.
Real.
I mean I really am feeling more and more
everyday like we're living in a
simulation and the simulation is
revealing itself to us.
A hundred percent.
A guy named wiener can't stop showing
his dick.
Really?
How you obviously
this guy.
Damn script.
One hundred percent was writing this.
The,
it's Eddie Bravo.
It's like a 1990 [inaudible] Sitcom.
Eddie Bravo isn't.
They had a trolling us.
Corey Feldman back on the today show
dressed all in gold.
Yeah,
I did another crazy performance called
America and then he accidentally threw a
flag on the ground.
Corey Feldman looses his damn mind again
with another today.
Performance.
Well,
hey man.
That's how he staying relevant.
He banned me off twitter after I talked
about him.
Last time we talked about him on here.
Blocked you.
You blocked me.
Did he block you?
I don't know Corey Feldman's twitter
page ever,
ever,
but I'm sure he's a good guy.
I don't.
This one.
I'm not giving him out here.
That's what I'm saying.
Saying he's just being super outrageous
in order to get attention.
It's smart because otherwise they're not
going to pay attention.
It's fucking hard for a guy that's been
in movies and had a lot of shit going on
that it all kind of goes away and he's
just trying to do it himself.
He's trying to figure out some way,
some way to stay in entertainer.
I get it.
Nothing wrong with it.
It's weird.
It's doing weird stuff,
but I,
I get.
I mean look,
we're talking about him because he's
doing weird stuff.
He does questionable things though,
that it's on purpose.
Weird,
but think he's just a weird dude and
that's kind of art he likes to make.
I mean the whole feldman angel thing
really is gross and creepy and awful,
so I think he's just talented and he
thinks he is talented.
Like he's in denial.
Could be a grand Andy Kaufman
requirements could be.
But if you've watched any ethic,
magnitudes the album cover for his
double disc that he's releasing and
Jello to the core.
He hates rock on Corey Feldman on you.
Dude,
I'm not hating on you.
They are racer tool around some fun
crop.
That's what he likes,
man.
He's at a party.
He uh,
he know he sells like $20 videos or
something like that.
If you pay him,
pay him 20 bucks,
he'll be like,
he'll read something for you.
And he does it in characters like when
he was in lost boys who has the same
jacket on and stuff like that.
So Larry,
forget what's comic.
Uh,
there's one of our buddies just spends
like 20 bucks a week just getting a new
video.
Well that's,
that's probably a smart way to make
money.
I bet he can turn out fucking dozens of
those an hour.
Yeah,
if he's just doing that.
That just reminded me of the story I've
been hearing recently.
You know all the comic con convention is
others,
not just one.
Now.
There are multiple.
They're all over the country and they
have a old TV stars come in to beyond
them.
They're making.
When I heard hundreds of thousands of
dollars per convention leaving with cash
and bags because they're.
It's 20 bucks.
It's at least 20 bucks a photo if not 40
or 50 or 80.
If you're signing them and it's a deal
they're making with the photographer
that's taken the photo and the
convention and then the person who's who
of the actual star gets the rest of it
and they're making a lot of money,
like really old people making.
I forget it.
I can give you an example.
I've said this before on the podcast
when I saw daisy duke,
the girl that played daisy duke and I a
comic convention and she was just
sitting there and Catherine Bach?
Yeah.
She was just sitting there by herself.
No one knew who knew who she was just
sitting there and then I'm like,
Holy Shit,
daisy dukes to sitting there.
And so I came up and said,
oh,
can I get a picture?
And she's like,
sure it's going to be 20 bucks.
And sounded like she was just making
money.
Like I had to use my own camera,
but she was charging 20 bucks for to
take a picture with her.
Yeah.
So it was pretty sad.
Uh,
I just saw that a fucking weird man.
That's a weird practice,
right?
It is,
it's gross.
The guy played thor is going to wander
around a little over $350,000
in a weekend.
Robert Downey jr would make about a one
point 5 million for his appearance at
comicon.
And then it goes down to say how much
like a autograph from John [inaudible]
Jack was like 70 bucks.
But if he's,
he's probably not there.
So wait a minute.
So these guys go there and take pictures
with people for money.
Yeah.
Ralph Macho cost 40 bucks for a photo
op.
But his costars
honestly the ones you were saying in the
millions.
So Robert Downey Jr.
Yeah.
It takes pictures of peoples from
probablY not doing that,
but that's for him to show up at just at
the event to other people.
So just to get them to show up and be in
the main hall to say like,
hey,
here's the new avengers trailer.
Oh my goodness.
That's Insane how ballers.
that guy.
That's insane.
That's a lot of money,
man.
God damn.
Just to show up.
Hey dude,
just come to my thing and I'll give you
a million bucks.
That's awesome.
Okay.
But I'm only talking a couple of lines.
Okay,
good,
good.
It's cool.
Just smile costs like 200 bucks for a
ticket for the weekend.
Just to go to comic con.
Just to hang out with everyone.
I mean that's pretty much what paris
hilton does nowadays.
She just makes appearances and get some
shitloads of cash.
Buys new puppies for $10,000.
Yeah.
Appearances are big,
right?
It's like the way people who don't have
an act perform to show up.
I'm here like just being there is your
performance now and now she's a dj.
She literally just presses play and just
wave their arms around for like an hour
and that's it.
It's good.
It's probably have someone else do it
for like someone else.
Can cox the music or does she cocked her
own music?
She just gets a cd and she presses play
and turns knobs here and there to make
it look like she's doing some typical dj
stuff nowadays.
Russell peters would get angry.
he doesn't call that dj and.
Oh yeah,
I know.
You know russell gets furious.
I've heard some of the bigger dj's that
are making money in vegas.
They have to fees for an event like
that.
They have a press play fee and then they
have an actual like outperforming mixed
songs fee.
Oh,
that makes sense.
That's really expensive.
That makes sense.
I to do that,
a comedy show have one fee where I just
stand there in front of a tape recorder
and I go like this while my jokes play,
I pause.
I do my whole act like they got another
fever.
I actually do the stand up.
That's cool.
Have you ever ate one of the hottest
peppers in the rural members?
would you ever eat one of those peppers?
Um,
I'd probably try it just to see what the
fuss is all about.
I mean I've had some,
um,
there was a piece to be a place in
encino called chili,
my soul and it was just like super
awesome fucking chili place that had
like the most legit chili,
like they had mild chili where it didn't
fuck with you at all.
But then at the top end of the scale
they had like some himalayan death shit.
They had some chili that you couldn't
even fucking believe a person can eat
it.
And I never even tried 10.
They have a 10.
Apparently they had a 10,
but I did try a nine once and I,
they give you,
this is how strong the chileans they
give it to you in like a thimble and I'm
not fucking joking.
It'S like a little tiny cup that you
would get ketchup at,
at a shitty diner.
Those little tiny ones.
That's what they give you.
The chili.
And I put it in my mouth and immediately
start hiccuping.
My body's like freaking out.
Tears are pouring down my face,
my snots porn out of my nose.
And that was like a tiny little bite of
this stuff.
I was like,
what the fuck?
My whole tongue was numb.
I was like,
whoa.
Youtube videos of like ghost peppers,
I highly recommend is sitting there and
watching this.
One of my favorite shows is called hot
ones.
I want to like,
I wanted to do this show so bad.
I don't know if you've seen it where
this guy answered 10 questions and each
one you start off at like,
like tap eto.
Then it gets hotter,
each chicken wings.
So each one you take a bite of a chicken
wing and then he will ask you a question
and it starts off to see how if you
could get all the way to the end in the
end it's like the hottest one.
So it's really interesting to see who
can do it and who can't.
And it's genetic.
I don't know,
like a tommy chung did it and he did it,
but I think there were some shenanigans,
but uh,
the first three he was like,
even the tapteal when it goes well or
this is hot and he's like,
whatever.
But then he gets to the end.
He wasn't breaking a sweat where other
people are like gagging on the japanese,
whatever you want,
couldn't handle that hot shit.
He went for it first and like almost
started barfing heat the hot one first
and then he touched his dick with it
instead.
It was,
you got broke.
Chrysler did one of my favorite
episodes.
A shout out to hot ones.
So jamie just pulled this up while we're
talking.
This guy does a bong rip with the
carolina reaper.
Carolina reapers.
Apparently the top of the food chain
when it comes to the hot peppers.
One of them.
Yeah.
That's they say is the hottest.
Is it?
I thought it was that other one,
but I think I read recently.
Yeah.
I thought.
I think I read recently the carolina
reaper is the hottest.
See,
I want to know what would that really do
anything though.
You're,
you're burning it,
you know,
I don't know if that would actually.
This might be a fucking bullshit.
Until.
What was it doing?
Just a ghetto.
Exactly what happens to me second after
he takes the hit.
It's like three minutes of him coughing.
It's not search flying out of his nose
and.
Oh,
let's watch.
Oh shit.
I have something better to do.
Go full screen.
Please don't let anybody see it.
So this guy's got the carolina reaper.
Here's if you want to watch online.
Ted barris bong rips the carolina
reaper.
And then uh,
ask derek puke warning original video.
Here we go.
So this guy's just telling you to
fucking take a carolina reaper.
Oh,
jesus.
OH my goodness.
I don't think I would do anything.
Let's try it.
Fuck that.
It's no professional though.
Comes to bong.
Rips a bud tender.
So tender.
I don't say that again.
Bong rip and bud tender.
Come on.
Is that what they're calling them now?
That's like the barista at starbucks.
I have issues with that.
It's like the guy at the restaurant that
wants to get really fancy with the wines
and explained to you the way that wants
to get really crazy and tell you what
part of the world it's growing in,
why the grapes are so important there.
I'm a bud tender will.
Okay.
This is going to give you that stony
high.
The most important thing here is no more
than three heads do.
Trust me.
I know you like to do deep.
Trust me three heads and you can.
He'll be beautiful.
It'd be mellow and they just.
This is more like an earthy,
nutty.
Somebody like the girls are like,
I always smoke this.
I start cleaning my whole house.
It makes me so mad.
Cleaning your own ass liar.
There is definitely some wheat I've had
that makes me feel like cleaning my
house.
Well,
you just look around you.
What am I doing with my fucking life?
Yeah,
eat edibles.
Do that to me.
Edibles freaked me out,
man.
I had a bad edible the other day.
EverybOdy does.
If you take edibles,
you're going to have,
but the good side of those is almost
every time I've had a bad one I come out
of it and I realized like whatever was
bothering me,
like whatever issues or whatever,
paranoia,
whatever weirdness,
I look at it from a different way.
I look aT it in a better way.
Oh,
here he is.
Even though I didn't believe this,
that's not real bad.
Acting always going to keep digging.
Don't know.
Have you ever hit some really harshly?
That just immediately tastes terrible.
Yeah.
Well,
here's the thing,
man.
We don't know that this,
uh,
that the oils from the pepper or
transmitted in the air and they really
don't know and that looks good.
Overacting from a hillbilly,
maybe a little bit,
but maybe it's trying to get used to,
knows what he's doing with that,
but it's still like,
no man.
He mighT be seriously experiencing the
oils.
I mean,
do you think the oils from the pepper,
that's where the heat is.
You think you can carry carrying the
smoke be right?
If it can transmit just skin to your
dick,
of course.
That's a good.
That's a good point.
Yeah.
This guy's fucked.
This is real dude.
Maybe.
Yeah.
I think this guy's foxville.
IT doesn't seem like a good idea either.
anyway,
watch this video.
Support it.
Give it a few folks.
Don't go smoke.
Carolina rebreathe dumb ass.
There's that.
There's this one guy that does it at
vegas.
He like walks around on the streets in
vegas and he goes,
hey,
you know what?
You eat one of these peppers is the
hottest peppers you can eat it.
I'll give you 20 bucks and it's just
destroying people's lives here.
Like families like dab will do it for a
tour and you're trying to do a hot spicy
pepper,
you know,
but they're eating like those peppers
and just like puking and crying like and
toxic.
It's not.
You could probably get sued for.
Yeah,
but I mean is it toxic to the person as
a person eating a carolina reaper?
Is that toxic?
This is the guy.
What does it.
What does it say?
They're payinG people to worlds house.
This guy's a complete asshole to like,
well,
I think you have to be.
If you're having people eat the worlD's
hottest pepper,
he holding this guys
at the end of this video,
he acts like such a dick to this chick
that made me hate this guy.
What?
He's like a prick.
I think I've seen another video of his.
There's a couple.
He's a prankster that dustin on the
street and uh,
the strip in vegas and he might be
getting away with extra.
Can't you do a,
do things in vegas?
Yeah.
That's why,
uh,
what was the comedy central show?
Okay.
I see people throw up anymore.
Yeah.
Crank yankers yeah.
These,
do that in vegas because you could Just
call people up.
Yeah.
that's the problem with tv and nowadays
is half these shows are like that.
They're all like,
there's a show.
I don't want to say what it is.
It's,
I don't wanna say what network at his
arm because people hate me so much when
I talked shit on this network.
But uH,
uh,
this show is a prank show where they pay
all the people in it.
So the other people that are getting
prankeD.
No,
they're getting prank,
but they sell it as a real show and
dries me.
Why do you know that?
They know they're getting pranked before
the prank.
Okay.
Because I know somebody that did it.
This is say he got paid to be a.
Okay.
So we're going to come in here.
We're going to hand make a fart sound
in.
You're going to,
you know,
like daily.
Yeah.
And it's on a channel that's.
Huh?
I just,
I just hate that shit.
That's why I say get away with that.
They'll say it's a scripted show.
They say written by or I don't know.
Probably.
What do you think?
They just hope that.
Well,
is it like here's the question,
right?
Is that different than like see that's a
prank.
Prank is like almost like a sketch,
right?
So if you have a setup sketch like that,
that's a bigger deception then a reality
show where you already know what you're
going to do during that day.
Right?
Right.
Like what's a reality show?
Like,
oh,
we're all
going to go to the football game,
you know,
my sons playing football.
Today's is big day.
And all the cameras day,
yay.
Go making enriched.
Here's like,
like they know that they were going to
do that,
but It is at least technically like a
real thing you can do.
It's a real thing.
Meaning like they were going to do it if
the cameras were there and not exactly.
They know the cameras are there.
So I consider that like duh.
They know the cameras are there,
I've accepted this.
I can see.
But it's like real,
like the most.
One of my favorite shows is the profit.
Yeah.
But it's a lie though.
All of it is a lie was different than.
The other thing is.
The other thing is like they're going to
the game.
Yay.
We're cheering.
We're aware of the cameras were acting
weird because it.
But the other one,
you're pretending that you didn't know
that that fart sound like a plan.
Yeah.
So like it's not really acting like
you're,
you're being deceptive.
Deceptive.
Right?
Like it's not.
You guys aren't doing a sketch about a
prank show.
You're doing an acTual prank show zone.
The only one reason to watch an actual
prank show is to see people legitimately
get what?
What do?
What do you mean?
What does that speak like?
People come up to people and a lot of
people act in weird ways.
You ever had someone come up to you and
you don't know who they are and they
touch you.
They got their hands on you like,
whoa,
whoa.
Who are you?
What's this?
What's going on?
So people get weird and defensive.
Like that's a real prank show.
That's why like ali g in his prime,
in that ology character.
SOme of the all time best prank
interviews ever.
I mean,
some of his shit was fucking hilarious.
Now,
could you imagine if you found out that
those people on the other side were in
on it?
Like remember he did not do one with ron
paul [inaudible].
He did one with Buzz aldrin.
Yeah.
How did you tell If the moon is made out
of cheese?
He had a bunch of like ridiculous
fucking interviews with people where
they just.
They couldn't.
They had no idea.
They thought he was a guy from an mtv
show that had come to do interviews with
them.
Check it.
No,
he was the best.
It was the best.
If you found out those were all
fraudulent,
wouldn't you be mad?
Yeah,
and that's what I'm saying.
That's why it pisses me so off,
like not even.
That's one of the things that drives me
crazy about this network because they
have a lot of these shows just like that
where they're selling things that.
But is that okay if it's good?
It's not good when you know it's fake
though.
You can tell it's fake.
A lot of the actors are such bad actors
that you don't even need to know
somebody that's working on you.
Just watch and go,
oh god,
they at least got good actors.
You know,
like it's that bad.
Well,
maybe it's tv.
I hate garbage to you,
but maybe in a way,
maybe in a way.
It's good if you're really that stone.
I guess it's good.
Yeah.
Maybe in a way it's good because it's so
stupid.
like there's a show that I like.
Have you seen impractical
jokers?
No,
I have not,
but I've heard it's really good.
It's very funny and when they keep doing
it really bad,
what I'm saying is like if,
if it sucks,
I don't know.
It sucks because they haven't seen it,
but if it sucks,
as hard as yOu say,
it sucks.
Some things that suck become awesome,
they suck and then you go to see him
later or he seem when you're high or you
go to see them knowing that they suck
like showgirls.
Remember showgirls?
God damn dude does one of my all time
favorite ridiculous movies.
That's totally different than what I'm
saying.
Troll troll to.
It's like the worst movie ever made it.
Everyone loves it and I saw that
documentary.
Yeah,
it's so stupid,
dude.
It's so stupid,
but it's awesome.
You know,
but it's.
They have to be.
They have to be shitty on accident,
like waterworld,
like a movie that or worse way worse.
The post man,
you gotta give him credit because you
know kevin costner is the man.
He did wyatt earp,
which I really liked.
He did dances with wolves.
Dan's waterworld going to have a few
fuck ups in there,
bro.
Just didn't work out,
but what had happened in my pain was
constant and a while he was doing a
bunch of.
You think he's doing some new thing for
hbo?
I believe too.
It can't be on purpose.
You can't make something bad.
Yes.
You can't make something bad on purpose.
My point being like a movie like
showgirls and there's a few other ones
you could go back to Texas roadhouse and
a lot of ways I fucking love roadhouse,
but it's so dumb.
It's so dumb when you watch it,
it's awesome.
It becomes really good.
It goes away from being like Just a
statement,
like a just a bad ass action movie and
it becomes a comedy,
like it really does morph,
especially over time because what it's
like,
it's like something.
You had a plant and it had to grow and
as culture grew around,
roadhouse roadhouse is in a lot of ways
it's a time capsule because it captures
how fucking ridiculous people were in
the year that it was made where you will
let you.
You could see like what people accepted
back then.
You could see how lame the script is,
how ridiculous the dialogue is,
how preposterous the fucking plot is is
a bad guy.
I've been screwing this town over and
out.
I'll have keeps drilling them over like,
hey,
you've been screwing up his towel for
too long.
a cheap.
Keep screwing them over too.
it's so bad that it becomes awesome.
Are you worried about the potential new
one they're going to make and the
thought behind it might be they're going
to try to make something badly awesome
again,
but start with bad intentions.
Here's what I think.
I think.
Do you piggy back like,
and this is coming from a guy who did
the man show to version to me and
stan home,
but I think you piggy back on when you.
When you're,
you're confined to the ideal,
like you piggyback on the love that the
original roadhouse hat,
right?
Because it's a classic movie.
You piggyback on that love and you're
already in a deficit.
It's like the ghostbusters thing,
which by the way wasn't a good movie.
It was a good movie for a little bit
though.
There was some funny shit and
ghostbusters,
but then it got monotonous and I didn't
enJoy the end,
but I thought you told me you loved it.
I love some parts of it,
so I bought it based on your
recommendation.
Not saying I love that.
Definitely did not say I love it.
It just wasn't a good show.
At the end of it I was like,
wow,
this is like,
it seems like 200 people fucked with it.
It's one of those things where sometimes
you look at a movie and you go,
what so much going on here?
So much special effects.
The special effects were so monumental.
The one at the end that used to be the
donut guy or the,
uh,
the pillsbury doughboy.
Yeah.
In the original ghostbusters,
that fucking thing is taken to this
crazy new cgi level where they're going
into,
spoiler alert,
they're going into other dimensions or
retrieving their friends and it's
fucking craziness.
Fucking craziness.
But there were some funny moments in the
beginning of that movie where I laughed
pretty hard.
I was like,
there's a funny fucking movie.
I tend to Just lost its way,
I felt,
but it's hard to make a movie,
man.
I bought that godzilla movie that came
out like two years ago.
That was dog shit.
You didn't like it.
I thought it was okay.
The guy from breaking bad in it and
stuff.
He was great.
He was great and everything,
but it was like god.
So corny.
You know they're making another one.
Right.
Was funds being made by a.
I think it's being made in Japan,
so it's like the way they originally
made god.
Here's my problem with it.
I shouldn't say it's corny because I
love monster movies and it definitely
don't want to discourage monster movies
and we'll absolutely see it next time it
comes out.
The problem Is there's a dude in this
movie,
spoiler alert,
the original godzilla,
not the original,
but the most recent one,
the one with the guy from breaking bad.
There's a.
There's a dude that keeps fucking
surviving.
This guy,
I mean he falls off buildings.
He said earthquakes.
they dig them out of the bottom of the
fucking earth.
He's dusts himself off.
I'm going to go fight godzilla.
His fucking families waiting back.
For me.
It's just a.
It's a tornado of cliches that literally
literally makes you travel back in time
to the 19 sixties.
It's so corny to like look at each other
in the eye.
It's a big green monster.
I think you could do that big green
monster with like the kind of People
that write game of thrones or tHe kind
of people that are writing this
westworld show.
Holy shit.
Westworld is good.
What is this head?
Fucking harris is playing the yule
brenner character from the movie
westworld from 1973 and now they made a
series of it on hbo and it's amazing.
People are still even moods you fuck
fucking terrible taste in shoes or to
us.
It'S fucking good.
This is a really good show.
It's complex.
It's weird.
There's all these patterns that you
don't expect.
There's a lot of weird shit going on.
It's a.
It's a strange kind of violence because
it's like a robot violence will hope I.
Yeah.
Do this whole.
This movie is a trip or this show rather
is a trip.
Oh cool.
And it just keeps getting better.
They've been like $25,
million dollars a hopkins.
Anthony hopkins is in it.
ed harris is fucking fantastic in this
show.
He freaks me out at home.
I'm at home and I'm on my couch.
I'm like,
please don't let that boogeyman come get
me.
Ed harris.
You forget what a bad motherfucker he
is,
and he watched his show.
Wow,
this looks really interesting.
I thought it was just a cowboy shirt.
No,
no,
no.
It's about westworld.
The movie westworld was all about a
place where you would go,
well,
you'd have these shoot them ups with
robots and the robots eventually smarten
up and rebel and that's what this show
is about.
It's fuck it.
There's ed harris.
Dude,
I'm telling you.
I kinda forgot how good of an actor ed
harris's.
You watch him in this movie and you're
like,
this guy's one of the most untalked
about best actors ever.
It's great.
he's so creepy in this fucking show.
I'm watching this tonight,
dude.
He's so good at freaks me out.
like I really believe him.
You know?
I really believe he's a psychotic madman
that can't be killed.
It's fucking awesome man.
It's really good.
I recommend mr.
Robot,
but every said that to you.
It's.
Yeah.
I don't have that time for that.
I love it.
It's right up your alley.
I prime for one robot.
Christian Slater thing is like,
this is the problem with movies like
godzilla.
No disrespect to godzilla again.
I love a good monster movie.
I watched the fucking wolf man with
Benicio del toro like five times.
I don't even like it.
I thought it was corny,
but I watched like five times just
because I love a fucking werewolf movie.
It's fun.
It's cool.
When you,
when you do movies like godzilla and you
have these kind of,
you know,
really cookie cutter cliche cbs drama
type.
You know what I mean?
Like it's like that like a show.
It's not a bad show,
but like a tv show,
it's kind of obvious what's happening to
the other.
Wrap it up nice and tight at the end and
you have to compete against game of
thrones,
game of thrones,
which goes season.
It's like a movie every week and it goes
season after season of chaos and
awesomeness and amazing writing.
Like you can't just have that dude
living over and over again,
getting trampled by godzilla.
I'm fine.
I'm just fucking this fucking dinosaur
up.
This to just keeps getting his ass
kicked.
He's falling out of helicopters into the
ocean,
swimming to soar.
Fuck up godzilla.
He just keeps surviving and it's driving
me nuts.
He doesn't even have a coma,
You know,
concussion.
No broken bones.
Yeah.
I fucked up my neck And a shower once,
dude.
Okay.
I,
I turned around and try to grab some
shampoo and I popped my neck and I had
to drive to vegas that day and I drove
to vegas like this.
Uh,
this fucking dudes get launched off the
top of buildings and dinosaurs are
chasing them.
And in the end he sticks around to watch
the fight out between god's bad.
You'd be shitting your fucking pants if
you were in a boat off the coast of
seattle and a 600 pound lizard was
duking it out with another 600 pound
lizard and they're fucking going to war
with fire breath and one of them opens
up.
The other ones had and blows fire into
it.
Spoiler.
You would not be sitting there going,
yeah,
godzilla go,
good.
That thing's gonna.
Fuck you up to stupid.
It's going to fuck up everything.
It's not going to care about these ants
in these buildings.
You wouldn't be watching that.
You can't say out.
You can't say.
Those people wouldn't be screaming and
crying and spasming and snot pouring
down their nose and terrified because
their eyes must be deceiving them.
They're watching a 600 foot lizard that
lives in the ocean and blows fire out of
its mouth and it's not going over
buildings like their little cardboard
boxes.
That's what he just sitting off the
coast watching this.
You'd be shitting your pants.
There's not enough cool in the world to
just sit there and watch that.
You'd be like,
fuck,
how far as Australia?
Fuck,
fuck,
fuck.
You just get to a plane or to a boat.
You get In a traffic jam.
People would die.
They would run over each other and not
care.
That would trample each other like a
fire in a building all throughout the
land to get the fuck away from a 600
foot fire breathing lizard.
So until you show that in the movies,
you have failed us in this.
You have failed us
in this portrayal.
We're going to say we'd actually,
that just came out yesterday.
What movie know?
But that's the fake.
that's the.
Yeah,
that's the one that came up dahlia.
That's the japanese one.
The guys are wearing suits.
yeah,
right.
It's still good.
Good.
It's,
it's just a different kind.
It's like the original godzilla.
Good.
I would like to see that.
That's kind of good.
It actually got good reviews and it
actually looks really cool.
Look,
the movie godzilla and the idea of
godzilla is very fun.
The ocean is
fucking huge folks and uh,
there's whales in it.
Right?
Okay.
So we know that there's something as big
as a godzilla sort of.
Not really like what's a big whale,
how many hundreds of feet is a big
whale?
There's the size comparison of the
godzilla is of all of them.
Yeah.
They all get bigger.
We need bigger.
We need to double doubles and big gulps.
Big gulps.
And our godzilla's what I just asked
you.
Jamie whale.
oh this?
Yeah.
How big is the biggest whale?
Sperm.
Is it a sperm whale?
A blue whale?
Blue whale.
How much?
One hundred and 70 meters?
Ninety eight feet.
okay.
Wow.
Okay.
So that's still quite a bit smaller than
godzilla.
But if a whale can be real and a whale
is 93 feet long and you are five.
Eight.
Okay.
So we know one thing can be way bigger,
right?
Because I'm five,
eight,
but my daughter has a hamster and that
little fucker fits in my hand.
So let's start thinking here.
What's the stop?
Something from getting godzilla sized
for so far we haven't really seen
anything other than the dinosaurs.
But then it really got godzilla sized
either.
But it doesn't mean that it couldn't
have happened.
Me and someone probably has like an
argument against like the gravity effect
on something that large,
like how much mass you'd have to be
moving around and how big your muscles
and bones would have to be.
They'll they say that happens to certain
animals at a certain size.
It just becomes impractical due to the
environment of earth.
And that was one of the things that they
thought was a reason why the dinosaurs
are so huge.
Was it?
The atmosphere might've been different
than that.
It might've been a different kind of
atmosphere that allowed them to move
more easily,
which is really fascinating.
Right?
Where oxygen maybe.
Well,
I think it was way warmer,
right?
Wasn't that in real tropical?
I think they think during the dinosaur
days,
obviously not everywhere.
There's,
I'm sure they had probably had polarized
caps even back then.
But I think that the temperature in the
jurassic and the other,
um,
here we go here,
dinosaur era at five times today,
ceo two.
There you go.
Oh wow.
Listen to that folks.
Okay.
So they had,
they knew world.
The dinosaurs roamed the earth 250
million years ago,
knew a world with five times more carbon
dioxide than president earth.
Today,
researchers say,
and new techniques for estimating the
amount of carbon dioxide on prehistoric
earth may help scientists predict how
earth's climate may change in the
future.
Fuck dude,
we're going to have dinosaurs.
We fucked up.
We had coal power plants and we're gonna
make dinosaurs.
Those lizards are just going to keep
getting bigger and bigger and all the
liberals are going to go.
We have to keep them alive because
they're important part of our ecosystem
and they are scaly.
Friends can.
And then the alligators just keep
getting bigger and alligators get to be
like 30 feet long.
And people go,
hey,
what's going on?
Why the alligators so big?
Like they're getting bigger.
do you guys?
no,
no.
These are just unusual examples.
These are outliers.
These are outliers of our scaly friends.
And uh,
you know,
a size shame as a human or with animals.
And a big alligators don't next.
He no alligators or 300 feet long anD
they just smashing through buildings,
eaten your kids.
JuraSsic park was technically real
alligators.
Keep growing.
My story that I'm talking about right
now,
it's not too far off of that.
like what would you go visit it?
They kept them on.
Why jesus jv?
I don't know man.
I'm just saying that at one point in
time the alligators keep getting bigger.
They're going to have to say,
okay,
they're too big.
We gotta kill him.
Yeah,
we can't have him wandering around if
they're 50 feet long and they just want
to kill people,
we can't do that.
Right.
so my point is they accept alligators up
to a certain size.
Like right now,
alligators like the alligator on the
golf course video,
which got like millions and millions of
hits.
That alligator was like 15 feet long.
Like that.
Alligator is like on the border.
Like okay,
we're letting that thing live.
You don't let this 15 foot long monster
just roam around and everybody's like,
hey,
we always have before.
Okay,
okay,
we're cool.
Cool.
But if he's 30 feet long,
you're not going to be out there.
Right?
If he's 90 feet long,
like a fucking whale,
you're not going to be out there.
No one's going to be out there and
you're not going to be safe.
That's a giant carnivore.
So my point was,
what?
When do we shoot that thing?
We.
Would you shoot it or would you capture
it?
Sci world record stakes,
stokes,
or stakes stokes.
Stokes,
stokes,
alligator.
What's the stokes alligator?
Is that a type of alligator?
no.
Fifteen feet.
Nine inches long.
Holy shit.
God.
Oh,
see,
that's an sci.
You know what that means?
That's safari club international.
That's like a,
it might be.
Make sure that I'm correct there.
But that's like,
um,
that's one of those organizations that
measures the largest animals of each
species that were killed hunting.
hmm.
So that's,
that might be what that is.
See If that's right.
Is that the sci?
What is it?
Stokes was.
It keeps saying.
oh,
the name mandy stokes told the website
now.
Okay.
Dan.
Oh yeah,
they kIlled it.
They killed that thing.
Eric.
It goes so that she went through with a
range of emotions as they first stalk
the animal before baiting it.
Oh,
battling it and killing it.
Finally struggling to take it and
finally struggling to take it back to
shore.
How weird alligator meat is supposed to
be super good for you,
which is really kind of crazy,
right?
You look at that thing like,
how could you eat that fucking thing?
But apparently their tails are
delicious.
You just have to,
uh,
prepare it properly and you get it like
right off the alligator and that,
those things
in that place we used to always go to in
Texas,
have alligator soup.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
So he's favorite place.
Was it popping out in the hotel is right
next door,
right,
right.
There's more than one dose.
There's,
there's like a poppa doughs and just
like does a seafood one and the cajun
one,
right.
There's a steakhouse.
They have like a,
it's like a bunch of.
Yeah,
it's a chain.
Yeah.
I think if you get alligator,
you've got to get it from someone who
shot the alligator like I think or get
it from a chef that knows how to get it.
Like when it's really fresh.
It's supposed to be amazing.
It's.
It's a really uncomfortable subject for
people.
At what point in time are we in danger
and at what point in time do we step in
like a grizzly bears?
Just start wandering the streets and
eating people.
Are we gonna have the same feeling that
we have about them in the woods?
no,
we're not going to.
So we're going to have to do something
then,
right?
Yeah.
Okay.
I just checking.
I just want to check.
I just want to know what team you're on.
I'm not saying we need to go to the
woods and clean out the grizzly bears.
I just want to know if the grizzly bears
come to burbank.
Okay.
We can stop that.
Right?
We could shoot them.
Right.
If the grizzly bears just start eating
people in burbank.
You're on team people write it.
Okay.
I'm not.
I'm not saying we should kill them in
yellowstone.
Hey live and let live.
Let those big giant monsters go wander
through the woods.
Have a good time.
Eat your hiker.
OCcasional oCcasional hiker.
Just stay the fuck out of,
uh,
san francisco,
right?
If grizzlies started wandering through
san francisco.
Fuck that dude.
I was in this town near bakersfield
called le bec and it's named after a
dude named peter lubeck,
who is purportedly the last man in
California to get killed by a grizzly
bear.
So I went to the website to read about
this dude.
And uh,
that's.
We're reading it.
I'm reading that his feet were bitten
off.
This is not financial.
It's not funny because his feet were
bitten off.
One of his hands was gone.
This bear just fucked him up.
And uh,
they named the town after him after the
guy had died in his honor.
They named this town after the last guy
to get killed by a grizzly bear.
So like,
people that go,
huh?
You know,
they've ruined California.
The grizzly bears extinct from
California,
listened to me,
listened to me.
Let Montana have the fucking grizzlies.
You don't want them here.
Just trust me.
I know they seem so romantic.
They seem so lovely when you're on
television.
That's great,
and there's a spot for them on earth.
That's great too,
but this idea of bringing them back like
what do you want to be one of those
pioneers.
It's scared to get to your fucking
recyclable bin in the middle of the
night.
You're terrifying because your
neighborhood is filled with bears and
lions and shit.
The fuck out of here.
That's ridiculous.
30 foot long.
Crocodiles wandering down your
neighborhood.
No,
no.
Gotta.
Shoot.
Those things got.
Dammit.
They found the story of him because it
was scary.
It was written into a tree.
Did you read that one?
Let'S say.
Whoa,
whoa.
Let's
say I'm looking up the story about,
and I keep talking about this
inscription written on a tree that was
found when people were passing through
and the 18 fifties low.
Do you think if we didn't have the teddy
bears as kids,
we would not be so attached to bears.
Oh,
for sure.
Well,
that's right.
There was a story written on the tree.
I dug him up and his bones were torn
apart.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's exactly what it was.
Now that I refresh my memory,
I'd forgotten it was written somewhere.
I didn't know it was on a tree.
I thought it was a note.
That's insane.
Fuck bears,
dude.
Seriously,
fuck them.
And again,
I'm not for eradicating bears,
ladies.
Gentlemen.
I just want to be clear.
I love them.
I'm glad they exist.
They're cool.
Just like lions are Cool.
I Don't want lions in burbank.
You know,
I just a whole cecil the lion thing.
Let's not get carried away folks.
Let's not,
don't bring them over here.
Don't get crazy because a guy who wants
to bring them over to england.
Do you know the guy who is the,
um,
when bulls created rivers guy,
the guy with wolves change rivers.
He made this really cool documentary or
a video that shows what the.
It's been criticized.
I don't know who's right,
but to me it's interesting and it makes
a lot of really cool points.
And one of the things was that these
wolves were reintroduced them to the
yellowstone.
They started killing the elk and killing
the deer.
And that allowed a lot of the plants to
grow better,
which allowed a lot of the rivers that
changed the course of the rivers because
the root system got stronger and all
these other animals survived and
thrived.
They all did better because they weren't
the prey of the wolf,
but they were benefiting from the elk
and the deer not being around anymore.
and so a look,
it's really cool to see like how when
they introduce a predator into an area,
it's almost like you're watching a
mathematical program,
like you introduced this and it's a
really controversial subject because a
lot of elk hunters in particular were
really mad when they brought these
wolves in because they killed half the
elk population.
They chopped them down to 50 percent.
But some people think that it's probably
overall healthy for the actual animals
themselves.
It's like a more honest life.
It's not really honest for these wild
cows and undulates to not have any
predators.
They've never had that all throughout
history.
So our idea that we're going to
eliminate all the predators and they're
just going to run wild.
That's crazy.
Like that's how you get like Michigan,
where people are fucking hitting him
with cars to a tune of a million a year.
Some was it.
No one was at one point $5 million in
the whole country for a year.
Right?
200 people dead from colliding with
deer.
You know.
So like wolves.
Wolves are important.
Bears are important.
They're interesting.
They're fucking fascinating,
man.
I'm so glad they're around,
but don't get crazy.
Don't get fucking to coyotes in my
neighborhood.
It's getting out of hand.
And the crows,
crows and coyotes
out of control.
I love coyotes,
man.
I do.
They're fucking
cool.
I mean,
I remember the first time I saw one,
I was staying at the um,
what is those a furnished apartments
that oakwood's oh no.
You know the oakwoods everybody gets you
first moved to hollywood.
I was staying at one of those things,
man.
I was driving to the apartment and I saw
these fucking dogs running down the
street,
like little german shepherds and is the
first time I'd ever seen a coyote.
And I realized,
holy shit,
these are coyotes.
How weird is this?
He's a little wild predators,
just small enough that we let them stay
just small enough.
If they were hyenas,
we would be gunning them down from the
top of buses.
Right?
If he needs a roman down the street
tearing apart dogs and shit,
we'd be terrified,
but is just dickie enough to slip under
the radar.
I like to eat a cat every now and then.
Don't leave your cat out,
bro.
I'm going eat your fucking cat.
We like tolerate that.
This little predator will eat your dog.
I just snatch youR dog right out of your
art and hop over the fence with them.
You got to deal with that.
I saw one kill my chicken saw and saw
that fucker hop over the fence with my
chicken and its mouth,
but I still love them.
I love them because they're like.
They're like little criminals like
skirting the system.
They're scary enough that you don't want
your kids to be around them,
but you're not scared of him.
A little skiddish it Probably fuck you
up if they want it to.
Like if a coyote really came after,
he'd probably have a real problem.
You probably have a real problem.
It's like a dog,
right?
It's a lot less sharp teeth.
Yeah,
but they're more survival oriented.
They'd be scared if you put up a good
fight,
like if you booted a coyote in the head,
if you've got a good roundhouse kick,
you know,
if feel like a chocolate dell,
like have a coyote,
tries to fuck with chuck liddell and
chuck a duck kicks that fucking thing in
the head that that's how he's going to
run.
He's going to go,
what was that?
Fuck this that's ever happened to me
before.
And they'll just take off.
You know,
if He doesn't knock them unconscious,
they'll just run and get the fuck away.
But they'll kill you if you're small.
If you're a little kid,
coyotes will kill you.
Well,
they don't.
They don't have any morals.
Like why would they not?
The only thing they look,
is there people arounD?
Can I get away with this?
I'm going to do it.
As they do,
they don't have any rules there.
God damn wild animals.
Remember that 19 year old singer who was
killed in Canada a few years back?
She's a folk singer,
she's killed by coyotes.
Really?
Dude is ugly because they found her.
She was still alive.
God,
but here's the thing about coyotes,
dude,
they start eating.
You asked first.
Oh,
that's right.
I remember that.
Do you have any idea how horrific it
must be for a coyote to pull your guts
out through your asshole while you're
screaming and no one can hear you and
you're in the woods?
That is a demon.
It's Just a demon that only attacks
occasionally if coyote,
he's wearing a real thing and there was
a murder where a demon from hell came
out of the ground and ate a 19 year old
aspiring folk singer through her asshole
eight.
Her ripped her guts Out,
tore apart,
and then the demon just disappeared and
went into space and we knew that he was
gonna.
Come back in 30 years,
that town would live in terror,
lIve in terror of the possibility of
something they could commit that kind of
enact would return like you'll be
looming over us.
We'd prepare,
we'd have armor and shit.
Be waiting for the thirtY years to come.
Meanwhile,
they're outside,
checking out your mail.
They're sniffing around your garbage
cans,
tick either nails,
click,
click.
My security camera gets in once in
awhile.
Of couRse it does.
Of course it does,
man.
Yeah,
they're everywhere.
They're everywhere.
I'm having a guy come on soon.
That is a a wildlife biologist that
studying.
We're trying to coordinate a date.
He's studying coyotes that live in the
city and surprisingly like healthy
populations of coyotes that live in the
city.
It's crazy.
Yeah,
there's a lot of them,
man.
They just.
They find places where they can sleep.
They find find places where no one's
going to fuck with them and then that's
their spot and then they venture out at
night or venture out at dusk or they're
and they've just figured out a way in a
fucking.
AvoId people bothering them,
but they live in cities.
Man,
it's weird.
Everybody just gets out of their car.
They get into their house,
getting your car drive off to work.
You'd go down here,
you go on there.
How often you check in that weird
alleyway behind your apartment building?
How often you check in that place?
Is anybody checking that place?
You know,
there's like trees back there for no
reason and then behind that there's a
fence you ever go look in.
There were coyotes live motherfucker.
If you don't go there for a certain
amount of time,
they find that spot.
They sniff around like these dumb fucks
don't come here anymore and they'll
just,
they'll use that and they find these
spots all around the city.
Apparently it's pretty cool to.
So like a weird animal that's just small
enough that will let it hunt near us.
I wish it was.
There was foxes more foxes around boxes
are pretty dope.
Did you say you see that video with the
fox laughing like,
oh,
this guy I guess has a fox.
Oh,
pet fox.
Pet fox.
And the guy just be like,
ha ha.
And the fox just goes.
Yeah.
Like it's just like,
it's so weirD.
Such a weird video.
Yeah,
box.
It's a pet.
Yeah.
It's got a collar on and everything.
That's a far.
Yeah.
And look at.
Oh my god.
Laughing.
Whoa.
That's a hilarious sound.
It rolls over at fox,
probably so happy.
He's inside a house getting free food.
You just have to go out there and earn
fox.
Do you ever see the video,
uh,
of the fox with a grizzly man when
grizzly man was up in the woods and the
fox and him became buddies?
Yeah,
it's really beautiful footage.
I think honestly,
I know I make fun
of that movie a lot because that guy was
out of his fucking mind and that's
another unintentional comedy.
This is another perfect example of
something that's not supposed to be
funny,
but it's god damned hilarious and no
disrespect to this guy who got eaten by
the bear.
No disrespect because I think he really
did do a lot of great stuff.
I think he was a little delusional with
his idea that he was saving these bears,
but what he did do,
his got amazing,
incredible up close footage of grizzly
bears involved in all sorts of crazy
shit.
Like he,
he captured grizzly bear wars at like
really close range and he did a great
job and he deVeloped friendships with
these animals.
Like this little fox right here.
This fox just comes right up to him,
man is hanging out with him.
AT one point it steals his hat and
playfully runs off with it and he's
like,
hey,
give me that hat back and the fucking.
The fox isn't scared of a man.
The fox just thinks it's funny.
Like why would the fox take the hat?
He just rolling around and they're
biting on it.
It's really adorable and the grizzly man
gets mad,
so he goes chasing after the fox and
it was just like weird moment of
camaraderie between two life forms that
are just hanging out in the woods
together.
Like that thing accepted him into its
community.
Man.
It's really interesting.
Another interesting thing is the wolves
killed one of those boxes while he was
there already.
They got ahold of that fox torn apart.
They don't want any competing predators.
Same with coyotes.
Coyotes,
coyotes.
Same with coyotes.
They don't want competing predators.
That's apparently the main reason why
they kill cats.
They don't even kill them to eat them as
much as they kill them because they
don't want any predators that are
competing for the same things they're
competing for.
So,
so he got this amazing footage of him
like running after this fox hanging out
with his fox.
He was like buddies with this little fox
and then when the fox kid got eaten by
the wolf,
he found like a paul and you're like,
whoa,
this world is gangster.
Like these little crazy animals make
friends with this nutty guy who's camped
out in a tent and while he's camped on
that tent in the middle of the night,
the wolves come into town and tear one
of those boxes apart and he's crying and
he said,
I heard the screams.
I heard the howls.
I heard the wolves.
I'm like,
what in the fuck are you live in through
dude?
Like there you have in monster wars and
your yard.
LiTerally watched that movie.
I don't know where these parts are.
So good.
Fox a little,
but I've seen it way too many times.
I've seen that fucking movie
15 times.
I watched it on planes and I'm bored if
I'm bored
again.
Did you,
did you see that report that there's
like 1300 chinese old ladies or old
people get go missing every day?
Like there's this whole thing where the
old people just are missing like daily
1300 chinese.
Wait a minute.
This is recent.
Yeah,
and then they're saying it's up to
500,000
old women go ms dot or old people go
missing every year in China and so
there's all these theories like that
they become food and in the government
takes them because it costs so much
money.
Oh no,
that's a lot.
And I know $500.
Mark and old people.
500,000.
Okay.
How many,
how many people go missing in America
every year from the old people go
missing in America year?
See there's a difference,
but I think $500,000
seems like a lot,
but China has a billion in China.
It's 80 percent.
Eighty percent of what people are
missing people.
Eighty percent of missing.
Yeah.
Over 75.
Oh my god.
They're killing all people.
That's what I'm saying.
Oh my god,
they killed babies and older people.
Oh my god.
That's so insane.
On average in the usa,
there's only $90,000
missing persons at any given time.
Okay.
$90,000
missing persons,
but in their defense,
China has probably three plus times more
people than we do,
so wouldn't.
Shouldn't still be under 300,000
if that was the.
But that's close.
That's close.
And you considered the fact that they
live in a really rural place in a lot
of.
A lot of the errors are very rural.
Do they have predators?
They have bears,
right?
China has some bears.
What else did they have?
What kind of credit?
What hate?
Hey google.
What kind of shit eats people in China
and they'll say chinese people.
Chinese.
It's just the infinity sign.
Just a few animals.
It's very aware,
but we've got a few guys.
That would be a weird thing to find out
how many people in America,
he and people right now and if America
has 90,000
missing people or how percent of that is
old people?
Probably only like small amount.
What do you,
what are you googling here,
buddy?
Get exactly what you still kind of weird
shit meets people in China to meet me.
I was being silly.
You should actually go google.
That's hilarious.
Creditors of humans in China.
Sorry,
I had to be more specific for ladies and
gentlemen.
Just want tO announce right now.
We were way too high to start this
podcast when we did.
So.
Uh,
thanks for hanging in there.
We've come back around.
everybody's okay now.
Do they have predators?
Is there maybe the old ladies get
scooped up by tara.
Those are some shit.
Pterodactyls were real.
Shoot them out of the sky.
You can't be an alligator that can fly.
Right?
Right.
Agreed,
right?
Yeah.
You could crawl around on the golf
course.
I'm like,
ah,
leT that slide.
As soon as they can fly.
Fuck
you.
Fuck.
You can't just land in my yard.
You piece of shit.
and then what?
You can fly away and I can't fly.
Fuck you.
Is there anything that flies right now
that attacks people?
See that's the thing about eagles.
Eagles got smart.
They never got big enough to fuck with
us,
so we said,
all right,
we'll let you be our national bird.
He eagles got really close.
They got scary.
I mean,
if you see an eagle and you see those
towns and shit,
they'll freak you out.
I get attacked by birds a lot recently.
I think I just must be near ness.
You don't be doing that.
I just like sitting in my backyard.
What do you,
uh,
what do you got here?
James is just a wildlife with China on
wikipedia.
There's a different mammals.
Does it say predators of humans?
Did you have predators?
They have giant tiger's.
Oh,
they do?
Well,
that's it.
Old people getting eaten by tigers.
There you go.
In it.
What if we find out south China tiger
said,
toilet chinese people are sewing.
Figured.
Oh my god.
And they're like,
we told you it was in the fucking dumb
piece of shit.
Oh my god.
They have siberian tigers.
Oh,
they have a bunch of other cats to it.
What does that population of bengal
tigers.
What are those things?
Those other cats?
Laptop leopards.
Leopards are terrifying.
So this is what I think since they have
a bunch of shit that we don't have,
they can kill you.
My estimation is that poor
communication,
a lack of resources.
I'm very rural.
Neighborhoods connected to tigers and
cats are causing the extra 200,000
that would account for them having the
exact same amount of old people go
missing as we do.
Said 25 percent of those old people have
dementia.
Oh,
There you go.
You wander off.
You get eaten by the tiger.
I forget.
What am I not supposed to get eaten by a
tree?
No.
Did you see that video?
That chinese person eating the other on
the subway?
Like cannibalism.
What?
Yeah,
what?
Maybe just say asian and maybe it's not
in good.
Let's not show him for sure.
Well you can't really see anythIng.
You just see a guy hunched over another
guy and he just blood coming out.
So he attacks the dot.
Yeah.
Is that real?
It's happened a few times.
It's happened.
Like there's more than one real.
Yeah.
There's more than one video attacking.
He's attacking some other guy.
Oh my god.
Is that all blood?
Yes.
What did he attack them with?
He's with his mouth.
He's eating him.
Oh my god,
there's more than one of these videos
and this guy I know and there's more
than one of these videos to.
You would let that go on and it get on.
But I mean like,
oh my god,
I don't know.
You have how many people know?
But I know I can't do shit.
I would,
I would faint.
Killed the fuck out of that guy if I
could.
You'd have to worry that he's going to
go after you next or your kid or your
friend or your bite.
Shit.
You're fucked too.
And that's the subway in China by the
way.
And there's more than one of these
cannibalism videos.
Like there's China on subways,
there's this.
I don't know what happens,
but there's a lot of this happening.
This is a bunch of videos of people
randomly attacking people on subways or
something.
We were just watching.
Well,
here's the thing,
when you're some about being contained
in a subway where you're in this thing
or you know,
like it's a container and you know,
nobody can get away.
There's some weird instinct that people
have where like if someone was like a
predator already,
I bet they would be in that thing and it
would like excite their predator
desIres,
you know,
if somebody just with some crazy person
that wanted to go on a subway and just
beat the shit out of somebody,
like if they're there in the.
We all know there's people like that in
the world,
right?
They just want to go and hurt somebody
for whatever reason.
that's the place to do it.
Right?
Trapped.
You want to eat somebody,
subways the move.
And I think a lot of schizophrenia,
people blowing like pcp,
it freaks them out more and more.
And,
and they,
they're like,
they can't just like they get there,
they feel like they're in a confined
space,
that they freak out,
you know,
they,
they attack or I guess that cop that
shot or the.
Remember the guy that recently,
he got shot,
I guess like,
I had pcp in his system.
So says so says.
So it says who Alex Jones did you see
Alex Jones?
Uh,
let's stay on one subject at a time.
Fucking ocd.
Add,
fuck,
this guy had pcp in his system.
Yeah.
That one.
The girl cop that shot magic
fake that he didn't have any pcp and
system.
RIght.
Like a who's checking that shit?
Where,
where,
where that happened.
Wasn't it like North Carolina or some
shit.
Texas.
where was that?
Huh?
Tulsa.
Oklahoma.
Yeah.
They faked that mendez pcp in Oklahoma.
They rigged that.
Uh,
let me,
maybe.
Maybe he did.
Maybe.
Maybe that makes sense.
Like even if he wasn't threatening,
maybe that makes sense why he wasn't
listening.
Why walked back to his car and reached
into his door.
Like maybe he was fucked up on pcp.
It totally makes sense.
Yeah.
Well she shot him apparently what I've
understood by people that are around,
um,
a law enforcement and tactical
situations when people don't have
triggered discipline and they haven't
been in a firefight before.
Any kind of situation where your
adrenaline is jacked and you're really
scared for your life and she might have
been in some before,
which may be even,
could exacerbate that and jack it up.
But her adrenaline was jack.
She was shitting her pants.
Dude wasn't listening and then they
tased the guy and the my friend justin
said to me,
what most lIkely happened is when they
tase the guy,
she freaked out and pulled the trigger.
Absolutely because It's loud.
It's a loud popping noise.
Somebody.
I think what he's saying is that she
didn't even mean to shoot this guy and
that what happened with her was she just
didn't have good trigger discipline and
she freaked out because,
you know,
man,
if you've never been in a life or death
situation with a giant dude who might be
on pcp or might be on something and he's
not listening,
pcp scary and there's many videos you're
going to watch guy.
I'm pcp and mcdonald's,
you know,
battling cops and stuff like that and he
gets tased a million times and nothing
happens.
yeah,
dude,
you got to be careful.
Pcp people,
they feel pain different.
This,
this cop in Texas the other day just
tase somebody on a highway and almost
got hit by a truck.
They were chasing this guy and this guy
starts running through this highway and
so they cop tasers on the guy falls and
just misses like a truck by like an inch
it cars like who?
Why would you take somebody while
running on a highway while cars because
you don't give a fuck bitch,
but depends on what the dude did.
What if the dude was raping kids?
True.
Perfect.
Taze,
rIght?
It's all legit.
It depends on like if the guy was
growing weed,
that's ridiculous,
right?
We need to find out what his crime was,
but there's also a helicopter on you,
so maybe let the guy cross the road will
get you on.
Understand we don't get them.
We don't.
We don't get him and he's out there
fucking kids.
What if it's like spiderman?
If you don't get them.
This is craziness.
I mean,
Peter Parker member,
he led his dad,
go or lead to his uncle.
He let the guy passes uncle and the guy
wound up.
LeT me see how they do this.
Bam.
Oh,
oh yes.
I go on there like stock cars.
Oh my god.
He tased him in the middle of the lane
on the highway and if you go back 30
seconds when he first jumped on the
highway,
he almost gets hit like three times.
So like,
it's ridiculous,
you know?
Did you know that you could,
you could pay someone for that far away.
Look,
look How far he does this for me.
It's the ones that shoot out those
three.
Yeah,
that's pretty good.
That's accurate.
Hit.
Damn.
That's under pressure.
That's good.
True discipline control accuracy is in
check.
I found a taser in my car recently and
it's scary to you turn on.
See,
here's the thing.
Then even if that dude was on pcp,
she shouldn't have shot him by.
It doesn't make it any different.
It's just sort of explains his weird
behavior.
[inaudible] she made a mistake,
but it's a,
it's a mistake that cost somebody their
life,
but it's also like the whole thing is
kind of fucked up man.
Having a girl in that kind of a
situation.
I don't know what kind of training she
had or how long she had been on the job.
Do you know?
Five,
five years.
Let's make some shit up.
Five decades.
I want to say it was 52 and 50 of those
years were on the force.
I just think it's fucking terribly hard
to do and we don't get mad if somebody
fucks up your fries.
You know,
if you go to mcdonald's and you got
burnt fries,
like each guys fucked the fries up.
This is the equivalent in her job.
Fucking up the fries.
Somebody dies.
She made a mistake.
She screwed up.
Somebody got shot and kill that.
It's so much different than any other
job.
It's so crazy.
I,
I believed that it probably is exactly
the sound of the taser in her being in a
high stress that makes complete sense to
me.
I mean,
I think you just react by hearing the
sound and my buddy justin
would definitely know because he's,
he's down with all those.
A tactical guys and military guys and
he's a,
he's a gun nut so constantly around
those dudes.
So if that's what they're saying,
that's most likely what happened.
It's probably what she relayed and
private or what they figured out or who
knows,
but and fuck,
fuck that job.
Imagine just chasing after people that
are committing crimes all day.
Holy shit.
How stressful would that be,
man?
She Was a five year veteran.
Yes,
correct.
They drop.
Yeah.
It's just,
it's just weird,
man.
It's just weird that we need them and
it's weird that they become what they
are,
you know,
they become this death dealer or
lifesaver,
you know,
someone's coming after you and the cops
break in there.
The lifesaver.
They're gonna like what a crazy position
for someone to take,
you know,
fucking stressful.
I would never do that.
Fuck that.
especially nowadays it's even worse.
I mean,
I probably was cooler back then because
he got away with so much,
you know.
Did you see the seven,
five,
seven,
the documentary of the 75 whole lee
shit.
Okay.
And uh,
we had uh,
mike dowd from the,
um,
from the movie come in and explain to us
like what it was like back then.
Great guy.
By the way,
he's been on joey's podcast to um,
how do you spell his name?
Dow d
does the way it sounds.
He's awesome.
Yeah.
I didn't want to fuck it up,
but I think it's just the real mike
doubt on twitter.
What is the on twitter.
Great guy.
But holy shit.
Was he a criminal?
Really?
Oh my god.
They were the cops.
The 75th precinct he foUnd out from the.
It's an amazing documentary and you
found out from the very first week on
the job,
lIke in that range that the cops were
all corrupt and that you never turned on
one of your own and you know,
you just fucking.
They had rules that they would skirt
around and he got deeply,
deeper and deeper ingrained in this
world of a crime while you were a police
officer.
Drug dealing while your police officer
intimidation while you're police
protection,
while you're a police officer and he's
driving a corvette and live in like a
bar and they're going on trips,
they're driving a boat and then a bunch
of crazy shit happens.
And one guy,
rats the other guy out.
It's madness.
It's fucking great,
dude.
It's a great documentary and also he's
like super honest about the whole thing.
He's super honest about everything
because he went to jail,
did his time and then got out and then
they made the documentary because it's
all about like.
It's like the 19 eighties.
It's fucking amazing,
dude.
It's a great documentary.
I missed apollo.
Told me about it.
Well,
that's cool.
You still get it.
I mean it's on.
I think it's on itunes.
I think it's on everything.
Fucking good.
Dude.
Did you look at the video yet with the
pigeons in the bread factory in Russia?
No,
no,
I haven't looked that.
It's disturbing.
There's this a mil fill with grain and
these pigeons are eating from the top of
it and they're so stupid that they just
get sucked into the.
The grain jesus and chopped up into the
bread.
So like if you've had bread in Russia
lately,
a lot of his pitch and the pitch video
two down.
Oh my god.
Three down to one of them falls and
lands in and just get sucked in.
This isn't saying this is fucking
insane.
It's one of the most disturbing.
Jamie immediately make a video of this
to my phone so I can instagram this.
The world needs to know more.
Yeah,
it's fucked.
That's harsh.
It's very gross and scary and sad.
It's just a harsh life.
a dumber pigeons to.
Well,
look,
I live.
Their heads are mad if your head was
that little.
Yeah,
I guess,
but I mean zIka babies grow up to be
pretty smart.
Nope,
we haven't had any.
That's true.
It hasn't grown up are really.
I don't think so.
I mean not that I've ever heard of.
I just made that up.
I think there's actually adult zika
babies.
I think so because I was thinking about
making zika hats for zika people,
so it makes it look like their heads are
bigger.
I don't want to start a conspiracy on
it,
but I read recently that the zika has
been around for a long time.
Yes.
Like and then I just looked it up.
Now it says since 19 forties.
That's when it was first discovered.
Yes.
There's actually a zika adults and they
look like zika babies by grown up.
Yeah.
Google that google zika adults.
Hm.
There's some pictures of like really,
really old picture of people with weird
deformities that you'll think of like
carnival pictures and shit like that.
I wonder how many of those were that
kind of a thing.
So like or like.
Yeah,
I know what to say.
Like beetle juice or.
No,
that's.
I don't know.
Yeah,
maybe.
Yeah.
Who knows?
There's some.
I mean the little errors in the scripts
that make a person.
Now,
what are those errors?
What is this?
Oh my god.
So you can virus.
Michael microcephaly suffers.
Cephalopathy casey scarborough,
sef allopathy suffers campaign.
Wow.
How many people go,
oh,
that's crazy.
How many people are zika?
but they just have hats and you never
another zika.
See,
is that a thing?
Hold on,
go back to the picture.
That's crazy.
There's a fucking bug that makes your
head smaller.
Just just stop and think about how
insane that is.
We need to eradicate that bug.
There's a bug that makes your baby's
head smaller.
Okay.
I don't givE fuck what is going on in
Russia.
We need to kill all these god damn bugs.
Stop worrying about stupid shit is
people that are going to be born with
little tiny heads.
Well,
they're killing the bees in a lot of
cities.
They're spraying for zika,
ms dot rosemary are bs.
Yeah.
It's all fucked up from top to bottom.
It's fucked up.
Birth defects.
Ooh,
scary.
Terrifying.
It's just terrifying to think that
there's bugs that can just all this.
I mean,
even when you hear about things like the
spanish plague that like one flew over
the spanish flu,
one flu and like the 18 hundreds was the
1800 and $1,900
was the spanish flu.
I want to say the 18 hundreds.
18 nineties,
you know,
I know this.
My grasp of history ready beCause uh,
in,
um,
uh,
interview with a vampire,
the dude that plays brad pitt had the
spanish flu and he was a soldier and he
was dying in 1918.
There you go.
Yeah,
he was.
I'm so old timey.
Basically folks,
the other dude who played brad pitt's
character of brad pitt's character,
dude black brad pitt played.
It's hard to say he died with that flu
and the stat gave him the vampire gene
got real issues after that,
bro.
I didn't really like doing them.
Really like being a vampire,
really like choking on people's blood,
drink his own daughters.
Blood was kind of dark.
We were talking about westworld earlier
reminded me of something a thought I had
on here of a couple of people mentioned
some things about,
I think dimensions.
Maybe it might've had to do a string
theory,
but it had to go with the store.
I think I showed you this story before.
This came out earlier this year about
the scientists have found out that the
human brain,
the size of it,
or at least at what a store might be way
more than they thought previously based
on the way the brain codes,
what it's calling bits.
They need to stop the study right now
and examined red band,
but my only point on this is that a.
There was like 26 up to 26 neuropathways
are discovering the brain,
which allows for more of maybe thought
storage and they knew about,
but when the person came on to mention,
uh,
dimensions in the past,
a couple of months ago,
I'd never heard that there was up to 26
dimensions possibly.
I'd always heard it was 11.
Yeah.
And this is the first time I heard 26,
which made me go back to something I
had.
I had just heard about what had 26 to do
with it in the brain and it was this.
Okay.
So it says,
according to super string theory,
there are at least 10 dimensions in the
universe.
M theory actually suggests there are 11
dimensions to space time.
And then both sonic string theory
suggests 26 dimensions.
What is both sonic string theory?
I had never heard that term either,
but that was just kind of ask,
asking in a strange way like,
do you think that those could be related
in any way?
Dude,
when you see that stuff,
they're writing down on those little
yellow legal pads and they'll.
String theorists are going off and
they're doing computations,
like you just got to take their word for
it,
like you can't even try to rationally
understand how the fuck some dude is
looking at a note notebook and figuring
out how many dimensions there are
potentially in the universe,
what the masonic is.
The original version is string theory
and now they're on superstring theory or
supersymmetric string theory.
You know,
there's a push back about this stuff.
People and I don't know if the people
that push back or smart enough to
actually be hanging in there with these
dudes and their ideas.
I don't know who's right.
It's too,
it's way,
way,
way over my head.
I see them talking about this stuff.
I don't,
I don't have a fucking clue.
The all the stuff that fascinates me.
I mean that fascinates me for sure.
But it's.
So,
uh,
what's the word?
A theorial.
It's so.
It's so misty.
It doesn't seem like you can grab it,
but the quantum physics,
like the guys who are actually studying
things like the guys who were looking at
subatomic things,
that fascinates me like where they can
actually like the,
um,
like things being in a state of movement
and then being still,
you know,
they've,
they've discovered that and subatomic
particles,
it's called a superstate.
There's moving and still at the same
time,
like what,
what does that mean?
They don't know,
but they were observing it.
They're observing particles blink in and
out of existence.
And so I'm sure that it has some
mathematical computations that go along
with that.
But the bottom line is they're aCtually
observing this stuff.
This isn't something that,
you know,
they're writing down on notebooks and
you can't get it and you know,
I don't,
I don't know that language.
So I don't know what the fuck they're
getting at.
These are,
these are people observing subatomic
particles blinking in and out of
existence.
They don't know where they're going.
This is real.
This is where scientists are going,
holy shit.
At the smallest visible matter in earth,
in the world.
And the universe,
the smallest of the smallest measurable
matter,
subatomic particles.
It's magic.
So when you get to the very bottom to
get to the smallest thing that we can
currently observe,
you're looking at things that perform
magic.
They go in and out of existence,
they're there and they're gone.
They're still in.
They're moving there like a god.
They're like a crazy magician that like
a psychedelic trip at the smallest
measurable amount of reality.
The universe behaves like a magic trick.
That's fucking amazing.
It's mostly nothing like an atom is
mostly nothing.
It's probably still there.
It probably does a trick to the eye of
not being able to see it.
Your navy could be,
but I don't think if they're using an
item,
measure it.
They using some pretty sophisticated
equipment right there,
pretty sure.
Or
this thing somehow or another disappears
and reappears and they don't know how.
And you might.
Right?
They might be able to come up with
better and better equipment than 10
years from now.
They go,
oh,
that's not what we were saying.
We were seeing this.
It's totally possible,
but they're all saying it right now.
And if they're right,
if mean this is not only a debated
thing,
like the fact that subatomic particles
blink in and out of existence,
I think all those super smart dudes
except that shit.
That's magic,
dude.
they're going away and coming back like,
where the fuck are they going?
what's happening in there?
How's that thing moving?
Instill?
Well,
it just is what you mean.
What are you looking at?
Discovery by the large hadron collider,
jesus christ,
or not enough official discovery.
What's the new theory?
Large hadron collider set to discover,
discover fifth dimension and doorway to
other universes.
Jesus christ.
This is not good.
This is a movie.
They're going to open that fucking
doorway and those grades are going to Be
waiting on the other side.
You can take your exit.
Do you have any eggs?
If you have eggs,
they're going to take you middle of the
night.
Speaking of eggs,
did you hear that?
That there's one of those places that
gets like sperm and eggs and I made a
person with three people's dna.
No one wants to hear about that.
What's that?
They combined the dna of three people
and uh,
through in vitro fertilization made a
baby.
so the baby was born.
So there's a baby born with the dna of
three people.
Not two people,
but three people.
How did they mix it?
Like gargling,
they just don't know.
They just did.
We just put it on this in the bitches
mouth and tell her to gargle and spit in
a cup.
Don't use that word pitch and this show
just so rude.
Rich.
Hey,
where did that take place?
That baby was born in like Russia is her
name came up on the.
I just googled it.
There's an actual faq on web md about
it.
So it's.
Oh really?
What are they saying?
Babies definitely gay or no,
I've found another article.
It's going to be a gay gladiator.
It's going to be the most handsome about
the technique is safe on.
Whoa.
Three person babies.
Ivf technique safe.
Okay.
If you say so,
dude,
that's awesome.
I got to take your word for it.
I don't know wHat that means.
That it's safe.
We don't know how many people have been
born.
Do we have a real good study group?
Said 500 eggs from 64 donor women found
that the new procedure did not adversely
affect embryo development.
That's what you say.
Now when that baby grows up to read your
fucking mind,
he got a problem.
Imagine if They put chips in these kids
when they were little like killed.
Chips were just like,
we don't know how this is gonna work out
just in cases.
dude goes on a murderous rampage.
We want to be able to have a button that
we can press that just shuts them off
because if you have a designer baby,
me,
your baby could be like a super athlete,
super genius,
but we don't know longterm consequences.
So if you agree to this,
we'll put the chip and your baby and
we'll give you a kill switch.
So if your baby goes on a rampage of it
all goes wrong.
We'll give a kill switch.
But the parents of the babies,
a super baby was going to be pissed.
How come these fucking regular babies
don't have a kill switch?
You think about all the goddamn
murderers that have ever existed all
throughout time.
none of them were super babies,
so you're blaming my kids.
You're blaming my super kids for all the
shit you regular kids.
Do you want my kid to have a fucking
chip?
You can kill them.
Everybody's got to have a chip.
We can kill them.
So we all signed an agreement because we
want to keep the people safe from the
super baby,
so everybody signs an agreement that
everybody has a chip in the back of
their head and we all were chips,
regular baby,
super babies and everybody just say so
polite because you're terrified.
Terrified that the government is going
to come along and kill.
Switch,
chip.
That's the.
That's the key to a healthy,
happy society.
Everyone's terrified of getting your
kill switch hit.
ThAt's the future.
That's why we have to look forward to
it.
Close to the house.
Remember that movie gattica with ethan
hawke and they have a kIll switch.
It wasn't kill switch,
but when you're born you're either valid
or invalid,
I think is what it was and like the tie
the society and invalid do all the rest
of the shit work.
Whoa.
He likes chicks himself to become a
valid in some way.
That's how the.
That's what the movie's all about.
He tricks his code.
Yeah.
He gets a fake fingerprint hair,
fake eyes and all this shit and all
those sensors.
This is the early nineties,
late nineties.
I feel like for
if somebody creates a synthetic person
who told me this synthetic person's not
going to have a kill switch.
Like if you don'T know,
if you don't know what that guy's
capable of.
Like if someone says,
well there is one option.
Like what if they tried to pass it
through congress congress like fuck you.
And then someone says,
okay,
there's this solution would if every
synthetic kid is born with a kill switch
and then they go,
okay,
well it's reasonable,
it's reasonable.
And then everybody by 2070 we're all
born with a kill switch is no more
crime.
Every now and then someone freaks out
and they just zap,
drop them,
chop them up,
feed it to the garden.
I'm remembering that other movie,
that justin timberlake movie where he's
got a time to end time now everyone is
25 and then they all die.
You watch too many movies.
The so future movie that you made a
movie.
the concept is really good.
Movies.
Timberlake did a bunch of movies.
He was actually actually a good actor.
Alpha dog or something else.
It was in something else too.
It's good actor.
Okay,
kimberly,
it will be in time.
It was a really cool concept.
Once you get 20 fIve,
you stop aging and then your,
your uh,
your whatever,
a year of life starts going.
But that's all the currency to you.
Work for time.
You can trade time,
you spend time and then once your time
is up,
you're done.
But people have thousands of centuries
of years built up on their little clock.
Right?
So like a sultan of Brunei or some super
rich centuries and centurIes live
forever.
Huh?
Listen man,
all this we're talking about when it
comes to the future about what could
happen like these,
these silly science fiction movies,
they probably in comparison to how crazy
it's actually going to be
playing vr know you've got to play the
dunkin's vr.
How awesome was that on the gary?
Was it scary?
Awesome,
scary,
awesome and awesome in a way where you
go,
well,
it's not.
Not like right now.
I knew I had goggles on.
I knew I was playing a video game where
you're on a castle and these little
cartoons are bouncing.
You shoot bows and arrows.
I don't know if you've played that one
yet.
Yeah,
no.
Yeah.
I haven't played it,
but I know what we're talking about.
It's really fun.
Yeah,
so part of it was like,
whoa,
this is so cool,
but there's another party that goes,
you know where this is going.
Right.
Where this has gone in.
This is not that far of a time.
You got to think when we were watChing
that phonograph ones.
That photograph from jamie.
Yeah.
Okay.
So let's,
let's give it 1880,
let's say 18.
18.
Think about 18,
80 to 2016.
That's not very fucking long.
So we've gone from a phonograph to a
fake world in what,
a couple hundred years?
Yeah,
what a thousand years.
Exactly.
We're in it right now.
That's why this election is happening.
Yeah.
That's why this thing is so ridiculous.
Yeah,
it could be that it's happening right
now.
The playstation just release their
virtual reality today or last night.
And uh,
so now that's going to be.
It's for the first time.
It's a price point that's going to hit
the masses.
Uh,
so you're going to see a lot more people
are going to have it.
Uh,
so this was a huge day yesterday and
there's one of the games that come,
comes with that I believe is where
you're underwater and it's not really a
game.
You're just hanging out in a shark,
comes close to you and you get attacked
by a shark.
But I guess it's so scary that you're
like,
oh good.
And that's just the atari 2,600
of vr.
You know,
what is going to happen?
And it's going to be insane if it hasn't
already.
I mean,
we both remember pong.
Oh yeah.
Amazing.
Right?
But when it first came out,
you were amazed.
You can actually interact with something
that's on the tv.
Yeah,
it was insane.
That was so good.
Was so crazy and wasn't that bIg.
He like,
look how little it is when we plan and
you stick a cartridge in there.
Dude.
Dude,
dude,
it was awesome.
And compare that to this new doom,
you know?
I mean,
what,
what we're seeing now in just a short
amount of time is insane.
I mean we've got a,
a giant jump of progress in 200 years.
So what the fuck is it going to be in
less than 200 years?
Right.
And you say 18.
Eighties.
I mean that's.
What
did you see what bmw is announced?
I don't know if they just did it
yesterday or this week,
but it's,
it's long this vr stuff.
Oh,
I did see this motorcycle.
Yeah.
Dude,
that's insane.
Says you won't get into a wreck and you
won't need a helmet.
it balances itself.
Dude,
I don't know about.
Won't get in a wreck,
but he basically can't,
is what they're trying to say.
How could it not rec?
Explain that.
it doesn't make any sense.
Nothing can record.
Something can still reckoned to you
probably.
But uh,
but you can't fall over it.
That's what I'm saying.
You could fall off it.
Yeah.
Maybe.
Sounds fun.
You're going to fall off it because the
force that it's going to need to require
to correct you.
You can look at that.
Oh my god.
That's what it looks like.
It's trying to find the helmet because
you don't have to go to the thing.
Here's the head.
Show us a video bitch.
These are all from.
These aren't real.
Oh my god.
What were you going to stay there and
opened that up?
Oh my god,
that's real.
That's tron.
It's,
I don't know that it's out yet,
but I already have.
But they have visors.
The visor gives information including
speed and cornering hints to help ride
or it's got a rear view like it's a,
it's a screen.
It's ar,
which is what a lot of companies are
making a bet on.
Vr,
ar,
augmented reality.
So this is an ar visor that's gonna sit
there.
Your rear view mirror is going to be in
that.
Your speed is going to be in that
updated info on cars.
Probably ahead of you are going to be
in,
especially if it's dark dude,
that's the batman thing.
Right in the upper right hand corner.
The dark knight batman thing.
How close is that?
Pretty close.
I would sue like bitch,
that's my try.
God damn that link.
It's so.
It's basically they look,
it looks like the wheels are a little
bit wider than a typical motorcycle.
Is There a different profile view where
you could see how,
why the tires are okay now?
Not much wider.
like a little bit though,
right?
A little bit wider than a regular
motorcycle.
Yeah.
They have a car that goes along with
this I think is what I was hearing,
but the car,
the car they showed seems like it's
completely computer generated.
We're living in The future.
Is this real nice?
they're eating healthy so I can have
this in sunday.
Dude,
look at this.
This is insane.
This girl is on this thing and she's
flying around in this space age
motorcycle.
Oh my god.
And looking at the.
The view through these goggles that are
showing where everything is.
Oh my god,
this is amazing,
dude.
We live in awesome times and that's the
navigation system.
Is that what she's looking at it or
goggles?
That's what it's going.
Oh man,
this is amazing.
It illuminates the road in front of you.
Is that what was supposed to show?
What was that acid kicked in?
Was this called jamie?
I don't notice the video next.
The next.
I don't know.
It's just be observant of motorcycling.
The bmw motor.
Rad.
What does it say?
Modal.
I'm not on youtube for this video.
This is from the daily mail website.
Motor rad vision.
Next 100.
It's sexy.
It's pretty dope.
But
you know,
it's still like someone Could still run
a red light.
You can't say that.
You're not going to get t boned.
The car looks like they get a car that
does the same thing,
but check this shit out because the way
that you're going to say this is super
fake stuff.
StrAnge looking.
Oh my god,
thIs is crazy.
You sit inside of it,
you press a button
and a steering wheel pops out of the
dashboard.
What is this?
Real,
real tired.
Pretty cgi,
but it's like a cdi.
This is what they're saying they are
making and whether or not they're going
to actually get there.
Oh my god.
This is dope.
So it shows you where does debris is on
the road ahead and like highlights.
It says there's a bike right there.
See it?
Biker.
How's it?
See that though?
It saw it before.
I don't know.
It's using.
Wow.
Different kinds of technology.
Like probably like radar and pulses and
excuse him.
Big brother bro.
We going to know where you live bro.
What about the handle?
I want an actual steering wheel.
Bitch.
Don't give me this stupid joystick.
Need to drive it because it's going to
be self driving.
So it's a really self driving 100
percent here.
God,
you trust that.
I do not trust that now and I haven't
done the test with him and some people
don't even change their oil.
No.
You think you think they're going to
have this thing maintained properly,
right?
I mean,
how many people are out there?
You get stuck in a lot of traffic and
someone in front of you,
it's just below in pollution,
out of the back of their pipe and you
cough and just have a fucked up exhaust
system or something.
Did you see the self driving car that
ran over its own?
Like one of its own engineers?
Like he was trying to Make it,
trying to show like how the car detects
people walking.
Oh no,
it will slam on the brakes.
And so I think it's volkswagen or
something and the guy just said goes,
now watch the car will stop and it just
runs them over.
No,
really?
Yeah.
Oh,
poor bastard.
Yeah,
he,
I don't think he got hurt too bad like,
but uh,
it didn't stop.
Will,
they'll probably get it down eventually.
But you want to be like super sure.
Here it is.
Oh no,
please don't tell me that this is going
to happen.
Oh no.
Oh my god.
And they did that for a demonstration.
The guy had a suit on his hands in his
pocket and that was the winner.
The engineer.
Yeah.
How about just put a cardboard cutout,
right?
Okay.
WhaT are we playing games here folks?
They're real doll.
Yeah,
exactly.
You don't need to do that,
but the crash test dummies.
This guys just disappeared.
Exactly.
Why don't they have crashed?
Has done,
but to stand.
They're fucking idiots.
Still stand there yourself.
Don't you have a life?
Get hit by a car,
bro.
That guy is probably broken.
Probably every part of his body is
broken.
Yeah.
I mean,
if you don't think you're going to get
bumped by that car like that,
you could easily have broken hip,
broken legs.
Fuck that dude.
I'm very passionate about this.
we're losing our autonomous nature.
We're gonna.
Eventually.
We're going to.
We're going to be controlled by
everything that we have in our life.
You're not going to have
any freedom,
any freedom to move around.
You're going to get in your car.
It's going to take you on a path to
work.
You're gonna punch in the data.
You'll be allowed to have your own car,
but nobody could drive anymore.
Well,
once we stopped letting people drive
their own car,
I mean it was just.
First of all,
road rage,
death stopped.
That's one thing and it was worth it
alone to lose that freedom.
you know why your road rage right?
In a way?
Road rage,
road rage,
because you're scared when you get in
the car and you're going fast,
you're senses are heightened.
You know your senses are heightened.
Everything is dangerous.
You don't feel it because you feel like
I'm just chilling going on the road,
but you're super aware that you're going
fast.
You're super aware.
there's people around you.
They're also in these metal boxes.
You got to trust these idiots to stay in
your lane.
You're already on level eight,
so when someone gets in front of you,
even if it's like nothing,
that's why people don't get road rage
when they're walking.
Like if you're walking in the mall and
it's kind of a lot of people and someone
gets in front of you,
you can go,
fuck you.
Don't give a fuck at all.
Do you ever give a fuck if somebody
walks past you and get them in front of
you with the mall?
They're just walking down the hallway.
No one gives A shit.
Right,
but there's something about being in the
car that your senses are super
heightened up because you're worried
about the consequences of someone
crashed into you.
So you're like,
fuck dude,
fuck box.
And that's where all that shit comes
from.
And then you pull over bitch,
pull over bitch.
Like that's where all that shit cut.
You'll fuck you think you.
Your life's on the line when it's really
a minor fender bender or a minor traffic
infraction or minor rudeness where
someone cut you off were they didn't
have to.
Maybe they could have waited a little
bit and got behind you.
That makes sense.
It just happen to me,
but when I left the other night after
the fight companions,
like 2:00
in the morning,
I was almost home in hollywood.
Some cars were In front of a bar is
there was a little.
You couldn't.
Some cars were blocking the two lanes of
road,
so everyone was merging over.
I merged over,
that guy behind me apparently thought I
cut them off,
so we started getting up on my ass.
I could tell like the guy behind me is
pissed.
I was getting that time so I started
slowing down to just like let them go
past me,
let I'm in a hurry,
go for it.
He just pulls up next to me and stops
and starts cussing me out.
Middle finger,
all this and that.
I just thumbs up,
man.
Like I don't.
I'm not in a hurry.
I don't know where you're going.
I don't know why you're mad,
but I started thinking like,
oh shit,
he's going to follow me around the
corner and it's going to have to get
serious.
But he just went away.
Some people are just nuts and some
people are angry at everything,
right?
They're angry at their wife.
They're angry at their job,
they're angry at their friend.
They're angry at their fucking
neighborhood softball league that won't
let theM pitch.
you know,
people are nuts.
You run into someone.
That's why like getting in those kinds
of exchanges,
like over nothing over cars getting in
front of you.
I state this chick,
she was hilarious.
She is very smart,
like super smart,
but she also would do occasionally she
would do dumb,
reckless shit and one thing should do if
someone cut her off she'd be like,
fuck you,
and she can't find a car and cut them
off.
It was totally contrary to her regular
personality,
her regular personalities,
like super fun loving and she was always
smiling but there was something in her
head about like someone cutting her off.
She was like,
fuck that,
and she would get in front of them and
she cut this dude off and she had a
convertible to little white convertible
bmw.
I was like,
what?
What are You doing?
Like what are you doing?
Like you can't.
You can't just go around doing that.
Like you.
You've gotten lucky if you do that,
someone's going to do something terrible
to you.
Like do you know like this is a part of
like the news road rage murders.
There was at one point in time,
la had a streak of them were it became
trendy and there was people were just
shooting each other on the freeway
during traffic.
Like that scene from la story.
They made fun of it where he has a gun
and it was mrs when I was a kid and I
had heard and we would hear the news
about road rage deaths.
There were always in California and
there was people just shooting people
like fucking crazy.
In California,
you just got to be careful.
You can't cut off the wrong person.
You can't like you can.
You could fuck up in those situations
and you accidentally get killed like you
accidentally.
People kill people in road rage
incidents all the time and I bet the guy
who kills the other guy probably regrets
it for the rest of his life.
90 nine point nine percent of the time,
but you just run into the wrong person
at the wrong time and you stand your
ground.
They stand their ground and next thing
you know,
there's violence.
Unnecessary,
stupid,
senseless violence.
There's too many gangsters in la,
especially like people that have way too
much money and gang violence and so you
don't even know who you're fucking with.
like a prince shore that is a
billionaire and he'll just like kill you
and just be like,
fuck it.
I'll just go,
you know,
go back to la has most road rage related
incidents in the us study finds.
Wow.
Of course,
I'm not surprised what's the numbers
though?
Auto insurance center analyze $65,000.
Us on instagram.
Hashtag road,
rotary.
Chatswood lucky reporting of our
detailed analysis of the situation by
going to hashtag road rage.
I wrote this article five minutes before
I posted it and a fucking.
California is a lot.
You know what that means?
People just bitch in California.
Oh my god.
Fucking road rage.
It does say there's more than 1500
people have been killed or injured in
road rage incidents in the us over the
last five years.
But what about California?
And it doesn't say that he's got to be.
There's gotta be like California road
rage statistics for 2016.
I mean,
we have polIce chases multiple times a
day.
I mean,
I'm watching them nonstop all day,
either the greatest.
Don't you think that what's going on
with us though is that it's just so over
populated.
There's a real frustration that people
have and that's also
part of the road rage.
So if you try to drive to orange county
at 4:00
in the afternoon,
if you leave in downtown la and you try
to make it down to like redondo beach,
good luck.
How many hours is that going to take at
four.
If you leave at 4:30.
Oh,
you fucked up,
dude.
What time do you leave?
I left at five.
Oh,
two.
How long did you take you to get home?
Three hours.
I got three hours in the car.
that's normal.
That happens.
That can happen.
Do you want to go to newport beach?
You want to.
You don't want to live in newport beach,
but work in downtown la.
There's still many of us.
There was a.
I had to go to culver city wherever sony
studios is and all that.
It's at culver city.
I had to go there the other day at like
two in the afternoon.
Now on paper it's like seven miles from
my house or something like that or like
it took me an hour and 20 minutes to get
there the other day and it's literally
like seven to 10 hours for my h or s
seven to 10 miles from my house.
Yeah,
you
could almost walk there.
Yeah.
That's quick.
I mean if you walked how many miles now
and he walk five.
I think if I were on a bicycle I could
got it half the time.
I bet.
Yeah,
for sure.
A bike fOr sure.
If you didn't get killed by someone with
road rage in a fucking fuck you with
some other guy drunk.
fuck.
You cutting each other off and you just
get clipped.
You go flying through the air.
People are angry.
It's too many of us,
but meanwhile you get in a plane,
you fly over the country like a space
while we all huddled up while we fucking
huddled up so much because the ocean,
we need to figure out a way to get the
fucking salt out of the ocean in big
pipes.
Pump it to the middle where everything's
dry and let's fix this.
We do have a lot of desalinization
plants.
If you look it up,
it's a super expensive and slow.
They're not that efficient.
It's a very difficult process.
It's very expensive.
It's not worth it,
you know,
and even not worth it with water,
as jesse ventura was saying on before,
water being more expensive than oil.
It's still not worth it.
Take the salt out of the water.
That's how hard the process is.
It's kind of ironic right next to the
water.
We had a water problem.
Fucking hilarious.
Really stop and thInk about it,
but the like when you're flying over and
you look down at like some of the big
dry spots on the way to vegas,
like,
jesus,
can't you boIl the water out right now?
Kind of go ahead,
try it.
What am I thinking?
That boy not boil.
Boil spring water or pond water or lake
water and you kill most of the shit
that's in there.
There's some shit that can survive that
though.
They have all these water filters that
people take when they're like hardcore
backpackers shit in it and drink it.
Most recently I got really into like
hardcore backpackers because I was
listening to this one podcast where they
were talking about the appalachian
trail.
Have you ever heard of that?
Appalachian trail is a trail that goes
from Georgia all the way to Maine and
they walk.
It takes five months.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
and they wear the clothes the entire
time.
They live off their backpack.
I mean I was listening to you talk about
it.
I'm like,
that is nuts,
man.
That has a nutty way to live.
Like that's how crazy accomplishment.
I mean people think they're bad ass by
doing a marathon do to run 26 miles.
Took me four hours,
but I've perseverance now.
These people are walking to main and
it's one of those things.
Once you start something like that,
like you're kind of committed to it,
you're kind of committed to the stupid
thing.
It's going to take five months.
Fringes did not the whole thing,
but he was just there for a part of it
for five days.
Like last weekend I think he was a
marine but they just went and camped and
you just put up facebook message like
I'm in a hammock but it's 37 degrees.
It's raining and we're fucked.
But the point was they don't know where
they're getting their water from,
so a lot of them bring filters and they
have these things that they hang there.
There's a bunch of different kinds of
filters.
Some of them actually are straws and you
can take it and you actually dip into a
pond and suck it through the straw and
you can drink it and then they have
other ones where they're gravity filters
and they have these like buckets and all
this shit.
If it gets filtered out of the water and
then it comes down to it comes out
clear.
It's really interesting man,
because these people are using like the
best state of the art survival
technology,
like that kind of shit and just drinking
out of ponds and stuff.
Yeah.
I saw the [inaudible] where they like
the ceo goes,
now watch this is urine and it makes it.
Shrinks it.
Yeah.
But you can drink piss.
Pisses new.
Taste that bad.
I know.
It's nothing.
I drank my own piss a bunch of times.
There's a video of you drink and piss on
the internet of me and this dude,
no name because someone had told me that
drink in your own piss was like really
good.
Had vitamins and minerals in it isn't
it's stuff that came out of your body.
Yeah.
The fighter guy.
This is about a bunch of them,
a bunch of people.
Leo machida did it.
He was like kind of famous for drinking
your own business and so I will.
What the fuck is this about?
And I drank it a couple of times and uh,
I was thinking after I drank it,
I can't believe I just drank my piss.
Like,
what the fuck is wrong with me?
Yeah,
yeah,
me and that dude.
So we both just whipped it out and peed
in the cup and then we make.
That's the dude incidentally.
It's no name.
That's the dude who,
uh,
introduced me to a nootropics,
believe it or not.
How ironic.
Inappropriate when we're about to do
something really stupid because we feed
in there.
We clicked it,
I just download it.
But you know what man,
I've been working on fear factor for so
long and he couldn't do it,
man.
He was hurl and don't be a pussy.
Damn,
that's what I'm talking about.
Don't make deal
old school,
old school.
Um,
I don't know why point was about
drinking piss.
Oh,
it's not that big a deal.
It's all in your head.
It's like eating roaches.
Same thing.
It's all in your head.
Like there's a lot of bugs that we
serve.
People on fear factor.
They didn't taste bad at all.
They barely tasted like anything.
Like spiders,
a bunch of spiders.
We ate,
you know,
spiders are um,
they're cousins of crabs,
lobsters and shit.
You know,
oysters taste bad.
Oysters are,
is amazing that we eat oysters.
Like just pulling them out of the ocean,
you can just open them up and just like
sucked down this
slimy vagina.
It is kinda like that,
you know what?
As I said,
do you know how lobsters switched from
being like a,
I don't want to say poor people's food,
but I thought that's what it was.
I didn't make the change.
Well,
um,
it all happened when lobsters used to be
like a bar food.
They used to go to the east river and
the turn of the century,
I think it was like in the 18 hundreds
of the early 19 hundreds and they would
cast out for lobsters and catch them and
feed them to people that were like
hungry at bars.
And it was taught to be like garbage
food.
Somewhere along the line probably the
supplied dwindled because they overfish
them.
Who knows?
I don't know.
I don't know who.
I was reading this thing about diamonds
the other day and how they managed to
keep diamond super valuable when they're
not really rare anymore.
It was fascinating that they recognize
it coming and that diamond production up
until the time they discovered these
mines in South Africa,
I think it was diamond production was
very small,
few pounds a year,
and then all of a sudden they just hit
the motherload.
They just found so many diamonds.
They realize,
oh my god,
diamonds are just weird,
like they're not valuable.
So they formed this giant group,
the debaters group,
and they said,
well,
just hoard all these fucking diamonds
control all the diamond mining.
We decide that they're still valuable,
so because they don't release them,
but they keep mining them and so they
have way more diamonds than they sell.
Like the amount of diamonds,
the diamonds they sell,
and then diamonds are worth a fuck load
of money.
So they.
They're rare,
right?
They split,
they sell them all the time.
They sell them as if they're rare,
but they couldn't be rare.
If there were that rare,
you wouldn't be selling so many of them.
Like how many do you have?
They essentially have an unlimited
supply of diamonds,
but they're making an outline.
Times are so rare.
It's so rare that we found this diamond
like,
bitch,
you got a lot of them.
You got warehouses full of them.
It's kind of like the sunglasses and
glasses industry are all owned,
like all the known,
like ray bans,
oakleys,
they're all owned by one company,
so they.
So like glasses shouldn't be that
expensive or sunglass shouldn't be that
expensive.
It's a lot of sunglass companies do and
they are all owned by the same company.
If you should,
if you look it up,
there's a company.
How many,
how many different.
There's got to be competitive.
It's the same thing.
You watch those on a tv show,
that guy like a whole big breakdown,
big video of the whole thing.
I'll look it up.
But uh,
even what's weird is that like companies
held out like oakley was like,
no,
we're not gonna.
We're gonna to
africa.
What happened?
It's like the store was like,
no,
we don't want to carry this brand
because they won't,
they're not a part of our company.
And then,
uh,
then they just ended up buying oakley
and then raising the price.
Like ray bands used to be cheap glasses
and then when they bought ray ban,
they pumped it up to like now you can
buy a ray ban and like 200 bucks for.
Yeah.
And what did they used to be?
They used to be just like the cheap
glasses,
like a $10 glass or something like that.
Turns out a single company control
several of the outlets where you buy
eyeglasses.
Okay.
So they control the outlets,
but did they own the company?
Yes.
And they have on the company.
So they also own lens crafters.
They also own sunglass hut or any of the
sunglass stores.
They own everything.
That's pretty slick,
right?
Because how many people
buy sunglasses from those sunglass huts?
That's where a lot of people buy them
right statement to snopes.com.
The company said it's sales account for
only 10 percent of the frame sold
worldwide's shouldn't snopes.com
did.
However,
conclude that regardless of the actual
figure,
much of adam's ruins everything's
assessment of luxottica's market
dominance was accurate.
Okay,
so that's that.
Adam ruins everything show interesting
fucking show.
I love that guy.
Yeah,
it's,
it's an interesting show.
It's a,
some of the stuff that he gets on it.
It's really a really,
it's a well measured take that some
people disagree with.
But um,
there was one that steven crowder just
was mocking one and he had some really
good points.
Car dealership is one of my favorite
episodes.
I had no idea about car dealerships.
It was about illegal
ration and he was talking about how the
fence wouldn't help and the fence
wouldn't help because only I think it
was like a certain percentage of the
people that got into the country came to
the country by foot.
It was something like only like 60,
60 percent came in by foot.
So the idea was like,
wait a minute,
see if you could find it.
This is interesting statistics because
it means a lot of people came in by
foot.
Like yeah,
fence would definitely stop that.
Like it wouldn't stop everything,
but by the own,
the definition of the own show explored,
it would stop a large number of people
you see it.
But it probably just changed people
video.
But I'm trying to find the,
the numbers.
So that's 60 percent.
I don't know what the numbers are.
You go,
if you go to louder with crowder is
website explains it in the,
the not just in the video but in the
actual description of the video.
It has the numbers.
So yeah.
Wouldn't that 60 percent though?
Like if there was a wall just fly,
go.
Well I guess we have to fly now.
It's not that easy to fly though.
It's super hard to fly.
The idea is that it's really easy to
walk across that stage.
The idea that offense would help.
But here's something even weirder.
Pete,
dominick.
Pete dominick from the stand up with
pete dominick,
I think radio show on sirius.
I think that's what this show is called.
Forgive me if I'm wrong.
He um,
he was saying the actual
amount of mexicans that immigrate to the
United States,
like the net amount and.
No,
they go back and forth.
Who goes here?
Who there is zero.
It's like it's even like the same
amount.
Go over there as,
come over here.
Yeah.
But how do they know that in plus are
all those people just killed?
Like are people that go down there to
murder?
It depends on where they're going.
Right.
What do you got there?
Jamie doesn't have anything.
He just has a three paragraphs of like
his opinion of what the video is talking
about.
Does it have anything with numbers?
No numbers at all?
No.
Okay.
Well he explains it in the,
if you like play the beginning of the
clip,
it explains it in the clip.
It gets to it pretty quickly.
It's kind of interesting.
Why don't you just play it?
It's kind of interesting because it gets
to the,
the weird numbers of it pretty quick.
We can get this taken off without his
permission.
Can we play?
It's only brian and I can hear it.
Sorry fuckers.
I'll reenact what he says.
Okay.
What'd you do?
Go to the beginning please.
It's a 32nd intro for.
Okay.
Twenty 40 percent came here on planes.
Kill it.
You can kill it.
That's all I wanted to hear.
So that's 27 to 40 percent of the people
came here on planes.
That means that between 60 and 73
percent came here walking like.
How would you say that?
A fence is not going to stop that.
We're in a car.
Yes.
Which will.
Which even if we had a wall,
we mexicans are still allowed to come to
the United States to go on vacation,
aren't sure.
Yeah,
and that's all they're gonna do it.
They have one shot.
If especially if I don't know how it
works,
like how you can get a visa or how you
don't get a visa to visit
some countries.
Some countries are harder,
but Mexico,
the United States ain't that hard.
But going into like philippinEs,
like trying to get it can I try to
remember them when I tried to rescue a
filipino woman,
but she was killed by that tsunami.
I Tried to get her visa and it was like,
oh no,
you have to wait in line.
You have to like six months you won't
get approved because they know they're
not coming back to the Philippines.
That's a lot of people from a lot of
parts of the world.
If you're in a really,
really super poor part of the world and
you get a shot at trying to eek it out
here in the United States,
like fuck it,
I'll take a chance here.
You can establish a life over here over
long periods of time,
man.
Yeah,
I guess you could just come over and
visit.
Pretty easy.
I mean there's a road there.
They have to find a reason why you can't
come over and visit video.
I saw recently people climbing the
fence.
Yeah.
And then they take the kind of stocks
and notice they're caught on camera.
So they run and climbed back over.
well they've got
backpacks on.
They look over at the camera.
The guy got a cell phone near his ear.
Yeah.
I assume there are drug runners,
but I don't know that that's necessarily
because they have those backpacks so
they climbed back over again.
It's that easy.
Skip,
I'll skip ahead.
But
holy shit.
Border patrol.
So border patrol season.
So they're hanging out for a minute.
Wow.
So then the United States right now they
got walkie talkies dude.
Oh,
they see that.
Don't know.
Grab in.
No good.
I've been,
yeah,
they're talking and then they're
covering their face.
Wow.
It's so easy to climb.
That was easy
clock showing you how fast it takes to
take 10 seconds.
Holy shit.
Those dudes are like,
they're like little acrobats to be able
to have that kind of hand strength to
pin down those things and climate like
that.
That's pretty fucking impressive.
So they're just holding onto those
things,
right?
Yeah.
Wow.
That's interesting.
Is that the news caster catching them?
Look at that.
Pretty god.
Oh,
she's.
She's very angry.
They were on the wrong side of the dirt.
Wow.
Yeah.
Imagine if you're on the wrong side of
the dirt.
You're looking at all those nice people
hanging around corpus christi,
partying it up down here,
dodging bullets,
going fucking bull fights and shit.
It's fucking weird that we just decide
that people are born in the wrong batch
of dirt.
Drives me crazy.
Especially with the mexicans.
I just love all my mexican friends and
everything like that.
And the fact that like,
you know,
like trump just pisses me off when it
comes to that.
He's a string,
man.
This thing's very strange.
I just have the crazy feelings.
This is like the last gasps of this
silly system.
It's going to take a few more election
cycles before completely mpo implodes.
Some,
some disasters occurrence has to take
place for someone comes up with an
alternative method that people embrace.
Let's got to be something like it's not.
It's just not going to keep going like
this and can't,
you know,
this is why we're down to these two.
Nobody wants that gig.
It's going to be how long until it's a
computer program.
It's probably not the worst idea.
Twenty years.
Yeah.
You have a siri that's just is common
sense.
It looks up facts and figures and it
tells you what the best answer is that
that situation.
Well,
not only that may be instead of you just
sitting down and making one impulsive
choice as to who's going to be the
leader of the free world.
Maybe if you want to participate in
choosing the next leader,
you have to interface with the system
and then asked to talk to you about your
wants and your needs and desires and
they try to find a solution that's
mutually compatible with ethics and the
desires of all the people that are
attached to the system so they run the
attached to the system through some sort
of ethics program where they try to
think about what's important and what's
unimportant and where people are just
being bitches and where people are being
lazy and where people are being too
controlling and where and just figure
out,
figure out a way that you can concoct a
system of government where a.
Nobody's profiting from being in charge
and as soon as people say they won't do
that because there's just too many
people that profit from being in charge
and gigantic way.
So it's too valuable to be in charge.
It's not something you get off on doing
just because you did a great job.
It's something you get off on doing
because you used it in a personal way to
enrich your own bank account.
You've figured out a way to use these
weird laws that you set up to suck a
bunch of money out of the system.
That's what we're getting over and over
and over again.
That's just all that's,
that's,
that's the reason why they're doing it
in the first place.
Nobody else wants that gig.
You have to be like a crazy person with
a,
uh,
an amazing view of yourself or you just
got to grab them by the pussy grabbing
grabbed by the pussy man.
But imagine if he wins magic.
We have a president that talks about
grabbing chips by the posting.
I just so sick of him.
I just kept on it though.
It's kind of if,
if this is a simulation man,
they're ending it good.
It's coming down nice.
I'd love to see somebody.
I'd rather have kania then trump.
Yeah.
He's going to win next year.
It's gonna be jesse ventura versus
conduit.
They might team up together to kanye
smart,
make jesse his running mate because
jesse like spent a lot of time,
Mexico,
make some sort of a joint agreement
where president kanye takes care of the
heavy lifting and then a vice president,
ventura,
he just works his fanny pack and hangs
around Mexico and case needs me as calm
on the phone because he doesn't have a
cell phone at least to try to get
somebody elected like one of our friends
like joey diaz or something next,
that's not going to work,
but it's almost coming down to that.
I mean the reason why kanye west really
could be president is because it is kind
of almost coming down to a popularity
contest,
so it's almost coming down to.
It doesn't necessarily have to be the
person who could do the job best.
It's the person who the people love the
most,
who they can convince themselves,
can do a good enough job or who the
person can convince them,
but they'll do a good enough job.
It's not necessarily the best person for
the job.
A popular person,
like if a guy like kanye west and kanye
and drake ran together for the children,
it might be they might win.
Man.
Kanye and jay z ran.
Okay.
What if nas runs for president nas and
jay z?
It's a joint ticket.
Hey man,
I might fucking vote for them.
I might do that to nausea.
Smart dude.
Jay z is a smart dude.
Maybe they would come up with something
that makes sense,
but then jay z did have that streaming
music service.
That wasn't really good idea.
What it still does.
Doesn't he still do that?
People buy stuff tight,
didn't work.
I think they're trying to figure out how
to get bought by somebody else probably.
Right?
Yeah.
I mean he's just trying to make a buck.
Got to take a chance.
But anyway,
at the end of the day,
there's a lot of fucking smart people
that are super popular is my point.
If you can get really,
really popular,
like george clooney,
me.
If george clooney didn't run for
president,
he couldn't.
When george clooney can be the president
of this fucking country,
without a doubt,
ronald reagan even sampled when now the
door's opened.
Alec baldwin.
Okay.
Because after all that,
grab the pussy stuff.
All that crazy shit that alec baldwin
did screaming at people calling them
faggots and shit.
No one's going to have to remember that
anymore.
The daughter stuff was terrible.
Yeah,
the daughter.
That was terrible,
but you know why he could say he was
drunk.
He apologized.
They have a great relationship now.
People forgive you.
You don't have to be perfect.
I think if we look for a person who's
perfect to be president,
we're not going to have a president
because there are no perfect people,
but everybody's been lying,
so we have to readjust our curve.
Our curves all fucked up because we've
been dealing with a bunch of
politicians,
had been pretending to be someone who
whether or not they've been lying about
everything they do,
they've been lying about who's paying
them to do this and who they're
supporting,
where the money's coming from and why
they do it,
and there's unspoken arrangements that
they have with certain people that pam
large sums of money.
They don't even have to say,
I want you to do this.
It's understood that you're going to do
things to support their interest because
they've paid a shitload of money to help
you out and to pay you to come do these
fucking speeches of these ridiculous
play.
Nobody wants us.
Nobody wants to see a fucking bill
clinton speech.
Who's paying?
Who's paying for that?
Who's,
who's excited about that?
Who's going to pay enough money to
justify a $250,000
hillary clinton's speech?
Who's paying that?
A crazy person.
You have to be like,
dude,
this is going to be the shit we have.
We have tickets to kiss.
We're going to see kiss.
They have a reunion tour.
I know it's not the real ace freely and
it's not the real peter chris,
but the fucking show is awesome,
dude.
It's amazing and then right after that
to top it off,
hillary clinton is going to speak.
Now.
That's not something she can be a very
effective politician,
but to pay someone that much money to
speak like you just make it an obvious
you're not.
That's not what a normal super famous
person gets.
They don't get $250,000
to speak at a luncheon.
Some comedians not that much clothes,
but you sell out madison square garden.
You know there's a difference.
Like that's ticket sales.
Like if bill burst sells out madison
square garden,
he's going to get a giant chunk of
money.
I don't know what that number is,
but it's probably a giant chunk of
money.
Right?
I'm sure we could ask dane cook.
Dane cook sold out madison square garden
four times.
okay.
That's a giant chunk of money he must
have made,
but he made it because people paid money
to see them,
like they want to see him entertain them
or the bankers really doing that.
Are they fucking psyched?
they have lighters up while she's
talking like,
fuck you talking about deregulation.
Fuck
yeah,
hillary,
she's up there with a bite suit on like
a german shepherd is to jump out of the
back of a paddy wagon and bite her legs
and try to take her down wearing that
boxy bite suit the fuck out of here.
It's the whole thing is ridiculous,
so it's so obvious.
These people are just.
They're just running this thing the way
they've always been running this thing.
We're just getting to see it.
Now we're getting to see it like really
super clear.
We're a real weird,
real weird to watch them scramble and
readjust and change and shift and move,
but if you want to be successful in the
world that those people run in,
you got to be one of those people like.
That's why bernie sanders is shunned
because bernie sanders,
whether you agree with his politics or
you disagree with his politics,
and I agree with a lot of things,
he says he's an outsider.
They don't want that guy.
that guy's not going to play ball.
That guy's going to talk to people,
he's going to be reasonable.
He might be,
you know,
anti capitalist to a certain extent to
some people,
but ultimately what he does represent is
some thing that's different than the way
things are running now and that they're
not having that fuck that.
But he got closer than anybody like him
has ever gotten ever.
So I think if four more years of chaos,
whoever the fuck gets in qa,
you might want to go to Canada for a
little bit,
just hang out,
just go to vancouver and yeah,
who knows what the fuck's going to
happen man.
I mean people are up in arms.
I've been watching exclusively fox news
because those are the people that think
the least liked me.
So I've been exclusively watching and
occasionally I agree with them on many
things,
but those are the people that I agree
with the lease.
So it is fascinating watching them.
First of all,
the trump debate.
I thought he's too.
I thought he's.
Oh,
and two,
I thought hillary whooped him in the
first one and I thought she.
She clearly outboxed him and out moved
him in the second one he did land a
devastating blow that you'd be in jail
because you'd be in jail.
I was devastating.
That was like a total two point round.
It was a 10,
eight round for sure.
He dropped her.
She got rocked.
Referee saved her.
She saved by the bell there,
but other than that I think she won.
I think she's just,
she's just better at that.
She's got better economy of words unlike
me rambling.
She's got.
She says her sentences more concisely.
She's more measured in her approach.
She's more disciplined in her
preparation to say that she didn't win
is.
It's not fair.
It's not true.
Like if you're.
So I'm watching these people just lie.
Well obviously Donald Trump was the
winner of that debate.
I think there can be no doubt.
There could be no doubt.
Like,
oh,
are you really serious?
Is that what you guys are arguing?
It blows my fucking mind though.
Like like,
how are you watching the same thing as
me and every person that was in the room
with me agreed with me.
You know,
like how like if you were in the room,
would we be both sitting there like
fighting?
There's,
there's terms that he uses that you
should only use very,
very sparingly because they indicate
that you're scrambling and one of those
is a,
and I'm going to be honest with you and
I'll be honest with you.
This is A shame.
I find this to be a shame like that to
me,
says he's,
he's in the moment.
He's in the moment,
but he's free ball and a little bit he's
free balling.
She's not doing that.
She's saying the America that we see in
front of us is not perfect,
but it is the best that we can find in
the world today and I'm proud to be an
american and she says this stuff with
the right inflection and whether or not
that's.
I know it.
Google news crew can choose going to
ruin this country.
I understand that,
but that's not what the debate is.
Okay.
Would a debate is some sort of a contest
of words or it's a battle of words.
It's a battle of ideas.
It's battle concepts about of words and
personalities.
Importantly,
he did everything wrong in that respect,
looming over her and it wasn't
effective.
You know,
she,
she didn't take the bait.
She didn't engage.
She laughed and smiled when he said
ridiculous shit.
Even when he said you'd be in jail,
she walked off and jusT stood there as
if nothing happened.
Like she had.
She had a great reaction to him.
So it's not whether or not she'd be a
better president,
but if you want to judge a debate like a
game of tic tac toe or checkers or you
know,
or,
or some sort of a thing that you're
sCoring your scoring this thing.
I mean the people,
it's like a team.
You watch it on online.
Sixty seven percent think mr.
Secretary of state clinton won the
debate.
Now the trump supporters feel
differently and then you go to these
people and they're like,
well,
I felt he was strong.
I felt like what he said and that one
thing,
you go to jail that really rang with
moo,
and see all these people that they've
chosen that it kind of interesting or
controversial or stupid or that one guy
with the crazy sweater they had that
poor bastard,
they have some poor bastard with a giant
red sweater and he stood out there and
he saId his name and so his name became
like a meme.
that sweater became a meme.
That sweater sold out everywhere.
All over the world.
Like instantly.
People are going to be that guy for
halloween now.
Yeah,
he's everywhere.
He's everywhere.
Shirts.
Good for him,
good for him,
but he's cool.
But that's.
It's a fucking.
It's a game and it's an entertaining
show.
That's what these debates are and it's a
giant hustle and this is what I'm
sending out saying this a conspiracy
theory sort of a way because I think
we're hustling ourself.
We want this hustle.
This is a hustle.
We all want to say,
we all want to pretend that he's going
to fix it or we don't want to pretend
that she's going to be amazing.
We all want to pretend it's a.
It's a weird,
weird show.
It's a weird show and we're watching
these people improvise right in front of
us.
Alex Jones,
response to it was very upsetting to me.
It was wonderful.
Alex johnson,
literally,
she's a demon from hell.
Literally.
We've flies land on her head.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we seen flies,
talked to people who are on the scene.
He's fucking beat red sky purple,
red face.
thursday evens demons are real.
he was crying.
It's wonderful.
I love that guy.
He's the best.
I agree with that.
That was upset and he's taken it to the
right place.
I think he's just gone full parody.
Just go.
Just get so crazy.
I think it's perfect.
That's perfect.
Yeah.
Just give people just a little more than
they can swallow.
I'm choking back.
The irony and the crazy is making even
like the serious conspiracy theories
reconsider their position,
which I think is good.
Which is also the best argument that he
psyops that he's actually cia,
nsa undercover to discredit the entire
truth or movement.
Don't you understand?
I went down to rabbit holes last night
to tower seven rabbit hole.
So I went down the explanation tower
seven rabbit hole,
which I found to be very plausible.
And then I went down the other rabbit
hole,
which is actual scientists that are uh,
saying that nine slash 11 was absolutely
a controlled demolition.
And it's really weird man because one of
them,
the scientist guys who's given this
lecture,
I forget the gentleman's name,
but he's a professor emeritus of some
university which means a,
he was a professor and then he retired,
but they allow him to keep his title and
keep his office.
And this dude is off his rocker.
He's.
He does.
He's to our speeches about tower seven,
you know,
about free fall speed and thermite and
all these different chemicals that were
found in the wreckage.
And he's just obsessed with this idea.
And apparently he's not the only one.
There's thousands of different,
at least a thousand.
I think it was like 1500 or something,
architects and engineers in that nine
slash 11 truth thing that think that
nine slash 11 was an inside job or tower
seven was a controlled demolition or
both.
You know,
there's a spectrum of belief systems
that's involved in the nine slash 11
truther movement.
You know,
some people think that there's a lot of
nuts to think that planes didn't even
really hit the towers,
that there were explosions and then
there's other people that think that the
towers were rigged and that they rigged
these things like years in advance and
they remember seeing these maintenance
people and they were like these
nefarious maintenance people are setting
up through my bombs all throughout the
beams of the.
But then there's this other video that
shows how how easily things weakened.
A under fire shows a bunch of shit
collapsing under fire,
including a bridge.
There was one where a bridge collapsed
just because of a fire underneath the
bridge.
The steel and the bridge heated up too
much and just couldn't support the
weight and apparently what is explaining
is that people think that steel melts at
a certain temperature,
which is very true,
but it's significantly weakens way lower
at a way lower temperature.
Then it melts.
So they were showing all these different
things that,
that collapsed just fall
down to just give up just like that
tower seven did.
But it's fun to think that there is an
evil genius that lives in a mountain
that rigged all that shit.
And now he's laughing in a pile of money
because he got away with it 15 years
ago,
you know,
they opened a walmart in burbank,
thank god.
And,
and I was excited and I decided,
I decided I hate mom and pop businesses.
It just because it's not.
See people working for the sheep,
you know,
it's just nice.
Uh,
but you go there thinking it's in
burbank,
one of the suburban nicer areas of los
angeles.
No way.
It's going to be the same people that go
to a walmart in burbank.
Then you're,
you know,
you see on the internet or no,
whatever it is,
it's like a,
like flies on poop.
Uh,
it,
it was just filled with like tits
hanging out.
This woman's Bruises all over like kids
with no shoes on.
Like it was just like,
where are all these people from?
They find it,
they find it and I,
you know,
the,
the conspiracies and all that crap.
To me it just,
it's like that half the people on my
facebook,
I just look at him like,
dude,
I,
I should leave.
We need to get chinese assassins of old
people to come over here and make
walmart big fly trap.
Walmart's and he just say,
hey,
you tired of white people being pushed
down and we'll come on in this room were
organized and know,
like having a bunch of different like
social honey traps where people just
fall into a pillow up
all the walmart's on black friday and
then trump loses.
Could you imagine if we got to a point
wHere we had to start killing people
off?
Like there's just way too many people
and there's no other way around.
In China.
We got a call people the same way they
want to call wolves and the greater
yellowstone ecosystem.
What the fuck,
man?
Is that possible?
Is it possible?
I mean,
we're keep overpopulating,
right?
We're at 7 billion.
They project,
I think they project 8 billion by 2050.
I think that's what they said.
See if that's true.
Jamie.
There's a lot of middle states though.
We got a lot of room.
We just got it.
You don't have the water right that we
talked about this,
the desalinization.
It can't fill up those areas,
but don't you think that there's gonna
come a time if we survive,
right?
Say if there's no super volcanoes,
no asteroid impacts,
no plague,
no nuclear war,
and we avoid all that shit.
You know the water is going to ride.
We're going to move in.
We'll be fine.
The coast to just be in a different
spot.
It's not that big of a deal.
I mean it's a big deal obviously,
but it's not the,
it's not a kill off the population.
Big a deal.
So if it keeps going and we keep.
the technology keeps getting better,
we Just keep.
Keep making people,
we just keep doing it.
We keep the numbers keep rising and
rising and rising and then we get to be
like $30 million,
$40,
million,
$50 million and we have real problems
where we don't have enough food,
we don't have enough air,
we don't have enough space.
What are we going to do?
Make food.
That's already a thing.
What about gil?
Stupid people.
Stupid.
Sure.
No,
you
can't say that because that's what
hitler wanted.
He had.
He had some good ideas and some bad
ideas.
No,
I mean there's definitely like the look
this chinese thing that makes complete
sense if they're killing off.
Do you think they're doing that though?
Yes.
There's too many people in China.
They cannot have that many people.
So if they get rid of a certain age of
people,
especially if they have mental issues
like homeless people,
you know,
but we already figured out that the
United States has almost 100,000.
Right.
Was it [inaudible] 90 something thousand
at any given yet said about $90,000
any given year.
Any given day.
Any given 10,000
missing.
Oh,
excellent.
So overall I see,
I see,
and this is elderly people.
Oh this is including kids.
Well that's way different.
Are they talking about 500,000
elderly or $500,000?
100,000
elderly.
Ooh.
Oh yeah.
They're killing them for sure.
Right,
right.
For sure.
That's why they killed kids or they used
to,
but they,
you know,
if you will.
That's kind of what I'm saying.
Right.
About populations.
If they get too high,
see people aren't valuable anymore.
500,000
elderly people go missing in China every
year,
which is 80 percent.
Eighty percent of the missing people
are,
I believe to 80 percent of people.
Do you think that's real?
Do you think they're killing people or
do you think people just get lost really
easy.
A look at it,
it's eigHty percent of 80 percent are
elderly,
so yes,
I believe that they're killing them or
there's 72 percent suffered some sort of
memory impairment.
Yeah.
But it might be a mental health issue,
but they might just not treat their
mentally ill.
But look at the numbers in that chart.
Jamie.
Scroll back up there,
look at that shit.
Look at the difference between what is
the earliest part of the chart in 1965
population of people over 65.
Yeah,
but 1965 page thing.
Jamie the bottom 19.
Sixty five to 2015.
If you look at the way he runs up to
2015,
that's a spike man or at least a steep
ramp and then they're saying that kill
an old now and they're saying that out
of those groups that are missing,
a large amount of them have been
diagnosed already with like an illness
like alzheimer's or something like that.
So they're already on the way out there
saying so.
So they just.
They isom they get rid of soy.
Yeah,
because it's costing them more money and
population.
It's.
It's taken up space to to imagine if we
find out that there is a murder racket
in China that kills 500,000
old sick people a year.
Imagine.
I mean,
right now we're just looking at a
number,
but if we found out that is absolutely
what was going on,
I think by 20,
30 they're going to have more than 400
million people over 60 their g and they
last longer.
The asians because they eat so nice.
That's so racist.
It's so funny.
As a meme,
like a racist,
mean people are going to beat your ass.
Isn't that funny?
But you said nothing but a good thing.
No,
you said good things,
but it's racial and so when it's racial,
people automatically get recreationally
upset,
recreational outrage kicks in and
they'll call you a racist for saying
that asian people last longer because
they eat well.
But you just said eat night.
Nice.
That was a better way to say it.
The,
uh,
the,
my,
my girlfriend's agent and she's the most
racist of chinese people have all the
time and most asians hate chinese people
and you're like,
why are you racist against chinese
people?
She's like,
oh,
they're stupid dude.
Then you research it and you're like,
maybe you should let her say to my ex
girlfriend the one that died in the
crash,
but uh,
but,
but then you read all these things like
that.
I like about this and you're like,
holy shit.
what's going on in China?
It's fucked up over there,
man.
Tell you what's going on.
Or he's been there.
I know of quite a few people that have
been in China.
Somebody just.
Oh,
tate tate's in China right now?
Yeah,
he's doing some crossfit shit over
there.
He's doing some stuff with the guy who
owns crossfit.
Yeah.
Is a trip man.
Apparently though there's something like
50 new billionaires are created every
day in China.
Something insane like that.
Tate told me I should probably know
these things before I say them out loud,
but you know,
it is folks.
How many new billionaires are Created
every day in China?
What do you say,
brian?
50 sure was it say business insider says
China gets the new billionaire every
five days.
So not five every day.
It's one every five days.
Well that sounds more likely.
So that's a 20 a month one every one
every five days.
Six month wait a minute.
When every five days or seven days in a
week,
there's four weeks in a month.
Thirty days every month.
So every so six,
six times 5:30.
So every month they get a billion.
Except for like february.
It's short months.
Sixty every year.
Something like how crazy is that?
So it's 68 year essentially 50,
60 year instead of 50,
60 a day when I was only off by a factor
of 365.
Let's see whAt tate said.
Maybe tate lied to me.
Motherfucker.
It is a strange place though.
Like when we think about like that
language can develop in two different
places in two completely different ways.
Like if you got your language that we
have over here with our very specific
sounds that sound like english and then
they get a little weirder when they go
to certain places.
Like if you go to a,
you know,
like a Germany or like thoSe places that
they have different sounds and they have
the parts of the world where they have
like different sort of sounds like that.
And then you've got China which has got
its own kind of weird thing and then on
top of that,
okay,
here he says they
have made a here each year for 400,
$9 millionaires made their each day of
the year.
That's more impressive.
Wow.
That's what it was.
He said 409 millionaires made their each
day and $50.
Million people living in shanghai.
Okay.
That's,
that's the 40.
That's the 50.
That's where I got confused.
Fuck man.
But their language,
like when you look at it written down
and you're like,
whoa,
this is alien.
Alien language.
Like we didn't know that chinese was
chinese.
You know,
you pass by chinatown,
you go,
oh,
they have a.
Yeah,
chinese language on the wall.
If you went into space and you found
that shit on a rock in a cave somewhere,
he'd be like,
oh my god,
it's alien language.
It's so much more sophisticated than
ours.
Look at the characters.
I can't.
I can't be deciphered.
We will be looking at it like what is
that?
These little characters,
sort of strange characters and they all
know and they have way more characters
and we have letters way more because
each character is like a word,
like waterfalls.
Exactly.
Fucked up.
What was it supposed to be on your arm
are for chinese are from my last name.
Written.
There's no such thing as an in chinese
and so they thought you said wow,
a waterfall fall.
Yeah.
Well it wasn't a asian person that did
it though.
Right?
A white girl horse.
She didn't know.
Eighteen year old was writing.
That bitch made up some shit on you,
drew on you.
I made up some shit.
She had a book that actually said like I
said,
hey.
And it showed the symbol be,
but it was Just bullshit.
People that made that book are laughing
while they pushed it out the door and
chinese joke book,
racist,
racist.
Do a chinese accent,
but you can do an english accent all
day.
It was strange,
but isn't it odd he can go,
hello and how are you brian reichle and
no to go.
You fucking racist.
You're racist piece of shit.
But if you will,
not the whole malakal
if you do that,
you're racist.
Right?
That sounds racist.
You are mocking the way chinese people
sound.
well.
he ever unusual
sound like I'm on the whole or you hear
them talk.
It's like a very weird kind of
fascinating.
I think it sounds cool,
but it's,
it's a strange sound in comparison to
the english that we're used to.
Is it racist though?
I mean like I've told you about.
How old is mr brian?
Well,
yeah,
but if I just like I told you about
this,
my girlfriend who has to speak korean,
so I try to speak korean,
like I just tried to make the noises,
not anything racist.
Like I jusT try to make the noises and
then like every couple,
like 10 seconds she'll be like,
you just said grasshopper.
You just said haka and like it's weird.
And then like make noises,
noises that sound like,
like,
well if you collect these,
doing that with her and you'll learn the
language I know is to constantly create
a database in your head.
You can do it.
Dude,
I got faith in you.
I've learned that.
I've learned a few words.
I used to teach taekwondo in Korea and
really stiff count and korean.
No way.
Do you still know?
Yeah,
I think so.
I'll probably fuck it up.
Uh,
it was like a dual set net dose now
fucked it up already.
Those use.
It'll go to dude.
I'm not saying it very good either
beCause my instructor had a very strong
accent and it was hard sometimes to
understand exactly how to say the words.
But like a kicks would be in um,
in,
in taekwondo kicks would be.
You'd say it in koRean,
like a up chuggy.
Chuggy was front kick.
Chuggy is roundhouse kick.
It was like a bunch of different.
Yeah.
I don't remember all of them though.
I forgot a lot of them.
Man,
I forgot a lot of it.
I learned how to say like,
I guess it means like gay or something
like that.
But you say I did,
but you say it as like,
like,
like that or something.
So like japanese?
No,
no,
no.
Korean,
korean.
So,
so.
Okay.
So I embarrassed my girlfriend,
like will be in publiC and out have
nowhere.
I'd just turned to me like.
And she's like [inaudible].
I guess it's really embarrassing saying
nookie.
Nookie.
Yeah.
Like,
oh,
that limp bizkit song.
Yeah,
I did it all for the nicki.
Nicki.
so if they went to see limp bizkit,
they just start laughing.
Oh,
I cAn't believe I'm saying this.
Is that what happened?
Yeah,
probably there was a weird time where
I'm like,
it's very strange where a word from some
other language means nothing over here.
Like we say words and it means like
something really fucked up over there.
Like just certain words like,
okay,
here's a perfect example of fanny pack.
Fanny means vagina and england.
I got that app,
have fuck that happens.
Simulation theory or facts for
cigarettes,
they call cigarette a fag
or a faggots.
You know what that is,
man.
Here's the thing,
there's,
there's a misconception about that.
The entomology,
I think that's the word of that word,
the word faggot even was even miss
misspoke on the louis ck show that they
said that it was originally that the
reason why they use that term for gay
people is because it's a bundle of
sticks and they would light the bundle
of sticks on fire,
and so the reason why they call someone
a faggot in the reason why it was so
offensive is because that means that
they're to be lit on fire.
That's not true.
No,
that's not true,
and it wouldn't have taken long to
research this.
The actual origin,
what it means is it's a bundle of wood,
like a burdensome woman.
A faggot is very difficult to carry
because it's like a bundle of wood and
you're,
you're.
It's very difficult to balance a budget.
It's cumbersome.
So a burdensome woman became a faggot.
So a guy who act like a woman,
like a burdensome woman became a faggot.
It had nothing to do with lighting on
fire,
and there's no evidence other than
isolated hate crimes,
crimes.
There is no evidence of a practice of
lighting people on fire other than war,
you know,
some horrible things that people have
done when they've conquered cities.
They've lit entire villages On fire and
shit along those lines,
but for the most part,
even the salem witch trials,
like most people think that they let
those people on fire,
most of them were drowned.
That's what theY did with most of them.
They weren't burning witches at the
stake really,
but they did drown a bunch of fucking
people.
BuT they didn't,
they didn't,
they,
they've done it throughout history,
but it's not been something that they
practiced on gay people to the point
where that became the nickname because
it was a bundle of woods.
They're going to light them on fire.
But people love to reiterate that
without looking into it and it's uh,
it's still,
it's still a gross word when you're
applying it to a homosexual person to
sort of dehumanize them.
It's still gross term,
but that's not what it originally meant.
it meant a burden.
some woman,
yeah,
I've never heard the fire before,
but I've always heard the wood and like
if you talk to your gay friends,
it's okay if you,
if they say it back to fourth year,
that we can do it around other dudes are
getting to the punch you gave.
Those are dudes,
man.
Hey,
I'm make sure that I'm correct on that.
I'm 99 percent sure I am,
but um,
the,
the entomology of the word faggot and
pretends to a burdensome woman as it
pretends that it's one of those things
just get sort of repeated as an urban
myth or as a,
you know,
it's,
it's weird.
It's weird how many different fucking
slurs there are for people.
You know,
it almost in some ways be better if
there's just one and we use it
universally [inaudible] what would yours
be?
Oh,
I like for everybody.
Like it's too,
it's too hard to call morons.
Like moron is always good.
I to say here at jimmy.
No,
make it a little bigger.
The word faggot,
it's been used in english since the late
16th century and his abusive term for
women,
particularly old women,
uh,
in reference to homosexuality may derive
from this,
uh,
female,
as female terms are often used with
reference to homosexual feminine men.
Uh,
duh,
duh duh.
Um,
what does it say?
The application of a term to a woman as
possibly the shortening of the term
faggot gatherer applied to 19th century
people.
I'm going to call mIlo that from now on.
A especially older women who made a
meager living by gathering and selling
firewood.
Interesting.
Hmm.
Also the sense of something awkward to
be carrIed.
Okay.
That's where it is.
So compared to the use of the word
baggage.
Okay.
That makes sense.
As a pejorative term for old people in
general.
So awkward to carry.
Okay.
Yeah.
So that's essentially it.
So that's where it came from.
The comparing men to women,
not comparing men to something that theY
light on fire.
So when people say that it's just not
true,
still doesn't excuse people for slurs,
but we shouldn't lie,
you know.
And that's the problem wIth something.
Sounds so good.
You want to repeat it over and over
again,
but it's not true.
Like,
yeah,
it's terrible to slur people.
Yes,
you're rIght.
But we should be honest about the origin
of words,
you know,
and that's not honest,
but It's something that gets repeated a
lot and people don't look into it at
all.
They just want to say it because it
sounds awesome.
And when you say it well,
the reason why it's so offensive because
at one point in time that's what they
use to describe a bundle of wood.
Okay.
So when you and your friends,
you think you're funny,
you think you're Casually calling each
other faggots.
Okay.
Calling each other the other f word.
How long before faggot becomes the other
f word?
Is it already happened?
Is there any happened?
I think so,
right?
Riders on the storm.
Doom.
Doom,
doom,
doom.
Anything you want to add before we wrap
this bitch up with George Perez,
ontario.
October 20th.
Powerful ontario improv.
That'S a fun place,
man.
Good.
That's a good spot.
We're super lucky in California that we
have.
I heard the oxnard one is the shit.
Yeah,
me too.
It's a new one,
but thing of the just the improv chain
alone.
You've got [inaudible],
you've got braya,
you've got irvine,
you've got ontario,
all his fucking bad ass places to work
all within a couple hours drive.
Yeah,
I mean if you're like a southern
California comic,
the improv are the shit.
I love it.
we're lucky.
We're fucking super lucky and we didn't
even mention hollywood.
Oh yeah.
I mean there's the big one in hollywood,
which is one of the oldest and best
clubs in the world.
I mean,
how,
what a strong chain,
you know,
that's.
I've worked those fucking clubs all the
time,
man.
I'm always there.
It's a,
it's amazing when you stop and think
about it,
like what are the fucking city has that
many major clubs that close like that.
Dude,
we're so lucky.
Yeah,
but ontario is awesome.
George Perez is awesome too.
I love working with george.
He's a,
he's fucking hilarious and he's such a
good person.
So he's a great dude man.
I love that guY and we have fun.
We have fun on the show.
It's because they like,
you know,
you get this like cool desk squad mixed
with mexican audience and is.
It just works.
It's just great.
It's a good time.
Live bet,
man.
He's fun.
I should do some shows that you guys.
Yeah.
Love it and be fun and do some,
some.
I want to get some of his crowd to see
what that's like.
Oh,
it's a party.
It's a party.
He's a fun guy.
He was a fun guy to do a podcast with
man.
He's a smart dude.
All right.
Um,
that's it.
You fuckers.
We'll be back tomorrow and until then.
Oh,
Russell Peters.
And that's it.
See you guys.
Bye.
Thank you.