The Joe Rogan experience.
Oh,
kicking it down.
These mice or hottest fuck chicken and
live from the Rogan compound with my man
already.
Shaffir already motherfucking spheres in
the house.
Ladies and gentlemen.
A R s h a f F I r,
follow him on twitter.
Joe Is Mad Flavor,
Aka Planet Rock,
Aka Joey Karate.
He's here as well.
Brian,
right?
Brian Redman,
red,
b,
a n.
As long as that was going on.
When it's background music.
Did you make that Song Brian?
No,
it's my laptop.
Oh yeah,
we did.
We used to put between garageband and
guitars.
Yeah.
We haven't been playing music.
I'm trying to clean it up for satellite
radio,
which may or may not ever happen.
Hopefully.
Well,
it looks like it's happening.
Whatever bitches.
I'm much respect to the fleshlight.
Our sponsor,
before we even get started,
before we get groovy,
which you bitches if you go to Joe
Rogan.net.
What's that?
Buddy was in the corner.
Just.
That's one of them yesterday.
They're all over the place.
There's one over here too,
so house is littered with Mrs.
Rogan comes in there the other day.
It looks at all of them.
She goes,
is there enough of these?
Is what she looks at him.
She goes to these,
so she looks at them like this is like
her competition that she has to accept
like little things that live in her
house that I fuck houses full of baby
dolls and male Gobos.
Yeah.
What's up?
Filled with child's toys and Dick Toys.
Big Fat box addicted.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net,
click the link for the flashlight.
You go to the website,
type in the word Rogan.
Get 15 percent off.
Some looking out for your bitches.
You know what I'm seeing?
I'm trying to get you some discounts on
your masturbation at me.
God is calling you to do what you gotta
do.
If you could save 10 points and whack
off at the same time,
it was better than you.
We had a good goddamn time last weekend
in Vegas.
Holy Shit.
Was that fun?
That that was a good fucking time.
These guys dropped acid.
They were up in the the stairs watching
with big smiles on the faces.
I don't know.
When I found out that they dropped acid,
did I find out a dinner I tweeted you at
during the UFC?
Yeah,
but I don't get tweets.
I mean,
I mean tax texted him.
He texted me.
Yeah.
So that's how I found out.
No,
it was like the last half hour.
Right.
You look,
you look it up.
I thought waved at us.
Oh,
okay.
Then I must have known it was sitting in
the drawer,
red cable.
One day we're talking about something
else and I go,
it's to be great this weekend that as
I'm talking to them,
I open up a lot higher in low and there
were seven hits.
Acid.
If we dropped the s and he's like,
oh,
I don't know.
And I go,
every time somebody gets hit will feel.
It was the original plan.
At first we were like,
well what do you think about red band?
We don't know when we're saying that we
should fucking dose I'm ever going to
put out some for the said Nah,
because I know it's hard to have nine
slash 11 fucking.
That's my little brother acids.
A little different.
You don't want to dose somebody with
acid made a decision not to do it
anymore in my life because I've gotten
to a point where my brain,
I just want to keep my brain a little
bit together and it was together.
Station stuff.
This stuff is very mild.
Sure.
If that was kid stuff that was good.
He said,
yeah,
well if you took a two hits and you were
still being able to sit there,
then it had to be shaved.
Very Mild,
very mild.
It came in spurts and burst.
It was very nice.
The lights fucked with you.
Uh,
what did they voice fuck with you from
time to time?
Have Buffer,
buffer,
be a really great.
Is his vibrated you and that video
before the UFC he starts.
Oh,
that was powerful
throughout.
There was a part where already looked
over and goes,
this is the most beautiful thing I've
ever seen.
The best job on that thing.
It was the bathroom that you have to see
video when it first starts,
where it's like
they said it to the,
uh,
American.
That teenage or teenage Riley's and uh,
yeah,
they set all the beats,
all the punches to the,
you know,
junk hits.
He realized how brilliant something is
sometimes when you're high.
What is it about that?
Why do you,
why do you have to get high to,
to realize that?
I don't know.
It seems silly when you're sitting
there,
you're straight out of the UFC and it
starts.
We don't say all that shit.
You feel it.
When we,
when we did ds,
it was a different fucking level.
We felt everything.
It's funny how like you go to the movies
and if you go to the movies you're on
acid or on pot or anything.
You could see bad acting domino that
night.
Huh?
That's why we sat down,
watched domino with fucking Mickey
Rourke and carrot dangling.
It was interesting.
It was from a different angle.
You're watching acting.
So.
I'm sorry I interrupted you.
So what were you saying?
You were saying that you're,
you guys are there,
you're on acid,
and the Babo Riley's starts playing in,
which is,
if you've never seen it,
never been to a lot of UFC.
It's really brilliant.
Whoever edited it,
it's like some of the highlights of some
of the greatest fights ever and it's all
put together to the WHO.
It's fucking.
It's one of the greatest videos humans
have ever,
so it's a perfect volume to rip you
apart.
You could hear it,
but it doesn't really bother you.
Dana and Dana and I were watching that
the other day and I go,
dude,
I think I've seen this a thousand times
and I still like watching it.
I love it.
It's a good thing if you're there live
10 minutes before the UFC actually
starts,
you have to be in your seat.
You have to be so good to like whoever
did it.
You can tell that guy loves fights like
he just.
He nailed it to perfect beats to the
perfect fucking punches and kicks and
gets you pumped up.
Definitely do.
Today.
I'm telling you,
it never wears out.
I've,
I've seen it hundreds of times.
I don't know how many times I've seen
it,
I've seen it.
I mean every UFC star have done at least
100 us' and you're there.
You're not getting food when that's
happening.
Yeah,
because between spikes between spike and
regular UFC is.
I think I've done over 100,
so been over a thousand fights.
Well,
here's the best one.
It and we need it.
Like I said,
when you're there as a civilian and on,
it just goes from Babo rally and it
locks down here.
You just see a picture and this is
silver saying,
when I go back tonight,
I'm going to knock his fucking mouth
block right now.
Think about it on the acid.
Now his head just came out and I think
it was vetoed and it was just a fucking
head.
I thought it was fucking Marlon Brando
is superman.
The fucking heads around them.
It was like you're going down in New
York City,
got water.
They were judging them and it was just
heads will.
That's the brilliance about it.
That at one point in the UFC as a
civilian,
it just gets very dark and it's just a
perfect timing.
Austin,
you see a head pop back tonight.
I'm going to take them pound them
submission.
You're like,
yeah,
you just gotTa keep showing little
tidbits,
you know,
and they showed a veto.
Then they went to John Jones,
then they went to Jake Ellensburg.
It was just so well done.
Every time that show a new allied or
ducks crowd explodes and it's when you
watch another sporting event.
Now it's so below that.
Paul,
I went to a Laker game last year
against,
uh,
against Wade waves team though he might
Miami here.
There was a fucking great game,
but there was a lot of lols in it.
There's a lot of lows in it at the UFC.
When Bruce Buffer says,
do what you gotTa do,
Go for 22 fucking minutes.
I like glass.
I like,
go get a hot dog,
right?
We argue that fucking thing.
We now want a fucking game stuff that's
huge that they tell you that courtesy
and what that is Fox had done.
No.
Sometimes we have a certain amount of
prelim cards,
but then the main card started saying
like,
you know,
7:00
PM and if the main card starts at 7:00
PM,
we have to have,
if the prelims are all done,
sometimes you get 20 minutes for the
fights are supposed to start.
So we don't start fights early.
We have to wait until paperview starts.
Sometimes you get like five first round
knockouts in the early fights.
Yeah.
And they're just like,
yeah.
And then we run out quick and it was
weird because this particular UFC
started off.
I think we gave Ruediger as wherever he
for Paul Taylor and beat up fast and
then Kingsley came out against Romero
and hit him with violent gladiator fuck
it up.
And these to the body and like fuck man,
you can feel bad motherfucker.
You could feel the fucking chimney
strikes.
I kinda have the asset.
I was finding myself like this and also
I looked around and adjust myself.
What's going on?
Check yourself before you wreck
yourself.
Even when you're not high.
That dude's a specimen or specimen it.
He's kind of like a fucking solid 12
pack.
He's got a 12 pack on his back.
He's one of those dudes.
You look at his back,
there's all these crazy striations in
their super athlete.
Yeah.
It was fun shit with those football
players on another level to another
level of athleticism and Kingsbury
smashed that dude.
He just,
he's one of those guys every time you
see him,
it's like he's been training for three
years,
you know,
he makes these leaps and a couple of
months.
And I was like,
yeah,
all those super athletes,
man,
that Jon Jones dudes,
those guys,
they make these giant leaps.
You know,
there's some dudes to just get so good
so quick.
You know,
when you watch like John Jones,
the first fight that he had a um,
you know,
or even the fight with Stephan Bonner.
Yeah.
He looked promising but bought or made
it to the distance,
you know,
I mean he beat bond are up and
everything like that and did some wild
stuff.
People are like,
wow,
this kid is wild.
He's unorthodox.
But then you see them now and you go,
fuck man,
this kid is on another level to another.
The way he handled Brandon Vera and you
know,
I mean his last fight was just,
just proved it.
Brian painters a fucking stud.
He just manhandled that kid.
He was on top of him.
Every time there was an exchange,
he was on top controlling the position.
He was never remotely threatened and
squeezing.
Yeah.
The kids a beast,
man.
Ryan Bader is a fucking gorilla.
Do would you just stand next to that
guy?
He's one of the biggest tool fibers out
there.
And the fact that Jon Jones is able to
handle him like that.
It was like a half second where there
was like a scrum,
like he tried to flip it and get them
all the way over and then John's got out
of that and it was done in.
Jon Jones has two brothers and both of
them are fucking football player.
Bad motherfuckers.
Yeah.
It's like his whole family's got like
super genes that was standing there that
night.
He had two brothers that were bigger
than.
I guess he's the.
He has a baby brother or whatever in the
1975 nba playoffs on those years.
Daryl Dawkins member,
Daryl Dawkins,
he was six foot two,
smashed it backboards six slash 11 to
90.
I remember that into a brawl with
Maurice Lucas and all of a sudden they
showed his family coming down from the
stands and they had two brothers and his
sister bigger than him from fucking
Florida.
You know what those mother online
trolling security important.
They're all nice white people up there
in Portland.
These four fucking fucking people were
just throwing them out of that six foot
11.
Jarrod was smashing fiberglass.
Unheard of.
I remember.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm just crushed up glass.
Why aren't they with their fucking
reinforced.
That guy who was fresh out of the
jungles of fuck.
What?
What did they do back then when the
glass breaks?
Did they just roll it out and they roll
another again?
Another one that the fuck you got to
find.
How much did he get fined?
I don't know.
Maybe 10 grand.
This is so worth it.
That's.
We know about your highlights.
What Glen?
Luckily they don't all do that.
That would be so douchey if they all did
it.
It's like a douchey way.
You can do it by accident game.
We'd go back.
We just come up like Shaq would just
smash through it and he wouldn't be able
to.
The Sun.
You can really try to break it to Shaq
smack him occasionally.
Yeah,
but not on purpose.
He just fucking what's so hard down.
I'm looking into it.
Okay.
He hasn't done in a while,
but when he was the first couple of
years ago,
dude,
I met him a couple of times on the first
amendment,
the UFC and I met him.
He did an episode of fear factor with me
and he,
he did the countdown,
you know,
like three,
two,
one go,
you know,
standing next to me.
Dude.
It looked like it didn't even look like.
I mean it looked like we were two
totally different things.
You met him in Boston?
We ran into him at the hotel.
Oh yeah,
that's true.
He's giant.
He's so big.
It's ridiculous.
I feel like I like a little child.
You know what?
This dude,
Daryl Dawkins played for the sixers and
he got traded to the New Jersey.
I hope that I'm fucking powder,
that he really,
really good that would sell him the
powder was the sneaker kid.
He was the book hit on the net.
At that time.
This kid ran a tremendous scan because
the players on contract,
they take after every game,
they put on new speakers and they drove
away.
Real kit would take every sneaker and
take it into the city itself.
One of his jobs is a ballboy was to get
the Balkans powder.
That was it,
Brian.
Whatever he did and we all met and I
remember one day he took us down or
House Darryl Dawkins showed me a fucking
Rolls Royce with a 14 motherfucking
carried dashboard dashboard.
Financially irresponsible while his wife
died.
Later on,
he came back before a couple of years
there.
I went over to his house like three
times lived.
See quote because New Jersey Big Pimpin
with the motherfucking 14 karat
dashboard shit.
Wow.
That's ridiculous.
That is ridiculous.
Doug,
you gotTa love it though.
What is it about black people and shiny
things?
Don't live in a tent to have a fuck
Rolls Royce to the 14th is my kids will
start it as much as rock stars like to
rock it and like to look bad ass.
They don't go that deep.
They don't go diamonds.
I heard a theory on that.
Is it black people are rappers and
stuff.
They're just doing what they thought
about was rich when they were little,
so it's always them holding a bowl of
sugar.
Cereal and cars and put women.
Yeah,
but it's like,
oh,
this looks like rich stuff for while.
Got a urinal installed in his house.
Nothing wrong with that.
That's probably a good move.
Especially one of those flashlights
splashes here and I'll say the cake in
there.
Save water.
They have like a little disk,
little Ufo you piss on somehow or
another.
Go somewhere.
You don't have to just rent the word
water.
Yeah,
that's like the latest eco thing,
but it's been rejected by plumbers.
Plumbers don't like it because it cuts
back on the maintenance,
so they try to say unsanitary,
but in actuality the other ones are more
unsanitary.
How weird is that?
Know there's been studies,
Joe Diaz,
studies on pis that's talk about urine.
Tell you something.
When I was a kid in the first house,
I moved into block burger,
but nice big one.
We had a fucking the day religion.
Really?
Yeah.
That shit.
When I was about eight or nine or 10,
I used to go over there and take a shit.
My mother's bathroom turned down and hit
me in the fucking face.
You know what I'm saying?
But then you,
you put your little muffled on that,
but day you get that little hot water
going.
That was the first time I have that.
That little cranky.
You're a little muffled,
but then he blasted hard.
Your asshole spotless.
You could feel it shiny.
I was about 10.
I mean that's what my son used to shine.
You know what I'm saying?
I use my for carrying magazines.
You don't use it.
Never him have one.
Use that shit every day.
So much better than wedding.
Toilet paper seemed so bizarre.
I am so.
Seems UNAMERICAN given into the French.
What am I doing here?
Supporting my own.
What a role a God damn toilet paper's on
enough for you.
Rogan.
I feel like I'm not supporting my own.
You some French bullshit,
but day is nice.
Hands.
A lot of commitment when you wipe your
butt.
It's like slow.
Yeah,
I know it's still stinky and gross,
but wiping my button a that had some
fucking soap in that mother fucker use
baby wipes.
Have you ever been a white flight,
but what?
Have you ever been about the fucking
realize my app.