Hello everybody this weekend,
Friday,
December 21st,
2012.
It's the end of the world
show at the Wiltern theater.
Honey,
honey ban.
Joey,
Coco Diaz,
Doug,
Stan hope and me.
Last time we checked,
there was only about hello.
Hello.
Last time we checked,
there's only about a hundred seats left.
So,
uh,
if you want to end and no,
we don't think the fucking
world is going to end.
All right,
settle down.
You really don't know.
Everybody settle down.
Um,
also,
uh,
what do you got going on this week?
Uh,
the Improv.
Yes,
Thursday we're going to try
to do a live podcast there,
up above and while we're trying to
do like a nice house chronicles,
but at the Improv,
it's a death squad show.
Joey Diaz.
It's going to be on it.
Um,
Jeff Richardson is going to host it.
I don't know if you've
seen Jeff Richards lately.
He is fucking hilarious.
Now.
He's good and he's got the best.
Uh,
what's that Jimmy Fallon.
Jimmy Fallon on a roller coaster.
Oh,
it's hilarious.
It will,
it will make it for yourself.
But,
uh,
I don't think I'm going to pee myself,
but thanks for the plug.
If you're interested,
people keep asking me,
where do you get those?
Uh,
those crazy cat tee shirts.
A desk bought shirts,
go to death squad.
Dot TV.
And uh,
that also,
uh,
pays to support the desk.
[inaudible] desk squad podcast
network that Brian produces,
which has the excellent Kevin Pereira.
Pointless show on it now.
It's a fucking great show.
All those podcasts are for free.
You can get them all
on death squad dot t v.
All right,
dirty Fox.
We're about to start the podcast.
We have Dennis Mckenna here and
we're going to get down to business.
We're going to find out what the fuck is
up the author of the Brotherhood of the
screaming abyss.
Well,
good experience.
Hey Joe Rogan podcast.
What's with the craziness?
What are you doing with that sound?
So,
so Dennis Mckenna,
first of all,
um,
and your friends,
I'm sorry,
I forgot your names cause we,
we might've indulged in something that
makes you forget things really quickly.
Can you put you,
if you can talk into the mic,
if you want to keep the clean
Keith Levers and what was that?
No,
Katelyn Mckenna.
Caitlin Mckenna.
That's legacy right there.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Dennis,
first of all,
thank you very much for coming on and
thank you for sending me your book.
Not once,
not twice but three times.
Thank you,
Joe.
Happy to be here.
I want to be sure you got a
copy of the book in your hand.
Yeah,
I started reading it in Vegas,
which I think is very ironic,
you know,
to be in that the,
the,
the darkest of places that mankind is
created and a to start to read this book.
But uh,
as,
uh,
I have known of you for a long,
long time.
Um,
I was,
uh,
turned on to some of your
brother's stuff through,
uh,
it was a song someone played me,
not a song.
I'm
a rave that he did where he would
talk over the rave and do like his,
his end of the world.
End of time sort of rant.
Yup.
I think it was the,
it was called TimeWave zero,
wasn't it?
Like even the,
the,
uh,
the piece,
yeah.
It couldn't have been it.
I mean,
I know he was in several of those things.
The one I remember is alien dreamed I,
yes.
Yes.
Was that the one and only dream?
Tom,
wasn't that like a movie or was that the,
that was the south,
that was the album.
I think Ken Adams actually who just
recently released a movie called the
Terrence Mckenna experience.
It's a documentary.
Well,
no,
not exactly.
I mean,
it's old clips,
you know,
from other appearances.
Pretty good.
Interesting movie.
Now,
uh,
that one clip that I'd listened to,
um,
really may,
might have started,
uh,
like an entirely new chapter of
my life just because it was so,
it was so,
first of all,
it's so freaky,
you know,
and it was you,
you never heard anyone talk that way
and your brother had this really odd
inflection that was like,
like,
uh,
when,
when someone is really smart and they
talk with a really odd and flection,
you start wondering what's wrong with you.
You know,
like,
why am I not talking like this guy?
Like maybe he's right,
he's on to something here.
Like they're confident
is to talk like that.
Well one of the things that was always
sort of charming about a terrorist was
that it didn't really matter what he said.
I mean,
I used to get after him and say
what you said 20 minutes ago,
didn't make any sense of it directly
contradicts what you just said,
which also doesn't make any sense,
you know.
But the thing is,
it doesn't matter because Terry,
Terrence,
he could read the phone book
and it would have sounded great.
That would be hanging on every
word because he just had that gift.
You know,
he had the voice,
he could mesmerize people and he was,
you know,
obviously super intelligent,
widely read,
knew all this stuff,
you know,
as a result of his reading and in the
tussle with program and before that
alchemy and you know,
black magic and eastern
philosophy and all of this stuff.
You know,
I mean,
he was by far a much broader
scholar than I'll ever be.
I mean,
I'm,
I'm quite narrow.
You know,
I mean,
I know science,
that's what I know,
you know,
not really.
He was just incredible.
He could draw on so many,
you know,
threads of knowledge and,
and people were hungry to hear it.
I mean,
here was a guy who could say,
you know,
he loved provocative statements.
Right.
And He'd love to,
you know,
antagonize that,
make people think and people
want it to be challenged,
you know?
And that,
that was part of his appeal,
I think a great deal of his appeal.
I remember in the early eighties
before anybody really got to knew,
know who Terrance was,
but he was out a few radio
clips and that sort of thing.
But back in the early Avs,
do you remember singing along
with Mitch Sing along with Mitch?
What was it?
You were probably too young for this.
Yeah.
Sing along with Mitch.
It was like this really cheesy,
stupid a music show with this Guy Mitch.
Uh,
do you remember what his last name was?
I don't know,
but it was all about sing along with
Mitch and he would present the show and
they'd sing all these old songs and
he get people in the audience watching
television.
So sing or write.
And so Terrance went on one of these
programs on the moderator said,
you know,
you're like sing along with Mitch.
Except it's like think
along with terrorists.
Okay.
Right.
And it was like that,
you know,
he just stimulated people to think about
things they never really thought about.
So this was the show singalongs mentioned
there's a darn good reason
why the excitement here too.
That was the one.
Yeah.
Marto wrong time.
Shirley temple.
She's new at this duty any moment.
Crazy.
You really can't talk
like that on TV anymore.
People will wonder why
you're talking like that.
No,
I know.
But this was so,
you know,
this was way back an interesting though,
that style of talking like there was like,
it's a weird fake style of talking on
television back then that they just don't
do anymore.
What an interesting show.
Yeah,
it was very interesting.
So that was,
that was really,
you know,
that was a big strength of terror.
He was so articulate,
charismatic,
he was well educated and he could make
whatever he was talking about make sense
even or sound like it was making sense.
Even limit it didn't,
well he,
he had so many interesting ideas that uh,
opened up so many people to uh,
to new possibilities.
But there,
there were,
it was most certainly a
few of them that were very,
very controversial.
Timewave zero novelty
theory being a big one,
which I tried to explain this to a
friend of mine once and just trying to
explain it,
I sounded completely crazy.
I said,
dude,
it's a something.
He was trying to figure out how to
measure time through using the each thing,
which is an ancient Chinese method of
divination that somehow based on hexagrams
and maybe a map of time,
and my friend looked at me like
I was out of my fucking mind.
And I'm like,
well,
the idea is that time is like a,
an algorithm somehow or not.
Right.
And you can track it,
right.
So are you,
do you,
are you familiar with the chain?
Yes.
So,
so that was the framework for this idea.
And,
and you know,
the time wave,
I mean,
that's one area where we had
a very different perspective,
you know.
Uh,
and,
uh,
actually in the book I have a chapter
on the time wave and I kind of unpacked
the TimeWave and my own
perspective on it was that,
uh,
you know,
he
postulated that the TimeWave
was an actual map of time.
Right.
And I think that's where
he overstepped the bounds.
I think what really happened was he
rediscovered an ancient Chinese calendar.
You know,
that because you can use the
each thing as a calendar.
There's no doubt he's demonstrated that.
But if he rediscovered an ancient
Chinese calendar based on the chain,
that would have been remarkable.
A few Chinese scholars would have
congratulated him and nobody would have,
you know,
notice neon that,
but then he,
he,
you know,
sort of possibly this whole crazy notion
about time and about how time was a
fractal structure of
made up of resonances.
And anyway,
the,
the sort of,
you know,
the thing of interest for most people
was that he had to postulate an end date
and he postulated several end dates,
you know,
because the theory said it
had to have a beginning,
a middle of it.
And he postulated several end dates.
But the one he finally
settled on was December 21st,
2012,
you know,
which was close enough.
I mean,
he actually postulated an end date that
was slightly off that by some of them
remember November,
right?
So we're talking about a cycle,
billions of years,
right?
So he looked at that and many found out
or already knew about the Mayan calendar
and thought,
well,
they're close enough.
Let's just sink these together.
But there's no direct connection to
the Mayan calendar other than that.
But didn't he say that he arrived
at a completely independently
of the mind of the,
well,
the time date,
he said that it was that like
a little factory here arrived at
a date that was close to that.
Right.
You know,
and then,
but,
but also,
uh,
you know,
during the time,
there were several times in the past
when he postulated and dates that,
you know,
we're,
I'm the time I wasn't
well known and there were,
you know,
it came and went,
nothing happened and he just viewed that
as part of the process of trying to,
uh,
to,
you know,
fit this thing against history.
Did anybody go back and reexamine the,
each thing for the possibility of it
being a really effective ancient Chinese
calendar?
Did,
has anybody looked at that aspect of it?
Well,
no one to my knowledge except terros.
I mean if you,
if you just split that part out,
it's like it's out there though.
Well,
that he said that it's a calendar.
did Terrence believed it was like why
wouldn't someone want follow up on that?
I mean that it let us forget
about the map of time thing,
which is like really,
really hard to follow.
But just that aspect of it seems like
it would be worth looking into it.
It would be worth looking
into from scholarship.
Yeah,
definitely.
I mean,
there's no doubt that
it is a perfect 384 day,
13 month lunar calendar.
I mean,
it works very well as works as well as
any other calendrical system that we
have.
You know,
they're all,
they all have inaccuracies.
Um,
you know,
and,
and that alone is remarkable.
And the fee,
you know,
but he had this whole other theory and,
and you know,
the,
the problem
that I have with the,
with the time wave theory was that,
um,
there was no way to quantify it.
This idea of novelty.
I mean,
I believe novelty in
dresses into the continuum,
but it's hard to put a number on that.
I mean,
it,
just to look around novelty is ingressing
end of the continuum and it appears to
be accelerating.
But maybe that's just our impression.
But this was his idea.
The question is how do
you define a novel event?
Right?
Our novel events,
I mean,
he,
he had the theory that novel advance
suddenly erupt into history and,
uh,
you know,
make a change.
And those kinds of events are really rare.
You know,
I mean,
asteroid impacts,
that kind of thing.
Yeah,
those are abrupt novel events.
But he used to site,
for example,
you know,
the dropping of the bomb on Hiroshima,
I mean that was,
that had a huge impact on history.
Everything after that time was different,
you know,
it changed our lives.
But was it,
was that the novel event or was it the
testing of the bomb and Alamogordo or
Wilson,
you know,
Einstein's discovery of the equations
that enabled this to be possible.
All those things were novel events,
which happened very quietly
and kind of unnoticed.
But if they hadn't happened this
spectacular thing over here,
Ashima would not have happened either.
Right.
So,
so my view of it was that novelty kind
of diffuses into history rather than the
rocked into history.
And pretty soon,
you know,
everything changes.
But it changes over time and we're not
even subjectively aware of it that much.
What was his motivation to pursue that?
Like to pursue such a strange
and very hard to follow theory?
Well,
to pursue this timely theory?
Well F two take splain that
we really have to go back to,
we should probably explain the TimeWave
too for people don't know what the hell
we're talking about.
There might be people that are going,
what the fuck is the TimeWave Siri,
right?
Well,
the time wave theory is
this mathematical construct,
you know,
based on the teaching that Terrence got
basically download it to him when we did
the,
what's it been famously known as
the experiment it lot sure era,
you know,
which the book also talks about them,
which again,
a lot of PR,
if you're a Terence Mckenna Fan,
you know what that is.
If you're not,
you're wondering what the hell is this,
you know,
so,
but the experiment that
lecturer was when we,
you know,
well how do we explain it?
I don't even know if we could
go into it on the podcast,
but it was something
that we attempted to do.
You know,
when we went to,
uh,
South America looking
for exotic hallucinogens,
and this was in 1971.
And,
uh,
we were motivated.
I mean,
I'm sort of getting off track here,
but I'm trying to bring it back
to the issue of the TimeWave.
We were motivated to go in 1971,
basically by are interesting
in fascination with DMT.
I mean that was what got
us going because we had,
uh,
encountered DMT and the hate and in
Berkeley in the 60s it was very rare.
You know,
it's extremely not,
not on the streets or anything.
It was,
it was hard to come by,
but we had come by it and had
the experience of it and thought,
holy Christ that,
you know,
there is nothing else more interesting
than this that we've ever encountered.
And so,
you know,
we were involved in all the political
turmoil and the Anti Vietnam War movements
and you know,
free speech and all of that.
Terrence was at Berkeley.
I wasn't particularly,
but we,
we just thought,
you know,
none of that is relevant.
This is truly the most amazing
thing that we've ever encountered.
And so,
and so,
you know,
our original motivation to go to
South America was because the,
as you know that the smoking
of Dmt is very short,
right?
It's 10 minutes,
15 minutes,
and you'd come back and you're like,
what the hell was that?
What the fuck was that?
You know,
you,
you can't bring back much from it other
than just an overwhelming impression of
awe and amazement and that you've
looked into some other world that's more
bizarre than anything you've ever seen,
you know,
encountered.
So we thought if we could
find an orally active form of,
of this DMT that we,
it would last longer.
That was a simple rationale.
It would longer and we could kind of get
our sea legs there and figure out what
was going on.
So hilarious expression for DMT,
get your sea legs,
just spend a little more time.
And,
and so we read about this very obscure,
uh,
drug prepared from a species
of tree and South America.
It was called Beralas and shelties,
the famous ethnobotanist
from Harvard wrote about,
wrote,
published a paper in 1970 called Varroa
as an orally active hallucinate champ.
Right now for role is normally
used as a snuff in South America.
Right?
I mean,
that's certain tribes,
the Yanomamo and other tribes,
they extract the SAP,
they dry it down and they
make a snuff out of it.
But there were a couple of tribes
that made an oral preparation from it.
So that attracted our attention and we
decided to go to South America and look
for,
you know,
this,
this with toto drug called Uq
who hae or something like that.
Oh,
cool.
Hey,
uh,
and it happened to be that
the ancestral home of the wit,
toto was at La Chorrera.
That's what led us to go
to La Chorrera originally.
Right.
Which the search for this drug that
no one ever heard of except us and our
racial taste.
And uh,
so we went there looking for that.
well at the time nobody
knew much about IOWASCA.
I mean I Wasa is also an
orally active form of DMT,
but we didn't know that at the time.
And nobody did that.
Maybe we can talk about that later,
but uh,
but we went looking for [inaudible]
right when we got to Letcher era,
we found that,
uh,
the mission village that we set up,
that we stayed at the mission
lodge Herrera had cleared
pastors all around about
a couple of hundred acres of pastures and
they brought say boot cattle into this
place.
The white humpback cattle.
Well,
the shit,
the Dung of this cattle is the preferred
substrate for psilocybe cubensis and it
was a particularly rich year that year.
I mean the lots of rain missed
on the pasture and all that.
So literally every cow pie had huge
clusters of psilocybin mushrooms,
uh,
you know,
growing out of them.
All right.
And again,
this was 1971.
A lot of people hadn't had much
experience with psilocybin mushrooms,
but we knew from our references
let this mushroom was,
we didn't,
we'd never taken it,
but we thought,
great.
Psilocybin mushrooms,
wonderful s so we were delayed.
We were misled,
right?
We thought that [inaudible] was the
real mystery that we were after.
It turns out psilocybin mushrooms where
the real mystery and silicide than the
is in fact the perfect
orally active form of DMT,
right?
The syllabus,
the active form of Psilocybin is just
one mile one Adam different from DMT and
it's a perfectly engineered
for human metabolism.
It's nontoxic,
it's orally active,
it's easily,
you know,
excrete it.
It's all,
it's ideal.
It really is.
That's a perfect psychedelic in some ways.
So we thought,
but at the time we thought we were after.
Oh,
cool.
Hey.
So we thought,
well,
okay,
so these mushrooms are here,
this is great.
While we're waiting for the real mystery,
we'll we can eat these mushrooms.
When we started eating the mushrooms and
pretty soon and things got very weird,
you know,
because we were literally eating
them every day and they were,
they were,
uh,
we started having a lot of
very interesting conversations,
shall we say.
How many days did you do this for?
Oh,
well,
you know,
uh,
I mean,
there wasn't that much to eat at lot.
Sure.
We had brought canned goods
and rice and things like that,
but we found that it was very easy to
just kind of slip a few mushrooms into the
soup.
You know,
they didn't taste bad.
So probably for a week or 10 days or so,
we were pretty much taking
mushrooms constantly.
Wow.
And,
uh,
and it began to suggest this
experiment that we could do,
you know,
if it began,
it,
it the mushroom or the intelligence
that spoke through the mushroom,
you know,
it was never quite clear,
but there was definitely,
it was like having a very intelligent
guests at your party and you know,
you didn't see it,
but you definitely were in touch with it.
And it began to suggest this,
this experiment that we could do,
I mean,
this wild experiment,
the experiment that lunch rare and uh,
uh,
we,
you know,
I don't know how much detail
you want to go into on this,
but we,
we performed this experiment that the
trying to get it back to the Ching and the
TimeWave thing.
We performed this experiment,
which was something like creating the
philosopher's stone essentially out of our
own DNA and the DNA of a mushroom and
sound and light and singing to the
mushroom and coming up,
you know,
creating these superconducting
residences and you know,
I mean,
okay,
crazy stuff.
You can,
you can read the book,
you know,
but it,
but we had this idea that,
that we could essentially,
I mean I guess I should
back up and explain it.
We have this idea that the sounds
that you could hear on high doses of
mushrooms.
I don't know if your experience with Dmt,
you hear things right.
You often hear over tonal
sounds and the whole,
our old spaces as interesting as
the visual space in some ways.
Well on high doses of mushrooms
that's similar as well.
And you know,
if you listen to these sounds a,
you can start to sort of
try to imitate them and uh,
you know,
he can sing along with them or you can
vocalize along with them and the attempts
to vocalize them or generally,
you know,
not so good,
they're hard to imitate,
but you reach a certain point where you
just locked on to it and then it just
pours out of you in a v
in a very powerful way.
And in a way that's,
it's like almost being
possessed or something.
This,
this,
this sound energy just pours forth.
So the mushrooms suggested to us a lot
of ideas about what these sounds were and
how they could actually set
up molecular resonances.
You know,
in our own brains,
our own DNA and the DNA if a mushroom
and that we could essentially,
uh,
well create in some ways
create the ultimate object,
create the ultimate artifact,
which would be our selves,
our own minds in an externalized form.
The,
in a physical form,
the interior was single form that
you could actually carry around.
It would be a binding of
space time and it would be,
I know this is crazy.
That is the highest you can get.
I think that's as high as a human can get.
Well there's no harm
could have this thing.
Well,
so we had this theory about how to can,
how to,
how to uh,
you know,
induced this sound,
generate this object.
Not only generate this but,
but fix it like it Alchemy,
you fixed mercury,
you know,
I mean that's the final step of outcome
may cause this stuff was like mercury.
This was like mines.
It was the violet psycho fluid.
We called it c,
you know,
this was a shared vision between the,
both of you both have a shared
ideational vision in a certain sense.
And so that wasn't coming to you.
It was the mushroom was uh,
you know,
the mushroom or whoever was communicating
through the mushrooms was just matter
of factly sort of wrapping this down.
And,
and you know,
we were receptive to it and it was like
we're writing furiously and it's like we
developed this experiment,
this idea,
which had a whole lot of predictions.
I mean crazy predictions that yeah,
you would actually have
at the end of the day,
you would have at night more accurately,
you would have a physical
object that would,
you know,
would be outside the body,
but it would be you
and it would be like,
and it turns out there's all
sorts of precedent for this,
right?
I mean,
the idea of the outcomist stone,
the philosopher's stone
or the time machine,
the flying saucers,
the,
you know,
the outcome is scrying mirror,
that you can look into and see the future.
I mean this idea haunts the human
imagination that there is a way you can
externalize the imagination and you know,
still be it.
And this thing that you would
have or whatever it was,
would be responsive to your imagination
and it would be able to do literally
whatever you could imagine that song
that's sort of an alternate theory on Ufos
isn't as well that you're,
you're the imagination actually can
conjure up a physical object and even,
yeah,
exactly.
Yeah,
That's what we're saying.
And even young speculated about that.
That's right.
So,
you know,
I mean,
I know this sounds crazy 40 years later,
if it sounds crazy to me too,
but at the time,
and it's like this is what's going down.
Right?
And you both agreed to it.
That's what's even crazier.
He two and then we made predictions about
what would happen right at when we did
this experiment.
This is what will happen.
And the predictions were such that
they couldn't possibly happen because,
you know,
this is absurd.
You can't create camp,
externalize the mind in this way.
But we made predictions and
when those didn't happen,
a bunch of other
interesting things happen.
Instead we had literally painted
ourselves into conceptual corner where
something happened to had to give.
And so we both went into a prolonged
altered state for like 14 days.
I was smeared across the cosmos.
Literally,
you know,
I,
I was,
I hearkened back to a recent period when
I'd smoked DMT and my entire mind was
coke contiguous with the,
you know,
boundaries of space time.
And Terrence became extreme know
he became complimentary to that.
He became extremely hyper vigilant
and a very focused on our place.
And being like the anchor,
like if I was out there in the cosmos,
he was the beacon that was bringing
me home and our companions,
these poor people thought
that we were completely nuts,
you know?
And they were not participated.
The locals?
No,
no.
The two people that we'd gone where it
was like they had stepped back from it.
So they were so earlier.
Oh,
well yeah.
that must've been so we were like,
oh,
it was very strange for them.
I'm sure she is too strange for us,
but we were making sense to each other.
There's actually a term in this
for a psychology in psychology.
It's called the Folia do.
It's the,
it's the,
the folly of two simultaneous,
you know,
psychosis essentially.
But it wasn't a psychosis.
That's the thing people
have to understand.
It wasn't a psychosis.
If anything,
it was closer to a shamonic initiation.
I mean,
the motifs of shamanic initiation more
than the motifs of psychosis fit what
went on.
We were transformed and we were
transformed in a complimentary way.
And we also reintegrated more or less,
uh,
you know,
so that,
I mean,
I'm fairly functional now.
I don't know that I've
ever totally reintegrated,
but you know what I mean?
It wasn't a shamonic initiations where
you go through this metamorphosis and
things are done to you and you're
torn apart and year changed,
but then you're put back
together in a different form.
And,
and that's really what happened.
But I wasn't put back together as the,
you know,
super conducting,
uh,
you know,
bionic creature with access to all
information and all space and time that
didn't happen.
Uh,
you know,
and,
and so to try to bring this
around to whether the TimeWave,
the TimeWave came about
because Terrence was,
you know,
in this hypervigilant state where
he didn't sleep for 14 days,
you know,
he was watching over me for one thing,
cause I tended to wander off and you know,
I was completely three sheets to the wind,
literally,
you know,
and,
and often this,
this cosmic fantasy world,
but he was very focused,
but he started making,
um,
making charts of time.
He was trying to predict.
We had done this experiment and we had
predicted that the stone would can dance
in this physical form.
And at the end of the experiment,
that didn't happen.
But we were getting the message that
we did everything right.
It's just your timing that's
off and it will come right.
The stone will condense at some points.
But so it became this whole game sort
of of trying to predict when will the
stone can dance.
And so Terrence begin charting our course,
you know,
and he,
he found like he was,
he counted back 64 days,
two types of 64 days to the,
to the,
uh,
you know,
from the date of the experiment.
And it turns out that was the date of
our mother's death the previous October.
Right?
And then he started counting
forward from that date,
several cycles of 64.
And it turned out that
was his birthday in 1971.
So that became a sort of focus for
predicting when it would condense.
That course came and went.
So over the years,
he tried to
find,
I guess,
fine tune this prediction,
fine tune this.
And that's what the whole elaborate
TimeWave theory grew out of.
You know,
if,
if there was an alien artifact that
was given to us by this experiment,
then it was this,
it was this mathematical construction,
you know,
which wasn't given to me.
It was given to him.
What was given to me were,
uh,
you know,
I mean the experience,
uh,
of,
you know,
being smeared over the cosmos and
then gradually over 14 days basically
condensing myself back
into a body and eating.
Was I eating?
Uh,
I don't know.
I guess somebody was feeding me.
I mean,
I wasn't doing those things.
Uh,
it was,
it was someone must've fed me.
Do you remember going to the bathroom?
Do you remember?
I don't,
but you know what?
I remember I remembered
that I was in hyperspace.
I was coke contiguous.
Uh,
I shared topology with everyone.
So if I wanted to take a shit,
for example,
I would ask my friend to take a shit.
Wow.
I could,
you know,
and the,
and I could eliminate that
way because our typologies,
we're joined.
Or you know,
if I wanted to smoke a cigarette,
I'd ask Vanessa to smoke a
cigarette and I could all,
all those kind of crazy,
just like a cigarette for you,
please.
Right.
I mean,
I know this sounds crazy,
I shouldn't even be talking about,
no,
you should public.
Do you subscribe to the idea that like
these ancient cultures like the Mayans
and,
uh,
these,
these people that have these incredible
structures that are very likely this was
suicide and induced or their
culture was so Simon induced?
Well,
I,
yeah,
I do.
I think there's a good
chance that it was a,
I mean,
I think that that wasn't the only,
that certainly wasn't the only name in
theologian that the Mayans knew about,
but that was an important one.
What else should they know about?
Well,
they knew,
they knew about it a lot.
They do about,
you know,
they knew about all the
Central American ones,
the morning glories,
Olo,
leaky,
the,
you know,
probably Salvia,
probably all of those.
But the Mayans definitely
knew about mushrooms.
And,
uh,
I think it's likely that mushrooms,
you know,
I mean,
if,
if you,
if you talk about the stoned ape theory,
you know,
it's,
you've talked about,
and Terrence is talked about,
it's most likely mushrooms,
you know,
that because mushrooms are pan global,
they're found in every,
every climate,
you know,
if it's tropics,
it's stiff.
It's,
I lost Sufi cubensis if it's temporary,
it's so lots to be semi Ilan Siada.
But these things are all over the place.
They're potent.
They don't require any preparation,
right?
No technology needed other than
the curiosity to bend over,
pick it up and munch and you know,
and once you do that,
then the impact,
it had to be profound.
You know?
And,
and,
and we're talking about omnivorous
primates here who are hungry all the time,
very acutely keyed into their environment.
I mean,
it's not like they're
going to overlook things,
right?
So they'll see it and they'll eat it,
test things.
And they are exactly,
exactly.
They,
they're omnivores and they test things.
And so they test this
and then they get the,
the message,
you know,
and I,
I think that,
uh,
you know,
I mean,
and the stoned ape theory there,
there are things that are
puzzling to me that I,
I totally don't completely understand.
It's like,
you know,
we were near,
if you,
if you look at the archeological
evidence for the critical period when
consciousness emerged in our species,
except for a couple of indications that
go way back like half a million years,
but,
uh,
you know,
the efflorescence of artistic expression,
which is really the only way you can
tell happened sometime between a hundred
thousand years ago and 8,000 years ago.
You know,
you look at the cave paintings
and some of the oldest ones,
the Blombos cave in South
Africa goes 80,000 years.
That was clearly,
those artifacts were clearly done by
conscious beings within artistic sense.
You know,
so if that equates to cognition,
but then the,
the,
you know,
then clearly consciousness was happening,
somewhere after a hundred thousand years,
up until now,
presumably,
you know,
consciousness was happening.
But if you look at the fossil record,
the neurologically modern
brain was much older than that,
you know,
I mean,
essentially,
you know,
at least a hundred thousand,
maybe 200,000 years older
than this emergence of,
you know,
the neurologically modern brain with
all the apparatus needed to generate
language,
right?
And it's all about language and it's about
this making this connection between sound,
image and symbol,
you know,
meaningful symbol.
And,
and I've argued in,
uh,
a lot of lectures and so on.
I mean,
my shtick,
if you will,
that what this is what this
amounts to is synesthesia,
right?
Synesthesia.
It'd be in the translation of
one sensory mode to another.
Well,
like psychedelics do,
right?
Psychedelics reliably induced synesthesia
where you can hear colors and see
sounds,
that's the most reveal aspect of it.
Um,
most people can't do that
without psychedelics,
but some cam,
some are genetic,
some people are genetically synesthetic.
And their experience of
meaning and language is a,
is very different.
Uh,
it's interesting that synesthesia in
genetically synesthetic people is often
associated with languages
and language and number,
you know,
so they'll say crazy sounding stuff like,
the letter c is hard and chrome color,
you know,
and they're think they're
speaking in the abstract,
but this is a,
uh,
an actual perception for them or you know,
the,
they'll talk about the
personality of the number nine.
Whoa.
Now these functional,
these kinds of,
some therapy,
many of them are brilliant.
Yes.
They're totally functional.
So they're seeing all this
around them all the time,
but they can still manage
the way to move through it.
So they're essentially walking
through a living mushroom trip.
Yeah,
kind of in a sense.
I mean,
I think they are aware of their
sort of cognitive environment,
if you want to put it that way.
Uh,
uh,
the one,
the same one that we inhabit,
but a lot of this stuff goes
into the background for us.
Right.
And less we take a psychedelic
or something like that
and then it comes out into
the foreground.
It goes on in the background that
that's essentially what I'm saying,
the process of understanding language is
this process of synesthesia that we're
not even aware of.
Right?
Where we have,
we live in,
we live in a world in which abstractions
and symbols are as real as you know,
anything in the outside world.
Right?
And we live in a world in which symbols
have significance and that is the basis
of language.
We are our ability to perceive meaning.
Uh,
and it's based on this sort of unconscious
synesthesia which we do all the time.
And uh,
mushrooms may,
I mean,
with respect to the evolution
of the primate brain,
I what I,
what I think I'm postulating that,
you know,
something like mushrooms,
we're able to trigger these types of
synesthetic experiences it people and they
essentially became training
tools for learning cognition,
training tools for learning.
You know,
how to associate meaning with meaningless
sounds and essentially meaningless
symbols,
meaningless visual cues and oral cues.
But it made the essential
connection to significance,
the feeling of significance.
It's,
you know,
am I making any sense?
Yes,
absolutely.
So that's the mechanism involved
of taking an intelligent thinking,
lower primate and turning
it into a human being.
Right,
exactly.
One they,
and give it a lot of mushrooms
and see what happens.
Well,
yes,
of course.
My God,
that's all I want to do.
Right.
I just feel like there's
gotta be something to that.
Right.
But it doesn't happen abruptly.
It's happens over time,
right?
Just have a whole farm.
Well,
yeah,
but Shannon,
but again,
I mean there are other things going on.
There are,
there are,
you know,
I don't know if it said
climatological factors,
criminological factors,
maternal inheritance factors,
you know,
I mean,
this is a whole other area of,
we do,
you know,
really
described the theory for people that
don't know what the higher primate theory
is,
or excuse me,
the,
um,
that's my,
uh,
that's his tee shirt here.
The,
um,
the stoned ape theory is that siliciden
mushrooms or psychedelic mushrooms were
responsible for creating human beings.
And the one of Terrence's
assertions was that,
uh,
the,
the doubling of the human brain size,
it occurred over a period
of about 2 million years.
And that this correlates
to the timeline of,
uh,
these,
rain forest receding into grasslands.
And then these monkey,
you know,
the apes,
uh,
experimenting with different
food sources that does,
that.
Does that stuff all jive with like core
samples and like climate studies and
cause all that stuff the same time with
the human brains has doubled is at all
legit?
Well,
yeah,
it's pretty much legit.
I mean,
we know that there were,
you know,
I don't think you could put your finger
on any one factor and say this was
responsible for the
expansion of the human brain,
but definitely the transition from
our boreal to to plain type existence
existence on the Serengeti,
uh,
was a time of incredible
environmental stress for these,
for these primates and
the whole environment.
They had to adapt and they had to,
you know,
learn a hold of diet,
a whole new mode of existence.
And it's not clear at the timeframe that,
that this took place over.
But I,
I think that,
uh,
and,
and it's,
and it's not clear how
much of it just happen.
I mean,
it's not clear that this
necessarily triggered consciousness,
but it certainly triggered adaptations,
uh,
in,
in these primates that,
you know,
they were,
they were forced into so that
perhaps got them ready when the time,
Kay,
it's,
I mean,
that's the part that's difficult
to predict or nail down.
How long,
how far back were these mushrooms used?
You know,
was it a transient thing
or did the climate change,
you know,
there,
was there a point around a
hundred thousand years ago
where the climate in that
area got much wetter and suddenly
these things became more,
uh,
more common,
or were they always there and you know,
it's,
it's difficult,
but I think one of the characteristics
that we do know about psychedelics is
that they,
they can induce this feeling of
what's been called portentous snus,
right.
The feeling of a feeling that I've
experienced something is significant.
So feeling of reverence or awe or,
you know,
all of those things that we associate
with religious sense abilities.
You know,
it's not that psychedelics,
you know,
there are religions that have
been founded around psychedelics,
obviously the mushroom cults
and all of these things,
but psychedelics are not a religion.
They are in a sense the religion or they,
they,
they hit those parts of our brain that
are capable of having religious religious
responses in some way.
And so when you get that going,
um,
then
you have these primates
with a sense of being
in touch with some,
you know,
in touch with some transcendent other
that is more significant that themselves,
that,
that they feel a longing for.
And I think that's the religious
sensibility and that that's also what,
what drives our species forward,
you know,
is this,
is this longing to know
the unknown essentially.
You know,
I mean the Terrance talked about,
and actually Rudolf Otto talked about
the psychedelics are a mysterium
tremendum,
right?
Rudolf Otto talked about this.
They are a tremendous mystery that is
terrifying and fascinating at the same
time.
And,
uh,
this has been the
continuing carrots that's,
that's pulled our species forward,
you know,
and,
and my lectures,
I sometimes liken them to the
ID of the monolith in 2001.
If,
you know,
Kubrick tried to concretize that
idea and the idea of the monolith,
something that's utterly alien,
totally incomprehensible,
completely terrifying and fascinating,
right?
They can't take their eyes off of it
and it inserts itself into history or
evolution at critical junctures.
It just shows up,
you know,
and things happen.
And I'm saying we don't need to invoke
the monolith because that's what the
psychedelics in nature,
our,
you know,
our own builtin monolith,
built into the biosphere.
Do you find it frustrating
that that's not considered
mmm bye.
Standard people of science when
they discuss theories of evolution,
the,
I mean they'll,
it's really strange to me.
I find how they factor it out.
Yeah.
It's weird how they,
uh,
there's obviously a bunch
of different factors.
Cooking meat,
eat the throwing arm,
you know,
there's a lot of different factors,
but why would they not
consider that as well?
That's always been really confusing to me.
And the only thing that makes
sense is that they haven't done it.
There you go.
You're just sending an insight there.
But I mean even,
you know,
um,
Graham Hancock talks about this,
the uh,
the person that wrote
this very interesting book
about the cave paintings,
the mind and the brain.
This is the name of the book.
I forget the author at the moment,
but this very well respected,
you know,
South Africa scholar who wrote a
book about how altered states in,
you know,
in the,
shamonic rituals carried out in the
dark or in the almost total darkness in
these caves.
That's what the cave paintings were about.
These things were painted by people in
highly altered states doing shamanic
ceremonies.
But even the guy who wrote the
book will not take mushrooms.
You know,
Graham Hancock attempted to get him to,
I mean he wrote about his work with
great enthusiasm and evaporation.
You know,
if you want to confirm your theory,
this is what you do.
Why is it that did do it though?
If he did do and did do it publicly,
it would,
it would hurt him.
And in in an academic sense.
Well w do you know what that's
probably why he didn't do it.
Why would it hurt him?
I mean it seems to me it would hurt
him because drugs are verboten.
Yeah,
no,
but in fact that is the honest thing
to do as a scientist and,
and I think if enough of the right people,
you know,
the people in this field actually would
let themselves have this experience.
I think the controversy with resolve
itself because those of us who have
experienced it just seems obvious.
It just seems,
it's very strange to me that it's not
considered even as a factor at all.
When if you've had the impact,
you've had the experience personally,
you know,
the incredible impact that it has,
how could that not be considered
in terms of something that affects
consciousness?
If you're,
you're talking about
someone who has no science,
someone who has no books to read,
someone who has,
you know,
whatever language existed at the time.
Having a blowout psychedelic experience
would be so staggeringly profound on the
shaping of your vision of the world.
But it's weird that it's not considered.
And it's really a shame as far as the way
the people that educate people in this
world,
whether it's in high school or whether
it's in universities or colleges,
that they're,
they personally are not aware and or
have been educated by this experience
because it's,
it's not what everybody thinks it is.
That we,
everyone has this idea that
it's an escape from reality.
You're running away from things,
you're clouding things up
with the drugs and that the,
because it's under this one blanket,
this one blanket of description drugs,
it's,
it's really weird that it's not considered
as a factor in the development of the
human being.
No,
well exactly because of
the rubric kits put under,
I mean people,
it's one of these things
that exists in the shadow,
you know,
it's,
it's in the shadow and,
and the reason it's in the shadow is
because it is a true mystery and true
mysteries are freighted with numinosity,
right.
With the numinous and you know,
I mean,
despite the lip service that the
church pays to all this stuff,
I mean,
the main mission of the church is to
ensure that people do not have genuine
religious experiences.
Right?
I mean,
that's the most dangerous thing to the,
to the church that
there could possibly be.
If someone bypasses all
the priests and the whole,
you know,
hierarchical structure and
just goes out and talks to God,
well,
God's going to give you a different
message than the priests are giving you.
I tell you,
you know,
that's dangerous.
It's dangerous.
What did you think of John Marco?
A allegro is work,
the sacred mushroom in the cross.
His assertion that he,
for,
for the folks who don't know this one,
just a brief one,
he was a scholar who was a,
an ordained minister
who became a theologian.
As he was PR studying theology.
He became a agnostic and
reviewed according to him,
the Dead Sea Scrolls and believed at
the end of 14 years of studying it,
that it was essentially the
entire Christian religion was about
psychedelic mushroom use and fertility
cults.
And he wrote this book called the Sacred
Mushroom and the cross and it's his,
that's his assertions that
Jesus actually was a mushroom.
Well,
I dunno,
I dunno if Jesus was a musher,
but I do think that,
uh,
[inaudible] was a serious
scholar and I think he,
I think it's a shame that he was
vilified the way he was because he was a
philologist.
Right.
He was a specialist in these,
in these aromatic languages.
He was one of the people appointed,
one of the scholars appointed pointed
to the translation of the Dead Sea
Scrolls.
And he was incidentally,
apparently according to Andy
relevant and people like that,
he was the only one who wasn't a
priest on this committee for one thing.
So he was immediately sort of outside
the officially approved circles,
I think to the,
I'm not a philology list,
but I think to the extent that,
uh,
I mean,
Eh,
you know,
so I'm not really qualified to interpret
whether his scholarship was together or
not.
Uh,
he was,
well,
it,
he was well enough qualified
to be appointed to this,
to this translation committee.
So he must've had something
going for himself.
And when he and his,
his account is,
he says,
honestly,
you know,
when I reviewed all this stuff and
began to put two and two together,
it seems that there were all these
illusions to fungi and you know,
to mushrooms and,
uh,
I didn't come to this with this agenda.
That's what sitting here,
and he was a straight guy too.
He was a straight guy.
Yeah,
he was a straight guy.
So I,
I think that he was a good example of
an honest scholar who honestly reported
what he found and who his
message was unacceptable.
And so the,
you know,
the establishment,
the powers that be,
the higher authorities decided basically
he had to be destroyed and he was,
his reputation was thoroughly trashed.
Uh,
uh,
you know,
now is it true?
I mean,
it was Jesus a mushroom.
Did they use Amanita miscarry
or some other mushrooms?
I think it's likely,
uh,
you know,
we know that the,
uh,
the Gnostics,
which is the pre Christian
or quayside Christian group,
out of what you know,
that wrote the Dead Sea Scrolls out of
which Christianity supposedly sprang,
um,
they have a lot of very peculiar notion
and notions that would be considered
heresy by,
by,
you know,
Christians now.
I mean,
the God of,
of,
uh,
of the Bible of Genesis was seeing
that Gnosticism as an evil entity,
right?
Because it was keeping
keeping humanity in prison in,
in the world of matter,
when the soul long to be liberated
into the light and all that.
So that was his view of this whole thing.
That was not a Legros view,
but that was the view of gnosticism.
That's a pretty psychedelic
vision right there.
You know,
and I,
I wouldn't surprise me
at all if this group,
you know,
I was,
uh,
was using either,
I'm an eight,
a miscarried and,
or some kind of psilocybin mushrooms to
craziest quote from the book was that he
had translated the word Christ
back to an ancient Sumerian word,
which meant a mushroom
covered in God's seaman.
Yeah.
Wow.
I mean,
that's a,
that's a heavy one.
Yeah.
Especially for a guy is not doing drugs.
I straight academic to
do this is what I got.
Right.
This is what he had and he had
to be discredited because
that wasn't the message that,
you know,
but uh,
but it's weird that she
wouldn't be surprised.
I mean,
the church has been suppressing stuff,
you know,
for years.
I mean,
look at the Bible.
The Bible is,
I very select compendium of gospels,
but there's a lot of material that
never made the cut as we know.
It's weird that to me,
that with the incredible power that the
psychedelic mushrooms must have had on
ancient people,
we know people have been
taking them for a long time.
We don't we,
we,
we know for sure they existed.
How are they not being used all
throughout these religions today?
Like how did,
how did all the different intellectual
societies of this world lose touch with
perhaps the very thing that gave us
our initial intellectual curiosity?
Like how did that happen?
How could it happen that at
the highest levels of learning,
which is where we're at in 2012 if you,
you know,
if you follow a linear timeline,
this is advanced as we've ever been.
So if that is the case,
how is it possible that it's removed
from CNN and the New York Times?
It's not something that's being not
just a once in a blue moon John Hopkins
study,
which shows that it
improves your personality,
but some legitimate consideration too,
that it might have been a factor in why
we're here and we're one of the reasons
why we're so fucked up.
One of the reasons why our society is
so crazy is because we're detached from
one of the very things that might have
created this human being in the first
place.
That seems to me to be something
that should be considered.
It's,
it seems to me like if you look at all
the other factors like eating meat and
the throwing arm and you know,
figuring out complex problems and hunting
and all the things that could have
happened,
how could you not be looking
really closely at this one
mushroom that makes you
see incredible visions,
explore realms that seem
realer than this real,
this reality that we live in right now.
The only reason is because either you're,
you're,
you haven't experienced it or you have
experienced it and you're terrified and
you're trying to keep
everyone else from it.
Those are the only two.
So we're,
you know,
I think it's more the latter.
I mean,
I think you know what,
we have to understand the proper venue,
if you will,
or the proper human institution to
kind of be the steward of this mystery.
It's a real mystery,
right?
The Cape,
even though we understand a
lot about the neuroscience,
we can talk about neurochemistry
of receptors and all that.
That does not make the connection or cross
the bridge between what we experience
when we take it.
We,
we know all about the,
the underlying neurophysiology of it,
but it still doesn't bridge the
gap to what we actually experience.
Right?
So it's important.
So it,
so I say it remains a mystery as,
as does the very,
you know,
conundrum of consciousness.
You know,
how does the brain mind generate
or experience consciousness.
But you know,
it is a genuine mystery and human
institution and properly should be the
province of religion.
But religions don't serve that anymore.
Religions or political institutions,
right?
I mean they,
they,
if they have a real mystery,
they want to put it in a box and put it
over here someplace and keep people from
it.
You know,
because that gets in the way of Promo
gating the doctrine and the doctrine is,
you know,
told the line,
don't ask too many questions,
have faith or I,
you must have faith,
which generally means,
which means essentially you
have to believe a lot of stuff.
We tell you that for
which there's no evidence.
That's another part of them.
You believe it because we
tell you to believe it.
So have faith.
Uh,
don't ask too many questions.
you know,
and,
and basically told the lights.
So they're their political institutions.
Religions are there into bludgeoning
people into a certain mode of behavior and
they work in conjunction now in our
culture with governments and corporations
and to have people,
you know,
taking mushrooms and,
and having all these funny ideas
and questioning the status quo.
This is not,
this doesn't serve the agenda,
you know,
let the people who are making the agenda,
how many people really truly have had
the experience as it is it a very few.
So is it,
is it that they don't want
these people having that and,
and,
and you know,
thinking about things and coming up
with new solutions and trying to reshape
society?
Or is it complete ignorance and just
trying to suppress it because it's,
it's in their best financial interest?
Well,
that's hard too.
That's really hard to know.
I mean,
whether they do it out of ignorance
or whether they were there,
there's a more sinister agenda,
which is,
you know,
perhaps some of them
have had this experience.
And,
and realize that for people to be
having these types of experiences,
a threat to the status quo
because exactly as you say,
it motivates us to change the way we are,
to change the way we relate to the world.
You know,
and we're no longer
good producer consumers.
You know,
we don't fit into the agenda anymore.
I mean,
I think it's ironic,
you know,
it just,
in a way,
you know,
back in the 60s,
DMT used to be called
the businessman's trip,
right?
The idea was you could smoke it on your
lunch hour and get back to work after
your lunch hour,
except that after you've smoked DMT,
who would even want to
go back to your cubicle?
You know?
So they're inherently,
uh,
you know,
subversive in a,
in the sense that they encourage people
to take personal responsibility for
themselves and think for themselves.
Thinking for oneself.
Is it
discouraged activity these days?
There's also the issue of a lack
of guidance in this country,
especially when it comes to these
different things because of the fact that
they're illegal.
There's a lot of misinformation.
Don't understand how to use them.
They don't understand where
they're going to get them from the,
it's right.
If there was like,
it would be amazing if we had shamonic
institutes or people would go and there
would be someone who could
literally guide you along.
I mean,
if we were really an intelligent culture
that trusted each other as grown adults
with the ability to make choices and,
and have educated choices,
we,
you know,
it just seems like we're missing out.
Well,
I give it 20 years.
I do.
I think,
I think that despite all the resistance,
that's probably where it's going.
I mean,
it will happen in a very subtle way and
it won't attract a lot of attention.
But I think that I,
you know,
until it's a done deal in a sense,
I think that what we're witnessing
now is that with this psychedelic
renaissance,
you know,
and it's six days and all that,
that's all gone.
But now and a lot of the hysteria has
died down and now we're in a position to
revisit this whole thing and take
a second look in a calmer way.
And I think a lot of the research
that you see happening is going to,
I mean,
I know the,
I,
the work,
the institution I'm affiliated with on
that respect as the Heffter research
institute,
people should check that after.org um,
because most of the
leading researchers in,
in psychedelics are on our board.
Rider either on our board are supported
by or by halfed area to some degree.
Uh,
but the work that people like Roland
Griffiths or doing their other
investigators,
but he's well known,
what he's doing is,
is the way you opened the door,
right to the use of these
things is two paths,
either religious or medicine.
You know,
if you could find a legitimate
medical use for silicide,
then that changes everything because that
means that the FDA can be pressured to
change the scheduling of it.
Once the scheduling of it has changed,
it's now scheduled one.
Right.
And the first criteria,
and it was scheduled,
one is a dangerous drug with
no possible medical use.
Well,
if you do good rigorous science and
you do several clinical studies,
which is what they're doing with the
silicide when end of life kind of approach
to it,
helping people to come to terms with
their impending death and deal with the
anxiety and they may,
you know,
spiritual crisis around that.
That's essentially what they're using.
But if you can show legitimately
that it has a use in that respect,
then you can change the
regulatory framework.
You can,
you can actually get it
approved for that use.
Once it's approved for that use,
you have to change the scheduling of it
from schedule one to probably schedule
too.
But then you open up the
possibility of off label uses,
right?
As with any drug and then
therapists can start to use it.
And I think that you will see in 10 years,
maybe you will see exactly that.
You will see institutes,
places where you can go.
I mean,
the next step is to say,
well,
sill,
if psilocybin can benefit dying,
people maybe can benefit.
Well people,
maybe it can help.
Well,
people,
people who are not sick come to PTSD.
Uh,
another example,
you know,
but just spiritual evolution,
just a discipline,
you know,
uh,
which is what shamanism is.
People have to go to South
American now to find this stuff,
you know,
and they do.
And a lot of them go there because
they're not finding any spiritual
satisfaction in our own institutions.
So what we have to do is create our
own institutions that are not copies of
South American shamanism,
but our own,
you know,
our own Neil shamanism in a sense the
borrows from these different traditions.
But that works for us,
you know,
works in our culture.
Do you see
the lack of a changing of the
classification of marijuana?
It's still scheduled one,
despite all the evidence of
his medical uses for that.
Do you find that as like discouraging?
And if anybody hears that noise,
that's Dennis play with velcro.
Okay.
Don't get mad at us and say that some
static electricity because people will get
mad and send like a
hundred Twitter masters.
I'm so sorry you're
showing fucking stone it.
Sorry,
I'm a fiddler.
What can I say?
Don't worry about it.
But deep back to the question,
do you see that the,
um,
the classification from marijuana,
which still,
despite all the evidence to the contrary,
even some really interesting
stuff about cancer,
you know,
some all that Rick Simpson,
hemp seed oil and,
or I guess it's really hash oil.
It's cause it is psychoactive belts
hash and he calls it hemp oil.
I guess maybe to make
people feel better about it.
Whatever it is,
they're there.
The work that that guy's done and all
the different studies that have shown the
what it does to for Glaucoma patients,
we had duds for wasting syndrome
and people will have a hard time.
Why is it there no change
in the classification of
that because it seems like
there's a good body of work that
shows some medical uses for it.
Especially when you consider
the cocaine and schedule too.
Right.
Cocaine is scheduled too because
it hasn't recognized medical use.
Right.
That's hilarious.
Well,
yeah,
I mean the,
the whole situation in a way is I
think with respect to cannabis is,
is somehow different because it's so
freighted with political considerations.
I mean that don't really
play the psychedelics to
the same extent because even
though we're immersed in this world of
psychedelics and we think it's important,
we're still talking,
you know,
two,
3% of the population at most.
If that even gives a
shit about psychedelics,
marijuana is like 60% of the population.
So I just think you're seeing,
yeah.
You know,
I mean,
I don't know.
I think the pharmaceutical cartel in some
ways is lined up against this because
medical marijuana is potentially so
useful for so many things that they're
making money on right now by
making drugs to treat them.
And you know,
if you look at their research efforts,
if you look at what's going on in the
back room and they're not talking about,
they're totally into
cannabinoid chemistry,
right?
I mean they're developing
all kinds of pharmaceuticals,
but those are patentable compounds that
they can own and produced synthetically
and charge you a lot of money for.
So I think that pot is a threat to the
hitch devotee of the pharmaceutical
cartels.
That's one thing.
I think the government is kind of
deer in the headlights about it,
you know,
as the Obama administration's
to the latest legalization.
I mean finally they're beginning
to get their act together.
I would say the right thing,
which is okay,
apparently this,
we'll just let this social experiment
go forward and see where it goes,
which is the right thing to do.
And I think if they do that,
you'll see it evolve toward.
Other states will say,
well,
Washington and Colorado legalized pot,
they didn't collapse and they're
making a lot of money off taxes.
We want some of that.
We'll do that.
So I think he'll see it change over time.
But I would agree with you.
But what,
look what Obama did in the
first administration is his
first years with the DEA.
The Dea busted a lot of pot clubs where
he said he wasn't going to do that.
I know,
I know.
He said he wasn't going to do that.
And that's even grosser.
What they do,
what they actually do.
I know a bunch of people
that have been busted.
They take all your money,
they take all your pot and then they
say your case is pending and they do
nothing.
They just,
they just rob you.
They essentially rob you and stop you
from doing business and scare the shit out
of you so you to do it again.
But because you're not
violating state law,
they don't really pursue you.
They just steal from you.
They just show it down.
They just ruin you financially and every
other way and physically because you're
going to be freaking out cause you're
thinking you might have to go to jail
cause federally what happens is when
you are not violating state law,
but you are violating federal
law when you go to trial,
they don't even let you use
the term medical marijuana.
It's not allowed to be used in court.
It's an admissible.
So there is no medical marijuana in
the eyes of the federal government.
So you can't even defend yourself by
telling the people in the jury that you
were not in violation of a state law.
It's incredible and it's really
a terrible crime on humanity.
I mean that's really what it is.
And the government is
essentially a criminal cartel.
And the way that the,
and the way that they handled this,
the question,
you know,
putting people in jail that do not,
not only do they not
deserve to be in jail,
they haven't done anything
wrong or they're providing
people with something that
they want and they're doing
it according to a law.
It's a state law.
And that is a real sickness.
When people think that they're vindicated
or justified in some way for locking
those people in cages.
Those are the real criminals.
That's the real criminals in our society
is that people that are locking people
in jail for pot,
and that's a real sickness and a
real end of the hypocrisy is just so
outstanding and everywhere in
every bar and every drug store,
everywhere you go,
there's alcohol,
and yet you're going to lock these people
in a cage for doing something that's
not nearly as bad.
That's insane.
The here's the thing.
Yes,
it's everything you say is true,
but the thing is the
people see through this.
The fact that you could get this vote
in Washington and Colorado is a very
hopeful thing.
If they will let it go forward,
then over time they'll begin
to see the benefits of that.
Right.
In the sense that exactly as you say,
pot smoking is not nearly
as harmful as alcohol,
so you'll see reduced traffic fatalities.
You know,
people may be driving stone
but they are safer drivers.
Or if they're stone,
then they,
if they're,
if they're intoxicated,
you'll see reduced incidences of domestic
violence and other kinds of violence.
You'll see that actually letting people
smoke pot alleviates a lot of societal
problem and it won't eliminate that.
But you'll see statistically significant
reductions in a lot of the parameters
that you know,
because we know that alcohol re,
you know,
fuels violent behavior at fuse,
it fuels domestic violence,
traffic accidents,
all this stuff.
Those things will be reduced if people
start smoking pot in place of that.
You know,
I guess I'm just disappointed in the fact
that it's taken so long that I become
kind of cynical to how the,
the,
the way the government
approaches it because it just
seems so ridiculous at this
point.
Well,
it does seem ridiculous and it's
like the emperor has no clothes.
I mean it's like this policy has so
long been in placed and there's so much
inertia behind it.
Right?
There's the whole law
enforcement infrastructure,
you know,
the DEA,
the prison industrial complex,
the,
you know,
I mean,
so many things depend on,
it's not just the drug cartels.
I mean,
and their profits go away.
But the whole governmental infrastructure
to support the prison guards union,
all of those things,
they're enormously threatened.
They don't want things to change.
You know,
the last people who wanted to
see pot legal is drug dealers.
Their profit margins go out the window.
I don't think they really
lobby that much though.
I don't know.
No they don't.
But you know what I mean?
And the government has a big
investment in the current,
you know,
situation.
I feel if anything,
the one thing that's going to
change everything is the internet.
It's just the access to information is
so complete now that there's really the,
it's,
it's too hard to maintain an ignorance.
Right.
And for people,
for the government to
maintain that marijuana has
no medical application is just
absurd.
I mean,
it's just absurd.
Although they,
they do everything they
can to discourage research.
You know,
out of one side of their mouth,
they say,
well,
we want people to apply for
grants and we encourage research,
but then they make it impossible to get
legitimate sources of cannabis to do the
research.
So,
which is it,
you know,
uh,
so it is a,
it's a bad situation.
But,
uh,
but I would say this,
I would say that we have to remember,
you know,
we have to take a longer term sort
of view of this and we have to remind
ourselves that we are
witnessing a what were,
what is really going on
here is a coevolution,
you know,
between us and these plants.
And this has been going on for,
we don't know how long,
a hundred thousand years at least
cannabis is among those plants.
Right?
And,
and so
if you take a small slice
of historical time and say,
what is our current,
you know,
species relationship with these plants,
it does look very good.
You know,
they're being suppressed and all that.
But it's a small slice of time in the end,
the plants when,
right?
Because this is what's going on.
The plants when you cannot eradicate
cannabis from the face of the earth,
much as they might want to
and they really don't want to,
you know,
there's just a small
group that are profiting from it being
illegal and they would like to continue
to do so.
They wouldn't let you continue.
Yeah,
we'll change.
It will change over time.
You know,
I,
I really think so.
Yeah.
I guess like I said,
I think I'm frustrated by the
fact that it's taken so long.
But yeah,
but that's also because so many
people have had to suffer needlessly.
People that are in jail loud don't belong.
This terrible case about a guy in Montana
who was a grower who was following the
state law,
even had a state law
enforcement authorities on a
regular basis come out to his
grow houses and he showed them what he
was doing is providing for all these
different patients in Montana.
And this guy's up for eight years in jail.
You know,
he's,
he's up for more in jail then he would be,
if he killed somebody,
you know,
jails 25 to life for murder and this guy
is 80 years is as potential sentence.
It's insane for growing some
plants that the state approved.
The state made a law.
They approved it.
He was there.
He brought the state people in.
They said,
Yup,
everything's good.
Brought the state police in.
Yup.
Everything's good.
Okay,
we're good.
Let's grow some pot.
Right?
What was the plot?
Gives it to all the sick people and
now this poor guys and learned 80 or
stretch.
Right.
It's insane.
It comes in and now as a man
of science and you clearly are,
what,
how do you feel when you see like CNN
and you see like doctor drew talking all
this craziness on CNN about withdrawal
symptoms and withdrawal syndromes.
He was saying from,
from cannabis use.
And how about the cannabis today is so
much stronger than it was where younger.
It's incredibly dangerous.
These words.
Incredibly dangerous.
It's like I hear this
nonsense and I'm like,
this is again a man who can't
see describing a kaleidoscope.
This is a person who doesn't know
what the fuck they're talking about.
A guy who's incredibly straight and he's,
he's,
he's describing something
and it's always negative.
Ignore every artist,
ignore every person who tells you it makes
food taste better and makes sex feel,
but ignore all of that.
Ignore all these people that are quoting
all these positive things and focus on
what is most likely bullshit.
If you,
if you go by personal experience like
what we all know if someone is having
psychotic episodes because of marijuana,
I have gotten to think they were going
to have psychotic episodes anyway.
I got to think marijuana
just got them there.
They were already fucked.
I mean,
I would,
I would have to assume just knowing my
own personal experience with the drug,
when someone who hasn't had an experience
with the trunk and they're talking
about it,
it's maddening.
It's,
it's a crazy person talking.
It's like,
where are your bodies?
Where are these numbers?
Oh,
these people are,
you know,
their cultural icons.
Who are paid to paid to
be very important already.
Right.
Not just that paid by the
pharmaceutical companies,
paid by the pharmaceutical companies,
the media,
everybody else to pull
it out a certain meme,
a certain message and you know,
so you shouldn't be surprised.
I mean,
I mean that's just,
you know,
this is drive you crazy though.
Like when you see that if
you have all the channels,
yeah,
it does.
I mean,
it drives me crazy,
but I'm so old and cynical
and jaded and you know,
I mean it,
it's like I've done it drives,
it doesn't surprise me at all.
I mean,
I think the only solution is,
I'm not sure what the solution is.
The solution is to get the right
word out to people somehow.
And that's what things like
your program and other,
other channels I feel like I tried to do.
And uh,
you know,
I mean,
um,
I like to plug Arrow would you probably
know about Arrow with wonderful people
who are doing a good job
of bringing actual facts,
you know,
to the table.
And so we need more resources like that.
And they're not pro or anti,
they're pro fact,
which is what I admire
about them as a trip.
Reports are very helpful for
very helpful and they will say,
you know,
the dangerous or this the,
you'd need to be aware of
these possible hazards and,
and uh,
and that's the only thing,
education,
the only solution to this is just say no,
you know,
k n o w that's the thing,
and this is,
and it's all a matter of education.
Some money.
Yeah.
It
banded believe whose quote is that?
Just say,
I think it's Timothy
leary should be online.
If someone should have a
cafe pressure ready to go,
I'm going to get off on
amazon.com right after this.
And by,
you know,
the thing is,
uh,
it's,
it's really all about education.
It's about empowering people to make
informed decisions about what kind of
substances that are going to use,
under what circumstances,
what their intentions are.
There's a protocol,
there's a way to use these
things in a positive way,
in a way to use them.
Destructively I'm fond of,
I mean,
I always tell my students
there is no such thing as
a bad drug or a good drug.
They don't have moral qualities.
Human beings have moral qualities.
There are plenty of
opportunities to misuse it,
drug or use a drug in a bad way.
That's not the drug's fault.
It's simply has the pharmacological
chemical properties that it has poisoned
isn't evil.
It's just poison.
It's all about how people use it,
right?
It's human behavior is
what we need to focus on.
And that's what drug
education doesn't focus on it.
It talks about the drugs almost as though
they were demons are pathogens or like
they had some kind of independent
existence and they were an evil virus or
something.
They are not.
It's the way people use them.
And what,
what needs to happen
with drug education is,
you know,
they don't want to admit this,
but here's,
here's the ball truth of it.
It's not about teach telling
people do not use drugs,
right?
I mean they say that's
gotta be the message.
And that's the only message.
True Drug Education has got to
tell people how to use drugs.
That's the difference.
How if you,
if you choose to use a
psychoactive substance,
then here's a way to use it.
You know,
here's what you do to maximize the
benefit of it and minimize the harm.
It's simply that's,
you know,
uh,
but drug education doesn't,
you can't institutionalize programs
that are going to tell people how to use
drugs.
Isn't that funny though?
It's funny.
I mean,
it's stupid.
We,
we,
we expect people to
learn how to drive a car.
You know,
we encourage,
uh,
responsible drinking,
whatever that is.
So in that one instant,
you know,
we,
we say we encourage responsible usage,
not that people use it
in a responsible way.
Well,
I think we're big on people
figuring out shit for themselves,
which is why we send people out into
the world essentially with almost no
knowledge whatsoever about sex and love.
When you're young,
you just sort of have to stumble into
it at your most vulnerable and confused
time.
Same,
same issues.
Apply to sex,
right?
Sex Education and drug education.
Our jokes.
I think they're currently
practice that that's a joke.
And what is also a joke is just the,
the raising of human beings.
I think so many people in this country
are being raised by people who are
essentially children their entire life.
They never really did develop a true
understanding of themselves or of their
place in the world or an objective
sense of this whole thing.
And then the great mystery of it all,
it's never conveyed.
And then they raise children.
The children have to somewhere,
another wake up and go,
okay,
nobody knows what the fuck
is really going on here.
This is we,
we live in a world of madness and
momentum and it just continues on the same
path.
Even though everyone knows it's crazy.
But can you imagine?
I mean,
how many people can step
out of that framework?
You know,
it's rare.
I mean,
if here,
you know,
if you grow up,
if you're,
if you're relay raised
in a religious household,
you know,
especially a fundamentalist household,
you're not encouraged to think
about very much discouraged,
heavily discouraged.
You're encouraged to,
this is what you need to believe.
And all this other stuff is,
you know,
heresy and you,
you,
you know,
you're condemned if,
if you think about that.
So I really,
I mean,
well,
I don't know.
I mean,
we could get off for another 40 minutes
on antireligious Rachel's to say it,
just do it.
Don't say it.
Right.
It's the,
it's ideologies.
Any ideologies is that the issue is
when someone is thinking about what they
should do and it's already written
for them to subscribe to this,
well,
everybody's situation is different.
Everybody's life is different,
your wants and needs are different.
And instead of all these different ideas
of what we're supposed to do and not
supposed to do,
and what is evil and what is good,
we've lost the ability to figure out what
kind of an impact what we're doing has
on other people.
And judging that first and foremost.
And that I think is a very,
very much a religious and a
psychedelic principle that I,
that idea the idea of
looking at everything and
how it's affecting the other
people around you first.
And if you did that,
no one would ever impose that kind
of restrictions on your children.
Because if you were truly looking
at the development of the children,
the first thing you'd say is,
well,
I don't want to fuck this kid up.
Right.
You know,
instead of suppressing this kid and
having this unbelievable resistance,
which every God damn human
being has ever had ever,
when you tell someone not to do something,
they want to do it.
When you try to control them,
they want to break free.
When you're a controlling person,
they want to pierce their
nose and go fucking crazy.
Right?
It's,
it's,
it's the same all throughout humanity.
So we should have,
we should be able to
figure that out by now.
Well,
some have and some do.
But do you know,
I mean for you to be able to say that,
to have that perception,
a million had to have it before you.
Well,
and you had how you have
to be an exceptionally in
the lighten minded person,
you know,
if you're,
or comedian or,
or someone.
Yeah,
exactly.
Who Pushes the envelope,
right?
Who Really,
who makes a profession of out of stepping
out of the box or trying to look at
things from,
you know,
a broader perspective.
But if you're a person who,
you know,
I mean,
if you were raised in a
strict religious household,
chances are your children are going to
be raised in that household and you never
really look,
you know,
you never take the blinders
off because you know,
there's all sorts of bad
stuff out there and you,
you just don't want to know about it.
You know,
and,
and that's the problem.
Uh,
you know,
of the ideologies,
the,
the problem is that predetermined
patterns of thinking.
Yeah.
I'm in one of the things I like to say a,
I think that psychedelics are
extremely valuable with respect to,
you know,
sometimes I talk about faith.
One of the things that's interesting
about psychedelics is they don't require
faith,
right?
I mean,
religious belief,
religious tenants are usually postulated
on this idea that here's a whole bunch
of things that you should believe.
And there's not a shred of
evidence for any of this,
but you must have faith.
My son,
right?
That this is why,
why should you have faith?
You know,
chances are it's a lie.
Yeah.
I mean,
you know,
we know that the religions have been
scamming this for centuries ontology.
Oh Wow.
They're legit.
Sure.
They're legit trying to join Scientology's
when he knows I see worth of my land.
But the thing is with psychedelics,
faith is an impediment.
You don't have to have faith.
We can just have what you
need to have is courage.
But what do you say to the people,
the cynics,
the,
you know,
the people who would look at the
psychedelic experiences and say,
okay,
you are glorifying and,
and you're over exaggerating
what's essentially a hallucination.
Your visual cortex has being bombarded
with these foreign chemicals.
You're seeing things that aren't there.
And all this is,
is just your,
your brains need to make something
profound out of what's essentially a
malfunction,
a malfunction of your,
you're,
you're thinking a malfunction of your
visuals and you've sort of attached to all
this importance to it
after the experiences over.
Well,
that's the cynical point of view.
That's the cynical point of view.
But to that,
I would reply that you know
what we call ordinary reality,
ordinary consciousness,
even consensus.
Reality is essentially a hallucination.
I mean,
right?
The reason drugs work is
because we're made of drugs.
You know,
and whether or not we're on drugs or not,
our brains are creating,
you know,
this reality which,
which we know does not
resemble the real world.
Whatever that is.
I mean the instruments of our physics
and so on tell us that the world is a
quantum world is full of vibration.
That it doesn't look anything like this,
that Adams,
we mostly hard.
A lot of what our brain does
is synthesize a hallucination,
essentially create a model of the
world that we proceed to live in.
You know,
I mean the world that we,
you and I share and everyone shared,
this is a model of the world.
This is a model reality,
not the real reality.
The real reality is completely
unknowable and will always remain so.
So for people to say,
well,
you've just,
yeah,
you've disturbed your brain
chemistry in a novel way.
If you've tuned into
different channel essentially,
but you're still working with a model,
whether it's a model of the world
experience through the lens of a drug or
whether it's experienced
through the lens of,
you know,
sober conscious perception.
It's still a biochemical
artifact in a sense.
Our brains create this,
we live inside of it,
you know,
and uh,
that's so,
so that's what I would say to
those people that it's not that,
you know,
there is some kind of objective reality
which we're immersed in when we're not
on drugs.
It's more that were on drugs all the time.
You know,
our brain is a organ that
happens to churn out drugs,
you know,
which we called neurotransmitters and
hormones and that's what our brains run
on.
So all,
all you do when you take an external drug
is you tweak one or more of those sets
of receptors that,
that there were Unser
talking to and you know,
you get a slightly distorted
signal from what we,
what we have come to
accept as ordinary reality.
There is no ordinary reality
or we don't know what it is.
It's,
it's forever unknowable in terms
of our subjective experience.
There's a very strong makes sense.
Yes it does.
There's a very strange desire
to discount something that,
uh,
you can't like put on a scale.
He can't like can't bring it
back and show it to someone.
But essentially most of
what you experience in your
everyday life is just that.
It's just an experience.
You're seeing things,
you're feeling things
and you're traveling,
you're taking in information.
But we have this real
need a lot of people to,
to discount the things that
happened to discount the,
the vision of the psychedelic experience,
the hallucinations,
the,
the visuals,
the profound impact and the sounds.
Even though those are experiences that
you are taking in as an individual,
as a human being,
as an entity,
you're taking those in there.
They're dismissed.
They're discounted because the,
you know,
you can't,
you can't hit them.
You can't,
you can't paint them.
you know,
there,
there's nothing there.
You have nothing there.
You can't that experience,
although significant to you.
Well,
yeah,
but,
but now,
I mean,
that's part of the task I think is to be
able to bring something back from that
place.
And people do.
I mean,
I think that's a lot of what psychedelic
art does and these sort of creative
interfaces.
It's not that people go out
and take psychedelic drugs.
I've never produce anything.
You know,
those experiences influenced
them profoundly and you
may not be able to exactly
reproduce them.
But given the technologies
that we have access to,
you can come pretty darn close,
you know,
with multimedia technologies and
computer graphics and all this stuff.
And it may be that,
you know,
well,
I mean I,
I think this technology is only
going to get better as we evolve,
you know,
toward it maybe a 10 or 15 years.
He won't have to take psychedelic drugs
because we'll have neurotechnologies
that just do the same thing,
you know,
or you maybe it is that you,
you take one psychedelic drug,
you take a capsule and it's a nano machine
that will on demand produce any kind
of altered state that you want to call up.
One of the more faster but also
within the realm of possibility.
That's the scary part is that
it's not just science fiction.
And one of my fascinating concepts,
et Cetera,
Terence had was the,
uh,
the,
the concept of the
singularity is he saw it,
you know,
the,
the technological singularity it a little
bit different than the Kurtzweil and a
lot of these futurists saw it.
He thought it was a very likely going
to be a time machine or something along
those lines.
Something that will,
they'll be created where there's a
new technology we're time ceases to be
linear.
What did you,
did you wrap your head around that?
Like how did you feel about that one?
Well,
yeah,
we did that mean we'd love to,
to play with that idea and uh,
you know,
in fact we used to,
Terry used to speculate that the 2012
that the singularity will be triggered the
moment that time travel is invented
and everyone and everyone after that,
we'll of course want a migrate back to
the original moment when time travel was
invented.
So suddenly there'll be all these time
machines condensing out of nowhere and
basically it's to do everything changes.
Right,
right.
James only can either wrap their head
around that idea that infinite time and
distance into the future would all be
able to access the moment the first time
machine was invented.
That's true.
All come back
time.
Travel would certainly change
everything if you could do that.
I don't know.
I mean physics pretty much tells us that
time travel is technically possible,
but only if you have access to
manipulation of energies that are likely,
there'll be way beyond
us for quite awhile.
You know,
black,
whole levels of energy and that kind
of thing to do things with time.
But there's always a possibility
that there will be a breakthrough.
Right.
You know,
you never know.
Well we're gonna,
we're never going to stop.
My thought about human ingenuity and
the r constant desire for innovation is
that I don't ever see it stopping.
It seems to be a part of what the
human animal is and what it does here.
So when,
if someone like,
um,
I do not remember his name,
the guy out of a university
of Connecticut who was the,
he's the lead time travel,
uh,
expert.
It's a really fascinating character.
He's like a guy in the Spiderman book
because his father died when he was a
young boy.
So he became determined to build a time
machine to go back and save his father.
Oh yeah.
Really fascinating guy.
I cannot remember his name.
Uh,
I will eventually.
Um,
but his,
um,
his Ronald Mallet,
his,
uh,
his idea,
I think a,
was that once he had really
thoroughly research time travel,
he realized that you would never be able
to go back before the moment of time.
Machine was invented that there's,
you're never going to
be able to go backwards,
but you can go back to that moment.
Yeah.
Well that's,
Terence had that idea long before
this guy did and this guy was like,
you know,
he's a legit peer reviewed scientists.
I mean,
he's had like,
he has a peer reviewed paper on the,
the science behind time travel
and they all agree that yeah,
if you could generate this
insane amount of power,
you could be able to do it.
You could do it.
I find it amazing that
Terrence had this idea as well,
like really long before it was
like sort of a mainstream thought.
Well,
you know,
you can attribute that to in a sense what
we were immersed in when we were kids.
I mean we were both completely
sucked into science fiction.
We were very much immersed
in science fiction,
hg wells novel the time,
just like,
you know,
at the time machine.
I mean,
that was a huge influence on me.
I probably read that sucker Tanner time.
I read that when I was a kid as well.
I was a whole lay fascinated by by that
I all the versions of the movie as well.
Well,
so at least two versions.
So at least two versions.
Yeah,
it versions.
I think the first one was
possibly a little better,
but yeah,
so those ideas,
you know,
we're,
we're out there and,
uh,
and again,
in other psychedelics and shamonic states,
you couldn't type travel,
you know,
have you read a Graham Hancock's do novel?
No.
Very interesting.
Tangled.
Oh,
you should read it.
I would love to.
Very interesting.
I've read his nonfiction stuff and uh,
this is his first novel,
but it's all about a,
essentially a time bridge between a
shamonic person 17,000 years ago and a
modern counterpart and
they're communicating across
there and tangle literally
quantum entangled.
And it's,
it's quite a fascinating novel.
He had fun with it.
I find it amazing that we've able,
we've been able to,
for the most part,
not destroy ourselves
with nuclear power because nuclear
power and a lot of the ways,
the big impact,
the biggest impact that has
not just powering cities,
but destroying them and on the fact that
we've sort of figured out a way to put
a cap on that.
And really,
even despite all the conflict in world,
we haven't had a nuclear event
like that since the 1940s right.
I wonder how much more evolved we would
have to be to be responsible for the
actual use of a time machine.
I mean,
how much more evolved would we have to
be before we could have something like
that?
It wouldn't be the president
has access to the button.
It would be,
you know,
the president has access to
the hole in the universe.
You know?
I mean,
what,
how do we decide whether or
not we're going to do this?
How do we decide who we
go back in time and save?
You know,
when events happen in the news,
do we have like a congressional meeting?
Do we go back in time and a well person?
I mean,
I think that's a,
that's a misunderstanding
of the nature of time,
right?
I mean,
if,
I mean one of the reasons
time travel is impossible,
supposedly that kind of time is
because you can't do those things.
You can't go back and prefab
the Kennedy assassination,
you know,
because you proliferate another timeline
and things to at least one more.
But then,
you know,
physicists tell us,
I'm the current theory is
everything you do pre precipitates,
you know,
proliferates multiple timelines.
It's please explain that because Duncan
and I have been trying to wrap our heads
around that one and we've,
we've brought it up to each
other a couple of times.
The,
I,
it's sort of a,
an abstract idea in my head,
but every decision you
make literally brings up,
uh,
creates a different universe,
creates a different universe and not
only every decision you ever make.
If I understand it,
it extends to,
you know,
every collapse of a,
of a wave form every,
you know,
collision of Adam's,
every event,
every offense,
no matter how minuscule or insignificant
that we're not even aware of
proliferates multiple,
multiple time frames.
It doesn't make sense.
Obviously we can't wrap
our head around this.
And it may be that we're,
you know,
I've been,
maybe we're not,
maybe we're not confined to one of these
timelines where it maybe we're living
simultaneously infinite
number of timelines.
That's so hard.
Yeah.
It's hard to wrap your head.
The idea of fractal universe is
an infinite amount of faculty,
universities and they're constantly
changing and moving like,
like a,
a,
a tide filled with cells,
like a tide of cells just washing
over the world over and over,
back and forth.
It never ends,
but why not?
What,
why,
why reality?
Why this,
this is a bizarre enough as it is.
Exactly.
I've always said to be,
be like,
if you don't,
if you,
you know,
you don't want to have a
psychedelic experience,
you are,
whether you like it or not,
it's called life.
Because if you existed in some sort of
a logical continuum of real objective
thought and reasoning,
and you had to exist in,
in life,
in today and the human world
in 2012 and that was my point.
That's what we were saying earlier.
The brain is a machine that simulates
the reality that we live in.
You know,
and
then,
you know,
so,
so it,
it just is,
I mean,
it's our,
it,
it takes the raw data of experience and
it mixes it together in the way that,
and it extrudes it into
something comprehensible.
So the brain is as much a processor
of this data from outside visit.
I mean,
I don't,
I think the question of whether the braid
generates consciousness is one of the
con,
you know,
one of the things that
neuroscience has to confront,
and I think the evidence
is that it doesn't,
it's more a real detector
of consciousness.
This what evidence,
what evidence is this?
That the,
the brain detect consequences?
Well,
it's not all of the evidence
of non ordinary states.
You know,
these other dimensions that for
shamanism and for psychedelics,
they present as real.
I mean,
does the brain dream all those up?
Why is the,
why are there commonalities
between those states?
Uh,
you know,
between people.
I mean,
you don't have to be fans of Terence
and Dennis Mckenna to take DMT,
have to have similar experiences,
you know,
to us.
So I think,
I just don't think that we really have
a definitive way to say that all of what
we experience arises from the brain.
It's more that
consciousness is built into the
structure of space time in a certain way.
And our brains are detectors
and processors much in
the way of television is a
detector of a signal,
takes it,
the signal processes it in a way that's
comprehensible and puts it out there,
the screen.
So the,
the ego and the personality and the
lifestyle you choose and what have you as
you're making your way through this,
this dimension is essentially just
clothing that you wear in a shield,
you from the great outdoors
of reality essentially.
Yeah.
It's a model that you create.
It's a model that you create
and it helps you get through.
This,
helps you get through it
and it maps closely enough,
close enough to some external reality
out there that you can navigate.
You're not stepping off
cliff cliffs or you know,
walking in front of buses.
So it has a definite survival value
and there's enough overlap between what
you're consensual world is and mine is
and ours is that we can talk to each
other,
we can live in this same space.
It out to a certain extent.
Fascinating concept and it,
it really is and that's one of the more
profound aspects of the psychedelic
experiences.
The stripping away of that personality
and culture and and and everything and
getting to some weird strange source
getting to this strange that exists
is this clear thought without our a
minute you get to turn the circuit board
over,
right?
You begin to turn,
you get to turn it over
and see how it's wired.
I think that's one of the
big
useful,
interesting things about
psychedelics and particularly DMT.
DMT just rips the curtain back and you'd
get to see the raw data of experience
and how it's all,
it's everything.
Everything you know,
memories,
people you talked to,
fragments of you know,
songs,
just whatever things are
swimming around in your head.
You sort of see they're all going into,
you know,
through this funnel or something.
Then it's coming out all a taped together
some way and that kind of a coherent
picture of,
of reality.
But DMT strips that back
and you get to step,
you get to see it from
the other side briefly,
how it's,
how it's working,
you know,
the reality generating
machine if you will.
That's what you see on DMT.
What is your thoughts or
what are your thoughts on,
uh,
alien abductions and Ufo experiences?
And do you think that these
are indogenous dumps of,
uh,
Dante,
that it's most likely what these people
were experiencing is some sort of a,
um,
well overflow or something,
you know,
a,
no,
I don't,
I mean,
I think that,
you know,
I think that Strassman's work on
this where high doses of DMT can
in,
you know,
in some people reliably induce these,
these abduction type in categories.
We'll,
we'd,
no,
they're not,
you know,
standing beside a highway in New
Mexico and watching it Ufo land.
They're in a hospital bed,
you know,
with an ivy installed,
but they're having these
types of experiences.
For those who don't know
what you're talking about,
it's Rick Strassman's work.
It's a book called DMT,
the spirit molecule.
It's all about the clinical studies,
right?
Things you did with TMT,
clinical studies with DMT at Straussman
reported that in many of his subjects
who are given high doses of DMT,
they had experiences that were similar,
if not identical to the classic
alien abduction type experience.
So then you do think that that's
what these people are having,
they're having indogenous
dumps while they're sleeping.
It's just something's
happening and that's,
no,
I think that not necessarily.
I think that,
I think that there,
I think that what DMT does is it lets
you poke your head temporarily into
another dimension.
So when these people are having
these UFO abduction experiences,
you think that other dimension is
poking his head into ours and yeah,
something like that.
So somehow the membrane
is Theon and you know,
whether it's you going there,
them going here,
there is,
you know,
there,
there are interfaces between
what we call ordinary reality,
which isn't ordinary at all.
And these other thesis
alternate realities.
And occasionally they come together,
you know,
and the membranes stretches and then
you get these types of interactions.
If that's true.
I mean if that's true,
uh,
that,
you know,
that model is,
the usual model of,
of experiences reductionist.
It's like the braveness generating all
of this and that's where it's coming
from.
And uh,
you know,
everything we think we know about
the world is based on that premise.
If this other premise is true,
then we have to reexamine our most
fundamental assumptions about how it is,
you know,
how the world is
the um,
the issue isn't the,
isn't part of it though,
that all these abductions parents is a
good percentage of them happen at night.
They happen a lot of them.
All of these people aren't bad.
They're not happening
while people are like,
um,
Monday morning on the highway,
right to work,
happening while you're
supposed to be sleeping,
while your brain is producing
DMT in the first place.
Exact.
Do you think that the DMT could possibly,
I mean this is complete speculation,
but act as a doorway
where the actual real,
true entity can come through.
So these people that are having
these UFO abduction experiences,
even if they are still lying in their bed,
they are actually still
having this real experience.
Yeah,
I do.
I mean,
and if you talk to Sherman's people that
deliberately induce these states for
exactly this reason,
to communicate with these nonhuman
intelligences that give them useful
information about all kinds of things.
I mean,
the Shamans are just matter of
fact about it and they'll just say,
well,
yeah,
that,
what did you think it was?
You know,
this is the way reality is then
that that's where the cynics,
so he's coming like,
where,
where's this information?
What are you bringing back?
Can someone please bring back and
unsolvable equation that fast?
Maddix that's a tough one.
Yeah.
What do you think like that?
If you had a point to anything that's
been brought back from the Psychedelic,
you expect,
uh,
you know,
not the,
the Francis Crick thing that's disputed.
Right?
Whether or not Francis Crick,
you actually saw the double
helix while he was on Lsd.
Well,
he said that he did finally
death bed on his death bed.
There's no recording.
You know what I mean?
How much of that is just very Moelis
pcrs totally out front about his LSD
experiences contributed to
his insights about this ear.
Right.
It's difficult to measure
bringing something back.
I mean,
and Terrence was,
you know,
he,
he has talked about this.
He used to what he was taking
mushrooms do exactly this,
get I thou
dialogue going with the
mushroom and you know,
insist that the mushroom tell him
something that he couldn't possibly know.
You know,
and the mushroom was
always very cagey about,
didn't cough it up.
But when you think,
well if I tell you that you won't need,
that sounds like the imagination to me.
I mean if I was the cynic I would say,
well that's obviously your imagination
then cause he can't concoct to anything
and it doesn't exist or something
you couldn't possibly know.
It doesn't have the resources because
it's coming from your own mind.
Well that would be,
that would be the criticism.
But then out of that
comes something like this,
the TimeWave zero.
I mean,
I would submit the time where zero was
an artifact from this other dimension,
but do we really understand what it was?
I mean it was a conceptual
artifact in a certain sense.
It was an idea.
So even certainly came from left field,
you know,
regardless of whether or not it
actually is some sort of a map of time.
It most certainly is a
13 lunar cycle calendar.
Well it certainly is.
That came from a psychedelic experience
that the knowledge of that essentially.
Yeah,
essentially.
So that's,
that seems to be something that
you can at least that aspect of it.
It seems very unfortunate that it's
connected with this idea of a map of time,
which makes people stick their nose up
in the air because if they just looked at
it for that,
just the,
the each thing being a,
um,
a calendar and an,
an a last calendar and
unleavened calendar.
Indisputably it's a calendar
or you can use it that way.
I mean,
the mathematics is clear as long as
you don't begin to postulate that this
actually,
you know,
describes the structure of time.
That's where I have a problem
with it because for one thing,
you know,
TimeWave zero completely
ignores relativity and all
the aspects of time that go
into that.
So you know how cell,
well,
it claims that,
you know,
uh,
if claims that this
map of time describes the
structure of time everywhere,
you know,
in all parts of the universe,
but we know from relativity that it
all depends on the reference frame.
Right.
So,
you know,
so it's not clear ship
traveling speed of light,
someone aboard it experiences time at a
different level and it's given on earth
different way.
How do you con side that,
how did,
how did the,
how do they call it?
Can't reconcile.
It just doesn't account for it,
you know?
I mean,
the problem with the TimeWave to stay
up for this conversation that the,
I'm trying to wrap my
head around it while,
while we're talking
about the TimeWave in my,
in my opinion,
is that it's not,
it can't be disproved.
Neither can Jesus.
And so,
right.
Science can't disprove anything.
Science can't disapprove.
Well,
yeah,
science can disapprove things.
They can't prove it.
Not unique events.
Right?
That unique events happened.
The other words,
in other words,
Terence or whoever created the
TimeWave theory never defined,
these are the criteria that
will invalidate this theory,
right?
And science depends on,
in order to qualify as a theory,
you have to say what's
going to invalidate it?
What is,
you know,
what are the criteria that's going to
take the foundations out
from under this theory?
That either means you have to chuck the
theory completely or you have to modify
it.
So the model fits the data better.
Right?
And,
uh,
he was never able to,
or he'd never did.
And I don't think he was really able to
define what would invalidate the theory.
So it's an untestable theory.
So it's not a theory.
So it's just an idea.
It's an interesting idea,
but it isn't the theory.
It's not something you can disapprove.
And so it's,
it's useful as an idea,
but it's,
but in some ways it's not.
I mean,
you know,
you've got,
if you want it to be scientific,
if you want to call this a
theory in the scientific sense,
you have to define what's gonna,
what's gonna disapprove it,
what I meant,
the science can't disprove
things when I met as,
I can't disprove like
really unique events,
like the idea of a Ufo actually existing
and then disappearing like once it's
here in God.
If there's no physical evidence,
if there's not,
I mean,
how do you,
how can you disprove a
unique event like that?
But when you,
well,
yeah,
you,
you don't,
I mean that the doesn't mean
they don't exist though.
Right.
They do exist.
Sure.
Something makes is,
I mean,
I always thought that what Jl Heineke,
the UFO researcher,
famous Ufo researcher
said about Ufo as he said,
I don't know if you have
photos are real or not,
but I know absolutely 100%
that Ufo experiences are real.
Hmm.
And that's the data.
That's the data that
you have to investigate.
I think that,
I think that's a very
perceptive thing to say.
Especially coming from him.
Yeah.
He's coming from Jay on.
Nick was a guy who actually
worked for operation.
We're project Blue Book and uh,
he was,
uh,
assigned by the government to go and
research different UFO sightings.
And somewhere along the line he cited,
listen man,
I'm going to just do this.
And he stopped working for the government.
It just started spending all
of his time researching Ufo.
He was absolutely convinced.
He was always clear that what he was
investigated where Ufo experiences because
that was the data that
he had to work with,
you know,
and that's absolutely 100% true.
Ufo experiences do occur,
whether those are
confabulation of,
you know,
the mind or whether they're,
whether they're extra terrestrial origin,
extra dimensional.
Laura,
I don't think we can really say,
did you ever have any
sort of alien experience?
Did you ever have any sort of
extra terrestrial physical contact?
Um,
no,
I can't say I have,
you know,
um,
other than being smeared
over the entire universe.
Yeah.
But that was,
that was,
that was saying it was
extra terrestrial but,
but Terrence did you
know at lunch Herrera,
he did.
Of course there was no
one else to witness this.
Right.
And I write about that in the book.
I actually quote at length the section
from a true hallucinations in which he
describes this.
And I have no doubt,
I don't doubt that it took place.
I mean,
there was all sorts of anomalous
things taking place a lot.
Sure.
And then again,
it goes back to the fact that you guys
were ingesting the most incredible
silicide mushrooms every day.
All Day.
I mean,
but,
but the really interesting stuff didn't
start until after we've stopped that.
Well,
even after he stopped that though,
how much of that shit was still
floating around in your head?
I mean,
you guys were talking
about crazy quantities.
Are you to say,
did you ever sober up?
I still high from that.
Substances are still high from
it because that experience,
you'd never,
you know,
you're always integrating it.
I mean,
it's rather strange to me that,
you know,
it's like that was 1971
so that was 40 years ago.
And one of the more interesting
things that Terence said about,
uh,
siliciden,
which was a real mind
blower was first of all,
how closely it relates to normal human
neurochemistry is that silicide been,
is like almost exactly the
same as chemicals that are
on brain produces and very
alien in that form,
that form the form that it exists.
Whatever the molecule
structure of suicide of it is,
it's the only similar,
the way it exists it,
there's not something similar to it or
there's not something like it that exists
in the organic world other than a
chemistry.
Yeah.
Well that's not quite true,
but I think what he was trying to
say that it's silicide button is,
is only found in the fungal kingdom.
Right.
As far as we know,
it's never been found in a higher plan.
Although lots of tryptamines DMT is
all over the place and a lot of mess
derivatives.
But psilocybin and Silversun do not occur
as far as we know outside the fungal
world,
outside the world of mushrooms.
Why that should be hard to say.
Maybe it will be discovered in a
higher plant tomorrow or next week,
but I kind of doubt it.
Uh,
you know,
uh,
I don't want to get too
much into the chemistry,
but I do think,
I think that,
you know,
this,
this touches on another,
you know,
remarkable aspect of,
of our universe,
of,
of uh,
biological being,
which is that these tryptamines
DMT five methoxy DMT,
Bufo,
silicide and Silversun DMT itself
as two steps from Tryptofan,
right?
Tryptophan is an amino
acid that is universal.
It's part of the 20 that go into proteins.
So it's an essential molecule of life.
Tryptofan is the molecule are the
enzymes that convert Tryptofan to DMT.
There are two primary enzymes,
a
amino acid decarboxylase
aromatic amino acid,
decarboxylase and methyltransferases,
what they're call called.
I don't know if your
audience cares about this,
but the point is too trivial
steps from tryptofan leads to DMT,
right?
And so DMT,
you know,
the,
the biosphere is saturated with DMT.
It's not an uncommon chemical at all.
It's found in probably
thousands of plants.
It's found in animals
that's filed in fungi.
It's everywhere.
I think it's interesting.
I don't know what it
means except you know,
stepping away from science for a minute,
strict science,
but thinking maybe this is a kind of a
subtle message that nature is trying to
send to the monkeys.
So that's why DMTs everywhere.
Yeah.
Look guys,
just look around the corner,
right?
It's all waiting for you.
It's all there.
If I remember one time I
said was what he found fast.
It was a,
what he was alluding to was that
silicide and may have come here and uh,
from an asteroid that it
could survive in a vacuum.
And He,
I think it was,
um,
the phosphorous,
I believe in the four
position describing the,
the molecular structure of suicide,
suicide and its
phosphorolated form position.
As you said,
it was the only thing that was like that.
Is that right?
It's the only one we found so far.
It's the only phosphorylated in
Dole that we found in nature.
Well that and some close derivatives
which also occur in them.
Yeah.
Does that make any sense then that
that could have possibly come here?
We know that what it's
called Pennsbury as a,
how they just have the sperm
Mia Panspermia is how the,
they believe that amino
acids and essential building
blocks from life may have
traveled here from asteroids.
And that may be how life
was seated on this planet or
I mean I suggest in the book actually
people have to read the book because they
have to kind of unpack this.
I actually have a section in the book
called reflections on Lunch Herrera.
And I,
uh,
trying to,
not only I'm it for the reader,
but try and look at it myself
from the standpoint of 40 years
Hanse,
you know,
after the experience and say what
was going on and what makes sense.
And what might've been going on was,
was it simply to,
you know,
nerdy guys who went to the Amazon,
took too many drugs and m had these
experiences and that end of story or was
there really something else going on?
And the whole issue touches
on what we were talking about,
about the evolutionary potential
evolutionary significance of mushrooms.
I mean it may be that what
we are is a million year,
multimillion year long
biotechnologies a essentially where,
you know,
if a super technological civilization
biotechnological civilization with plenty
of time on its hands in
a certain perspective,
if they wanted to take an ecology and
see what happened when they see did these
molecules into the ecology,
you know,
and then watched it unfold.
Do you know,
perhaps manipulating
the way things unfolded.
They,
it's almost like,
you know,
they wanted to,
okay,
kind of I guess create the conditions
where intelligence and consciousness could
arise and then see what the effects
were in a certain sample media style pro
Mithias style.
Although prometheus's we all agree was
pretty lame.
But something like that you
said at first something,
something along that,
those lines.
So you know where if you seed the
ecology with Tryptofan and the enzymes,
then this,
this thing is going to
be all over the place.
And then,
you know,
I'm probably predate the appearance
of complex nervous systems.
But you know,
we know for example,
that the serotonin receptors
are evolutionarily the
oldest receptors that we'd
known the oldest
neurotransmitter receptors.
So,
uh,
well,
I don't know,
I mean it's tempting to speculate on this.
It's very sexy to,
it's sexy.
It's comforting in a certain way to
think there is actually an overlord that
south their CD and intelligence
throughout the galaxy.
I mean,
what a cool idea.
But you yourself knowing
so much about biology,
looking at the complex processes that
occur on this planet that are completely,
I wouldn't say they're
orchestrated by nature,
but like this,
the parasitic relationships,
they're really complex ones that eh,
parasites have with
like the aquatic water.
A worm that gets inside of a grasshopper
grows then convinces the grasshopper to
commit suicide so it can
be born into the water.
I mean,
we know about these weird
crazy relationships that exist.
Right?
Exactly.
So,
well,
but this is a kind of an example of that,
right?
On the galactic scale.
Exactly.
You know,
if,
if there are fungi in nature and actually
your cordyceps in years supplement is
exactly that.
You know,
it's biology,
you know,
it grows on caterpillars.
There are,
there are some species that will grow
on ants and you probably heard how they
work.
They will infect the
APP at a certain point,
the Haas Storia,
they will put these mycelium,
mycelium will affect the amps sprain and
trigger it to go from the base of the
leaf of the blade of grass to the tip.
Then it will kill it and parallel.
Oh right.
And then,
and then it can sporulate right.
It will overgrow the body
and released the spores,
but it's induced the hand to go from
the least optimal place to distribute
spores to the most optimal,
credible.
So it's controlled.
So that,
that's a phenomenon that's
an intelligent nature.
Yeah.
So kind of intense spreading intelligence.
So why is it so far fetched to
think that there is a galactic,
you know,
uh,
super race or maybe it's,
you know,
that infects,
complex nervous systems when they be busy
in our ecology that that then induces
us to,
you know,
invent culture and language and technology
and eventually build star ships and
get off this bud and do what they're
doing and do what they're continuing the,
the most advanced form of uh,
like forming life and other places.
Yeah.
Maybe or might maybe just
also just could be that.
So I mean this is getting so far out.
We should probably add the,
we went as far down the what if ladder
galactic overlord sending spaceships
filled with mushrooms.
Yeah,
that's,
that's like next top crazy.
I remember
what I mean.
This seems to remember that we exist.
You have to remember that we're putting
a rover on Mars and taking photographs
and possibly contaminating how unlikely
this whole thing is that we should even
be here.
I mean one of Terrence's favorite
phrases and I think it's true.
We should always remember
what JBS health aide said.
You know,
the universe is not only stranger than
you suppose it's stranger than you can
suppose.
I love that quote.
And I love that he used to
say queer because that's
what [inaudible] said it was
going to say,
actually he said Queer,
but we can't use that term.
Isn't that funny?
That they took queer,
they took queer.
That's what the universe is a queer thing.
It doesn't kind of exist
in that way as well.
They know anything that has hatches to
homosexual men can't have a gay old time
anymore.
Place it with a white university.
Just a stranger.
They say stranger.
No,
like you can't say you
have a gay old time.
The Flinstones had gay old
time in their fucking song.
You can't have that anymore.
We are so sensitive for
such a little babies.
Yeah.
In the middle of all this information,
we've tried to chalkboards away.
We're trying to take him,
take him away.
So,
you know,
I think,
I think that,
uh,
yeah,
I think that ultimately,
you know,
people say,
well,
what can we conclude from all this
and what have you learned from taking
psychedelics,
you know,
for 40 years and all that.
And the answer is kind of disappointing.
It will be disappointing to some people,
which is the,
exactly this,
the world is a marvelous place,
much more marvelous than we can imagine.
You know,
and we don't know very much,
you know,
I mean,
there are,
knowledge is so restricted,
you know?
Um,
okay.
And I think that's,
that's what you learn after all this time.
And this is what I owe Osca you know,
my main plant teacher always insists,
you know,
remember,
you don't know
shit.
You know,
don't give up.
Don't give up
arrogant because you don't know shit.
You know,
you just don't know very much.
And so
it's like,
you can say,
well,
I don't know shit and
I feel really stupid.
But it also clears the decks to appreciate
things and remind ourselves that we
don't know very much.
But if clears the decks for learning,
it means there's so much left to be
understood that marveled about and thought
about
ga excepted position.
Yeah,
except the position that you don't know
shit and then enjoy all the information
there is to take in and all
the fascination and the wonder.
Yeah.
She was like,
people are trying to control the position
and they're trying to control it and
pretend that they do no shit
and that's the big mistake.
That's where the knee jerk reaction to
a denying global climate change comes
from.
It's a just a desire of insecure people
to try to rationalize and control things
that can't be controlled and the
politicians want to do religion,
politics,
corporations,
the whole thing.
Like we have a model we
don't want to change.
We have a corner on the truth.
The way we think about
it is the way it is,
you know,
and anybody who challenged
us that is a is a heretic.
Now,
how long did it take you after lecturer
before you jump back on the horse?
It seems like if I got smeared across
the entire cosmos for a couple of weeks
and I don't remember how I
shit or smoke cigarettes,
I might just fucking quit.
Okay.
But not you.
How much time did you take
off before you jumped back on?
Well,
I don't know if some people
never have jumped back on,
but,
but how much time did it take
after psychedelic put the can
of tuna fish and do like normal thing?
No,
no,
no.
I mean,
how long before you had
another psychedelic experience?
Oh,
another site.
Well,
it was probably a couple of years.
I don't know.
It makes sense.
It wasn't that long.
It wasn't really that long.
That's a long time.
Yeah.
Did you like before
you did it and be like,
what the fuck am I doing?
Am I really want to get
spread across the university?
Well,
yeah.
I mean I have,
I have some,
some worries about it
when I went back to it,
but,
but not really because there
were so many other circumstances.
The psychedelic was just a part of it.
A lot of it.
The reason that's happened was
because we set ourselves up into this,
you know,
conceptual or I don't know what
you call a it cognitive box.
We set ourselves,
we painted ourselves into this corner in
terms of our predictions about what was
going to happen,
you know,
because it was all about time,
right?
A lot of it was about time and so
when we were leading up to doing the
experiment,
we thought that,
well,
the reason all this strange stuff is
happening is because a few hours up ahead
in the future,
we've done the experiment
and it is succeeded.
And so what we're getting is
the backwash from the future,
like approaching a singularity,
you know,
we were getting the backwash from the
future and that's why every it's warping
reality.
It literally is warping reality
as we approach this thing.
So we went into it with the attitude
that something had to happen,
something physic shattering.
I'm the,
we were trying to overturn,
literally the laws of physics came into
it with the idea that something had to
happen and guess what,
something happened just wasn't
what we predicted would happen.
He just went cuckoo for a couple of weeks.
Cocoa for a couple of weeks.
Yeah,
exactly.
And we,
but it was more than just cuckoo.
It was this,
you know,
this,
this coordinated,
uh,
experience of Terrence and myself were,
we were linked and we understood that
one person is becoming mirror images of
each other,
almost like a photograph
and it's negative and one,
one entity was going forward in time.
And then another was
going backward in time.
And you know,
a lot of,
I mean,
we had a whole framework
where it made sense.
It might not make sense now.
Yeah.
Well it doesn't,
it doesn't,
I mean it does,
but I'm lying.
I does,
but I mean,
I,
it does have,
but not that I'm lying.
I mean,
I'm sorry.
I do understand that you're trying to
express something that I can't understand.
Right.
Did you have a lot of
experiences or experiences where
you saw ancient motifs?
And May,
whether its hieroglyphs or Egyptian or
I've heard people that say they've seen
aromatic or Arab type writing and w
with seems to be maybe perhaps the
experiences of other people that have
taken the same sort of psychedelic drugs
and that it's a stored,
collected experience.
I thought,
I know that was one of the things that
Terrence believed that when you are
taking psilocybin you're not just taking
silicide when you're sort of conjoining
the experiences of everybody
who's ever taken that drug ever.
Did you feel that
you mean that La Chorrera uh,
at any point?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Subsequently I have had,
I have had those kinds of impressions.
Yeah.
I mean there,
I mean I think it's interesting that,
you know,
one of the things that when,
when we,
when we came back from La Chorrera one
of the priorities that our life was to
figure out how to grow those mushrooms.
Right.
So that we can reaccess.
But I mean then there was partly,
you know,
there was partly a mercenary motive,
but there was also the,
the real motive was we want other
people to have these experiences.
To see if they confirm,
you know,
what we were experienced.
I mean,
where we just nuts or do other people
have this similar kind of experience at
turns out they do.
You know,
so that's evidence I can for the objective
reality of some of these dimensions
or the reality.
I don't know if it's objective,
but you know what I'm saying?
You don't have to be Terence or Dennis.
You don't have to know what we talk
about or believe in what we talk about.
You can take mushrooms under
the right circumstances,
you know,
in the dark five grams,
pay attention and you
will go to the same place.
Many people go to the same place.
Do you think that that also explains
why the in the Iowasca experience is a,
a lot of jaguars and a lot
of snakes and a lot of,
uh,
that,
that type of cause to them,
that's the dimension.
That's the dimension that's
real for those people.
And it's just,
you know,
it,
I mean,
if it is to us it seems
implausible and unlikely,
but to them it's like it's a
part of their everyday reality.
They just accept it.
I mean it's much more matter of fact,
yes,
there are these realms,
there are these entities you can
get there with Iowa Osca and uh,
you know,
if you look at,
if you look at the paintings of Pablo,
Emma Ringo for example,
or others,
you know,
I mean he had this ability to paint
that realm as best direct elected,
but that's a tremendous contribution
because he provided a window into that
cosmology.
You could sort of look into that
conceptual place without actually taking
Iowasca as Alex Grey as does Alex
grey a similar kind of thing.
Yeah.
All of in Pablos iconography,
all of these spirits that you see and
you FO's incidentally and plants and
animals and all that,
they all have names.
These are not things that he dreamed up.
These are part of that cosmos
that he is able to depict.
What is his name again?
Pablo Amarigo and may our Ryan,
I've got to check him out.
I've never heard of this guy before.
No.
I believe I've seen his art,
but I knew his name and more ring go.
He has a book that he
put together with Louis.
Eduardo Luna had good friend of mine,
Louis Louis wrote the foreword to my book.
Oh,
I absolutely have seen this guy before.
Yeah.
You've seen it.
You've seen stuff.
Yeah.
So amazing.
But yeah,
that's so he recollects his visions and
was able to put them out on to canvas,
you know?
Wow.
Yeah.
When,
when a guy can do that,
like,
uh,
Alex Grey,
especially some of his images,
um,
they,
they appear Egyptian,
they appear DMT slash.
Egyptian.
You know,
and I've always wondered like,
what is,
what is that that you're
seeing when you're,
when you're seeing this sort
of ancient motif and all that,
the,
it seems,
for whatever reason,
it seems like a crazy
assertion that you're,
uh,
you're accessing the experiences of all
these people that have ever done this,
this drug.
ButW is it any weirder than cell phones,
you know,
is that any weirder than the
ability to Google something?
And that one,
Scott,
and weird,
it's inherently not any weirder
than the hobbit in three d.
I mean,
you could say,
yeah.
You could say,
you know,
well,
it's a similar experience because these
mushrooms activate the same receptors
that everybody,
and we all have a similar brain
architecture and all that.
And I think that to a certain extent,
that's part of it.
But that's not the,
that's not the whole story.
I mean,
again,
that comes back to whether,
you know,
the brain is generating this
stuff or whether it's actually,
you know,
sort of just making the membrane
thinner so that you can look at it.
Did you have any experience with
a sensory deprivation tanks?
I haven't had very much with that,
no.
Wow,
that's so crazy.
That seems like it'd
be right up your alley.
You'd think so.
Yeah.
I haven't experimented with it.
Have you been interested in at all?
Uh,
not really
that the,
uh,
the substances,
you know,
seem to reliably do it,
but yeah,
I should,
uh,
should look into it.
I'm a big fan.
Are you?
Oh yeah.
Even just for relaxation,
uh,
for,
just for the body.
You do it in conjunction
with psychedelics or,
yes.
Okay.
So at night,
Sam,
eating,
eating is my favorite
one.
Oh yeah.
Okay.
Eating cannabis and getting
to the point where you're,
you're like,
the way I describe what,
I try to describe it as a,
when you're so high
that you feel like the,
the,
the parallel dimension,
the neighboring dimension
is like a waterfall and
you've got your nose touching
the water and you're right about
the push to the other side.
That's when you get in the tank.
So right when you just,
you know that there's a moment when
you feel like you've eaten too much,
like you had a pop round and you're like,
this is not a comfortable feeling.
Terrible.
I definitely ate too much.
That's when he get in the tank.
Interesting.
And the complete lack of sensory input
from the tank along with that just blows
the whole experience out of the water.
I've had some of the
wildest trips in my life,
um,
from,
from doing that,
the sensory deprivation tank on its
own can put you in some crazy places,
but,
but about on its own,
but it's really good for his relaxation.
It's amazing for like loosening
you up and just soothing the body.
And it's an excellent
source of magnesium too,
because of the salt and the water.
It's Epson salts.
So it's one of the best ways for your
body to absorb a good amount of magnesium.
But I just,
I,
it's one of the things that I've never
understood why more people didn't get
into it.
I don't knit.
Lily.
John Lilly was the inventor of it
and he used one on a regular basis.
I just,
I never,
I always wanted to know
why that didn't catch on.
I never heard Karen's
talk about it either.
No,
he,
he didn't,
he didn't use it as far as I know.
Um,
I don't know.
It's such an amazing resource because
he was always in a silent darkness.
Yeah.
Well,
exactly.
Take it.
So assignment in,
in near total darkness,
there's kind of a sensory deprivation.
You're still in your body.
I mean,
he's still are not in this amniotic place,
you know?
Have you ever tried mushrooms?
Will see the isolation tank?
No,
I have not done well.
I did it.
I have done at once,
but I have not done a big dose.
I haven't,
I haven't done a lot but,
but mostly seem to be a good place for it.
Good.
Yeah.
The problem is I have kids and I don't
want to be blasted on in my head and that
thing and then to have something go wrong
and you open the door and reality just
hasn't tuned back in yet.
You know,
you've got to plan your sessions,
you need somebody to look after kids.
It's hard said aid,
all that.
One of the things about cannabis,
those are eating candy.
If,
if I get too high,
I can still deal with shit.
Right.
Adrenaline rises.
I got a phone call,
I can call,
I can talk to people,
I can come back out of reality.
I can get back.
It'd be okay.
And that combined with the,
uh,
the sensory depth tank is a,
it's a pretty,
pretty profound experience.
But I think probably if
you were into silent dark,
the thing about suicide and those
that he pulls you out so much,
you almost don't even
need a sensory dep tank.
It's almost like unnecessary.
It's unnecessary.
Yeah,
but by itself.
But it would be interesting.
It would be interesting if your
experience with those things.
You,
you go first.
I'll follow.
Yeah.
Well,
I have one,
I have
one in my basement,
so I like to use it.
I use it all the time.
But uh,
even just like I said by
itself just for relaxation,
but I just never understood why more
people didn't want to have that.
Just as a meditation tool,
it's a,
as a tool for completely getting alone
with your thoughts and just separating
yourself from any of the input of the body
seems that it would be useful.
But Terrence wasn't into that.
But he was in the pot on
a serious regular basis.
God,
yes,
man.
Had the capacity for cannabis that
I've never seen in anyone else.
Is that part of the reason why he
went on these rambling lectures?
He's incredible.
I mean,
he would wind the wind him up and some
of the great mp3s that are available on
the psychedelic salon of you even
familiar with the soccer Exelon,
great podcast and Renzo,
the guy who hosts it has,
I'm just hour upon hour
of Terrence's lectures.
Amazing,
amazing stuff.
But what was incredible was that you just,
he would just go up there
and the wind him up,
put him on the stage right when we're
in front of the microphone and he would
just go on for hours.
Just wrap it out.
Yeah,
it was,
I mean,
I'm sure he was high as fuck,
credit,
cannabis,
a lot of that,
you know,
his inspiration,
what he was doing was essentially what,
you know,
what he used to do,
I mean,
back before anybody knew
about him or us or whatever,
you know,
back in the Berkeley
days in the 60s you know,
he loved nothing more to that to
get a bunch of people in a room,
you know,
pat pass around hash or some
kind of really strong dope,
something that would render
everybody else completely speechless.
They couldn't say anything.
And then he would just regale the first
hours,
you know?
And,
and he was,
and they,
everybody was fascinated and mean.
He was totally coherent.
I mean,
everyone,
you know,
a lot of people,
they smoke a lot of cannabis.
They get quiet,
right?
I'm one of those,
I can't rap on cannabis very well,
but he just,
he could do it and that,
and then he found not only,
you know,
if it works for a bedroom full of people,
I mean,
as you know,
and his Hippie crash pad
though and Telegraph Avenue,
it'll work for audiences
all over the world.
So he turned it into a shtick
and living and thank God he did.
You know,
cause uh,
cause you know,
we have all that out there.
Thank God he did as well because
those recordings and the books and the
lectures,
those experiences changed the entire
direction of a lot of people's lives,
including mine.
Absolutely.
Mine.
The first time I did DMT,
I literally heard him saying
something in the DMT trip.
I'd heard his voice saying,
right.
It was a,
it was just,
it,
his impact I think is,
uh,
it was unbelievably profound.
That ability to relay those thoughts
in this really compelling way.
Really.
I mean,
there,
I can't tell you how many gigs I've
gone on where I had to travel or how to
drive.
And I just listened to
a psychedelic salon,
listened to one of the lectures,
just so compelling and fascinating.
And I think that opens up a completely
new lines of thinking for a lot of people
does.
And you know,
it's interesting the,
the,
you know,
the currency that this has,
he's still out there.
He's achieved this weird kind
of immortality on the dance.
You know what he said when you think
about most of this was early nineties when
he was talking about this,
but you could put a tape on and it's
just as timely as though we're other
yesterday he has this real
feeling for the future and,
and you know,
people come up to me,
a lot of young people
come up to me and said,
I've,
everything I learned,
I learned from Terence Mckenna.
And it was like before
that my life was empty.
And now I understand that.
And you look at these people in,
you say they couldn't have been more than
eight or seven or eight when he was at
the height of his career.
You know,
these people,
some of were in diapers when he was,
you know,
at the height of his career.
So they discovered him later.
Yes.
Somehow.
And he still had this impact.
Well,
it's because it's so compelling.
It's a very completely viral thing.
I mean there's a lot of different people
that have a lot of different ideas,
but they,
whatever,
for whatever reason it wasn't compelling.
I think it's,
uh,
what,
one of the great things
that you're doing in a,
in this book is you're
not sugarcoating anything.
And you know,
the way you described your brother is
with obviously with great love and respect
and admiration,
but also great honesty.
And I think that's,
that's very important.
I think it's,
it's really,
really important for recognizing his
true contributions and recognizing that
like all of us,
he's a human being who was experimenting
with all these ideas and sometimes they
didn't,
they weren't correct.
But that's the only way
you get to those Id.
They have to sort of evolve and form
when you have to keep playing with them.
And in the nature of that and the
nature of like full disclosure,
like what were the,
like if there's any glaring errors
that he had made that people have,
uh,
either repeated or that they
have misinformation because
of these glaring error.
So like what would it be?
What glaring errors did he,
or any errors that like
deserve mention?
I don't know.
I'd have to,
I'd have to think about,
uh,
you know,
I mean,
I,
it is,
it is an effort to depict him.
Honestly.
I hope that people don't,
you know,
I hope that people see that.
You obviously do,
you know,
I'd love to him a great deal.
I respected him a great deal and,
you know,
but we had our rifle Reese
and like all brothers,
you know,
we had our sibling rivalries.
So,
you know,
I mean,
I loved him deeply.
I hated him deeply.
It was,
you know,
that kind of dynamic goes on.
Well,
when you said earlier that he
would say something and you say,
well,
that didn't make any sense and you just
contradicted what you said earlier.
Do you have any like specific,
well he,
he would always respond to the,
you know,
he didn't like me to go to his seminars
so much cause I was the only one that
would ever challenge him.
Everyone else's list name and sort of
slack jawed fascination of his utter in
these completely,
you know,
wild ideas.
And I was the only one who would
really ever get up and say,
well what you've said 20 minutes ago,
it doesn't make any sense and
it contradicts what you say now.
And he would respond with,
well consistency is the
Hobgoblin of small minds.
Describe
what a great quote.
Right?
Oh that's my new message board quote.
Cause his actually I think he was,
I think he was quoting
Walt said that's great.
That was so the thing is terrible.
It's a like to have fun with ideas,
you know.
And in some ways people took
him too seriously and you know,
I mean there was a tendency on the part
of some of his constituents to view him
as a guru or a,
you know,
even a cult figure to a certain extent.
I think he rejected all that.
He didn't want to be a guru.
He did see himself as a girl.
He wanted to stimulate people to,
I think for themselves.
You know,
that was the thing.
Don't believe me,
but okay,
here's a whole bunch
of really crazy ideas.
You know,
there's a great video with a bunch
of images and Terrence's words.
Culture is your enemy.
If you ever,
culture is not your friend.
Yes,
culture's not your
culture's not your friend.
It's very quick.
But it's so,
it's so powerful,
even to this day,
really.
It's,
it's,
it's so powerful that you,
you can listen to it and then
watch CNN and not be affected.
You can reassess,
reassess the impact of modern media.
Yeah,
exactly.
And that's a very,
that's a very valuable
one because in fact,
culture isn't the year friend.
And a lot of what,
uh,
what Terrance's point again,
think for yourself.
Don't believe what anybody tells you.
You know,
and psychedelics are a challenge to that.
All these people that dismiss
the psychedelic experience,
as you rightly point out,
they haven't had it,
you know?
Or if they have,
they didn't pay attention,
you know,
so,
so their opinions count for nothing.
I mean,
they're like the people,
you know,
they're like the
Dutch lens makers who built telescopes,
but you know,
refuse to look through the telescopes
because that was a blast from Isac.
Sure.
It's the same thing.
The Brotherhood of the screaming abyss.
It is available right now.
I have it in my hand.
It was all funded through Kickstarter
because people wanted to get this
information.
You,
you,
you spend a year about a,
we discussed,
we talked about this
about December in 2011.
Right?
This is when we first
were in contact three.
Yeah.
But I actually started,
well,
it took about 18 months to write the book.
I started racing Kickstarter money and uh,
April of 2011,
um,
uh,
it's taken,
you know,
a year and six months to write the book.
Please ladies and gentlemen,
go out and buy this book.
It's fantastic.
Is the Brotherhood of the screaming abyss.
If you have not subscribed to
the psychedelics Alon on Itunes,
go subscribe to that shit
and go and get online.
And there's a millions of Terrence's
lectures and I don't say millions,
but at least a hundred there are available
and they're fantastic and they're
fascinating as is your book.
Thank you very much for coming down here
has been a real treat and an honor and
a pleasure.
And I enjoyed every second of our
conversation and if you ever want to do it
again and we'll push this fucking
thing until they run out of paper,
I should mention where it is.
The easiest way to get it as Amazon,
there's,
there's ebooks at the soft cover.
Books are on Amazon.
You can order them.
Yes.
I got one of those uh,
kindles.
That's awesome.
Just hadn't done it.
Bang.
Well thank you so much.
Pleasure.
Thoroughly enjoyed this.
I did too.
And I think you ate fun.
Yeah,
it really has.
I think you blew a lot
of people's minds too.
I got to go back and re listen
and Google some shit and,
and,
and think about some
things because it was a,
it was,
it was awesome.
It was really a lot of fun.
Thank you very,
very much.
Is there any way people can
give a website if a yes,
we have a website,
brotherhood of the screaming
abyss dom with the,
without the the,
and that actually we're
opening up a new website.
Uh,
it,
it exists,
but we're completely revamping it.
So that's,
that's already online.
And just the other day
I launched a dentist,
j mckenna.com.
There we go.
You're on Twitter.
Are you on Twitter resistant?
Am according to my daughter.
I can't access it.
Oh,
you're one of those guys
know one of those guys,
ladies and gentlemen,
resisting change.
That's right.
Existing chain change.
She,
she'll,
she'll get me onto it.
There's something wrong with a password.
I don't know.
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you very much.
Of course.
Uh,
we will be back this week.
We'll be back tomorrow with the great
honey honey band who will be appearing at
the end of the world show with Doug,
Stan Hope,
Joey Diaz and myself.
That's December 21st,
2012 at the Wiltern theater.
Uh,
like I said,
I think it was,
as of the start of this podcast
was about a hundred tickets left for that.
Uh,
this Thursday night,
uh,
the Improv in Hollywood.
You,
they could watch it live
on Ustream at Ustream.
Dot.
[inaudible]
I will try and do it live.
If not,
it will be recorded to Vimeo.
Abida we're going to try to do a
podcast upstairs and do a comedy show
downstairs.
Just like Joey Diaz would be
their ideas and most likely me,
most likely you.
I think I'm gonna try to
get Ari or Doug's dad hope.
If he's in town,
Dunkin can do it right.
They can do it.
But yeah,
I'll get some people together.
Some quality desk waters if
you want to buy the tee shirts.
Death Squad.
Dot Tv
if you want it.
Oh,
this is,
this is actually,
this is a higher primates show
that's actually based on the,
uh,
based on the [inaudible]
Terrence's stoned ape theory.
It's a chimp with a mushroom in his mouth
and on his left hand is a floating ohm
and the right hand is the
symbol for nuclear energy.
Oh,
that's just lovely.
Come on son with a,
and he's also got a third eye with like
some geometric shit coming out of it.
I'll get you one of these.
Would you rock it?
Oh,
you bet.
Would I take,
if we take a picture of you wearing this,
we'll sell it.
Fuck up a thousand of these bitches.
Okay.
All right.
Listen,
if you ever need anything promoted,
please let us know.
And again,
one more time,
folks.
The Brotherhood of the screaming abyss.
We will be back to Mara with honey,
honey booboo back Tuesday
with Joey Coco Diaz,
and that's our 300th episode.
That's what?
300 episodes.
Oh Shit,
bitches.
So that's a great way to do it.
All right.
We love the shit out of you
guys and we'll see you tomorrow.
Bye Bye.
Hmm.