Hello Freaks,
Rodney and late night style.
It's 10:30 PM here in Los Angeles,
California.
And this episode of the Joe Rogan
experience podcast is brought to you by
audible.com if you've never been
to audible.com and you're a fan of,
uh,
either audio books or podcasts or,
um,
I mean they have old radio shows,
they have the opie and Anthony show.
It's,
it's really one of the best resources
online for audio entertainment,
uh,
more than a hundred thousand different
titles and unmatched selection,
if you will.
Some of the best books that you could get,
including,
um,
uh,
our friend Christopher
Ryan's book sex at dawn.
That's on their rent.
It doesn't it?
I believe so,
but yeah,
there's no one else is reading it though.
That's what it was.
And I told him that was bullshit.
Um,
it's,
it's an awesome resource.
And if you go to audible.com
forward slash Joe,
you will get one free audio book and 30
free days of a audible servers at World
War z.
How was that?
You saw that,
right?
It's really good.
And then not so good.
And not so good together.
He's dreaming.
He's always,
yeah.
I don't want to say too much.
I don't want to spoil it for anybody.
I enjoyed it though.
It's,
it's an enjoyable film.
It's a fucking Hollywood movie,
man.
It's a big Hollywood movie
with Brad Pitt and it's PG 13.
This is a certain amount of
fuckery afoot unavoidable.
Anyway.
Um,
you could buy that book or get,
get that book for free.
If you go to audible.com
forward slash Joe,
you get one free audio book,
30 Free Days of audio surface
from audible audio service.
That's like,
that sounds sexy.
Uh,
we also brought to you by ting.
if you go to rogan.ting.com you will
save $25 either off one of tings,
delicious,
sexy android phones or their service.
If you've never used or heard of Ting,
I'm assuming you haven't
used him otherwise.
I'm just wasting my fucking time here.
Maybe you have,
and maybe you've heard this
podcast a million times.
It's also possible there's no other
way to do this commercial folks.
So I got to plow through.
Um,
with ting is a,
a cell phone company that uses the
sprint backbone so it's all very high end
service and uh,
they tried to do it in a,
like a very reasonable way.
If you want to cancel,
you can cancel at anytime.
You don't have any contracts.
You also get credit on unused service.
If you don't use a certain amount of your,
your service,
they'll drop you down to the next level,
which is really beautiful.
If you lose,
use less than you thought you would take,
drops you down to the next level and
they credit the difference on your next
bill.
It's awesome.
Love Tank,
man.
I used them,
uh,
two days ago at this place that I had my,
eight t iPhone and I couldn't get service
there and he like good data service.
I tried my iPad,
which is Verizon could,
same thing,
pull it out.
My Ting device was used
streaming on their network,
uh,
from the comedy store and it was just,
yeah,
it was doing [inaudible]
has always had sprint.
That's right.
Yeah.
I guess Brent works in places of Verizon.
Doesn't versus me.
No one's perfect at this point in time.
But what they're trying to do at
Ting is just give you an option,
an option that's easier to swallow and
a it's cool company and we enjoy doing
business with them and go to [inaudible]
dot [inaudible] dot com so he shows how
some money you dirty bitch.
We're also boss.
Finally,
this is the last one,
I swear to God and on it
but on it's just a given.
I'll try to make it funny.
Uh,
legal zoom.com is our last sponsor,
a legal zoom.com is a
website that essentially the,
they lay the framework for legal issues
that you would normally have to go to a
lawyer for and pay a lot of money.
Um,
and what legal zoom wants to emphasize
very clearly is there not a law firm.
They provide self help services at your
specific direction and they can also
connect you with an independent attorney
if you need additional guidance.
What they are therefore is to make it
much easier to do things like incorporate
or form an LLC.
You can do it@legalzoom.com for just six.
We're just $99 sex on him.
Nora came sex.
It's cause it's evil legal,
legal stuffs,
eval.
I was thinking six,
six,
six.
It's really nice.
Um,
they can also help you
out with trademarks,
copyrights,
patents.
If you've got a great idea.
You want to protect.
If you're with family,
you can make a well.
Yeah.
You know what?
That's crazy.
None of us have wheels.
I was,
I was talking to my friends
the other day about that.
It's like,
do you have a,
well,
no.
What happens?
Well,
if you live in California,
her parents live in California.
California gets all your shit.
Unless your parents breaking in
your house and steal everything.
Really?
Yeah.
I think it's the foreign,
he gets all your shit.
I might be 100%
no,
but I guess there is a thing
if you don't have a will,
it doesn't automate.
You think it just automatically
goes to your family.
But that's not always the case.
Know what?
I assume there would be a pain in the ass.
The side.
Right.
Especially if you're living with someone,
like if you're living with a
girl or something like that,
that girl has a key to your house and
she knows you're dead and just comes over
and takes your shit.
That's how I know a little,
a little.
She cares about you.
No doubt.
I told me that was mine with you.
Don't say who would be like seven girls.
All budding heads trying
to get in the door.
It has the area and I dare you there.
You just,
there was a humble brag.
No,
no.
Anyways,
we will zoom legal,
zoom.com.
It's a not a law firm.
Remember,
it's a,
they're just trying to help you out.
Um,
and I know there's like some
code and I'm supposed to use,
but of course it's not on this copy.
I think it's just the code name is Rogan.
But let me just make sure you
get all these guys together.
Just make it Rogan for everything.
I know it would be nice,
but it's not that way.
Bet You lose a lot of
people that are just like,
fuck it.
I don't know it.
I'm just whatever.
Yeah.
Probably right?
It's a code name.
Rogan.
Oh,
sorry.
I was writing from my face.
Not only that,
it's highlighted,
um,
you a special discount from
listening to this podcast.
So just enter the code name,
Rogan in the referral box and
checkout for more savings.
That's legal zoom.com.
You always have to say
it like that at the end,
cause that makes you more professional.
If you just go,
okay,
that fucking commercial's over next.
Like a theatrical ending.
I'm surprised you don't have
to do of those like quick,
fast talking things like Tom Segura
on their podcast and I have something,
has something similar at the end.
They have to do one of those nine,
the representative they
really like and it's like,
they really amazing.
It's weird.
We're,
well,
someone's going to tell us what
to actually say on the podcast.
I'm cool with almost anything
that's a reasonable ad.
Right?
It makes sense.
If it's something I would use number,
totally use this.
I've used this as long
as it makes sense to me,
but uh,
that's,
that doesn't make sense.
I'm not reading off any
following Connecticut.
All right.
Dot.
Coms.
The last sponsor,
If you've never been,
go check it out.
Get yourself some fitness equipment.
We've got a lot of new shit.
And if you haven't been into the
website before in to the website,
I don't think you go into a website.
If you go onto a website
and why is it on and not in?
I mean you're not really on it.
What are you doing?
What are you doing when
you go onto a website,
you're going on,
are you going in it?
You're actually entering into it to it,
and then what do you do
to go in or do go on it.
So I'm on the website.
You're on the website,
right?
But why is it on?
Because you're like,
you're on it.
You're facing molecule in though,
were in the website.
You're clicking different pages.
You're like,
you know a book.
Oh,
I'm 50 pages into my book.
Or you're in most websites,
like your pictures and stuff.
So I think that's more
confusing to most people.
Me,
I'm in most weapons.
Most people go to a website,
they're not in it.
Well then what do you mean like on it
to do retarded?
I'm talking to you.
I'm being serious.
I'm never going to stop
saying retarded either.
Fuck you tried to take
weight training now.
How dare you?
That's so hard.
I'm taking retard back.
Just some,
I'm putting more words
back into the vernacular.
You know what I'm talking about?
I'm not talking about diseases,
dummy.
There's the retarded
tranny somewhere going,
oh,
I can't believe you did
the voice on the.com.
Uh,
the new prime bells are in a,
if you haven't seen them there,
this,
we hired this awesome sculptor to draw
these angry chimpanzee faces for a kettle
bells,
uh,
gives you a little bit of extra
motivation when you're working out.
I like to picture that chimp clamping
down on my scrotum with his teeth.
That gets me through the
last four or five Reps.
Uh,
if you've never used kettlebells before,
what they are is in my opinion,
one of the very best strength and
conditioning exercise equipment,
pieces of exercise equipment
that you can buy there,
a Russian invention and it's like
a cannon ball with a handle on it.
And he's swinging him around and
you use your entire body in these,
uh,
these movements.
And I find that that's what really
applies to not just physical,
um,
uh,
sports.
But if just if physical movement,
physical movement,
like I'm picking things up,
the ability to move
stuff around your house,
you,
you gain a balance sort of strength.
Whereas a lot of people,
one of the problems with people who,
uh,
don't use a professional trainer or
don't exactly know what you're doing.
You can develop imbalances,
uh,
with your body because maybe
you use your arms too much.
You don't use your legs enough
or vice verse and it can be,
it can be a mess.
Um,
one of the best things you can
do if you're going to think,
if you're thinking about kettle bells
or any kind of exercise thing is to hire
someone who's really good,
who can show you what to do.
You can learn a lot of stuff from youtube,
but you really should have someone sort
of correcting subtle things in the way
you're moving,
just to make sure that you have good form.
Use a lightweight to begin with,
try to try to be very reasonable about
what you're trying to do and then build,
right.
You're right it down and build.
And when you do do that,
you will get an immense
set sense of satisfaction.
The sense of satisfaction that you get
from pushing your body and getting your
body into a good state
of physical fitness.
It's not just a vanity thing,
it's really good for your health.
And uh,
you know,
I talk about it all the time,
but it's very hard for people to stop
eating donuts and get off the couch.
It's very difficult to choose to have a
salad instead of a shitty cheeseburger.
It's hard.
It's hard to get your shit together.
But if you can get your shit
together even just a little bit,
you'll feel better.
That's a fact.
I lost eight pounds in two weeks.
Have you really?
And that's after quitting smoking,
which is like usually a gain
weight with a few you sexy bitch.
Brian Ryko looking at health,
he's a,
he's cutting back on his coughing.
He's doing all kinds of shit.
Next thing you know it,
but taking t plus,
I need some of that.
Get some,
we got some,
I'll give you some,
I'll bring you some,
a next podcast.
Cool.
All right.
That's the end.
Uh,
use the coordinate Brogan.
That's r o,
g a n and you will save 10%
off any and all supplements.
All right,
my friends,
Rick Doblin is here and we are going
to get to the bottom of some shit.
Please cue the music
experience podcast by night.
He made it.
I did.
Rick Joplin,
who is the head of maps or if you uh,
have never heard whether the,
it's called an acronym where
it's maps or is it yeah,
it is.
Cause it's,
you say it right when you don't say it.
It's an abbreviation.
Is that what it is or which we
tried to figure that out once.
Um,
but it stands for the
multicultural as far it is,
what Google is for it.
But somehow or another,
I'm not quite,
I don't totally have it together.
Multidisciplinary Association
for Psychedelic Studies.
Uh,
you founded this.
Yeah.
And I was surprised to discover it.
It has the most syllables
of any organization in
the nonprofit world for drug reform
really?
Well,
it's a very interesting title,
Multidisciplinary Association
for Psychedelic Studies.
That's what I love about it.
It's like you're coming at it from
a whole bunch of different angles.
So as he just doctors,
it's not just chemists,
it's a whole bunch of human beings.
Yeah.
And I had learned from a previous
nonprofit that when you want to create a
nonprofit,
it's good to try to make
it as broad as possible.
The purpose as you see different
strategic ways to do things.
So I made it multidisciplinary,
which means we could look at psychedelics
from virtually any perspective,
um,
association to mean that it's
publicly supported a nonprofit.
And I had images of,
you know,
tens of thousands of people banding
together to support research in different
areas.
Um,
psychedelic was a big choice,
actually,
whether we should use the word,
whether we should use a different word,
whether we should use a euphemism.
And so I felt like I wanted in this kind
of second coming of psychedelics into
the culture 40 years after the crackdown
that I wanted there to be a certain
transparency.
And so I wanted to use the
word psychedelics so people
knew what I was doing and
I was hoping that we can change the
cultural connotations from what it was in
the 60s of psychedelics,
uh,
rebellion,
dropping out,
uh,
you know,
finding your own sort of
private utopia somewhere,
certain kind of,
um,
not integrated into the culture.
And now that's,
I think the arc of the story
is psychedelics came at a
time when culture wasn't
really ready and brought all
sorts of things to the surface.
And over the last 40 years,
our culture has gotten
ready with hospice centers,
with birthing centers,
with Yoga,
meditation,
all the things with flotation tanks,
all the things that were too
hard to integrate at the time,
death and birth and
just raw emotions that,
and also this globalization and
growing sense of global spirituality.
Now our culture is ready and I think we
can over the next 10 20 years integrates
psychedelics without the
connotation of rebellion.
But to enhance what
we're all doing together.
That's interesting.
I like the use of the word psycho dogs
cause you're owning it and that is what
it's about and you know,
and it's,
it's shouldn't be something that people
are afraid of or afraid of adding to
something because it'll somehow or
another make it silly or make it,
oh psychedelics.
You know,
people want to dismiss it
and they can much easier.
Owning it is,
is I think is very important.
And there's no other
word that's even better.
No.
Hallucinogen was used by the government.
It's like you're fake.
Yes.
I don't like that feeling either.
Hallucinogen always makes me feel like
I'm seeing something that's not there.
Yeah,
that's the idea.
Yeah.
It's not real and don't know
anything about psychedelics.
They imagined like literally like
imagining someone in the room with you and
that guy,
it doesn't really exist.
The word before that in
the 50s was even worse.
It was psycho.
My medic.
Ooh.
Which means it mimic psychosis.
Well it doesn't.
Some people should be careful.
It does.
It does bring in all parts of ourselves.
I think we all have those kind of parts
where they're not really integrated and
it seems extreme and you let the emotions
carry you so that the safe place we
have to be careful I think is true.
But the bad trip,
the difficult challenge,
the death rebirth,
it's in all of us as are
these psychotic states.
I,
I actually had what I felt was probably
the most psychotic or diluted state of
my whole life was doing
LSD and a flotation tank.
Wow.
I can imagine.
So self examine story.
Anyway.
Yeah.
I'm not an LSD person.
I never have tried it because I've never
trusted anybody in the right way to get
it.
But I've done a lot of time in the tank
on especially on high doses of edibles,
edible weed,
that insanely uncomfortable
feeling that you get.
Will you get,
you could examine story about
shit you did in high school.
Like really in depth.
Yeah.
In high school.
Good for yeah.
And the tank does that on its own.
So the tank with that together,
it's,
whew.
Yeah.
Well imagine acid in the tank
would be a similar experience.
Yeah.
Well I grew up reading
John Lilly in the 1971,
actually,
but it was before that was programming
and Meta programming and the human bio
computer.
And that was so technical and complicated.
I had to spend like a whole day on each
page or something that just like cam at
figure this stuff out.
It was so early computer discussion,
discussion and language about and
how the brain in that parades,
yeah.
He was a real pioneer.
Like a real pioneer.
I mean that dude was out there.
Yeah.
But he went too far out and he
wasn't grounded in his last,
uh,
30 years.
We're kind of a sad tragedy,
I would say.
Wasted potential.
Um,
it was that because of ketamine,
cause he got involved
heavily with Ketamine,
which has some pretty disastrous results.
Yeah.
Ketamine is the most addictive of
all the psychedelics and I physically
addictive,
not so much physically,
which,
but more this,
a reliable escape that and
this delusion of superiority.
So was their withdrawal.
I'm not in that same way as heroin or
it's not like physically it's just a
psychological addiction more so
there's a shift in the attitude and,
but what I think was the problem
with John Lilly more than before,
the ketamine was a certain kind of
brilliance that was unbalanced and he was
kind of arrogant and I don't think he
was patient and he was way ahead of his
culture,
you know,
way ahead.
And yet when he saw the crackdown calm,
I think he,
he sort of took this superior position
and just felt like he's not going to work
on a
political struggle or even a scientific
struggle to get these tools back.
He kind of withdrew.
And even from boy he just had this um,
somewhat self destructive aspect too.
I read a lot about him and I
met him and I actually ended up,
I'm trying to do Mtma therapy with him
when it felt like he was really going
downhill from the ketamine
and from cocaine and wow.
Yeah,
that's intense is the
word is kind of my hero.
One of he and Stan Grof,
and I would contrast them that Stan
is doing fantastically as traveling.
The world is totally together and a major
inspiration who is able to integrate
into his life.
Whereas John Lilly was,
you could say arguably as
brilliant but went off the track.
Yeah,
it's,
it is possible.
That's one of the real
issues with anything that
completely alters the way your
mind works is that you could
get into that too much.
She can get into that more than
reality and lose your grip of this one.
Well,
it is reality.
It's just a different view of reality.
Um,
and I think that the grounding part and
what we emphasize in our psychedelic
therapy is that it's the integration
work more than the experience itself that
produces longterm benefits.
So then you can have
these unusual experiences,
but what do you bring back from them
and how do you integrate that into your
daily practices so that it's anchored
so that you can try to get there without
the drug.
It's like this evolution process
where you learn something.
And I've found,
at least for me,
the psychedelics are something that
I can work with through a lifetime,
through a lifespan that I've learned.
Some people say when you get the message,
hang up the phone.
And I felt that there's been different
messages at different stages of my life
and that I'm more able,
although it's still really hard,
you know,
to hear those things,
those the self critical stuff like
what he did in high school or what,
you know,
how you try to hear the message
underneath the criticism.
And um,
I learned that a lot during
an Ibogaine experience.
So I've seen that these experiences
can have these lasting changes,
but that they don't always,
and they don't have to.
And particularly when you had these
experiences that are unbalanced,
the drug starts wearing off and
you haven't come to a new balance.
And during those periods,
the best solution at least is to
continue therapy and do another session.
And that's where people often back off
and they kind of free something in place
that's at such a deep level.
It's hard to get to that deep
level to move it forward.
Yeah,
it's um,
it's,
it's a very personal thing,
isn't it?
Like where you start from to,
you know,
for some folks it's like they've already,
they already have issues
with reality itself.
They have issues with being grounded,
with being calm.
And I mean it's some
people you could just,
you know,
you could just get them high or they
could have some sort of psychedelic
experience and they would be able to
assimilate it into their life and they
would benefit from it almost immediately.
Whereas other folks almost needed to be.
I think education is one of the big
ones that were really lacking in this
country when it comes to these things.
And the word Shaman is such a,
such a loaded word
because it's like healer,
you know,
when someone says their healer,
all of a sudden you,
oh,
okay,
you know,
what,
what other dumb shit or
you're going to say next,
you know,
are hollow therapeutic approaches based
on the idea that there's an inner healer
and it's the support that we provide
to help people heal themselves.
So there's a power dynamic
often in shamanism where
sometimes the shaman is even
the only one that does the
drug and then heels you.
Hmm.
It's not teaching you how to heal yourself
so that we have this idea that like
the body heals itself.
If you get a cut that the psyche has
these self healing mechanisms and brings
things kind of to the surface so that
it's not so much reality and psychedelic
state.
It's almost like reality and more reality.
And we know that from a Fmri brain
scan studies that were recently done in
England with Psilocybin,
that what it does in the
brain is different than what
we had been thinking and
we had been thinking that
it makes the brain speed up,
that that you know,
some things work even faster that,
that your perceptions are going.
And actually what it does is it
makes parts of the brain slow down,
but it's the filtering parts of the
brain so that we have enormous volume of
perceptions coming to us at any one time.
And that's kind of what you can see in
the tank to that when you start quieting
everything down,
you can really,
you know,
think in different ways.
But we have this enormous amount of
information and we only narrow and look at
some of it what we need
to do either for survival,
for we focus and the controlling the
filtering parts of the brain are what
psilocybin slows down so
that they work less well.
So you get more of a flood
of what's already there.
What is the mechanism,
the filtering parts of the brand.
When you say the filter
in parts of the brand,
what,
what are those?
Um,
they're generally linkedin,
what's called the default network,
the default mode network.
There's um,
and here becomes kind of a practical
side of the work that I do,
which is basically trying to develop
a psychedelic drugs into prescription
medicines and marijuana.
So from the FDAS point of view,
um,
you have to show something
safe and efficacious,
but you don't have to
explain how it works.
So therefore,
I haven't really focused on that.
So,
I don't know the answer
to your question because,
um,
it's neuroscience and I don't need
neuroscience to know the exact quadrants,
the brain.
So I've kind
of got,
um,
people I work with and other people I
rely on another scientist to do that part.
It helps if you have an
explanatory mechanism,
but at the same time it's not necessary.
So what I've done is tried to be
strategic and tried to focus on the stuff
that's essential to move
the culture forward,
to create legal context for psychedelics
to show that they can be used
responsibly.
Why is asking more for my own edification?
I wish I could answer you.
I always,
one of the,
I think I read that very study
about quieting areas of mine.
I thought it was really
fascinating and um,
I attributed it to uh,
the,
the idea being that we
are filled with noise.
You know,
that our mind is filled with noise.
Our mind is filled with concentrating
on a bunch of shit that's not really
important and that that gets shut off
and then you can sort of tune in to
whatever the fuck it is
that you took and uh,
whatever it is that you took
that's doing something and yeah,
I don't see it so much.
That stuff is not important,
but it's not as important.
I mean,
you need to do certain things
to get through the day,
so you need to have a narrower focus.
Maybe not important.
Wasn't even what I should've said.
It's just,
it's not that it's unimportant,
it's just sometimes there are things in
your life that aren't that important,
but they take primary focus,
they take center stage,
you know,
whether it's an argument that we,
you got with a friend over almost nothing.
Something that can be addressed,
you know,
really easily and quickly probably.
But whatever it is,
it's bothering you.
Should I say something because I really
feel like I'm being slighted and no fuck
with you all day until you actually
have the conversation with the person.
And it can be a million other things.
Could it be financial
issues that you have?
Could be something's wrong with your
house and you have to pay to get it fixed.
And all these things just constantly
chip away at your ability to focus on the
now and to enjoy,
uh,
just to enjoy the
experience of life itself.
Yeah.
I've never really felt comfortable kind
of meditating to try to let all those
things go because I get into this state
where I have this idea of something
should I do,
I should do.
And I think those things that you
mentioned are really important.
How you relate to your friends.
Those are words,
those are the most
important things of life.
Not that at least important,
but I've always felt like when I'm,
if I were to be meditating,
this idea will come up and I'm
supposed to just let it go.
And I thought,
why don't I just do it?
I'm more outer focused in,
for me,
the,
uh,
jogging and being stoned
are like meditation.
Oh,
it's definitely the meditation.
Yeah.
Jogging stone is a trip.
It's very different than,
than just exercising.
Yeah.
Fight.
I have,
but I think that this idea of creating
a space like in the tank or like a
therapeutic setting where you're not
paying attention to all those daily things
where you can sink deeper to,
um,
other questions of life that
that is really important.
You have to kind of consciously
create a space for that.
Yeah.
The,
the things that always up in trips,
um,
for me that they're,
the,
the uncomfortable things are always
things that I really should be working on
anyway.
It's always like,
maybe I've hit an imbalance and I focus
too much on this and not enough on that
or,
or whatever it is.
Those,
those moments where it hits you,
it's like you should've known that anyway.
And if you,
if you knew,
if you were living in a harmonious way,
we wouldn't have to tell you this.
All right,
so get it over with.
Figure that out.
And every trip that I've had that,
that,
where that's happened,
they've only been a few of
them that are really liberal,
like super uncomfortable,
just really bad.
But those always,
I benefited from those,
every one of them.
Now?
What do you mean by bad?
I don't mean bad.
Uh,
I mean,
um,
uncomfortable like
especially with the eating,
eating marijuana,
the eating marijuana thing.
Yeah.
A lot of folks do not give that the proper
respect and that's why they freak out
and call the cops.
If I'm sure you heard the great video of
the police officers who stole marijuana
from someone they pulled over and then
made pot brownies and then got so high
they panicked and called the police.
They call the ambulance,
call the ambulance.
He was saying right there.
Have you heard that before,
Brian?
Yeah,
we played it on here.
That's right.
He played it.
Oh sure.
Play it just for the goof.
Cause it's fucking ridiculous.
These poor people,
but they didn't know these,
these dirty cops is that marijuana
and when it's processed by your liver,
when you eat it,
it's produces something called 11 hydroxy
metabolite and incredibly psychoactive
material.
It's not like the THC high at all.
It's a totally different
experience in much stronger.
And that's why a lot of people
think that like the aide cookie,
that it was laced like,
oh my God.
So when he lays this was something,
I know you're taking a
totally different drug.
Yeah.
We do harm reduction
at festivals to try to,
uh,
imagine a post prohibition world.
So at burning man,
boom,
other festivals where we provide,
um,
an organized teams of therapists and
others that work with people that have
difficult trips and people at the most
people come sometimes is for eating too
much marijuana.
Yeah.
People don't realize how this,
this easily can be as strong
as any psychedelic g tech
and that's not bullshit.
And listen to these poor folks
calling nine one one call.
You will hear,
tell him where the
information had been removed.
Boy,
Michael.
Yeah.
Can you please send rescue?
I think I'm having an
overdose and so is my wife.
Okay.
You and your wife?
Yeah.
Overdose of what?
Marijuana.
I don't know if they had something in it.
Oh,
okay.
The police and rescue.
Okay.
How old are you?
I'm 28.
29 years old.
And my wife is,
uh,
25th.
Please calm 20 sec.
Yes,
please.
Hey,
I think paint also.
What have you guys been
drinking tonight too?
No,
that's it.
Is there any weapons in your house?
No.
Please come.
Okay.
Are you guys like you guys have fever?
No,
I'm just,
I think we're dying.
Oh,
how much did you guys have?
A,
I dunno.
We made brownies and I take what dad?
I really do.
Okay.
At.
Well,
how much should you put your mounties?
I don't know.
I,
I hit him back.
Um,
my wife and I did too,
but come here.
Okay.
She's on,
she's on the living room ground,
right?
Yeah.
Barely breathing.
I think so.
Okay.
Pardon?
Did I?
Yeah,
I could feel it.
She's laying right down in front of me.
Time is going by really,
really,
really slow.
Pardon?
Yeah.
How much did you buy
this?
Please send rescue.
It's probably like a quarter ounce total.
Yeah,
we did.
Okay.
Why is that funny?
I'll tell you why.
It's funny cause he can't die from it.
The only way pots going to kill you is
if you take 25 pounds and he dropped it
off of a CIA drug plain
and it lands in your head.
That's how pots going to kill you.
You could probably get a heart attack.
A good movie could kill
you if that's the case.
You Pussy.
Yeah.
The other question is why did they
think they would die and it's not just
because their heart was racing or things
like that that the judgment day it's,
well it's like these feel during parts
of the brain that the pie when you eat it
like that,
it's kind of very powerful.
It is like tripping code and
so your sense of who you are.
He was pretty logical.
He was pretty good at
answering the questions.
He had some problems.
So some of that,
but I think people confuse ego
death with physical death and ego,
death of letting go of who your narrow
sense of who you are and opening up into
something very scary.
And so people have defenses
and they converted into,
I think I'm dying because
it feels like that you,
that you is dying in a way.
That's interesting.
But I mean,
don't you think also he's just fucking
panicking and thinking that he overdosed
on a drug and just shitting his pants?
I can maybe not even an ego death.
Just absolute fear of the fact that you
don't know what the hell was in there
and you,
well,
he knows he made it.
It was pot.
He knew what it was.
He just got taken by
surprise how strong it was.
But he said he doesn't know
if there's anything in it.
Well,
it's what you said right before,
as people start thinking it was
laced with something that it's not.
So,
I mean,
I think the guy thought he was dying.
Well,
I thought I was dying on
weed before I caught it.
Really physically if that you're dying.
Yeah,
it'd be because I had
something in my life,
I always thought it had
something wrong with my heart,
you know,
so I had,
uh,
like as a kid would pass out
and black out and just
like fall to the ground.
I had to take the stress test
as like an eight year old kid.
Like,
you know,
taking,
running on the treadmill and stuff.
No,
they could never find out what happened,
you know,
then it would happen again
like four years later.
So like growing up,
I always had this thing like,
all right,
I have a bad Boone heart type shit.
Like it's,
it's like it's a broken heart or there's
something with a valve that they just
haven't detected.
And so when I smoked too much weed,
I immediately thought I
felt my heart and I'm like,
all right,
my heart is fucked up.
So I,
it wasn't that the weed was killing me,
but it might be doing something to what
I already thought I had a problem with
my heart already,
you know,
type thing.
In other words,
you were panicking like a little bitch.
Yeah.
When you thought you were going to die.
When you hear,
when you feel your heart double beat,
you know when it just like bup up,
up,
pump,
you know that starts doing shit like that.
You certainly mind fuck yourself.
Yeah.
You know,
I didn't know you had that thing though.
I didn't know that you blacked out.
I blacked out five times in my life.
Wow.
You know,
and they've tried everything.
They've done tons of tests.
You know,
it's only been like the
last maybe five years.
I just don't give a
shit about that anymore.
You know?
I don't know what happens and I don't
ever get panic attacks anymore anxiety
anymore.
It just went away.
I mean I've been using a lot Molly lately,
so maybe that's why
you,
you probably look good
evidence for my therapy.
I believe in that a million
times over storms or anything,
especially when you're with a loved one
and there's definitely something minute.
I don't think over,
I don't think it's a
competition or a race.
I think they all have
their own little impact.
We're talking about psychedelic medicine,
psychedelic spirituality,
and it's the whole range of drugs at
different times at different places.
But yeah,
we did it.
The other thing about
psychedelics is it can,
there's a lot of states that can be
achieved naturally and I think in the
pursuit of a psychedelics as a discipline,
as,
as something just to
truly legitimately study.
I think one of the things that they're
going to open up is what yoga does to the
body.
Yeah.
Yoga does something,
they're intense.
Come on Brian Class,
stop it.
Get it,
get.
If you,
if you take a really strong yoga
class and you get through it,
you feel like your high
yeah.
Yeah.
And I,
I am aware of friends,
longterm yoga practitioners,
long term meditators who have found
that it's not either or that you can,
when you're practiced in these ways too,
that you can have a
psychedelic experience.
You can go to a deeper
place and then you can work,
you have a better sense of where you
want to be and you can work sometimes for
years to grounded and integrated.
And it's,
it's this flow back and forth.
So I think the overreliance
on psychedelics can prove
to be harmful because
you're not doing the
integration or with John Lilly,
you're escaping,
but the idea that you'll
stay somehow or other,
you know,
pure and do things all on your own,
there's a certain kind of,
um,
slowness or egotism about that.
It's,
it's not,
uh,
inappropriate to admit sometimes
that we need physical catalysts.
We need help.
We need tools.
Sometimes our defenses are so strong.
No,
I don't think it's an either or situation.
I don't think there's anything we,
for whatever reason,
we have this idea in our head that
taking something to get somewhere as a
weakness.
You know,
there's a lot of people that believe that,
that taking a drug to
achieve a state like,
oh,
you can't deal with reality.
You're weak,
you know?
Yup.
There is that.
But then you switch it to cars.
Like you'd take a car to get psych
suck a plane and a car to get here.
Yeah.
No,
you could definitely look at it that way.
I just think the,
the idea is very strange
when we know that,
look,
our,
our bodies are these weird biological
machines that were constantly feeding
different things too.
We're constantly giving a
different kinds of nutrients.
We experiment with the diets,
we experiment in our carbohydrate
balance and our protein,
but we experiment with all
these different things.
But when it comes to taking a plant,
especially something like mushrooms sets,
we've documented many thousands of years
of use and to decide all of a sudden
that this is a weakness and that this is,
you know,
just unnecessary in society as if
our society is perfect in every way.
And you know,
yeah,
no need for self examination here at all.
Yeah,
well we're actually an anomaly as far
as society goes cause most of them have,
uh,
the use of drugs,
the use of altered states in
some kind of sanctioned manner.
It's repressed and prohibited
throughout our lifetimes.
We kind of have a sense that maybe that's
the way it's been large parts of human
history,
but it's not been that way.
They're encased in a religious rituals
or different kind of cultural context.
But they're not prohibited
and they're respected.
And I think that's where
we've lost touch with that.
And there's so much coming from people
finding it on their own through various
methods that the culture is changing.
I think it's definitely changing.
And I think what's really crazy is
that the people who are suppressing
psychedelics,
that people who seek to suppressant are
the ones need them more than anybody.
Well exactly.
So our study right now that we're doing,
and again the with Mtma for
posttraumatic stress disorder,
I owe it to the point to Brian,
you're the poster boy kid revelations,
just the first one for tonight.
Um,
so we're working with veterans and then
we've also expanded it now to work with
firefighters and also
with police officers.
And I had pretty much given up hope about
getting a police officer actually to
volunteer.
So we've had 15 people out of 24
the 15th is going through screening.
The first 11 we're 11 of them were vets
and were firefighters and now we have
the first police officer that
is going through screening.
So the people that are repressing it in
some ways they do need it the most and
how to help them relax about it,
at least to let others
or to explore themselves.
But at the same time I've been trying
to get my father and mother to smoke pot
since I was 20 years old and
they've never once done it,
but they're totally
supportive of what I do.
They think it's a tremendous,
but they will not.
There was one time when my mother had um,
uh,
some pain.
She had fallen down in,
in her leg,
was really in pain and she said she would
try marijuana for pain and I got home
like a week later because
she's in a different city
and she said then she wasn't
in enough pain anymore.
Oh Wow.
I was too slow for a mom.
Well,
you know,
there's a lot of folks that are a
prisoner to that propaganda that was just
really shot home from the 30s on.
It's,
yeah,
it's a pretty incredible feat when you
stop and think about the effectiveness of
marijuana and not just for people like
as far as like a a drug and not just for
its psychoactive properties,
but just the plant hemp itself.
Just all the amazing benefits
it has for as far as nutrition,
construction methods,
making paper and clothes and
all these different things.
The fact that somehow none of that kept
that from the public and kept it under
wraps and kept the from really
from the average person's database.
Most people,
if you ask him about
marijuana being illegal,
what about hemp?
Oh,
it's isn't the same thing.
Like what does that mean?
People don't even know
what the fuck can't,
is
the,
what they should know is that the largest
hemp importing country in the world is
the United States and the largest hemp x
sporting country in the world is China.
So why is that?
Why we've kept it narrow legal.
We're inputting it,
but relating other people grow it.
It's incredible.
But that's,
that's all the largest producer of,
of,
of pharmaceutical drugs is United States.
That's why,
and that's really what it boils down to.
The pharmaceutical drugs without a doubt
don't want marijuana to become legal.
And one of the doorways from
marijuana to become legal is him.
His people.
Figuring out how incredibly effective
hemp is for so many things that we use
other stuff for besides the
psychoactive properties.
Just it's a makes it
fantastic protein powder.
My,
the company that I'm involved with on it,
my friend Aubrey and I,
we,
when we was first you met
Aubrey up in San Francisco,
when we first started
talking about a Hamp,
we,
we thought,
well maybe we could get a farm
in this country and you know,
grow this hemp hemp seed and then use
it for the protein powder completely.
Non-Psychoactive when we found
out you can't even do that.
Like even though hemp is legal,
I didn't know that.
They literally can't be
grown in the United States.
We buy it all from Canada.
Yeah.
One of the,
um,
people on maps as board of
directors is David Bronner.
And so from Bronner soaps,
his grandfather started and he's been
very active in that hemp hemp oil soap.
They use hemp oil and writing like a
crazy person documentary on Netflix about
him.
Yeah.
Oh really?
What's it called?
I think it's called Doctor Bronner's.
Magic soap.
I have a friend,
so I'll use 80 bravo.
That's all he uses forever.
Well,
David and his brother Mike
have built this business from,
their father was kind of obsessed.
They are their grandfather
and they knew that.
So they took this business over when it
was really fragmented and like a million
or two a year in sales and they've
built it up to over 50 million,
50 million.
And they in sales not just hope at
other products and they don't advertise,
they don't advertise.
What they do is they
do now Bronner's soap,
kill it,
go get it.
Well,
here's your local.
What they do is a social
justice illegally activism.
They do,
um,
they focus on fair trade and other things.
But what David did about four months ago
or five months ago is he constructed a
cage,
a metal cage,
and he had someone drop it off with him
inside it in front of the White House
right across the street.
And he was processing hemp plants.
He had gotten real hemp seeds.
He had grown it in the United States
and he was processing it into hemp oil.
And he did this as a protest.
And the cage was to prevent the police
to slow them down while they tried to
stop them from doing it.
And he actually got convicted
and it had to do public service.
But what he was trying
to show is that hemp,
which can be a food,
which can be any number of different
things and can be grown in the United
States,
was a crime.
That,
and just making it into hemp oil to put
on his bread was enough to put him in
jail and to give them,
uh,
penalties.
It doesn't make any sense and it's
insane that it continues to go on.
It's one of those weird aspects of our
society where you look at it and you go,
well,
there's gotta be a reason.
Let's,
so let's search for a reason.
And you look for a reason and
it literally doesn't exist.
I think there are real strong reasons
that go really deep that make us easy to
miss them.
But I think they're the natural fear
that each of us has for when our social
controls are relaxed,
that will become a
whatever we will become.
It's what you talked
about even in the tent,
when the t the flotation tank,
when things come up,
you know,
it's just people are scared
of the compromises that
they've had to make to live
in society and have their basic urges
and what happens when they're not in
control.
And that's what these drugs represent.
And the 60s also represented not only
these people that let themselves get out
of control,
then they want to leave and drop out
and then they want to change things.
And it,
it was a difficult,
people are scared of their own.
I feel it in myself that
I'm scared sometimes of,
uh,
you know,
my deep desires or you know,
oh,
that you just created a meme,
sir,
too.
Right?
I feel like I'm scared of my deep desire.
I didn't need to see here's some
1970s music playing over that.
Yeah.
So I think that's a big part.
Speaking of that,
Jim Kelly died today,
man.
The great karate master,
Jan,
Jamie clued me on that.
A dude from enter the
dragon breast of pieced.
Mr. Kelly.
Sorry.
Yes,
no,
no.
That's important to think
about how short our time is.
It is,
right.
It really is.
That's why we got to get all these anti,
we'd people high or at least
help them see more human rights,
more freedom.
Why should they tell us what to do?
And I think the other part of it is that
the drug laws have been used for social
repression against minorities and
either Mexicans or blacks or you know,
hippies and that letting loose
of that avenue of control.
There's in the power system.
And I think what we're needing
to do to integrate these things,
to legalize marijuana,
to legalize gay marriage,
these kinds of things where people see
it's not going to tear apart the fabrics
of society,
that people can make contributions and
that people can also learn to deal with
their deep desire so that
they're not so scared of him.
Yeah.
We've made some massive headway
as a culture because of that.
Um,
the,
the gay marriage thing,
the fact that I'm Idaho
got it before California,
that that hurt,
that really hurt.
There was like,
how's how dumb you fucks.
And the,
the,
the name of the bill that eliminated the
ability for gay people to get married,
the marriage,
but it was it fencing,
defensive marriage act.
Oh God.
How about if you really
want to defend marriage?
I'll be stopped.
People from getting divorced.
See how that works out.
You really want to defend marriage.
Tell people they have to say together.
That should be a t shirt
right there for real.
You want to defend marriage.
Marriage is ridiculous.
This is coming from a
person who's married.
It's a stupid idea.
It's a legal contract that you signed
with another human being and then you're
going to bring in a bunch of other people
if it doesn't work out and they get to
dictate where your
money and property goes,
so why don't you do it?
Because I love her.
She's an awesome person and it makes
her feel better and I don't give a shit.
We have children together
and I'm not going anywhere.
So I actually love being married to her.
I love her as a human being.
She's a great person,
but the whole involving the
legal system part of it,
it's so dumb.
It's just so ridiculously dumb.
It doesn't make any sense to me.
And I,
I understand completely the need for
child support and for some folks needed to
be written in stone what they have
to pay and things along those lines.
But you know,
I'm not that person and I,
I don't,
I don't think that I need to be regulated,
you know,
if I've done nothing wrong,
I don't think I need to be signed up to
some system to prove that a relationship
that I'm in is valuable to me.
It just,
it seems stupid.
It's almost seems like it's,
if you,
if you trust someone,
it's like,
I do trust you.
I'm going to need that shit on paper.
It's like,
I wonder,
since we're assertive male
and more positions of power,
maybe marriage often is
to more protect the woman.
Oh,
maybe.
I mean,
I,
I certainly think that
there's something to that,
you know,
a woman wants to feel more secure.
I've heard women say that.
I've heard women,
um,
complete,
like being completely outside of them,
eavesdropping in on a conversation
and a women were talking about,
you know,
I felt like much more secure
in the marriage once or in
the relationship once we
were married.
It doesn't make any sense,
but we were together for 10 years,
but once we got married that I felt
like it was real and then I could relax.
I had that part of my,
you know,
but that's their own social hangup,
you know?
I think it's just some,
did Sandra Bullock movie shit any
different after you got married?
Absolutely not.
I felt like a,
I did something that,
I always thought it was ridiculous.
Well,
you know,
it's like you,
the idea behind it of,
of committing to a person and
then giving your all to a person,
that's all beautiful.
The,
the,
the real problem with anything where it's
two people is who knows what those two
people are going to be
like five years from now,
who knows what they're gonna
be like 10 years from now.
And I've seen it and it's ugly.
I've seen people that got along great
and then the one person took a left,
the other person took a right and they're
stuck in the same house together and
they don't like each other anymore.
And it gets really gross.
And then when they have to separate,
I've seen what happens when they use
the legal system against each other.
I mean,
I wrote a whole bit about it because
I saw my friend who had to pay for his
wife's lawyer.
He was,
they were going to war and he had
to pay for the enemy's general.
Right.
I think it's ridiculous.
I think the idea that if you,
uh,
you know,
if you're taking care of the woman,
you should pay some form of alimony.
Yeah,
definitely the child support.
Yes,
definitely.
You know,
you split property that you
got when you were together.
I'm for that,
I'm for all that,
what I'm not for is this gross system
where the lawyers play off of each other
and try to stretch things out because
that's how they make the most money where
they asked for outrageous amounts so
that you come back with like a little bit
less and it becomes this mad hustle.
And like I said,
I am in no way saying that I'm not,
I'm not pro relationship,
but I've watched someone's life
fall apart because of a bad divorce.
Whereas if they just broke up,
it would be cool.
But she dragged him through the mud
legally for like a year and a half,
two years,
emptied his bank account
and it was horrific,
like targeted him.
And that can happen you,
when you're legally attached to someone,
it just,
whereas you could be like,
okay,
we're broken up.
Right.
Well,
I don't want to be with you anymore.
You don't want to be with me anymore.
So we'll just go our separate ways.
No.
Well or if you had the lord,
that's what was even squirrelier.
There's not even any kids involved.
So why do you have to pay for this person
when you described that
somebody takes left,
the other person takes the right.
Yeah.
I think that when we started tying to
think about Mtma for couples therapy,
cause that's one of the main people
reason people use it is for relationships.
And there's um,
but not all relationships
should stay together.
So trying to do a study,
a scientific study of,
of MDA with couples.
If you decide that your success
is how many of them stay married,
that's not necessarily
the smartest thing to do.
So what we felt was that it would be,
if they make a mutual decision and
whatever that decision happens to be,
if it can be,
they stayed together,
they split up.
If there's some kind
of mutuality about it.
If the MTMA helps them to listen to each
other and to communicate and they can
make a mutual decision,
that would be considered a success.
But we haven't gone forward with that
research because politically having a
difficult relationship is not a disease
and we need to work in a disease context
so that we can get prescription approval
to have legal access in a medical
context.
So you,
that's a real issue.
You know that was the
issue with Modafinil.
Do you know what that is?
The,
that's one of my whole vigil use agile.
I'm using that right now.
I am.
I might as well.
That's that shit that I've given you.
This stuff keeps you awake.
Yes.
Well,
Tim Ferris,
who I respect very highly,
I had a very interesting point about it.
He said,
I don't believe there's any biological
free lunch and that's why he doesn't,
he didn't even put it in the four hour,
whatever for our body because he was
worried that people would just start
chewing them like candy.
Well,
I happened to know somebody
that uses it for narcolepsy.
He uses a twice a day for about,
uh,
you know,
that's what I'm here to say.
The reason why it's
prescribed for narcolepsy has,
because they initially created it for
performance enhancing purposes and then
the government's like,
um,
you can't just like say I
want my brain to work better.
Like you have to have a disease so they
go narcolepsy and that's how it got
approved.
Right.
But it was probably,
it works for narcolepsy.
Okay.
And I got to use it.
People falling asleep all the time.
They're conking out with this stuff.
Does it keep you awake?
Yeah,
but it doesn't,
it's pretty transparent.
It doesn't add a lot of other things.
So it's very weird.
The military is actually shifting towards,
towards it,
away from speed and amphetamines.
Oh,
that's smart.
Yeah.
Speed fucks you up and makes you do shitty
things and the next you make terrible
decisions.
Poor decision making capabilities.
And that's worse than
alcohol and a lot of ways.
Yeah.
And it's a Modafinil is also for jet lag,
for shift work.
And,
uh,
you know,
the only reason I took it tonight is
because I was caught in the gay pride
parade for Francisco
couldn't get out of town.
They got you.
And so I just wanted to,
um,
how easy is it to get
prescribed something like that?
Because as an example,
I,
I had just got off cigarettes.
I wake up,
you know,
I could barely get out of bed.
Whole Day is
just like I can,
I just lay back down.
I take one fourth of a,
an Adderall and 20 minutes
later I'm just like,
how much work can I do?
And I can,
oh my gosh,
my brain's like,
that's a lie.
And it's working.
That's,
but that's a completely
different sort of experience.
But for something like,
like that,
it's,
it's also given to people
that have like weird shifts,
you know,
jobs,
entertainers and stuff.
You know,
a lot of times I'm talking too much.
I can get your prescription.
Oh,
okay.
You go to a doctor tell you,
don't worry.
I got a doctor.
Okay.
Jesus.
No,
my main person I guess.
Is it,
is it something that's hard to know?
I know people who've done it.
Good.
A doctor.
I'm not feeling so good.
I'm sleepy.
I think
this is something called new vigil.
I think maybe that'll help me.
Boom,
Bang,
boom.
Shut.
Bam.
You're out the door with description.
We're trying to give out prescriptions,
man.
Doctors are trying to
give you prescriptions.
Do you know that?
You want to hear something fucking crazy.
There was something in Montana the,
they recently released where Montana
has x amount of people living in it.
One fourth of them around oxycontin's
no,
fucking crazy.
That is,
I need to verify that because
someone told me that today.
Uh,
oxycontin's
I guess I just never tried to go
get prescription medicine ever.
Well
I think there's a time when,
uh,
if it's,
um,
possibly helpful that
it can be okay to do it.
I think I prefer trying to do
things on my own without it.
And then only if it's,
um,
beyond my capabilities or
something that I think enhances it.
So I think the,
uh,
the idea of a jet lag shift,
you doctors do want you to have a,
um,
relationship to what it was approved for.
But around 40% of the prescriptions
in America are called off label.
We're doctors prescribe it for things
that it's not been approved for.
Oh.
And that cannot be stopped.
That's not bad.
What's some of the things that
this drug is used off label,
I guess?
Well,
I think it's a
off label.
People are just taking it for
performance enhancing substance reasons.
That's why they're doing it.
That's the big reason that I always here.
And the big diseases narcotic.
Yeah.
And the concern is that,
um,
you know,
if people have performance
enhancing drugs,
but they're willing to hurt themselves
in order to do it because there's no free
lunch.
But with modafinil there,
there are ranges of use of certain drugs
where it doesn't seem like there are
harmful constant.
Well,
it Montana,
a gazette,
the billings gazette is
the one that printed this.
It's,
it is one out of four
that's unfucking believable.
Montana has just under
a million residents.
One out of four have an
oxycontin prescription.
It's incredible.
Huh?
Is that pain?
I wonder how they,
listen.
I have,
I've gone in for operations and they
gave me a all kinds of shit that I didn't
tank,
but they'll,
they'll give you whatever
you need for pain.
Even did you tell him it's nothing I went
into to get a deviated septum and uh,
they,
it's kind of uncomfortable thing,
stuff your nose and they crack
it and break it and widen it.
I had a really fucked up
septum and it was kind of,
I literally,
my nose was useless for most of my
life until I had this operation.
But my doctor gave me like two
different kinds of pain killers and I,
and I was like,
this doesn't even hurt though.
He's like,
well it's going to probably tonight,
tonight you're probably going
to be in significant pain.
Never came.
It was like,
it was weird.
I had this stuffed,
stuffed up my nose,
but there was no pain.
But meanwhile,
if you're a person is easily addictive
and you take one of those and you go,
God damn it,
I can't sleep.
And then you take two more of those.
And the next thing I know,
you're going to another doctor
and telling me you're in pain.
You get a second prescription
and you're off to the races.
Yeah.
We had one of the veterans and our,
uh,
PTSD study,
um,
took one dose,
dropped out of the study and under the
influence of this medium dose of Mtma,
um,
he started feeling that
he was taking pain meds,
not just for the pain,
but he was kind of getting addicted,
depended on them and he didn't
want to do that anymore.
We're war wounds,
things like that.
And so he decided that he didn't need
the pain meds anymore and he also felt
like he had come to terms with the issues
that had caused him to be suffering
from post traumatic stress disorder,
that he accepted these things and that
he could go forward without a PTSD.
And so he dropped out of the study,
but we said,
we want to ask you at two months,
in 12 months,
our followups,
how you're doing.
And his PTSD was still gone after a year.
That's amazing.
The PTSD,
um,
use,
uh,
the use of Mtma for PTSD is a,
one of the ones that was
discussed recently by this,
a soldier who wrote this very eloquent
letter and then committed suicide when he
was talking about the Dea [inaudible]
letter on the airplane here.
Yeah,
I assumed that it was,
when he was talking about,
it's a big,
big issue with,
uh,
with veterans.
I assumed he was talking about marijuana,
what can I do as well?
But I thought it was Mtma probably both,
but the MDM main one has been discussed
a lot by friends that I have that have
been in the military.
They know it helps and
they want to know about it.
You know,
I heard it's the one where you hear a lot
of people going through very traumatic
things and then they get over it.
They're okay,
they understand it and
accept it and that's it.
Yeah,
they've heard about it.
Anyway,
we had a meeting in the Pentagon where
we are trying to get formal cooperation
and they expressed that their biggest
fear was that if they were to cooperate on
an MDA study,
that the word would get
out Moreso than before.
And that a lot of people
who were in the military,
who only a small number of them
will get into clinical studies,
that they would go out on their own and
get stuff that was impure or not in s or
pure but not in a safe place and that
there that would cause more harm.
And they said that
shouldn't stop the research,
but that that was the concern and
what we're thinking of saying it,
what would we did say is that the word
is getting out and we've had articles in
Stars and Stripes and the Marine Corps
times and military.com about the results
of our study.
I think they owed to the soldiers.
And I think that if they wanted to start
a Kickstarter to have MTMA clinics pop
up with a legitimate stuff,
government approved and tested
all throughout the country,
it would,
it could be user funded.
We are going to do that
with the Indiegogo.
Kickstarter doesn't take medical shows
but Indeigogo does and we are going to
try to do it to crowdsource a
support for the study with veterans,
firefighters and police officers.
Great idea.
The thing about the psychedelics so
that people understand what we're really
talking about with the psychedelic
Madison is it's only used a few times.
It's not like the drugs that we were
talking about that people get prescribed
every day or several times a day.
It's only part of a psychotherapeutic
process with more non drug psychotherapy
sessions and what they
can integrate from it.
So our three and a half
month program for Ptsd,
uh,
treatment includes only
three days of Mtma.
I think people need to understand that
all these things are tools that have been
denied us.
And uh,
that deal,
I used to joke about it that
like marijuana is like a hammer.
You know,
you could,
you could hammer nails with it or you
could just hit yourself with a dick if
you're fucking crazy,
right?
Like just cause you have a tool doesn't
mean you're going to use it properly.
And when you smoke too much
pot and freak out and when you,
you know,
take acid and jump off a roof.
Yes you've done it improperly,
but you're dealing with this incredibly
complex thing that is really not being
explained to the general public.
The dabbling in psychedelics is all sort
of done with anecdotal evidence passed
on by friends or books that
you've read or all the,
all these,
you know and it's
unnecessary at this point.
We have enough information.
There's enough data.
There's enough online@maps.org
yeah,
add mass that are we,
we are doing drug development in the open.
We publish our protocols,
we publish our data,
we publish all of our timelines of ours,
relationships with regulatory.
We publish our review of the literature.
We have a treatment manual that describes
what the therapy component is that
they are with our adherence criteria.
We're trying to make the all of it
publicly available and at the same time
that's the pressure that's coming on
the pharmaceutical companies actually to
release more of their data.
But the important thing is that the
DEA is not stopping MTMA research.
The FDA is not stopping.
We are able to do psychedelic research
in the United States and most countries
of the world where we want to.
We have studies right now in Israel,
Switzerland,
Canada,
and we've done,
I began research in
Mexico and New Zealand,
I wasco research in Canada,
so that the only thing that's really
politically blocked right now is marijuana
research.
It's hilarious.
It's shocking,
but it's true.
You're getting all this
research done and this is,
this is very new,
like two decades ago,
this was not possible.
It was impossible.
And when did it start being possible?
Well,
actually what happened was,
and I did my dissertation at the
Harvard Kennedy School of Government,
I got my master's and phd there,
and the part of my dissertation
was on how this happened.
Who at the FDA change things
and was it other places as well?
Was it a social consensus?
And it turns out that in the
late 1980s there was a lot of,
particularly Reagan had
been before pro business.
There was a lot of concern that the
FDA was too slow evaluating drugs,
that they were mostly trying to block
risks and they didn't care that much about
treating illness.
And so the FDA set up this group
called the pilot drug evaluation staff,
which was that they would pilot drug
evaluation methods to try to speed up the
drug review process.
And this group needed drugs
to actually work with.
And so they looked around the other
pro parts of the FDA and they kind of
cobbled together different kinds of drugs
and they looked at the people that had
control over scheduled
drugs and marijuana,
all the psychedelics,
and they had been suppressing
things for decades and they said,
sure,
we'll give this up.
And so this new branch came,
they didn't,
but they also were more
science over politics.
So starting in 1990 the first study was
approved with Dmt by Rick Strassman.
And we had tried for five studies before
for years before with the Mtma all
rejected.
But once this new team got into place,
uh,
then they had to review our study
Mtma for cancer patients with anxiety.
And there was a 1992 advisory committee
meeting to determine whether the FDA
would go forward with psychedelic research
and they did it bureaucratically in a
brilliant way.
They had the DEA there,
they had the uh,
office of National Drug Control Policy.
They had the national
institute on Drug Abuse.
They had representatives from all of
these branches and they proposed an idea
and their idea was that the regulations
that they put on the major drugs for the
pharmaceutical industries that the risks
of the medical use of psychedelics and
marijuana,
we're no different.
And so they would treat these drugs as
if they were drugs being developed by the
pharmaceutical industry.
And the same procedures would be fine.
And the Dea,
Nita,
the drugs,
ours office,
they all thought,
man you put it in there,
they'll,
it'll never get out again because who can
act like the pharmaceutical companies.
And so they all signed off and FDA
got this policy in 1992 and then they
approved our first study with Mtma,
which was a safety study.
And then they started approving studies
with psilocybin and then expanding our
MD may studies into patient populations.
So there's a 20 year history now and a
lot of track record and data and now we
have data on the benefits side,
not just on the risk side so that we
can talk about balancing before people
could say there are no benefits,
there's these risks,
therefore nothing's permitted.
So the dynamics have completely
changed and we've demonstrated so far,
over 800 people have taken Mtma and
clinical research all over the world.
And you know,
nobody's gone.
Nobody's had a serious adverse
event that left them harmful.
Nobody has become addicts
as far as we know to Mtma.
Nobody went crazy.
So we've demonstrated
there are safe places.
Our study with LSD and Switzerland for
people who are dying was 12 people and 11
of them had never done LSD before.
So it's not,
we're trying to show that it can be
brought to people who are not from this
culture,
not used to this,
but it can be helpful to
them in a controlled setting
with supportive therapists
and with a lot of integration
and preparation work.
And people were aware of a other
studies like the Johns Hopkins study on
Psilocybin now that's gotten
a lot of steam because,
uh,
these people many years later experienced
great personality benefits that stuck
with them.
Yeah.
That was,
um,
the study of psilocybin and people who
were spiritually inclined to see if they
could have a spiritual experience that
actually there was the classic study that
that's modeled on was called the Good
Friday experiment and it was done in 1962
and it was one of the best things
that Timothy leary ever dead.
And I ended up doing
a 25 year followup to,
at tracking these people down.
But basically in 1962,
lots of people thought that psychedelics
had some genuine spiritual potential.
And Martin Luther King was getting a
phd at Boston University and his mentor
there was Reverend Howard Thurman.
This dynamic black minister
who's just fantastic,
and he agreed to have Timothy
leary and Ram Das and others,
20 people and 10 guides come into
their church on Good Friday and do an
experiment.
And these were all students from Andover
Newton theological seminary and half of
them,
they all got pills,
half were psilocybin,
30 milligrams,
which is pretty strong.
And the other half was nicotinic acid,
which gives you this hot
flush and it acts quicker.
So that was going to
be there double blind.
And then they went through the Good Friday
service and Walter Pankey who did the
study,
was a doctor or a minister
and getting a phd at Harvard.
And he had spent a year going through the
world's mystical literature to develop
a questionnaire for what
the mystical experience was.
And he extracted all specific mentions of,
you know,
Jesus or Moses or it's
just more of this abstract,
what is a mystical experience and
administered this questionnaire.
And nine out of the 20 people had either
a partial or a full mystical experience
and eight out of those
nine had the psilocybin.
And so the conclusion was that for
people who are religiously inclined in a
religious setting,
you can have a psychedelic drugs.
Psilocybin does precipitate what seems
to be a genuine mystical experience,
not a hallucination,
but in the mystical literature,
the real test is called the fruits
test is what does it you bring back,
what are the fruits of this experience?
And that only comes with time.
And Mulder Pankey who did the study died
from a scuba diving diving accident in
1971 and so he would have done this,
but in the middle eighties when I
was getting my undergraduate degree,
I decided to track these people down
for my senior thesis at New College of
Florida,
which is this experimental school.
And my father was really helpful.
My mother was too.
I identified 19 out of the 20 and
was able to interview 16 of them.
And what I found was that the
people who had the placebo,
most of them didn't
remember it that vividly,
but the people who had the silicide bun
had very vivid memories of parts of it.
And at the same time they said that
they considered it to be a genuine
experience that had non drug mystical
experiences since they preferred the
non-drug mystical experiences cause
they were more uniformly positive.
They lost their fear of death and they
felt more focused on the here and now and
on social justice cause they had this
unit of experience that helped them
identify with the planet,
with the people,
with not so much that all
the divisions that divide us,
they saw deeper unity.
And so they were more social
justice minded and activists.
And I think that's a little bit of
a key to the 60s as psychedelics go.
Right.
They inspire people to try to make
a better world and we can do that.
Not In an oppositional way,
but we can do it with in
the heart of the culture.
And that's the challenge that we face.
It's really interesting that you said
that what they had was a real religious
experience or real mystical experience.
Um,
one of the things has been on my mind,
uh,
over the last few months when it comes
to psychedelic parents is that when
people want to tell you,
oh,
you're just,
something is going on,
your imagination,
you create,
your visual Cortex is getting stimulated
by this drug and it's creating a bunch
of hallucinations.
It could be that,
but it also could be something else.
It could be you are experiencing
some divine state of consciousness.
You are in contact with some other
form of intelligence and either it's a
hallucination or it's this
other real experience.
But either way you have
the exact same experience.
Whether you really went to a place
and talked to super spiritual,
highly intelligent beings,
or you imagined you did,
you're still having the
exact same experience.
And it's incredibly vivid.
Yeah.
That's the one of the weirdest aspects
about any sort of psychedelic experiences
that they're almost more
real than reality itself.
And I think because that it's even more
important that we keep our critical
faculties in a way because we are
always a filter and our culture,
how are,
so I don't think we're ever seeing
absolute reality or the truth.
And I think that's where you get
in danger where people think,
I,
you know,
God spoke to me,
God said this or I know this for sure
because there is our filter that we're
seeing it through.
But you try to see as much as you can.
But I think we have to be aware that,
uh,
and be cautious and see
how it works in life.
So under LSD therapy and Mtma therapy
would tell people don't make decisions
while you're doing the therapy,
you know,
wait for a couple of
weeks after or you know,
at least under the
influence is for exploring,
not for deciding.
Hmm.
That's interesting.
Although some things do get changed
cause sometimes though you have,
yeah,
you have like a really
obvious reaction where,
you know,
you're very aware that,
okay this is,
this is what needs to be done
and I need to do this right away.
Yeah.
But it does happen.
And I think one of the more vivid
examples for me was when I was sitting for
someone who is doing Mtma,
he was a physician.
And during the experience,
his arm became paralyzed,
completely paralyzed and stop working.
And we were like,
it's not permanent and it's,
it's psychosomatic.
You don't really need to,
you know,
we don't need to take you to the hospital.
And he was a doctor and
his arm was paralyzed.
And over time he told this story
that lasted a couple of hours.
But the story was that he as was with his
mother and his siblings at the bedside
of their father who was dying
and all of this life support.
And they had this discussion about
whether they should pull the plug or not.
Um,
and because he was the doctor
and they decided that they would,
and so he actually pulled the plug in.
The complicating thing was that he hated
his father and he wasn't really sure it
was this his anger at his dad or was
this what his mother really wanted.
So as he explored this emotionally complex
issue and realized he really didn't
kill his dad,
he did what his mother and
his siblings were saying.
It was humane.
The feelings started
coming back to his arm.
Wow.
So that was the arm that pulled the plug?
Yeah.
Is there a real plug that actually
I thought was can be done,
but you know there depends on it.
I don't know.
Good,
good for her because like pulling
the plug is the expression.
But what a fucking stupid if life support
systems were really like you just go
back there and unplug it.
That's how they shot him on.
Well we never,
we don't want to kill people
so we don't have an off button.
So you have to just pull the plug.
Like really silly
expression is true today.
You said something that I thought was
really interesting too where you said that
in the 1960s you don't think
people were ready for it.
I think a lot of people were,
I think that the culture wasn't,
and I think even if you read the
electrical aid acid test,
you know there there's ways in which
people are damaged and left behind and
that's something where I felt
they weren't quite ready for that.
Isn't that the case?
Always.
Just with life in general,
there's always going to be people
that are damaged and left behind.
Well I think one of the beautiful things
about the marines and the military is
that they don't leave anybody behind.
And I think that the site that we should
adopt that should be the psychedelic
marines in a way,
don't leave anybody behind.
That's really good advice.
Except there's some really annoying
people out there and if you get hooked up
with them and you know,
for whatever reason,
they can't carry their
own weight psychically,
psychologically,
emotionally,
they're really fucking meeting.
If certain point Tom,
you need to cut,
need to cut ties,
can't fix the whole world.
I think that's really can't,
you know,
you can't and you to tell people
that they can is crazy talk right?
You,
there's some people that
are just broken animals,
you can't fix them.
Um,
unfortunately they are
not you and it's not me,
but we both know people who say,
you know what,
if you had like if there was a show,
like a one of those fixed me up shows,
you know they have those like home
improvement shows or weight loss shows.
If you had a guy who was just a
complete fucking mess and they said,
just Rick Doblin,
this is your assignment for this show,
you're going to take this guy and
elevate his consciousness and,
and just make them a much better person
because he could do it with a complete
idiot.
Well I think the beauty of it is that
people have to do part of it themselves
and if they're,
and they own it and that's where they
become empowered and if they want to fix
them without them taking the courage
and maybe there's ways you can help them
through drugs or through therapeutic
alliance to have that path in mind.
Right?
They have to be willing to take
certain kinds of steps forward.
And so that I think that is the
beauty that we can't heal everybody,
that they have to heal themselves.
I think there's also a big danger as a
human being in almost embracing the fact
that you're not going to improve because
it takes away all the pressure of
trying to improve all
the self examination.
As soon as you just say,
I don't give a fuck,
you know,
I don't give a fuck.
Do you really not give a fuck?
Or do you,
is that you're psychic shield to keep
you from examining all the holes in your
life,
the game?
Cause that's more likely the case.
Well we talked about the uh,
army veteran that committed suicide,
who wrote that letter.
And one part of that letter was that he
had felt like he would never get better.
Yeah.
And I just kept thinking if he
could have had an Mtma experience,
would he still have been able to find,
uh,
some hope and a reason to live or
would he still have committed suicide?
And those are the questions.
There's,
he,
he talked about 22 veterans
a day are committing suicide.
He was dealing with physical pain as well.
I think there was a,
a bunch of different things and
that's where he was upset at.
The Dea I think also
add,
uh,
pain meds and how they
regulated pain meds.
So I think the MTMA actually
in combination with morphine,
it's been used in dying people,
um,
enhances the pain control.
So MTMA has pain relieving qualities
and when you combine it with morphine,
when people are,
you know,
in hospice settings,
things like that,
that you have better pain control and
you don't need as much morphine and you
start waking people up so that they're
not tranquilized out and you open their
hearts so that people
can have these beautiful,
beautiful,
pretty much pain free experiences.
There's a woman that wrote a book,
uh,
honor thy daughter about her daughter who
died in the early thirties from cancer
and how she had gone through a series of
psychedelic therapy sessions as she was
dying with,
um,
Mtma and mushrooms,
Lsd,
MD may combination,
but that it really enriched her daughter's
life and she felt she needed to write
a book about,
it's to let people know.
So I think that the use of these drugs,
when people are in pain,
it's not just mental pain.
There's a whole link between mental
pain and physical pain and Mtma actually
does help in this kind of,
I see psychedelic medicine,
psychedelic hospice will be pretty common,
I think 2030 years from now.
And we'll look back and think that,
you know,
it made sense 50 years ago.
Oh,
it absolutely does.
I mean,
I think that's one of the best uses
for them to give people like a,
I remember Larry Hagman who died a,
was on CNN and uh,
died recently.
Great Guy.
Uh,
I never got to meet him,
but I really loved his interviews.
He was so candid and
just warm and friendly.
And he was talking about
the importance of a,
an acid trip to the,
had that where it took
away his fear of dying.
Yeah,
it was a joy.
Paccar and CNN.
That was fantastic.
It was fantastic interview.
It really was because he wasn't
saying it like he was a Kook.
He was just,
is explaining what it
did and why I did that.
And you believe them,
you know,
you really did believe him.
Yeah.
I spent years trying to meet him because
I knew that he had done LSD therapy in
the 60s.
And he wrote about it
in his autobiography.
And My mother in law actually
sent me this message saying,
Larry Hagman has done LSD.
So then I started trying to find them
and eventually I did meet him and we got
to be friends and he was a
donor to maps and he wrote this,
um,
he helped us in a lot,
a lot of different ways,
and he was so human that he would be
from Jr and known all over the world.
But when you were with him,
he just was present,
present,
and,
and he wasn't,
you know,
ego inflated.
And he was just a really nice person.
And,
um,
I felt that,
that he had this idealism and
this joy from his whole life,
but he also really valued
his psychedelic experiences,
his experiences with Mtma,
it's experiences with marijuana.
And it was kind of ironic that someone
who was so valued by the culture,
um,
couldn't be open about that,
that he had to keep that hidden.
Well,
he did for a long time until,
until he wrote that book.
Yeah.
The Joy Bihar experience.
But I think also it's like the,
um,
the atmosphere for an actor.
Actors get picked for things.
And if you're very controversial,
I mean,
for every Charlie Sheen,
and of course we're dealing
with 2013 were Charlie.
She can get away with being,
it's crazy.
Coke snorting whoremonger and
like he just wears it and owns it.
For that to be a thing 20
years ago for an actor,
it could be a career killer.
Yeah.
And when he was doing Dallas,
I mean,
the,
the consciousness of
the public's opinion on,
on psychedelics was very much
different than it is today.
Yeah.
Well,
he was,
um,
in Dallas when Mtma first became a party
drug and it was used at the stark club
of which there's a documentary
that sort of the explosion of MDA,
the transformation from
MDA as a secret quiet,
um,
therapeutic drug used underground isn't
quite right cause it was still legal,
but it was used in a quiet way for fear
that if it became known it would become
illegal.
And then in Dallas it started being used
and distributed by different people in
nightclub settings and go
to Dallas was the place,
right?
Dallas was the place and
there's a documentary about
the star club and there's
interviews with Larry Hagman in there.
And what he's talking about is this
a discussion he had with one of the,
um,
police officers in Dallas and they were
saying that Larry had caused them to
lose lots and lots of money.
And he's like,
well,
what do you mean I cause you
to lose lots and lots of money?
He said,
well,
after MD may became illegal,
we were going to bust the star club
and we had this whole tactical team and
everything was set to go.
And then you and some friends came in.
It's a party.
They're not necessarily to take MTMA and
so we didn't want to bust Larry Hagman
from Dallas.
That's a land.
So we had to call off the bus and
then come back and do it another time.
One more time.
More and more rather evidence at times
have changed because today there'd be
psyched to bus Larry Hagman,
you know,
if was like some dude like that,
like don't make it Larry Hagman making,
I know some other female star,
he didn't necessarily have anything
that they could bust him on,
but he was so nice.
He led us to auction
off a dinner with him,
uh,
as a donation to maps and this couple,
and also Andy,
Andy Weil did that too.
So we had a dinner,
but that,
the deal they made is I
had to come a long Ah,
and I was like,
that would be great to do that.
Why would a great dinner.
Yeah.
Who'd you guys eat dinner with?
This group,
this family from Canada.
And they,
they were just ordinary people,
but they had one of them.
The woman had struggled
with cancer had they were,
um,
just love Dallas and loved
I dream of Jeannie and hold.
That's right.
He was on I dream of Jeannie.
Yeah.
And we had such a nice time at the dinner.
They also,
the dinner with Andy Weil,
who was he?
The boss on I Janie,
Janie.
And now he was the astronauts.
That's true.
It's the other guy.
He was the main character.
Very in love with Barbara Eden.
That's right.
Yeah.
I always get them confused with bewitched.
I get,
I dream of Jeannie and
bewitched confused there.
There he is.
Wow.
B,
which was the one where
they had a different dude,
like they killed off the
dude and brought in the same,
yes.
Yes.
That was same name,
different guy.
I think now that Larry is the gun,
I can share that.
Um,
he had a bond that was made like
the bottle that she lived in.
Oh,
that'd be worth a long weekend.
And we got to smoke pot together in
this genie genie bottle and he said that
somebody had talked to him about marketing
it and making lots of them and he
said,
no,
he didn't want to have that done.
Yeah,
that's too bad.
We're going to make it now.
But sorry.
But then the family,
he was so nice with this family and just,
and also with me just treat us as like,
you know,
part of his family.
We had dinners kitchen that when it
came time for the dinner with Andy,
while that the family invited Larry and
he came with a friend of his to help
them travel and we ended up just
a few months before he died,
um,
going up and see planes and stuff onto
this island where Andy Weil lives and
having this really wonderful experience.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
I think guys like him that
do those sorts of interviews,
that's a really,
really important thing because
the public's perception
of people who do LSD is
almost entirely limited
to fuck ups and you know,
and crazy people and wild people.
Or they used to do acid.
Oh,
this guy used to do acid,
he did acid back off his rocker.
You never hear about it.
Positive drug experience like
that from a very respected person.
Right.
And that's what we need is the coming
out of loads of people like that who are
retiring baby boomers.
So I think time is on our side.
There's all these people who are more
fearless because they're not worried about
what they tell their kids or they're
not worried about their jobs.
They've made a reputation and
they can talk like Steve Jobs.
I had a wonderful opportunity,
I tried for years and finally managed to
have a half hour conversation with him
about our LSD study.
Did he give you like a half
an hour on an iPhone and go,
ready press star.
Is it facetime?
Cause Start 29,
28 before I had an iPhone.
And uh,
you didn't have an
iPhone when you met him.
How dare you.
And I didn't meet him.
It was just on the fun.
And um,
at the end of it he said,
you know,
send me a proposal.
But um,
I didn't never heard back.
He wasn't known for being philanthropic,
but I had gotten a letter
from Albert Hoffman to him,
um,
on his,
after it 102nd birthday.
Wow.
And,
um,
I'll say acid lives to be one or
two.
And he was married for over 70 years.
The same person.
Um,
he led,
I mean,
Albert Hoffman to pivot just for a
second was such a perfect example.
We're so fortunate that he's the
one that invented LSD because he was
everything.
What I'm trying to talk about
in terms of integrating,
he was a big successful chemist
for a major pharmaceutical company.
Sandoz.
He made drugs.
It's sold hundreds of millions of dollars.
He lived in more or less
than the same place.
He had a wife for over 70 years.
He had children,
very normal,
very normal guy with
his wife up pink dragon.
Um,
we,
I was fortunately able to be with the
Albert when they tried to MDA for the
first time.
How old was in the drive?
It's they soon as 80s
or late seventies.
Um,
and so what he said was,
um,
ah,
finally something I can do with my wife
because she had had kind of a scary
experience with Lsd.
A lot of people have,
man.
Yeah.
Have you done any tests
with like candy flipping,
like mixing,
you know,
acid?
Well,
I believe that that actually has
incredible therapeutic potential.
Um,
however we've not actually tested it
because in the scientific world you want
just one variable if possible.
And so to combine LSD and Mtma,
which drug are we trying to make a
medicine and are always going to combine
them,
but I honestly,
it becomes legal.
That would be I think maybe even before,
well,
that's the question.
You know,
it maybe it's 10 years before these
drugs can become medicalized legal in a
medical way.
I think that that long,
um,
I,
you really think it could be sooner.
I think that's possible
now more than ever.
There's a certain track of data that
you have to produce a certain set of
requirements that were
on the track of doing.
But it looks to me like
it's eight to 10 years,
even if it was certainly,
no.
Well,
I've always been wrong.
And I've always underestimated
how long it takes you more.
We were talking about earlier
gay rights.
I think they equate,
cause when I was a kid,
I remember I was living in San Francisco,
uh,
from seven til 11.
And uh,
it was around a lot of gay people and uh,
it was completely normal because
that was just what I was around.
And then when I moved to Florida,
when I was 11,
my friend candy is
Candido is or Cuban kid,
his dad was really pissed
off with the newspaper,
slams it down and he was,
he was mad that,
uh,
the,
the fags wanted to get married.
That's what he kept saying,
I believe this shit,
these fags want to get married.
And then I remember I was like 11.
I was like,
what?
Why do you care?
Like,
well,
you're a grown man.
Like this is what,
how stupid some grown manner.
And I was like,
that's a weird argument.
Like that's a strange thing.
So that was,
you know,
a long ass time ago.
I'm 45 years old now,
so I was 34 years ago and um,
the,
I know it's not,
yeah,
it is.
Okay.
But it's the idea that
that back then it was,
it was really something
that people fought against.
It was really a,
a subject of you could,
you could be public about it and
not feel like an ignorant asshole.
Whereas today if you say that you're
against gay people being married,
like you're nothing but a fool,
right?
You're nothing but a full,
if you,
you,
you honestly think it's either you're
crazy with religion and you honestly
thanked that somehow or another,
it's possible to cure person of being gay.
And if they believe in
the scripture that's,
you know,
that I can't even talk to you.
That's,
that's a different animal.
But if you're a rational person and you
accept the fact that people were born
gang and you,
you have an issue with
them marrying their lover,
like you're a crazy person.
Yeah.
I think though that
people who are irrational,
they're there.
That's the question.
How do we rationalize the ration?
I think there's a way that they're
fearful of something that blocks their
rational thinking and if you
can somehow or other help them.
And I think a lot of people who are so
anti gay are scared of their own gay
feelings.
It's kind of a cliche,
but I think that's often the case.
But I think what drove me early on into
an interest in psychedelics is that I
was so terrified of World War II and
the Holocaust and how people can be so
blind or be willing to be so driven
by irrational factors that I thought,
what can we do to try to
help get to heal that?
Because some people,
you know,
they,
they can be quite powerful and they can,
um,
how do you respond?
And that,
that was the dilemma for me.
And I finally felt that,
um,
growing up with the Vietnam war,
that that was something that now I was
being called to fight and I decided to
become a draft resistor.
But I saw the nuclear standoff between
the U S in Russia and it just seemed like
the irrational was so powerful.
The demonization of the other.
And the making of the
enemy that there was,
I couldn't figure out how to uh,
contribute to breaking through that cycle.
And it finally felt like this,
um,
deep spiritual experience of connection
and letting people's fears come up where
they could look at them more.
That that would be for an individual make
us more grounded and less likely to be
manipulated are irrational factors.
And if millions of people
could have that experience,
which did happen during the 60s,
but if we can expand it,
that maybe there is a basis to go through
the crises that we're facing over the
next couple of decades as a species and
as globalization and people are bumping
up against each other that it felt like
somehow or other the irrational is based
a lot on fear and how can we help
people to counter that with love,
with hope or with looking
with self acceptance.
And I think that's where the MTMA is so
useful that the fear of self criticism
or the fear that Mtma helps people to
accept who they are and the LSD and the
silicide bend,
the Iowasca,
the masculine,
the Payoti,
those,
the drugs,
they are challenging in a different way.
And that they do this dissolving of the
control mechanisms and dissolving of the
ego and,
and hopefully people can let go and
blend and be strengthened from that.
And that's the support that we need to
provide to help that to be happening.
And I think,
you know,
just the way that this religious
fundamentalism against gay marriage,
I mean,
right now we have a crisis of
fundamentalism around the world.
There's a crisis of ideology.
Yeah.
So,
and it's also a crisis of power because
once someone gets into a position where
they can espouse their ideology,
you listen to them,
that is power.
And then they use that power to get money,
to manipulate,
to get sex,
to do whatever the fuck
they want and not pay taxes.
There's a lot of craziness.
It's almost like in and
not pay taxes thing.
It's almost like they're in cahoots.
It's like the government has decided,
look,
it'd probably be beneficial if you
guys did a good job and you know,
cult it up the shit out of some people
and get them all whacked out on your
ideas to the point where they're
complete fundamentalists on your idea.
So how about you not paid taxes?
You know,
how about we help you along there,
you know,
make it even more profitable,
more susceptible to corruption?
Well,
I think that there,
there is that,
um,
way in which the government
can be influenced by groups.
Sure.
And I think that's something also
that we have to be wary of some mess,
but at the same time we have
to work through groups and
work through government.
So I think this,
um,
one of the first things we learned
at the Kennedy School is there is no,
the government,
it's like your body,
there is no,
your body,
there's all these different organ systems.
They all work in different ways.
So we find out about that when
the government goes after itself.
Like when,
when this general Patraeus thing happened,
we found out the CIA and the FBI
don't necessarily see eye to eye.
Right.
You know?
And that's where our strategy is built at.
The FDA is putting science over politics
while the other forces are trying to
either slow down or black research.
And where it comes with marijuana is
that there's a government monopoly on the
supply of marijuana that can
be used in federal research.
So even though there is no
monopoly on the supply marijuana,
the only kind that's been grown under
DEA license is controlled by the national
institute on Drug Abuse.
And it's hilarious.
You want to get to do research to
make marijuana into a medicine.
The FDA will give you permission.
We have a permission to do a study
with marijuana in 50 veterans for post
traumatic stress disorder.
And our distinction is that the marijuana
is more about treating symptoms and
the Mtma is more about curing is getting.
And then you only need Mtma a few times
with the marijuana people sort of need
every day.
Yeah.
But we have FDA approval and Nada and
the Public Health Service rejected the
protocol and refused to
provide the marijuana for us.
And they only can review protocols for
marijuana because they've got sitting on
this monopoly and we were 12
years lawsuit and we won and won.
And then we lost in the first circuit
court of appeals to break the monopoly.
But that's the core reason why we're
not able to make progress with marijuana
research and we are able to
make progress with psychedelics.
And are they afraid of with marijuana?
I think they're afraid of the
whole drug war collapsing,
that the marijuana is
incredibly demonized.
It's widely used most.
There's a lot of people that
know that it's not so dangerous.
And I think it's the,
it's a symbol,
it's a symbol of cultural rebellion.
And that's where it was embedded
in certain people's minds.
And even though it was made illegal
in 37 with the marijuana tax act,
then it was illegal shortly
after prohibition ended.
And it was illegal during the depression
and mostly it was Mexicans and blacks
that smoked pot.
And so it was a way to repress people
who are competing for low wage jobs.
It was a way to block the hemp industry,
various things like that.
But,
but it largely was a minor thread in
American history until the 60s and white
suburban people started,
kids started smoking pot and you had this
massive explosion of pot and then pot
and LSD got associated
with cultural rebellion.
And now all these years later,
you know,
there are many people that smoke pot
that are at least out about that.
And it made a lot of contributions.
So I think it's more now about
fear of parents for their kids.
It's shifted.
But that's what's driving what's left
of the drug war is parents wanting to
protect their kids and also all these
vested interests that have the prison
unions and things like that.
The,
but I think that dynamic we're
trying to is shifting also.
And so there's a way in which those of
us who were interested in enhancing our
lives with these drugs in positive,
responsible ways need to do so.
Need to speak about it,
where possible and need
to demonstrate that.
It's not about tearing down the society,
it's strengthened.
It's all of us coming together to face
these incredible challenges and we need
all the inspiration and we need all the
creativity and we need all the energy
that we can.
So unfortunately for some people they
really can't speak out about it because
they get drug tested at work.
That's a big issue.
I mean the,
the,
the idea that something that stays
in your body as long as marijuana,
it gets tested.
When the psychoactive,
the,
the time in which your body brings it
back to baselines lines less than 24
hours,
right?
I mean is your,
your,
you basically just have
traced metabolites.
It stays in your system
for a long ass time,
but they're not psychoactive.
So you're at work,
you get it.
You spoke to join on Friday,
you're at work on Monday.
Then like you take a piss test,
you piss positive.
They're penalizing you for
something you're doing when
you're not at work really
is not going to
affect work.
You can also be arrested for
driving under the influence.
Yeah.
From metabolites that you
took from pot a week ago.
Right.
It's nonsense.
It's so crazy.
The idea that that,
first of all,
the idea that they treat,
they have some arbitrary level that
they test you for and they say,
well this is,
you can't operate a marijuana vehicle
vehicle on marijuana if you have this
function or system.
It's been proven.
What tests have you done?
Well,
where's the science
behind the national level?
When you look at the science,
the experience,
marijuana smokers are not debilitated by
in their driving and there's been a lot
of driving tests that had been done.
And what they show is that when you are
drinking alcohol and driving that you
are impaired,
but you don't think you're impaired.
And so you were more reckless that under
a marijuana people know that sometimes
their instincts,
their reaction time might be slow.
So you take compensating action.
So people are more careful when
they're driving and more aware.
So in driving,
not in simulators,
but when they're out in driving roads
and cars that and in simulators to that
marijuana is very
minimally affecting driving
and you become paranoid.
So you'd drive a little slower and,
and you react a little slower to,
and really you think you
react slower physically?
No,
I mean by that that,
no,
cause I've a lot look at all these
basketball players that you know,
tied into it.
It's just,
yeah,
you didn't know about that Jujitsu.
I didn't.
Huge in the Jiu Jitsu community.
Massive snowboarding.
A massive amount of people
smoke pot and then go train the,
the,
it's so much.
So they have t shirts rolling all stoned,
rolling stone.
They have all these different,
uh,
I mean it's so common
in the janitor world.
Yeah.
I play racquetball and so I
can have combined marijuana,
racquetball and train myself
to be really quick reacting.
Yeah.
And sometimes I play my best games
when I'm stoned and sometimes I don't
give a fuck and it balls,
but I can never tell ahead of
time whether it be better or not.
But that's funny.
But I think with driving that,
um,
what I meant by reaction time is that
you don't take precipitous action.
So the classic thing is that you're,
I'm going somewhere,
I'm thinking about something I,
I don't turn where I wanted to turn,
but then I just like calm way,
find my way back.
I don't like jerked the wheel.
I do want to clarify though,
that that's you,
you're in a,
you're an intelligent guy and
you have your shit together.
Right.
That's true.
I think for most folks it's,
you know,
I don't like driving Tai.
I don't,
I'd rather be sober.
I don't like it.
There's a lot of things that I
don't like to do when I'm high.
I don't mind it,
but I want to get pulled over and I'm
high and I got to talk my way out of,
you know,
some cop being upset at me for being high,
like two of them telling
me how to drive fine.
I'm good.
I don't want to be involved
in that situation and I don't,
I think I'm,
I would be kind of a hypocrite if,
uh,
if I said that and like,
or if I,
if I had a problem with some
people getting high and driving,
but I know some people were impaired.
There's,
there's,
there's certain people that
freak out and they get high.
Even driving when you were impaired.
Yeah.
When you freaking out.
I think even if it's only psychologically,
even if your reflexes are still there,
you're still impaired,
you know,
your
don't drive like that.
Please stop sobriety driving.
I think go hand.
I did have you talked about being high
and having to talk to a police officer.
Um,
I was actually going to visit John
Lilly and a chemist friend of mine had
separated the isomers of ketamine and
I was going to bring that to John who
hadn't tried the different isomers yet.
Um,
this is in Florida and
it was way long time ago.
And uh,
I was,
um,
I had a Porsche nine 14,
which is small,
cheap car,
but just says the open top.
And so I was going from Sarasota,
Florida to Miami,
and it was just such a beautiful night
and the moon was out and I was stone.
And I thought,
okay,
I'm going to speed.
It's just beautiful.
I'm going to get a ticket,
but it's okay.
And I thought,
okay,
as long as I'm just
going to get this ticket.
Well,
why don't I just think about what I
could tell the police officer when the
inevitable happens.
So you're thinking about this as you're
planning for your ticket as and fire for
it tickets.
What,
what can I tell him about that would
somehow or other the bok and I thought the
first thing is don't
deny that I'm speeding.
You know,
don't,
don't contradict an I think,
but the main thing I thought
is what do we have in common?
You know,
and the only thing I could think of
is we're two guys out in the road.
I don't fry lonely guys on a
Friday night out in the roads.
And so none of blow this
car to get out and took it.
And I'm very,
you know,
the story was that I was on my way
to see my girlfriend and I was,
and that was late.
Okay.
And officer,
I am speeding and I'm sorry,
but that's what I was doing.
And so it happened.
I got pulled over,
I told the story and the guy was like,
you know,
I'm going to let you go.
Just tell her that it's from me,
that you owe this for me.
Well,
that's a nice car and get
lucky and get a nice cop.
Yeah.
I don't have a many time.
And then with John Lilly,
um,
you know,
one of the isomers is more
active than the other.
And so that was interesting,
but I also did get the sense that he was
too much into the ketamine and too much
into this other state.
And it,
I started trying to think about how
possibly we could help him because he was
such a major contributor
in a hero of mine.
And one of the people that was a dolphin
trainer that worked with him with some
of his dolphins,
had this sense,
uh,
Roberta Goodman had this sense that,
he was also going down hill.
And so we are,
are arranged to get together
with them to do MD may therapy.
And during that he kind of
became very much into his body,
but he had abscesses from
where he was shooting himself.
He was in terrible shape.
So he was shooting ketamine.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
In our Moscow.
Really?
Or did you do IB would do it ivy.
Sometimes he would do it.
[inaudible] he would get,
he just was so trying to be out of body
and another place that he wasn't taking
care of himself.
Wow.
And he was,
and,
and it was painful to them.
And,
and so he kind of bounced into this
awareness of what he was doing.
So he had infections and infections.
Yeah.
He was her.
Wow.
And He,
um,
he didn't want to stay
there and deal with it.
And so what we,
we couldn't help him,
you know,
because he didn't want it,
didn't want to deal with it.
Also is probably dealing with the
reality of what the king body,
and he was an older man
and he probably figured,
you know what,
this,
these states of mind,
I like this better.
You know,
I'll just ride this bitch
until the wheels fall off.
I mean,
there's a lot of people that
take that approach as well.
Yeah.
And I'll end up to a guy who spent
so much time in altered states of
consciousness.
I don't think it's unreasonable
to like prefer that.
I think it is.
I think it is because I think when
you get this deeper sense about how
life is so precious that that you
can have these other states of mind,
but that it should be
inculcating compassion,
a sense that you have to contribute
to make it a better world.
That this kind of self destructive
isn't ultimately a few times,
I mean,
there isn't,
we live,
we die.
I mean,
um,
that this guy is feeling is Bobby
giving out on him and he says,
you know what?
I'm just gonna Shoot Ketamine
until the boat hits the rocks.
Well,
I think giving makes people happy.
A lot of times people are depressed,
you know,
if they serve or help others.
I even thought about that,
about the vet that,
you know,
if there was some way,
he felt that he was a harm to his family
and that he was doing them good by
killing himself.
And I think if only there would've been
some soup kitchen or something that he
could have felt that he was contributing,
maybe that would have,
and we kind of addressed that.
Didn't even know he was talking about the
all the widows and created and that he
didn't feel like he had
the the right to exist.
Right.
But that's psychological
material to work through.
That's not necessary.
And I think even that's
a hard thing to say.
But you're saying it from coming from
someone who was an MDM experiences.
And I think unless somebody has,
they really would,
would listen to this
like a straight person.
Not not mean knocked day,
but I mean a square car
has never done any drugs.
And Paul,
I've really not been into drugs and
I've took some percocets in college.
If that person heard that,
there we go.
What is this guy talking about?
Like if the guy had post traumatic stress
disorder from murdering
people and you know,
committing war crimes and he's openly
spoke about it in this letter and then
you're telling them he's going to
take ecstasy and he's going to,
he's going to be able
to work through that.
Like what of,
what the fuck are you talking about?
Yeah,
that's a really good point.
In fact,
people have accused us of like,
you're going to try to help
people just forget what they did.
And you can make mindless soldiers who
will commit war crimes and then they get
a drug and they feel
better and they go back.
And so I think that's a really good point,
your race,
because it's not that
people say that was good,
that I can accept that that was good.
They don't reframe what they
did into something good,
but they realize that they,
it's done.
If they accept it,
it can give them the chance in the
rest of their life to make up for it.
Not that you can in any way,
but it gives you a way to go
forward in a positive way.
And I think that if we
do this in a marine's,
let's say,
my guess is that it will make them more
sensitive about those kind of occasions
where they might be reckless with their
machine gun or something that it might
make them more careful.
Um,
I don't know.
These are like unknown questions and it's,
it's really important.
But the process of dealing with post
traumatic stress disorder is to more live
in the present,
to let the past inform you,
not to deny it and,
but not to be so oppressed by it
and to accept what you've done.
And I think once you accept that there
is that evil and all of us that we have
to like those,
you know,
that we all have the capacity under
certain circumstances to that,
that you can accept that.
And,
uh,
what we hope is that people then can move
forward and recognize that they still
have some life and every day they can
make choices and everyday they can try to
be helpful to somebody or we're not.
And I think that's what
we're talking about,
the healing.
It doesn't make them look back
and say that was okay what I did.
I think we are in a
very strange period of,
of,
of human history where we,
we know that we have all these issues.
We know we have massive
government corruption.
financial corruption.
We know we have the great majority of
people who don't agree with war acts that
are going on,
whether it's drone
attacks or what have you.
And we wonder like,
why is our society so far behind?
Why have we achieved so such great
technological and military heights,
but yet socially were so fucked up.
And we have all the tools to fix that.
And that's what's really insane.
It's like individuals have found with
their own unique situations that through
yoga or through Mtma or
through meditation or even some
through religious chanting.
And,
and,
and learning how control of your
breath can change states of mine.
People have gone that through jogging.
You were talking about
smoking pot and getting high.
I know a lot of people who think things
through when they're jogging and let
things go when they're jogging too.
I think there's many,
many,
many pieces that we can use
to try to fix this problem.
And they all,
they're all documented.
Like we're not living in
the dark ages anymore.
Right.
And I think this is one of the
first generations it's been around.
It's experienced that
that has that many tools.
And I think you're right on when you
talked about how we're overdeveloped
intellectually and underdeveloped
emotionally and spiritually.
It's not even that were underdeveloped.
It's just were not developed at all.
You know what I mean?
It's like most people were acting on
momentum or imitating their atmosphere.
Yeah.
Well,
were developed some,
we think the primates are pure instincts.
Yeah.
I mean,
as a science society it's pretty crazy.
groups are,
you know,
that,
that's what I thought about,
you know,
Hitler's Jeremy,
that,
that you've got a culture that's insane.
We're not,
we're rights North Korea right now.
They're all programmed and yeah.
So that there's a way in which
if you look at our technology,
which is miraculous,
but we,
and we have capacities now to alter
the planet with global warming,
but we don't have the emotional and
spiritual development to cope with the
technological changes.
And in a way that's
been really productive,
this kind of separating out the
intellect from religion and morals,
you know,
because religion and morals sort of
squashed the intellect and didn't want a
Copernicus and Galileo and
just a whole history of things.
But is that really religious or is that
just the people claiming to be religious
human beings?
Yeah.
Right.
It's just the ideologies behind these
ideas that didn't want to relinquish
power.
Yeah.
Because Albert Einstein talked about
how a true science and true religion are
not in opposition,
and that the scientist is also,
you know,
in a state of wonder and
spiritual appreciation.
Yeah.
Because people that think that religion
is ridiculous or that God is ridiculous,
or the concept of a
higher powers with Dojo,
us,
you know what else is ridiculous?
The whole universe itself,
the fact that there's a
floating ball quarter,
the size of the earth called the moon,
just floating in space above us.
How?
How heavy is that stupid thing?
It's just floating above us.
Oh,
and without it,
our world would not exist because our
temperature would not be regulated enough
that we could live in cold
climates and hot climates.
It wouldn't be predictable enough.
We'd be fucked.
I mean,
that's,
that's crazy.
That's way crazier than some guy
who built everything through,
you know,
big bang.
That's crazier than anything that
religions ever come up with ever.
That the whole universe was smaller
than the head of a pin and then exploded
13 point whatever billion years ago and
created the skies above
and everything you said.
Yeah.
Well you said,
is it futile?
You live and you die.
And I think that those moments of
wonder or appreciation for just how
miraculous,
mysterious and comprehensible
or those moments of love,
that there's a way in which
they make life worth it.
I agree.
And I think that there can be a,
I wanna,
I don't wanna use the word religion,
but their kin and then I'm like ideology.
But there could be a way of living
the life with wonder and with sharing
knowledge and with just looking into
what we have learned rock solid about the
very universe we live in and
respecting that and worshiping that.
I mean in a way,
you know,
not like I'm not talking about
like a deity but about like,
like a great wonder,
like the great wonder that it really
is and there's a benefit to that.
Yeah.
And taking that into the pain I think is
being able to take the loving energies
into the places that need
healing and that that's where,
so just having a spiritual meditating
on top of a mountain top and trying to,
you know,
get off the wheel of suffering and stuff.
That seems like a very
egotistical way actually.
And having the sense that while we
though some of us are privileged in all
different ways to really be healthy and
be wonderful with that and in wonder
without being so threatened that there's
a lot of people that aren't and that we
have to
not only feel those moments,
but then try to somehow as Martin Luther
King talked about the arc of history,
make some contribution of some
way that helps it for others too.
You know what was also ironic,
one of the weird things
that's going on with society,
uh,
is that as our technological
capabilities increase,
we also fill our skies with light
pollution and we can't see the stars.
And one of the best psychedelic
experiences I ever had
outside of doing a drug
was I went to the Keck observatory
and y on the big island.
And we drove through the
clouds and as we were driving,
like you wonder if it's going to be a
cloudy day eggs and you won't be able to
see anything because it takes
a while to get up there.
And I was like,
Damn,
looks like it's cloudy.
But then we drove through
the clouds and you realize,
oh,
this thing is so high up there that you
actually drive past where the clouds
are.
This is nuts.
And we went up to the observatory and
the view is just insane because the big
island is set up for the observatory,
so all the lights that they use for
streetlights or a very special type of
diffused lighting that doesn't
give light pollution off.
So you have this incredible view of the
stars where you see the whole Milky Way,
like a movie,
like,
like those pictures of space
and somehow or another,
it's just above us and
you're looking at it,
it's,
it's so unbelievably humbling and,
and,
and magical.
I was like,
I was staring into the impossible and I
remember being upset that I couldn't see
this every night that's
up there all the time.
And,
and not seeing that and just
making it this blank screen.
By doing that you sort of like lose,
you'll lose the feel for
what's really going on.
Yeah,
we're out of touch with that a lot.
I had this bonding moment
with in some ways my opposite.
And my family and I were on a vacation
in Israel and we decided to go across the
Sinai desert by car to go
see a Cairo and the pyramids.
And we had to work with an
Egyptian company and they
had people had armed guards
cause it's kind of dangerous now.
And so as we were driving
through the Sinai desert,
um,
and it was so dark and
the sky was magnificent,
we asked if we could just stop the car
and just sort of walk a bit from the
road.
There was hardly any,
virtually no other traffic on the road.
The only thing,
we're military checkpoints every
once in a while and we just went out.
And so these,
um,
it was Ramadan too.
And so these Muslims who
were with guns to protect us,
uh,
who are Jewish,
we just stood under the stars in the
middle of the desert with no light
pollution and just had this
shared moment of kind of odd.
The Majesty.
Yeah.
The,
the,
the view of the actual view
that we're supposed to see,
I think is really what inspired
people throughout history to,
to create the idea of
gods and to create this,
I mean the,
the,
the insane view that you get of that,
that just the images of those
magical lights in the sky,
millions and billions of them.
Just to see that it's,
it's so humbling and to not see that it's,
it's so dead.
It's sold numb.
Like we don't have an appreciation
for the fact that we're in space.
You watch a documentary,
it seems kind of abstract,
but when you're on top of
the observatory and you,
you look out and you have that
incredible view of the stars,
you go,
oh my God.
Like we are really in space right now.
We are on a big organic spaceship and
we're moving thousand miles an hour in a
circle.
Yeah.
It's nuts.
It's,
it's weird to see.
Right.
And what,
what it's done to Stuart brand
talked about a lot about the,
with the whole or is cloud the
picture of the earth from space?
Yeah.
We're the first generation or
two that's ever had that image.
And those astronauts that
go up in the space station,
a spatial,
they all talk about the experience.
It's being very transcendent.
You know,
when you take that view of the
earth from above and you look down,
you see just the nature of the whole
reality of a planet in the solar system,
in a galaxy,
in a universe.
And it's,
it all just sort of falls into place.
You're like,
oh my God.
But when you're down here and you're
stuck in traffic and the skies dark,
you don't even think about it,
but you're,
you're on this majestic
ride through the heavens.
Instead you're overwhelmed with a Moan,
mundane bullshit of this
person in front of you,
not reacting to the green light.
Come on.
And if you can somehow do both,
it's not that.
Yeah.
And that's where I think
lily lily got wrong.
You know,
you've got the spiritual part
was the more important part.
And it's the balance.
I,
my daughter,
Ellie is in eighth grade and
she had to do a project with,
uh,
for national history day and
with a couple of her girlfriends,
they did a project on Apollo 11,
which was,
and it turned out that,
um,
the girl that she did it with,
Michael Collins was her grandfather.
He was the one that was on the,
when Armstrong put his foot on the,
and I'm buzz Aldridge that he was
the one that stayed in the capsule.
And so they actually got to interview
him as part of this and he did talk about
for him what was so amazing both being
up there in space and seeing the earth,
but also when he got back and they
went around the world and people were
cheering and talking about things,
he said that he thought
that people would say,
you know,
look what you Americans did.
And wherever we went,
people said,
look what we did.
Like it was the human race that we went
to the moon and people wanted to be part
of that.
And he,
because it was such a
space race with Russia,
he started,
we did it.
But he saw,
you know,
we're Americans did it,
but he saw around the world that
people said we all collectively did it
well,
the idea of we all collectively
are in this thing together,
that we are a global community.
And that's really one of the
last saving hopes of humanity.
And I think the Internet has sort of
reinforced that idea in a way that never
existed.
I think nationalism,
the idea of nationalism seems
so much more preposterous now,
especially nationalism and a war sense.
Nationalism,
it's nothing wrong with being
proud of the town you live in.
No,
nothing brought warm
with a cheering for the,
you know,
your home basketball team.
There's nothing wrong with any of that.
But what's wrong is when
it translates into war.
And I think that this is the first
culture that has really sort of openly
embraced a global society.
You know,
I think kids today,
they're far less likely to
buy the bullshit when it
comes to us against them or
any ideas about,
you know,
what's really going on with
geopolitical struggles.
Yeah.
We know the kids in Iran,
like they're just,
they're kids to try and get out of the,
under the thumb of an
oppressive government.
What my son Eden,
who is just going to college,
he was playing a halo
and you can play multip,
you know,
and he was playing with
somebody in a Saudi Arabia.
It's so great.
It's fantastic.
And I think what we see a lot
is the rise of fundamentalism.
You know,
the Orthodox Jews are nuts.
The,
some of the Orthodox
Christians and Muslims,
all these,
I think because of the
forces of globalization,
because it's harder to
sustain that we're the one,
right?
Religion,
they're,
they're kind of having to circle their
wagons and they become a bit more
extreme.
And so it might look on the surface
that things are getting worse.
But I think that's this defensive
mechanism where they can barely hold it
together.
And I think it won't end up with
homogenous one world religion,
one government.
We'll appreciate those
small things about the,
you know,
the local town,
where are you are,
you can appreciate the differences
even more when you feel part of the
commonality.
You don't have to be scared of the
differences cause there's something deeper
that connects it.
I think there's also a problem that
people have in the human beings.
We share chimpanzee Alpha male DNA
and we are always looking for leaders.
And Yeah,
the other problem is once
someone becomes a leader,
uh,
we see there was with
politicians and dictators,
we saw it with the people that that came
in after Mubarak in Egypt tried to pass
all these crazy fucking laws that
essentially made them dictators.
And then the people were like,
what are you talking about?
Like this is,
this is what we just shed blood for.
Like in you assholes are trying to make
yourself immune to prosecution for all
these different things
that you could be doing.
Like fuck you.
No,
you can't do that.
And I think seeing that
for the first time,
you know,
globally,
even though right now it may be very
frustrating for us and it is frustrating
for us because we don't think
change is coming quickly.
Enough change that the corresponds
with what we know about the world.
I think it is.
If you look at it historically,
if they look back to this time,
I think this will be a time of
great turmoil and great change.
It's just that we measure
history and he's 20,
30 year bursts.
You know,
and I think the 20 year bursts that
we're in right now is just bananas.
Well,
I think as I get older and
as I watch my kids grow,
that for me,
10 or 20 years is no
longer such a long time.
Right?
It's not.
And I think as you get older,
time speeds up to,
and so it's like those cops
that were there so you can,
so you can,
but we're not quite so scared.
Parts are late.
And the um,
the side
of having a 20,
30 year plan or even to recognize as all
the spiritual traditions talked about
is that,
uh,
these great things are not accomplishable
in one generation or buy one in one
lifetime.
So that we just start the
process are we not start it,
but we continue and then we try to
pass it on to the next generation.
But I think that there is this,
you know,
intensification and crisis and
in that I think eventually the,
um,
the,
the fundamentalists,
we'll need to find more
genuine spirituality,
not in this rigidity and hopefully
they'll be able to coexist.
There was these demonstrations
of millions of in Egypt,
the,
you know,
against the Muslim broaden brotherhood.
This is the first government in Israel
that doesn't have the religious orthodox
as part of the governing body,
which is a really healthy thing.
This,
what does it who,
who made that quote history is a race
between education and catastrophe.
Who's that?
Who is responsible for that quote?
You know,
I don't know.
That's,
yeah.
I don't remember who it was.
Whoever it was.
They were bad motherfucker,
whoever it was.
But that's a,
that's really what seems to be going on.
Was it hg wells?
Yeah,
that was good.
That there really does seem to be,
well of course it's a,
she was,
the guy was awesome.
Um,
I think that that does
seem to be what's going on.
It seems to be also that sometimes
it almost feels like people need an
antagonist in order to
perform at their very best.
It's almost like we need a rival to
inspire us to reach great heights.
Yeah.
And it depends on how you see them.
If they're deeper down your ally,
so that like,
let's say in sports teams,
you know,
you want your opponents to be as good as
possible because that will call out the
best in you.
So at some level you want the worthy
opponent that you don't have to totally
destroy.
You just are sort of
coal valving together.
So I think we do need to
test ourselves against,
against others and against our ourselves,
but we don't need to see the other
side as the enemy to be destroyed.
And I think,
uh,
I used to play this game,
um,
grew up in Chicago in Winnetka and Lake
Michigan and some friends and I would go
in there and we'd play the greatest
catch game and each of us guys,
we'd throw a football to somebody else.
It was like half in the water.
And our,
our goal as the thrower was to get it
just barely where they could reach it,
where they had to make the spectacular
dive and show off to everybody how great
they were and then they
would have to do it back.
And so we are sort of helping.
We are,
we are like allies,
but we were pressing each other to,
to do spectacular things.
That's really interesting.
Well that's one of the principles of a,
of Jujitsu and a martial arts is that
you really only as good as your training
partners.
Yeah.
Have you trained with really good people,
you become really good and that's you.
You elevate to the level of the
competition in the training room.
It's also the same a lot with a standup
comedians were inspired by other really
funny standup comedians.
And when you find a particular group
of group of talented people in a,
in a town or an area,
oftentimes they'll develop a lot of
very talented people around them who we
imitate the fact that you know that
there's a high level of the art form and
that area.
So like Austin,
Texas is a good example.
It's like there's always a lot of really
good guys there and because there's
always a lot of really good guys there,
there's always a lot of really good guys.
There is a New York city's and other one,
but obviously this much more money
involved in places like New York or La and
being good.
So that becomes sort of a factor as,
but are you from
us?
Did you spend time in Austin?
No,
I just have a lot of friends there
and I've done a lot of stand up there,
but I just know the local
scenes or he's really strong.
So there's a few places in
the country as a comedian,
the scene,
the local scenes are very strong.
Denver,
they always have a really
strong local scene.
And that's another one that's pure because
it's not really attached to Hollywood
and any way it's just pure standup comedy.
And then there's San Francisco,
um,
Boston,
La,
New York,
little bit of Phoenix a little bit,
but it's,
it's a very limited thing.
And you can sometimes one or two
great comedians will be in one area.
And then boom,
it'll blossom.
Like,
um,
Houston was Sam Kinison and Bill Hicks.
They were all at this Houston comedy
annex and because of them in this one
particular area,
it started to take off.
Yeah.
That's sort of the idea of silicon valley.
Yeah,
sure.
Get a bunch of brilliant people and you
get inspired by other brilliant people.
They share ideas.
They,
they,
you know,
they pump each other up.
And the idea that there's plenty for
everybody and that working together can be
much more satisfying and you're,
you're much happier if your friends
are doing well as much as you are.
Yeah.
In fact,
one of our,
um,
uh,
Shawna haylight when,
if our board of directors who recently
died was a brilliant computer guy and he
kept trying to say that,
that we should try to think from
abundance rather than from constant need.
And Yeah.
Well that's a,
that's a,
just a,
a general principle of life.
Famine mentalities are terrible way of
approaching life and that's the way a lot
of people approach life.
They approach life as if there's a finite
amount of resources and they have to
get theirs.
And that's what leads to
people cheating on their taxes.
That's a reason people lying,
trying to steal money and stealing money
from their employers and shit along
those lines.
They're coming from,
from a,
a standpoint of famine.
Like there's stockpiling
nuts for the winter,
right?
They're not as comfortable about their
ability to generate new resources.
And that's,
that's a terrible mentality.
And that is a mentality and that,
that sort of,
those sort of philosophies and those
ideas can be reinforced or they can,
the opposite can be reinforced.
Uh,
uh,
generous bountiful mentality
can be enforced as well.
Yeah.
Well for us,
I mean,
it's going to be 15 to $20 million
to make Mtma into a medicine.
And the same for Psilocybin or LSD
and we don't have all that money.
It's crazy.
But it caused pharmaceutical
companies way,
way more than that.
It should cost the amount that it
costs to get one guy high on Mtma.
He should do it and go,
oh,
listen to me and make it legal for us.
Just stop.
Stop the bullshit.
Yeah.
But we've had to have that attitude
that the resources are out there.
And once we can demonstrate that
we can use them wisely as we grow,
the resources will grow.
And so far,
you know,
we're in our 27th year and
that's what's what's happening.
How happy are you now that you're seeing
all this like really tangible progress,
real tangible progress,
very happy.
But I'm also,
uh,
because I woke up to all this in
1971 and 72 right after the backlash.
Um,
I'm concerned a lot.
I'm trying to be very sensitive
about another backlash today.
I think it's possible.
I don't think it's impossible.
I don't think it's likely right now.
It just seems,
it seems like the information,
it's just too prevalent.
Well,
but how would you explain the fact that
we can't even do marijuana research?
Maybe there's a massive repression.
And so if all those
people should be in jail,
that's really what should happen.
Someone should realize what's going
on and start locking people up.
And I go,
let's play your game because
what you're doing is ridiculous.
You're ruining people's lives for
something that really should not be your
choice.
It should not be another person's
choice whether or not they masturbate.
And it should not be another person's
choice whether or not they smoke pot.
And it's really along the same lines.
Yeah,
well I'm not so sympathetic
with putting them in jail,
but I would like to take
the source of their power,
which is people's fear that they've
generated and others and try to get more.
That's why I'm so glad to
be talking with you in this,
you know,
podcasts to people to
try to educate them to,
to realize that there is a way where
we can work together and make things
better.
I agree.
But I think the people that have done
things that have put people in jail for
things along those lines for,
for selling pot or for growing
pot or from owning pot there,
they're criminals.
Those are societal criminals.
Well,
I'd say that they have a bridge to other
people's human rights without a doubt.
And they have done so with
full cultural support.
And I think the way to move forward is
not to be so punitive for those that did
it.
Although for some,
I mean,
uh,
but,
but to talk about evolution and to
talk about how a different approach is
necessary.
And you know,
whenever I'm in Alaska,
when there was a medical
marijuana legalization bill
one of the first years ago,
there was this whole idea of reparations
to pay people that were in jail and the
polling that was done by the politic,
by the people trying to
pass this initiative.
Um,
it showed that that
was a really weak part.
So where you try to impose these penalties
on people for past behavior that at
time was sort of socially sanctioned.
What I meant by that was the,
the people that are actively working
like privatized prison unions and things
along those lines,
working to keep these drugs illegal
so that they profit and that's creepy.
There's,
yeah,
there's some real reprehensible
shit that's going on.
It's not as simple as they're acting
within culturally defined rules and
regulations.
There's some behind the scenes shady
shit that's based on deception.
Well that the stuff like
that is should be illegal,
you know?
But I think that the corporate
capitalistic approach
that we have does permit
that
kind of stuff.
And it permits lobbying
congress and it permits this,
this process where people try to get their
own interests advanced sometimes over
the interests of others.
And isn't it fascinating that,
I don't know if you feel like this,
but that the thing that would fix the
woes that society has more than anything
is a thing that these people were
trying to keep from becoming legal.
I,
that might be the big race.
The big race might be recognizing that
there are some fantastic tools to change
the consciousness of this culture.
Right.
And I think that idea of thinking about
them as tools is really the crucial
distinction because they're not
good or bad in and of themselves.
It's how they're used.
And our whole drug policy is,
there's good,
bad,
good drugs and bad drugs,
bad drugs are illegal and good
drugs and get a burger king.
Yeah.
Or from the pharmaceutical company.
But it's all about good and bad
when it's actually how you use it.
And even the drug that was demonized the
most in a way in the 50s in the 60s was
thalidomide.
The drug that was the medical drug
that caused birth defects in babies.
And the FDA stopped that in the u s
but it was prevalent throughout Europe.
And now thalidomide has become a Madison
and the same kind of shrinking of blood
vessels and things.
It's used in leprosy and it's
used in cancer treatment.
So a drug that was among
the most demonized of all
has now been approved by the
FDA with certain kinds of
safety procedures to make
sure pregnant women don't
get it.
But it's the idea that these are tools
and we have the ability to approach these
tools in an intelligent way and a
respectful way or in a reckless way.
And what we want to do is try to change
these value judgments and prohibition,
support people's human rights to
explore their own consciousness.
Uh,
they have freedom of thought and to
find a way to integrate into a society
that's moving forward.
How do you do that?
By getting through the corruption because
that's the only thing that's holding
it back.
Really the only thing holding it back
is corruption at this point with the
amount of data that's been
accumulated on medical marijuana.
Well,
okay.
It,
the amount of data
that's been accumulated,
the,
the government has been effective.
The,
the DEA parts of the government Niva in
preventing what's called the phase three
studies,
the large scale definitive studies
that by law congress has created,
FDA must have to prove
safety and efficacy.
So at this moment there is not enough
data of the kind that the FDA uses for any
other drug.
And if we accept the idea that the
FDA should regulate marijuana and
psychedelics,
like they do any other drug,
then we have to acknowledge that there's
not enough research for the FDA to
approve it.
It's people twist it and say the FDA
has rejected marijuana as a medicine,
which they have not.
We just don't have enough research that
way and they won't allow you to do phase
through research.
And so that's why the states,
I think have enough evidence to make
it legal and patients and doctors have
enough evidence to decide to try it.
It's just that in our system that
we've created to try to make it so that
through science we don't
just see what we want to see,
but we kind of have a
closer view of what's there.
There are these procedures that still
need to be undertaken for marijuana and
also from an May.
So that's why I say we're probably
10 years away from making Mtma into a
medicine and I think we'd be five,
six years away from making marijuana
into an FDA approved medicine if the
repression would be lifted right today.
Now,
what are the,
what is the difference between the stage
that the FDA FDA requires and the data
that has been accumulated?
Well for,
there's the preclinical stage,
so what that means is preclinical
clinical means humans.
So there's a whole series of animal
studies looking at toxicity that are
required by the FDA before you
can get a drug into humans.
Once you've done that,
then there's phase one,
two,
three and four and phase one is working
with people who are not patients who are
healthy volunteers to try to categorize
what the drug does and what it does at
different doses.
And for certain drugs that are
especially toxic like cancer drugs,
they have like phase one,
a phase two where it's a combination where
the drug is so dangerous that it only
can be used in patients.
And so you do these dose finding studies,
looking at the side
effects and it in general,
that's what phase one is.
Phase two is where you start working
with patients and you start seeing what
does it do?
What is it good for?
How good is it?
What are your measures?
How well did your measures work?
How do you do the double blind to make
sure you're not seeing what you want to
see?
What is your scientific
methodology for the studies?
Um,
what is your treatment approach?
What dose are you using?
The,
that's for phase two.
And that can take years
and years and years.
I mean we've been phase to,
uh,
for Mtma for,
about nine years so far.
Wow.
Yeah.
Starting in 2004 is when
we got the first permit.
We actually had permission in 2000 from
2000 and 2001 in Spain for Mtma for
PTSD.
And we had some media attention that was
very positive on the radio and the main
TV and newspapers and radio and it
motivated the anti-drug authority,
the forces of oppression
to shut the study down.
And we weren't powerful enough
to overcome it in Spain.
And that's where it was first
started though with a study that,
that we were working with
women survivors of rape with.
Okay.
But then you've got phase two.
So then once you have figured out
your designs and the magnitude and the
variance of the effect,
how strong is it and how common is it?
Is there a large number of people that
don't respond at all or do most people
respond then you can size
your phase three studies?
So with marijuana,
we have enormous amount of information
up to the phase two level and the FDA
will have more information about marijuana
Mtma LSD than about any other drug
that they've ever approved
in their entire history.
And the reason is because they,
the research is usually done with
hundreds or thousands of people.
10,000 is about as high as you go.
But we've had LSD used by tens of millions
of people and marijuana by hundreds
of millions of people.
And we know the one,
one in a million side effects or the one
in 5 million side effect that we only
discover from pharmaceutical
drugs once they're approved.
So it would not take a long time.
We already know that we
would work with marijuana,
with a nausea control for cancer,
chemotherapy,
marijuana for pain,
particularly for people on opiates
because we've already shown in phase two
studies funded by the state of California
that when you combine marijuana with,
uh,
opiates,
that people get better pain control and
they don't need as much of the opiates
and because of Oxycontin
and all these big concerns.
So we know the areas that we would study
with marijuana and we know the safety
profile.
So we mainly need to just do studies
and 200 5,500 people to look at the
particular patient groups
that we want to approve.
We have to get high quality standardized
medical grade marijuana to do it in.
Um,
and so maybe we're five years away if
the political barriers were removed right
today,
which they're not.
What happens
to someone that takes LSD and goes crazy
because I've had many people tell me
stories.
I know the Syd Barrett story from
a pink Floyd is a famous one.
I don't know if it's true,
but that was the word was that he had
taken too much acid and lost his mind.
I think it's possible,
but it depends on the supporters context.
And before you ask them about
the candy flipping about MDA,
Lsd,
so in in the future when people are
having this very difficult LSD experience,
maybe they go to the
emergency room or something.
Adding Mtma takes it from this
terrifying sense of dying.
You go destruction and grounds it
so that people can work through it.
So I think that LSD has that potential
to destabilize people but in a supportive
environment that can be helpful
and handled in support it.
So that's fascinating.
The candy flipping aspect over the
adding end VMA might mitigate some of the
negative effects of the stress
that you could get from the,
the acid experience.
Oh yeah.
Completely.
Yeah.
And then you can,
so you know,
one possible,
um,
thing we would like to study one day
would be to take people who are dying and
start them like we did in Switzerland.
Start them with LSD and
four later administer MTMA.
So that way LSD peaks in
around three and a half hours,
three,
three and a half hours.
So they go through the whole challenging
Lsd of letting go of opening up and
it's,
you know,
hopefully they can make it through that.
And then at the four hours you give Mtma
and then everything softens and they
can take it in more.
And then they integrate
as they're coming down.
Oh,
so you ride one wave run to the next year,
or if they're flipping out,
if it's too painful or
too difficult for them,
maybe at the one at the two hours you
could administer it Mtma there and you
don't even have to minister
full dose of MD May.
It'd be like a half dose of Md Mace
softens it somewhat because they have a
synergistic effect.
Yeah,
they do.
They do.
They go the two of them together.
What's the difference between,
well,
it's more like,
um,
there,
there's an expansion aspect to it,
but there's a grounding aspect as well.
So you think that's a really
good combination then?
That's how I,
I think it is.
Yeah.
On the other hand,
for,
um,
you know,
sometimes for spiritual purposes,
let's say,
uh,
where people are looking
for this ego dissolution,
um,
you know,
you start with Lsd,
you start with Psilocybin,
you know,
sometimes the experiences last day,
10,
10 hours or more.
Sometimes if you don't fully,
if you open up to the
energy flowing through you,
then the psychedelic experience tends
to take a shorter amount of time.
And if you end into this resistance,
because for whatever reasons
it's really difficult.
It prolongs the experience and once
you enter into those kinds of places,
if you were to add Mtma,
then people can integrate
it more helpfully.
Have you done any studies,
like with the differences between like
hippie flipping and candy flipping using
mushrooms instead of,
uh,
is there any difference to that or,
well again,
we haven't done any studies,
right?
This can't be because combining
drugs but more or less it's,
it's similar.
MTMA blends with ketamine,
even MTMA grounds people
with ketamine ground shame.
Why not about it?
What did it,
it's probably going to turn
out to be like a jack and coke.
Well people were like,
why didn't you guys do this?
From the beginning it was my
favorite thing in college.
It was so hard to find.
But when you did you,
you bought a lot and you just saved,
you sat on this.
How did you do it?
Did in terms of the timing,
cause I I'm talking about where,
you know,
did you take them both at the same time
or actually a designed together where it
was like,
it was like a candy where it
had both of the chemicals in it.
That's the only way I've ever done it.
Now I've done it since then but done it
separately with mushrooms and then just
taking,
you know,
uh,
yeah I think it was,
I took it when I was peaking.
I would dose myself with the Mali,
which would then take whatever an hour
or so 45 minutes later you'd start
feeling it.
But yeah,
it's great.
I love those two together.
If you need any,
if there's a way to sign
up to any of your things,
let me know.
I was robbed by gunpoint so I got the
post traumatic stress if you need that.
Well we need people to be,
it's not as easy as getting a prescription
for marijuana to get a nurse study
sheet.
We have independent raters.
She would have to have treatment resistant
means you have to have had PTSD and
diagnosis.
Very minor compared to
like a soldier PTSD too.
They're dealing with
real debilitating issues.
You just got freaked out one night.
Well I got a gun in my chest and I
thought I was going to die and it was,
I scared of black people for six months
and it still comes back to me once in a
while when it's dark out.
Right,
right.
Well people can sign up online to
donate to maps because we're funded by
individuals.
The pharmaceutical companies aren't
interested because these drugs are off
patent and they're only
offered a few times.
So far we've not been able
to get a government grant,
although we are working with the
national instead of mental health.
And we are,
uh,
Senator Rockefeller from West Virginia
recently sent a letter to the assistant
secretary of defense for health affairs,
um,
saying that,
uh,
MDA PTSD research should be looked into.
So,
but we have yet to obtain any kind of
federal funding or pharmaceutical funding
or major pharmaceutical
or major foundations.
So we're more individuals and family
foundations trying to bring this,
um,
research forward.
Well,
I think what you're doing
is awesome cause you,
you,
you guys are bringing legitimacy to this.
It would never be done by guys like
Brian or myself and a or any of the other
people that are out there
enjoying the fruits of your labor.
And the fact that these doors have
been broken down now on or open,
I should say,
and work is being done and evidence is
being put forth that really can't be
refuted anymore.
It's slowly but slowly
starting to accumulate.
Yeah.
I would say that this can't be refuted.
We're right now we're at this stage
where we have to replicate our results
because that's the key part of science.
You,
you may have done it once,
but can you do it again
and again and again?
And that's where we have still to prove.
So we haven't completely
proven our case yet.
Uh,
but it's,
you know,
moving,
we hope in that direction.
Oh,
that's awesome man.
And I think,
uh,
I think there's really
exciting things coming up.
I really do.
I feel like our culture
is starting to shift.
And a,
I think it's stuff like what
you're doing is a big part of that.
Getting that information,
having that on the Internet land,
allowing people to share links,
allowing people to go to,
whether it's maps.org or any
of the different website.
erowid.org era was a great website.
Their fiscal
sponsor,
we went to college together.
We try to help other
organizations in that way.
Um,
I think this idea of getting
honest information out for
people to make their own
decisions.
Yeah,
that's what we're about.
It's a matter of time,
right?
Hopefully.
Yeah.
Well my dad is hilarious.
My Dad is 86 and three quarters and
he sent me an email today and it said,
uh,
here's a link to an
about a marijuana reform.
And he said,
oh,
it's going to be legal in my lifetime.
Wow.
I was like,
Dad.
I said,
I hope you're right.
You know,
even if you have to live another 20 years,
I would have never thought in
2013 it was still being illegal.
And when I was a kid,
I would,
I thought it was a matter of time.
Well,
I was on the board of normal for awhile,
quite awhile and I was with people who
started normal in 1970 and 71 and thought
it would be legal in a few years.
So that sort of temper is my,
uh,
sense of time to be with people who,
you know,
over 40 years ago thought it was only
going to be a few years away that
marijuana would be legal.
Unfortunately they're still working
to try to help bring that about.
Do you lose enthusiasm sometimes when
you see that it's still illegal after all
this?
No,
it's the um,
it's about,
it's a worthy,
like on a worthy opponent.
It's a worthy goal.
And so I think we just
do what we want to do.
There's times when I felt like I was so
blocked that I needed to do something
where I could actually see change.
And so I stopped work for
a week and painted my house
and that was great.
That's real.
Must must get some feel like you're
spinning your wheels sometimes.
Well for years and we just spent four
years with a Health Canada to trying to
get an import export permit to
bring in eight grams of MDA.
And this is after Health Canada had
approved the protocol and our IRB had
approved of protocol and the,
uh,
four years it took and they went through
all these ridiculous things about the
pharmacy had to have bulletproof glass,
it had to have all these alarm systems,
class people are going to come in
and steal your eight grams of acid.
That was eight grams.
Yeah.
That would be in a safe and the safe had
to be disguised in a wooden cabinet and
the safe had to be bolted to them before
they went harder than the u s it was
ridiculous.
But we eventually,
you know,
prevailed.
We just took every ridiculous
thing and we did it.
I mean,
my policy is surrender.
You know,
when there's certain kinds of irrational
things coming from people who are more
powerful,
try to give it to them.
Well that's probably why you're in the
position that you're in your facilitator
of this.
I'm willing to dialogue venture forth.
Yeah.
And there are parts that are exciting,
that are connections that you know,
are just coming together.
Like even for the national
incident mental health there,
there was a,
um,
uh,
in the late 1980s,
the fellow who's the current head of the
nationalist of mental health was doing
Mtma neurotoxicity research in animals.
And I visited him and he was,
um,
you know,
this sort of hidden away in the
countryside animal research lab to,
you know,
not attract all these
animal rights protesters.
And we had to go through all his
guards and Barb wire and stuff.
But he seemed like he was
sincerely interested in the
question and wasn't trying
to twist the results to
justify the drug war.
And we developed a respect.
I certainly respected him.
And about two years ago,
year and a half ago,
I wrote him an email and
I hadn't talked to him.
And since that point he's now become
the head of the national incident mental
health.
And I just said,
is now a good time to apply
for a grant for MD May,
PTSD research or is it so politically hot?
It's just not worth it.
And he said,
now is the time.
And he appointed someone else inside the
Nmh who is an expert at PTSD to help us
prepare applications that are
more likely to be accepted.
But what he did say is that the actual
decisions are made by peer reviewers,
the way they've set up for
government money to be distributed,
that they bring in the scientist.
And he said the system of peer review
as well known not to be sympathetic with
innovation.
So even though we have all the support,
it's still may not work.
It's hard to get systems to
accept innovation and change.
What can people at home that are
listening to this podcast or watching it,
what can they do to,
to help you to help keep
this momentum going?
Well,
first off,
become a member.
Um,
sign up for a monthly membership.
we just had the incredible conference.
We're a psychedelic science 2013 largest
psychedelic conference that we've ever
had in the u s over 1900 people.
There's a whole,
I WASC attract the biggest Iowasca,
uh,
conference ever and clinical research.
And um,
I was approached by a more Amara,
this group that helps groups crowdsource
a transcription and translation of
these talks and videos are
not searchable on Google,
but when you do a transcript or
if you do transcript of the shows,
people can then search on the transcripts
in that gets them to the video.
So people,
if they're interested,
and it would be a tremendous
thing for them to learn to,
to go to the maps website,
map s.org to our psychedelic science 2013
conference page and you could sign up
if you wanted to listen
to some of these lectures,
which are tremendous and transcribe
or translate them if you know other
languages.
Awesome.
Yeah,
there's other things people could do.
I just have a Twitter page.
We have Twitter,
we have a map maps.
News apps do is,
yeah,
we have a tremendous
social media team already.
Remember we are going to do a Indiegogo
campaign starting probably in a week or
so to raise $10,000 for the Zendo
project at burning man are harm reduction
program so people could tell
other people about that.
And then we're going to go,
as we said earlier,
to a probably a $250,000 request for
the study with veterans with Mtma.
Um,
I think people can come
out to their families,
people can come out to people that they
just talk about and not be so reticent
if psychedelics been helpful or
even if they've not been helpful,
you know,
to talk about how,
what they learned about,
about what they think are these tools.
Maybe they use them poorly,
maybe they used them well,
but I think look at the
gay rights movement and
thinking about this,
the wrong tool for the wrong job too
because they didn't have education about
it.
Yeah.
And we're finding that
people that sometimes you
psychedelics at festivals for
what I would say is the wrong reason,
just to have a fun time
and not the right reason.
Well you told us it's beautiful,
but I think you have to be
ready for the difficult stuff.
And if you're trying to
suppress the difficult stuff,
that's when people get into trouble.
You should have more joking around.
But I think the celebratory
use is really important.
And that's why for us medicalization is
not the for maps as a five o one c three
not change to change the laws.
We're about medicalization.
But I think as a society
we need spiritual use.
We need personal growth,
creativity.
We need a broader drug policy,
which would have adults have
the right to use psychedelics.
I think it would be like the driver's
license model where you would perhaps have
a certain education,
you have to pass a test and
maybe even to start out.
So we avoid backlash.
There would be psychedelic clinics where
you would go have an experience under
supervision and if you did it well,
uh,
meaning you didn't totally
flip out or you know,
then you would have the
right to buy it on your own.
And I think what we
would do with children,
I think drugs would be illegal for minors,
legal for adults.
But 23 states in the United States have
a parental override for alcohol that if
you want to give your
kid alcohol in 23 states,
you can do that.
And I think that that's how we
handle under h is that we leave it,
not the government prohibited at all,
but that it's families decide among
themselves how they want to handle it.
That's awesome.
One more question then
I'm gonna let you go.
Uh,
Terence Mckenna's stoned ape
theory was a fascinating,
the proposal that human beings evolved
from lower hominids because we got in
contact with psychedelic
mushrooms and his theory,
I don't know if it's correct,
but according to him and his brother,
his brother,
um,
if you just Google search the,
uh,
Dennis Mckenna podcast,
I don't remember which number it is.
You can find it pretty easily
and it with a quick search.
But he gave some really
interesting scientific reasons
for why he believes it's,
it's a very possible that
that's what happened.
The doubling of the human brain size
over a period of 2 million years.
All this attributed to sy silicide.
Well,
Dennis was one of the speakers at the
conference and so people could actually
translate and transcribe
his talk if they wanted.
Awesome.
Beautiful.
But I think that the,
the,
the deeper question is can the apes
that we are today evolve further with
mushrooms?
And I think answer to that is clearly
yes clear whether the apes of several
million years or a hundred thousand years
ago it used mushrooms.
It's certainly plausible and I
hard to say one way or the other.
I am not in a position to
say I believe it or not.
I think Terrence said some
things that were pretty um,
exaggerated.
Like this whole idea that the end of the
Mayan calendar was going to be the end
of the world.
And while I was in a cable,
well he talked about a massive
constants in a shift and it would all be
different and like per space,
he talked about that we were going
to reach a point of technological
singularity.
He thought that we were going to reach
a point of infinite novelty and that
right tracking it with his TimeWave
zero algorithm that he created,
he created this really sketchy thing
when he was on mushrooms because based on
the each thing that's supposedly a map
novelty or human innovation that you
could put it through a graph.
But I think when you
get really fucking high,
you could see patterns in almost anything.
Yes.
And he had this,
this eating pattern that he had chased
down for like 20 plus years in created a
formal mathematical program.
He had some,
uh,
mathematical experts actually engaged him
in dialogue and one's in disagreement,
right?
Yeah.
So I think if,
if you know,
Dennis Mckenna just wrote a book brothers
at the screaming abyss and there's a
good discussion about some of the
criticism and the value of time wave zero.
So I was actually,
Terrance was the one that started help
start MTMA research because we were at a
conference at Esselyn,
it was in 1983 and it was already clear
because of Dallas and stuff that Mtma
was being used in public setting.
And that the crackdown would come.
And so the underground therapists
and the shoguns chemists,
so we had this meeting
to figure out what to do.
Um,
and Terrence was like,
forget about Mtma it's from the lab.
It's gotta be a plant,
you know,
mushrooms,
thousands of years,
plants are better,
you know,
we can trust them,
they're from nature and you know,
and look at all these risks
of Mtma and all this stuff.
And I was like,
well,
I don't see these risks.
And so,
um,
and I also don't believe that plants are
drugs from plants are inherently better
tools that,
that we're part of nature that comes
from the human mind is out there.
So I said,
I'll put up $1,000 towards an MDA study.
We'll see how risky it really is.
And then Dick Price,
who founded Eslan like 30 seconds,
10 seconds later,
said,
I'll put up a thousand hours.
And so it was in response to Terrence
going on about plant medicines being best
and MD may being super dangerous that we
did this study and kept it quiet until
the DEA moved to criminalize.
And then we surfaced with the study.
That's interesting.
Well that's great.
Yeah,
that's very funny.
I've always wanted to hear different
people's take on that fear because I
thought it was a fascinating theory.
The idea that humans became
us because of psychedelics.
And the best culprit is mushrooms
because they're like sort of built in.
You don't have to cook and
you have to do anything weird.
You don't have to,
you know,
extract anything,
just chew away and boom,
here comes the boom.
Well,
I felt when I had my bar Mitzvah when
I was 13 it did not turn me into a man
coming of age.
That's a really unrealistic
expectation to 13 shit.
I mean I was the oldest of four.
That's what my parents,
so that's what I expect.
That belt went,
came up with that back when
people only live in to be 30 yeah.
So when I,
and I was disappointed,
I was the same.
It was really Bauer.
I was like,
I remember being in bed for the whole
week and I'm thinking a lot of people must
have had their bar mitzvahs
that day and God must be slow.
And he'll come around to me eventually.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
You know,
and then finally,
nothing happened.
And I just was sad about it.
But when I took LSD for the first time,
I felt that it touched the parts of my
psyche that I had hoped my bar Mitzvah
would touch.
Wow.
That was d better than Barmitzvahs next
you got to mean so far the show.
Well,
thank you very much,
Rick.
This is a really awesome glad we could
pull it off to spite the gay pride parade
in the Illuminati.
Trying to hold it back.
I made it happen.
Go to maps.org Ladies and gentlemen,
and uh,
what is it?
Maps,
uh,
news on Twitter.
Please follow that as well.
And Facebook.
And let's do this again sometime.
Yeah,
I figured have done it three
hours if I wasn't so tired.
Yeah.
Well,
I uh,
maybe you should have tried modafinil.
I want to sleep.
Thank you.
Everybody
tuned into the podcast.
Thanks to Ting for sponsoring us.
Go to a rogan.ting.com and save yourself
some cash or an awesome company.
Thanks also to audible.com
go to audible.com forward
slash Joe four your free
audio book and 30 days
free of honorable service.
And thanks also to legal zoom.
If you use the code name
Rogan in the referral box,
you could save some cash.
Legal Zoom is not a law firm,
but they provide self help services
at your specific direction.
Thanks also to [inaudible]
dot com that's o n N.
I t.
Use the code named Rogan and
save yourself some money.
Uh,
we will be back some day this week.
I'm working carets the hours,
so I,
I hardly know what day it is or what's up.
Um,
I'm a mess lately,
but um,
we'll see freaks in Vegas.
Look,
Joey Diaz and I are playing
in Vegas at the joint,
uh,
in the hard rock this Friday night.
There's some tickets
still available and uh,
it should be an awesome weekend
cause it's a UFC weekend.
So that's July 5th,
Friday night,
the joint in Hollywood.
All right,
we love you and we'll see you soon.
[inaudible].