Do do
hello world.
What's up?
What's going on?
Rather than my man back from fucking
Canada back from Canada.
Awesome.
What was that experience like for you?
Well,
that experience was,
besides doing mushrooms and running
around the woods by yourself.
Experienced.
Exclude that or you can exclude that
from me.
That's like taking away of fighters.
Ability to talk about fighting.
We're up in Canada,
bear hunting and are we decided to do
mushrooms?
Go run off into the woods.
I had to check in.
Know I understand it's on the right
path.
Yeah.
That was fucking.
It was powerful,
man.
Super powerful because bears,
as I was telling you,
bears have come to me and my visions.
Do An eyewash Osca and everything since
the drop from the very first time I was
doing,
I was Osca bears were coming to me and
teaching me lessons and I was talking to
him.
So what kind of lessons,
man?
The first time it came was the first
time I did it and I saw this bear and it
was wrapped up in all these chains and
it was struggling against these gold
chains.
It's like a Mr. t dot bear had like
fucking crown and these heavy gold
chains and he was stuck and I couldn't
move and the bear like stopped.
She was like kind of frantic trying to
get out of these chains.
He stops and looks at me and he goes,
I remember when I was just a bear and I
didn't have to worry about all this shit
and it was less than about the wealth
that we have can become like a prison
that holds us back.
It prevents us from being our true
nature with the bears.
True natures.
You'd be in a bear chasing after shit,
eating shit,
climbing trees.
But the wealth that had accumulated
prevented it from doing that.
What a bizarre weird.
Right?
Is that like what?
Who's teaching you that?
Like what,
what is that your imagination?
Is that like,
what's going on with that?
I know I have no idea.
And,
and that's,
you know,
it just appeared to me.
That's the funny thing.
Like it's so strange.
It feels real.
Like this is a spirit guide teaching it,
but it very well could be your
imagination.
But man,
I'm not that creative to think about a
bear and gold chains telling me a lesson
about wealth.
I have a thought on that,
that we look at the imagination and we
say,
oh,
he's just imagining things.
But everything in the world is from the
imagination.
Every building,
every airplane,
every car,
every piece of clothing,
every computer,
everything came out of the imagination.
Everything.
I think the imagination is something
really fucking weird.
And it.
I think we've somehow or another,
we've almost like,
no,
I don't want to say underestimated,
be underrated.
We put it into this weird little
category.
Like it's a silly thing.
Oh,
you're just imagining.
And that allows it to operate and by,
by underrating it or by undervaluing it,
it allows it to sort of roam free and do
all of it's work.
But it's responsible for creating
everything that we see the humans have
ever done in the world.
Yeah.
It gets interesting for me too,
and you think about these mythical
creatures like bigfoot and dragons and
things like that.
When we create them,
we actually create the light,
the neurons in our brain that form
around that memory and that
concept.
Even if we draw a monster,
we've actually created that monster on
unlike a micro scale inside our brain
and it's just we value this macro scale
of the world where it actually breeds
and lives,
but we're actually assembling light in
our brains to create that thing that
we're imagining.
You know,
it's just on a very,
very small level and it doesn't have the
freedom and flexibility,
but we are really truly creating
entities all the time.
Brian.
Yeah.
I've really wondered about that with
aliens.
Would that archetypical alien,
the iconic gray with the large black
eyes and the like.
That thing is real now.
It's a real thing whether or not you
ever meet one or whether or not one
exists in the physical state where you
could drag it in front of the national
enquirer photographers and get some good
shots of it.
It's a real thing and what I mean by
it's a real thing is if you do
mushrooms,
you'll fucking see them.
You'll you will see them and do.
Are you seeing them because you did
mushrooms and you're hallucinating,
or are you seeing them because we've
created this archetype that plugs into
the imagination easily and connects you
to this thing,
this,
this imaginary world or this world that.
See,
I don't even like the word imaginary
because like every time I've done a
psychedelic,
I don't.
I don't like that word imaginary because
to me it seems like it's some sort of a
frequency that you're tuning into.
We're a real world exists that you can't
bring back anything physical from.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
Yeah,
and I feel like it's entirely possible
that what we think of as these,
these like gray aliens,
they're like a,
almost like a frequency of the universe
that you can tune into whether you're on
psychedelics or whether you're dreaming,
which is of course your brain producing
its own psychedelics.
Your brain produces dimethyltryptamine
while you're sleeping.
So these,
these things that we think of as being
like all these imaginary things like
aliens or bears that talk to you or
Hagens.
Yeah.
I wonder what the fuck that really is
all about.
I think you're really onto something
there,
but it seems like there's this archetype
of frequency,
like a dragon is a being of unlimited
power and we've imagined what that would
look like visually if that were an
animal,
what does it look like?
And a dragon just fits that so fucking
perfect with the wings and the Scales
and smaug from token.
Yeah.
And you're looking at that and like,
Oh yeah,
that fits that thing.
You know,
and you think about a cold,
dispassionate,
calculating machine that is dissecting
you like than,
Oh yeah.
Alien with the big eyes and the no nuts
that fits that
so that no vagina either.
They don't need that shit.
They just dispatched of it so that just
like we,
we create this visual representation of
this,
of this archetype.
Even Zeus,
Zeus should look,
look,
look like Zeus looks like we're good at
like the physical look of something to
this concept that is kind of very real.
Yeah.
We wouldn't trust Zeus if he had like a
dark goatee.
He's got to have a fucking white beard
and white hair.
He always says white hair.
Right.
Have you ever seen Zeus without white
hair?
Well,
I mean,
he turned into all kinds of shit.
He would turn into like a swan and rape
somebody and like golden missed and
rape.
Somebody was like a mass rapist was
constantly right,
but everybody.
It was the bill cosby of,
of ancient gods go in as a goal is
golden rain.
He raped somebody.
Got Pregnant as golden ring.
Wow.
That's rude.
Yeah.
Seriously.
What's the defendant?
Somebody as rain,
at least give them a heads up who
expects to go outside and just get raped
by the rain.
Good.
No.
It was also a convenient excuse.
If you got pregnant.
There was a sprinkle.
It was golden.
I think Zeus.
He's raping a dude there.
What's he doing that cutting off his
dad's Dick.
Oh,
good lawyers was the.
Was the titan.
They were always cutting off each
other's Dick and then they would throw
one,
think he threw one into the ocean and it
created some other tighten and cut his
own dad's Dick off.
Life was hard back then,
man.
That was a hard world.
Those people live.
Yeah,
for sure.
A bunch of Dick cut and assholes.
No doubt.
I really do wonder like what I mean,
there's,
it's,
it is,
uh,
an ent in empty wonder.
Like there's no end to it.
There's no way you'll ever going to
solve like no one's going to say,
oh,
we figured out exactly what's happening
when you tripping on mushrooms and here
is what it is and this is why,
you know,
you see these things and this is what
those things actually are.
And this is the part of your brain that
creates them and they're absolutely not
real.
Oh yeah.
Well,
there's the materialist reductionist
point of view,
like something that Sam Harris could
explain very well.
All right.
When you take psilocybin,
the default mode network and your brain
gets starved of blood which starves at
of oxygen,
which downregulates it,
allowing the other parts of your brain
to come forward,
like,
got it,
but then take some
and then see how that feels,
what that,
what comes through.
Yeah.
Well there's a chemical process,
right?
But then there's the experience and the
experiencing itself.
This is if you've heard me say this
before,
but this is kind of important.
The experience is exactly the same
whether or not it's in a physical form
or whether or not it's something that
happens to you while you're tripping the
experiences the same like if you have a
trip and during that trip you meet a
golden serpent that explains the
universe to you and it.
It explains that every single person is
in fact a representation of what we
think of as love,
love or or a God or creativity or some
divine force that is pushing forward
improvement and innovation and that that
is the reason why life today is so much
different than it was 30 years ago or 30
before that or 300 years before that.
It will constantly keep improving and it
is the way of the universe and that if
you.
If you have that in a psychedelic trip,
it's exactly the same as if it happens
to you.
Like if you go to a field and a dragon
rises out of a marsh and confronts you
with all of the problems of your
personality and all the mysteries of the
past and gives you an understanding and
a blueprint for how to move forward with
your life and then goes back in a swamp.
It's exactly the same as if you're
tripping.
Like the experience is the same.
Like whether like,
well we found the Dragon,
we've located him on gps and I look on
Google Earth.
You can see the dragon moving through
the marsh.
It's a real dragon.
It doesn't matter like physically if
it's a real dragon,
the experience is the same and the
impact that it has and that's the thing
that we're seeing now in these
scientific inquiries is that it's not
just you have this experience like go
into a movie and you come back out and
you're relatively the same afterwards.
These are having the lasting impacts and
the significant changes throughout a
lifetime that you would expect from a
huge event like you just described
happening in the real world because it
does feel real to you and the
information you're getting and the
experiences you have.
It changes you.
It's not like you put it in this dream
world like,
oh,
that was weird.
I saw this person naked in my dream,
but it's different.
You know,
that feels like kind of like random,
like you just shaken up some dice and
throwing it.
This stuff comes to you in a way that
just leaves a significant impact.
Yeah,
and the scientific reductionist point of
view is really important because we
really do need to understand what's the
chemical process that's going on in the
brain when you consume whatever pod,
whatever it is,
we need to understand.
I mean it's fascinating and it's
important for research and it's
important that science keeps moving
forward.
The greater and greater understanding of
the mind,
but it can't discount what is happening
as a human,
as a person,
as a,
an entity with consciousness.
What's happening during that experience
like you really you can really talk to
God really can meet him for sure.
I mean you and I've met them together
yet or met whatever the fuck we met,
whatever that is.
When you're in the DMT realm,
I don't know what that is,
but if there's a god that's cooler than
that holy shit,
and that's the thing.
It comes like the stories are not.
They're not inconsistent.
You'll go to these IOWASCA retreats.
You have 20 people and seven of them
will talk to God.
That's the same dude they're describing.
It doesn't matter what religion
background they come from.
You hadn't like pre discussed what this
notion is.
It's like the wisdom that comes through
from that element source or whatever you
want to call it God.
Or have you talked to mother earth that
the wisdom is all consistent and it's
weird that way.
You know?
It's like you never hear something like,
man,
that's strange.
It's really contradictory to what I what
he told me,
like to see some people given dmt,
like preferably the way strassman does
it cause strassman minus the anal plug
that made them think that aliens were
sodomized him.
There was an anal plug.
There was like an anal thermometer.
Oh,
check your core temperature.
Yeah.
That's not good.
It had everybody thinking that aliens
were raping them.
Zeus,
Zeus stuff.
Not the best idea.
Yeah.
Well is he.
Well,
there you go.
Like why?
Why is that?
Why are we thinking that aliens are
raping us?
Because there's something in your
breath.
It's obviously thermometer.
You're are you given knowledge of with
the mometer in your.
But before you go in there,
you are right.
Do they whisper in your ear?
I mean,
I don't know.
It's it.
The world itself is so fucking slippery.
You know,
they're just the world itself.
The idea that I'm looking at you through
my eyes were making noises with our
faces and somehow or another we're
translating this back and forth to each
other through this thing,
which is a microphone which works in a
way that neither new nor I can describe
to anybody.
Jamie.
Again,
it goes through these wires and it's
going wirelessly out into people's
phones.
I mean,
these people that are streaming it right
now live with their phone in their car,
driving around four g lte.
The fucking world is slippery as shit it
is,
you know,
it's amazing how fast we adapt though
humans are really good at adapting to
this new shit that comes in.
We almost adapt so fast that we take it
for granted way earlier than we should.
It's like,
oh yeah,
that thing.
Cool.
Got It.
Yeah.
There was an article about that recently
about how primate brains are sort of
predisposed to being able to adapt
incredibly quickly and that sort of
makes sense.
If you look at the wide variety of
cultures throughout the world and what
they think is normal,
what they accept,
like um,
those women in Africa that have those
giant plates in their lips.
Like how was like,
how did that get going?
Well the next that they will judge that
they stretched their necks out so far
and they have those things that they
couldn't support themselves.
Yeah,
there it is.
The primary brain is pre adapted to face
potentially any situation.
It's a really interesting article and
I'm not going to do a good job of it
without someone reading it,
but that's,
that's the title of it.
It's unfair.
[inaudible] dot org,
a p,
h,
a y s.org and it's the prime.
The title is the primate brain is pre
adapted to face potentially any
situation and it just talks about how
your brain sort of calculates potential
outcomes and all these different
variables that could possibly take
place.
So when it moves into that direction of
sorts of set the landscape.
When you look at how we developed and
you look at something like the genetic
bottleneck theory,
where these big cataclysms would happen
dramatically,
reduce the human population,
you're dealing with these macro changes
on a global level,
well,
the most flexible and adaptive are going
to survive the stubborn acids that are
like,
nope,
I'm not leaving my forte.
My Forte is my home.
This is a model and land like,
fuck that forest was burning in.
You got to go to the ocean.
You got to figure out how to fish quick.
There's food in the water,
figure out how to get that food on land
into your belly or you're not going to
make it.
You're not going to make it.
And those are the humans that have
survived.
So that trait will continue to be one of
the most important traits and obviously
it comes to the surface in these large
scale events.
Yeah,
that's why I've always laughed.
Like I told you a,
and I know you.
You rented a place there recently too.
I've rented a place in Malibu for awhile
on the beach and I'm like,
what the fuck kind of place is this like
you just banking.
That's something that's constantly
changing and moving and growing is going
to stick around long enough for your
investment to pan out,
you know,
because you made an investment.
Like these houses are worth fucking
millions of dollars and there's no yard
in the back because it's just the ocean
and without a doubt that ocean is going
to keep moving forward.
It's without a doubt.
It's just like,
how much time do you have?
It's like a long real estate game of
musical chairs.
Yeah.
I mean I was at the house and the waves
would hit underneath the house so hard
that the house would shake it around,
so it was like it was like a plan for am
high tide earthquake of the waves and
just like you're counting on the fact
that there isn't that rogue 15 footer
that comes in and just wipes out your
whole window.
I fucked up because the first day,
literally the first day we stayed there,
I got barbecued,
like barbecued on edibles and uh,
we were downstairs.
There's three floors to this house we
were renting in.
The first floor was literally the water
you would,
you could open the window and jump into
the water and it's a four foot drop and
I'm not exaggerating.
It's fucking ridiculous.
And in the daytime it looks so amazing.
It's so beautiful and Baloo and lovely
and the sea,
the birds and the waves are so gentle
and inviting.
But at nighttime in the dark,
it becomes a monster,
like giant,
dark,
black,
uncaring beast that will swallow you
whole and not give a fuck.
It's absorbed a billion people before
you.
It'll absorb you just as easy and you
realize the true nature of it.
When it's dark,
when it's dark,
you go,
oh,
this is like another world like you're,
it's like as if,
if you could get a high rise and that
high rise could like hit the edge of an
alternative galaxy.
It's like if you,
if you could like climb on top of your
roof and throw rocks into the event
horizon of a black hole and they would
disappear into another galaxy and that's
almost what it's like.
It's like it's another world.
Yeah,
and the farther you get out into the
deep,
crazier it gets,
right?
Because there's no limit on the depth.
You're going over one of those chasms
that are miles deep and had no fucking
idea what animals are in there.
And that's where these ideas of these
crackings,
these beasts,
the deep would come because he plays
with our subconscious.
It's outer space,
but in our planet and underneath us in
the water,
you know,
so you're just looking at this like,
man,
something could definitely come up there
and eat me.
Especially,
you know,
you don't have enough vitamin C,
you're getting too much sun,
you're a little delirious.
Then all of a sudden you'd fucking seen
mermaids and sea monsters and shit.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They,
they found cracking suction cups.
What do they call those things?
What do they call the suction cups?
Tentacles.
It's just suckers.
They found them in a fossilized form,
but that would indicate something that's
well over 100 foot octopus,
so that was a real animal at one point
in time.
So this idea of the crack.
The problem with those things is when
they die,
they just die.
Like there are soft tissue animal.
All they have is a beak and that gets
absorbed by the ocean too.
So there's virtually no evidence other
than these fossilized suction cups they
found.
But when they found him,
they went,
Whoa,
Holy Shit.
Because you're talking about,
you know,
like fucking garbage can lids that are
suction cups and you just think like,
well how big is the fucking technical
man?
Jesus Christ.
It's like an aggressive garbage disposal
is.
That is all the tentacles.
Grab everything that is soft enough to
get chomped by that beat,
grab it,
push it in and smart as fuck and fast.
Well,
there was another article recently where
the scientists were saying that
essentially octopuses are aliens.
There is nothing like them.
They have more chromosomes and any other
observed animal.
They're different than any observed
animal be besides cuddle fish.
Their ability to rapidly adapt and
camouflage themselves to their
environment is unprecedented.
They change their texture,
they changed what they look like.
I had a Ramey warrant on who's a great
guy and he has a television show called
Apex Predator and one of his,
one of his a apex Predator episodes and
in his show he's a hunter and he used to
be on the show called Solo hunter where
he would go by himself with like a bunch
of cameras and just go deep deep into
the woods and hunt and sort of ics and
capture this experience in this really
remote forest is in a really cool way
because it was literally just him like
survivor man style with a few cameras
setup and hunting and then cooking the
food and eating it and heading back and
running into some weird difficulties and
dangers and strange animals while he's
out there too,
but he did an episode on octopus and he
came in and was talking to us about it
and it fucking blew my mind.
Add no idea.
I don't mean I was 47,
48 years old.
I had no idea that a fucking octopus
could do that.
They can change like that instantaneous.
I think I've told this story on here
before,
but I got to see one in Fiji and watch
this.
Virgin man hunt it and it was one of the
craziest experiences ever.
They were.
It was flowing over the coral and just
like you said,
half of his body would be one color,
half the other color.
It was fast.
It wasn't like it weighted because we
have a noise and chameleons in Texas.
They plant somewhere and there's some
weird color that they're not supposed to
be and then eventually they turn into
Brown for tree bark or green for the
leaves or whatever they're at,
but not an octopus man.
That shit is instant,
instantaneous.
And when he was fighting it,
so he eventually goes down,
their jams,
his hand in there and the octopus bites
and there's blood in the water was this
crazy struggle.
But eventually he jams his hand back in
there,
pulls the octopus out,
and when he was fighting with the
octopus on the surface,
the octopus knew to go for his airway.
Like it was wrapping,
kept wrapping its tentacles around his
mouth and his nose as he was trying to
get this thing off his head.
He knew exactly what he was doing.
It was pulling off so eventually
wrestles is snorkel free and starts
beating it to get it to calm down.
And he brought it to the shore and
barbecued it.
Now everybody else was just fucking
horrified at this show because it was
completely savage.
I mean it was the octopus trying to
choke the airway of this primate in this
primate being stronger and more
determined and using a snorkel is a
bludgeoned to,
to kill it so he could eat it.
I think I want to.
I like octopus is delicious,
but I think on my backend off that there
might be a little too fucking smart for
me to be eating them.
Yeah.
But that's,
you know,
that's again that bias that have of all
of the things.
Like if people say,
oh no,
this animals too intelligent to eat,
but there are a pescatarian when they're
probably eating the fuck out of some
octopus,
which are way smarter than deer.
That's a good point,
you know,
like,
so it's just a weird.
It's a whole weird dynamic that we have
of what we decide we should or couldn't
do.
And here's a good point for people that
are vegans.
If you are a Vegan and you think you
need some form of protein other than I'm
like a look at this thing,
killing a shark.
Um,
if you need some sort of protein other
than I'm a ethically raised chickens,
eggs,
which is harmless and doesn't hurt
anybody,
but um,
mollusks apparently there's a real good
argument that they are incapable of
feeling any pain at all.
They don't have any fear.
They have zero emotions,
zero reaction.
They have one instinctive reaction to
close their shell.
And that's it.
Like they're barely an animal.
Get you some cashew milk.
Clam Chowder,
clam chowder is got milk in it.
That's what I said.
Oh,
that's right.
Okay.
Cashew milk.
Have you had this?
No,
I just made it up with somebody to do it
in Austin right now.
Someone's opening up cash register,
clam chowder,
fucking food truck.
But like um,
like scallops,
scallops are probably the most delicious
food on the planet.
Like pound for pound.
Yeah,
they're right up there.
And if they're,
if they don't,
if they're just like a meat thing,
it's like essentially what I'm saying is
there are,
there are like,
you know,
how they have the scientists that are
developing meet in laboratory and dishes
there that with a hard shell,
like you can eat them convenient
packaging because I know a lot of vegans
that are absolutely nutritionally
deficient.
They're not getting enough vitamin D,
they're not getting enough d three,
they're not getting enough [inaudible].
They're definitely not getting enough
essential fatty acids unless they're
scooping coconut oil and almond butter
into their mouth everyday.
Cla different things and you know,
they,
they're committed to the cause and so
they're just physically not doing the
best because of it.
Yeah,
I mean,
do you start,
you start,
as you've done,
you've talked about the intelligence and
plants.
You start looking at that and then
versus a mollusk they're way smarter
than a mollusk yeah.
Are Mollusks and plants.
They're possibly fairly equivalent,
you know,
so like the whole cause of,
of why you're not eating them gets a
little blurry when you start reading.
All right,
well plants are smart as shit and
mollusks are mollusks and they're
probably equivalent.
Just one has the ability to move
slightly more than the other one.
Yeah.
The movement thing is something that we
cling to.
What we essentially cleaned too is
things that are closest to us.
Like we really don't give a fuck about
fish.
Like we're worried about people killing
all the fish in the ocean.
We're worried about the police in the
ocean.
But when a little kid catching the fish,
you go,
you go and look at the instagram page,
there's no hate.
You know,
a little kid shoots a bear back the fuck
up.
You don't even want to read those
comments.
You know,
if something,
if someone eats a bear like,
well that's too close to a dog dogs.
My friend dogs are just like people.
Sally's my baby.
She's a dog.
And the bears just like sally and I
can't eat a bear.
Yeah.
It's just anthropomorphization.
Like just putting human traits on
different animals,
which I can totally see.
You know,
there's some animals that seem more
human,
like we recognize more attributes than
others.
Well,
I have a thing with wolves.
I,
I absolutely have some sort of a weird
anthropomorphization thing with wolves
were um,
you know,
I think there were like probably my
favorite animals ever.
There's the fucking coolest things of
all time.
They,
they,
they have these packs.
They mate for life,
they get together and fucking,
they have this social group,
they have this really complex method of
hunting where they communicate with each
other.
They howl out to each other and they
have like a roll call.
I mean,
there are complex,
really intense society.
Yeah.
I won't hold it against him that they
mate for life.
I'll excuse them.
That was pretty amazing because their
life is hard as fuck.
And it doesn't last long because you
can't be a pimp.
But apparently there's a documentary
about a wolf and ironically enough to
call it the black wolf.
And there was a black wolf that
apparently wasn't following any of the
rules and this wolf would go across the
highway,
away from the rest of the pack and lure
the women over to him.
And he was banging these women and
female wolves,
obviously not women,
human.
I'm really anthropomorphizing now.
Um,
and,
and then protecting actual bitches.
Yeah.
And wouldn't the right way of saying it
and wouldn't mate in,
wouldn't like find a mate for life until
he was old.
And then when he's old as are,
I'll come back and start running shit.
And then when he's old he came back,
got a mate,
started running things and just sort of
settled down.
But it was interesting.
It's like this wolf had chosen a
different way of life.
And it's a documentary
on it.
It's interesting because,
you know,
in,
in all of these Iowasca trips and all of
these things,
I've talked to animals of all kinds of
variety.
And again,
this could be just pure imagination,
but in that,
you know,
they always have lessons or things that
we discussed.
And one of the common themes is the
amount of freewill that the animal hat.
So when I talked to the insects and you
really talk,
you don't talk to one insect,
you talked to the insect over mine.
Again,
this could all just be my imagination,
but it helps me understand things a bit.
You talked to the insect over mine and
the insects say basically we are like
the trash keepers of the,
of the world.
Like we have no flexibility for
freewill.
If we all decided to go on strike,
the world's fucked,
you know,
nothing gets decomposed.
There's no spare parts.
We run out of spare parts for the world.
Everything.
Nothing else gets built.
The whole thing goes to shit.
The food source at the very bottom,
so we have no freewill,
were perfect,
perfect creatures acting in perfect
accordance with the laws of nature to
allow it to happen.
Where you get these things like the
atomic automatons,
like the digger wasps.
But no matter how much you fuck with
thing,
they'll try to do the same thing over
and over again.
Well really that's,
that's perfect because it's doing
absolutely what it must and then you go
on up the up the chain towards the
mammals and there's gets to be greater
and greater access to free will.
So you talked to like I've talked to
dolphins and dolphins.
Spirit was like super happy,
playful and they said,
you know,
dolphins,
one of the best existence of all because
we have greater access to free will,
we can choose to play,
we can choose the fuck,
we can choose these different elements.
Getting food is easy and it's also how
easy it is to get food.
Like getting food is easy for us,
you know,
there's not a lot of natural predators,
so we have kind of the ultimate
existence and we don't have the human
brain,
which is the ultimate Sabbath tour.
You know,
it's our own minds that lock us in.
These depressions and anxieties and
hell's and dolphins don't have that
level of self awareness that they've
created all the problems.
So it's almost like they're in this
perfect sweet spot,
which is one of the things that you feel
when you encounter in both in real life
and envision is that they're just happy
as fuck because they have the most
flexibility with the least amount of
troubles that come from it.
Yeah.
We were talking about this on the,
on the ride when we were in Edmonton,
Alberta Rather.
And it was really interesting because we
were talking about,
was it Ben O'brian that was telling us
about a queen that got stuck in
someone's car queen bee.
They got in a car,
a queen bee got stuck in someone's car
and the colony followed them for like 20
miles,
some insane amount of distance and you
know,
this guy was just getting fucking
followed by bees and couldn't figure out
what the hell was going on.
Well,
they had a mandate.
There was,
there was no freewill.
There was no discussion whether or not
I'm tired of fine.
Like they were just going to fly to the
end and they flew and found this guy's
car with the fucking queen in it.
And I don't know how it got resolved but
how they knew
exactly.
But yeah,
that's,
it follows that that would be the,
that would be the behavior because
these,
they don't have the flexibility to do
that because everything would fall
apart.
You know,
they're like the perfect robots of,
of life.
And I think,
you know,
you start talking about these
distinctions between life and,
you know,
artificial intelligence life.
I think really consciousness and
freewill are inexorably linked.
Like that is kind of the key component.
You know,
like yes these insects are alive,
but are they fully conscious?
You know,
while I think it really depends on their
access to free will,
their ability to make a choice.
I think that is the defining
characteristic of consciousness is
choice.
Well that's another weird thing about
people that are really into animals.
Like we'll,
we'll make a distinction between animals
and insects.
Like I have friends that just fucking
love animals.
They adopt dogs and cats and.
But they'll fucking kill any bug.
It's on their counter.
Know this.
They'll see a bug or other counter.
They just,
Oh you bitch,
you're dead.
Could be random.
Harmless beetle over,
it's like a mosquito lands on them.
Slap,
you know,
there's no negotiating with.
With insects.
We find an insect but they won't eat
them,
which is weird.
You know,
it's one of those weird things.
Cricket protein bars.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
they just.
Vegans don't eat bugs.
They don't need animal protein.
They're responsible for the death.
Listen,
I'm not trying to put this on you guys.
If you're a Vegan,
you know,
if you buy grain from a store,
you are directly responsible for the
death of countless bugs.
Countless rodents.
Who knows how many rabbits.
Who knows how many deer fonds.
If you buy anything that is
indiscriminately collected with a
combine and that's how they get grain.
They have these huge machines.
If you've never seen it before,
Jamie,
pull up a grain combine inaction because
it's like,
whoa.
That is some alien machine sent down to
sheer the earth.
This is,
it's kind of fucking.
It's a weird way we do it.
I mean,
we used to do it with like the grim
reaper sickle,
you know,
that's how they used to do at that cool
thing with the two handles on it.
Is that what it is aside?
What's the definition of sickle and
aside sickles?
The Russian thing,
right?
Yeah.
I think what does that one smaller one.
It's a handheld jammy
the.
When they use those things,
it's really,
it's that that's only one aspect of one
of the things that's problematic about
large scale collecting of food,
but look at this fucking thing.
This enormous machine,
and this is not even a big one.
That's a fairly small one.
They have ones that are like a football
field.
Why?
At the mega farms?
Yeah.
This is like something like if you had a
small farm you would do,
but anything that's in there is getting
chewed up.
And one of the things about fonts,
it's really unfortunate,
but fonds when they're young,
they will lie down in these fields and
they don't move because they can't run.
They can't run any predators.
So their strategy is to just not move
and hope something doesn't find them.
Yeah.
And that's why
they have those,
uh,
the coloration on their bodies very
different.
They have the white spots,
which is kind of a nature's version of
some sort of form of camouflage to blend
in.
But those poor fonds get chewed up in
those things all the time.
I have a friend who was a,
he is a large scale corn farm in
Illinois and they,
you know,
they make a corn for mostly for
livestock.
They grow corn for livestock and they
have those giant,
huge ones and they just chew fonds up
all the time.
I think the problem that a lot of people
make is they attribute morality to the
actions you're taking rather than the
intention behind it.
You know what I mean?
And I think people make that mistake a
lot really.
So it's hunting good or bad.
Well that's a,
that's a ridiculous question to ask.
It depends on the intention of the
hunter while he's doing it.
You know,
and I think that's why a lot of people
reserve this kind of native American
idea because we feel and we understand
that the intentions of that person,
that hunter was in a way that was
different than the guy just looking to
put a trophy on as well,
right?
One of those automatic guns that are on
a camera that shooting animals that way,
it's not the act that's either good nor
bad,
nor is it Vegan good nor bad.
It's about the intentions behind it.
And I think people tend to lose that
perspective.
You know?
So that's when,
when I was in bear camp,
that's what I needed to get straight is
what my intentions were.
If I was going after the hunt a bear.
So I would be cool and cam would think I
was cool and everybody in the hunting
party would be like,
yeah,
well that was the wrong intention for
me.
So that's what a lot of the work was.
That's what the part of what the taking
the mushrooms was for was to make sure
that my intention in doing it was the
right intention and that you know,
and what was that intention?
Well,
to me it was some part meet acquisition.
I wanted to have that experience of
taking my own meat from the field,
which was incredibly powerful for me the
first time I wanted and then I wanted to
have to be able to use the code and use
the,
the clause for jewelry and really
connect with that.
But you know,
so that if that intention was leading,
then it was a correct action for me.
If that intention was not leading and I
was doing it to be cool,
they're doing it because I was nervous
or any other way,
then it wasn't immoral act for me and
that's to me how I just kind of sorted
it out.
So I was able to get to that comfortable
place where I knew that I.
If the bear came the right,
the right bore came,
I was going to do it for the right
intention because I'd worked through all
of the other forces and pressures that
desire to be cool or the desire for
this.
There are all these other reasons that
would have made that act.
Not Cool.
You know,
I've worked through those as best I
could.
And so I knew if the bear came,
I was comfortable killing and I had no
idea in my head that this was the wrong
thing because my intentions were right.
Well also your intentions.
I mean,
you had many opportunities to kill a
bear as it I totally.
But what we go for is very big mature
bears for a couple reasons.
One,
because very big mature bears kill cubs.
Um,
it's one of the favorite things to eat
when they come out of hibernation,
which is really fucked up.
They actively hunt cubs that go for
them.
They even go into dance and pulled them
out of Dan's and kill them.
There's a lot of debate as to why they
do that.
The initial thought was that it brings
the female back into estrous and that
the bear can breed with the female and
that way that bears passing on his
genetics,
but there's some scientists and
biologists and wildlife biologists that
believed that just doing it for meat and
it's just there's a lot of competition
out there and it's hard to get meat and
this is meat and they've gotten
accustomed to it and whether they're
doing it because they're hungry or
whether they're doing it because they
want the female to survive a and or a
come back into heat and breed again.
Either way they're they're killing cubs
and they're limiting the DNA.
They're limiting the genetics and it's
not good for the overall population of
the bears.
So the idea is when you kill the large
male bores that what you're doing is
you're actually enhancing the genetics
of the area and you're saving the cubs.
So,
you know,
it seems counterintuitive.
When you kill bores,
you're actually increasing the
population of bears.
Yeah.
It's really weird when you,
when you,
you know,
when you look at it outside of the world
of hunting,
when you don't have all the information
at your fingerprints,
you,
you have this idea that like hunters are
like those bad guys in that wolverine
movie that we're poisoning the bear.
Did you ever see that?
They're always in the movies.
They're always the assholes that are
killing bears,
you know,
meanwhile wolverine,
we'll sit down and eat a steak and he's
a good guy.
Very were,
were so fucking torture.
Didn't and twisted when it comes to our
morality.
But the,
uh,
also the big one is the population of
the traditional game.
Animals like the Moose and the deer and
the elk.
They get decimated by bears and it's the
Fonz.
They kill all the fonts and the,
all the calves.
And that's a huge problem in those
regions like Alberta where we were,
which is just overrun with bears.
I mean,
have you ever imagined you're going to
see that many bears in the first night
we were out there,
there was eight,
nine different barriers just cruising
around crazy all within five to 15,
20 yards.
Crazy.
It was insane.
You know,
one of the stories that Cam told I think
gave me one of the biggest lessons and
takeaways of the trip for me was the one
who told about there was a mother with
her cubs and the cubs were kind of
cruising around and then a,
a big male bear came in and then killed
one of the cubs and I think the mother
like scared her off,
scared off the bore and it was just a
dead cub that she had there.
And so for a moment the mother kind of
wanders around and looked like she was
like,
mourning the death of this cup,
but just for a moment.
And then within minutes,
you know,
seconds it was eating.
The cub was eating her own cup and that
was like a really,
you know,
we humans have this idea of this trauma
we carry,
like
if our,
if our kid got got killed,
you know,
we would carry that trauma for the rest
of our life.
But for the bear,
yeah,
there was a moment of recognition,
but bears are constantly living in the
present moment.
They're like the embodiment of the
present moment and in the present moment
that death happened in the past,
that death was over.
What's there now is there's meat on the
ground that'll feed her and provide an
opportunity for her to live longer and
provide for the rest of her cubs.
So it's a simple decision at that point,
if we don't carry the traumas of our
past with us,
there's meat on the ground.
You eat the meat,
you know that simple,
that simple thing.
And that's in that way it's wide.
Like nature is really perfect because
nature is always in the present moment.
You know,
like I was blasted on the mushrooms and
I went to that bear carcass near where a
cam and killed his bear.
They had this just decomposing bear
carcass,
which you know,
taking mushrooms and seeing a
decomposing bear carcass with.
Well,
it wasn't really that decomposing like
was it one night,
but that was one from a week before.
Yeah,
it was like there was another one that
they've already taken all the skin and
all the meat off of,
so it's just the bones in the organs
that were there and cam had his.
His bear is still nice,
wasn't even smelling or anything.
It looked great fresh,
but this other bear which was right in
the same area.
It was really interesting because I was
very aware of the forest around it and I
just looked at the forest around it and
the forest was not mourning the death of
the bear,
the foresters in the present moment.
It was just going about the business of
returning that bear to spare parts.
It had no traumatic memory of that
incident and it's really how,
how nature works perfectly because it's
always in the present moment like this.
The body doesn't weep for the death of a
cell.
Cells die all the time,
but the bodies in the presence so it
just carries on.
It doesn't carry that trauma with it,
you know,
and ultimately the forest doesn't.
We've for the death of the bear and
ultimately the cosmos won't weep for the
death of the earth.
When the sun explodes.
No,
you know,
like everything will just be in the
present and that's,
that's where you know this,
the ease of all the suffering is so much
of our own suffering is we're carrying
all these dead bodies of the past with
us all the time and these expectations
of the future and that's where we get so
fucked up,
but if we really look to nature,
nature has this allure and this beauty
because it's just constant presence and
body.
It's just looking on the bleeding edge
of now and making decisions based upon
that rather than these mental
constructs.
Yeah.
It's this beautifully intense system
that's just constantly moving.
It's just constantly moving forward.
It's one of the things that I find so
attractive about wolves and I think many
people do this.
They're so romantic in that their,
their existence is so vibrant and
powerful and so brief.
You know,
if a wolf is super lucky,
they get to 10.
You know?
I think getting managed imagined.
I mean,
my,
my middle daughter's eight years old,
like wrap your head around that.
A wolf is like almost dead.
Like I have a dog that's 10.
He's almost done.
You know,
he's,
he's got gray all over his face and he
limps when he walks now and he likes to
lay down mostly,
you know,
that's,
that's a wolf man.
Ten years,
that's all they get.
But during that 10 year,
fuck they live.
Yeah.
They just run in howland together and
grabbing the back.
I mean,
that's one of the crazy things about
wolves to that I admire in some sort of
a real fucked up way that they kill for
fun.
Like they sport kill,
you know it.
It's people that love animals.
When you bring that up,
they defended to the death.
Oh my God.
They go off about it and know whether
the animals were probably sick and
they're taking them off.
Nope.
They're having a fucking blast.
They're running around and tearing these
elka part.
Like we were talking about it a couple
of weeks ago.
They found 19 dead elk that these wolves
didn't even eat.
They call them surplus kills.
They just go on rampages,
you know,
I have a,
um,
a friend of mine who lives up in BC and
he said they'll get into like sheep,
like they'll find like a pen of sheep
and they'll kill 19,
20 of them.
They just rip them apart.
They don't give a fuck.
They're just having fun.
It's part of what they are that like we
have this like intense romantic
connection to wolves is like they have a
little bit of us and um,
they have a little bit of party in them.
You know,
they're the towel in and shit and having
a good old time and they have battles
with each other to see who becomes the
king,
you know.
So did you see that video recently of
these folks were in Canada and they were
driving down the highway and as they
were driving they saw these mountain
goats running or sheep running away from
a wolf and the wolves chasing them and
the wolf tackles the fucking sheep and
kills it instantly.
Right in front of them.
It's always fucking Canada.
Like that Martin that killed the bear.
See if you could find it though,
because it's pretty cool and it's pretty
cool to see wolf takes out a sheep
mountain,
rocky mountain sheep.
But the,
when the wolf took out the sheep,
he carries this thing up the side of the
hill like you would carry like a five
year old.
Yeah.
And it's like things like basically his
size and he just grabs it with his face.
Here it is.
See these,
uh,
see he breaks away well back up a little
bit.
So you could see and give us some
volume.
Look at this.
It breaks off and watch this Bam bitch.
That's a wrap.
Rips it apart.
Instantly.
Look at that instant death.
I mean,
there's no quicker kill in a wolf and a
sheep.
I mean it's,
it's,
it's still breathing,
but its neck had snapped and it's done.
Fucking beautiful animal.
That wolf is now watch when he grabs it,
he's like,
get over here,
bitch.
Look at this.
Don't open that window too wide.
Yeah.
He might come and get you a bitch.
Boy,
he probably wouldn't know.
He's got that right there.
People probably tastes like shit.
Tastes like cheetos and cigarettes.
The fucking animals.
Just.
It's such a fucking majestic animal.
I think that's why we have such an
allure to it and people love animals so
much is because they're not carrying
around all the bullshit that we are.
They're just living full and presently,
and they're not straddled with these
concepts of morality in these
differently.
They're just living to the most of their
directive.
It's in the present.
You have the idea of eternity with you.
It's like there's.
You're not worried about this other
stuff,
so they you just go and you just fucking
live to the very fullest and we can
count those moments that we have is our
best moments in life,
you know,
and we can recall maybe dozens of times
if we're lucky,
they'll be hundreds of times in those,
in a normal person's life where they're
just totally present,
embodied,
free doing exactly what they fucking
want to do.
Yeah.
And in a lot of ways,
the world that we've constructed,
the modern world with social media and
with constantly being inundated with new
new stories that have almost nothing to
do with you there on the other side of
the world,
you know,
someone got shot on the other side of
the planet.
Someone fell off of a mountain.
You know,
this guy who died in a fiery car
accident a thousand miles from you.
I mean all this stuff is like constantly
going on.
It's constantly coming at you and it
makes it really difficult to focus on
the actual life that you're living.
I mean,
we almost get,
are getting too much data.
I think that's,
that's one element,
but I think the more toxic element is
the look at me element,
which is the,
here's what I'm doing at this time,
here's me snapchatting this because it
puts above.
Take a picture of you and put it on
instagram saying that it puts,
it puts the awareness of other people
watching you into the forefront of your
mind,
you know,
so like right now that was a fucked up
smile.
I just gave her that because I was
thinking about you taking a picture of
me.
So I changed my behavior.
It wasn't handed,
it wasn't normal and that's what we're
doing constantly.
We have,
we have this idea that everybody's
looking at us and we're,
we're like,
we're really are the stage actors.
And that was that famous line from
William Shakespeare.
We all but actors in the world is a
stage.
Well with social media it becomes that
we're always just acting and playing
this role.
That's not our authentic self.
Like bear down asked on the grass like
what the fuck is this thing?
Let me get back in touch with the monkey
and figuring out what feels good for
him,
what I want to do,
and it becomes your world like it might
not be your world,
but it becomes your world when,
when you're one of those,
uh,
Yoga booty girls that just sticks her
ass up in the air for all our instagram
pictures.
Now God bless him.
God bless him.
Thank God.
Thank God they're out there.
But when,
when there's a gal like that that has 5
million instagram followers and her
notifications are constantly coming in
and she's checking her likes and damn
girl,
you hot damn girl,
you find,
oh shit,
can I get with you?
And they're looking at all their
comments and getting all that love,
all that attention.
Then that becomes them and then mean.
I mean,
I would hope that they're well rounded
and they also read books and they also
do a lot of other things and they
meditate and take yoga and really get
it,
but it's highly likely they don't.
It's highly likely that they just stare
at the pictures of their own ass and go
back to the gym for the second time in a
day and do dead lifts and just fucking
fat that ass up and thinking about
getting fat injected into it and like,
oh right.
Yeah.
What people fail to realize is that that
in itself is a pressure and that
pressure needs a response of equal
magnitude in order to balance here.
It's like all of these people with,
with fame,
you know,
especially fame that you really didn't
work that hard for,
you know,
and so I think where we're athletes and
just kinda just celebrities,
pop culture,
celebrities are instagram celebrities
have a little bit of a different feel
because that athlete knows all the
fucking quiet moments like steph curry
knows all of those hundreds of thousands
of shots he took when nobody was
watching and dribbling around and
practicing and practicing.
So when he gets out there,
his what he's doing and what he's known
for,
it makes sense and it's solid.
It's grounded in something,
but all of a sudden you have a great ass
and the ability to take a decent photo
and you're,
you've got the reach of 5 million
people.
I think that amount of pressure really
fucks with you and you have to take
extreme measures to counteract that and
to get yourself back grounded again.
More time in nature,
meditation,
float tank eating,
we'd whatever you want to do,
you know,
find that other thing to counteract
that.
Recognize it for what it is and,
and don't just look at the positive
aspect of it.
Look at the negative that it's having
because I think if you don't,
we see the effects of that all the time.
We see the Robin Williams,
we see,
you know,
the people who are dying of these
overdoses that ostensibly should be
happy as fuck,
but they're not.
They haven't dealt with the pressure of
fame in a way that's as aggressive as
the pressure that it's caused on.
Yeah.
Robin Williams might not be the best
example because we had a bobcat in the
other day and bobcat was a really good
friend of Robin's and Robin was
diagnosed with several illnesses.
One of them was Parkinson's,
but there was another one.
There was a,
a brain illness that he was diagnosed
with.
Do you remember the name of a Jamie Lewy
body disease?
I believe,
but it,
it,
um,
it directly affects the way he perceived
the world.
Like he had a real issue.
Yeah.
Batman in Batman or whatever the joker
was.
Heath Ledger.
Pillow guy.
Yeah.
So the pressure,
but they're responding to the pressure
in a way that's deleterious for their
life rather than responding to the
pressure being like,
man,
this is fucked up.
I got all of these people looking at me.
I got to do some other work in society
is not pushing them in that way either.
They're just saying more and more and
more,
get another roll,
get more followers.
Right.
Um,
you know,
it's like the demon voice that you have
from your act,
like exactly that they have that fucking
thing in their head.
And the other guy like,
hey man,
go fucking on a vision
quest,
like find some mountains by yourself
where nobody's watching it and you don't
have to act at all.
You can just be you.
Well,
this is what I wrote a note earlier
because we were talking about depression
and I've always wondered if the
depression that people see in mass
today,
there's so much depression that people
mean there's a ca.
It's a common trait.
Like it's a common condition.
Oh,
he suffers from depression.
she suffers from depression.
Like,
oh,
he's got herpes.
You know,
you know what I mean?
It's like,
it's a,
it's a common thing.
I've always wondered or I've been
wondering more and more recently.
Um,
it really hit me when have you ever seen
a Heimos Arctic adventure?
It was one of the first vice pieces that
ever.
So I think the first vice piece I ever
saw,
in fact,
no,
the first one was David Choe looking for
a dinosaur in the Amazon or was he in
the Congo?
I think it was in the Congo.
David Choe.
So fucking crazy.
I love that guy.
But he went to Africa,
the guy's worth $100,000,000.
We went to Africa looking for a fucking
dinosaur.
That definitely doesn't exist.
But,
but uh,
vice has done some awesome stuff.
But one of the things they did that was
really interesting was this guy,
his name is Huynh Mo.
I think that's how you say it.
Age.
I am.
Here it is heimos.
Hi mo.
I had an n in there I think heimos
arctic refuge and this guy lives in this
incredibly remote area of the arctic
national wildlife refuge in the alaskan
interior.
And he,
he lives in this really small log cabin
and he hunts and gathers and that's all
he does.
And he's very smart.
I think he's not a dummy at all and he's
been up there.
He lives with his wife and his.
He raised children up there and it's
really,
really.
There's some dark moments in there
because they lived like this from the
time,
like when they had children up there and
they lost their two year old baby in a
fucking canoe.
Like they tipped over in A,
in a canoe and lost their kid.
And it's like it's a really intense when
they revisit the site and leave flowers
and it was like 30 years ago and they
had several children since then,
but this moment is still like this
intense moment of loss for them where
they lost their baby,
but this fucking guy is very happy and
very,
very smart and very connected and very
articulate and he firmly believes that
human beings,
when we evolved and developed and were
hunter gatherers,
that there's a set of rewards.
There's reward systems that are set up
Inside the human body,
inside the.
The,
the very being that we embody that don't
get met in today's society.
And tHat's one of the things that's
causing depression.
One of the things that's causing this
funk that people are in is that we're
living our lives.
many of us,
at least in these very unfulfilling ways
where you're going to this office with
artificial light and you're doing
something you don't want to do all day
long and then you get home and you're
tired.
And on top of tHat you're eating shit.
You're eating potato chips and you're
drinking soda and your body is just
like,
what in the fuck is this?
We're supposed to be out in the fields
were supposed to be walking up hills.
We're supposed to be looking for aniMals
or gathering vegetables were supposed to
be doing all these things that our body
is designed to do.
We're supposed to be in nature and
nature is like a medicine.
LIke it literally is a medicine to you.
Like people.
People that go,
you don't have to go hunting,
you don't have to go fishing.
Just go fucking hike man.
Just go hike up to the top of a mountain
and look out.
You know there's a reward that you get
from that that Is intensely like soul
filling.
Just like something about like wHen I
was in Colorado and there was this,
this area of boulder where you drive up
one of these roads and there's this area
where you could park and it was this
incredible view,
man.
These people just pArk and just go out
there and just look,
but you get there and you park and you
go,
fuck [inaudible].
You would see you,
you literally seeing the continental
divide and these snow capped mountains
in july,
july.
It's covered with snow because those
mountains,
I don't
give a perspective.
Oh,
just this whole new perspective on it
and I think nature,
I think the ease of suffering is always
in present in this.
You know when you're in president is
truly locked in and presidents,
there is no suffering.
There can be pain,
but no suffering.
Suffering is something created by our
own minds and I think nature is one of
the great ways to do this because
humans,
we learn,
we take cues from our environment and
nature.
As I was saying earlier,
is always in the present.
You know there's this natural presidents
of all the animals,
everything around you.
Whereas if you get around a bunch of
people watching housewives and stressed
about this and pop them pills,
you're going to take on that energy too
and you're gonna lose your present in
this because of your surrounding.
So it's like this ultimate regrounding
tool where we get back to a present
moment.
Again,
that's such a fucking key element to
human happiness and I think the other
key element is having something where
we're fighting for,
we know,
having a mission,
I think we're all forces and that forest
needs to have an effect,
needs to have A reason that it's moving
in a certain directioN and I think with
all of our meats and all of our needs
met,
you knoW,
where we don't have to hunt for food,
we don't have to acquire everything.
Everything's relatively easy and it's
all about advancement and all this.
We've lost a lot of the basic mission
which was the mission to suRvive and
procreate,
you know,
so.
And we haven't replaced it with any
other universal mission,
which is I think one of the big allures
of these things like wars and these
things like creating an enemy.
Well at least then you hAve a mission
and when you have a mission,
human beings are happy.
You know,
like a birch and russell talked about,
he did book conquest of happIness and he
had his own fucked up attributes.
Every time I bring them up,
people talk about is fucked up.
And as he was into phonology and he
might've been racist,
whatever,
but he was a good philosopher,
smoke.
But,
but Anyways,
he talked about the happiest person he
knew,
the happiest person he could find was a
groundskeeper on a manner who every day
woke up and was at war with the rabbits,
have the guy he just declared that the
rabbits were the fucking enemy.
And he would go out with his gun and he
would hunt as many as possible and he'd
go morning till,
till night,
and he would kill as many rabbits as he
could because it was the rabbits were
the ones eating the hedges and the
flowers and whatever.
So he basically made the rabbits his
enemy and struck out every single day to
kill as many rabbits as possible.
And that dude,
according to bertrand russell,
was happy as fuck.
He had a task,
he had a task,
he had a purpose,
you know,
he had a mission.
My mission is to destroy the rabbits.
I just have a dog like that.
Yeah.
I had the happiest dog over,
his name was frank sinatra.
And uh,
he was a pit bull that all he lived for
was killing lizards and my house,
my old house,
not the house now,
but my old house had this,
uh,
one,
um,
it's like a on a hill and there's this
one wall where these lizards would run
up the wall.
And so frank,
I would literally let them out in the
morning and he fucking bolt out that
door.
It's like time to go to war,
like any would run and go look for these
lizards.
And he would stand there like eddie
bravo.
We'll just watch it.
And marvel.
He'd be like,
fuck man,
this dog does this every day there's,
doc does this every day I go,
this is what he loves to do.
And he would go there and he would have
his paws on the wall and
crazy and he would jump up and try to
grab a lizard and occasionally he would
get one and he'd be like,
fuck yeah.
And he would get one.
They would go looking for another one.
He would go and he was a pretty big
yard.
So he would go wandering around the yard
looking for anything else that fucked
up.
Anything else that was slipping and it
was constantly,
unfortunately twice.
I had to take him to the hospital
because he got bit by rattlesnakes
because rattlesnakes are slipping to.
Apparently he killed the rattlesnakes,
but the rattlesnakes fucked him up here.
Like a water balloon grown out of the
side of his head.
Both of my dogs.
It.
By the way,
that's a real problem.
If you don't have the money to pay for
the serum,
it's super expensive.
It was several thousand dollars to treat
them for this rattlesnake venom.
Antivenom shit.
It's like.
I was like,
man,
what if I was poor?
What if a whole fucked up system like
you.
They inject horses with the venom and
they like get the antibodies from the
horses except this archaic system.
I think my friend Donald Schultz is
working on.
He's a big snake handler guy.
He's working on ways to innovate around
that because it's kind of like a real
backwards system that they have.
How you get antivenom?
Well,
a horse will survive,
so let's just fucking sorta put the
venom in there and then we'll get the
antibodies from the horse and then,
you know,
it's,
it's a weird.
It's a weird thing how they do it.
Yeah,
well that's a real problem with people
that are vegans.
If you're a vegan,
you don't use any animal products.
You get bit by a rattlesnake,
you got two choices.
Compromise your morals.
Well that's a wrap.
Yeah.
You know,
um,
but this dog was so goddamn happy.
He had missions,
you know,
he would go out of that yard and he
wasn't bored.
He was really pleased to see me for a
walk.
Come on man.
He was like,
see it dude.
Don't opened that door.
He was gone.
He just had his little mission.
And I think you can see that in the
people who are the most unhappy.
THey seem aimless.
Like,
what am I here for?
Why am I doing this?
Nothing makes sense.
You know?
And I've even felt it in my own life
when,
you know,
I know what my mission here.
My mission is to expand human
consciousness,
to help people be happy.
Like that's really what I find my
greatest purpose in.
But every once in a while I'll get this
kind of like fuck people attitude.
Maybe someone said some fucked up shit
and I'm like,
man,
people fucking suck for people.
And then at that poem,
that's when I'm actually depressed,
you know,
because I've lost my mission.
Instead of having a mission,
like,
yes,
my mission is human consciousness.
All of a sudden it's like fuck people,
fuck that mission.
THey'll figure it out and then I'm
depressed because I've lost my purpose.
It's very hard to rise above like
literally when something like that
happens and realize like,
oh,
you've just,
you're,
you're encountering one diseased
individual.
You've got to look at the mass of
humanity.
Like when you encounter one diseased
individual,
it's so like this guy who shot up that
nightclub in orlando,
you're,
you're looking at one diseased
individual and if you say,
man,
people fucking suck.
Look at what they did.
We'll look into how many people that are
responding with rainbows on their
twitter pages and love and,
and,
and all the best wishes to those folks
that got killed that other.
I mean I was looking at this guy's page
who's a,
an animal lover who was organizing
people to go to the homes of the victims
and see if they have pets that are
trapped.
You know,
there's this beautiful people out there.
There's a lot,
there's more beautiful pete.
This is without a doubt,
not just the safest,
the easiest.
This is the happiest time in terms of
like being able to like reach out and,
and,
and send love to people and have people
send love to you,
but just occasionally you run into conc
yeah,
no,
and the constant self.
BuT the beauty is out there too.
It's just not as dramatic and it doesn't
impose upon us as forcefully,
but we've,
we just look.
It's around all the time.
We run into good people all the time,
but you just make eye contact with that
good person or that kid.
He's just looking at you and just that
little smile and you're like,
oh yeah,
the good of humanity.
The fact that,
you know,
we really are love,
being expressed outwardly all the time
and it's just these other delusions that
get in the way of that.
Well,
we're oddly attracted to negativity to.
It's almost like we look at negativity
online or that you run into is a
possibility of war.
Like you have to look at this fucking
drums beating,
goddammit.
There's an army on the background.
They're coming,
they're coming.
You know,
it's like there's this real impulse to
sort of batten down the hatches when
really it's just some fucking 36 year
old losers sit in his parents basement,
you know,
farting and smelling his own farts and
angry online.
I mean,
that's really what a lot of you're
dealing with.
You're dealing with like really sick
people,
like people that have just,
for whatever reason,
they've not found their path.
They've not found any happiness.
They have found any fulfillment.
They don't.
They haven't found any growth there just
stifled
or rotten and some sort of a weird way.
It just hasn't really worked for them
and so they're,
they're lashing out,
the lashing out at the world and you run
into one of those people suck and that's
the initial response and then the more
conscious response is to look at and be
and have compassion for that person.
That is hard to do and our system isn't
based upon that.
Even if you look at the u s penal
system,
it's very much about punishment.
Whereas if you watched that documentary
that Michael Moore did,
who to invade nest,
where they go to Norway,
they have a whole different idea of what
the penal system is for.
It's about restoring human dignity and
cultivating a change.
Really making change in the person.
It's not about punishment,
it's about.
It's about actually changing that
individual so he doesn't do it again,
and then you look at the recidivism
rates between our prisons and norway's
prisons and they're just dramatically
different.
That impulse to punish immediately,
you know,
is not the healthiest impulse.
That's just gonna create more issues
down the road.
You're not rehabilitating anybody.
You're just taking even more broken
people and putting them out in the world
and hoping they're not going to do the
broken things.
Well,
it's not going to fucking work.
You know,
the right impulse is always that
compassion and looking to see as if that
was you,
how all of these fucked up elements of
the world and choices.
I'm not overriding the fact that they
had choices and all this.
They're not free of guilt,
but look at,
look at that.
Like this is the person that just made
some bad choices and had some tough shit
to deal with and couldn't overcome it.
The resistance in the video game was
higher than his skillset and he wasn't
able to,
to choose to work and choose to the
positive elements that would allow them
to overcome it.
you know,
it's,
it's also norway's dealing with far
fewer people,
you know,
and that's,
that's a good thing for them.
And it's also they,
they don't have that conquers mentality
that we have.
So when we were so wrapped up in success
and also in punishment,
I mean that,
that is a big aspect of our culture.
Like punishment and I mean like when
anyone does anything wrong online,
the amount of people that feel like it's
their job to shame that person and
embarrass that person and insult that
person,
it's pretty crazy to watch when
something goes down.
It's also,
it's also counterproductive and I see
that in the people shaming people for
appropriation,
right?
So let's say for example,
someone wears a head dress at a fucking
festival,
right?
They're probably mildly.
They're not doing it to mock the native
americans,
most likely,
probably like a,
a mild appreciation and interest.
I think this looks cool.
I'm in a place and you know,
and then all of a sudden they get all
this intense hate and shame and putting
all of this stuff,
all of these intentions on them that
weren't true.
Again,
going back to my point about morality,
it's not about the act,
it's about the intentions of the act,
but right now we make it all about the
act.
Oh,
you wore this headdress.
That means you're insulting thousands of
years of native americans.
You're oppressing,
you're appropriating Like,
no,
I fucking wasn't.
I was wearing a fucking harris'
headdress.
But then all of a sudden that imprint
will create trauma and that trauma will
have a poisonous impact that will make
them feel weird and make them want to do
that to other people.
So it's like you're in injecting someone
with a,
like a hate virus,
you know,
that they're going to then pass on to
other people rather than doing the
opposite,
you know,
spreading the love herpes where this
contagious positivity that goes the
other way and we have those choices with
how to deal with people,
but more often than not,
we come with this thing to punish and
create more trauma which triggers their
own self judge and their own self hate,
lowers their own self love.
And then they're going to pass that off
to kids,
family members,
people around them.
You know,
there's just two sets of dominoes that
we can choose to take to take either pat
and the concept of copd.
Cultural appropriation is so stupid
because culture itself is bullshit.
Culture itself is just a bunch of shit
that people have done over and over
again as a habit.
Right?
So your idea that no one should
appropriate someone's other bullshit
habits is so fucking ridiculous,
like you shouldn't wear your hair like
that because other dummies women wearing
their hair like that for 100 years.
Now they've decided thAt this is theirs.
They own the dreadlock yeah.
You know,
or they own the braids.
Are they?
Oh,
it's fucking nonsense.
It's nonsense.
And it's just one of those things that
michael shermer likes to call virtue
signaling where you see someone who's
doing something and in chastising them
you're not just trying to stop them from
doing it.
You're also letting the world know how
ethical and how moral you are.
And so you get a lot of like really
goofy fucking white people who get mad
at other white people for doing things
that they deem to be cultural
appropriation.
And it's one thing if you're deeply
embedded and rooted in that culture,
like um,
what is that thing that a hindu people
put on their forehead when they're in
love in love?
They put the third eye symbol on their
head.
I think it has something to do with
love,
or is it a bindi?
Is that what it is you can be?
Yeah.
Well,
I've,
I've seen people get upset at people
appropriating that and like,
but what is that?
You get,
you get a sticker on your head,
man,
for real.
Well,
what about us?
We're wearing tattoos clearly yet
someone's culture.
I mean the kind that we have is fairly
american I guess,
but my inner,
like aaron dellavedova did mine and sort
of a japanese style japanese tattoo on
my ribs.
Yeah.
It's this sort of cultural appropriate
in a time where we need all the best
ideas ever.
You know what I mean?
Like we need to bring everything that's
good and everything that made sense and
everything that can tap people back into
something positive.
we need all of that stuff.
We don't need to.
We need,
so we need to gather all of the best
practices of the culture.
That's the fucking beautiful part of the
time we're in.
We can go eat moroccan food or chinese
food or japanese food.
We can go enjoy all of these things and
we need all of this enjoyment because
there's all kinds of other fucked up
stuff that's going on as well that we
have to deal with.
So I mean,
I,
I just have such the opposite
idea that,
you know,
like tesla is doing with his patents,
this idea of protect and hold.
This is our own shit.
Nobody else get it.
That's to the detriment of the world.
Like everybody should want to share all
the ideas and best practices that they
have to be like me secretly doing
psychedelics.
Right?
Happy or not motherfuckers fuck you.
You know,
it doesn't make any sense.
like you want to talk about it and say
like,
this is what worked for me.
This is,
hey,
how can you,
how can you improve yourself to,
well,
ironically,
that's what people believe.
The biblical scholars who have studied
the connection between psychedelics and
ancient religions that say believe where
it all went wrong and so they tried to
hold back the psychedelic rituals and
hide them from conquering armies.
And that's what john marco allegro
believed that christianity was really
initially all about.
It was about writing down these things
in the bible,
in parables and hiding them in these
stories and that these stories were to
mask it from the conquerors from being
conquered by the roman army.
Yeah,
and then really the opposite is what
they needed.
They needed to share this open sources
as widely as possible,
so you look at that period.
It's riddled with war and atrocities and
all this fucked up stuff that's
happened.
It's in the human rights record and in
the archaeological record,
you know,
cities built,
destroyed,
barbarian,
blah,
blah.
Then you go take the counterpoint of
that to a culture ancient shoving in
Peru,
which archaeologically has been shown
that for 700 years there was no records
of war in this region around shoving and
shoving where the curators of the plant
medicine,
which enhances serotonin,
very hard opening medicine I've talked
about here on this podcast,
but they would give it to everybody.
You just showed up.
Maybe you brought a seashell as a gift.
Maybe you didn't.
Didn't matter.
They would hold these open ceremonies
for everybody who came.
kings peasants doesn't.
They didn't differ,
differentiate.
They were offering this to everybody and
everybody was just more open and the
records of war and the destructions
destruction that it's just not there in
the archaeological record and it has a
lot to do.
Obviously you can't prove causation,
but the correlation between them open
sourcing these psychedelic rituals to
everybody and they're not being war for
hundreds and hundreds of years is
absolutely there and that's should it is
where people went wrong because they
tried to hoard information for power
because that knowledge of course yields
power.
If you have the knowledge and only you
have it,
you'll have power over people who don't.
Whereas real,
you know,
heart based power,
leading with your heart forward,
just open source all that.
Let it all sorted itself out.
Yeah,
it only makes sense that if you want the
world that you live in,
to be a better place.
You've got to tell the things that have
made.
Tell people the things that have made
your life better and things that made
your life fucked up.
Don't hide that shit either.
Don't pretend like you're perfect and
things don't fuck you up and everything
is good.
Like people need to hear all of it.
Like,
oh yeah,
I tried this thing.
It was fucking terrible.
I wouldn't want to do that again,
but
how could they possibly have known that
thousands of years ago?
You know what I mean?
It's,
I would love to have gone back in time.
I would love to go back in time like
several thousand years,
just be invisible being some sort of
invisible cone of protection and just
sit down in a village,
you know,
in ancient days,
in somewhere really populated area of
the world,
whether it's Greece or rome or wherever,
and just try to try to take in what
these fucking people are doing,
how they were living and look at what
they're essentially like.
They're not just our ancestors.
There was,
I think we can look at ancient cultures
in ancient societies and see if we look
back and see all of their weird crazy
stories and traditions and the way they
sort of established the government and
would look at what we're doing now.
And if you sort of extrapolate deep into
the future like where were.
These are all the.
This is just not that long ago,
it's a small little blip in time and
there's obviously some sort of a process
going on,
some sort of a process of improvement
and have a of innovation and some sort
of a weird way innovation of culture and
society and communication and I think
that's one of the things that we're
dealing with now with this age of
information and all the data that we
have to sift through and all the
communication that we have to sift
through.
We're becoming some new thing and it's
happening in our lifetime and it's
happening in a really fucking confusing
way and it's one of the things that make
people yearn for the past.
It makes people yearn for the good old
days.
You know,
it makes a slogan like donald trump's
keep America or make America great
again.
What the fuck does that mean?
It's never been better.
It's never been better than right now.
It would make America great again.
Like how could it be greater?
Like when has it ever been better than
right now for anybody?
This is the safest time.
This is the most communication.
There's the most information available,
there's the most medicine available.
You medical science can save people.
you can live healthier lives.
We know more about nutrition,
we understand more about the body,
like when was it better?
Yeah,
and still we're in this weird
transitional period that I think we all
can,
can notice because truth hasn't
percolated down to the rest of the rest
of society.
It's and it's a frustrating point.
Like we know that people should not be
getting thrown in jail for marijuana.
That's not a debatable facts.
Like the act of throwing them in jail is
bad for the person.
The act of taking the marijuana is not
bad for society.
There's the truth is there,
but still we're in this lag.
The lag is really frustrated people
because you know,
but that's just the.
That's just the nature of it.
It's like when you go from switching
from mcdonald's to starting to eat
healthy and drinking kale shakes,
the body doesn't respond instantly.
You know,
you have to be patient with the body
like it's not just because you change
your mind.
The mind is instant.
you can change your mind and instantly
it's changed,
but the body is different and so a
society like it's going to take awhile
for truth to percolate all the way
through and in the process
like if you switch from mcdonald's to
going on a juice fast,
you're going to feel like shit.
You know all the toxins are going to
come up.
Everything is going to bubble up through
the body and you're going to have this
massive detoxification period where you
actually feel worse than if you had just
continued to eat mcdonald's all the time
because the body's going to go through
the process of at reacclimating to a new
way and I think we're in a little bit of
that stage now where a truth is come out
and a lot of different aspects of
things,
but it hasn't percolated all the way
through.
So we're going through this kind of
societal detox where we have an applied
the knowledge that is that is there
readily available.
I have feelings on the tour.
I think that a lot of this resistance to
new knowledge,
new information,
and even the resistance to freedom,
like the marijuana laws and a lot of the
things that we deeply deeply disagree
with,
that this is all in some sort of a way
fueling change that the resistance
actually fires people up and makes them
more motivated to move forward and
actually it actually strengthens the
resolve of the resistance.
To know that there's so much ignorance
out there in the world.
Like when some slob like chris christie
starts going on about nonsense saying
how dangerous marijuana is,
and meanwhile he's kalille abusing the
fuck out of his meat vehicle.
I mean that guy.
If anybody should not talk about health
and consequences of negative actions.
It's someone who's morbidly obese who's
already gone through fucking stomach
surgery and still morbidly obese,
but that guy,
whether he knows it or not,
as ignorant statements,
has fueled a massive amount of
resistance.
There's people that have like fucking
doubled down on their resolve because of
the stupid shit that he said and it
actually fuels things in a,
in a positive way and in a horrible way.
Even a mass killing of gay people like
what happened to orlando,
horrible,
terrible tragedy,
but ultimately that's not going to stop
people from being gay.
What it's gonna do is it's going to fuel
all the people like you and me who have
nothing but love and acceptance for
everybody regardless of your sexual
persuasion.
To double down on that and to get that
out more and that's where all the people
on twitter and instagram and facebook
and all the social media posts about
love and respect and and not giving a
fuck.
And I've seen,
I don't know how many fucking memes from
that bit that I did about this.
Two reasons to hate gay marriage.
You know,
you're.
You're either dumb or you're secretly
worried.
That dixit delicious.
That is fucking all over the place.
After one of these things happen and
that and then a million other ones like
it and a million other rainbows and
hearts in the shape of a rainbow and
it's people doubled down on their
acceptance,
double down the result.
And there might be some people that were
on the fence that might've had some
negative ideas about gay people and see
all this and go,
man,
you can't fucking kill people in a
nightclub just because they're gay.
That's crazy.
And then they might open their mind a
little bit and then they might read a
little bit more and then they might see
an interview with some gay people that
are holding hands and go,
well,
why do I give a fuck?
Like,
what is this?
What religion?
What some ancient stupid tradition.
Is it cultural appropriation?
Like,
what is it?
You know,
what,
what is it about this idea that people
should or shouldn't love people of one
sex or another sex?
And if they do love them,
they definitely shouldn't fuck them.
You know,
I love you.
Like we're,
we're really good friends.
We've never fucked.
I hope we never do.
But you know what I'm saying?
Like what it.
Why would anybody care if you love
somebody and then you wind up touching
your body with them and pleasuring each
other.
Like to some people that becomes this
taboo worthy of violence.
That's a nonsense point of view that is
highlighted by horrific acts and these
horrific acts,
it's horrible,
despicable as they are in fact fuel
people to be more open and more
understanding.
It's like the more you push back,
the more the resistance grove.
Yeah,
and that's a point that you always fall
back on.
It's absolutely a hundred percent right.
I mean the obstacle is the way these
things that in any video game you need
resistance in order to test your skills
and improve,
you know,
in a weight room you need gravity and
the additional weights to stress your
body so that you respond.
And that's the same case with,
with all of these elements.
We underestimate the value of
resistance.
And that's a great constant reminder
like,
yeah,
there's a lot of fucked up things that
happened,
but that resistance will allow us to
cultivate our own consciousness and our
own love and a much greater way than,
than if it wasn't there.
You know?
And so in a loT of ways to really grow,
you have to seek out,
you have to seek out resistance in your
own life and society.
You know,
it'll come naturally in society,
but put yourself up against your own
fears to grow and put yourself up
against it,
and when these things do happen,
they are a great natural things that you
can rally behind and then bring forth
your best asset attributes and best
aspects because that's what.
That's what allows us to grow its
resistance.
Absolutely.
I mean that's what working out is.
Yeah,
pretty obvious.
Like if you don't train hard,
your body does not grow.
If you don't put forth effort,
your body does not get stronger.
You don't get more endurance unless you
push yourself.
There's only one way and it's you got to
go through something hard in order to
get something good out of it.
There's no other way.
And that's one of the weirder things
about being a person.
Yeah,
and really it comes down to people also.
One of the things that I've been ranting
about a lot lately is choice.
You know,
and people this,
we live in a society that loves to take
choice from us and say,
all right,
everything is a disease.
Everything is privilege.
Everything is this thing.
You know,
you really didn't have a choice because
there were these preconceived conditions
and and it really,
it's robbing us of choice because with,
if we accept our inherent superpower,
which is choice,
then we have responsibility for who we
are and if we have responsibility for
who we are,
all of us have such a harsh self judge
that every failing we have,
if we say,
well,
it was up to us,
the judge just beats us to death about
it.
So we'd rather shrug our responsibility
and go with our hands up to the judge.
Judge,
it wasn't my fault,
it wasn't my fault because we have such
a harsh self judge in our own head that,
that we intend to do that.
So we,
we give up our inherent superpower,
which is choice because we don't want to
take the responsibility,
but at any point we can take that back
and you have to deal with the judge and
you deal with the judge by making a pact
to always forgive yourself.
Forgive yourself for any of the fucked
up things that have happened and just
accept that we're all imperfect.
This idea of perfection is nonsense.
We're all gonna fuck up.
We're all gonna make mistakes,
and so the judge is,
this is nonsense.
You know,
it's like we're all gonna have come to
the place we are,
you know,
through any variety of channels and
where it's going to be an imperfect
path,
no matter what.
So continued to pound that own message
of self love and forgiveness and then re
harness that element of choice so that
we can then decide what we want to be,
who we want to be,
what we want to go and put our intent.
Fourth and yeah,
and maybe not everything is possible,
but what better thing to do then tend to
fail in the cause of your greatest wish
and your greatest intention in your
greatest desire.
I mean,
that's the ultimate warriors death.
That's what they would talk about with
vala to find an enemy worthy enough to
kill me in battle.
That was the the ultimate idea,
and we can all choose those battles and
choose that thing that we're fighting
for and fuck,
if we fail,
so what?
But at least if we're going out on that
way,
you know,
we'll go out with a smile 100 percent of
the time,
but it starts with really harnessing
that choice
and the worst people that you know are
the people that don't have a good self
judge that everything they do is
awesome.
Yeah.
Those motherfuckers never grow anywhere,
right?
I mean,
that's a huge issue with comedy.
Um,
when you run into people thAt have
terrible comedy sets but think they did
great.
Like we would always,
greg fitzsimmons and I would always talk
about that with like open miker.
So there's people that hear phantom
labs,
like they think they're doing great and
they have this delusional self opinion
where everything they do is awesome and
they don't know why they're not
successful already.
They know why they're not famous.
And those people,
I believe in some sort of a weird
narcissistic way.
You could look at it this way,
that those people are there to teach
you.
This is the consequences of not feeling
that awful feeling when you fail.
Well,
that comes from the ego being so fragile
that their ego is so fragile that they
can't accept the fact that they may have
not done a good job.
so they will manufacture ideas in their
heads so that they did a good job no
matter what,
because their ego can't take the truth
of the blow.
Like,
man,
you fucking bombed out
there.
So it comes from insecurity and
fragility and then they create this
ridiculous story in their head about
what it is because they can't withstand
that truth because ultimately I think it
all comes from the same thing.
Lack of self love.
That lack of ability to be like,
man,
I fucking shit the bed and I'm okay.
Everything's okay.
I'll be all right with,
you know,
but the good ones can,
I was talking to bur,
um,
couple of weeks ago he did a set at the
comedy store and I saw part of it.
It was a,
he was killing and then I ran into him
in the hallway and uh,
I go,
oh man,
main room show was great,
right?
And he goes,
I fucked up.
At the end thOugh,
I tried to hang in there too long.
The last pit bomb,
like he was just,
it was a rotten adam that the last bit
like he goes,
I fucking hung in there too long.
I should have got off of the bit before
that puck,
you know,
like,
but you know,
when I was in there he was fucking
killing you know.
But that wasn't in his mind.
The success was not in his mind.
This was like,
okay,
whatever that happened at the end,
don't fucking do that again.
But that's why he's bill burr.
That's why he's really good.
And because he's so,
he's,
he's able to take that feeling,
but at a certain point he'll be able to
have a beer or drink or whatever,
you know,
dinner and just laugh about it and he's
not going to carry that.
Trauma exists forever.
It's just like feel it,
like fuck,
I could almost had it and that's
healthy.
But then it ultimately you have to have
that moment of forgiveness really like,
yeah,
fuck it.
Of course.
Well that's the beauty of being a comic
as opposed to being a fighter.
Because the comic can have that moment
and just the next night go on stage and
I'm sure he killed were my.
He was killing like he's a super self
critical guy,
so whatever the bad moment at the very
end it was probably just fairly,
you know,
like less funny than normal.
You know what I mean?
I'm sure it was funny,
but like for a fighter,
like,
like here's a perfect example,
someone like luke rockhold who just got
knocked out one round by michael
bisping,
he's got a fucking rot with that.
That's kind of chew away at him.
That mistake that he made for months and
months and months until he gets back in
there again.
And even if he wins his next fight,
he didn't win that fight.
That fight is still there.
The fight still gonna be chewing away at
him and if he's smart he'll keep that.
That's a,
that's a little engine that when he's
thinking about like when he's at the top
of the hill and he's like,
has got to be the last sprint.
That engine with like wrong bitch.
Michael bisping knocked you out and he
mocked you.
And it'll get right back to the bottom
of that hill and hopefully he won't blow
his joints out and break his body with
that kind of motivation because that
also can happen to people where they.
Their Motivation sort of it out,
pushes the physical capacity of their
meat vehicle.
That's a possibility too.
You got to be real careful with that,
but.
But that even though it seems like a
terrible thing that happened to him is
not just a good thing for him,
it's a good thing for all martial
artists.
It's a good thing to understand.
You are a human being.
Your jaws made out of bone.
Your skin is made out of flesh.
The nerves are just like anybody else's
nerves.
If you get cracked by a left hook,
the way michael bisping cracked,
luke rockhold,
you're going night,
night,
everybody goes night and unless
your market,
and it just seems to be pretty fucking
tremendous shots.
It just,
it goes back to that idea that the act
is neither good nor bad.
It's how you respond to it.
You don't like another coop.
Carlos castaneda,
he had a great quote that for the
ordinary person in everything,
his blessing or curse,
but for the warrior,
they're only challenges and and that's
really applies the fighting at this
point.
That was neither a blessing nor curse
that he got knocked out by michael
bisping and his response to it.
Is he going to respond like gsp did when
he got knocked out by matt serra and
ringing.
Oh,
revolutionized his fighting style and
become the legend that we know them
today.
You know?
Yeah.
Maybe the old gsp was more exciting,
but it carried way more risks.
So we adapted any became better and you
know,
he became this indomitable force.
See,
I don't even think the regular gsp was
more exciting that I,
I,
you know,
exciting to me is a weird term.
Like when I look at the gsp that
destroyed bj penn or john fitch,
that motherfucker was pretty god damn
exciting and that's post matt.
Matt serra I think,
but the matt serra a analogy is a
perfect one because it's the same sort
of thing.
who's fighting a dangerous guy that he
underestimated.
And by the way,
both of them won the ultimate fighter,
so it's perfect.
Perfect analogy.
And both of them were huge underdogs and
both of them went on to win with
spectacular first round knockouts.
You gotta respect everybody and human
beings that are professional fighters.
Even if you think you're better than
them,
they have weapons,
man,
they take people out,
they all have.
And you're a person,
but you think that because you beat
chris weidman,
you destroyed leo machida,
you beat the fuck out of all these
people and you strangled bisping.
The first time you met him.
Me like,
there's no way this guy's going to beat
me.
No way.
It's impossible.
And so you go in there super relaxed.
And I remember when I was competing in
the taekwondo dates,
if I was relaxed and I didn't feel
nervous,
I felt like shit.
Yeah,
it was terrible feeling like I,
I only fought well when I was scared.
And I think that's a,
that's a really important point for
almost anybody you know,
you,
you really have to have some element of
danger involved in,
in the contest,
if that's not there.
If you just like,
you can't do shit to me,
and all of a sudden,
boom,
that left hook lands and your legs go
well,
that's the.
That's a key characteristic of being in
flow state that the stakes have to be
high.
Like everybody uses surfing as an
analogy.
Well you can serve some baby ass waves,
some two foot waves and a sand bottom
and you're not going to get in flow
state.
You're just going to be kind of paddling
and cruising around,
but you surf that gnarly fucking double
overhead on a reef,
on a coral reef,
bottom fuck out of here and in flow
state,
let alone what like laird hamilton is
doing,
surfing those monsters when the stakes
are high and you're really feeling that
that's what drives you to your highest
performance level.
So shane dorian coming in next week,
oh shit,
can't wait.
Talk to that guy about sharks and shit.
Guys,
I'm an admin and he's a bow hunter to it
should be a lot of fun,
but yeah,
these people that are,
that are doing really exciting,
really dangerous things,
they carry with them the consequences of
those really exciting,
really dangerous things like
occasionally you're gonna fail and when
you fail this,
an important to know that you can fail.
It's importAnt to know that no matter
how much you have mastered whatever
you're trying to do,
there are consequences to every zig and
zag.
Yeah,
you know,
it's just really about mastering the
ego.
The ego is the main thing that thwarts
you on either side.
It gives you this false sense of
confidence and importance.
I remember I was recently reading a ryan
holiday's new book.
Ego is the enemy and he has the story of
the persian king,
xerxes,
you know,
who is a mortalized in 300 and whatnot,
and this guy was such an egomaniac.
It makes sense that he got his ass
kicked,
you know,
repeatedly.
So they were building bridges over this
canal.
It's as the story that historians wrote
and the water came up there.
Storm came in storm surge and it wiped
out the bridges.
Well then he ordered his men to take his
chains and lash the water 30 times as
punishment,
you know,
for,
for knocking down the bridge.
And he cut off the people's heads.
Who made the bridge?
Right?
Oh,
so this fucking ego maniac.
And then another storY where he,
he's trying to build this tunnel under a
mountain and he sends a letter to the
mountain,
has his emissaries go out to announce
this letter to the mountain saying to
the mountain mountain,
if you give us any trouble,
I will move you piece by piece into the
sea
king xerxes.
What the fuck you talking about?
You know,
so no,
just no acknowledgment.
He's been fed his own bullshit so much
that he's just,
he thinks he's god and he plays that
role and then he runs into 300 bad
motherfuckers at the hot gates that
their marbly and they just wipe out half
of his forces because he's just.
He can't fucking see beyond it.
And there's so many ways that ego does
that either inflates you or it makes you
too fragile or you know,
and that's really,
if you're going to be good at anything,
you got to have to come and confront
that,
confront that beast.
Listen,
isn't it?
The problem with royalty to is that it's
just sort of bestowed upon you.
It's not earned.
And so you have this distorted
perception of your own greatness,
right?
That's sort of,
you could say that about a lot of hot
chicks.
Yeah.
Royalty or like reality tv stars.
It's the same thing.
You have all of this bestowed upon you
for some mysterious combination of luck
and timing and whatever.
But royalties.
The weirdest example of it,
you know,
I was at disneyland a few weeks back
with my family and uh,
I was talking to this guy that works
there and he was talking about this five
year old boy who was a prince from some
middle eastern country.
And he came here with this huge group of
guardians and watchers or whatever it
was,
but they were all at his beck and call.
And so this five-year-old was telling
all these adults what he wanted,
when he wanted,
what he wanted done,
and they all just scrambled and randall
and he was saying like,
it was so bizarre watching all these
people
at the wrath terrifying of the wrath of
a five year old boy and that this five
year old boy wielded just fucking like
supernatural power house.
And he never earned any of it.
He's like,
he was just born a five year old boy
who's born this little child and now
he's lived for five years.
He's just a boy.
That's all he is.
Didn't that never done shit?
Yeah.
But they're all like,
you know,
I actually have a really unique
perspective on that because my parents
split when I was two and very quickly to
worlds develop.
My dad was wealthy commodities trader
and I was his only child on that side.
My mom remarried to a swat team,
squad leader who had three older boys,
you know.
So those were my older stepbrother.
So at my dad's house I was the little
prince.
My dad was busy trading and doing his
thing and I had either body guards or
other people around and I could feel I
could,
would develop these punk tendencies that
come from that,
from having basically servants taking
care of me at the time,
and then I'd go back to my mother's
house and I split time half the week I
go back to my mother's house and my
three older stepbrothers would just beat
the punk out of me.
Literally like,
what the fuck are you doing?
You're like,
you're being ridiculous here.
And so it allowed me this perspective
where I didn't get to go and follow down
that path too long because it's,
it's so alluring.
You know,
if you have power,
you're going to take it,
you know,
especially if you're young,
I got all this power,
oh,
I'm not going to take it.
I'm a five year old,
but I know what's right.
And I know,
you know,
if you can do that and you can push
those buttons,
you're for sure going to push those
buttons as a kid.
So it's important to,
to have that balance.
Fortunately for me,
I had the other side to keep me,
keep me in check because I serve,
I surely would have been a fucking
menace if I had just gone down that
perfect older stepbrothers two,
not brothers stepbrothers.
Sure.
So they have no problem beating the shit
out of it.
I remember one time I came,
they bought us all paintball guns and I
remember my,
one of my older stepbrothers just laid
in wait behind a wall like this.
We were on the property and you could
hear me coming and just shot me point
blank in the fucking face.
Paint ball gun just lit me up,
you know.
And that's the thing,
like obviously at the time I was not
happy about it,
but this you learn,
you learn things about the world and you
get like a different toughness that
comes from that form of resistance that
if I didn't have that I wouldn't be
nearly the balance person.
I was uh,
you know,
I am now.
I'm not fucking,
I'm not perfect or balanced or anything,
but that certainly helped.
Yeah.
I think competition is good for that to
failure.
Losing,
you know.
Um,
especially individual one on one type
competition when you realize the
consequences of not working hard and you
run into someone who has worked hard,
you know,
I remember my competing days,
I had a chance to see some,
uh,
when I was 19 I went to the olympic
training center
and there was the world cup in Colorado
springs and I got to see like the best
of the world compete and I remember
seeing like this insanely high level and
it was one of the most important things
as far as like my development as a
competitor,
like seeing the top of the food chain,
seeing the best guys and realizing like
fuck,
look how hard they work.
Like jesus christ.
I was watching them train.
I was watching guys compete and I was
realizing like I'm not nearly as
dedicated as these people are.
I'm not nearly as.
I have to ramp it up like in a big,
big,
big fucking way.
And seeing that and comparing yourself
against other people's efforts and
realizing that your fall short so
critical for people.
It's so critical to to realize like,
oh,
that guy would fuck me up,
like look,
because if you're that five-year-old
prints that five-year-old prints
probably has no idea that someone could
beat his ass,
you know,
he probably just thinks he just gets to
yell at you and you have to get on your
knees and start bowing and lowering your
head and if you,
if you don't experience other people's
efforts,
if you don't experience like a real
competition where you see people pushing
themselves as far as they can to try to
win a race where you see the last few
meters of the race where guys,
you could see it in their face,
the fucking struggle.
If you never do that,
if you never do that,
if you never push to that very edge of
physical capacity,
then you don't.
You don't really understand what's out
there.
It's like one of the reasons why people
who have never had a,
any martial arts experience at all or
don't know how to fight at all gets so
weird around confrontation with men.
I mean,
how many times have you been around men
who don't know how to fight,
but all of a sudden they get a few
drinks in them and they start yelling at
people and talking crazy shit.
It's like they don't know what to do.
It's almost,
they're like confused and so they're.
They're almost inviting their own doom.
They're almost like sending out a bat
signal for someone to punch them in the
face.
It's almost like a subconscious thing
where they want someone to kick their
ass because they kind of know that
they're so unbalanced in their approach.
The fight club moment,
like they're running a light,
their own place on fire and beat
themselves up just to get that attribute
out.
But you see that.
And the other thing is where people just
don't take the idea that there may be
consequences to their actions to heart.
Like I had a perfect example of this.
I was after partying with an ex gamer,
I won't mention anything farther than
that,
but an x game guy,
super successful like 20,
like 20 year old kid and he's been so
successful for so long.
One of those child prodigies,
right?
And We go and he's,
he's over at my apartment downtown in
austin and we were having fun and he
continues to.
He goes in immediately puts on his
music.
Then he cranks it all the way up to full
volume.
I'm like,
yo man,
we got neighbors.
You can't do that shit.
You know,
you can't crank it up.
He's like,
okay.
And then he goes and he does it again.
And he goes and he does it again and I
keep warning.
I'm like,
man.
So finally,
like time number five,
I go up to him,
I go,
you turn the fucking volume up,
shit's gonna,
get real.
And I looked at him with a total
different tone and then he looked at me
like,
oh my god,
I didn't think that that consequences of
my actions was even a fucking feasible
possibility.
Like that moment of like,
oh shit,
this other dude may punch me if I
fucking do this again and be that
disrespectful.
It was like for him,
he had surrounded himself with other
people in this environment where just
having respect for somebody in the
consequences for repeated disrespect
might actually be.
There was like a,
a world changing moment for him or he
looked up like,
oh shit,
this is weird.
Yeah,
I'm royalty.
exactly.
You don't punch me.
Exactly.
And then after that he was like,
shook by it and he kept saying,
oh man,
you know,
no disrespect,
blah blah blah.
But he needed that moment of like,
look bro,
fucking shit Will get real.
There are consequences,
you know,
this is not some fucking fantasy land
here.
You know?
And then that moment totally changed,
totally changed things,
but people don't get those when they
don't have that resistance,
they don't have the older stepbrother,
they don't have that person that can
step in and be like,
yo fucking knock,
knock that shit.
Attention to the other people to just do
what you want.
exactly.
You know,
there's a thing about like,
not necessarily just x gamers,
but people that do these extreme sports.
There's a lot of these guys are like,
um,
I don't want to say like pranksters,
but they,
they revel in annoying people and
pissing people off and the attention
that they get from it is real strange,
strange,
like sort of a vibe that comes with a
lot of bmx jumpers and all these crazy
fucks that do a lot of risky shit.
They have that sort of personality trait
where they're constantly pushing the
envelope and some sort of a strange way.
You know,
they,
they like people pissed that I'm mad.
You mad a,
it may come from the fact that
particularly skateboarders,
they're constantly getting persecuted by
lame ass authority figures telling them
not to skate on their fucking hand
rails.
Some banker comes that don't scare on my
hand rails kid you fucking punk,
you know,
instead of constantly being chased
around by people who are dummies and so
maybe it develops this kind of like
counter,
you know,
this,
this reaction.
So that reaction of being persecuted for
doing what they're enjoying to do
creates this like,
fuck the man.
Yeah.
but maybe
maybe they should yell at them.
Like if I was fucking walking down that
some dude came flying down the rail and
broke my leg.
I be like,
you piece of shit.
Like a lot of those guys are fucking
nuts,
man.
And they'll put people in danger,
like I've seen some crazy stunts on
youtube where these dudes jump on top of
these railings and slide them to the
bottom and fuck up and plow into people.
Like
the world is not an x game.
Like you can't just,
you can't just do that with a bunch of
other people around.
But some of those folks care,
certainly not.
And I think you,
we appreciate that.
Not giving a fuck like no.
Johnny,
knoxville and steve.
Oh steve,
he's still doing it.
He's,
he's like deep in his thirties.
You still climbing up on top of gigantic
towers and cranes and shit and risking
his life.
Man.
He fell off of a billboard.
He was climbing up on top of a billboard
to shit on seaworld to change.
uh,
a street sign.
What's is 42?
Is he jesus christ.
You can break a lot of shit falling from
that high.
And he fell.
He's just so ridiculous.
He's hilarious though.
He also did something that I was kind of
trying to tell them not to do.
He had tim kennedy choke them out on it
is a showtime special.
Tim kennedy choked him out.
He went completely unconscious and
balanced his head off the ground called
blanca.
I mean,
you mean if you ask tim kennedy to choke
you out,
you're going to sleepy sleep,
sleep,
sleep.
That's deeper than red.
Is there a video that.
Oh,
jesus christ here.
Let's play it,
man.
Silica.
This.
Oh my god.
There's no sound.
Okay,
so he's not just choking him.
He's choking them for quite a feW
seconds.
He's already out.
Likely that that is not cool.
Like tim shouldn't have done that.
Like right there,
that drop.
That is a fucking huge head wound like
to to drop and bounce your head off the
ground like that.
That is really bad.
Really.
tim should let that dude down.
A little lighter.
That's probably steve o's agreements.
Diva wanted it to be fucking savage.
Maybe you think he asked for that.
He didn't know then.
Well,
tim should have known him.
Doesn't give a fuck.
He's been knocked out.
No,
he doesn't give a fuck if someone tells
them to do it.
Yeah.
Got.
It's got a lot of that wolfington oh,
what like 70 percent will get the joke
out and drop you for sure.
He has hashtag hard to kill on like half
of his fucking posts.
He,
he,
he put a fucking post out with isis
giving his address.
I don't know,
like,
come get me bitch.
I don't know.
He's a.
I mean I've gotten to know him really
well because he trains at on an academy
so I see them coming through there all
the time and just the sweetest dude too.
Great.
And he shows up like no chip on his
shoulder.
No,
like you've comes in wearing silly
little shorts and a fanny pack and just
a big old smile on his face and a silly
fucking mustache and he just,
he's got nothing to prove.
But then he has that switch,
you know,
obviousLy where
he can do whatever access,
whatever that place is.
That fucking wolf heart.
is this a new post of his jamie that you
put up?
It says,
my friends and I are just kicking back
waiting for the call when we can fight
these bastards the way we need to and
not go to jail.
Hashtags still serving.
Hashtag hard to kill.
Let us know when it's time.
He's got his shirt off with an axe with
one of those ridiculous.
What are those things called guy fawkes.
Beard and mustache.
Yeah,
it is.
like musketeers,
three musketeers style.
He's,
he's an animal,
but we need people like that.
This,
this,
this.
That's the extreme on the,
uh,
on the warrior end of the spectrum.
That's the extreme,
you know,
the,
the flamboyant warrior.
Yeah.
The thing that you can really appreciate
is the truth of it.
Like it cuts all the way through to the
core.
You know,
the peopLe that are,
that you shake them a little bit and
some other person emerges and you shake
them again,
like a fucking magic eight ball.
That's gonna come out.
Like those are the people that are the
worst.
Tim,
it's tim.
You shake it again.
It's a little slightly angry or tim.
It's the same fucking guy.
And that's,
that's always a beautiful thing when you
see it.
People have dealt with those deeper
things,
they've reconciled all these forces
that,
you know,
you're not going to put them in a
situation where this other person
emerges and you're like,
what the fuck is this selfish piece of
shit
guy?
You know?
Yeah.
And this is also something that we were
talking about earlier when you were
talking about people like the,
the camaraderie and the craziness of
going to war,
that they actually enjoy it and become
happy there and some sort of a weird way
because life becomes real because life
becomes real in this chaotic moment.
There was a ta,
I think it was a ted radio hour.
It might have been a radiolab podcast.
I think it was a ted radio hour,
but they were talking to someone who
there were talking to soldiers and they
were talking to people about happiness.
Like what makes you.
It wasn't ted show,
it was a ted talk and it was.
They were talking about happiness and
I'm.
One of the things they got into was
these people that went over to Iraq and
Afghanistan and served and they would
come back and talk about it and they
said it was horrific.
It was chaotic.
It was scary,
but it was the happiest days of my life
and one of the reasons why I was the
happiest days of their life was this
intense bond and comradery that they had
developed with these other people that
they were serving.
With.
That there was nothing like it.
There's no sort of closeness and bond of
brotherhood that even comes close to the
bond of brotherhood when you need to
rely on these people and they rely on
you for your very life and you're taking
other people's lives.
Yeah.
I think that's a huge missing piece in
our society and I think a few people get
to access it on sports teams and,
and on different,
you know,
and obviously in war,
but I think that tribal element of going
through these shared rites of passages
and going through these things that
bonded a group together so that you
really had true altruistic love for more
of the more people around you.
You know,
I think that's a deep calling that we've
kind of ignored,
you know,
like those soldiers would truly fight
and die for each other,
which is the epitome of altruism.
It's wanting the other person's good
even at the cost of your own,
you know,
and,
and that's a feeling that I think feels
inherently the best.
It's our natural state to be this like
the son of love,
you know,
like,
uh,
like Just pouring it out and not
deciding who gets a bit truly feeling
that way about a group of people.
And I think there's,
you know,
as we develop.
I think that's one of the concepts that
I'm always talking about is recreating
some kind of tribal element where you do
go through these rites of passage and it
doesn't have to involve war,
which is inherently an unsustainable and
unnecessary practice,
but how do you create that same
closeness,
but do it through ritual,
do it through,
you know,
going and climbing this mountain and
taking the psychedelic,
however you want to do it in a way that
can bond you together with the group so
you have those feelings where there's
no,
there's nothing.
You're holding back.
Your truth is completely exposed.
You're naked with all your intentions
and thoughts and ideas and you just
truly want the best for another
individual and and that tribe,
that feeling of tribe.
That's what tribe is and I think we're
missing that.
We have this ourselves in the small
nuclear unit and then we have this whole
wide world which is too big to really
care to that degree about and we're
missing the intermediary,
which is Just this band,
this group,
this family that were willing to do
anything for.
Yeah,
and then obviously expanding that even
further from your media group to the
rest of the human race.
Yeah.
So difficult to even conceptualize when
tim kennedy fought,
there was a fight for the troops and um,
I believe it was in Texas.
Was that where it was?
He fought half natal and he knocked him
out and this was like,
I don't think they even captured this on
film.
Tim hopped on top of the fence and he
was just calling out to all the troops.
I mean,
I really don't think.
I don't know if the camera's caught this
or not,
but he was pointing to everybody who's
just telling them he loved them.
He's like,
I love you guys.
I love all you guys.
I was pointing at people,
I love you guys.
And then like what,
what he was doing,
he served.
He's fought.
I mean he's,
he served in combat many,
many times.
He's still serving now that the reality
of like his expression and his love for
those people,
it was very,
very intensely moving.
It was one of the most intensely moving
post-fight speeches or post-fight
celebrations I've ever expect.
Not not one of the most that I've ever
experienced
and they,
they were pushing so much energy back
them chanting and it was tense.
ReallY amazing moment.
I mean,
you imagine those,
you read about those moments in history
where the great leaders come in and have
that moment with their,
with their troops,
you know,
and you don't see that now in today's
warfare,
you know,
there's no,
there's no that,
that independence day moment right now
where they give that rousing speech and
everybody's just pounding their chest
and you know,
that was.
That's something that's really deeply,
deeply moving and powerful and to have
that,
you need
to have that force of resistance that
you're all allied against,
your all banded together against that,
that other thing,
and it's just choosing a thing that is
truly worthy of,
of your fight.
So choosing to fight against something
that's not just another people or
another race or all the stupid things
that we choose to fight against,
but choosing to fight against something
truly worthy of that fight.
Yeah,
and this,
this thing to them,
to these soldiers was this concept of
the enemy being a truly evil force,
you know,
whether it's isis or whether it's
anything else like these guys were all
united against it and to have tim
kennedy as this person who's like a
figurehead representing them and win by
knockout in a military base in such a
spectacular fashion on television and
understanding all the weight behind all
that because there are cameras.
It is being televised.
It is being broadcast all throughout the
world that will be available for ever on
the internet and you know,
through the ufc fight pass archives.
You'll always be able to watch that.
And when he,
when he connected with that left hook
and the crowd fucking roared and natal
went out.
It was nuts,
man.
It was nuts.
You know,
you like history,
especially the history of rome,
which I'm most familiar with.
There was always these moments in time
where a leader would naturally emerge
like that for whatever reason,
and then it would always made the
emperor is really squirrely because at
any point in time that person could all
of a sudden be like,
yep,
my army now bitch deal with,
you know,
obviously that can't happen in that
time.
But if tim said,
you know,
if tim after that Jumped off the cage
and said,
follow me,
like,
fucking all of them,
be like,
yeah,
fuck it.
I'm going to tim,
tim kennedy and brian stann run for
president.
I'm in.
Totally.
I'll campaign.
I'll fucking,
I'll follow them around the country.
We know that's what we need.
We need someone who understands the
realities and the consequences of what
these people in these hallowed halls of
justice are trying to pull off all
throughout the world.
Instead of having these old chicken
hawks or sydney's has a hose.
Was.
It was from.
There was one of the best quotes from
the documentary on hunter s thompson
where he was,
uh,
talking to.
It wasn't ed muskie.
It was a mcgovern and mcgovern was
saying I'm sick of old venn in air
conditioned buildings,
sending young men to go off and die in
war,
and that's,
that's really one of the most despIcable
aspects of the decision making process
by quote unquote leaders is that there
their consequences are so minimal.
I mean if,
if every single politician and leader
had to be at the head of the army,
had to go to the fray,
had to be on the front lines.
How many actual wars where we get into
or serve,
let's say they weren't Capable of
fighting,
but at least they'd have to serve at the
frontline hospital so that every person
with like for a week,
you know,
you're at the front lines,
you're just a nurse assistant,
you know,
so everybody coming back blown up,
shrapnel you know,
sent.
Can you pass this message to my
sweetheart,
tell this to my mother.
Like they're receiving that.
So at least they have to get in touch
with it and,
and understand the consequences of what
they're doing.
But it's easy to get this sociopathic
kind of mindset like,
oh,
these are just pieces of those,
you know,
those like the conquest boards,
it looked like big chess boards you see
in all of game of thrones or whatever
know I moved my troops here,
I move.
this becomes all strategy.
But you lose the humanity of it,
you know,
you lose that connection with really who
you're dealing with.
And those moments are incredibly
important to,
to really keep the thing going and keep.
Keep you,
keep you in line.
Yeah.
And people would say,
well,
if they did do that,
what would it be?
Impossible the way we need it and the
way we do it now.
Yeah,
exactly.
don't do it that way.
You fuck.
I'm trying to say it's one of the main
problems with,
with war and with leadership is that the
people that are in charge at the very
top and a lot of ways are behaving like
that five year old boy at disneyland is
a prince.
They have too much power with no
consequences.
They have too much power that
essentially they haven't really earned.
You know,
when you've got a guy like jocko willink
who,
uh,
was a real military hero who is over
there commanding when that guy talks
about the military or talks about war or
talks about actions,
the respect is that you don't need to
respect him.
You're going to respect him.
You got to understand that this is a guy
who's been there and you're going to
listen because it's real.
When a guy like dick cheney started
talking about military actions,
you're dealing with some fucking weird
detachment from the reality and
consequences of war from a guy who
during the Iraq invasion a lot of the
times was in a bunker member,
that member,
they would talk about him being in some
underground bunker and I was always
like,
why is dick cheney in the bunker?
And george w dot bush is on tv.
I will fuck is running this country for
real.
But these guys that got multiple
deferments like dick cheney did to avoid
actually serving in the war.
I mean,
I think he got several deferments to
avoid having to actual see,
actually see real combat.
Those are not the people that she'd ever
be able to make those kinds of decisions
to put people in harm's way.
They just shouldn't be able to.
You need a guy like jocko.
You need a guy like tim kennedy.
You need someone who's actually been
there.
Yeah,
yeah,
no doubt.
It's,
it's an interesting time and the nature
of war is.
I don't think we're obviously with
posttraumatic stress being such an
epidemic that it is now.
We're not adequately dealing with,
with that element of things.
I mean,
it's an incredibly traumatic aspect of
we're not prepared for death can come at
any moment unseen,
you know,
like our bodies.
Yeah,
it makes sense.
All right.
There's the barbarian hoard.
They're gonna run with their pointy
thing and I'm going to have time to run
at them with my pointy thing and that's
when death might come,
you know,
but does not gonna come from this random
explosion that happens.
You know,
every car could be a bomb.
All of this.
It's this crazy time that we're in and
we have to really pay attention to what
that's doing to the humans and use the
best technology available to to fix
that.
And I think obviously rick doblin has
been on here a few times,
is on the forefront of that,
but we're just looking at the whole
thing completely wrong.
You know,
we have old ideas,
bad ideas,
bad leaders,
and it's again,
that thing where truth is there.
We undersTand that there's this
epidemic.
We understand,
here's some possible ways to fix it,
but it hasn't percolated all the way
through.
So we're in this transition period.
That's,
you know,
it's,
it's ugly right now and a lot of ways,
but you can see the,
you can see the horizon,
you see that sun poking through the
clouds and you know that truth just has
a different resonance.
It has a different frequency and it's
adopted eventually.
You know,
it's,
it's only,
you know,
there'll be people who still think
there's flat earth and whatever.
There'll be some resistance to be some
resistance.
But for most of us,
it has that frequency in that resonance
where it's going to eventually win.
And that's what gives me a lot of
confidence.
I'm just kidding.
I'm eddie said he doesn't believe he
does post a lot of pictures of the
whole video the other day about some
dude who's arguing against the flat
earth and,
or for the flat earth in the weirdest
way possible.
But it's what I was talking about before
that I don't know if I articulated it so
well,
is that when you look at our culture and
look at society and then you think back
to the time of xerxes and all the crazy
shit that was going on thousand years
ago or 2000 years ago.
That's not that long ago,
man.
No,
it's not.
It seems like it is.
But like when,
uh,
I was listening to a dan carlin's
hardcore history and he was talking
about world war world war one.
And he does this amazing.
Um,
I think it's a five part series on world
war one and it sinks in like jesus
christ.
I was 100 years ago.
like that's nothing that is fucking,
nothing like that is so recent and the
world is so different now than 100 years
ago in 100 years before that.
So different.
And then,
you know,
he does.
He had this piece on the mongols a
thousand years ago.
Well,
not much different,
you know,
it's like,
I mean,
not much different in terms of the
relationship between then and now.
It's,
it's so,
so recent.
So recent.
Yeah.
A thousand years is nothing in the scope
of the world.
Right.
you know,
and then you take it back it out to,
some graham hancock's theories that he
puts out magicians which are seemingly
make a lot of sense that we'd reached
heightened states before and gotten kind
of wiped out and restarted.
How many times did that happen?
Well,
how many times did we restart?
Hit the reset button.
One hundred percent with randall
carlson's evidence with the two of them
together.
They really sort of both provided the
missing pieces that each other need.
And if you've never heard those
podcasts,
there's some of my all time favorite
the randall carlson ones and the graham
hancock ones and the one time that I had
the two of them on together,
which is just a fucking epic meeting of
the minds.
The world is most likely experienced
some cataclysmic disasters,
most likely due to asteroidal impacts
and it was most likely the cause of the
end of the ice age.
And also the collapse of civilization
was available then and the rebirth of
what we're seeing now as ancient
history.
So when we look back at things six,
7,000 years ago,
we think,
wow,
this is the dawn of civilization,
not so fast.
This is the dawn of this current era of
civilization before we get hit again.
And that is entirely possible and it's
the crest of this wave.
Maybe they got,
maybe they got hit in the 19 twenties
level of technology or something like
that,
you know,
but,
but.
And they didn't reach 2016 level,
which is probably most likely.
I think we've probably advanced the
farthest that we've gone in the wave.
But who knows how far they got,
maybe it was 1850 where they're shooting
fucking revolvers and fucking whores and
saloons and whatever.
Or maybe it was some amalgamation,
surely was different.
It's going to be.
They'd had some things that may be
better and other things that we're still
kind of silly and.
Yeah,
but it's really interesting to explore
that and give yourself some perspective
on.
Yeah,
they have some sort of a parallel
development in terms of their
achievement,
but in a different way.
Like Egypt to this day we,
we can't build those fucking buildings
the way they did it.
And people could say,
oh,
we certainly could 2 million,
500,000 stones that way,
between two and 80 tons.
If you put 10 of those a day in place,
it would take you 600 plus years to make
the great pyramid of giza.
That's how fucking crazy that building
is.
So if you say,
we could build that today,
good luck,
bitch.
Need more faith in the unions.
Yeah,
well if you get it done,
if you're off by literally like a
quarter of a centimeter with each block,
you're fucked by the time you get to the
top.
Yeah.
Think of that like if you're lopsided
one way or the other,
by the time you get to the top you're
fucking doomed.
This an interesting theories about how
they did it,
but none of them really sink in.
All we definitely know is it took an
incredible level of sophistication and
it was done.
The most recent it could have happened
was 2,500 bc,
which is just nuts,
nuts.
They're so smart and it's not just
Egypt.
You're going to go to Peru.
I think I've shared that photo of me and
one tombow the same one that crazy
sucralose shared as well.
You go there and you look the way the
stones fit together and look at how the
things are carved out and it just make
any sense the size of the stones,
like what did you do?
How'd you do this?
God,
I would give so much to see the
construction of the pyramids.
If there was like one time in history,
if you could take that sort of a time
capsule and go back and watch.
For me,
it would be ancient Egypt for me for
sure.
I would want to see how those crazy
fuckers walking around with their wacky
goth makeup on and weird golden robes
and making those hieroglyphs and god
what a fascinating,
weird blip or weird era in the.
The development of the human mind and of
culture.
If you think of what they were capable
of doing and what they did accomplish
over.
Who knows how many.
You know,
we're.
We're sort of going back trying to piece
it all together.
But one of the things that graham
hancock and even more importantly,
John Anthony West,
John Anthony West has a new series.
Apparently a magical Egypt too.
I haven't seen it yet,
but magical Egypt one is just fucking
mind blowing when he goes into great
detail about the different construction
methods from the old kingdom to the new
kingdom and that he points out that this
is most likely evidence of a different
era of construction and not.
Not as not just a different era,
but different by 10,000 years maybe,
and that the hieroglyphs on the inside
of some of the pyramids which dictate or
rather which,
um,
go over and depict the various pharaohs
throughout the different stages of
Egypt.
Think go back 30,000 years.
But what modern egyptologists choose to
do is to say,
well,
all those guys that was all fiction.
Yeah,
like back when anything more than 6,000
years ago.
Just fiction.
Like,
okay,
so that's who bitch says,
oh,
you know,
how do you know like this is,
it's crazy enough that they did this
4,000,
500 years ago.
That's just crazy enough.
Okay.
But it's no more crazy to think that
they were doing it 30,000 years before
that.
Like this whole thing is this majestic
sort of monument to human innovation in
a,
in a weird way that's not like what we
do now with cement and steel and glass
and asphalt roadways and fiber optic
cables.
No,
they had some other thing going on and I
think graham mixed up kind of a cool
point.
Like they were building something
specifically for permanence.
Yeah.
Like why,
why did they want it to extend through
time?
Because all of our shit,
you know,
another ice age hits and you know,
that the ice moves in and starts
grinding everything and basically grind
most of what we have to dust anyways,
you know,
but they were creating these big stone
blocks,
these things that were harder,
you know,
that would withstand the test of time
and why.
And that's,
that's kind of an interesting
speculative part of graham's theory,
but what seems concrete is that
there was these cultures advanced and
decided to do it now why gets into the
speculation but go back tappy in gunung
padang and Indonesia and then Egypt and
all of these places really,
really super interesting and interesting
to imagine,
you know,
if,
if the flood did kill off most of that
civilization and they kinda just settled
in different places and the accounts.
Just one of the best books I think ever
written was that magicians and just
going into the mindset of,
you know,
he talks about they call these people
watchers and then some of the watchers
when I would get a bad reputation
because they like sleeping with local
girls and so they would be like the bad
watchers than the good watch.
Well maybe they were just.
The pimps have their time,
you know,
they,
they were eating more proteins that are
a little bigger,
you know,
they have their little smarter as of
course the girls liked them,
you know,
like why you got to hate on the watches.
Well,
when they burned the library of
alexandria,
man,
did they do the human race a massive
disservice we could have learned so much
could learn so much about why the
ancient greeks would go to Egypt to
learn shit and to engage in psychedelic
rituals.
It's funny that the greatest minds of
their time would go specifically to
Egypt to engage in these psychedelic
rituals and to learn from the egyptians.
The greatest minds of our time today
will mock psychedelics.
It's kinda,
it's kinda fascinating.
There's so few in terms of like
mainstream recognized scholars will even
entertain the possibility that there
could be some beneficial aspects to
engaging in ritualistic hallucinogenics
well,
all of academia is about defending to
the death,
your own structure of information and
psychedelics are inherently disruptive
and I think people have that knowledge.
They know like,
shit,
I may totally rethink all my whole
theories and you have to confront those
demons that you're hiding that that
which is hidden will come to the surface
and that's generally the beauty of this
process,
but if you're defending something,
you know and you're attached to it and
it's part of your identity and because
it's part of your identity,
it feels real.
Like that's the trick that the ego
plays.
Ego says,
my identity is me and I will defend it
as if it was my flesh and blood.
You know,
like all of these things,
my theories,
my position in academia,
it becomes real to the ego and so it
fights as if it's defending your own
blood and bone body,
but it's not.
It's just,
it's bullshit.
It's your identity.
It doesn't matter shift,
it's fluid.
It's,
it's,
it's a manufacturing of that,
of,
of that ego,
that attachment,
and so psychedelics are threat to that.
If you've been defending something that
you don't want to get challenged,
it could threaten your position of
authority and power and people are
afraid to do it.
There's no real other reason to have
that fear widespread.
Yeah.
There's a time and a place and it's not
for everybody,
etc. But you know really it's such a
powerful tool to access truth and you
can't be afraid of truth.
It's just a silly positioned to be.
Yeah.
There's a really interesting documentary
that's a
funny enough,
a narrated by charlton heston about the
mystery of the sphinx.
I think it was on nbc at the time,
but one of the weirder moments in it
where was when robert schoch,
the geologist from boston university and
John Anthony West presented this
evidence that the sphinx most likely was
far older than 2,500 bc because of the
erosion in the sphinx compound that
could only be attributed to water.
I've heard arguments against it.
I'm against it being water and it being
wind and sand,
but they just,
they don't fly.
It seems like they're.
They're working to try to make that a
wind and sand erosion.
Whereas it's pretty obvious the fishers,
the way it's cut into the.
I mean it makes total sense that it was
water,
but the only thing that could make it
water would be that it had to be before
9,000 bc because 9,000 or 7,000 bc,
9,000 years ago,
one of those somewhere a lot longer than
2,500 bc and the argument when it was
presented to this archeologist,
he was laughing,
mom,
well,
what culture was around 10,000 years
ago,
they could have done this.
What culture.
Meanwhile now we have those cultures.
Now we have real evidence of go beckley
tappy,
which is 12,000 years old.
We have real evidence of all sorts of
weird shit that they didn't know me and
then now they're finding evidence of
human beings in north America.
Fourteen thousand years ago,
they're finding a woolly mammoth bones
with a clear indications that they were
slaughtered by human beings like cuts on
the bones and then like,
oh jesus,
like people we don't know.
We just don't know.
We don't know what the fuck happened
between 10,000 years ago when the ice
age ended and today there's just so much
weirdness and we definitely don't know
what the fuck happened before that.
Before that there is a lot of unfilled
pieces in that puzzle.
Yeah.
It's,
it's like it's really as the greatest
mystery of all,
you know,
like the greatest mystery novel that
I've ever read was graham hancock's book
uncovering something that was real and
trying to piece together the puzzle and
in 20 years from fingerprints to
magicians,
all the new evidence that have come
really supported his initial evidence,
which was pretty good and fingerprints.
But then by magicians it's fucking
whelming.
You know,
he was just so openly mocked by a lot of
people that didn't want him to be right
or didn't want anyone to achieve any
sort of notoriety by having some sort of
an innovative idea.
I mean,
they just,
they,
they pushed back on him so hard,
but the stuff that randall carlson
presents,
like these various cradle craters that
they've uncovered all throughout the
world that indicate asteroidal impacts
as recently as 5,000 years ago and deep
into 12,000,
10,000 the,
the nuclear glass they found all
throughout and europe
that indicates massive meteor impacts
somewhere in the neighborhood of 11,
12,000 years ago.
Yeah,
I mean it's all.
It all makes sense at all for files or
fills in like,
well,
what could have said,
oh,
well that caused it.
Oh,
that fucked a lot of shit up for sure.
I mean if you look at that nuclear
glass,
that's the same kind of shit that they
find when they do nuclear tests and they
find it all throughout europe,
all throughout asia,
which indicates that they literally got
bombed on by the.
Yeah,
the circumstantial evidence.
It's just mounting and mounting and it's
interesting.
You know,
we hear about these things that are like
myths and one of the ones that I saw
that I'm not sure if it's true or not,
but it's an interesting take on what
actually happened to the cities of sodom
and gomorrah because in the bible,
you know,
god rained fire upon,
it,
turned all these homosexuals and
sodomists and people that sounded like
they're having a great party and you
know,
what they were suggesting is that it was
a media that burned up in the,
in the atmosphere,
and it raised,
it created this flashpoint effect,
which they know can happen and created
this flashpoint effect where instantly
the ground temperature reached several
hundred or thousand degrees or whatever.
So it was like this instant,
everybody's just fucking crispy,
you know?
And how do you explain that other than
an angry god doesn't make sense,
you know,
you have no idea.
So these stories and myths get passed
down and they're like,
well,
why did that happen?
Well,
I don't know man.
I went to sodom and there's some crazy
shit going on.
But fucking so after the fact,
you make up these stories.
Man,
I've of course,
yeah,
that's why it happened.
It was just an unlucky party town.
What was.
It was hard to do.
I mean that was,
that was hard to explain.
Then.
So people went to that,
but today,
I mean this guy in orlando,
obviously he's fucking crazy,
right?
But he's killing gay people because he
thinks the gay people are doing
something against god's will.
They're doing something bad and evil.
So like in his mind like his wrath is
like the wrath of god on these people
with in 2016 with the information that
we have with all the evidence that we
have,
there are still people that are inclined
to go towards some sort of a,
of a biblical or in his case,
the koran version of,
of the reality in which we live in like
this.
This is today when you're talking about
7,000,
8,000 years ago,
I got only knows what it would've been.
It was probably straight out of game of
thrones,
like the reaction that people had to any
sort of a natural disaster.
It had to be the will of the gods.
It had to definitely be something that
our own actions had caused and so when
someone would stand up,
like I'm the old dirty dude on game of
thrones was once everybody to repent.
High sector high sparrow.
Yeah.
That when that type of person would
stand up and tell the people of this is
because you have
angered god and it will come again.
If you keep doing that and god forbid,
god forbid,
strange use of words,
but another meteor shower.
I mean meteor showers.
Oftentimes they come like one after
another after another and then he says
this and then it happens again.
He's right.
I told you god is angry,
you know,
and then that gets passed on projections
and it is.
This is a really strange time and what I
found interesting is I think that
christianity will never go away and our
cath catholicism and these major
religions,
but they will evolve.
Like if you look at the trend,
you know,
back in the middle ages,
they were doing crazy thing torturing
people.
I went to a dungeon in the inquisition.
All of this crazy shit that was in Italy
who were going,
I'm going to Italy this summer.
It was fucking horrifying.
It was in one of the mountain towns.
I don't know exactly when,
but there's several of them there and
all the different torture devices that
they have.
So many of which by the way,
involve the genitals.
Like I would say at least 40 percent
involved,
different things,
different ways towards falls and dick
and pussy and tits and all this.
I mean,
it's just these ways that they could
channel their own perversions into this
unarguable point about,
you know,
this is god,
this is what god wants,
but they're really just pure status.
Accessing that sadistic demonic energy
and,
and doing it under god's name.
You know,
and that's what happens when you create
these systems that only a select few can
access the knowledge.
You know,
nobody else can talk to god,
these few people that did it and we're
talking and we're the descendants of
those people.
We guard the knowledge.
You can't reach it.
So it creates,
instead of decentralizing in it and
opening up truth to everybody,
it's a select few that have it.
Only a few people know god's will,
not everybody can find it.
And that's creates these massive power
and balances.
Whereas any good religion is going to
completely decentralized and say,
you know,
not listened to me.
I'll tell you what god says is,
here's how you go talk to god yourself.
Here's how you reliably go find your own
deepest truth.
You don't need me.
And it's the same with any good teacher,
any good healer,
you know,
like the very base level is,
uh,
is a teacher healer who,
who fixes,
you know,
you come to him and he fixes,
and then the next level is someone who
teaches you how to fix yourself.
Like that's the,
that's a master,
but give a man a fish.
Yeah,
exactly.
You can.
Yeah.
And then the final level is just to
really the great mystics.
And even if you go back to jesus and you
go back to the really great mystics,
their message truly is that,
you know,
you don't need us to fix it.
You're already whole like just recognize
that you're already whole.
You're already perfect,
you know you are.
You are the son of man.
You are god.
I mean that was really the core message
that's got twisted in a million
different ways and manipulated for
power.
Those was one of the other more
interesting podcasts from dan carlin was
on martin luther and lutheranism
lutheran,
this discipline and that he was the
first one to translate
the bible from latin into german and
translate it in the phonetic way that
the people could actually understand
what the word of god was and not have to
be a priest because they were relying
upon these priests and not only that,
he was also the first one to say that
your interpretation of what god meant is
essentially up to you,
which was just a blast for me to these
people that had massive amounts of
control.
I think if you're looking for that one,
I think it's called the prophets of doom
or the prophet of doom.
I think that's the name of the podcast
from carlin on on that insane time,
but it's amazing.
Amazing to think that,
you know,
in that sense you're talking about like
what was it,
the $1,400 or something like that there.
That's not that long ago at all.
That's nothing and people couldn't read
the bible.
I mean think about that.
They were relying upon these.
I mean they weren't even pedophiles back
then.
They were allowed to fuck,
which is really interesting.
Like that pedophile thing.
They.
That only happened once.
They wouldn't let the priest fuck and
they wouldn't let the priest because the
priests were fucking too many people
because the priests were the rock stars.
The priests were the celebrities totally
to power.
They're terrible.
Always create,
get you pussy.
They were getting mad pussy so someone
came along and said,
all right,
you fuckers no sex.
They just made that up along the way.
I mean,
it wasn't even like it came from god and
it's like it came a lot with.
They had already established one way of
behavior.
Like even the pope pope's used to have
wives.
They had armies like pope's weren't like
this weird fiba old guy who sits on a
golden throne and it has little gay
people do.
Cirque du solei dances in front of him
like that last asshole,
but not the most recent pope is like
kind of humble pope is humble hope the
cool pope.
Yeah,
but it's,
it's,
it's evolved and changed throughout the
year,
but just,
you know,
600 years ago or whatever it was you,
or 500 years ago,
you couldn't even fucking read that
shit.
Yeah.
Again,
it's the control of power,
the control of information rather than a
shamonic way,
which is always show you not tell you.
You go to a two,
then that's another great way if you're
trying to find out who you should go
with,
like if someone's busy,
blabbing their mouth and trying to tell
you all of the things that you'll see
from an iowaska journey or something
like that,
tell you all the lessons and give them
to you that way.
If I can go the other way,
you know,
like the true,
the true path is,
you know,
here you go.
I'm going to create the environment and
you're going to go find truth for
yourself.
You're going to find whatever the truth
that is and they have faith that you'll
arrive at the truth that's going to be
most beneficial for you and most often
than not,
it comes back congruence with those
ideas and that's that's the true path.
That's the path that any religion should
take,
and I think one of the reasons why
buddhism is so popular because it's
similar in that way.
It teaches a practice or zen teaches a
practice that allows single person to
access that higher state of
consciousness.
Everybody can reach nirvana.
It's not just the chosen,
preselected,
this thing,
here's how you do it and go for it.
And I think any good,
any good spirituality system is going to
have that in common.
Isn't it interesting though that that's
sort of the exception to the rule to
find a system or finding an individual
like a martin luther or like someone who
steps up and says,
no,
the whole world should benefit.
All the people should learn this.
Everyone should get.
It shouldn't be about centralized power,
shouldn't be about controlling the
people,
like that's a rare thing and that's
fought against like vehemently like it's
the,
they passionately resist this and in
many ways it's like what we were talking
about before,
like it kinda takes almost negativity
and evil to bring out the best in people
in a response.
And it almost,
it sort of takes this horrible control,
this dictatorship of religion and
ideology to resist in such a powerful
way that you change everything around
you because of these people were just
sort of,
well,
you know,
this is the word of god,
and go with it.
Don't go with it.
Don't give a fuck.
Everything's cool.
You know,
oh,
you don't have to give me any of your
money and I'm not trying to fuck her at
anybody.
I'm just hanging out over here.
Would probably be no resistance to that
religion and there would be no sort of
rebound effect where people are trying
to find their own truth and
understanding that the negative
attachments that they have to all these
religious cults or sex or whatever you
want to call them,
the negative attachments that we have
them are completely unnecessary.
Like they don't have to be there.
That through what everyone's trying to
find through religion.
You're trying to find the word of god
trying to find ultimate love and wisdom
and power and this one individual who
has created literally the entire
universe or this force has created
literally.
So why is it this guy's trying to fuck
my wife and why is that?
I have to give everybody my goal that
how come I can't read the bible myself?
How do I have to trust this guy was
trying to fuck my wife and steal my
goats?
I have to trust that asshole.
Fuck that man.
Yeah,
and so then as martin luther guy comes
along who actually can read it and
understand it and translates it and
there is a massive blow back and
obviously just based in Thailand,
dan carlin's podcasts,
but apparently his influential position
in the community was the only thing that
kept him alive like anybody else doing
the exact same thing he was doing would
have been killed by the church.
The church would have killed people for
distributing the word of god in a way
that other people could understand and
it hadn't been done before.
Like people had questioned the church
before.
They just fucking strung them up and cut
the dick off and shoved it in their
mouth and lit them on fire and launched
them in a catapult.
They didn't give a fuck back then.
Barbaric.
Yeah.
And it's in the.
How does.
So how does that,
how does,
how does a system like that take hold
and take fact and you know,
we,
you've talked about the kind of the
toxoplasma that alters behavior,
this disease that will alter human
behavior or altered mice behavior and we
have that disease too and it's called
fear and it's,
it is the primary disease that once fear
takes a hold of us,
once we fear that if,
if we do something wrong,
will be punished in the most obscene
ways,
you know,
look at like a bosch painting from,
from Italy during the time of all of
these inventions of how you were going
to be tortured if you went against the
will of god and you'll be punished not
only for a little while,
but eternally eternal torture and
suffering.
Like that's some kind of just punishment
for,
you know,
having lustful thoughts or whatever.
But that's what they believe.
So they inject people with this fear of
virus and then the fear virus robs them
of their own freewill,
robs them of their ability to think.
So it's like this form of virus that
takes a hold of somebody.
And then you allow these atrocities to
take hold because fear is within you,
and in other cases,
maybe it's the greed virus or some other
thing that takes hold,
but it's really like this thing that
really limits your ability to use
rational thought into,
you know,
to harness your own power of choice.
But fear is that original,
original virus that the religions played
so,
so well,
you know,
fear and guilt.
It's weird because it's such a
distortion of a really important aspect
of being alive.
Like you have to have fear of
consequences.
You have to have fear of animals and you
have to fear of the ocean.
You have to have you.
You have to have a healthy respect for
the consequences of stepping off of a
cliff or the consequences of walking
into a bear den with a mom and her cubs.
All those things are real.
You know?
And so you have to have fear.
But there's some fear that people have
that exists for no reason.
Well,
the,
the idea that he's a good god fearing
man,
god,
god fearing god is fucking love.
It's like the most perfect form of love
and truth,
not when the skies on fire because
people are blood fucking
right,
so yeah,
you see where this other perspective
comes from,
but you know to fear,
love.
It's this trans.
It totally fucks the mind like it sets
the mind upside down.
Once the minds upside down,
it looks at everything all funny.
Yeah.
Nothing makes sense.
You've removed a cornerstone of logic.
Now you need to fear god.
Oh fuck,
fear god.
Well then everything else is just
twisted up and fucked up and you can't
even use your rational mind.
You can't find the way out because your
whole.
The whole paradigm has been turned on
its head and twisted.
Well,
isn't it an interesting in that respect
then that it seems that the more
knowledge we gathered,
more information we acquire,
the less we have to be fearful of,
the more we can say,
oh,
that's not an angry god,
that's a meteor a,
and then one day,
oh well we'll figure out how to deflect
those meteors.
We don't have to worry about the ice age
ending or,
or rather a dinosaur killing chunk of
iron and stone from
the sky slamming into the ocean and
killing all of us because we see those
fuckers coming.
Now we just shoot a net at it and push
it off into jupiter or some shit mean.
This is all information that will slowly
but surely eliminate the need for fear
and I guess that's probably going to
extend to the consequences of injury and
death as well.
I mean at one point in time they're
going,
things keep going the way they're going.
I guarantee if they get to you within a
certain amount of time,
that probably going to be able to
reanimate.
Animate you.
Yeah.
I mean it will certainly remove
consequences eventually,
but there's so much we can do right now.
We surrender our power to use those
fears all the time.
How many times have you seen somebody
shriek,
you know,
because the fucking cockroach was around
in the room.
It's a cockroach.
They're clean,
they're cleaning up the garbage that's
on the floor.
They've never harmed anyone ever.
And that little thing is going to cause
you to scream and your heart to race and
like you can actually choose,
actively choose through,
you know,
exposure to that and working through
that to get over that fear like we have
these choices and I think you have to
collapse your fear into actual danger so
that fear and danger on the same level
and you can go too far where you can
remove too much fear so you're not
actually afraid of danger.
And you know,
people do like grizzly man clearly did
that,
you know,
when he was hanging camping with the
grizzlies and should've had more fear
for those fuckers,
but he didn't.
By the way,
I'm getting werner herzog.
Oh nice.
Yeah,
that's awesome.
That'd be really cool.
Is going to come on.
Beautiful.
I'm excited.
I don't give a fuck what he wants to
talk about.
We're talking about grizzly man
cave of forgotten dreams.
That too.
I'll talk about that as well.
That was amazing.
I want to talk to them about that tom
cruise movie where he played a bad guy
as well.
Time of jack reacher,
but grizzly man.
I also think we're dealing with,
if you have never seen that documentary
is one of my favorite unintentional
comedies,
you have to see it.
It's about a guy who decided he was
going to save the bears.
The bears did not need fucking saving.
They didn't want saving.
They didn't need saving.
They weren't interested in his saving
and eventually the atum eventually they
determined he was.
Yeah,
they've figured out the assessment.
Yeah.
Harris part bears are so amazing,
man.
Bringing it back to our camp as we bring
this bitch home.
When,
when we were up there,
it was like,
I felt like,
um,
since you're,
since you've been practicing archery for
a couple of years now and you've been
really getting into it,
that would have been the perfect first
archery hunt because it's a controlled
environment.
It's,
um,
it's a,
a really high likelihood of success.
Even though we both struck out it's a
high likelihood of success.
And there's,
um,
there's,
there's a crazy intimate connection that
you have with an animal when you're up
close with them within 20 plus yards and
you shoot it with a bow and arrow.
That is like some really
old dna that you tap into that some like
there's a,
there's like a switch that goes off
where your tissue is like,
oh,
we've seen this before,
this we did this 500 years ago.
Like there's,
there's genetics I think that are
attached to archery and some sort of
strange way.
Apparently I have,
I'm not a traditional archer,
I haven't done that,
but they say it's even stronger in that
that shooting,
even just shooting a regular bows like a
recurve bow has an even more sort of a
visceral connection to the human body
and the human mind and you know,
with ted nugent calls the spiritual
flight of the out of the mystical flight
of the arrow that there's some sort of a
weird ancient calling.
And when you,
when you do that,
when you.
I wonder if a catapult to do that launch
catapult on a motherfucker like,
damn,
this feels good.
I think people progress that all the way
to the,
you know?
Yeah.
But I think the catapult wasn't used for
hunting,
for use,
for war cattle.
Jesus christ be a herd of elk.
Boom.
Then you go look for scraps.
Take you shoot a recurve all the time.
I shoot a recurve all the time.
I really enjoyed it.
Super way less accurate so I wouldn't go
hunting with it,
but it's really accurate with them.
No.
Yeah.
First,
yeah,
I guess.
I guess for me it's way less accurate.
I'm sure some people are really practice
and they get really good at it,
but there's so many weird things like
judging distance,
super weird site.
Well lisa,
yeah,
shoot instinctive so there's no site so
you're just feeling it.
But you read a book,
zen and the art of archery,
eugene arrows book,
great book and it.
It applies to regular compound bow,
but you really feel it when you have the
recurve and.
Yeah,
and just a piece of wood and sinewy
twisted and you're knocking the air and
you're just going off instinct cause
there's so much more variability.
It's less,
it's less,
you know,
mechanic.
It feels like you're just more of like a
flow type of thing and it's fun.
It's fun to fun to do that.
I always imagined that.
It's like,
yeah,
like
a lot like playing pool in that you
develop a feel for where it's gonna go.
Yep,
and you have to do it.
So they say that it's one of the most
important things about traditional
archery,
instinctive shooting is that you have to
shoot hours every day to be really,
really accurate,
but like if you watch like olympic
recurve shooters,
they have a lot of weird shit going on,
man.
They have like a clicker so they'll pull
the arrow back a certain distance and it
click will go off because you could have
the go all the way to when I'm making a
motion like you could pull it back to
your chin or you could pull it past your
chin and it gets not like a compound bow
or it hits a wall.
Compound bows extremely accurate and
guys like john who was a
guy who have set up my bow and he.
He wrote the curriculum for the world
archery federation,
whatever the fuck it is,
and travels all over the world to teach
people proper technique and teach people
and coach international teams and
archery.
He was saying that if you get like a
rifle shooter and they shoot like
freehand,
not resting in something to 100 yards,
that archers are actually regularly more
accurate at a hundred yards with a bow
and arrow than someone holding a rifle
as well.
Yeah,
that's really wild.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
I mean with the,
with the traditional shooting though,
compound bow shooting your.
If you've got a 70 pound bow it's going
to shoot 70 always.
Yes.
So that's,
that's a variable.
You don't have to factor any kind of
recurve bow can shoot 20 pounds if you
just pull it back a little bit to
fucking 65,
whatever.
Depending on how much you can actually
bend the limbs of that.
Yeah.
And go.
So the up and down variability,
I mean side to side,
you should get pretty accurate,
you know,
just by anchoring and kind of lining
that up.
But the up and down really depends on
how far you pull and your breath and
your release is not all.
Your release gets super squirrely too
because its fingers don't have a little
release thing.
So you hold on a little tight or you
don't let the string flow through your
fingers the right way.
It's just
shoots off all squarely.
Yeah.
So that's why the olympic recurve
people,
they have like clicker.
So they pull their arrow back and once
it gets to a certain length it sets off
a little click.
So it's like click and then they
released the arrow so they know when to
release it.
They know when they've pulled it back
far enough to get that click.
Yeah.
It doesn't make sense.
But you know,
it's uh,
I,
I gotta think you'll lose a little some
of that.
Yeah,
magic.
You're starting to move at all,
all the way towards the compound,
but at a certain point might as well
just shoot the compound if you take all
of the,
the feel of that thing out.
Yeah,
I wouldn't.
If you look at a compound bow,
if you look at someone who's shooting a
compound bow like people,
I put a picture of me up,
uh,
from our camp that ben took when we were
there.
And one of the things that people have
commented on,
like look at that fucking weird thing,
like always pulleys and cables and all
these things hanging off of it and the
site and the stabilizer.
There's so much going on.
In your case,
it's to the max as much shit going on on
any boat is ever,
ever been on a boat.
Yeah.
I tried everything.
I mean I've whittled it down,
have added things and taking things
down.
But oh,
there it is.
There's the photo.
Yeah.
There's a lot going on and I fucking
that thing.
But all those cables and pulleys and you
know,
the stabilizer and the adjustable site
that goes up and down depending on
distance,
but it's so fucking accurate.
Yeah.
But so fun too,
man.
It's like there's very few things I
enjoy as far as clearing my mind as much
as just shooting at a target.
Yeah.
Well it demands president.
This demands that you're in the moment
you're thinking about other shit,
you know,
because everything is so finite.
Same with pool.
I think gravitate naturally to these
activities that to be good demands full
attention and inattention is bliss.
Is happiness in intention because that's
the present moment.
You will.
It definitely removes all of the outside
distractions that really aren't.
They're not important right now.
Like right now,
you're breathing.
You have food in your belly,
you're alive,
you're healthy.
What is important?
Well,
you have a bone in your hand.
What's important as you make that arrow
hit that x,
so shoot it stupid.
Stop thinking about some girl you fucked
when you were 18,
right?
While you thinking about a car that you
sold when you were 22,
man,
if I had that car today,
I could fix it up and like,
what are all these extraneous silly
thoughts?
What are these traumas that these
animals don't carry?
Like you ever heard of a bear with
erectile dysfunction.
Maybe never.
Maybe maybe this gay bears maybe,
but they can still get it hard and
viagara I don't know.
All of these things that we have in our
that our monkeys are just broken because
we've ceased to recognize the monkey and
all of us.
You know,
so getting back to that and looking at
nature is just a great way to do it.
Whether you're hunting or camping or
whatever.
Just fucking soak that in.
You'll learn shit.
There's also a feeling that you get when
you're in the woods where there's.
There's no cell phone reception,
there's no people.
You don't hear anything.
You're just surrounded by trees and
wildlife in some weird way.
It's for some people,
they find it lonely.
They find it like,
god,
I hate this place.
Doesn't give a fuck about me because it
doesn't because you realize that you
really are a part of this enormous,
almost infinite system,
infinite and the terms.
If you go down to the macro level or the
micro level,
you're,
you're down to adams and you're down to
subatomic particles and then you expand
from there to cells and cell walls and
the structure of tissue in the body and
then the instincts that come with
keeping the body alive and then with a
human being language and then the
culture and media that you have absorbed
that has given you this distorted idea
of what life is,
what being a human is,
what being a man is that music should
play.
When you see your girlfriend,
you know,
you know what I mean like this,
like they.
There should be a a score to your life
and that you are enormously important
because your ego wants you to survive
long enough to shoot your loads into
someone and make little baby arby's and
this.
All these things.
They don't.
They don't matter.
When you're in those woods,
all those things,
it's like the woods confront you with
this ultimate reality that you are a
part of this infinite system and this
infinite system.
When you really expand upon it,
the,
the very itself,
the very planet,
this planet and all planets themselves
become tiny little subatomic particles
in the nature of the universe.
Yeah.
That's the perspective is so key and it
can be kind of mind boggling to think
about it.
I'd like to,
you know,
it's almost like we're,
we're lords of our own universe in our
universities.
Our body,
our thoughts can manifest different
things.
Our choices create the environment that
we live in.
So you know,
it's like we have our own universe and
then we're plugged into this,
you know,
greater universe that is,
that we know all around us,
the planet and everything else and
that's plugged into the larger and you
start just expanding your perspective
and it just kind of really goes on
infinitely.
You know,
like the cell is as part of an organ is
in there.
That's it's universal liver cell,
the university,
the liver cells,
the liver in there,
one cell in that thing.
It goes up and down infinitely and you
just get a,
get a perspective that,
you know,
everything's gonna be okay no matter
what.
Like everybody,
just fucking relax,
enjoy yourself,
get back in touch with the monkey,
get back in touch with love and whatever
happens,
it's gonna,
be all right,
there'll be another earth,
there'll be another time,
there'll be another opportunity for this
thing to go.
We get so caught up in the minutia of
the details of this thing or that thing.
It'll be okay if the earth blinks out,
you know,
some other point in some other time in
the vastness of eternity,
another fucking awesome earth will come
with new,
awesome animals and it'll be okay.
Everything will be okay.
You heard avi gentlemen,
everything gonna be okay and with that
good night,
ladies and gentlemen,
much love buddy.
I'll remark is on social media.
If you want to follow me,
I love you guys on a dotcom pitches.
Go there and get optimized.
Holla.
Oh.