The Joe Rogan experience,
we just,
we just adapted to our environment.
This is one reason why Chinese people
have like really skinny eyes.
I don't know what it is,
but whatever the reason is why they like
to develop that,
that thin slit where you're,
you know,
you don't have like this big wide eye
and develop like a less hairy body.
Whatever those reasons are.
I don't know what they are,
but that had to thank God for them.
Well,
I had
one woman,
like every one of those attributes,
the little,
the little slitty eyes,
so she can't,
she can't see that I have no hair
because she can only see the middle part
of my face and she's got no hair,
so that's really nice.
Beautiful Feet.
A lot of them do,
but there's some women that get their
feet bound.
That's an Asian thing to how they got so
nice.
They were,
they were bred to have little tiny sweet
feet.
They're not,
they're not like big American women feet
with the fucking Bunyan and like
endless,
like one toe that's longer than the
other one.
Doesn't bother me now.
No,
it doesn't bother me at all,
but the crooked toes bothered me.
Yeah.
Shouldn't,
shouldn't really care.
I'm all broken up.
Why would I get yours?
Must be all fucked up from kicking
people then.
That's weird.
Yeah.
I don't have any.
Anything.
Is your feet smell go?
Oh,
definitely.
Who's don't?
Well,
if you have your feet don't smell.
It means you're not working.
You're not getting anything done.
I feel like mine smelled bad.
Like I just put spray everything and it
still comes back the next day.
If it's a health issue,
maybe she wears sandals thing,
man.
Well you know when your,
your feet are sitting in these like
polyester cotton socks.
Right?
And you're sweating and it's all just
brewing function there.
I mean when you have a plastic sock.
Okay.
That's what a nylon sockets.
Plastic socks on.
Is it?
Does anybody wear nylon socks?
I guess they do,
right?
They're kind of nylon,
Yeah.
Ray on whatever fucking socks made out
of.
It's not made out of wool.
Okay.
And anything other than wool.
It's not going to accept all that
moisture and dry it up very well.
So things that get soupy in there,
like especially if they're like plastic,
cotton's pretty good about saying to
the,
to Mundo your balls smell Brian.
Uh,
no.
But if I take two showers a day,
but I was thinking they should have like
ball hats,
you know,
like where you put your balls and like a
little little sock.
Wouldn't that make all underwear dude?
Yeah.
But twitter doesn't like fuck he talking
about this thing that you put.
They're like smaller than pants and you
put them on there like shorter than
shorts.
Wait a minute.
Wait,
I feel you on this.
What would you call him?
Greg there under your clothes.
The ball socks,
socks.
And then they have like an opening.
What if there was like an opening you
can open for your penis to come out of
like it's there technically,
but the flap is so big that you actually
can't.
I'm,
I'm down dude.
Let's invest money.
You want to hear a crazy thing you're
talking about like intellectual
connection and stuff like that.
Um,
so coffee was invented in Ethiopia as we
said in,
in Ethiopia.
They do it like a coffee ceremony,
like a,
you know,
a very ceremonial way to prepare it and
drink it and when they do the coffee
ceremony,
they,
it's like they gather people together
from the village.
They and they talk about things.
They talk about the news of the village,
they talk about,
um,
things that are going on in the,
in the world.
When coffee moved from Ethiopia to
Yemen,
totally different deal.
Like in Ethiopia,
it's always a woman that makes coffee.
Whereas in Yemen it wasn't like that,
but they still would talk about news and
intellectual and stuff like that.
Then coffee moved from Yemen to Europe,
um,
you know,
Italy and England and places like that.
And the coffee house still remained a
place for intellectual exchange and
discourse and stuff like that.
They plan the American revolution in
coffee houses,
you know,
in
that's Kinda,
we're wired,
right?
Like fuck,
there's something.
But there's something about coffee that
like that like gets your mind going as
well as stimulates you and wakes you up.
But also the tea party movement like
that,
that had an effect on the way the United
States took off just by simply the fact
that they went from t to coughing.
That's the,
there is.
There are people that speculate that
that's totally valid.
Yeah.
That coffee consumption is a part of the
American,
uh,
drive to ingenuity and imagine
fucking speed.
We're country on speed.
I wonder if they could show gross
domestic product posts.
Starbucks.
Not starbucks impacted people's
productivity,
but still,
right.
If you go to meet somebody at a coffee
shop,
you're going to talk about something
that's different than going to drink
with somebody at a bar or have dinner
with somebody or something like that.
It's different.
It's somehow more about exchanging
information,
more imagination.
It's stimulating.
The stimulant of caffeine in coffee is
stimulating and then the flavor is
enriching.
You enjoy the flavor and then you get
fucking happy.
And it's been that way since the origin
of coffee.
Well,
coffee houses.
Yeah.
Coffeehouses were always thought of as
places where people read poetry and you
know.
Yeah.
And he politics,
etc. And as you said,
plan revolutions,
that's interesting to me.
YeAh,
it is interesting.
And that's one of the reasons that I
think that I like to work in coffee.
Like why?
What's one of the dumbest things the
government has ever done is try to keep
pot from people because you have,
you did smoke it,
you find out it's awesome.
You don't die.
And then you start distrusting
everything.
Right?
Well,
masturbation.
Think about how many people thought they
were going to die for masturbation.
right?
You lose your mind.
You get hair on your palms.
But when did that end?
That wasn't my time.
No.
Well,
no,
I'm talking.
I'm talking about earlier times,
early 20th century,
19th century.
You know,
I remember her that you were going to go
blind,
right?
Oh yeah,
there were.
There are medical books in the 19th
century.
Kellogg had this whole thing about it.
You know,
the,
the causes,
insanity,
insanity.
It causes hair to grow in your palms.
You know,
just a weird ability locked.
Is this kellogg from kellogg cereal,
right?
Yeah,
he had a thing.
He was very sick.
You ever see that?
The road to wellville pea did people who
masturbate.
You had a thing about that.
I mean the whole thing with cornflakes,
cornflakes were invented was to stop
boys from masturbating.
how was that?
How was the idea behind that?
Explained this to us before then?
The idea is that spicy foods excite the
sensibilities and so if you eat
something that tastes interesting and
you're going to want to come so they can
pet and also graham crackers.
Graham was another these big aunty
masturbation evangelizers,
so they invent these really
intentionally bland foods.
They like to keep the teenage boys from
jerking off so that when they finger,
they're assholes.
They immediately.
ExactlY,
exactly.
We'll keep them in the dark.
Oh,
that's true.
I'm so fucking horny.
Spend your finger.
Father
just touch me.
Squirt fucking mount
gay now.
sheds
could milk itself.
That would be bad.
It can climb fences.
Cows does yoga and can reach its own.
Teats accounted so smart.
Realizes how fucking huge is.
I can just run through that fence
anytime.
Wooden fences.
These keep cows in with.
That's unbelievable.