They got this all done.
Boom.
Live.
Okay.
What the fuck will you just tell me?
Hi Matt Farah,
what's funny?
You can see again,
we're just talking about Rolls Royce.
Yeah,
because I was hearing your in your new
baller studio,
which congratulations.
Thank you.
Sick admiring your skylights.
And we were discussing the Rolls Royce
and uh,
the starfield ceiling they do,
which is they put all these fiber optic
lights into your headliner and it looks
like the stars and it's,
I think it's 15 grand option,
but I bad ass.
So bad.
So bad ass.
And not only will they do it so you can
get your standard star pattern,
which is just whatever the guy,
just random random lights or they'll
make you exact constellations if you
prefer writing,
like if you were one of those astrology
pdf or they will make you,
you know,
the sky directly above your house if you
give them a coordinate,
there's a photo of a bad ass bad ass.
It's like so awesome.
You are,
you're balling so hard.
You were driving around with a car with
stars in the roof.
Well,
so the last thing I said before you hit
live was that they have just announced
they have come out with a shooting star,
so I don't know how it works.
I'm not sure exactly what,
but I guess you could do.
You can get shooting stars and you're
crazy.
What are they going to do to make the
whole thing a big lcd pattern or
something?
Yeah,
I guess or I dunno.
I guess you can.
You could have run on an led or a fiber
optic line that,
that works in a kind of a train.
I,
I emailed once I got that press release
because I get press releases and I just
delete them.
I don't,
you know,
but when I saw a shooting star ceiling,
I responded kind of further info in
video on this and they said they'd get
back to me.
So I've never even been in one of those
things.
Never.
No,
no.
You must,
you must.
What is it like in there?
It's like sailing yachting.
Phil Hartman had a really,
really old,
I think it was an old Bentley.
I mean like really like sixties old,
old,
older than that,
like 30 years old.
It was fucking old man.
I wish I paid attention to cars back
then,
but back then it was when I just started
getting on TV.
I really didn't.
I,
you know,
when,
when I was broke,
I always loved cars when I was a kid.
But then I was broke.
My attitude was like,
don't think about some shit you're never
going to be able to afford,
so just don't think.
Look at you now.
Joe Rogan with all the toys somewhere to
park them somewhere to park them.
But he had this old ball looking thing.
It was like,
it was like something out of a citizen
Kane.
Oh yeah.
Just this incredible boat and you know,
like pontoon fenders,
the whole deal.
Thank you.
Shifted it on the tree.
Probably I would say if I had to guess
something ball or that Phil,
like I would say Bentley,
continental [inaudible] would be the
most likely.
It might've been a candidate that's a
stunning automobile,
but he loved that thing.
He would just have this giant smile on
his face with that thing.
It was,
oh,
he loves cars.
That's great.
Phil Hartman's bit like that.
I wish I could remember because like I
said back then like if you asked me to
do like there's cars that I don't know
shit about like rolls royces or Bentley,
but if you show me like an old porsche,
I'd be like,
oh,
that's a 73 long nose.
I know that we all have our areas of
nerdom,
like muscle cars.
I can.
I'm a good muscle car guy.
Understand most muscle cars.
Like you could pick them out in the
lineup,
but.
Well,
Bentley and Rolls Royce were,
are a weird one because they have sort
of this intertwined history where they
were separated and then they became
together and then they became separate
again.
So there's a lot of rolls.
Royce's and Bentley's that are mostly
the same car.
Those are,
that's like super baller level.
Were you like,
okay look,
forget about it.
Let's just get a car that's makes no
sound like you can't say anything.
Hoses are really amazing cause they're
so fucking cool.
Dude,
I can imagine,
and even like to uh,
a lot of car guys,
especially like,
you know,
you are such like a manual transmission,
you want your car,
I know you,
you want your car to be like really
close to a race car.
I can be in dirty,
gritty,
like I wanna I wanna feel the rocks as
our drive over them for you would,
you would appreciate a Rolls Royce is
ability to make a hundred percent of
that disappear.
You know what I'm saying?
Like disappeared entirely.
And like there's really neat details.
Like you are the word flying or floating
or sailing is so true because you don't
really drive it.
You just kind of fucking will it down
the road.
And you know how like you're,
you're a porsche or a sports car will
have like the thumb grips on the wheel
at night and three.
So Rolls Royce has thumb grips at four
and eight.
Really?
You drive them?
Underhand gangster.
Extremely gangster under.
See,
let me try that.
Let me feel this.
It's that you.
Yeah,
it's underhand.
Yeah.
Because you don't even lift your arms
above shoulder height and then you know
your car has a tech commoner,
right?
It shows you your Rpms.
Is there a rough indicator of how much
power you're using?
Right?
Roughly?
Not exactly,
but before people go crazy about the
lack of a technical term,
rolls royces,
don't have tech amateurs.
They have a power reserve gauge which
shows you how much power the car has,
but that you are not using at any given
time.
Whoa.
Right.
So if you're,
if you're coasting along,
it's at 100 going down a hill.
Maybe you're just off the gas off the
brake,
coasting.
There you go.
Power Reserve.
So if you're coasting,
you're using zero percent of your engine
and the idea is to keep that gauge low
because you want to be able to pass cars
and cruise down the road while using 25
percent of this car's engine.
So.
And they're stupid horsepower,
right?
Like crazy bomber,
Like not like crazy crazy.
But like for four to 500.
So.
Hi.
Yes.
Yet,
isn't that funny that saying that it's
not that hard for car of today,
our standards are so crazy blown out.
Our standards or the Internet has fucked
us all up.
You gotta understand.
I was reading about a new Miata,
which by the way might be like one of
the most underrated cars ever.
The new MIATA.
Lovely.
Yeah,
they're great.
Like for the bang for the buck,
for a fun little car to drive that Kinda
has real nimble.
That's around their fucking great.
But it was only like a hundred and 50
horsepower that's there it is.
That's the new Miata.
One hundred and 60 horsepower.
I think that's like,
you hear that and you're like,
what?
Yeah.
But you know there's a company in
Colorado called Flying Miata,
you know them,
right?
You know where I'm going with this.
Yeah.
They put an ls three in one of these.
So I drove on that has a 575 horsepower
ls three and it's fucking great.
That must be insane.
It's great.
You know why?
Because it's got these long legs,
you know,
like it's a little car,
but it's got the corvette long legs.
So your third gear's good for like 90.
Wow.
That's great.
Now when you're driving a car like that,
is the balance fucked up by then?
No,
it's actually similar weight it,
it's,
I think,
I think the ls conversion,
it's like a,
I don't want to say exactly,
but it's like maybe that's the older
car,
Jamie,
that they do it to a newer one as well.
It's like a few extra pounds in the
front,
but actually they have to use the rear
differential from a Camaro.
So a lot of the extra weight goes in the
back and so the cars maybe a hundred
pounds heavier with the v eight in it,
but,
but it's four times the weight of a
Miata,
like 2150.
That so like.
And then you see that that thing in the
picture was called an extra set which is
so that,
that exoskeleton thing that says flying
me out on it.
Oh this is an interesting photograph
actually.
Sorry,
podcast people.
We've got to two vehicles on a track
from flying me out of the one in front
is a an exoskeleton car with really no
body work on it at all and that's called
an excess set and so what is,
you buy that chassis and you buy a Miata
and you take apart the Miata and you put
all the Miata shit on this chassis and
so you end up with a 1200 pounds things
and you can put turbos and you can put
vh and you can do all different kinds of
stuff.
Is it street legal?
Yes,
it is street legal,
car legal.
And then the thing is called a bower cat
fish.
Did you say carb legal like as far as
like a missions?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean if you use a car legal,
like the Iraq engine,
like,
like John Ward likes or the stock Miata
engine for sure.
Yeah.
If you use a carb legal engine,
it's a carb.
It's California legal.
That's crazy.
I've driven them there fast,
but you know,
not nothing about excess sets design
should be taken from this statement.
I don't feel safe in them.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm not trying to insult or the open.
Yeah,
it's just,
it's to me,
I like having a body around me,
but it's way safer than a motorcycle.
True.
But a motorcycle.
I was thinking about this.
A motorcycle offers an experience that
cannot be replicated and if you are
going to take the kind of risks involved
in riding a motorcycle,
that experience is kind of worth it in
to,
to me in short bursts.
Whereas I don't think the experience of
driving a car with no body on it is
worth you.
I don't think teachers either,
but fuck.
Because you can get a lot of awesome car
with bodywork.
Yeah.
But it's also like the thrill of the
motorcycles,
like it is either you either have it or
you don't,
like you're either in a convertible or
you're on a motorcycle and the,
and the leaning of courses is really.
And is that thing any more thrilling
than a regular convertible?
Honestly,
I mean it's faster.
Um,
it's not faster than all convertibles,
but having the no,
uh,
you know,
the no roof.
I mean,
you just feel connected to the elements.
It's crazy and you can go because it's
so light,
you know,
you can use an a relatively mundane
engine and go very,
very fast.
Yeah.
Imagine 1200 pounds.
It's nothing.
You know,
and you put up.
Imagine,
imagine a corvette engine in that thing,
which you can do.
You know?
I mean,
yeah,
people are crazy.
I dropped some shit.
That is dangerous.
I know you're one take video series that
you do where you're kind of people let
you drive their fucking crazy hot rods.
No souped up cars.
Like,
Wooh.
I've just retired from driving people's
personal cars.
Yeah.
Good for you.
I just saw this.
I might go to reno and Brenda says this,
this is these weird software guys built
this thing in Reno that's called a test
Salon de.
That's a.
Did you hear anything?
No,
you didn't.
It's electric.
That is a tesla drive train in a 1981
Honda and it weighs,
it weighs 200 pounds and it,
it runs like an eight second quarter
mile a hilarious.
Right.
He just loved that.
This people like that out there,
the nerds are winning.
They're winning 100 percent.
Yeah.
The tests Londa Yup.
So I'd,
I'd,
you know,
weird shit,
but um,
I,
I figured out I have rolled the dice,
you know,
you gotta know when to walk away,
know when to run.
Nowhere to count your money.
Yeah.
I think the dealing's done,
I'm sure.
Yeah.
Good for you.
You made out one of the rare few that
beat Vegas.
I mean,
either I decide when to stop or a lawyer
does.
You know,
that's so true.
Um,
I just,
what we were talking about,
it's just so amazing that the horsepower
wars it because of their steady increase
every year,
you know,
you come out with a 2018 corvette,
people expect it to be faster.
It's always got to go,
hey,
we got the same thing.
Hey fucking it just put a new engine and
the Mustang 3:50
gt.
And so there's always something,
hey,
they got the gt 500 coming.
Well,
shit,
I'm going to go up to 900 horsepower.
Like isn't it crazy that it's just my
money,
like not even a lot of money.
Like you can get a hell cat for used
hellcat,
like 45 grand,
you know what I mean?
Like 600 bucks a month,
700 bucks a month and you got 700
horsepower.
You hooked me up with one of those when
I was in Denver when I was fingering the
central red hellcat mountains.
I remember that with the astronauts
outfit on fast.
Right.
Great.
It's a great car.
Now they have a wider.
Have you seen the wider bodywork?
I like that.
It's actually got quite a lot more tire
under.
That was good.
I had a complaint.
It doesn't have that muscle car ass.
I like a car with the wide body.
Hellcat does.
Yeah.
There's something about those fat tires
in the rear is an old school muscle had
dork.
That's what you want.
I saw a motivator.
Matt de Andrea?
No,
he was on Adam Carolla's.
Podcast card does car guys.
He just posted a picture on twitter of
Esau.
Your old sick fish spotted somewhere.
That's funny.
It was not in a.
It was not in the,
it was in a bit of a sad state,
honestly.
It wasn't really just,
it was a little tired and beat up one of
the picture.
Yeah.
Someone and that's unfortunate.
It was a cool looking car when that
thing came out.
Yeah.
That football player,
Reggie,
what's his name was Reggie Bush.
He bought it.
Oh really?
He bought it off.
The guy that I sold it to thing hasn't
been around.
Yeah.
It's a great looking car that,
that year,
like all those years,
like 70,
71,
those,
those second generation barracudas.
That's a special look and I think a lot
of the hellcat is in that same kind of.
It's pretty close.
It's pretty close,
but I really wish it was the same size.
A hellcat is a hundred and 25 or 130
percent inflated,
overinflated scale version of that.
That's those,
those 70,
71 Kudos are,
are the most valuable muscle cars that
there are today.
Those Hemi ones right at the Hemi.
Kudos are the rarest and most valuable
of the.
Of those they,
they're the ones that only get,
uh,
over over,
over,
like a million usually.
That's incredible.
For car.
That was what?
$30,000
new back in 1970 $5,000.
Was it?
Was it $5,000?
I don't know.
My reverse map doesn't go back that far.
Really?
Let's take a guess.
Let's say I think like five to 6,000
wouldn't be out of the question.
Hemi Cuda.
Alright,
perfect motor.
Let's go with 8,500
8,500
bucks.
Okay.
You go with 8,500?
What did I say?
30,000.
I'm going to read.
Reevaluate.
I think you need to reevaluate.
And four slash 26 Hemi Cuda.
I'm going to play a dirty game.
Prices,
right?
I'm going to go right above it.
Was Jamie coming in with a dollar
fucking assault?
Love winning the show for 2016 for
Twenty six Hemi Cuda.
Which year?
Nineteen 77.
Yeah.
Years.
That's the goodyear.
Well,
the two years of my favorite year of 70
and 71.
Seventy one and the same.
I think 70 one's got four headlights.
Two.
Yeah.
70 also has the smaller grill face,
like the teeth are small in the front,
which is what I had.
I had a 70,
whereas 71 has the full real.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's really more aggressive.
I think 71 might be a little bit better
looking,
to be honest with you.
I can't recall if one year is more
valuable than the other.
Seventy one I think is probably the
best.
Are the results in Jamie window sticker?
Yeah.
Thirty four,
33,
3000.
Four hundred and $33.
Oh my God.
But Dalton with Jamie's $1 when I want
it.
That's.
There it is.
Yeah.
Jamie,
pull up 1971.
Barracuda knows that is a.
that's my.
I think my favorite look and any muscle
cars in 1971.
Barracuda.
That's just like this aggressive
American some.
I mean that is.
That is about as fucking aggressive as a
grill can get.
It's got a mouthful of teeth.
It looks like a Barracuda really does
actually fucking nailed it,
man.
They were better at actually,
I think naming things,
what they looked like back then.
God Damn.
That looks good.
I do still think the corvette stingray
looks sting ray.
I think that's still a little bit.
The works kind of.
That looks like a fucking Barracuda
though.
It does that.
It looks like it's going to get you.
I just found a way for you to spend
another million dollars,
Joe Rogan.
I would never buy one of those.
I don't like.
I'm weird with Shit.
I don't like stock old cars.
What cars they drive,
like garbage.
That'd be why.
Yeah,
I zero interest in them.
You got your vet,
right?
But that's like a modified bob pro
touring chassis and all hundred percent.
Yeah.
And it's got a [inaudible] oh,
so it drives a supercharged.
Yeah.
It tries to have a normal car charger
driven.
The stock one of,
of that year.
No,
it's not good.
You're lucky guy up the street.
He hates me.
He,
uh,
we,
we live in the same block and he's got
an original.
Who's one of those original guys?
He drives around with a paper boy hat on
and drives around the neighborhood lawn
chair at cars and coffee and play
fucking music.
Fuck those people out of his face.
When I told them that it was,
none of it was original except to shell.
I go,
it looks original.
It doesn't have a goddamn thing in it.
The inside,
I guess the shape of the dashboards
original.
Oh,
Kim.
Well,
he's just.
I was like,
look man.
I liked him to drive like a car.
That works good.
Yeah.
Like why is it bad to upgrade the
brakes?
No,
it is not.
You're fine.
But this whole thing that it's somehow
another like doing a disservice to the
vehicle by upgrading the brakes.
These people are assholes.
Was cmps man.
It's an awesome if you're.
If you're going on the lawn at Pebble
Beach,
you keep it original.
Yeah.
Other than that,
I mean especially look you ever.
I mean you,
you love the depths of the Internet.
Look at Los Angeles driving circa 1960
and then Los Angeles driving today.
You know,
the heat,
the traffic on an old car is not meant
to handle that shit.
You want to drive an old car here.
You need to upgrade a few things.
Cooling breaks.
When I find out that a dude just drives
an old car,
I give them an extra level of respect.
You know what he's going through?
He,
Jimmy Smith,
my partner in the UFC now,
uh,
he used to work for Bella tour and now
he works for the UFC.
He drives a 1968 firebird everyday.
Stock Stock,
stock,
seats,
brakes,
everything.
I'm like,
whoa.
Does he know what he's missing?
Have you let him driven drive your
empire the fuck he doesn't give a fuck.
He likes old muscle cars.
He likes in the way they are.
He had a Camaro I think,
and I think his Camaro got hit by some
asshole and totaled it.
So he's like,
all right,
there's another one guys in my hood in
Venice where I live.
There's a lot of old,
old daily drivers for sure,
but I don't know,
I can't do it.
I just don't need that.
In my experience.
You've got to realize that you're not
gonna be able to hit the brakes real
good.
That's not worth it to me.
I like to drive too close to the people
in front of it.
Well,
even if something steps out in the road,
you know.
I mean,
how many times have you been driving in
a deer steps out in front of your conch?
A bunch.
I was driving down the road in a video
that's been viewed about $3,
million times and a guy was dragging a
log on like a 50 foot chain behind a
ford explorer back and forth across the
road.
Oh my God.
What the fuck was it?
The most viewed video on Reddit for 24
hours.
Oh my God.
It was crazy.
Just dragging a log,
like a,
like a log,
like you know,
four feet by two feet.
Giant tree trunk log.
Fucking assholes out there.
You can't have shitty suspension like
woop,
woop member trying to turn one of those
cars.
Literally like a boat.
Oh my God.
But you know,
what else is like,
tires is a big difference too.
Like,
you know,
old Porsche's used to be called widow
makers and shit,
but you take one of those old seventies
turbo Porsche that you know,
there's volumes about how scary they are
to drive and you put them on Michelin
Pilot Super Sport and you're like,
oh you,
you thought 300 horsepower was scary.
That's cute.
Funny.
You were scared of 300 horsepower.
Here's my log video.
Look,
wait,
watch this.
Boom log.
That is so crazy.
That is so god damn crazy.
You sitting there going what?
And I was in a supercharged Lamborghini
Huracan making like 900 horsepower.
Look at that and look at the road.
This guy is just free dragging up.
Fucking that guy.
Just not seem wise,
but I totally,
I,
I choked.
I mean I had an opportunity to,
to throw a zinger there at this person
and instead I just talked to myself and
drove away.
No,
you're better off.
You're not going to fix that guy if he's
so stupid.
He's driving a giant log down a public
road 30.
Look on the other side of the road.
Look at the marks like the log.
Actually,
as I go up,
you can see the mark of dirt like moving
back and forth across the road.
It was easier to see the other way I
guess.
But yeah,
Jesus don't do that.
People.
Yeah,
I mean I guess he couldn't pick it up.
It looked too big.
So I guess I don't see how that's an
appropriate.
So why would he be so convinced that the
log is going to stay attached to the
chain?
I don't know.
How much does he know about logs and
chains,
you know,
and he seemed like an advanced chain
scientists in the specialty of logs.
Fucking assholes out there,
man.
Dragging a log behind a car on a public
road has a big ass log to log,
right?
That chain is not going to hold up.
That law is going to bounce and go
through someone's fucking windshield.
God Damn Man,
they got.
It wasn't mine.
It was borrowed like look,
look how long it is.
It's so crazy and I mean now that we
need to like,
you know,
go back in the video,
but she,
that trail of whatever its leaves on the
road,
they're like that trail.
I had noticed starting like a couple,
like half a mile or so before that on
the road and the trail is going back and
forth across both lanes of traffic and
there was a couple of signs down,
some crazy shit to.
You mean you're making obstacles for
people that are driving,
especially if you're on a motorcycle.
If you're on a motorcycle and you're
coming around,
you're killing,
you're gonna kill somebody.
Yeah,
that's legit.
Like date motorcycles don't want sand on
the road.
Yeah,
they just don't.
And you're putting it on the road 100
percent with that smokers.
I also don't want to get clothes lined
by logs and chains and my buddy a wiping
out on a turn on some sand was one of
the major reasons why I was taking
motorcycle safety classes.
I was trying to get my license and I was
going to get me in a couple of my
friends for fear factor.
We were going to get a,
we're going to get motorcycles,
a couple of guys at work there and then
as things went on,
we were like,
fuck this couple.
They,
they,
two of them went through with it.
Two of US bailed.
Alonzo Boden is all about the bikes,
the bikes,
how many books he broke in.
I don't know how he broke his arm on a
bike a couple years ago.
I bet he did.
Yeah,
he doesn't.
He doesn't seem to,
uh,
think it's a bad risk.
I ride a scooter.
I have a little Yamaha scooter that I
ride around Venice and running errands
and going to my office and stuff like
because I can lane split and it really
makes my life a lot easier.
Oh yeah.
But I'm terrified.
I had a motorcycle and I wrote it in the
canyons maybe four or five times.
I was terrified.
I have no problem pushing a car,
you know,
a little bit in the canyons.
But on a bike like that,
gravel,
it's like,
yeah,
it's really fun.
I get it.
Motorcycle people.
I'm not saying you're wrong.
You're,
you're,
you're braver than me.
Yeah,
I've fruit or I've done,
I've gone through a lot of surgeries,
I know what it's like to rehab from
serious injury and like I am just so not
into that I've,
I mean I've had two back surgeries in
the same,
same spots.
So you've had those disectomy,
how was that?
Did it work for you?
Yeah,
yeah.
First one lasted 11 years and then my
bad decisions led to it being reinjured
and the second surgery was fine.
I'm in the best shape now that I've been
in,
in like 10 years.
So that's what you doing?
I do seven days a week of cardio,
so I built a gym in my house.
I did just seven days a week of cardio.
Yeah,
I got one of those arc trainers.
It's awesome.
Is that like a sort of like an
elliptical?
It's like the hardest elliptical machine
I've ever used and it's.
I do like 45 minutes a day on that.
I use one of those really recently.
It was great.
It's amazing.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's like a hotel with the video that
bad boy.
It's a,
it's like a hotel quality,
so no pounding.
You're getting your cardio in.
Your body's not getting done in 45
minutes.
I'll burn according to the machine.
I don't know how accurate these machine
counters are,
but I'll burn like 850 calories in 45
minutes and then I do three days a week
of weight training for an hour getting
in daily doubles three days a week and I
haven't.
I haven't had a cigarette since October.
Twenty 16.
The ARC trainer.
I have the one with the arms.
Yeah.
Yeah,
guy behind them.
It's get the arms.
It's serious.
Serious workout,
man.
I sweat.
It is a really good workout.
It really is.
So and then I do speed back.
I'll do 12 minutes a day on speed back,
which I like.
I decided to do this.
You could do.
That's what you.
How you hurt your arm?
Yeah.
We're,
we've been talking about tendon issues,
folks whose never had tendon issues and
I never had them until this elbow.
I mean,
I've had it on elbows before,
but I did it smart and I didn't keep
working out this time.
I tried to meet head my way through it.
Yeah.
Again,
uh,
it,
it flared up pretty bad to the point
where I'm four months later it wasn't
healed.
It's a slow healing thing,
right?
We're slowly tendons.
They don't have any blood supply,
so I got a bunch of shit.
Does that,
why the platelet rich plasma works so
well because it just gets it right
there.
It's very effective.
Yeah.
The other thing that's I think the most
effect is what we're talking about is
those therabands and actually it's the
cheapest twisty,
a blue thing that I use.
It looks like a big Avatar Dildo.
And you hold it out in front of you.
I wish I had it with me and then he
twisted like that.
Yeah.
And then I hold it like this and then I
let it on.
Yeah.
So I just got one.
And then you like.
And when you do the untwisting it
strengthens for,
for me,
that was my issue on the inside.
I'm on the outside so I go the other
way.
Yeah,
there would be.
There's another one,
they'll show they have diagrams with
different things you could do,
but it's different,
but it's just those kinds of muscles
don't get strengthened a lot.
My muscles and my hands picking things
up and I'm doing chin ups in rows and
stuff like that.
But I was never doing anything twisty.
So started to add that the amount of
driving I do isn't good for me.
Right.
For your back or my hands are for
anything.
It's flux on my whole body.
Do you put a lumbar pad or anything?
No,
but most cars I drive have like real
sporty,
you know,
seats and
a lot of them I'm lucky enough to have
adjustable lumbar Mercedes right now is
killing the seat game.
Mercedes seed game is so fire.
And what are they doing?
Just they um,
they work with this spinal center in
Germany.
Oh Jesus.
To develop all their high end seats and
the seats on the um,
the s class,
the amg s class is,
are so ridiculous.
Um,
it's like he,
they have it.
Okay.
So they have a simulated hot stone
massage function that works.
It's boss as hell.
It's like a nine zone massage seat in
the s class coupe.
So while you're driving,
it gives you a hot stone massage.
What is the difference between a hot
stone massage and a regular massage?
The air pockets that get inflated,
like you know,
it's,
it's like behind the seat,
the leather.
There's like these pockets of air,
like old reebok pumps,
right?
We're going to pump them up and inflate
and deflate them in sequence to simulate
needing or whatever it is.
Well the Mercedes s class heats those
pockets.
So they're actually the not with hot
air.
The,
there's a thermal thing on the surface.
It's so gangster.
Whoa.
It feels like a hot stone massage.
It's awesome.
Yeah.
They took it to the next level they
have.
And in fact I got the car,
you know,
it's like a $225,000
car and I got it for a week.
I drove it around a road trip.
All this.
I ended up writing 2,600
words on the seat.
The hot stone,
the fit has the fans behind your neck
that blow the hot air because it was a
convertible,
so.
Oh,
you got the convertible.
God Damn,
that's the backseat there.
Jamie.
Look at the.
Go for the front seat because that's
the.
The.
The front seats are just just
delightful.
It is,
but it is amazing that we are in the
zones six zones.
It's amazing that we're in this time
where the technology has gotten to this
level where cars,
they,
they're working so hard to improve upon
what is already ridiculous in terms of
performance.
Yeah,
and have you,
have you experienced any of this semi
autonomous stuff yet?
None.
No,
I haven't.
I'm surprised as intellectually curious.
Interested in cars that drive
themselves.
They can go fuck themselves.
You're not interested in a brief
experience into the world.
I am.
I am,
and she should be Pam,
but for the most brilliant mind cars,
those cars are going to take away our
right to Dr.
Oh,
that's why you should join the human
driving association.
Alex.
this is real.
We're beginning of starting a lobbying
association for the rights of human
drivers.
Will it sounds like a fucking goof right
now,
but it doesn't matter to me.
No,
it doesn't to me.
Yeah.
Because this,
what we don't want to ever have is a
situation where you summon your
autonomous pod and you say,
take me to wherever.
And it goes,
no,
Joe,
you're not going there today because
some political situation.
Yeah.
The government tells you the war on
driving is here.
Pick your side.
Oh my God.
What the fuck is that?
An Rs America on the left there.
I think it's a sign.
I think that is.
It might be an older car by the career.
A whale tail.
Like my nine slash 11.
Yeah.
What years?
Your nine slash 11.
It's an 87.
Were built.
We're doing a safari build.
What does that mean?
Oh,
so you're making it like one of those
offer rally cars.
Car?
Yeah.
It's called,
uh,
the Kenya project.
My friend Lee keen is a reporter racing
driver and he built one for himself and
it is the most glorious thing I've ever
driven.
And it's everything that you love about
a nine slash 11 applies to this.
I'm on loose surface.
There it is.
That's your car.
That's not my car.
My car is going to look like that,
although it will be a different color
and have a roof rack and it'll be,
it'll be slightly,
slightly different.
That seems crazy.
That actually is a Richard Tuttle build
from England.
He's a keen sofar k,
e n and you'll see closer to mine
tuttle's the guy that made a greencard.
Oh,
that's my.
This is my video of driving lease car.
Um,
and uh,
it is.
See,
look,
I was fatter there.
So it's just drifty woods,
oversteer and,
and you know,
the,
that,
that rear engine kind of snapped back
thing that everyone's all afraid of.
Nine slash 11.
The pendulum thing.
Will you get that when you slide and
then it catches and comes back on a
loose surface.
There's no catch a.
So you slide it,
but you don't have the scary snap back.
It just drifts in the gums back drift.
You know,
there's Lee,
he's building the thing that's probably
really good to have a rear engine bias.
It is real,
it is the most controllable.
Delightful.
And you've got four inches of extra
suspension travel.
So La speed bumps,
ruts.
Think about this in Los Angeles.
Right?
So you're going to drive this rally car
around La?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's not a race car.
It's a street car.
Wow.
That's a streetcar.
Yeah.
And then,
you know,
that looks like so much fun trying to
get in the dirt.
Oh my God.
We have so much desert here.
No one cares.
You got to have Mirage.
There's trails like there's no speed
limits.
Nobody gives a shit.
I got to be honest.
There's two videos that made me get
really interested in older porsches.
One of them was the Chris Harris build
with the tuttle and another one was you
driving that project?
Nasty cough.
Joey seely.
He's a local as well.
That car.
I was like,
oh,
that's it.
Yeah,
Just like get it down to the raw dog.
Yeah.
He took everything out of that car.
And Richard Tuttle,
who did Chris's car in England is like
the rally,
you know,
master.
He's like,
uh,
there's,
there's a project nasty.
And there's joey who built it.
And he also,
I love the little things,
he did make the exhaust come through the
rear bumper and those funky wheels on it
and the fact there's no carpeting and
all,
like everything inside was stripped
away.
His instagram,
his emotion engineering and that car has
been through a few changes since this
video has made.
It looks a little different now that he
changed the wheels.
Right?
Different wheels,
different like stairs,
a bunch of different stuff,
but it's amazing.
And that guy,
um,
he used to be a part of this business.
BBI autosport.
He left to go start his own business,
emotion engineering.
And he is a master of chassis setup.
Yeah,
I believe it.
Yeah.
That's a very,
very impressive video.
It's a very interesting video.
And that's not like the highest
horsepower vehicle,
right?
No,
it was really light though.
It was I think how many horsepower did
have,
I don't remember.
Maybe three.
Seventy five.
Three 80.
I mean it was,
it was fast.
It was not a slouch at all,
but you know,
have you seen what singer is doing now
with this air cooled engine?
It's crazy what you sent me.
That whole thing of the price difference
between a nine slash 11 engine air
cooled engine that's got 200 horsepower
versus one's got $500 and be like,
wow.
Yeah,
the exponential curve of Porsche
horsepower costs.
So it's really scary stuff.
Stan was $250,000.
Yeah,
so it was like,
okay,
if you buy an engine,
an engine on a stand,
you want that engine.
This is a porsche air cooled,
so a porsche engine for a porsche that
is earlier than 1995.
I'm 300 horsepower is gonna run you
about 40 grand and that's a ton of money
for not a lot of horsepower.
400 horsepower will run you about 100
grand.
I mean 100,000.
That's an engine on a stand.
Nothing else.
You want 500 horsepower out of that
motor seawater and $50,000
just for the end.
Just for the edge.
Why is that?
Because that sounds so crazy in
comparison to other cars because a lot
of techniques that you would use to make
horsepower and other cars you cannot
apply to a porsche engine.
You're limited on displacement size,
so it's not like you could shove like a
nine Liter v eight in there,
like a four point two is about as big
displacement as you can get in that
case.
And that's with like a stroker crank and
board out.
So you're increasing both the length,
the Pistons move and the size of the
whole,
um,
to get to the 500 horsepower mark,
you have to run some highly experimental
cylinder heads and singer to do that.
I don't know if Chris has been on the
show recently,
but he's working with singer to develop.
Um,
there's a company called Williams that
has a formula one team.
They are developing the cylinder heads
for singer.
So Chris Harrison is a part of this.
He's doing development driving for them.
That's great.
Which is a good decision.
That's amazing decision.
Plus the videos will be epic,
right?
So most of a,
they're doing a four valve air cooled
head,
which as far as I know has never been
done before.
All your,
your engine,
my engine,
all the are our two valve engines and,
and they're doing a four valve engine.
So,
um,
it's going to cost a million and a half
dollars.
Well the engine is 250 grand.
This is why it's so crazy.
Custom cars or a million dollars.
Now.
Isn't that nuts?
I mean you really want,
if you really want something next level,
it can easily be.
Emily knows Jamie,
pull up that new singer,
nine slash 11 singer nine slash 11.
And the Williams Williams engine.
It's green,
but it's got a lot of that.
Um,
what is,
who's the Japanese gentleman who takes
those porsches and our web?
Yeah,
it's got a lot of that to it.
Well,
alright,
so our web is really interesting because
in Japan there's the singer,
don't you think that's a God damn
gorgeous car?
Don't you think it's an odd choice to
artificially different.
Stop please.
Sexy.
That artificially differentiate like the
way he's got the fender flares,
he's just,
he's making him like he had a glue them
on carbon fiber.
The whole car is carbon fiber.
Why did,
why did they fake like they had like
extensions.
Okay.
So I don't want to disappoint you,
but that is a rendering and not a
picture of an actual car.
Far as I know he actual car does not
exist and I think if I had to guess they
put those over fender lines on the
rendering.
So you would specifically notice that
they have widened it a.
That standard would be if I had to guess
the final car may not actually have a
seam there.
You know what man?
I'm not.
I'm not mad if it does.
It looks amazing.
Champion.
Can you make that bigger again?
It's so real.
That's crazy that that's not a
photograph like a render.
Almost certain.
That's not a real car.
I'm almost certain it's not a real car.
Hire little.
I could be wrong.
There could.
There could be someone's screaming at
their whatever right now saying I'm
wrong,
but I'm pretty sure reflections in the
window in the last three years.
They're good at this dude.
Well,
I play a video game.
I absolutely believe it.
I'm not arguing against it.
I'm just saying it's so good.
Yeah,
but anyway,
if they'd make a car like that,
Holy Shit.
That's a gorgeous car.
Oh yeah.
And they will and it'll look like that,
but it may not have those seams.
It's pretty similar to what their car
looks like wider.
Much different than the wider.
I saw one of those that might've been
the best looking car I've ever seen in
my life.
It was a silver,
like a metallic silver,
like a bright silver singer,
and it was online understated.
It's like Lori's damn.
See if you find that bright silver,
a silver singer.
Have you seen one in person before?
A close dude,
your mind would be blown.
They have at a minimum,
minimum 45 or $50,000
of leather in one of those cars and the
interior,
the leather work in the interior of
those cars is unbelievable.
Beyond anything from any manufacturer
today.
Really?
Uh,
yeah.
That's it.
That's a sexy motherfucker.
Damn.
That's a good looking car.
Yup.
That's very,
very nice.
What is it about certain shapes,
right?
There's certain.
What singer does is they distill,
you know,
the best of each generation of car into
one car.
And so you're looking at a highly
idealized nine slash 11,
but you can't exactly picture what came
from where and why.
Yeah,
it's gangster.
And those folks,
those wheels,
for whatever reason,
they just work like,
especially that green car that we go
back to that green card,
they made them all they made.
I'm real big on the green card,
but the design works so well.
There's the Williams engine.
God Damn it looks good.
Yeah,
that's perfect.
So scroll down Jamie the Williams.
Look at this.
So,
so you see,
look at the air intakes.
That's where your rear windows would be.
So there are no rear windows,
there are only those air intakes that go
directly into the engine.
Cool.
That furnace off.
That's.
No,
not cooling.
That's the actual air intake to get the
end of the combustion chamber.
Okay.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
The cooling,
it's air cooled,
so you see that silver kind of nipple on
the right side there.
That's the center of the fan.
It gets cooled in from the back.
They're like this is basically the same
size as a regular inline six flats.
Yeah.
Roughly that the engine itself is
roughly the same size.
Yeah.
So what they've done is just engineer it
to the Max.
Oh yeah.
Well they have the.
They have what are inferior,
the most advanced cylinder heads ever
put onto an air cooled 9:11.
It looks incredible and they're going to
stick that in a car.
That was originally what?
Ninety three,
something like that.
Yeah,
91 to 94.
Isn't it funny though that there's
something unbelievably appealing about
those air cooled cars that is willing to
have these rich people pay a million
dollars or at least the current singers?
A half million dollars from this car
just because you feel it more when you
drive it.
It's just got a feel to it.
There's a certain kind of mechanical
brilliance to it that's really,
really.
You can't.
It's in comparable.
Really.
It's very unique.
Yeah.
Well,
there's something about those old cars,
particularly the ones that don't have
power steering.
You get a thrill out of them.
There's a weird thrill even when you're
not even driving fast,
especially with a porsche when you.
When you have no power steering combined
with front engine car,
it sucks when no power steering,
when the engine's in the back is okay
because the front of the car is pretty.
Is Pretty light so you don't need too
much muscle,
but the nine slash 11 steering is just
super,
super direct.
Yeah.
It's super direct and it's just.
I don't know,
man.
It just.
It just feels like a different thing
you're doing.
I had a buddy that had a a folks wagon
bug growing up,
didn't have a lot of power in it,
but those Volkswagen bugs,
those fucking things like when you drive
them around,
they give you a little smile on your
face because you're driving like
this little tiny thing that feels
completely connected with the road.
Very capable,
but it's like you're smiling when you
drive one of those.
It's the ultimate Volkswagen is they're
taking in Germany,
they take the buses,
the micro buses,
and they and they chop them down so
they're compressed and they put full
porsche floor pan drive,
train,
and so remember that nine,
nine,
six turbo.
You had the all wheel drive,
so they'll put that whole floor pan on a
microbus and they'll go to like track
days and beat up on race cars.
It's crazy.
They're look seriously.
Look,
here's,
here's one that is so crazy.
Five hundred and 30 horsepower portion
nine,
three by turbo powered Volkswagen
microbus.
Same.
Look in the rear window.
See the intake on the rear window there.
That's so crazy.
And that's on a racetrack.
Oh my God.
And it probably weighs nothing,
right?
Nothing.
And I mean,
look what happens.
God forbid you crash one of those.
Oh Wow.
There's crazy people taking a vw bugs
and put Porsche engines in them.
I know they've been doing that.
Yeah.
Well the common one is a suit.
Oh,
the old 3:56
engines award.
No,
no,
no.
I think someone was putting an older
nine slash 11 engine in it,
or a nine slash nine slash 12,
nine slash 12 engine.
Nine twelves are people are paying way
too much money for them.
Stop it.
Yeah.
They're like like 30,
$40,000.
Really?
They're so slow.
Yeah.
That's a slow ass.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You need to have like I get that.
It's about feel and yet nine slash nine
slash 12 slash five field,
but at a certain point there has to be
some pace associated him know when they
made those cars it was the same shell on
the outside.
Is it nine slash 11?
Yeah.
They just like d contented it cheap and
everything and then put it interesting.
That old engine,
if somebody wanted a hot rod or nine
slash 12 out and like put a crazy nine,
nine three engine in it and to all the
suspension,
it would still be a nine.
12.
Isn't that weird?
There's people that convert nine twelves
into nine slash 11 all the time.
Yeah.
But people know.
Care.
No,
but that's what's so crazy about it is
that you're essentially.
It's the same good stuff is the nine
slash 11,
what it looks like on the outside,
but do the numbers match.
That's the thing,
but the difference with Porsche people,
I mean the difference between $40,000
and $400,000
will be the most minute insignificant
bullshit of this one was delivered with,
you know,
leather covered vents and a leather
covered fusebox and a fucking Fuchsia
steering wheel and it had the
lightweight glass.
So that one's 400 grand in that one's
40.
I mean that's really what it is.
That's the only muscle cars.
Same thing.
This was one of four delivered and plum
crazy and automatic transmission on a
Tuesday with a white roof and a cum
stain in the back feet
from the factory.
I'd love those auctions where you see
pitch to greed and people's eyes just go
in off.
The funny thing is when they people like
will,
they'll get in a bidding war and overpay
for something by 40 grand and still feel
like they want.
They feel like they score.
I'll give her lungs that motherfucker
didn't get it.
I went to Barrett,
Jackson for the first time ever this
year.
I had to see it in person.
It's a shit show.
It's an,
it's an absolute shit show.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's crazy.
And you know,
it's in Scottsdale and,
and,
but a Barrett,
Jackson itself,
what they don't show you on TV is that
you can buy anything.
They're like,
you can buy fat.
They had a,
uh,
a jet turbine powered fan boats.
Whoa.
That you could buy like it's,
it's like the auction and I'm going
under and then like a mile of swap Midi
Shit.
And you could buy custom made cowboy
boots and tempurpedic beds and you know,
home furnishings and terrible art and
watches.
And it was a massage chairs.
Anything you can think of.
Whoa.
It was,
it was just such a,
like Sea of commerce dam and uh,
there's like a lot of cars that don't
make tv that are either amazing or very,
very sad and in their own way.
Do you have to do to get in there?
Do you have to there like a quotation
thing to just walk in?
No,
to set a car in there.
Oh,
you just,
you on their website and apply to sell a
car.
I think.
I don't think there's any.
I think are happy to take your money and
try and sell your car.
I don't think there's any restriction
guy like Eric Andre from going there I
would like.
And just pinto.
I don't.
I mean,
I don't know.
I don't think anything other than
someone figuring out the joke before he
did it,
but I don't think much.
I think you could probably do it,
but for the most part it's people that
are pretty serious about cars.
It was a lot of dealers.
There was a lot more dealers that seemed
like they were selling to each other in
terms of the actual buying and the
selling.
But yeah,
I mean there's a lot of nascar jackets
out there,
lot of nascar jackets,
and then you see the,
they have some of the higher end options
to which sort of resemble the pebble
beach ones.
Do you still have that crazy corvette?
Sold it.
Oh,
I have a crazy mustang now.
What'd you get?
Oh,
that one?
Yeah.
It's on the cover of carcraft this month
and it's in speed hunters as well.
It did a great article in it and speed.
Hunter's dad is a ridiculous car.
It's awesome to her rutledge on your
show and you guys were on Fox bodies.
You were him called it like the worst
piece of shit ever.
Fuck you.
Why did you decide to soup up that car?
Because car what I wanted in high
school,
but like it's my highest.
It's the high school,
the high school reliving car.
Oh Wow.
We'll over the top.
Imagine pulling up to high school with
that thing.
She'd go back in a time machine,
bro.
I went to my actual 10 year high school
reunion in a orange Lamborghini as a
goof and there was literally not a
single soul outside when I parked it up
upfront,
zero people's arrival.
It couldn't have been more that shit.
Isn't that funny?
Like that's what you want a car like
that.
It's like 80 percent of rival.
Yeah.
A hundred percent right?
One hundred percent up and getting out.
If they see the Lamborghini,
there's my mustang and you see the
Lamborghini on the way out of the
reunion.
It's really lame.
It just was not the best looking year.
No.
Look,
I have the notch back and the notch
stack is better.
Mine was a police car.
Was it?
Yeah,
it was a highway patrol car.
Wow.
See that's the notch back there.
And uh,
it was cheaper to get those.
I remember you can get the five point.
Oh,
engine.
And the point of that is the police cars
were the lightest ones.
So no air conditioning,
no sunroof,
no fog lights,
no power windows.
Power door locks.
So that was the Lightest v eight powered
Mustang ever made.
Look at my interior.
I love crazy fabrics so much.
That interiors,
bad ass Cholo.
Fantastic.
I actually like it.
I thought it would hate that.
Now it's like a seventies.
Outdoor patio furniture.
Keep that image back up there.
I liked the um,
we're getting joe and interior today.
I can never go like that,
but just leave that there.
Like the gauges,
man.
Everything you did there.
Porsche style steering wheel.
I love that.
I love the shifters at hearst.
Yeah,
her shifter.
And then the center tray in between the
recaro seats is from a 73 Mercedes to
80.
And then,
uh,
the pattern came from a modern fabrics
and it's like an outdoor patio furniture
fabric.
So it's uv resistant and spill
resistant.
What do those wheels Jamie Click on
those wheels and the righthand side.
What?
Where the wheels.
The wheels?
I have a,
it's called the hre rs one.
Oh.
Which is a three piece forged wheel.
Uh,
and I'm running to 95 tires at all four
corners.
So there are 18 by 10 and a half at all.
Four corners.
They're awesome.
We must handle amazing.
Oh,
it's sticks.
So it sticks like a gt three.
It turns in so hard and I'm running the
tires or sport cup tubes which are like
the gt three tires.
And what is this car way you think?
Thirty one.
10.
Well,
so it's pretty good.
It's got really good breaks,
really good handling.
It's medium fast.
It's about 350 horsepower.
So it gets quick enough.
You're going to leave the engine the way
it is?
Well,
it has a crate motor in it,
right,
which it could use some more,
could use a little more and so if I keep
the car long term,
I'm going to take out that engine and
put in the Gt 3:50
if I keep the car long term.
How many horsepower is the GT?
Three.
Five,
25.
But it revs to 8,200.
That's what it's really about.
You know,
I heard one of those in a video.
That's a great insight.
Doesn't sound anything like a Mustang.
It
doesn't,
it sounds like a something,
uh,
more Italian.
Yeah.
Most.
I was going to sound like a Ferrari or.
Well they do a different firing order
and they also,
I think it's,
someone's going to hurry me if that's
wrong,
but the flat plain crank changes the
sound gt 3:50
exhaust,
2018 gt 3:50.
It's pretty glorious.
Yeah.
Well I'm terrified that they're going to
come out with that gt 500 and I'm going
to fall in love.
It could happen.
It has a very uh,
yeah,
yeah.
That sounds amazing.
Nope,
I think you have one of my videos open
in the background,
Jamie,
because I'm hearing double God dammit
Jamie Lists.
But look at that.
Oh,
that sounds so good.
It's not,
it's a very unlike anything else on the
road.
Very distinctive.
So that's uh,
that's,
that's uh,
one of the most special engines.
Thirty 700 pounds.
They're all heavy.
Why can anybody figure that out?
Because people.
Lighter people want features,
right?
Everybody though some people don't want
that.
That's why people like you and I are so
fascinated by something like singer.
I'm like,
you don't want to spend that kind of
money.
You can't have light and cheap and fast.
You gotta you gotTa pick one.
If you want light and sheep,
you,
it's your Miata.
You know,
you can't have a.
If they're,
if they had a 3000 pound Mustang that
had the features that people demand from
a modern car,
it would be $200,000.
You'd,
you'd have a Ferrari,
you know?
Yeah.
But even for ours aren't that light
anymore.
That's true.
Nothing is like,
well,
what is the lightest thing you could
buy?
Like a Porsche boxster.
There's a lotus.
Lotus for 10 is under 3000 pounds I
think,
which is really,
really,
really nice car.
I drove that little one to little
league.
Yeah,
trove that a few years back.
Yeah.
So you've already beat you up like that.
Does it didn't have any horsepower
though?
It was the other one?
No,
not the core of the.
Exceeds the really the one where it
doesn't have any floor panels.
He doesn't have anything.
I was like,
this is kind of interesting because it's
like a little go cart.
It doesn't load us this thing.
Yeah.
So that's what I drove.
That's the evora sport for 10.
I just drove that and it's really,
really good.
Yeah.
Really Nice.
And that's also a manual transmission?
It is,
yeah.
It's a super charged camry engine,
believe it or not.
Really?
Yeah.
How many horsepower?
Four hundred and 10.
Supercharged carries.
Beautiful car.
It's really good looking and it stopped
that thing.
It's got a titanium exhaust.
God,
that's so unique.
You know,
in a sea of nine slash 11,
it does stand out.
Why you would like that car.
I think that that would be a good one
for you.
Like you need another one.
That's a
pretty cartoon,
but that's the other one.
That's the least.
Yeah.
The elise is the one that I drove that
gray one that you just clicked on.
Jamie.
I drove that.
That's a beautiful looking car,
but it's got no balls.
No,
but you can stun those.
Like this is crazy how slow the is.
They made some.
You might have driven the smaller engine
when they made some that were a little
faster.
Yeah.
The base one was like 180 horsepower and
then they go up to,
to 60 or to 80.
But there's something thrilling about
it.
Like driving a flea.
Yeah.
So how much does that thing way think?
Twenty 500 or something.
It's like,
yeah,
it's nothing and it's beautiful.
They just make beautiful cars.
Those lotuses are that.
They will be $30,000
used cars until the end of time.
The Elise?
Yeah,
absolutely.
Bottomed out at 30 grand and you can buy
them and sell them at 30 grand all day.
Isn't it funny how cars were worth
almost nothing and then like a 73 Rs
America.
It wasn't.
It wasn't an rs America just at Rs.
Three RS is worth like a million dollars
now.
It used to be worth $20,000
just a few years ago.
Like how did that happen?
I remember I saw those for sale and
someone saying this is the perfect
Porsche.
It's not the most powerful.
It's only like 225 horsepower,
something like that,
but it's so light and so fun to drive.
And I was like,
get the fuck out of here with 225
horsepower.
Well,
it's like you know,
the world,
the world has become more automated,
right?
Everything is faster,
more efficient,
but less involved and less mechanical.
And at the same time you've got a,
especially with Porsche,
a younger audience,
a very wealthy audience,
you know that as has really decided to
use the older collector cars is a
currency that you can drive and
investments and just a lot of rich
people out there right now.
And they're not making any more.
Nineteen 73,
nine slash 11.
Yeah.
That's one of the things that people
have a real problem with,
singer is they're taking those cars and
chopping them the fuck up.
I'd taken a nine,
six,
four and just chopping the shit out of
that.
Taking 100,000
dollar car and turning it into a
$500,000
that if you can get on the list and get
one and you take it home,
it's immediately worth $700 on the open
market.
I bet.
Right?
Because people don't want to wait.
Flipper market for a singer.
It's like name your price.
Name your price.
If you wanted to get a singer,
made it.
How many years is even his waiting list?
Two years.
Three years.
So two years.
Three years for waiting list than a year
to make the car and they're making it by
hand with carbon fiber.
It's crazy.
I've seen the videos of people visiting
the factory,
putting together here.
You should go.
I should go,
but I'm scared.
I'll introduce you to it.
I'll do it.
I'll start doing numbers in my head.
It's just all this.
I mean and there's.
And then there's a whole cut singer,
I think.
Not to dwell on singer so much,
but they opened the door for a,
a sub industry them that's
doing $200,000,
you know,
builds that are like halfway to singer
for most people.
That's probably like,
yeah,
that's cool.
That's really fucking excessive.
Most people I bought,
you know I'm doing this safari thing,
but I bought my 87 Carrera and its stock
and I almost didn't want to start
modifying it because it was just such a
nice thing to drive around.
It was just lovely.
Well that's recent enough where they
have like good breaks.
Yeah.
And it's a super light car.
Eighties is good.
I mean,
I think that the,
what's great,
there's a,
a series of shows now called Redwood.
Yeah,
it's a car show for eighties and
nineties cars.
A fucking great dude.
It's great because these are cars you
can drive,
you know,
they have air conditioning,
they have reasonably,
you know,
modern,
whatever.
You could just start them up and drive
him and do it.
It's like old eighties benzes and,
and just just as great,
great scene of eighties and nineties
cars at Rad when they've got a bunch of
shows around come out and say hi.
I met a bunch of them.
But um,
you know,
people like my age,
I'm 36,
are seeing these cars as collectible now
and it's going to usher in a new market
to.
There's a lot of good investments to be
made.
An eighties and nineties cars.
Yeah.
You know what I would say.
That's crazy.
These are good looking cars,
dude.
There's like,
this is like an 86 Acura Acura legend
that looks mint.
A buddy of mine had a,
an Acura legend just like that.
He loved that thing.
An 87,
87 legend.
That's a great car.
One car that I had that I wish I didn't
get rid of.
Prelude.
It's so clean.
I had the last year.
The NSX.
Oh really?
The.
Yeah,
with the headlights.
The headlights.
You shouldn't have gotten rid of it.
Got Rid of a big dollar car right now.
It's hot.
I don't have it.
I loved it too.
That was a light ass car.
I don't know what those things weighed.
Twenty eight,
28.
I'll tell you what,
if you like that car,
that Lotus for 10 I just showed you.
You would love that.
That is the new version of that car.
Really?
Yup.
I don't know if I want the new version
though.
I don't think I like the old version.
That's the thing.
No,
no,
no.
The new version feels like the old
version of it with like Bluetooth,
Bluetooth and your base,
etc.
It is.
Fuck.
That was a great car.
So lIght.
They're very durable.
You can drive them.
Yeah.
People who are hot and mean.
How did they figure it out?
so much better than the americans did
when it came to reliability?
Well,
they just built a light car and then put
their accord engine in it.
Pretty much.
Yeah,
but I mean all oF their cars.
Oh,
did you go through across the board,
like we were talking earlier about land
cruisers.
That's like god would be one of the most
reliable cars.
The history of the free world.
Like why the fuck are they so good at
that?
And most companies like american
companies during that same age,
like you get a 19 nineties ford.
No,
I know.
It's terrible.
That's terrible
running,
right?
Yeah,
I know.
But 1995 land cruiser driving through
africa right now.
Land cruiSers are specific or an
interesting example specifically because
I went on the press launch for land
cruiser,
so I know this.
Most cars are built to a 10 year service
life.
The land cruiser is built to a 25 year
service life.
The land cruisers parts are almost 100
percent unique to land cruiser.
They,
they share very few parts with anything
else in toyota's lineup and that's why
you look at.
You go,
oh,
iT's a full size suv.
Why is this thing $90,000?
Because everything on it is industrial
grade shit designed to last twice as
long as like any other car.
Yeah,
it seems like when you drive a one,
two tanks,
absolute absolute texts and there are
over engineered,
but I think in the,
in the eighties and nineties,
I think the japanese design and
production philosophy was just so far
beyond where we were.
Yeah.
We were making shit during those years.
Absolutely.
I mean I have an 88 mustang you just
saw.
I have an 87 porsche and I had a 1998
nissan skyline gtr,
the marsha and the fucking skyline.
Our same time,
save time period.
They're spaceships compared to the hunk
of shit that is my mustang.
I mean those guidelines are bad ass.
Awesome.
Skyline.
Yeah.
I sold it,
but I doubled up in six months though
there.
Think about what they did with the gtr
when they came in.
When nissan came out with the gtr,
the new,
the new interest.
Onewest one.
Dude,
I've only driven one of those twice,
but one time when I drove one though,
the most remarkable thing about it was I
was taking a turn to to hit an off ramp
and I was like a little late.
I was like,
oh,
that's the law.
I got to change lanes and it just went
like this,
cross the lanes,
zip you up,
like nothing.
No lien.
There was nothing just defied physics.
I was like,
this thing is crazy.
It's just,
it's calculating how much mass is
leaning this way and adjusting to
flatten everything out electronically.
So actually the new acura nsx,
that's like the supercar you one second,
150 grand does that same thing that the
gtr did and oh nine,
but it does it much more seamlessly.
So You think you did it really that
awesome driving that just happened in
the gtr.
You're like,
wow,
the gtr is doing all this awesome shit
in the nsx.
You're like,
I'm a fucking hero because you can't
because it's so.
It's so seamless.
Like the gtr,
it's a mechanical,
you know,
all wheel drive system with these clutch
packs and whatever.
So you can hear it like clunk,
clunk,
clunking around and like moving power
and doing all this shit,
right?
The nsx is rear wheel drive gas engine
and then electric motors in the front
wheel.
So it can do all kinds of funkY shit
with the front wheels.
The two wheels can be going completely
different speeds from each other.
It's comPletely independent of what's
happening at the back.
It's all this computer algorithms,
but it's magic front end,
front end that cannot happen within the
constraints of like normal rotational
physics.
Whoa dude,
you should work for an acura.
I should sell cars.
You got my dick hard for an nsx.
It's a good buy right now.
People don't want them to achieve.
I don't know because they're not like
the old one.
Like you said,
you want tHe old one and people wanted
to stick and simple and it's complicated
and.
But if people were looking for a double
clutch supercar that seems to be a
really good bargain.
It's a great looking car.
It is.
I had one weekend was awesome,
awesome.
And apparently the,
the power of seems very accessible,
right?
Sorry,
I'm thirsty.
It's,
um,
it's very forgiving and very easy to
drive and it makes you feel like mario
andretti,
hope they don't not make them anymore.
They've got to make them for a bit.
They've committed,
but I think uh,
you should buy one if you think you
might like on a tinge of responsibility
when the viper went out of business and
I never bought a viper because there's
so imposturous it's such a preposterous.
Like I thought about getting one of
those acrs with the wings vented hoods
and looked down like just for just
because it's such a douchebag car.
Yeah.
So if you were to list off like the
check boxes of things that you
personally enjoy,
it seems like it does actually tick most
of those boxes in there.
Totally looking like a penis.
Besides that,
it really takes the rest of the box.
It looks like godzilla is dick.
It looks like this sort of like super
autumn of it's very shredder,
but it's so american too.
It's such a ridiculous thing to build.
Well it's american.
What's so american about it is that
rather than,
you know,
porsche developing this insane gearbox,
that can shift in a microsecond and,
and nissan doing this crazy fucking all
wheel drive system and you know,
whoever accurate doing their torque
vectoring,
electric motors,
fibers,
just like more downforce,
you know,
we don't know manual gearbox,
just.
Yeah,
just more downforce.
Develop the stickiest tire.
You can find here.
You can pop these things out and get
even more downforce.
And that's the.
That's like the whole thing.
Yeah.
Swings just put wings on it and that'll
be fine,
but meanwhile they brought it to every
race track and they were tracked here.
Breaking records.
Yeah.
It's crazy.
It's the most american thing ever just
bought a bigger gun.
Exactly.
The biggest 50 caliber machine gun ever.
Desert eagle.
It's America.
It's big ole american dick.
It's super America.
Yeah.
But then they stopped making them.
I'm sad because merca isn't necessarily
commercially viable.
Sometimes a come on the age of trump
that they can bring it back,
bring it back.
Vipers for everybody.
Every coal miner gets a viper,
a job in a viper for every coal miner.
Right.
It's the most preposterous car.
Would you agree?
Oh,
well,
we have Some preposterous vehicles here
in America.
I mean,
the fact that you can get a,
a pickup truck version of an escalate,
it's pretty funny,
you know,
do that still.
I think they may have stopped.
I think I may have stepped on my own
job,
but um,
let's see.
Preposterous.
It's up there.
It's pretty awesome.
Yeah.
The ford gt is pretty preposterous in a
very,
in a very good way.
that's a superchArge supercar though.
It's extremely super.
And that's.
is that.
Is john [inaudible] in trouble for
selling his?
Don't think so.
I don't think the contract is
enforceable.
You don't think so?
I,
I'm just going by what I've read on.
Tell people what the story is.
So to get one of the new ford gts,
right?
It's what's called a homologation race
car.
Okay.
So they wanted to go when the 24 hours
of lamar in a certain class that the lmg
t class in order to race in that class,
it has to be a street car.
Right.
So you have to build a certain number of
streetcars.
you can't just build a dedicated race
car that would be called the prototype
class.
Okay.
So they had to build,
I think the number is 499.
It's 400 and something for 54,
99,
whatever it is for decides that the
demand will outstrip the supply and
there rather than,
you know,
highest bittering or whatever they make
you like apply.
So you,
you have to be a social media star or a
celebrity or someone you had to like
tell them why you should have a ford gt
and what you were going to do with it
and how you were going to share your
four gt with the world.
And then they would decide that you had
earned the right to buy their $450,000
car.
And it came with a contract that you
couldn't sell it for two years.
They didn't want people flipping them
right,
which apparently is exactly what sean's
seen when it did seem to be so fucking
rich.
Like why would,
why would he violate the contract for a
couple of hundred?
Huge.
Really huge,
very huge person or miss.
HoW huge is he?
Well,
he's just enormous.
Like with.
I bet he's probably only like six,
three or six.
Four,
six,
four.
He can't fit in it.
So if he can't fit in it,
that's probably why he would get rid of
it rather than tall mr.
Scene is,
but when my head hit the ceiling,
that's probably exactly what he's
probably six to at least.
He seems like a guy who should be even
longer and taller than he is because
he's so thick.
It's almost like they chopped off a foot
of his arms and every place bought a
giant,
but his risks are like fucking tree
trunks.
Hilarious.
Six foot 2:50.
Yeah.
See he probably be close.
It'd be close.
Six foot two or six foot.
Six foot 250 pounds.
Oh,
he's short of thought.
Well,
I don't know why he sold it,
but he did.
Maybe even for him,
if it's two inches for you,
maybe felt squashed in there.
Look,
I drove it for one day.
I don't know what it,
what kind of sacrifices to buy it,
but I think he fuck like me.
Might be a good car for you.
Good for you.
So the seed is fixed and the pedals and
steering wheel are adjustable.
You can adjust the seat.
How bizarre.
Yeah.
The pedals come to you.
I don't think I like that.
That's what you gotta do,
man.
It's what you have to do because the
color,
the shape of the car dictates the
seatback angles a bit.
Can you just make this seat slide?
Put the seat on a seat?
No,
you can't.
The car is so low.
You do see a seat.
Rail is like inches.
Precious.
Precious inches.
The roof is 43 inches from the ground.
that's like this.
Whoa.
It's so low.
It's that low.
It's 43 inches from the roof to roof
cleaning ground.
Yeah.
Compared to all the car at one law by
the way in the year was supposed to.
Wow.
You park it next to a nine slash 11 and
nine slash 11 is like six inches taller
than one of these things.
Well that makes a really big difference
in the 24 hours of le ma,
you're talking 200 mile an hour straight
away.
Speeds.
Like that's a huge difference.
So they've designed the car without seat
rails to get everything even further
down.
You know,
it's a dope looking car.
I saw one that was black with red
stripe.
That was the press car was driving
around,
has got the same color to god.
That's a pretty car.
it's gangster.
That's a Pretty car.
Carbon fiber wheels,
which are lovely.
Um,
carbon fiber wheels.
So there's two kinds of weight in a car.
There's sprung weight and unsprung
weight.
What's happening?
So sprung weight is weight.
That is most of what you think of as the
car,
the engine,
the body.
AnYthing that has sprung on the
suspension,
unsprung weight,
his weight on the car that is not sprung
on the suspension.
So wheels,
brake,
rotors,
tires,
suspension components that aren't
sItting on the suspension.
Right?
So it's like a rough calculation,
but like roughly one pound of unsprung
weight will translate the feeling of
five pounds of tongue weight.
So meaning like if you are able to pull
20 pounds of unsprung weight out of your
car,
each wheel is four pounds or five pounds
lighter than a stock.
We'll.
Okay.
So you're not about 20 pounds unsprung
weight to your car.
YOur car will feel like you pulled 100
pounds out of it and it will stop,
start,
accelerate,
turn better commute.
Uh,
a totally in all our,
it'll perform better in all areas.
So to go from a forged aluminum wheel,
which is 23 or 24 or 25 pounds a wheel
to a carbon fiber wheel,
that's like 11 pounds a wheel,
you,
you're pulling so much unsprung weight
out of the car,
it'll feel like,
you know,
swinging a baseball bat with a weight on
it and then just throw in that weight
away.
Wow.
Yeah.
Massive,
massive,
massive difference.
And the wheels are so expense,
I would imagine like how many companies
make carbon fiber wheel one wine called
carbon revolution and they're from
Australia and those are the only make
them for the four days.
You can buy the wheels.
They have fitments for a few different
cars.
Porsche gt three is one and they make
them for ford.
Will you do me a favor jamie and pull up
the photo of that black ford gt with the
red stripes?
It's on my instagram.
If you have my instagram handy,
the one I drove up,
I'm incredibly.
The road presence is just seen and it
makes noises that only god damn it makes
noises that only race cars make.
There's a specific sound like you know
the pops and crackles you get from most
of these modern cars and they dumped the
fuel in the exhaust and shit and it's
cool.
But it's a synthetic eee sound.
It's programmed right?
This does that.
Not programmed.
It's just like fuel into header.
Bang.
It's just.
Sorry.
Scars.
And this goes for like $500,000
for 50.
If you can get one but you can't get
what you can't get unless you know
johnson and then the route.
I mean the rumor is he got like over a
million for his butt.
Oh,
so somebody ordered off.
Well that makes sense.
Flipped it and flipped it.
And so they're suing him.
Yeah,
I,
I read that it was thrown out.
They sued them for breach of contract,
for selling it,
but he,
he claims or claimed that the contract
didn't say he couldn't sell it.
Oh.
So it was a verbal agreement or
something?
I don't know.
Maybe it was one of those things they
just hoped nobody would call him out on
and maybe it's unenforceable.
You know what I mean?
How,
how do they sell you something and then
enforced that you can't sell the thing
you bought.
You can't do that.
You really,
you literally can't do that.
I don't think that's enforceable.
I think once the contract is signed in
and you take possession of this object,
that's yours to do whatever you want,
I think it's morally.
I compare american moTherfucker,
but for fucking hats off.
You made a dope ass car.
That thing's amazing.
It's extremely,
extremely crazy.
it really in it,
it's,
it's unlike anythinG else on the road
because even even the,
um,
the very,
very high end super cars,
you know,
your lamborghini aventador is that are
400 grand and you're v12 ferrari's and
all that stuff are fundamentally they're
road cars and even when you,
they go racing with them,
they sort of take the road car and
modify it for racing.
This is so clearly a race car that they
had to build some street cars,
you know,
and I'm fucking rocking.
It looks amazing.
It's got an air brake on him.
The active.
So the go back to the rear picture.
Yeah.
So the wing,
the whole wing that,
that whole wing that goes across the
back there lifts up when you hit the
brakes.
Well it lifts.
When you start driving quick,
it lifts up and becomes a wing wing.
And then when you hit the brakes it
flips up and becomes a,
an actual airbrake.
And it is extremely effective,
I would imagine.
What it does is it know when you break
the car,
nose dives,
it completely eliminates the dive.
So the car just squats straight down.
Wow.
That's wild.
It's fucking gorgeous.
Are they going to keep making them?
I don't.
I don't think so.
Why not?
Ford?
I fired to guest.
They lose money on every single one they
make.
If I had to guess,
kind of a bullshit word.
We run in here.
I know trump.
I thought you were going to fix all this
thought that was part of your platform.
That's what I heard.
It's going to make american great again.
Do we?
The car economy is.
It's such a global economy like
american,
like we make a bunch of the hell.
Cats are built.
Like in Canada.
We make bmw x five in south caroLina.
Well,
we make up ford tundras in Texas.
That's what toyota tundra.
Toyota tundra.
Toyota is a make a couple different cars
here in America.
A couple of cars in America.
I think japanese automakers probably
have at least as many auto workers in
America as american car companies do.
This is definitely the same car I was
driving press cars.
God,
what is great is just the.
The buttresses like when it goes by,
you can see right through the side of
the car.
you can just see the air there between
the tunnel and the pod.
That's so pretty.
Yeah.
That might be the best looking car I've
ever seen.
It is so cool.
It was so fast.
As far as like american cars,
that literally might be the best looking
car I've ever seen.
I think if it's my money I want.
I would buy the older gt,
the 2005 one because I liked the manual
transmission.
Sure.
And I just think it was.
that was just one of the best cars ever
made.
Do you ever drive one of those?
YeAh.
What's that like?
The best?
Really?
The best,
best?
Best?
Yeah.
Because this is a race car,
right?
And,
and everything that comes with it,
that one,
it was a road car and it was let's make
the best road car we can make.
And so it wasn't a particularly
successful race car,
but as a road car it was just glorious.
The ride and the power and the style and
the sound and you know,
it's,
they had to develop that car very
quickly.
I think the last time I was on this show
we were talking about for gts and you
know,
so everything's overbuilt.
You can run like double stock horse
power and you can run almost 280 miles
an hour in the fucking mile and these
things on stock arrow and when people do
crAzy shit with them,
like put twin turbos in them and stuff,
I should not even that crazy.
It's expensive,
but it's,
it's proven science at this point.
They're not breaking any new ground.
Yeah.
Wow.
It's,
it's actually because they're super
supercharged from the factory.
Right.
So they're meant to handle forced
induction.
So the turbo system you take off the
supercharger in the turbo system,
supplants it.
Is that the right word?
I don't know.
It's just,
it runs more boost,
but it's a very,
very strong engine.
And so they're
not completely different systems.
They just,
they both force air in,
just they do it in different ways.
And when you buy one from the factory,
how many horsepower did he come with?
Five 55.
Fifty is a lot back then.
That's a bunch.
Yeah.
With no traction control.
That was the last last car.
The viper to the same year.
Viber might've had one year,
but basically the last car without
traction.
Control,
stability control.
Yeah.
So a lot of people would,
would crash them.
Oh yeah,
I would imagine.
Yeah.
My gt three doesn't have shit on it.
It has.
Yeah.
It has um,
control and that kind of thing.
So no,
it has antilock brakes.
I don't think it has traction control
hit really.
I think the next model did because it's
the rs,
huh?
I don't know how fortunate for you if it
doesn't,
it's a very raw car.
I loved your car out of a lot of fun.
Driving your car to fun cars,
man.
That's great.
I think maybe the next.
Maybe the next thing I buy my bnrs
they're great.
I know they're getting so expensive.
I know,
but safe money thousand seven.
Year two is like,
that's the year.
The one aFterwards they became,
they started having traction control.
Make sure that's true.
I'm pretty sure it's true.
Two thousand seven gt,
three rs.
No traction control.
I'm pretty sure there is a period of
2000 early two thousands up to an end of
two thousands where portia was using the
engine called the metzker engine,
whIch,
which traced its way back to the mall
and it was a very,
very strong engine.
Almost say that would give me correctly.
Let me se le mans le mans,
the movIe with steve mcqueen.
Fucking hate.
That movie really stinks.
Does it?
Steve mcqueen movies stink.
Wow.
You are a crazy person.
How dare you.
I liked the image of steve mcqueen.
I like what he represents.
This a broody american from the 19
sixties.
You know,
like one of the last of the real men.
Yeah,
I mean I liked steve mcqueen based on
the photographs of him.
I've seen his movies.
Like I thought it was interesting
because it was like a snapshot of time.
Like um,
what's the other one?
Oh,
bullet bullet bullets.
interesting.
It's like you're,
you're looking at a snapshot in time,
you know,
it's just weird.
San francisco,
san francisco,
so empty and pull it.
There was nobody alive back then.
People.
There was no tech companies.
There's very few people.
Chat.
Traffic was nothing back then.
Men talk to somebody about what traffic
is like in 1960 and la when the guy just
brought that up earlier,
this show.
Well,
I moved here in [inaudible] 94 and I
remember when I moved here it was
nothing like this.
really nothing.
It's gotten 100 percent worse.
it's like just twice as many people here
it is what it feels like us,
it's,
it's so crazy.
Like you get on the highway on a
saturday night just heading into la on a
saturday night and you're stuck in
bumper to bumper traffic for no reason.
No one's dead.
There's no accident.
It's just.
I read,
I'm reading a book right now called
traffic.
It's about the science of traffic and
it.
They did a study in la
and saturday,
2:00
PM traffic is worse than any weekday day
rush hour in los.
Everybody's out,
everyone's out doing their shit.
Dude.
You know when you go to another city,
like if you go to a big city like
seattle and you're like,
you're there with them and they complain
about the traffic,
go shut the fuck up.
Second of all,
what I'm doing must be wrong then
because I'm dealing with way too many
people.
You guys have got it right.
This is the right amount.
You got a lot of people,
but enough to many people,
I get a medium sized city that's not la.
Yeah.
And in traffic makes sense.
It goes in,
it goes out.
Yeah.
Like here,
it's just like the.
Hence the scooter you want to get out
before it gets all blade runner.
He.
When's that gonna happen?
Well,
You know,
it's like those dudes like magnus walker
lived in downtown la.
It was dreadlocks in his garage
warehouse district.
Those guys like that shit.
Right?
He likes that.
She likes being an urbanite.
I'm super fucked.
I'm in venice.
When that tsunami comes,
I'm super fall.
Yeah,
you're right on the edge.
It's not good for me not looking good.
All the cars had done will be on my
room.
App was the app that wants to give us
access to early warning app says you
have 60 seconds for your fucking day
Because that I had in Hawaii.
Well,
yeah,
there's a,
there's an app now that's working in
California,
but it's the,
you're about to die.
It's,
it's an earthquake's about to hit.
They apparently have it depending upon
the magnitude,
the earthquake,
which is really scary because the higher
magnitude possibility the more time you
have.
So they really can give you up to a
minute to know your foxville dude.
I'm just thinking what can I.
I'm thinking about one in a minute.
Nowhere.
Nowhere worth getting.
I can get to like my closet.
Do you have stored food or anything?
I'm embarrassed that I don't have a List
of shit I need for.
Probably should probably get for an
earthquake,
but I don't know.
You must have a whole room of shit in
this fuCking policy rather than here.
But here I have meat in here,
but I have um,
I do have commercial freezers,
courts for ell,
for elk,
right?
Yeah.
But um,
I have,
um,
emergency rations,
have a freeze dried food and you know,
that could last me a few months.
How would you,
like,
how would you physically get out of the
city?
You would really be fucked.
You says you just start walking.
Bicycle wheel.
The real fuck would be cars.
Too many cars,
right?
There's way too many cars for you ever
see what happened when the hurricanes
were hitting Texas?
People try to escape,
or Florida,
like Florida,
the last one.
You can't go anywhere and they just get
stuck on the highway and you run out of
gas and the highwAys.
Nobody's scared and desperate.
It's not good in hurricanes.
You see comment,
this earthquake get 30 seconds,
you know,
I think my scooter is the is what's
going to save me?
It's going to be.
They're going to go,
you're going to go somewhere.
They're going to beat you.
Gonna get away with a bunch of.
Yeah.
They're going to hunt you down and put
me on a spit.
Yeah.
They going to keep you alive so they
could eat you longer because there's no
refrigeration.
Refrigeration is going to tie you up and
cut off parts of you eat it in front of
you.
They come here and bust into this
fucking place.
Yeah,
I mean that's the move.
Come here.
we'll help you both.
This space.
Dude,
who has a fLoat tank.
That is so awesome.
Everybody should have one.
I agree.
I just.
My.
My real concern is the,
just that the mass of humans,
just the sheer number is so insane and I
don't think it's.
I don't think it's sustainable like this
number of people that are.
There's never been a time ever in human
history where we've had masses of people
crammed into areas like we have today in
our urban areas.
You mean modern America?
Modern Mexico city is like that jammed
up.
There's quite a few places that are like
the population numbers higher now than
it's ever been recorded.
Human history and so the population in
these cities is higher than it's ever
been.
We've never had,
like matt,
we never had 20 million people in a city
before in America like we do in la.
Was that jamie stay through the smaller
population than los angeles county?
Is that all of them on the full 30
something states?
Almost all of them is la county.
Twenty dollars million people yet.
It's like 16 something,
right?
I think of it.
This is like on the 10 to 11 million
units,
so looking at this map and it's one tiny
little area of California and it has
more people in it.
If it was a state than almost every
fucking state except Florida that in
Texas,
New York,
Pennsylvania,
Ohio,
and given me Illinois,
Illinois.
God damn.
That is just fucking banana leaves.
So crazy.
I don't.
Is it where would you if you didn't
live?
No,
if I didn't live.
No.
So where would you live if you didn't
live here?
I've probably like,
I like Colorado a lot.
Colorado's gets state.
Mountains are good.
I like noise.
I like northern California but not san
francisco.
Like farmers get fucked up.
Deal with that weird dude.
It keeps knocking on your door.
Yeah.
New woods.
Um,
Colorado.
I think I like Utah too.
I like Utah.
Utah's very underrated.
Those people are very nice.
They think everybody thinks you tell.
Go fucking mormons.
I can't do it.
Mormons are friendly.
Some of the nicest folks ever.
I spent like four months in st george
was that.
It's the very corner southwest corner of
Utah at the Arizona Nevada corner and
it's like the,
the town nearest to zion national park.
I was doing like landscape photography
for awhiLe that,
that's gorgeous science.
Awesome.
It's so pretty.
And aCtually to bring it back to cars.
um,
we had a show at nbc sports called drive
and did a national parks.
The roads through our national parks
here in America.
Our glorious,
glorious yellow,
yosemIte zion,
death valley,
bryce canyon.
All
have amazing roads going through them.
Yeah.
And just the view that you get.
We're very lucky here.
We've got a lot of cool shit.
And in California we got the best roads
in America.
Possibly.
We've got soMe pretty good ones.
You know,
that.
Just that place where everybody goes to
just to drive to fuck around that
angel's crest highway.
God,
that's pretty.
That's where I was this morning before I
came here.
What were you driving up there?
My focus rs was having fun,
we adjusted the suspension and so I
needed to shake it down.
Those are fast little cars very fast.
I worked with mountain on mine.
Um,
so it's making 377 wheel horsepower and
455.
We'll torque from a four cylinder and we
have a adapt kw,
ddc adaptive suspension,
adaptive coil overs.
That's hilarious.
Awesome.
The cars very,
very fast right now.
And that's a really like cartoon right
now that's not so light.
It's small but it's all wheel drive
which adds to the weight and so it's a,
it's not super heavy,
but it's not a,
it's not a featherweight porsche or
something like that.
And a liTtle less maybe 33,
34,
but it's a,
it's got a Lot of stick and porsChe at
porsche.
Fuck me for the irs has this trick all
wheel drive system.
You can actually power oversteer.
So it's not like when the front wheel
slip you get power to the back.
Like it has a,
what they call it drift mode,
which can send up to 100 percent of the
power to the back.
So you've been wanting you to get crazy.
You can actually,
yeah.
Oversteer and of engineered craziness
and wow.
the new and the new m five,
you know,
is all wheel drive in the new amg.
Sixty three is all wheel drive and you
can electronically disconnect the all
wheel.
Drive through a button in both of them.
Yeah.
So you can get drifting as well.
Get drifting.
Mr.
Harris.
Yeah.
Wanting to get drifting.
Whatever.
yeah.
What do you think of that new cadillac?
What is it?
The a six.
Oh,
was the ct six with the super cruise?
That thing?
It's the new big cadillac that has a
giant engine in it now.
Oh,
it's a putting a 600 horsepower engine.
What is that thing called?
Ct six v c sat.
What it is.
I don't.
I'm going to say the wrong thing.
I haven't.
I saw this thing.
Got me excited about cadillacs.
Well,
there's a ctsv no,
not that one.
it's the ccc.
I think it's called the ctcs.
Ct six is their biggest one.
It's the brand new.
The brand new one has a crazy v engine.
I don't think it has.
No,
no,
it's not for sale yet.
IT has a twin turbo like dual overhead
cam v eight,
which is like the most advanced general
motors engine ever and it's going to be
a cadillac exclusive engine,
which hasn't happened since.
remember the north star?
That was the last time kat.
He got their own motors.
Make it a big deal about it being
cadillac exclusive for k comerica.
Go fuck yourself.
That's sort of what cadillac hasn't had
right is right.
You know the cadillac,
like they actually the ctsv is the
lightest,
fastest car in its class that as the
best steering in its class as the most
horsepower in his class,
so making little not sell them.
What they can't sell ctsv is they can't
sell ats fees.
Like what do you mean no one's buying
those?
Well,
I mean I'm sure there's a few reasons,
but the,
the infotainment system,
that queue system is really pretty
terrible.
Fat dick.
A lot of people don't make it to the
test drive because of that.
Yeah.
That,
that thing is really like a liability is
not good.
It's very bad.
I've tried to like I was,
I rented an escalate and I was going
through all that shit to try to get to
the navigation.
Like what the fuck man?
The toughest bars forever.
I'm good at this.
I can't figure it out.
How to get the navigation.
Where do you.
Where's home?
Where's the fucking home button?
So that that's why.
Are they switching over to car play now
or worse than the android or apple
phone?
Yeah.
You can get those.
That's still.
That still doesn't get you around the
touch buttons and stuff and that he is
the cta cta to fucking slam.
I mean if that actually artist's
rendering on boy,
that's what.
It's really good.
That's the ct six if it looks like that
will say cadillac has a really nice
history of coming out with very bold
concept cars and then not building them.
Oh,
come on.
Seriously make that.
They have they build end up building
water down shit for every floor.
Does it to.
Cadillac was always the car.
Like my grandfather's day made it.
You got a fucking cat.
I can put that back up for a second
please.
That thing to me looks like a modern
version of what I felt like a cadillac
should be.
Well that's not entirely different from
a bentley flying spur.
If you pull up a bentley flying spur
that looks similar,
but that again is a rendering.
That's the best look in catalogs
rendering like they.
I hope they make that way because that
is the best look and cadillac I've ever
seen.
It's aggressive,
I mean aggressive for american cars.
Aggressive cells,
right chrysler 300 saved chrysler.
And when I say best looking cadillac,
I mean best looking new cadillac.
That's what I mean.
I don't mean like the batmobile style
old school catalogs because I really
feel it's unfair to compare because the
details,
those are works of art.
Yeah,
I mean like what year would that be?
Like a 57.
Eldorado would be retail custom.
Fifty seven,
you know,
and they're like 75 feet long.
Big bodies are coming up big.
So the,
the slammed on bags,
you know,
with steel wheels.
Yeah.
So there's your fins.
Look at that.
Jesus christ as a chopped roof.
Oh my god.
That one.
They've really gone batmobile.
That looks like a bat.
Yeah.
God,
it's beautiful though,
but fit man.
I wish you can't bring fins back,
but that would be nice.
Yesterday and impact and all.
Yeah,
that is hot.
That's older.
That's like a 55,
maybe seven.
That's a custom job.
The bill.
But you know,
do you.
Would you roll big body like that?
You have full,
big bought.
I mean you would take it out on sunday
and then you'd go fuck this car and then
you would drive something that you can
actually drive because part of the
thrill of driving is the interaction
with the road.
Right.
And like those cars are not interacting
very well.
Know there's so much weight.
You're moving them around.
They're sloppy.
Whereas like you got into like an old 73
porsche.
You could drive that thing.
Yes.
Even like stock from the factory.
You could drive that thing.
No problem.
Yeah.
The american car,
the older american cars,
like you have no idea where that limit
is coming.
It's like I'm there,
I'm there,
I'm there.
The wheels falling off trees.
Ooh.
Yeah.
They're just.
There was no communication,
the steering wheel,
old school,
electric steering is like a terrible
zero communication up and I used to be
so afraid of old cars and then I started
driving old european cars knowing,
oh,
this is how this is supposed to go.
It's just America.
Well,
it's a product of their environment,
right?
Like in the eighties,
those fucking gem guys that chomp cigars
and they're off the rack shitty suits.
They never left detroit and if you go to
detroit it's just fucking pot holes and
it's straight lines.
And so of course the cars would ride
like shit and,
or would float around and not handle
because there isn't a corner for 300
miles,
you know,
now you get the ctsv because these guys
and they go to the nurburgring and
tests.
It's a global world now.
Yeah,
it's a totally different.
And then detroit,
these,
these closed minded morons built cars
for their own city and sold them all
over the world with no regard to the
fact that they didn't work for shit in
Italy or anywhere with corners in it.
You know?
That's interesting.
That's a good point.
And it's set up America,
those you go drive a 57 cadillac in
detroit and you go,
well this makes all the sense in the
world.
The roads are straight.
Nineteen 57.
How's that beeline coffee?
This is your coffee.
Yeah,
this is really good.
It's good,
don't you,
you,
you.
Did you go to the place where they know
it?
I work with this company,
beeline coffee.
And at first they started sponsoring my
new watch podcasts called watch and
listen.
Or watch.
Store watch.
Dark to.
Yeah.
The logical extension from cars to this
is a delicious coffee.
And so thank you.
Yeah,
I got you.
I brought you some.
It's a light roast,
medium body,
single origin.
And that's an a lung and sohne watch.
Thank you.
And that's the back of a long cronograph
oh,
that's the back.
Yeah,
the back.
Oh,
that's beautiful.
That's amazing.
And that shit's all.
Anything that looks like gold.
That's gold.
So is that um,
glass or sapphire crystal.
So there's a crystal and the back end.
The front?
Yes.
Oh
wow.
Yeah.
They call that a display back.
Oh.
So just you could show piece.
So you can admire the hardware within.
It is crazy when you look at the detail
involved in one of those watches,
a lot of parallels with cars.
So many the they've,
they,
they rose up in parallel.
I mean the obvious connections of
timing,
races and stuff like that.
And wearing a machine on your wrist.
That's called self dealing.
As I went to advertise my own watch for
sale.
You can do that.
Yeah,
we'll get that.
What's that one on the far right?
That's a panorai that lots called a
retro,
which is a also known as a split second
chronograph.
So it's actually two coronagraphs laid
on top of each other.
So it would be used to measure the time
differential between say two cars on a
racetrack.
That's the most complicated movement.
Panoramics I think that was about 13 or
14 grand.
That's a beautiful watch.
Very nice watch.
It's pretty.
That was a demo.
I sent it back,
send it back,
send it back.
I sent,
I said most of them I send them back as
opposed to giving them 10 grand a month.
Oh,
is that how it works?
Yeah.
The part of my,
I have a sponsorship deal,
crown and caliber.com.
What is it?
What is,
what is the sponsorship deal like?
What does it do?
Well,
I started this watch podcasts,
so they're our title sponsor so they
gave me a budget for a year,
but I can also loan out watches out of
their stock if I so desire to try
something.
So it's like a chick trying on jewelry.
Jewelry for men,
right?
Yeah.
Yeah,
it is.
Yeah.
It's the only jewelry that you can kind
of get away with.
Pretty much that a fat diamond ring on
total asshole.
No,
but it makes sense if you have a watch
that Jonathan Ward from icon,
that was his case.
He brought jonathan is really into old.
Weird watching.
I follow his instagram as well.
He,
he's into old,
weird.
Anything fascinates me.
That guy is.
He's the most interesting person that
there is.
He's very intense.
He's like,
you like you,
you guys both just do so much stuff.
I don't know where all the hours are in
the day.
Like he runs his business and he's makes
videos,
but I also see like every weekend and
steering he'll put up like a handbag he
made from scratch leather.
Like where did you find the time for
that?
Yeah.
Youtube.
I don't know where you find the time to
do all this shit.
Illusion because um,
the,
the time I spent here,
it's very easy.
It's just conversation,
you know,
it's,
it's fun.
It's great having a guy like you get to
talk cars.
I agree.
It is crying.
Um,
standup comedy.
I've done so long.
It's like a part of my life.
Yeah,
it's normal.
The working out stuff,
it's like if I don't do it,
I can't do the other things.
I'll go crazy.
I won't be balanced and I want to stay
healthy.
So I do that.
So it seems that you seem to churn out a
large volume of content and you also
travel ufc and all that kind of stuff
and it's a of content.
The unit
you,
you told me the universe rewards,
hustle while it does I,
you know,
I have that engraved on the back of the
first rolex.
I bought myself a really good for you
matches from you.
That's dope and I sort of lived on that
mantra for quite a long time until I
recently.
I actually just totally burned myself
out on it a bit.
You can burn yourself out.
You gotta be real,
real conscious of how your body feels.
Right.
Well that's what I like about what
you've been saying,
that you're doing cardio seven days a
week and that's what happened.
I spent so much time working and
focusing on.
I was like,
look,
as long as I can stand and lift my arms,
I'm going to keep making videos because
this shit could all end tomorrow,
but my body completely fell apart and so
I had to go,
all right,
I think it's time to take care of this.
Well,
sTick with it.
Here's a car analogy here because this
is your vehicle and the difference
between having a 500 horsepower engine
and a hundred and 25 horsepower diesel
is literally how you take care of you.
So and if you can turn your body into a
race car,
you really can't unless you know
obviously have disability or something's
wrong with you,
but for most people the issue is just
will,
will in their mind and discipline and
then knowledge,
right standing how to do it correctly.
And I've lost large amounts of weight
several times in the past I lost,
I've lost 50 pounds and then I lost a
hundred pounds and then I lost this past
two years,
another 50.
So like I know how to do it.
What are you doing now differently?
But the difference with this one is I
wanted to do it every time I've done it
in the past it has drastically
interrupted my day to day life.
It's like either you go to fat camp and
do it or you,
whatever,
you know,
it takes away from something.
This one,
it was much more important to go,
I have a job,
I have a life,
I have to figure out how to make this
work in within that life.
So it became a lot more hotel gyms
really doing that.
Really making sure to just do that shit.
Oh,
when you're on the road,
the road is really hard.
Yeah.
It's hard with diet too.
it's very hard.
I don'T.
I didn't change my diet that much.
I just started exercising a lot.
My big problem wasn't that I ate badly.
It's that I would eat big meals spaced
very far apart and so my body would go
into like storage mode,
but now I try and eat smaller meals and
more of them and it seems to work much
more efficiently.
Well,
everybody's body is different,
but for the most part,
one of the biggest,
most significant things that you can do
is cut out most sugar.
Cut out,
most refined carbohydrates.
Red is my achilles.
Everybody I love bread out.
Weight would fly off.
You know,
especially when you're telling me the
volume of exercise you're doing.
Oh,
cut out the bread,
cut out the sugar,
you would lose ridiculous amounts of
weight.
Know Jordan Peterson was on my podcast.
He was talking about autoimmune issues
that he had and what he did was cut out
everything except for meat and
vegetables.
That's it.
And all his problems went away.
Yeah,
I know I,
I've done the atkins style cave.
Manny,
whatever you want to call it,
you know,
all protein and fat,
cut out the vegetables and cut all the
car.
I like,
I,
it works,
I've done it.
I've lost weight and it just,
I,
I couldn't stick with it because I
fucking love bread so much and I just
don't want to kill myself,
you know what I mean?
I want to.
It's like it's like growing a show or
something.
If the curve is going in the right
direction and I'm okaY pushing forward,
let me just push forward.
RiGht.
I'll get there.
I don't,
you know,
so.
Well it seems like myself currently
going in the right direction.
Think about saying that you don't want
to kill yourself.
I get it.
I love bread too and I love pasta.
I'm a big fan of lasagna and I just love
italian food.
I really do.
I love pizza.
Um,
but I just limit to one day a week.
That's probably good.
One day a week I allow myself to eat
whatever the fuck I want and if I decide
it's wednesday night,
if wednesday night I go out to dinner
and I said,
you know what man,
I want the fucking spaghetti and meat
balls.
Let's just do this.
Then that's the night.
That's the night I cheat.
And then the other six nights I eat
normal.
Yeah,
it do it.
I respect your,
your stick.
It makes it feel better too when you get
that cheat day.
Yeah.
Like then it really counts.
And if I get spaghetti with meatballs
with grated parmesan cheese over it at
five,
fucking digging in on that on whatever,
friday night like,
oh,
just let yourself enjoy the glory.
It's not just a regular spaghetti and
meatballs because it's dinner,
which is normal,
you know,
on wednesday,
friday,
whatever.
Who cares?
No,
it's the one day window you could eat
that fucking pizza.
The cheese.
Maybe.
This is what I take home from this one.
Maybe I take home the cheat day
philosophy from this show.
She days good.
The other thing is your body,
if you get into that habit,
your body won't be craving those things
anymore because a lot of the reasons why
you crave it is because your gut
bacteria that's being supported by that
diet and then you sort of go into gut
bacteria withdrawals and that makes you
want more and blah blah blah.
Crazy.
Yeah,
but you got to do is get your a biome in
check,
like start eating a lot of probiotics.
Yeah.
Like if you can stomach kimchi.
I don't knoW if you're into that.
I like the taste.
I mean I like korean food.
I don't know how much I can eat.
Kimchi is a daily thing for me.
Really?
Yup.
Acidophilus.
A yogurt is good.
If you could eat yogurt,
you have the time to.
To find these kids.
Go to the supermarket,
takes 10 minutes.
He gets some foods.
I know.
it was amazing.
I had to run around the city.
this is why I'm surprised at how you.
How well you do it because running
around this city,
you could have a whole day that's three
activities and it takes all day to do
those activities and you barely have
time to eat in between the.
I'm just bad at bringing that stuff with
me,
you know,
I need to know he's better at carrying
my own,
whether it's bars or kimchi or whatever
to bring it with me so that they don't
get to that.
Oh my god,
I'm starving.
And then murder.
When you leave,
get me your address and I'll have some
on it.
Stuff sent to you.
So cool.
Because we have some new onnit protein
bites,
coconut and cashews.
No guilt or like protein for each one of
these little squares and they're fucking
hell.
Yeah.
That'll just get you to the next thing.
Yeah,
they're heroin.
I like that.
Yeah.
I'll have some sense.
Said that in like three or 400 pounds of
elk.
Oh,
I want to tell you I killed something
when I went.
I went,
I went hunting.
I went bird hunting.
Uh,
what'd you shoot?
I shot a quail.
Oh,
I used the gun.
I didn't,
you know,
I can't shoot a quail with a hard,
um,
But they were delicious and delicious
food.
It was really the dogs.
The dogs were so impressive.
The dogs were amazing,
well trained,
so super well trained.
Went to this place in south Georgia and
uh,
they,
they had the most brilliantly trained
dogs like I've ever seen.
The dis found everything.
I think I got like 90 birds was a lot.
So you went on a full dick cheney full.
Yeah.
Without the humans.
I didn't shoot any humans.
this photo.
Did you cook the quail?
No,
they,
they sent me some which I could cook at
home.
Um,
but they,
they,
they were doing them there.
They were turning the quail breasts into
like nuggets,
nuggets,
but a quail breast.
And then,
uh,
like the drumsticks banging.
Absolutely delicious.
And what did they cook?
The,
the,
when you say mcnugget,
so they breaded that breaded and fried
it.
And it was like a whole quail breast was
like a pop it in your mouth nugget.
It was really good.
It's a delicious meat.
Yeah.
Are,
they're crazy,
crazy tasty birds?
Yeah.
But I didn't,
I was like super conflicted about the
hunting portion of it and I don't know
why I felt I,
my dad was like,
that's like fishing was likely not,
it's not like fishing,
but I didn't feel as guilty as I thought
I would.
You know what man,
it's like,
and this is a crazy thing to say,
but I'm gonna say it anyway,
it's,
it's like an old relationship like to
like,
oh,
like you run into an old girlfriend on
the street and you haven't seen her
since 1989 or somewhere to see where
this is going.
Okay,
the fuck it is a long time ago.
And you run into each other and you
start talking to each other like,
oh,
I remember you.
I broke up with something.
No,
not even that.
Just you,
you,
it's a relationship with a hunting an
animal.
People feel it very quickly with fishing
because fishing carries very little
guilt.
Some people like,
oh,
is it hurt?
Is it,
is it going to get her?
Some people get like that with fish.
Most people don't give a fuck about
fish.
Little kids.
TheY laugh.
My kids laugh and it's like this
flopping and die fish has a fucking hook
through its head and my seven year old
thinks it's awesome.
Oh my god,
she's so happy that this thing is dying.
That's crazy.
But if that was a rabbit,
she had never had that reaction.
Right,
right.
There's a natural thing that we have
with,
uh,
with.
We have a hierarchy of life.
Things that closest to us we feel more
connected to.
We don't feel connected at all to bugs.
Nobody gives a fuck about vegan slap
mosquitoes all day long.
Nobody gives a shit about that life.
But there is a life that you care about
when things get warm and they get too
close to us.
Yeah.
When they,
when they get too close to malmo,
like people freak out.
Yeah.
I went on a south african safari last
year and it was like I couldn't fathom
someone going and hunting a leopard or
something like that.
That's a weird thing.
That's a big game.
Shit,
that's a very weird thing.
It's a very different thing.
It's not,
it's not.
It's a,
it's almost like what that is and I'm
not saying it's just sadism,
maybe a little about what that is,
is like it's an aberration off the
original idea and this is the only way
to look at it and people would get mad
at me that are hunters because I'm a
hunter and like,
what are you saying?
Look,
it's not the thing to do,
and last year doing it on just to
control population,
there's no reason to do it,
but what?
What happened was in the past,
the only reason people hunted was from
me,
right?
You barely could stay alive anyway,
and when you went on a hunting party,
he didn't go for sport.
You went to go to kill things.
When you have so much food that you
don't need to worry about food and
you've already been shooting all these
animals.
Then they start doing these things
called slams.
They call doing super slams are the
grand slam.
There's a doll sheep slammed as a sheep
slam,
a rocky,
like a big horn sheep slammed.
there's like a jam burry.
No,
no,
no.
You.
You try to kill one representative of
each of the subspecies.
My god.
Really?
Yeah.
It's a big thing.
It's a big thing with these guys.
Got poker run calm,
like the the big six are the big eight
in africa.
Africa.
It's a big five.
Is that what it is?
The big five,
the five most dangerous animals to hunt
on foot.
It's like cheetah lion,
hippo,
rhino,
and whatever the fuck.
Leopard.
Yeah.
There's a bunch of these kind of slams.
They haven't for turkeys,
they have a wild Turkey slam.
You get the gould's Turkey,
get the osceola Turkey.
There's a bunch of different turkeys all
over the country.
One Florida.
There's one in Mexico.
It's different Turkey point being people
start collecting.
It gets.
It gets weird.
Well,
that's the trophy,
right?
Yeah.
It's weird.
It's like it gets to this weird place
like you don't think they shouldn't do
it.
Like,
okay.
Are you eating the Turkey?
You are.
Okay.
That's cool.
Are you eating the deer?
Yep.
Okay.
Well then I have no quarrel,
but when you start going like leopard
lion was.
I said cheetos.
Elephant was the other one.
Yeah.
Yeah,
man,
I mean the only reason why you shoot an
elephant is if the elephants going on a
rampage through our village people and
you want to protect people's lives and
I'm on team people.
Other than that,
why the fuck else would you shoot an
elephant?
I have no idea.
I saw an elephant.
The biggest elephant I've ever seen as
far away from me as you were sitting
right now.
My god and I almost had a harder to live
in africa on a safari see,
but I think those things are amazing.
It was amazing.
But like you just know what you're
doing.
The reason I was so close is because we
were watching them push trees down with
their trunks,
like four or five inch trees just from,
oh my god.
Like it's nothing.
You know what I mean?
Like you'd crash a car if you hit one of
those,
it would crash the car and like they're
just phone phone and they're right next
to you and if they go on your jeep,
that's the end of that.
You know what's complicated?
Someone was trying to explain this to me
and I should really be honest about this
guy was trying to explain to me that
when we think of africa,
we think of a country,
it's not a country,
it's a continent and it's way bigger
concepts in north America.
We've seen pictures of United States
stuck in the middle of africa.
Africa is fucking huge and he's like,
unfortunately,
there's places in africa where they have
over populations of elephants and they
encroach on human civilization and they
do have to hire hunters to come in and
do it and kill them or they don't hire
them.
The hunters pay and the money goes
straight to the village.
The meat goes,
the village and people get very excited
about people huntIng these elephants and
when,
when I hear that seems like a sort of
short term solution to the village right
there.
The village doesn't give a shit about
the elephants.
They want their,
they want to eat probably right?
They agency eat their crops but becomes
a big issue,
you know,
and they beat the fuck out of there.
You know,
like good luck.
They only keep guiding them.
Lfo now have no chance.
So when someone was explaining this to
me,
I remember we were saying this,
I was like,
why the fuck would you ever want to kill
an elephant?
We know there's not that many of them.
He's like,
yeah,
this is why it's complicated.
There's not that many of them.
In some places it's like in la there's
no grizzly bears.
Right?
But if you go to Montana,
the people that live in Montana are
going to start hunting these fucking
things.
They just declared them open for a in
Wyoming.
They're not.
They don't have.
They think they just started a hunting
season and it's very controversial and
they just end date.
No,
no,
not anymore at all.
Now they have a lot of them and the
people that lIve up there,
especially people that have been mauled
or know people that have been mauled to
like,
hey fucking enough.
And now I get it.
We,
they made a great comeback.
But you know,
if you're in chicago,
there's zero bears.
So if,
and this is a tiny place in comparison
to africa.
So when I was saying that like I thought
that elephants were endangered,
he's like,
yes and no.
They're are endangered in some areas and
good point to fucked up point.
The most dark point about all of it is
that trophy hunting is the only thing
that keeps those animals healthy.
This is what's fucked up.
I was talking about playing campaigns
about this this weekend when,
and this is what I say,
trophy hunting.
I'm even talking about normal hunting
for meat,
like impalas or you know elan's these,
these big game animals that people hunt
for because they're delicious.
Even them in Zimbabwe.
There's a lot of areas in Zimbabwe that
are not high fence.
They're Just open enormous areas.
All the money that would come from
people hunting there would sustain these
local areas,
sustain these lodges so it make it
viable to keep these animals alive and
stop poachers.
A big bonds.
The anti poaching,
right?
Exactly.
The only thing that funds the anti
poaching.
So here's what happened.
The cecil,
the lion shit went down.
Nobody wanted to go to africa anymore to
go hunting and all of these businesses
are going under,
so there's nothing stopping the poachers
so the poachers move in and kill
everything,
kill everything like that.
It's gone the other way.
How many elephants were killed last year
by people?
something like 400 or google this
legally killed elephants.
The number of illegally killed
elephants.
$30,000
come on.
30,000.
Most of them are killed illegally.
Most of them are poached.
They have this one elephant,
you know that last elephant that was
dying the mail,
or excuse me,
rhino,
white rhino or black rhino,
which was in a black rhino.
I think they have that.
That poor bastard with armed guards
around it.
Twenty four slash seven because they
were worried someone's going to kill it
and shoot it and chop the fucking horn
off.
Like the poaching is way scarier than
the hunting and the only thing that
protects the animals from poaching is
hunting.
It sounds so weird and so forth,
but you have to look at it honestly.
Yeah.
They said something similar to us in
South Africa,
both that,
that,
that they need the funds because the
anti poachers,
you know,
they,
they're,
they're all over the place.
And then here's the other problem.
When you say poachers,
these poachers,
you know what you're really saying,
poor people.
That's what you're really saying.
They're poor,
desperate people.
They don't know what the fuck to do and
if they could chop off a rhino's horn
and make some money,
they're going to do it.
If they can shoot that animal that's not
theirs and use it for me,
they're going to do it.
They're starving to death.
I mean they have no options.
There's appears people in parts of
africa that are living in grass huts.
My buddy justin wren,
he,
he goes and makes wells for these people
in the Congo and the stories he tells
you would just make your eyes tear up
these human beings and they're living
like this 24 hours a day for their
entire life.
And this is,
this is the norm.
So we're talking about poachers will.
you're talking about people that are
fucking desperate.
Yeah,
you can call them poachers,
you could dehumanize them with that
term,
but they're just poor people and none of
them.
The movie stereotype poachers somehow
some of them,
but most of them aren't.
Now here's what's even crazier.
Most of the anti poaching agents used to
be poachers because there's nothing else
to do.
Yeah,
that's not surprising.
NoW they're poachers again,
because they put their hunting people
who they got out of jail,
they got out of this position that can't
be [inaudible] because they can now.
They just got back from poachers again.
Perfect.
This happens.
A lot of it's gone well,
so when campaigns was explaining this to
me and when does it explain it to me?
I'm like,
well,
of course.
So they don't even know how many animals
are left in these areas where people
have abandoned them.
Ranches that were once thriving ways.
You see.
The thing is most of these animals,
a good percentage of it,
we're on the verge of extinction just 30
years ago because people were just over
hunting them and poaching them and doing
whatever they want it to him.
Then they started putting value on them.
People would go over there to hunt them
so people would keep these huge areas
in.
That population boomed because they were
taking care of them because they were.
They were A resource and,
and this is key.
This is conflicting to people.
It's wild.
It's very wild.
I just went to the galapagos on a
vacation,
which is interesting.
Have you been.
It seems like you're kind of spot.
I want to,
can't kill anything.
It's,
it's very,
it's like Hawaii if there were never
people.
Wow.
So it's an.
It's a completely empty Hawaii.
How big is it?
About the same size as Hawaii?
The big island or chain of.
I know it's a chain of islands.
There's probably 13 or 15 islands.
Whoa.
Yeah.
None as bIg as the big island,
but most the buildings on them,
there are two or three like towns wIth
like 25,000
people and the rest of it is nothing.
National park,
97 percent.
But they talk about these giant
tortoises,
you know,
and there were like potentially a half a
million of them on the islands and it
went down to like one,
like they found like a fall last one and
they tried to breed it.
There's like three varieties of
tortoises and the one of them got down
to one and they tried to save it and
they couldn't save it.
And now it's like,
you know,
embalmed fucking taxidermy on the
galapagos islands,
but you know,
these giant tortoises that lived at 200
but the,
um,
the,
all the passing ships would just like
grab a few of them and they'd eat them
on the ships and they'd completely
decimated the entire population.
They're all gone and they're trying to
bring them back.
I don't even know why we started here.
But will they take forever to grow?
Right?
Yeah.
They have 100 years old.
They live 200 years.
Yeah.
And then the whole rest of the islands,
what's crazy about them as nothing has
been hunted there in forever.
So the wild animals have no problem with
people.
No problem.
Like your face to face with sea lions
and stuff.
I could be to like birds,
like what kind of wild bird would let
you get within a foot of it,
but there's these giant blue footed
boobies that have no problem with you.
just being right here,
watching them like where they can have a
baby right there and they won't even
fuck with you.
Wow.
And like huge lizards and underwater.
The densIty of the underwater sea life
was insane.
Hammerhead sharks.
I think a baby hammerhead shark is the
cutest animal I've ever seen.
a baby hammerhead like this.
Why the why they developed their eyes
out there on the end site that
presumably it's like an echo location or
or radar sonar type of thing.
It gives you better range I think
because they are in darker waters.
If I had to guess,
they're
really,
really cool to see in person though.
There's nothing like a hammerhead shark.
Isn't the galapagos where they had that
thing that they were doing with judas
goats?
Do you know that?
Yes.
That is it.
The goats.
Wait.
Oh,
captain cook dropped off a bunch of
goats on those islands and they did it
so that when they came back they'd have
something to hunt and the goats go over.
Ran the island and they.
Oh yeah,
that was a big problems.
They're eating everything and then
everything in sight.
And then what did they do with the
judas?
The judas goes,
had like a disease or something.
Oh no,
no,
they,
they took one of them and they say they
neutered him and then they sent him out
with a radio collar on.
So he find out where all their other
goats are.
They would gunned them down.
HelIcopters and they would keep him
alive.
They would go,
that's the judas goat.
We keep him alive.
So they've got all these goods down
here,
will move,
kill all,
make,
makes,
move rooms.
And he would go and make some new
friends and then they would locate that
new path because otherwise it's very
difficult to locate packs that goats,
if you're really going to put a dent in
the population,
they wanted to wipe them all out.
Yeah,
there was they,
they killed like 75,000
goats.
It was a crazy number of goats,
but they were completely overruNning the
whole the whole thing.
Well,
yeah,
train sharpshooters from we're sending
helicopters.
Scoured goats once found the goatS would
be shot from the air,
either in the head of the heart to
ensure a quick death,
whatever,
using the stop lying.
They never caught him in the arm.
Yes shot in the face.
They shot him everywhere.
They could there in a helicopter.
You not even a steady.
Go back to that place so I can keep
reading.
Let me you know they're not even in a
steady place where they can steadily
shoot.
You don't have a good rest from fucking
hell.
They had mini guns.
Gun in those fuckers down.
Why lie like that in the heart or in the
head to ensure clicked around using high
powered weapons and military precision.
Stop with your military precision who
wrote this?
Many people,
including the plans orchestrators,
had Misgivings about such a large scale
slaughter of goats.
Whoever the decision was made that the
galapagos ecosystem under the threat and
under threat found nowhere else on earth
was valuable enough to justify their
actions.
Yeah,
there are invasive species.
History was written by the winners.
It's just.
It's funny.
It's funny that they're essentially
preparing for people who are animal
rights activists writing this.
That's why they're writing,
you know,
they're shooting them with such
precision.
It's actually very funny because you
know,
to the galapagos is ridiculously
restrictive.
You cannot set foot on a beach like
there without being like without a
naturalist with you the whole time and
you can't be more than like 50 feet from
the naturalistic ever.
HOw'd you guys do it?
Did you hire someone to organized a
thing?
It was a smallish yacht with like 30
people on it.
I heard they check your shoes to make
seeds and you rinse off the bottom of
your shoes and then they hand sanitize
you when you get back on the boats.
They said they've had real issues with
people that have tramped on on plants
and then come to the galapagos.
Now those plants grow there.
Yeah.
Well,
there's one island that has,
I was expecting tropical,
right,
because hawaii's kind of tropical,
none of them plants fucking native.
the ne like none of them.
All the jungle plants were brought
there.
Like the galapagos has one island that
has jungle on it and all of the rest of
them are like volcanic rock and cactuses
and shrubs.
Yeah.
NoT what I expected.
And I was like,
how come this island has a jungle on it?
And the rest of them they said,
oh,
all these plants are not native.
They were all brought here.
And like the 17 hundreds.
Yeah.
Wow.
So the plants that were brought there,
like those plants.
Whoa.
Look at that shit.
But I don't.
I'm not sure what that is.
I never saw that.
But it's awesome.
That looks like an artist's rendering to
me.
We're looking at this crazy tree that
looks like it's right out of the lord of
the rings.
Dragon's blood tree is what it's called.
That's an awesome name for that.
Want that shit in my yard.
And we got a big building here.
Can we get one of those?
Need a dragon blood tree in my life.
Look at that thing that looks like
avatar island that floats.
Remember that one that floated.
But uh,
it's the greatest looking tree I've ever
seen.
It was very cool tree.
It's a weird economy,
but the same naturalists that were like,
you know,
preserve everything are giddy when they
talk about shooting goats from a
helicopter.
Yeah.
Well they,
they,
they look at the goats is what they
really are.
They're an invasive species.
I mean there life lifeforms and the,
it's not their fault that they're there,
but like I was trying to explain to my
friend.
I have a buddy of mine who's a thinking
about hunting.
He eats meat and he's like,
if I,
if I'm not going to kill my own meat,
like why should I,
why should I have the right to eat meats
and this weird moral thing?
And he's like,
I'm thinking about being vegan,
but I know it's not the right move for
my health.
I'm like,
we should try it.
See if it's the right move for your
health.
It might work good for your body,
but if you want to shoot something,
the thing to shoot would be wild pigs
because they have three,
four litters a year.
Each one of them,
they get at four,
five,
even six babies and they fuck like crazy
and they eat everything and then they
might be four or 500 pounds.
Then they can get big kill one of them,
one of those a year.
You're golden mean,
but they get fucking.
The point is they they,
they get destructive and there's nothing
that kills them.
Where do you find these wild pigs?
Everywhere.
They're all over the country now.
I don't hunt joe.
Where's?
It's not even.
It's not even a hunting issue.
It's people live in san jose or have a
problem with wild pigs going through
your backyard and fucking theM up.
Yeah.
It's a real issue because because no
one's paid attention to them.
People are getting their highway,
getting going to school,
stopping at starbucks,
doing the normal shit while this is
happening.
They're out there In the bush,
earn it that fucking,
and they're making babies and there's a
shit ton of placement all over from
bakersfield on up.
Northern California filled with wild
pigs.
Are they tasting to that?
Are they taste like they taste like
domestic pigs currently exist in 56 of
the state's 58 counties.
Wow.
Yeah.
Where's that?
What state is that?
California,
California.
Fifty six of the state's 58 counties of
wild pigs.
Okay,
so when you say everywhere,
you're not fucking around.
No,
they are a biological plague.
They're completely invasive species and
they're designed to live in places with
wolves and lions and I mean that's what
their origins are.
What do they taste?
Good.
Phenomenal.
Really better.
Like domestic pork.
Great.
Yeah.
Especially when you cook them,
right?
Like you take a ham and you like slow
smoker.
Yeah.
Brian,
it made me for a few days.
First dude,
I'm telling you,
god damn delicious.
Not surprisingly delicious plAgue.
They're everywhere and they eat
everything.
Ground nesting birds like fucking
anything on the ground.
They just,
they're just all the time.
We're fucking up people'S lawns,
digging in people.
Anybody who just want to be ready,
you just,
someone's paid,
they have habit things be locked and
loaded in your yard and will in Texas
they just shoot them.
I mean,
theY did get into helicopters.
They have the helicopters.
Yeah,
I was,
I was at a thing and a guy was telling
me about shooting pigs from a
helicopter.
There you go.
A pork lIps now is what you want to look
up a guy named.
it's not a porno.
No,
no.
Should it be?
Probably is too.
But It's a guy named pig man.
Uh,
who I'm buddies with this guy a text or
text each other.
I know him.
You and peg texts me and I text him
back.
I was like,
okay,
it's crazy.
He's a good dude.
But anyway,
he um,
he's,
his whole thing is eradicating these
wild pigs.
They did them with 10 new gen or they're
shooting machine guns out of fucking
helicopter and they killed 200 and
something of them in one day.
30 feral hogs.
And now in 37 states,
look at this.
While this is a point $5,
billion in crop damage yearly.
I mean,
I liked the,
I like the anti pig propaganda film.
This was 6 million hogs in Texas alone.
Do you know how crazy that is?
And again,
delicious.
they've got a bunch of brucellosis and a
bunch of different terrible diseases.
So fuck ted nugent.
Well,
how dare you,
ted.
Ted nugent sucks.
Well he's definitely got issues.
Yes.
So they're up there with machine guns
gunning down these wild pigs out of
helicopters and parties.
Like They shouldn't be able to do this,
but party is like they have to do this
because if they don't do this then these
things keep breeding and there's more of
a.
They don't eradicate the numbers.
What's to stop these things from just
spreading across the entire country and
becoming a real problem?
well,
there already are a real problem.
So what do you do?
Which part of you goes that looks kind
of fun.
It looks the were very fun.
If it wasn't a life form,
it looks.
Yeah,
I would.
I would want to do that with like
targets.
Like do they,
can they do that and put one nba tarGets
out there?
Fun.
You'd you'd want to do it with,
but the thing is like you see a mama and
her babies and I mean it's the whole
thing is it's kind of fucked up because
there's not a whole lot of other ways to
do this.
Here's the thing,
it's like you got to locate them on
these enormous ranches,
so what are you going to do?
You're going to have people go out there
with a,
you know,
hunting camps and slowly make their way
through the bushes or in that they would
might kill 250 of them in a month or
these guys get $250 an argument.
The efficiency of this process.
This is extremely efficient.
It is an epidemic.
Don't mean What they're saying is
accurate.
You seeiNg all these pigs,
I mean look at the populations that
these guys are gunning down and this is
just a fraction of what exists is the
shot right there.
That was like right out of the
godfather,
the pig hanging from a helicopter.
The helicopter.
Look at that.
Oh me,
that freeze frame on ted nugent's face
was an extra creepy coming.
Wait on a real show.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
this was a goof.
I know.
Real real.
Oh my God.
Poor calypso pork lips.
His episodes on pigmenTs show by so.
But you see as a peRson who loves
animals and he also eats meat.
I understand conflict.
You know I love animals.
I love wild animals.
I love pets.
I love them,
but I also eat meat and they do too.
There's a weird relationship going on
with people and animals,
but that to me in modern world is one of
the weirder aspects.
Flying around a helicopter gunning down
feral pigs that destroy cop crops caused
billions of dollars in damage and are
spreading across the entire country.
What else do you do know?
It just seems so unfair,
tara.
One hundred percent unfair,
but the question is,
is it unfair if you're jogging through
the woods and a bear,
he you.
is that unfair?
that seems unfair to probably also
unfair.
I mean,
you barely levels of unfair,
barely able to just sustain a nice pace
and go jogging.
If yOu've got to rustle up there,
just trying to drop a few lbs.
Sit man,
I didn't want to get eaten this grizzly.
Fucking nowhere.
I don't know man.
We got to.
We have weirD relationships with
animals.
You know,
I know you eat meat.
I do.
Obviously I don't feel too guilty about
it either.
I don't eat meat from the grocery store
and I don't feel too guilty about it.
I'm sorry to say.
Well I'm.
Yeah,
that's fuckIng life.
What do you,
do you feel bad about factory farming?
I try to buy good quality meat from good
quality places and.
But that's the,
that's about,
I don't know.
I like farm raised fish and you know,
Try and buy good shit if I can.
I prefer to eat high quality things,
you know,
but I don't know.
She talked about cars more.
Yep.
Do we want to.
Do you want to end?
Yeah.
What else is,
what else are you seeing?
And if we just had.
We just got.
We stumbled into a,
an area of dead animals and this is your
show.
So that's what,
that's what's going to happen.
I didn't mean to bring it there,
but this,
this is when I get to talk to you.
So what are you going to do a.
So it happens.
Um,
I'll tell you what I'm interested in,
man.
I'm interested in that new corvette.
Zr one going to drive it next week on
monday and tuesday at road atlanta.
That thing looks ridiculous.
Seven hundred and 50 horsepower.
See,
that's what I'm talking about.
When are they going to stop?
I think thousand horsepower and a in a
regular car that people can buy in
China.
Yes.
Yeah.
You know what,
we'll probably do it first actually.
Um,
in terms of like a quote,
regular car with a thousand horsepower
would probably be electric,
like an electric car because it's so
easy to make that power,
to look at that.
It's aggressive.
Holy shit.
That's aggressive.
And you see they had to put this
monster,
a power bulge in the hood there.
Center.
Um,
so,
you know,
this corvette zero six was out before
and it was very fast,
650 horsepower,
but it had this issue where it was heat
soaking a wherein like it was you lose
power because the supercharger would
develop so much heat,
um,
and it was a small supercharger to fit
under the low hood because every,
the low hood is sort of a thing for
corvette and the way to make more power
while also creating less heat is to use
a bigger supercharger and spin it slower
as opposed to a smaller one that spun
faster.
So they had to put a bigger one,
which also,
which raises the hood.
So you fuck with,
you don't know yet a even drIven,
it was going to say your,
your vantage point,
your viewpoint.
I don't know,
I,
I'll report back you put that couple of
weeks,
but I think it's definitely a big,
a big old cow hood.
I have driven,
um,
there's a company called callaway.
You've heard of them?
Yes.
They modify the wing back to that image
that you just had.
The uh,
the aero package is certainly
aggressive.
Look at that thing.
Yeah,
it's a beast.
Yeah.
That looks so good.
So I've.
I have driven,
have a corvette of this generation that
has an engine like this and I can see
that drove something called the callaway
arrow wagon.
They actually turned a corvette into
like a shooting brake,
like a wagon.
Oh god.
It's not that bad.
It's pretty cool.
But it had 775 horsepower and it was one
of the scariest cars I've ever driven
that side profile,
that look,
you can get it as a convertible.
Wow.
That's amazing.
Zero one is a convertible.
They do anything to extra.
Stiffen it up.
They actually,
the reason they do this is they say that
the roof itself is not a contributor
towards the chassis rigidity,
so they can sell the car as a coupe or
convertible without any loss of
rigidity.
That's what they say thing drives like.
Honestly,
I think you're a douche if you buy a car
one convertible.
Wow.
How dare you.
Because you're just thinking about
binding by the coop and take the roof
off.
You can buy the coop and take the hard
roof rafters.
That's not the same.
It's not the same.
It is because you don't like a douche.
Convertibles for douchebags,
the fa,
the top performing corvette engine track
package
with an aero kit in a convertible.
Go back to that picture of the red
convertible again,
jamie,
the people who suck.
How dare you.
Who you son of a bItch.
what are you doing with the top down and
outgoing,
amazing wing look and like a planning.
Can you break down what's your verdict?
Convertible,
convertible,
tsl.
Music and letting people know.
in this instance were you driving with
was with you.
You just by yourself.
Just you and me.
By yourself.
It's not to the no convertible.
If you're a girl.
Oh,
okay.
For us to know convertible.
Yeah.
We look desperate out there by herself
in a convertible and the convertible is
weird.
That's a good point.
A guy and a girl.
That's a very good point.
So in the convertible is still weird.
It's still weird for you in 2018.
Well not there,
but any convertible to guys in any
convertible.
It's weird.
So what do you losers doing?
Real men don't put the top down by
yourself.
Yes.
You can tell somebody.
I'm just driving around.
You know,
you can tell someone's a real bad
driver.
That's a really surefire way to tell
someone's a terrible driver.
If they've got a convertible and it's
like a and they put the windows down,
but the front windows go down in a
little back.
Windows stay up lIke a three series bmw
where they don't notice those little
rear windows are just still up by
themselves.
That's how you can tell someone's a bad
driver.
Never checks their blind spots.
Well,
even when you drive it in a convertible
with the windows up like stop for is
even worse.
Two guys in the back too.
Oh,
that's in venice.
I see that.
I see all the convertible mustangs
loaded up.
When I see that,
I always look at those four guys and
like one of those guys dead weight
guaranteed.
One of those guys that paIn in the ass.
Three of them hating the other.
Yeah.
One of those guys always short on how
much he puts in for the tab.
It's funny,
one of those guys,
and you never pay every two weeks when
I'm doing better.
I'll pay man.
Fuck you.
That looks so good though.
Pull that picture up again.
It's really good.
That looks amazing.
Red with black that,
that [inaudible] convertible debt.
It's fucking amazing dude.
And it's apparently faster around
Virginia international raceway than the
ford gt,
which we just looked at and the ford gt
is like a race car,
race car.
this thing as like a big trunk and you
know,
it's a,
for all intents and purposes,
it's pretty normal car.
That's awesome.
I like how it's not,
you know,
it's not,
there's not a lot of sacrifice going on
with driving one of those,
you know,
you,
you get in it,
you drive it and it's got a big trunk
and freezing them comfortable and easy
to live with.
But It's interesting that this is like
this game of like,
okay,
let's look at watches.
There's no real improvement in
performance.
Right?
I mean they're beautiful and.
But I mean the performance difference
between now and 10 years ago is not
clear.
Yeah.
And a mechanical watch to know.
I mean it's such,
there's artistry and there's
technological complication.
I mean it's,
there's complication for the sake of
complications.
So they'll have watches like to use the
car example,
imagine a car.
Okay.
And from the outside it looks roughly
like a normal car,
right?
For four wheels,
don't the driver's seat,
right?
It has one engine and it has for
transmissions coming off of that engine,
all of which come back together to make
it the car.
One wheel drive,
[inaudible] right.
Imagine that applied to a watch.
So it'll be like one main movement that
goes out into four gear trains and then
comes back into just an hour and a
minute hand.
well why would you sync up for gear
trains when you could do the same thing
with one?
And it's like,
well,
because we can,
it would be like building a car with two
engines.
Like that's not smart,
but you do it.
Just be like god built the fucking car
with two engine less.
You're talking about like the nsx
engine,
we have the front engine electric.
Exactly,
exactly.
But I think what I'm getting at is that
with computers and with cars,
those are the one thing that you expect
and improvement every year.
Yeah,
just that nobody's going to accept the
old way.
You can't just build unless your singer
and you make something custom.
Well that's that the singer is what that
example was,
what the mechanical watch kind of
industry is,
you know,
they,
they position it as a luxury item from a
time gone by sort of thing,
you know.
Whereas actually if you want to talk
about innovation,
this right here is a grand seiko which
has a movement called a spring drive
movement in it.
And it is one of the most advanced and
unique mechanical movements available in
a watch today.
So this is a seiko.
It's a grand seiko,
which is.
So the difference is,
uh,
it's like,
think about a lexis.
Think about alexis.
A seiko is a lexus,
not a toyota.
This is a lexus.
Lfa.
A grand seiko is built in a different
factory from the regular seikos.
It's built by hand,
completely by hand,
all hand finished,
hand polished.
It's built of exotic materials.
It has a cool movement.
Do you should sell watches,
watch podcasts,
watching,
listening.
It's on youtube,
but yeah,
I mean I have what is called the display
back on this.
You can see the movement in the back and
how high the level of finishes and
you've got sapphire and titanium and um,
so the spring drive movement is without
getting crazy,
crazy nerdy about it.
Is,
is actually a true innovation in
mechanical watchmaking.
So run the chronograph is on the front.
The top button not here to watch the
sweep of the coronagraph hand.
The big secondhand.
you get a perfectly smooth sweep.
The smoothest possible sweep that there
be.
It is smooth.
It is,
it is,
it is.
How much is the website?
This worth around?
10,000.
Amazing.
Yeah.
God.
But it's just watch $300.
Well that's no g shocks are the shit
dude.
300 bucks.
G shocks are awesome as far as that of a
light.
No,
but it hasn't been,
but it's polished so that it can see in
the dark.
The date.
Motherfucker.
Look dude,
geez.
Shocks are dope.
A g shock is a watch guys.
Tool watch,
like highly functional,
durable.
I'm a g shock is a total watch.
Guys watch.
You can get gi shocks that are like
$5,000.
You know what?
Yeah,
they have dude.
Jamie,
look up a $5,000
here.
Hold that up.
That's shawn martin.
Wards own design.
It's cool.
I thiNk it's based on the duesberg.
Yeah.
Duesenberg gauge cLuster.
The watch is called the doozy and it's
got a complication on it called a jump.
Our complicaTion,
so the.
It's a basically just the black face
almost looks like a bathroom scale and
it's got two windows.
Ours on top minutes on the bottom and
the minutes sweep by slowly.
Whereas the hours do not sweet by slowly
at 59 and 59 seconds.
The hours click over write fast.
So it's a jump power as opposed to a
slow moving our.
Now he designed the look or did he
design the internals?
He designed the look,
the face,
the complications and he worked with a
swiss watchmaker to design an actual
unique movement to use for this watch.
He designed the case and that's crazy.
It is awesome.
And that watch is 12 grand and he's
making 50 of them.
I believe it.
Yeah.
He tried to use the face in that vantaa
black shit.
What does that.
Vanna black is the darkest.
The blackest black that has ever
existed.
Oh,
I saw they painted a building with.
It looks like it looks like a negative
space.
Dude.
Get a picture of vanna black.
It doesn't look real and it's the most
black that,
that,
that.
That's something painted in atlanta.
Black so black that it absorbs all light
and you can't even wait to see anything.
Can you paint a car in that you could
accept in the environmentally?
It's not.
It's not a good thing.
Hey,
fuck the penguins or whoever's gonna die
apparently to makes black g wagon,
bro.
Fuck bro.
I need my g wagon ventilation in the
event of black friend.
The black has the vantage has vantaa
black in.
Of course it does.
You'll see it's $95,000.
And the vantaa black is just the black
background.
When you said $95,000.
My balls made my balls go like this.
They went,
bro.
They got watches that are a million
dollars.
What does a million dollars?
You can buy a million dollar watches
right now.
300 bucks.
G shock do it.
There's a watch called the jacob a
stratta mia.
That is like wearing like a sapphire
fishbowl on your fucking hand.
I swear.
it's the craziest shit you've ever seen.
So rIdiculous.
It's like liberace.
The oil sheet.
That jamie top right picture there.
See this as a gold case?
That's a sapphire case.
The whole thing.
So what if you bump into something and
shattered her hand?
That's so stupid.
You are in a glass,
not glass.
it's sapphire cinderella mother.
The whole case is milled from a block of
sapphire case can go fuck itself.
Seriously.
It's a million dollars.
You deserve.
You deserve that thing to break.
That's crazy looking.
It's hilarious,
right?
That's a million dollar watch.
Yeah,
earth is the earth.
The or the planets are spinning around,
spinning around and you can find a video
of it thing.
It's nuts.
Look at the stars.
Oh,
it's kinda like a role of you drove your
rolls royce.
It would match our wash.
You'd be like,
what?
What?
You could coordinate this guy with your
starfield ceiling to dan is a small
earth that's crazy and it literally has
the continents and silver and then some
blue star thing.
What Is the water made out of?
You think scott would be like,
I'm gonna die of something.
But then there's a diamond,
a son on the other side of my god,
there's a ball diamond ball that spins.
Some of them have different,
different,
uh,
stuff on them too.
That's just $1.
You have to be to be sporting a million
dollar water.
That one's got out and checked.
The town's got a central.
Let me check the time on my million
dollar mother fucking watch.
It's crazy,
right?
That's crazy.
Yeah.
There's some rich people doing some
really,
really weird rich people things right
now.
That seems preposterous.
That thing with all the diamonds on the
baguette diamonds,
that's like some steam,
punk,
futuristic,
but like,
it's,
it's weird.
It's even more so than you know,
cars.
It's like because a car,
it's like,
okay,
you got a thousand dollar car,
kept $10,000,
car $100,000
car,
but when you zoom in really close,
that's the computer version because
that's not,
oh,
it's cgi,
but that is pretty much what you get to
see the astrological signs there.
Oh my god.
What is that red made out of that amber
or something?
Oh,
probably ruby.
The sons of ruby.
It's probably ruby.
The sun's probably a yellow diamond
motherfucker.
That is incredible.
I don't get it,
but I get it.
I mean,
you must be able to appreciate that
someone is making a machine that fits in
a little fish bowl on your wrist.
Look at that dragon and look.
I mean look on top of the crazy artistry
of this and the ridiculous price and the
jewels and all that stuff.
The mathematics of that machine work
that is not.
That's not just like that for nothing.
that does like moon phase.
You know the what sign astrological sign
is.
There is an actual function.
look at that one with the dragon in it.
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
Don't say something that come out of a
little kid's gumball machine.
So crazy.
Right?
Go scroll up.
That's amazing.
Look and scroll up.
The other images though that they had
those three watches together.
Do you ever look how good those things
look?
I mean that is.
That is a crazy thing to have on your
arm.
It's so crazy,
right?
That that's a million dollars and if you
see someone wearing one in person,
it's big.
It's,
it's like,
it's like the size of that back.
Any lid,
a coffee mug and your hands.
It's so big.
They're actually.
I mean you'd be shocked at what people
are doing with certain with machinery
and wanton mechanical watchmaker would
be received.
It's like the fight against friction is
the whole thing,
right?
you've got this tiny little spring and
you need to get as much power out of it
as possible.
So they engineered these like micro
grams of friction out of this stuff.
So they.
They are work star trek and a whoa,
that's pretty.
Yeah,
I think that is the lid liquids closed.
It looks like a star trek communicator
now.
How much does something like that go
for?
Probably 50 or 60.
Oh,
sorry,
I was going to get higher.
I was going to get 75.
I think you can get different versions
of it that are.
Don't hold me to the price.
It's expensive,
but whAt do you think it cost jamie
tayga?
Yeah,
that's what I was saying.
70th five.
That's top.
The top article should have it.
The hoa dinky article usually has a
price.
If you scroll dowN to the bottom of that
article,
it should have it.
That's it.
Closed right there.
So you can read the time when it's
closed on that watch.
It's eight.
A 27?
Yeah.
And what does it look like when it's
closed?
Go,
go up.
That's close.
That's closed.
Yeah.
And then that's another version of
different tops.
The clear top or the the or the metallic
one and then there's a carbon back and
that's a pretty watch.
Yeah,
it's pretty looking.
If you scroll all the way down,
it should say the price.
No,
68,000.
There you go.
Fucking expensive.
It's.
There's some wild stuff.
There's a company called h y t that is,
that makes watches that have a liquid
that moves around and it tells you the
time based on like almost like a
thermometer.
The liquid goes up to this level.
There's a watched by a company called
devin,
d e v o n that's a belt driven watch
where you have like a series of conveyor
belts on your wrist.
Yeah,
there's the h yet.
So the green,
the green liquid goes around the dial.
It's like a nuclear ooze that like flows
through the dial.
Yeah,
it,
it changes depending upon the time.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
So that,
that goo,
like it flows.
Go back to the one with the green goop
on the top left there.
So fills up around the dial.
And then is when it goes all the way
around.
Is it a minute?
Ain't no,
it's an hour.
It's awesome.
Right?
That's amazing.
Look down and that's how you know where
it is in the outline and then it had,
it had a typical hour hand.
yeah.
And then this one,
it flows around the skull to food.
You actually have something like that
cost 100 grand or something.
Actual rose is actually sponsored by
them.
Believe it or not.
It works,
right?
It's on brand for him.
I think this is about a hundred grand.
So when you say sponsored,
like what do they do to get axle to
where you just were?
Yeah,
he wears one.
Yeah.
I follow these dumb watch spotter
instagram accounts and they sell for
upwards of 50,000.
So I think,
I think it's more than that.
$50.
Seventy five.
They're expensive,
man.
It's David Cross selling watches.
Two hundred and $85,000
to eight slash three particular ultra
light.
High end model.
Which one's that one?
But it's,
there's,
you know,
there's some materials in this stuff.
They use crazy forged carbon.
There was um,
95 grand used for a skull one.
Yep.
Ooh,
let me see that.
that's pretty.
Yeah,
they're real crazy.
I mean it's,
you can Get lost in this stuff.
I mean the,
the machinery of it and the materials.
do you think the liquid is that goes
around that fuck?
I don't know.
They may have a different picture with a
different liquid,
so that's how the minutes go.
Yeah,
and then there was an hour is so crazy.
Press that.
Let's see if this works.
Here's the liquors.
The liquid going.
So cool.
That is fucking dope.
I love the fact that people are so
creative.
They can figure out how to do things
like this on something like a watch.
So you look at the blue,
the red googling around the skull.
Isn't that awesome?
Oh my god.
I'm in love with it.
It's so cool.
it's amazing.
I'm in love with this and then look at
it goes back,
but it goes back quick.
It goes back quick and resets.
Oh yeah.
Fill up when it goes back.
Oh you got to be kidding.
Oh my god.
There's some really next level,
like there's bellows and pumps and it's
like pumping liquid around dude.
Right?
I had no idea.
Yeah,
I had no idea people were doing this to
other people are doing crazy things that
is fucking like on a more.
So that's really crazy.
He'S like,
so I have a watch that is called the
perpetual calendar.
Which is like a traditional complicated
watch,
so it does day of the week,
date of the month,
month of the year,
four digit year,
moon phase,
power reserve.
Okay.
And the time obviously.
And it has all of those functions and
you,
if you keep the watch running,
you know it's a mechanical,
you gotta keep it wound up.
if you keep it wound and running,
it will be accurate for all of those
things without needing any adjustment
for about 300 years.
Like leap years.
How many days are in the month that
you're in?
Like all of that shit.
Yeah.
I iwc propecia,
big pilot,
perpetual calendar.
I'd like a watch that looks like that.
Like a classic looking either the big
pilot perpetual calendar.
I liked their watches.
Iwc,
they make beautiful watches that are
like that right there.
To me that's like a perfect look and
walk.
I like normal location.
Big pilot.
Uh yeah,
like one.
Is it orange?
Hands down.
That's it.
But go down one on the left,
bottom left or yeah,
that's the one.
Wow.
So it does.
It's got a lot going on.
That's the one I have that's a beautiful
wife and it's big.
It's big and chunky and heavy,
but you see it scott,
four digit year and then the month at
the,
at the 6:00
Mark Day of the week and the second hand
at 9:00
and then the date and the power reserve
at the 3:00
and if you keep that running that'll
give you june,
third,
2018 friday,
you know,
whatever.
Automatically it knows all the math.
Hundreds of years.
Wow.
Crazy.
Right.
All you have to do is keep it running,
just keep it running so you have to just
put it in a perpetual watch machine
where it or where it.
Fortunately I like wearing it and it has
an eight day power reserve,
so if I wear it one day out of every
eight days,
it's great.
Oh,
so it has a battery assist?
No,
no.
The sprinG.
We'll keep going for eighT days.
Yeah,
yeah.
Eight days.
And then you see in the the inneR gauge
at the 3:00
position it says days seven,
six,
five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
This one's dead.
It's an emptY gauge,
but normally it stays up by the des in
days when it's full and it shows you how
much is left.
This one,
this watch has a.
Has a fuel gauge as well.
This is mechanical.
Yes.
He looked right down here at the 7:00
position.
That watch has a fuel gauge as well.
Very helpful.
It's crazy.
My favorite feature and mechanical
watches.
The fuel gauge,
is that an actual fuel icon?
It looks like.
Kind of.
Yeah,
it does.
Kinda look like.
wow.
Wow.
That's dope.
So watches.
I have a podcast about all this called
watch and listen with.
I do it with a watchmaker who like to
take shit apart.
Cameron weiss,
he's the man.
Watches are connected to like extreme
materialism and a lot of people's eyes
like they don't.
Totally.
Yeah.
It's one of those thinGs like,
oh god,
you're in The watches.
Like he must be a do.
Totally.
It's a faiR argument because watches are
so are used as trophies and flashy shit
and.
But they're also cool.
They're all so cool.
Yeah.
it's like that is true.
I feel with cars.
I mean,
look,
if you is every person who buys a
ferrari,
la ferrari,
is every one of those people a whole a
douche?
No,
some are and some are represented.
The ultimate enthusiasts.
Seventy five might be fifth now it might
be 50.
It could be know there's,
there's enthusiastic and there's dishes
in everything,
in everything.
And the thing is those,
there's a reason why those things are
highly coveted because they're fucking
amazing.
Yeah.
You know that watch,
I don't want a million dollar watch,
but that watches the shit.
I
would never wear it if I had to do it.
If you're in beverly hills,
go in the store.
The jacobs store in beverly hills
frisked through the fucking tsa thing on
here,
right?
Yeah.
I'm sure they must be really worried
about people walking into that store and
you got to get buzzed in and do you
really fuck you dude.
You could smash and grab like $6,000,000
in appraising.
Somebody just did that recently in
england.
they smashed and grabbed a watch store
with machetes.
Yeah,
because you know there's this thiNg in
england going on right now.
I don't know if you know it,
but they have london haS for the first
time ever passed the United States,
uh,
passed a New York city rather for the
most murders.
Really?
Yeah.
Ever since he was a stabbing each other
and stabbing each other.
So the london mayor,
mayor of london on twitter wrote a tweet
that has been getting him tortured
online saying there is no reason to have
a knife.
If I saw that knife,
you will be pr.
We catch you,
you,
you regular guy.
Regular guy.
I open packages.
I carry a knife.
I want to cut a piece of rope.
I have a knife on me.
He said,
okay.
Not anymore.
No.
In london,
this guy saying if you have a knife and
you're caught with one,
you'll be prosecuted to the fullest
eXtent of the law.
And of course United States were going
crazY over here.
Like,
oh.
So I thought it was a gun problem.
That was a fucking gun problem.
You got a band?
Nice.
What's next?
Fucking scissors you can do.
What are you going?
Where's this going to end?
Yeah,
I do have to think that.
I think we have a little bit of a gun
problem.
We definitely have an issue problem.
We definitely have something going on,
but this smash and grab these
motherfuckers use machetes.
That's gangster gangster knew nobody had
a gun.
He tried to use a machete and dudes
behind the counter of shotguns.
Real problem.
It was a homemade machete,
a homemade machete.
Well,
how do they know It's homemade?
Because they caught the guy that says
I'll made caught up in my house right
here.
Good for good for you.
I guess he didn't get away.
No good attempt.
Yeah.
But it's again,
watches,
like when you think about something
small like jewelry and watches,
something that's this little on
something you fit in your hand can be
worth a million dollars.
It's only things in life where something
that fits in your hand is worth a
million dollars.
Yeah.
And there's also a lot of the mainstream
brands like rolex and whatever,
there's a lot of um,
a false prop up of the value.
They intentionally,
you know,
they don't build as many submariners as
they could because they want to drive
the market up demand up and it keeps the
used values high and there's this,
there's an entire ecosystem,
you know,
based on new and used watch values and
yeah,
well I think the craziest value thing in
anything of like high end things that
people love is diamonds because they're
not even really that rare anymore.
It didn't.
I just read you can make them in the
microwave now.
It's not a thing.
I'm like,
I read an article,
they figured out how to make diamonds
and I'm like,
how do they do that?
The same way they can make them in a
lap.
Someone figured out a process carbon and
keep,
you know,
when they make them in a lab,
it's really interesting.
I don't think they can make really big
ones in a lab yet.
I think they're gonna only make like one
or two carrots.
I might be wrong.
I would definitely be down with getting
cremated and being turned into a
diamond.
Here it goes.
Scientists figured out a way to make
diamonds and a microphone and it could
change the diamond industry.
Oh shit.
It's over bitches.
April ninth just happened.
oh yeah.
I read this article and I just noticed
now it's business insider.
I don't trust them.
Look at this.
Yeah.
Placing a tiny fragment of a diamond,
a carbon seat in the microwave with
varying amounts of carbon heavy gas.
The result is a synthetic ethical
diamond with the exact same structure
and chemical compositions.
That diamond that came from the ground
works so weLl.
Experts reportedly need machines to tell
the lab grown gems apart from the
natural ones estimated by 2026.
The number of lab made diamonds will
skyrocket to 20 million carats.
So then here's the thinG,
anyone who owns a naTuRal diamond,
that diamond is now in the toilet or you
think so will be like,
this is natural.
The shit came from.
What if they can't tell the difference
though?
You go to a machine like this,
motherfucker's got a machine who's got a
machine would want to know.
They would want to know.
I need to know is it machine certified
that it came out of the ground?
I don't know.
Is this blood diamonds?
I only want blood diamonds.
I got engaged a few months ago and I
should.
Thank you and I got a great deal from
somebody who I nicknamed.
Blood diamond is not a blood diamond,
I assure you,
but I just love calling him blood and he
gets very upset.
Can you just fucking stop it?
I don't want to wear this thing around
blood diamond.
Yeah.
Well that's the thing too.
It's like they've got that business on
lock down.
Do you want to prove your love and your
commitment to the relationship?
Well,
you need to buy one of these.
You can't buy out a fucking a car.
Nope.
You can't buy her an engagement car.
I tried to do that.
Actually.
I was going to propose with an
engagement jeep wagon here.
That's a good move.
It was until they get mad at you and
you're the one that they want the
diamond show their friends.
Matt stepped up asap.
That clarity.
It's amazing.
He's tapped that.
Did mike step up?
Mike didn't step up.
Matt stepped up,
mike did step up.
Mike's like,
fuck dude.
Fucking dorm.
Dual thieves throw.
No thought,
really worked up,
bro.
Just need a cz.
If a girl found out that you had a fake
diamond,
that was the thing that happened to an
aunt of mine.
she found out she found her.
Diane was fake.
She was getting divorced and she went to
bring her ring in.
She found out it was fake.
Don trump gave someone fake diamond
cufflinks.
Who was that?
Somebody.
Someone in business.
He gave him a pair of diamond cufflinks
and he went and looked and they were
fucking ccs.
If that's the case,
if he did that to you,
that guy's ready to fuck you.
He's.
He's about to go down.
Mueller,
mueller,
steam,
and right now fucking fake diamonds.
You don't respect me,
mr.
To trump.
Well,
I don't respect you.
Jump is fake.
Diamond cufflinks for years.
Oh my god.
He's hilarious.
Do they shrink his hands for those
pictures on purpose?
Because his hands aren't little.
Everybody was caused his hands.
Little.
There's something he does with his hands
that make them look a little.
It's like he does a lot of stuff like
this is like he brings a little in
proportion to his head,
which is gigantic and getting bigger.
Apparently poor.
He's,
he's going down now.
When they raided his,
uh,
his attorney's offices,
here's the thing that to,
in order to get all that stuff pass
through,
republicans have to agree to that.
Yeah.
Like there'S like in order to like
actual republicans and people that
should be.
His supporters had to be a part of that.
Everyone that's signed,
it was an appointee of his
administration.
He's in trouble.
If they're rating your lawyers office,
you are so fucked.
And if it all goes down that he winds up
getting in trouble.
Not even for Russia,
but for paying off a chick that he had
sex with.
Imagine it's a porn chick that takes
this whole thing down.
Listen man,
I need.
Oh justin martindale and apology.
He was saying that she's the monica
lewinsky for,
for this administration.
Oh,
come on.
No way.
He's going to brush this off.
It's going to be nothing.
Nobody cares because everybody knows,
they know we did it,
so it's not.
It's not even a question of whether he
did it right,
but it's a matter of whether or not it's
legal.
The camp.
Yeah.
It's a campaign finance violation
lawyer.
So yeah,
that that's a campaign finance pen.
Then admitting to knowing about the
payout is like obstruct admitting to
obstruction.
It's like a whole other.
When he talked about it in that
interview,
when someone caught him getting onto his
plane and he acknowledged the lawsuits.
Whoops.
Just he fucks up,
man.
He doesn't know how to shut the fuck up.
Not only that,
his whole life has been about not
shutting the fuck up about saying
whatever you want.
like that's his instincts and all of a
sudden you put them in this position
yet.
What's that?
I want you to be a totally different
thing.
Now I want you to be presidential.
Yeah.
You've always trying to pick fights with
joe biden on twitter.
You're not going to change a 70 year old
billionaire.
You're not going to change that guy.
He's been told yes a thousand times a
day floods.
Forty years.
Do you think's gonna happen with them?
oh,
do you think they're going to kick them
out?
Like what do you think?
Yeah,
I don't.
I think it's not going to.
I think it's,
I just don't see how he can make it
through for years.
I don't know.
It's only thing one year.
Yeah,
it's very bad.
While we've been going on,
Paul Ryan has announced that he's going
to not seek reelection.
Oh,
thank god.
Paul.
Ryan's probably sees the writing on the
wall.
Yeah.
What does that guy do?
And apparently he had some kind of
realistic challenger,
a democrat that has been really ramping
up their campaign and he does not want
to stick around to see how that's going
to go.
Really does want to lose.
he doesn't want to get humiliated,
you know?
Wow.
That's what it is.
You think?
Or maybe he's just tired of losing it.
No way.
Maybe needs to get paid for all those
fucking bribes.
Like now it's time saw today that uh,
the former speaker,
john banner is now on the board of a
major,
major marijuana legalization.
Shit.
Got to get that paper.
How do you feel about this legalization
situation?
I haTe it.
I hate it.
They should lock people up,
lock them up.
They're gettiNg high lock them up,
but compared to prop 2:15
compared to jet Seventeen to 18,
what do you think about it?
Well,
the 30 percent sales taX,
which was inevitable,
but this is what I like about that.
It's still reasonable.
You can get high on a very small amount
of money for a long period of time.
I don't think we should be complaining
about that too.
I think we could show that there's a
real benefit to legalization that
benefits communities,
benefit schools,
firemen,
police officers,
whoever can get that money.
I think that's where the money should be
allocated and I think you could get
billions of dollars for the state just
doing that and I think that is a real
positive aspect of legalization.
That might be the one thing that's going
to be the straw that breaks the camel's
back across the country.
When people realize that you can make
real money and that real money could be
beneficial to things that communities
need.
Plus you starve out illegal drug selling
illegal drugs.
Sellings with the real problem has
always been when you make something
illegal,
only criminals are going to sell it.
Then you have criminal mentality.
You have people that have guns and gangs
and those are the people that were
scared of not businesses.
Yeah.
If we were scared of businesses,
we'd be trying to close liquor stores.
Nobody gives a shit about wineries.
You know we're not.
Those are drugstores.
Have a winery,
is a drug dealer.
Are they liStened to you talking about
about wine?
You just sell delicious trucks and for
I'm 100 percent.
I love wine.
That's not my point.
My point is selling.
One thing should be legal.
Things should be legal and when
marijuana is legal,
tax the fucking shit out of it and give
that money back to the community and
everybody benefits.
People like you and I who were
responsible grown adults,
prepare taxes and are good people and
we'd like to get high occasionally that
we should be able to buy it with no
worry about being locked in a fucking
cage and that money should go to
schools.
That money should go to fix the streets.
That money should go to cops and
firemen.
That's what it should go do it that
makes that we know where it's being
allocated.
yeah.
I have no idea.
No idea.
I would hope it's.
here it goes.
I'm joining the board of anchorage
holdings holdings acreage.
Sorry,
because my thinking on cannabis has
evolved.
That's my man got high.
I was anti and then I got some of his
good shit right here.
I'm convinced dea scheduling the drug is
needed so that we could do research,
help our veterans and reverse the opiod
epidemic ravaging our communities.
Yes,
I agree man.
I would add to that.
Get high.
I'd say so we can get hot.
Put everyone out of jail.
Is there.
Is there evidence showing a weed reduces
opioid use?
It is,
right?
Um,
well it really depends upon how it's
used.
It can benefit some people with some
kind of paint.
I don'T think it's realistic to say that
some people that are in horrible,
horrible pain would get the same
reaction for marijuana to get for
opiates.
People with really bad burns,
for instance,
were there 24 slash seven addicted,
not for medical reasons.
I'm talking about if you're become
addicted to,
oh,
you know,
oxies,
there's better drugs,
there's better drugs that get you off.
Um,
there's quite a few that can help you.
Probably the most powerful in the most
efficient is a ibogaine because no one
like,
but no,
no,
no.
I began as non iowasca I was,
it is a hallucinogenic that is from
south America is dimethyltryptamine.
Ibogaine is from the boga tree and it's
a from breaking open the head that
there's a book called breaking.
I'm sure he did,
but ibogaine is like a roof and it's
something I haven't experienced.
I'm just talking out of what I've read.
Essentially a ruthlessly introspective
24 hour trip that rewires the way your
brain views addiction and has a high
level of effectiveness.
Interesting in rehabilitating people
like just killing the desire to do
opiates.
Are they doing that in America?
Mexico,
go to Mexico.
Can't go to America.
It's illegal in America.
Of course.
Is it like a sweat lodge sherman type
thing or is it a hospital?
Subsequent hospital type situations.
There's a.
My buddy ed clay runs a a,
I think he still does,
runs a clinic down in Mexico and he
started it because of his experiences
with pills.
He got hurt,
got on paIn pills and had a real hard
time with them.
Went to get on ibogaine to get off the
pain pills.
It worked like a charm and he was like,
holy shit,
I need to let people know about this.
You can get your life back and it's not
something you get addicted to.
It's apparently something that hard time
doing it again.
Yeah.
It's like it's rough.
It's like you go,
okay.
That was enough.
Like dmt.
Exactly.
It's one of those ones was enough.
He did it once in college and that was
sufficient.
You,
you can get a lot out of one.
Yeah.
I went.
I had a plaid plaid fucking world flying
around.
It was.
It was full out of body nuts.
Oh yeah.
It's pretty nuts.
Yeah.
I think the difference in ibogaine
versus dmt,
dmt is ego dissolving and very
hallucinogenic and you see these amazing
visualizations.
I began,
seems to not have that,
but instead be like deeply like to the
cellular level,
introspective and just an end.
there's some sort of a physical action
that happens in the way your brain,
the way your brain looks at addiction
changes pretty radically through it or
it just happens.
You should probably.
I think all of those things should be
done in places where people are going to
feel safe and where people have done it
before and where people have experience
with people that have done it before and
having a real center that has,
you know,
real professionals and medical health
staff,
that's,
that's what you want and the only thing
that's keeping that from happening in
America and keeping millions and
millions of people from getting off
pills,
companies,
drug companies,
lobbying to keep all these very helpful
things illegal and we're slowly but
surely going to work them out and the
way we're going to work the mouse
through money.
That's why I like the fact that
marijuana has a 30 percent tax.
Make it 50.
I don't give a fuck.
What's a joint?
How much does it joining?
A joint can get you high all day.
think about what a drink is.
Drink.
You go to bar,
you get a drink.
How much does a drink cost?
$8.
$8 worth of weed will fuck you up.
many days.
Men,
I don't know,
about many days,
two days,
maybe one day.
How much does the job you?
Half a day.
If you're buying a $12.
Twenty five bucks.
This is 25 bucks.
This fat cigar.
This is odd father.
That will put you on pluto.
You'll be over there with david bowie.
It was $25 last month and now it's $33 a
shot of macallan.
Those well over 25 probably at any bar.
That's it is.
He's right.
All right,
fine.
Fine.
My taxes on my weed or good fine.
thank you.
I 10 years I've been buying legal weed
and all of a sudden I want to buy
illegal weed because the taxes and you
just talked me guilted me even back into
legal weed.
I'm happy to pay it and I think that
it's.
I,
you know,
I understand you.
I get it,
but what I'm saying money.
No you're not,
but some people would.
But I'm saying the money if it goes to a
good cause,
if we really can change the way people
perceive drugs because it's not.
There's not a war on drugs.
That is a lie.
There's drugs everywhere they're
prescribed.
You can get them into the drug store,
you can get them at a liquor store,
you can get drugs.
There's a lot of drugs.
It's just certain drugs,
the ones that they can't,
you know,
corporatize as easily.
So the way to get it in is not through
the corporations influence,
but through the influences,
the consumer of the consumer to consumer
paying exorbitant amount of taxes on
these things willingly is going to
change the opinion.
You know,
I like weed.
Being legal.
I'll pay the fucking tax.
I will.
There we go.
I was just curious.
I mean,
I look selfishly,
totally selfishly my own benefit.
I as a guy who jumped through the hoops
and got a $40 medical card,
was happy to have it be called medicine
and get it and have it legally and not
pay taxes on it.
Now it seems like it's the same except
I'm paying the tax on it.
It is the same,
but it's progress because the money's
going into community.
I hope.
I hope if it is,
let's find out where it goes.
Let's say a guest.
I hope it goes towards law enforcement.
I hope it's divvied up between law
enforcement and education.
How about that?
Let's hope it goes to education,
but something tells me it's not.
I just feel like it's going to be so
much money.
Like Colorado had a gift tax money back
to us.
Oh,
do they really have to get a refund back
because there's so much money being made
by wheat.
That's like Alaska.
It's like the oil pipeline.
Exactly.
You haven't vegetative state taxes,
boss.
I don't know if they have negative state
taxes,
but I know they gave people refunds.
The gave people money because they made
so
much money on taxes.
That's awesome.
Fucking amazing.
And if that happens in California,
keep my fucking 30 percent sales tax.
Real estate went up 14 percent since
marijuana was legalized.
Instead of going down,
a lot of people thought,
well they'll no to move out.
There's pothead.
It's going to be on the streets.
Nope.
a friend of mine wants to open a like a
cannabis club and there's only.
There's a small area in the green zone
where you can do that.
And I'm like,
great.
Here's your map of the green zone.
I go,
okay.
What's for sale in the green zone?
Nothing.
Not a single building.
A place where you can get high,
like publicly.
Yeah.
It would be like a cigar bar.
Yes.
Um,
the,
there's a lot of rules a lot and there's
a very restrictive of Where you can put
it anD you absolutely under no
circumstances can have a drop of alcohol
anywhere on the premises.
Interesting.
So if somebody comes in with a beer,
you're fucked.
You can't take you gotta kick them out.
Yeah.
Um,
but if they're in west hollywood,
you,
there will be places where you can go
and smoke on premises.
Yeah.
That's going to be weird,
huh?
Yeah.
Go get high with a bunch of strangers.
It makes sense in amsterdam because it's
a walking city.
Then you can use your coffee shop tour,
you know,
to walk around the city And ground
coffee,
shop to coffee shop and sight.
See.
And it's really nice.
Sober up.
But in la,
what are your driving from coffee shop
to fucking come on.
Nobody walks here.
What are you goIng to do?
A drive car,
it's going to be like that.
See what the railroad of good fellows
with the helicopters flying overhead and
he's freaking out.
I remade that scene frame for frame and
it got kicked off youtube because you
have to use the real music and I got
trademark infringement but I did it
frame for frame with the helicopters.
You mean you did it?
I remade that helicopter chase you with
me and it into for a car review.
I was reviewing the cadillac and I did
the fucking thing right through the bag
in and when I'm looking helicopters and
we did the.
What was the problem?
You um,
what does that music?
Yeah,
the actual music.
yeah,
yeah.
You have to use the actual music.
Otherwise it's not rolling stones.
What is it?
It's not layla.
Layla.
No fucking hell.
That's whatever it is.
You have to use the exact music and it
didn't work.
And then that got kicked off of youtube
too bad.
Spends a lot of time in that.
Well,
they're really good at spotting
copyright music now or anything copy
written.
I thought I could get away,
get around it.
If I didn't monetize the video but it
didn't,
you know,
when we get fucked,
whenever we put up a video of any nature
thing,
like oh a bear killing something or
something like that.
All those were all bought by someone
almost like patent trolls.
People put them up,
they just take it down and you have to
offer him money to like stock footage
companies or something.
Yeah,
yeah.
All that stuff gets yanked dowN off of
facebook.
Yeah.
Youtube and facebook.
ThoSe are the two places that stuff gets
facebook.
Like I don't put videos on facebook
anymore because it just gets stolen
immediately.
And also their revenue is.
What do you mean by get.
It's
very easy for someone to rip your video
off of,
you know,
put it somewhere else on facebook and
whatever versus if they re upload it
somewhere else on youtube,
the software algorithm will generally
catch it.
Oh,
I know.
So the software algorithm and facebook
is not as effective and they don't
really give a shit.
They don't care.
Yeah.
They're too busy selling your
information.
So look in Russia.
Totally.
Jamie was watching the video of dr.
Soccer berg.
How did it go?
He should know the answer.
Yeah,
he had to go again today.
Uh,
I was watching right before you got here
in this.
I don't know where she was from,
but she was saying like,
you're the ceo of this company and you
should know some of these answers.
And she was like,
listing all the shitty.
Didn't know it was like,
this is ridiculous.
And then I afterwards,
now they've shown,
which I guess it's part of now,
public information has notes.
Oh no,
that he had like as references that he
was looking at.
I've only seen one picture of it.
Just very weird stuff that like,
seems blatantly obvious that he should
know or should say that's different from
what we've.
Maybe we think we should think they
should be able to.
I get the impression that this company
grew so fast,
they don't even know what the fuck is
going on in now.
Will those.
The other thing he was talking about,
their influence on possible.
Are we going to continue?
We'll continue.
Don't worry about it.
He was talking about his influence on
all these different upcoming elections
that were coming up and about how they
wanted to make sure that there was no
bots that were influencing these
elections and then I stopped and thought
about it and I'm like,
oh my god.
In that moment of him saying that,
I realized like what pressure he must be
under,
what pressure that company is under
there.
They went from being a thing where
people could share pictures like of,
hey,
this is us on our summer vacation and
like,
hey,
you know,
fucking we're going to go to the pub on
friday.
That's what facebook kind of was,
right?
People would talk about certain things
in the news.
They would have opinions.
You put up something,
a bunch of people comment on it.
That's what it was.
Now with this last election and with him
testifying in front of congress,
what I'm seeing is facebook being like
one of the most important sources of
influence in the world today and it's
not really being completely managed out.
I still feel like the russians,
the russians.
Yeah.
Maybe there's a little bit like google
needs to be looked into going on with my
mic.
So google also probably like they have a
data,
I think someone was just looking into
this,
you know,
people downloaded their facebook profile
and they're like,
my files one gigabyte.
Well,
how much data is in here?
People found out a way to download
theirs and find their information.
And what,
what does facebook know about me?
Apparently there's also one that google
has on everyone and it's much larger
to the music.
I'm not shocked,
you know,
I wouldn't be,
I wouldn't be nervous if it wasn't for
that.
That memo thing,
um,
really changed my mind about a lot of
things.
Not because,
you know,
it's a subject that's near and dear to
my heart,
but because the way they were handling
it was not,
there were,
weren't being honest.
They were,
they weren't being honest about the
science.
They weren't being honest about the
reaction.
They weren't even the way they were
describing it.
We're talking about the james damore
google memo.
Oh,
I don't know.
it was at the seXism thing was that was
the the what he was talking about women
in tech explain why women would prefer
to not like why some women are not
influenced by the way google handled it
was very,
very nervous because they weren't being
honest about the information.
They weren't beIng honest about the
results that weren't being honest about
what was in his.
They were saying he was reinforcing
harmful gender stereotypes.
That's not what he was doing.
What he was talking about,
the science of the difference in the
psychology between men and women and why
women would gravitate towards different
careers and maybe that's why more women
aren't in tech.
Maybe there's ways to get women in tech
will.
You've taken that angle before,
right?
with women and fighting and women in
sports,
right?
Yeah.
There's some women that are not going to
want to be into those things.
There's something going on that are
going to be wherever they are in
comParison to men.
It's less likely that a woman's going to
be into fighting than a man.
I don't think that's extraordinary to
say,
but a lot of women are into it.
It doesn't mean that it's impossible,
but it's just we're looking at human
beings like if you're an outlier and
you're a woman who really loves to
fight,
there's nothing wrong with that.
I'm not saying there's anything wrong
with that,
but I'm saying it's much more rare that
a woman who wants to,
you know,
do become a nurse or do something that's
traditionally a female,
a care giver,
sort of a position which is really
common.
And I read it.
Did the letter memo indicate like this
that science says women were less
predisposed to becoming programmers or
something like that?
No,
no.
It just was talking about gender.
I'm like,
choices and choices people make and why
they make them based on personality
traits and how,
why things are more common.
Certain things are more common in males.
Certain things are more common in women
and that this would indicate why there
were less women that were involved in
tech and it wasn't some systemic sort
of,
um,
discrimination campaign put on by men,
you know.
But my point was,
we're talking about them having all the
information that you have,
like google and facebook,
how much inflammation they hit on you.
It would make me less nervous if I
didn't know about that,
how they handle that google memo thing
because I'm like,
well you guys aren't being honest about
what this is what the guy wrote.
You're paying the guy out to be a
villain and you think if you fire him
and drown this,
that this story goes out.
And then you guys get to look like
social justice warriors and then you
don't take the heat from the what,
you know it was an objective analysis of
this issue.
WeLl,
I don't.
I'm not sure.
Mark zuckerberg has a lot of incentive
to be totally honest in this chase.
Either he's totally honest and he's
malicious or he's totally honest and
he's almost comically ignorant about
certain things.
Yeah.
What he's saying,
he's.
I think he's almost got to say he
doesn't know,
but the problem is that they improve.
He knows.
He should know though is I feel like
also
part of the thing he should know now,
him saying he doesn't know what if they
can pull up an email,
wouldn't mean what if they have access
to all of his emails and it shows that
he knows.
They did.
I was talking to yesterday about it and
we were like worried about the facebook
recording thing.
Is anybody gonna bring that up and it
was brought up and he said that they
don't record audio.
Facebook doesn't.
Right.
You were talking about it with google
weren't.
that if you talk,
if you were talking in a room about a
certain subject,
have you ever had that happen?
Right.
That's the apple home pod.
You've.
You've had,
you've been talking about something in a
room and then had pop up ads pop up,
right?
No,
I have it.
no,
no.
I believe it though.
It happens.
You had it.
It happened to me before.
Not.
I don't know how.
I couldn't tell you what were the
signals went,
but I've definitely had strain.
It could be a coincidence,
but I've had strange ads pop up that
are.
I read that,
that I don't know if it's accurate
though.
When I was reading that there people
have tried to prove and it could be
people on facebook side just to give
them propaganda that that's almost
nearly impossible to do right now just
because of the technology would take to
record your audio,
have it scanned by something and then
deliver an ad to you based off of that.
And amanda.
Yeah,
it's entirely possible.
I could have looked at something similar
at a recent time when it was just far
enough away for me to not make an exact
connection.
I don't want to quit.
It represents those that you recognize
that that is potentially in the future.
Like for things like alexa and things
like home pod and the devices that are
designed to listen to your voice or
that's the whole point of them.
You know,
all this good.
I don't know dude.
I get a lot of.
I get a lot of shit done.
I'm real productive.
You know I can,
I can.
I have things that are,
would Be very difficult to find that can
be delivered,
bro.
I had,
I have a,
I have a 2001 mercedes sl 500.
So my traffic car.
Ah,
perfect for traffic and nice big clarion
system is great.
I love my traffic car and you know,
it's got the old school,
removable hard top.
So I needed to get the stand to put the
hard top on when it took it off.
Right.
Amazon 12 hours.
I had a stand for a 2011 mercy delivered
to my house.
Wow.
That level of convenience.
Yeah.
I'll give up a little privacy little
bit.
Little bit.
Fine.
I'll give,
I'll give it up.
You can have it.
That's what's gonna get us.
That's what's going to get us to turn us
into machines.
Just give up a little bit here a little
bit here.
I don't want to give up all of it.
Like I'm definitely opposed to the drive
vehicle tracking,
you know,
like,
uh,
about having a car that,
that knows where you've been and tell
somebody about it.
Um,
which a certain company does do that,
what will companies this will tesla's
know where you been well done,
don't they all by virtue of their gps,
but tesla's are wirelessly connected to
tesla.
So the reason.
So part of the reason tesla
semi autonomous system works as well as
it does and part of the reason tesla is
doing what they're doing as a company is
your car's all tesla's on the road are
collecting mapping data for tesla,
you know,
in real time.
So they can,
you know,
be ethical with that data or they
cannot.
And odds are they don't give a shit
where you're going other than to help
them figure out where to put the next
superchargers and and whatnot.
And in general you have to assume that
to improve your experience.
But if you extrapolate this 50 years
down the road and some of our privacy's
get worn away,
you could end up with a car that were,
you know,
where it's very easy to subpoena the
records of your tesla and find out
exactly where you went.
So a test that would be the worst car if
you were like a bank robber.
Fuck ya know,
if you need a hundred miles analog,
analog,
big fuel tank.
Think transporter one.
Jason statham.
That's what you want.
big fuel cell.
Black.
Late model car.
What's that in invisible black again.
Vanna black.
Phantom.
Black car?
No,
no one right now.
We haven't painted anything like big in
it yet.
It's not yet motherfuck I have venta car
on the way.
There's some weird environmental shit
with vanna black because John John Ward
was telling me that there is one note
that is velvet.
My frIend velvet.
That's fucking velvet.
You?
Yep.
That's real.
Yup.
Oh wait a minute.
That's not.
That says vanna black,
but that's not vantive black.
That is a velvet car.
That.
Wait a minute,
this,
this rolls royce is not to,
but it's not vanna black.
Zippo.
Impossible.
It says it is there.
I'm telling you,
they haven't painted a car in vantaa
black.
So either that's fake or it's the velvet
shit they're doing now.
That's a computer.
Yeah.
Would what it would look like.
now what is it made out of that allows
it to get to this level of darkness?
You know?
I don't know.
It is just damn crazy.
Looks dope job.
Please don't put your make up.
We can't be frIends anymore.
You can do that.
I saw justin bieber wants driving around
in a,
a leopard print audi.
Oh,
he's got to do what?
He's got to do.
Fewer.
Twenty three years old and drownIng and
pussy.
You'd probably do.
This is think this was years ago.
It was probably 19.
He's probably trying to keep them away
from him.
It was probably one of the grossest the
car possible.
Just to say,
look,
stay away from my dick to cover.
Who of your crazy guest has rolled up to
your studio and the dopest car.
Do you.
Does anything come to mind?
To bill's area and roll up and that six
by six.
Got you.
I wasn't cool is so gross.
That's disgusting.
I didn't even really believe me because
I knew we had a uh,
a,
a chrome fisker,
fisker karma wasn't.
Um.
Yeah.
And they just released that thing I
heard they did though.
Company bought all the assets and
they've started blowing up and trying to
get water when the ones that I asked for
one for review,
they say hold.
Lightly declined.
Yeah.
I wonder why.
Yeah,
yeah.
You got a big mouth going to drive
through a puddle ones.
Yeah.
Electric cars,
man.
There's a bright future.
It's just a.
I don't want to jump in yet and I don't
want anything driving for me.
True.
Have you,
have you driven electric carver?
Yeah,
I've driven a tesla.
They're nice.
Yeah.
It's weird.
It feels weird.
It does,
but in an urban environment,
you can see why it's a nice experience.
When I drive An electric car,
there's the fisker.
When I drive an electric car and I get
where I'm going,
I am noticeably more relaxed than when
I'm driving a gas car,
especially if I'm driving like allowed
sportscar.
Right,
right,
right.
Yeah.
The goal,
those vibrations and stuff go through
your body and kind of like stick with
you versus the serenity of that silence.
Just the 250 mile range.
It annoys the shit out of me.
Yeah.
No,
it's.
They need infrastructure like they're
considering how many teslas are in los
angeles.
There's an embarrassingly small number
of superchargers in the city.
There's not a lot of places to charge
the tesla outside of your home and they
really need to do the infrastructure and
they need to come up with a faster
charging solution.
Which porsche it seems may have done.
Porsche has a new electric car coming
out called the mission e,
which is a tesla fighting thing and they
supposedly have a fast charging system
that can do like an 80 percent charge in
10 minutes or something.
Yeah.
Well,
so you know,
that's crazy.
Ten minutes is pretty close.
Ten minutes is fast.
If you get three right,
you have three to five.
10 is fine.
10 works.
Ten's good.
And a competitor is good because you
know tesla's,
you can't charge them for free anymore.
You don't know the model.
Three's and the new ones,
they don't come with free charging and
he's motherfuckers.
That's how they get you.
$5 rocks first one's free.
Yup.
No more free juice.
Wow.
How long was it free for a few years.
At 2013 the model s came out and four
years or so.
So what happens when you pull into the
airport and you go to one of them
electric spots per credit card or you
have a rfid fob or something?
Fuck these motherfuckers gotta pay to
play my friend.
Why can't they figure out how with all
the sun in la to have a solar powered
car?
Uh,
you just,
it's just not possible with photovoltaic
cells to generate enough much.
Dude.
it takes so much juice to move a 4,000
pound car down the road.
So much more than turning on a light or
playing a radio.
Like that mass movement.
It takes so much energy.
Fisker had something on the roof that
powers the radio,
right?
Yeah.
I know there are a couple of company.
FiSker was one.
Someone else did a photo voltaic roof
where it,
it likes circulates the climate,
the air when it's really hot out or it
can pre turn on certain things and shit
like that.
Yeah.
But it's not enough to run or charge a
car.
What if that's gonna change in the
future?
I'm sure they don't have solar panels
really.
Have they come that far yet?
We'll test a solar as a roof tile.
I've seen this.
Yeah.
Tesla roof tile.
They're trying to do a tesla solar tile
that goes on your roof that then will
feed into the tesla battery pack that
hangs on your wall.
You know,
and then you can be a autonomous
basIcally sorta.
But you're still in the grid.
Yes.
And you give money back to the,
the,
the reason why they do that they want,
they don't want you being completely off
the grid.
They don't want the grid that died.
You know,
people are really worried about that.
Well I'm building a building right now,
so get this la,
you know I'm a democrat,
but la will make you want to hang
yourself building shit.
So I have to prep my building for solar
panels,
whether I put them on or not.
If I put them on their $92,000
to cover the roof and solar panels and I
will pay.
They pay themselves off in seven years.
So I generate swelled thousand dollars
or so,
a year in power and then after that I'm
fully,
fully positive and the city will pay me
every year and they pay themselves off
in seven years and the life span of them
is 20 years.
So I could potentially have many years
of free power.
Wow.
Yeah.
So you're,
you're building.
I'm building a collector car storage
facility.
Here's where I plug it.
It's called west side collector car
storage.
It's going to be in playa vista,
California,
which is the sweet new part of la.
Beautiful area.
Yeah.
Do you know where the clippers practice
facility is?
You seeing that?
It's right next to the fox hills mall,
right by lax,
venice.
It's conveniently located.
Um,
and I'm going to have storage for 150
cars.
It's going to be secure climate control,
the whole,
the whole deal.
So this is,
you're doing it as an investment or as
a,
as a business.
He has a business ground up.
It's great for customers is not,
you know,
it's not for me and we're building a
cool studio there like this,
like you've got.
instead of my shanti little studio,
now I'm going to do a podcast and the
podcast studio is going to be elevated,
so we have car stackers,
so I've 24 high stackers and the studio
is elevated.
And when just look out over the stacked
cars.
yeah,
that's going to be killer,
but I have to comply with a lot of
California environmental craziness.
I have to put a fire hydrant in this
like for the city,
like I have to do it for the city to get
a building permit.
Well it kind of makes sense if you're
fucking cars catch on fire.
You got a lot of gasoline in that one
spot.
Yeah.
The fire system that we have to build is
incredible,
I would imagine.
Yeah.
And we have to have auxiliary pumps.
It flows 3,500
gallons a minute in every car.
So the stacks,
every car on a stack has two nozzles at
it front and back,
while every car has its own set of
nozzles.
Wow.
So if a fire starts over here,
it's completely contained over here and
I.
The idea that they kick on automatically
when.
Oh wow.
That's incredible.
That's a really neat,
but I'm four years into this now,
so broken ground yet hopefully next
week.
Wow.
Permits just got.
Just got approved.
Wow,
that's dope.
Dude.
Come back on when it's done.
Oh,
that'd be great.
CoMe back on wednesday.
So people.
No,
thank you.
Um,
we've been doing this for like three
hours And a half.
Is there anything else that.
is there any other shit going on?
No,
I'm just happy to see you.
I'm happy to see you.
I'm sorry I didn't get to come to your
new year's show because they've made it
a tradition two years in a row all over
this place.
I know.
I liked your new special to the one that
where it was crop tight.
Yeah.
I liked,
I liked that very much.
Doing that with my next went to.
I'm trying to make it like you're
sitting in the audience.
That's great idea behind it.
And I liked chappelle's tiny one.
He did in the belly roll.
Yeah.
I was at gotham comedy club when he
first told that iceberg slim story when
he came back from africa,
I was friends with christmas lee.
And he's like,
come down,
chappelle's back.
You know chris?
yeah.
Back in New York.
The corvette stingray like yours.
Does he really?
Yeah.
Chris and charlotte christmas.
And um,
that,
that special is good.
And judah free landers was amazing.
Is iT on netflix?
Yeah.
Uh,
it's called america's the best country
in the United States.
It is so good.
All right,
beautiful.
Thanks for having me.
My pleasure,
man.
My pleasure.
Uh,
the smoking tire on twitter,
the smoking tire on instagram,
the podcast it got to the entire
podcast.
And watch and listen podcast.
Check them out anywhere you find
podcasts.
Fair ladies and gentlemen,
joe rogan.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Thanks man.