The joe rogan experience were bananas.
It's crazy.
And then you know what it is though.
Here's the real victims of ending the
drug war would be all those prisons that
would no longer be full
of young black men.
You say this,
but what if your business
is running prisons,
right?
I mean it's your business
is prison guards.
I mean that's
someone think of the prison,
the prison industrial complex prison
guards lobby against drug legalizations
cause do it because they
want to stay in office.
They want to keep their jobs and how many
lives has to be ruined in the process.
Fucking crazy to vampire system.
So horrible vampire system and it's
a system that's brought out of it's,
it's based on these reverberations
are these vibrations from the past.
It's all like this scramble
when a people were retarded,
when they came over on boats and
this is just how they did things.
They throw in a jail,
he'll fucking scoundrel.
You were smoking marijuana or whatever.
The rule that you broke is that
they realize that they can do it.
So they do do it and they throw you in
some fucking cage in 2014 the fact that
that's still going on and that people
are actually profiting from it.
This is,
these are more things that the Internet
has a huge fucking problem with.
Cause the Internet's guys like you is
young fellas that are very smart and
unconventional and seeing
the system and being like,
you know what?
I don't buy it.
I think a,
there's shit that people I knew
growing up that were adults,
I knew they were fucking idiots and
they knew they made bad choices.
And now I'm looking at the,
the repercussions of this everywhere.
I'm looking at an item saying,
no,
this is dumb.
This is,
so this is one of the things,
especially talking to college
students that I love bringing up,
which is that,
and I'm the first to admit that like
I have no fucking clue what I'm doing.
99% of the time eat.
Especially when I got started,
I still don't know.
And I've,
I've come to realize like I've got,
I've got been lucky enough to
meet some pretty like successful,
impressive people.
But like you dig under the surface,
we're all just hacking it.
Like we're all just figure,
expertise,
experience those things.
I'll help.
But like every one of
us is a fallible human,
all the conventions and rules and
status quo we know were created by other
fallible humans.
And there's no reason not
to look at that and go,
Huh,
does it have to be that way?
Or why is it that way?
And if the reason why is low,
that's the way it is.
Well that's a terrible reason,
you know?
And,
and when you see the world
as being that hackable,
so to speak,
like you start to realize,
all right,
well let's just,
let's actually question stuff.
And,
and for,
you know,
I remember I was a freshman at Uva when
nine 11 happened for this generation of
millennials coming up.
We mow nearly all of us.
One of our first really vivid memories
of the world was nine 11 this awful
tragedy.
And then we get into these two wars and
then think of all the authority figures
we've had in our life since that moment.
They've all at one point,
other either misled us,
this sort of deceived us.
Um,
you've got the financial crisis,
you've got the housing bubble,
all these conventions.
Oh,
trust us,
we know what we're doing.
This is the thing,
the American dream is buying a home,
go to college,
take on that student loan debt.
Don't worry,
there's a job waiting for you.
Every single one.
These conventions from,
from all these people in
power have not held up.
And so I think in particular,
millennials,
millennials look at that very
skeptically cause we're like,
all right,
you know what?
So the conventional stuff
didn't work out for anything.
Like we have no choice but to realize,
you know what,
we're all just hacking it.
So let's,
let's really,
let's dive into the passion.
Let's,
let's figure out a better
way to do something.
Not Settle for the way it always been.
I think you're completely right.
And I think,
um,
first of all I'm slightly annoyed by this
new statement and I'm forced to absorb
millennials.
I know it's terrible for you.
I'm sorry.
I'm not buying,
you can rebrand this.
I think we should,
I really do.
This is,
I think there's a divisiveness or there's
a separation that comes when you start
labeling people by like
what era they were born in.
It's a state of mind
more than anything else.
Yeah,
I think so.
But I think it's horse shit,
generation x generation to fuck up.
It's just human.
It's like there's this idea of putting
things in a label generalization.
The human brace is evolving.
Watch father knows best and
then watch game of Thrones.
Okay,
shit's different now.
We don't have to come up with names for
the generations and your generation y
and there was fucking Jamie
from the laugh factory.
Tried to tell my friend,
uh,
Todd Parker,
Todd Parker's a standup comic
that I started out with.
Jamie was like,
body,
you have to be generation x guy.
This is what you would do.
You'd go on stage and everything.
My generation,
generation x,
think that's going to be your hook.
And I remember him trying to explain
it to change and I'm in the background
going,
did you hear what he told Tony to do?
What he tell tidy?
You must always wear a cowboy hat.
That was just thinking.
He would just look like woody from
toy story cause he needed the hat.