Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Live.
And we're live.
Mr Carmichael.
Hello,
my friend Joe Tomorrow.
I know a Gemara welcome.
Thank you man.
I know you were coming,
but glad to see you.
Me Neither,
man.
He made.
He made me come.
Just came by.
I'm going to Joe Rogan and he was like,
perfect.
Perfect.
What the fuck is going on man?
What do you have to.
I just got an from New York like two
hours ago and now I'm here.
I feel real.
I don't know,
I feel like,
uh,
you know,
you ever see like a homeless man smoking
a cigarette?
Yeah.
And he just feels like real zen and this
is his.
That's how.
That's how I feel emotionally right now.
Really?
Yeah.
Really homeless dude smoking a
cigarette.
I.
Weird analogy.
I feel it's great.
It's really great.
I'm trying to figure that out.
That feeling.
It's like I have everything that I need
right now in your life.
Have everything I need.
Yeah.
Well you've been killing it for a long
time,
man.
You know you were killing it when I
wasn't at the store.
I'd heard about you when I was gone.
I had heard about you.
I think our is one that told me about.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
You know,
and then I found out that spike Lee
directed your specials.
Like what?
Like what the fuck is happening over at
the comedy store
directing comedy specials.
That was a fun one because it was like
just such a.
immediately I was like,
it has to be in the O and nobody filmed
in the OA and so like getting everybody
to agree to that.
Yeah.
And then because he would spike was
like,
but the main rooms right here so big and
it's,
it was like,
but I don't do the main room.
We'll do our.
Yeah,
the main room is pretty good too.
I used to,
I used to be prejudice against the main
room.
I'd be like,
ah,
it's too big.
It's too showy.
It depends on how dirty and grimy.
It depends on like the sides of full or
open and what the,
the room can change depending on so many
factors of like seeding and whatever.
Just the sound of it.
Well,
the room really changes when it gets
empty late at night.
Like that's a strange room.
I like Brody's doing those midnight
spots.
Those have been some fun spots.
The,
it's just one bro.
These just
like I used to,
Tommy used to make me a follow brody.
Uh,
like all the time.
It's,
that's such a fun,
interesting thing to do to like.
Because what else is left at that point?
Your headspace?
Yeah.
It's in there in such a different place
that it's just one of the piece it back
together and figure it out tomorrow.
You get a lot of those freaky spots.
Yeah,
man.
The follow Brian Holtzman
like,
well,
he's just so crazy.
He'll say so much crazy shit
that the audience is just like stunned.
Like,
yeah.
It's like Brody Times 20.
Rarely ever see holtzman funny as fuck.
Yeah.
I don't.
I don't think I have yet.
Oh my God,
Dude.
Holsman said some of the darkest Shit
I've ever seen anybody say onstage.
He went on stage at.
Do you remember Susan Smith?
That lady that drowned her kids?
She was a lady that she drowned her
kids.
I forget what the context of it was.
Holtzman went on stage like two days
later.
I was like,
I heard those were bad kids.
I heard they sat that close to the TV.
They never put away their blocks.
If fucking spelt their milk,
those kids went up.
He missed.
Well,
when you say that,
maybe I have her,
Brian host 11th.
Mitzi wouldn't let them go on stage.
Oh,
I keep them off stage.
She will go out and risk the potential
like riot.
Well,
he's a really funny guy and a really
good comp,
but he's never been a professional like
his whole life.
He's been doing comedy forever.
When I came to the store in [inaudible],
94,
holtzman was already there and he's
never been a professional.
He's always had a job.
So He's been.
He was a dog catcher.
He was a meter maid,
like a bunch of different shit,
you know,
so he's never,
never really branched out.
Eleanor was telling me how you fought a
Martin Lawrence's,
a bodyguard,
or you can call it that you could say.
I would say Martin Lawrence,
his bodyguard,
beat the fuck out of Brian Holtzman.
Martin Lawrence was heckling and hope.
Well Holtmann's onstage.
You seen crazy shit and it's like 10
people in the room and and Martin was
heckling apparently and Brian got off
stage to point out,
but it was Martin Lawrence.
He's like,
look,
this fucking rich famous motherfuckers
hegland me.
Boom.
It gets knocked out.
There was that immediate.
This wasn't even a parking lot.
It was a showcase.
Is that what you heard?
The stories get twisted story.
Stories get weird after a while,
but yeah,
that was,
those were the dark days,
the comedy store.
That was like,
I want to say that was like,
I don't even know if that was the two
thousands.
What is it now?
I haven't really been in like I've kind
of been,
but I like,
what is it now like still that place
where you go experiment,
try out.
I do
Gemara.
It's actually though I go to see Jamal
was like,
when I go it's usually to like it,
like whatever 1:00 AM shit.
It's like great.
I just hit him up and be like,
hey man,
I'm going up.
I'm going to do some crazy shit.
You coming through?
Oh yeah.
I love it.
One o'clock sets.
It's a different.
It's experimental.
It's strange.
It's kind of sad.
There's a little sadness.
Perfect.
Yeah.
Oh the sadness is those late night
because you like,
you looking at your watch.
Like why am I not at home?
Why am I not asleep?
I remember that feeling my first time
going to the comedy store.
Just being like,
why?
Like why am I sad?
Like just like this thing that just
weighs you like it.
I,
I remember feeling Kinda like worthless.
No,
just like Kinda like the PR.
It just,
it really feels like a ghost is choking
you out.
It's like a weird ghost and pick,
pick one
89.
This is a lot of ghost in that room.
And they come,
they went,
everyone's gone.
That's when they show up,
you think?
No,
no.
I don't think for real.
Like you'll see them,
but you do definitely feel like
weirdness.
Yeah.
No,
there's a weird.
Especially when you bomb,
you get that cold.
Well,
you know,
he bombed there too.
Just some classic famous stories about
prior bombing as he was filming live in
the sunset strip.
Like some of the Salon,
uh,
had the footage.
Oh really?
Yeah.
The uh,
the show Tom that had like the footage
of the,
that show.
Oh,
the show.
Where was prepping,
like what was getting ready to.
Well,
not all,
like the show were just didn't go like
to stay with them.
Well they filmed the,
you know,
that strip show where he had to come
back the next night and,
and like Kinda Redo.
He just had like,
he was just,
he,
you know,
operating from such a place of just like
it was so it had to be honest to him I
think and it had just hadn't gone up in
a while and was on stage and was just
like in the room and just sat in.
It just,
he just sat there was footage is crazy.
Send me that.
Wow.
He's got the footage.
Well it's in the dark.
You can see it in a documentary like a
little bit,
but I think it's extended for it.
I haven't seen the extended footage,
if that exists,
but
there's some great old cassettes that I
bought from a,
like a gas station.
There were a red foxes comedy club.
Red Fox had a comedy club and prior
would go up and just fuck around man,
just fuck around.
And there was many of them.
I mean there was like seven or eight
recordings.
Mavericks flat.
I think it was right.
That was the name of the company.
I think so awful.
It was awful.
Like crenshaw or something over there.
Like Oh,
where the club was?
Yeah.
I don't know.
I got them when I was living in Boston.
I was living in Boston and I found them
like at a gas station there were for
sale.
Oh yeah.
And it was crazy because it was like,
it was a small crowd.
You could tell it was a small crowd and
prior was just fucking man.
He was just,
he was ad libbing.
You could tell that like it wasn't
structured and some of it was really
funny and some of it like kind of fell
flat and you could hear the clink of
glasses and shit in the background.
It was just so real rich,
you know,
Richard Pryor back then he was doing
something that it's like he had figured
out a thing that he could do that other
people hadn't figured out.
And that thing was like,
just be totally honest and also just
explore ideas on stage in front of
people,
like not even have it mapped out yet.
Just try,
just fuck around and find what's funny
and he'd be smoking cigarettes and just
talking and he figured out a way to turn
and then you would see it boiled in to
like Richard Pryor live or live in the
sunset strip or any of his specials.
You would see it boiled down to this,
doing it for tell,
you know,
he performed for television really well.
Um,
and that's kind of a,
an element that,
uh,
I think people kind of forget that.
Like how well of a it connected with you
watching it at home,
like,
you know,
even me 20,
30 years later after it's filmed and
just watching it with my dad if he plays
really well here,
you know what I mean?
Like to you,
it's like you can feel how personal and
how honest it is.
And so when it was like boiled down,
it was just,
he was also captured really well.
Do you ever see him live?
No.
Prior?
Yeah.
How old do you think I am?
No,
he was alive doing standup 10 years ago?
Yeah.
Maybe a little bit more maybe 15 years
ago.
But he doesn't,
he died.
Maybe it was more than 15 years ago now
that I'm thinking about it is you ever
seen him live?
Yeah,
I had um,
I had a follow them like five weeks in a
row,
man.
Really Weird.
Like a run in 2005.
He died.
Okay.
So it was more than I thought
he did a run before he died.
It was probably right before then.
I actually,
I want to say it was like the late
nineties,
early 2000,
somewhere around that he was real sick
and they would have to carry him to the
stage and it would take like five
minutes for him to get to the stage so
that he introduced him and the comic
would get out of the way.
And then,
um,
a chewy and Maryland Martinez,
his husband would help him,
walked the stage.
They would hold onto him,
take him to the stage,
let me take forever.
It was a slow process and they'd get
them and they sit them down and they'd
crank up the mic like this
because his voice was so soft.
Yeah.
And he would do standup,
do like 15,
20 minutes and then I would go on after
every,
almost every time it would be me and
just eat shit.
Shit.
First of all,
nobody
knew who I was.
And second of all they just saw Richard
Pryor and they're sad because he's
fading away.
You're right in front of everybody.
Yeah.
It's an interesting feeling like never
before it was like a British type in
admission,
been needed more British type
information.
You don't like where it's just like,
all right,
which prior is gone and uh,
you know,
15 minutes people go smoke cigarettes,
come back.
What year did you start doing standup?
A 2008.
Yeah.
So you missed it.
Did you go to the clubs at all before
then to look around A.
No.
Well,
two nights before.
My first two nights,
two nights before our first time I went
to the comedy store.
Wow.
Did you first day in la?
My first day in La I saw the whole show.
Nine to 2:00 AM.
Wow.
You sat through the whole show,
the whole show.
Did the open mic that Sunday.
Whoa.
That's an experience man.
The,
the people that do that,
man,
that's like running an ultra marathon,
like,
no,
but I am to,
to.
It's interesting.
I can watch,
I can watch it,
you know,
I can consume a,
like a high volume of it in,
in a lot of cases.
Like,
you know,
I'm,
I've always been interested in like
whatever people are talking about,
you know,
like,
and it was just an interesting sampler.
Like,
all right,
what's fascinating about the store,
this,
the 15 minute blocks that you're seeing
these completely different viewpoints,
15 minute chunks.
So it's like if you sit there for long
enough,
you sit there for a couple of hours and
you watched that many different people,
you want to eight different people go
up.
It's like,
it's very weird.
Yeah,
the strength of it,
I think for like what standup is
especially like right now,
what it helps is it allows you to think
of yourself in context.
Um,
and,
and that's Kinda,
that's best more important now than
ever.
Especially what stand up if you're on
and you're competing against the 3000
other specials that came out this way,
right?
It's in context of,
you know,
kind of mass consumption.
So if you go into a,
you know,
in the middle of a marathon,
so you're going up in the,
oh,
are in the middle of a show and they saw
eight comics for you.
They'll see nine after you or whatever,
right.
You have to like kind of sketch a place
in their minds in context of everything
else that they saw that night.
So it's really important.
Are you going like,
are you going like,
okay,
so what happened?
They said,
well no,
you can't do that because they,
you know,
it,
it forces you.
It's not saying like,
you know,
it's not saying change who you are.
I think it makes them more dynamic
version of who you are because you have
to be memorable in the context of all of
these people and these different styles.
It also,
you know,
I think what you do because you're
whatever you make and you release into
the world,
you are also releasing it in the context
of other are that people are consuming.
Right?
So like even if you release your standup
album,
you know,
a lot of times people will buy stand up
albums by stand up albums,
you know,
and so they listened to you in context
of the other standup albums that you
have.
It's a strong comparison.
Culture stand has right like hip hop
where it's always in relation.
It's not,
this is my favorite rapper is this is
better than that wrapper
and comedians and consumers of it,
you know,
it's a lot of association so it's like
you should force you to be you
specifically you that's needed more than
ever before.
You know,
like,
like you need to be yourself completely
or if you're a character,
that character needs to be hammered the
fuck down.
Yeah.
And who you are changes depending upon
your environment.
That's one of the things about the
store,
like since I've come back to the store,
it's tightened me up,
it's made me better coming back to the
store because it's like being in that
environment,
being in that pressure cooker with
around all these other creative people
and everybody's constantly getting after
it.
Yeah,
no,
it's great.
It's a really good,
a kind of artist's colony at his best.
It can operate like that.
You can just kind of run them on his
best.
Like I remember nights where we would
run in between rooms even before getting
spot.
It's just to go see each,
you know,
each room,
different comedians and you just kind of
absorb it and watch it and get excited.
Yeah.
You could do three different sets in
that place and have three different
universes.
Like you're in the belly room.
Then you're in the main room and the,
oh,
are those three different world?
There really are three completely
different entities.
It changes people too.
Like that's one of the reasons why
Kennison became who he was because he
was doing those late night spots.
He was doing those same spots at
Holtzman gets those,
those late spots and he just had to
capture people's attention.
So He'd just go out there screaming.
I mean they're really,
I mean he,
you know,
speaking of existing in context of area,
he is the light that is a style that's
just completely created from
frustration.
Yeah.
Other,
other,
other comedians create sim and it's
other comedians and ex wives,
you know,
I mean he,
he had like,
I mean everybody had ex wife jokes,
you know,
there was a lot of that.
Take my wife please,
you know,
that kind of shit.
There was a lot of wife jokes and ex
wife jokes,
but Kennison what he did was just
screaming,
you know,
it was just,
it was just raw and you looked at them,
this is a little fat balding guy,
and you're like,
oh yeah,
he probably had a real rough time of it.
Will you just believe it was hatred?
Remember that video is watching Sam
Kennison.
He was like really late night and um,
maybe it was like 1:00
in the morning and he was like,
every comment just gets,
just gets wires.
Well,
he also came from a,
he was a preacher,
so he had this ability to just rant and
rave from project and he knew the
retina.
Many knew that the fucking,
he had this thing that he would do that.
It was very much like,
like a revival tent,
like one of those tent preachers.
I remember watching them on a married
with children with my dad.
That's my personal.
It is brilliant on their team.
Wasn't he on a show where he played like
someone's conscious?
Oh yeah,
him on the shoulder.
Damn Jamie,
how'd you pull that reference?
Used to watch that show.
Herman's head.
Yeah.
It's funny how you discovered people
like you see them on married with
children and like he shot a wall.
What shot?
They fucking fix the sign at the comedy
store.
I was so depressed when I came back.
I'm like,
oh,
that fixed the kinison whole.
Why would you fix the bullet hole?
He shot.
Shot a hole through the fucking sign in
the parking lot.
You know that sign that's near the back
walkway?
The one that you know in the corner be a
bullet hole in the back of that thing.
They fixed it.
Oh,
it's not there anymore.
They fixed him.
Why did he do it?
Because he's crazy.
Oh,
he had a gun.
I think it was him and dice.
We're in some sort of a fight.
He pulled out a gun and he shot the
sign.
He tried to shoot dice.
I'm like,
no.
I think he just wanted to know that he
would shoot them all coked out of his
legs.
Preacher,
by the way,
that sounds like the store.
It wasn't.
Herman said.
No,
it was not.
That was under the same time the show is
called Charlie Hoover.
Really?
Yeah.
Wow.
I remember him standing on a show.
I remember the image of it.
He was like the devil conscience type
character.
Right?
Is that what it was to matheson?
Oh Wow.
What do that.
Is it and Tim Matheson,
the guy from animal house,
right.
I think why I confused it.
Herman said had four people in his head
and
they don't even do shit like this no
more,
you know,
for good reason.
There's a reason we're scrambling for
the name they have for him with Alex
Jones.
Look those back to those images you just
had.
Go back to the images and then scroll
down.
Scroll down.
Oh,
look,
Alex Jones is in the middle of that.
That's not even kinison.
Wow,
that's Alex.
Wow.
Someone's comparison.
That was a great headshot.
Him screaming.
No,
he was,
uh,
he's the guy that got me into comedy
really in a lot of ways.
Cocaine,
Sam kinison family entertainment.
Our.
Yeah.
He got me into comedy because I thought
Comedians were.
I thought it was like people who go on
the tonight show and they have their
sleeves rolled up,
you
know,
you ever notice.
Here's the crazy thing,
folks like that.
I enjoyed watching that,
but it never seemed like me.
I couldn't,
I couldn't see myself doing it.
People got to stop doing that.
They got to stop doing that.
Like why are you doing the tonight show
set in your Kobe's not even they blocked
is so fucking disrespectful.
They block shoot these things we use
like,
like it's,
they'll do like 10 comedians at a time
and he's not even there and they like
throw to it as if,
you know,
like he's,
it's the rudest thing I've ever heard
and the fact that comedians still go on
the show and would still do it is insane
to me.
Wow.
I didn't know that.
That's insane to me.
So how many they do in around have I
heard like 10?
I could get the number wrong,
but he's not there.
It's not,
you know,
you're just doing like this show in
front of this audience in the studio and
pretends to throw the yellow arrows to
you like you're there and it's like this
thing that's like,
there's nothing,
they're not.
Well,
it's again man,
like,
but it's on,
it's on us as much as it's like,
you know,
of course they're going to do that.
They're going to do that to any,
you know,
any John Rowe entertainment that would
allow such a thing to happen,
they will do it to you.
Right?
You know,
they're not going to do Rhianna's doing,
uh,
these,
these things are so contrived.
Like it's the same set.
You come out in front of the same
curtain.
People put on the same outfit that they
didn't wear yesterday and would never
wear again tomorrow.
And they come out and they pretend to be
a comedian from 1993.
And so,
who the fuck are you?
Who the fuck are you?
What are you fucking doing for a set to
get passed around to a couple of agents
that want to come see you?
Who Cares?
I was talking to the avant about this.
We were talking,
we were talking about like whether it's
worth it being on one of those shows.
No,
no,
it's never.
It's never worth it.
Capturing yourself,
not as yourself.
It's a waste of your time.
Used to be worth something.
This is why it's confusing because there
was no venues before.
So when Johnny Carson would have you on
the tonight show.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
and that was a listening.
It served its purpose.
It was very important at the time it was
an outlet where there weren't a lot of
outlets and now those types of fuck are
we doing?
Yeah.
Especially unless it's like know with
that said,
you know,
Kimmel built,
he built like a club,
like to enhance the audience,
travel from the studio to the club and
the comedians would do it there and it
was like,
oh,
that's like an effort.
You know what I mean?
Like an effort to create.
Yeah.
It was like a space,
a separate studio that like,
you know,
I believe this will do it.
I don't know if I've seen like a Kennel
set sand upset recently,
but uh,
but,
but the,
there was like an effort,
you know,
I've always really appreciated that.
Like,
like,
you know,
at least try like I don't know,
just try.
There are too many options for comedians
to go through the same filter of
capturing themselves,
uh,
in a way that's not authentic to them.
So you're saying that if I go on called
bear,
I should do with my shirt off.
If you want to have his shirt off,
it has a purpose.
You know what I mean?
Like,
like you should,
you should do it.
I do have regular set in the belly room.
Well,
I mean because it's like,
you know,
if standup is art,
right?
If it's,
if it is an art form then it's supposed
to be like the medium is supposed to
come to the artist.
Not the other way around,
you know,
because even even on those same shows,
if you see a live music performance,
like the stagings different,
it's specific to the audience,
you know,
and in the context of a show in a black
production and you have this space,
they fill it in the way that makes sense
to the artist and then it's like,
stand up.
It was just like,
you could just go through a slide show.
Just the exact same think,
you know,
it's,
I guess when the music
artists gets on Colbert,
one of those shows,
they're already kind of famous,
right?
They already have an album out and when
to stand up gets on those shows.
They're trying to get seen come up.
Like maybe you don't have a special yet.
Maybe you just use showcased and they
picked a few people.
You've done any of it yet.
Don't do any of those.
Oh,
specific reason.
Yeah.
I never liked it.
I remember once on like,
uh,
I,
I was gonna do letterman while Letterman
was on Letterman and I remember sending
a,
a set in or whatever,
and they responded was like,
okay,
you know,
we could do it,
but could he do his jokes in a more
traditional setup punchline format?
And I remember just like email them
back,
well,
I'll just do it when I'm famous.
I'm just not going to listen to this
bullshit.
No people,
they change.
That's the other thing they change.
Again,
compare yourself to a musician.
Imagine you're a musician going on and
they're like,
we liked the song,
but cut the bridge,
come first,
and then you do the,
you will be like,
go fuck yourself.
Right?
And the comedians allow like you can't
say pop tart if you say pop.
Exactly.
Comedians allow a Lotta Shit to say
pastry pastry,
but that doesn't make any sense.
We just trying to hit the road drive.
Toaster strudel is trying to hit the
road right now.
I'm in.
Do you man
do
it.
Even back in the day,
it didn't make any sense to me.
They would go,
you should put together a five minute
set for the tonight show,
and I'd be like,
I don't want to do it,
and they're like,
you should do it.
Like it's,
it's good exposure.
This is like the fucking nineties.
Right.
When it actually probably meant I was
like,
I don't,
I don't see it happening.
I'm not doing a not stand up.
You're,
you're,
you're taking a little piece of standup.
Like a short set is 15 minutes and in 15
minutes I might cover two concepts.
You know,
any time I go over things like I get
thorough if I'm,
if I'm talking about a subject,
I get involved in that subject.
I want to,
I want to bring people on a journey and
I also want to be able to set them up.
I want to be able to explain how I think
about things so that by the time I get
to something controversial,
they already have a sense of how I
approach things.
You can't do that in five minutes,
in five minutes.
You just got to just get into it and
it's,
it's a very condensed,
homogenized version of who you really
are.
Man.
We'll just do a late night spot.
Little five minute setup and leave just
to set up.
Just to set up this shake.
Yeah.
I remember I saw Louis do one Louis ck
did one,
one of those letterman or tonight show
or something like that and I was like,
God,
he shouldn't even do this.
It's not.
It's such a.
not a good representation of what he's
capable of.
Well,
some people are like,
Jerry Seinfeld should do.
Yeah.
That he should absolutely do that.
He could do it.
When he does,
he does.
I love Jerry's a tonight show sets.
Yeah.
And his like his makes sense.
Yeah,
it makes sense.
It makes sense.
It's like perfect for and it's like,
it translates very,
very well.
Well,
when I watched those shows today,
I'm like,
why are they still a thing when I see a
late night show and no disrespect
anybody who hosts a late night show,
but to me it's like,
it's like they took a boat and try to
turn into a plane.
Oh,
like,
Hey America,
it's in 2018,
but let's pretend it's not there when be
right back with a commercial.
Hey,
we're going to have commercials,
commercials the thing,
but today everybody watches Hbo and
Netflix.
Like,
what am I doing here?
Sitting through a fucking commercial.
I'm may be weird.
I like because I actually,
I enjoy advertising to do.
Yeah.
I like a lot.
I'll stare at like billboards or watch
commercials have watch like,
oh,
because I do think it,
it speaks to what a,
like America thinks we are as a culture.
You know what I mean?
It speaks to what they think it is
appealing and what they think is gonna
work.
And so in a sense,
it's like,
like in a way,
in the same sense,
like you can gauge a lot from a person
by the types of questions they ask you,
you know,
you engage a lot from like even a
climate by the type of commercials what
they feel is because they're trying to
appeal to everybody.
So this is what they're saying.
This is what we think everybody is
thinking right now,
you know,
or how everyone feels or what they want.
And uh,
but I,
I love,
like I'll watch it and even like the
tonight show in those,
um,
these things.
I mean,
look,
you know,
anything in function at its best is fun.
It's just,
you know,
the,
where it hits a wall and just what we're
saying about comedy and what we're
saying about a lot of things is like
when a thing tries to be something that
it's not,
you know,
when it feels like these late night
shows when they're just doing fun things
that they think are fun and interesting.
I love,
you know,
Kim will always,
every year does like the parents to tell
the kids that know Halloween that they
ate all the Halloween candy and the kids
reactions and stuff.
Like I eat that stuff up.
I love that you're going to be fun.
But,
but like when it,
you know,
when shows pretend to be,
19,
89.
It's just like when comedians pretending
to be of a different era of pretend to
it,
it just feels false and I think that's
where you check out.
Yeah.
It's just unnecessary at this point,
you know,
because of the Internet,
you just have too many other venues.
Yeah.
Well yeah.
It's a lot of options.
Yeah.
A lot of options and the vent,
like watching things on the internet is
so much more satisfying.
It's like watching a comic on a podcast,
you're going to get this chance to
chance to see who the fuck they really
are.
Sort of some weird set in front of some
audience that got shipped in from
Burbank and they got applause.
Signs and everything.
It's very surreal when you go to a live
taping and you watch that.
It's really surreal.
Oh,
it's very like,
and I'll sit at I,
I,
I have like,
you know,
it's always,
I have weird,
a late night thing because I like,
I'm bad at being like the,
you know,
celebrity type of thing.
Like I'm just in it and just like
looking at it and when the crowd is
giving an unnatural reaction to things
is just like,
what do you.
Right.
Too introspective.
You're not going to just dive into the
fake.
I'm like,
hey,
no,
hey bro,
what are we doing for real?
Is this,
what is this like,
what do you,
is this rewarding for you
blah side.
Everybody do.
What do we doing to the uncomfortable
moment?
This is where we'll be right back to
you.
Thank you.
We'll be right back.
That will be right back.
Shit like,
yeah,
where are you going?
They put
those commercials in later.
Just keep rolling.
Can we do and we'll be right back.
It's strange,
man.
The advertisement model of shoving an ad
in every 15 minutes to shove in a series
of ads in.
Yeah.
How the fuck did they ever do that?
Like,
well,
I mean look,
you know,
the unfortunate reality or fortunate Rio
I guess depends on what company you work
for is a.
I mean that's,
it's an advertiser's medium.
Right.
And
they'll find a way to put the
commercials that even with the Internet,
youtube becomes traditional television.
They.
Oh,
this internet commercials are longer
than the TV commercial.
Maybe two minutes.
You can skip them.
Do you get a two minute ones now?
I don't think I like it.
Don't they got like minute to minute.
You know,
I get excited when I see a 15 second one
was like,
oh man.
So we're gonna just sit here going to
sit through Ron Howard's masterclass
again.
Huh?
But did even sometimes you'd be like,
damn this is too long.
Even if it's 15 seconds.
But sometimes I'll look it up.
Commercials and I hate having to watch a
commercial to watch a commercial or like
some type of.
You know what I mean?
Like some type of ad or like a trailer
to something and I'm like,
oh,
now I have to sit through this trailer
to watch the trailer that I'm.
The commercial does kind of show you
what,
what they think the culture is about
right now.
Yeah.
What they think people are interested in
right now.
Like what,
what?
Uh,
a real manipulative,
mainstream version of what the average
think,
think depressed too.
Well,
a lot of people are.
You're not depressed.
No,
I'm good
bastard body going onstage shirtless.
Some people are,
you know,
a lot of people are like,
what percentage do you think,
I mean it's probably more than 20
percent of Americans are depressed.
Let's just,
Hey,
guess what?
A recent poll shows.
It's not going to give us a real good
idea,
but I'll say 20 percent,
20 percent of Americans suffer from
depression.
What do you think?
A form of the.
Or are we saying specifically depression
and we saying like mental
illness,
depression.
It is define.
Yeah.
Yeah,
because I'm just saying it.
It's the reason it's hard to quantify
because it's like,
it also is a thing that comes in phases
or post event specific like depression.
You know what I mean?
That's why I'm just wondering how we're
and I,
I can't believe it's not as easy as man
get over that shit.
Like I can't believe it's not,
but it's not.
Yeah,
that's how I could.
Oh Shit.
Fuck it.
You know exactly.
Like it's hard to like.
It's like,
wow,
you've got a cancer,
get over it.
Like,
man my man.
Oh you mean a tumor?
You mean like specifically like event
based thing.
Like if something has happened that
sparks like sadness,
I forget that there's more than one
reason to be depressed to white,
like six point seven percent.
Six,
16 point 2 million adults in United
States.
Quick Equaling six point seven percent
of all adults in the country who have
experienced a major depressive episode
in the last year.
10 point 3 million US adults experience
in episode that resulted in severe
impairment in the last year.
Wow.
Fifty percent of all people
well diagnosed with depression are also
diagnosed with an anxiety disorder.
It's estimated that 15 percent of the
adult population will experience
depression at some point in their
lifetime,
like posts.
But what does that mean though?
Like if your dog dies was.
I mean you lose a job,
girlfriend breaks up with you.
Yeah,
yeah.
Blog posts I went through,
I remember going through like a real
kind of dark period after losing a
friend like happened twice.
It just like.
And,
and I'm very much so I,
I get the Gemara and mentality of just
like,
I don't know,
Niggas just get over that shit,
but like,
but is that depression?
Uh,
right.
That's a good question.
Yeah.
I don't know clinically like where the
line is as humans.
Like isn't it just highs and lows?
Highs and lows deal with this.
Don't deal with to,
you know,
deal with that.
They what the happiness.
It's highs and lows but it's just your
expectation of what the next phases,
like your expectation.
Like it's all legitimate issues that
people have with mental problems.
Their brain doesn't produce hormones.
Yes.
There's people that are legit.
Serotonin and dopamine issues tomorrow.
I'm so ignorant.
Suicide hotline,
like Nigga that Shit,
get some ice cream,
go outside.
Don't you have friends?
You don't have friends,
your friend.
Fuck your wife.
Your friend was also your boss
and you know,
got a wife.
Okay.
And your dog's gone.
Whereas your dark.
Oh,
your friend took your dog.
Be My favorite episode of Frasier.
Yeah.
Some people have a rough man.
Some people's,
you know,
some.
Some people have leukemia,
some people have genetic disorders,
some people's brains don't work right.
For whatever reason,
whether it's nature or nurture,
there's something going on that's real
bad and they're just.
They're in a whole.
Red.
Described it really well.
He did a podcast recently with me and he
talked about.
He went through a serious depression
episode where he was suicidal and he.
His brain was just the way he described
it as like it was broken and I had to
get it fixed and he started off on
medication than weaned himself off a
medication,
but when he was on the medication,
that's also when his career took off and
when his career took off.
I mean it alleviated a lot of the.
The what a lot of his issues were was
also just like an unfulfilled life
frustration,
expectation,
unrealized and then on top of that
compounded there was like legit mental
issues that were bothering them.
I,
I guess I was just unclear on like what
depression actually is like.
I'm like,
because as you're saying that stuff,
hmm,
maybe I have felt that
everybody feels highs and the lows.
You're right about that for sure.
Right about that.
But you exercise a lot and I think that
probably helps.
Yeah.
I'm just super myself up in my head and
shit.
But no exercising just releases releases
a lot of the bullshit that people carry
around.
A lot of the what makes people feel
terrible is that their body is fighting
against their brain.
Their body holds in so much tension and
there,
there are so fucked up and they never
get an endorphin release and their
bodies like an overflowing battery like
oozing out of the signs
know.
And I always like,
people don't meditate like that.
Don't work for people.
Like this shit works.
That shit killed it for me.
How often you meditate?
Shit.
Like every day,
like how much time?
Twenty minutes.
Oh,
that's good man.
Look,
that is a beautiful thing.
If you could force that into your
schedule and make sure that that's a
part of your life.
I got it from Seinfeld and Oprah now.
Like 10,
maybe 10.
Yeah.
Like,
no,
it's.
I mean it doesn't activate something
that have,
which is like we're supposed to kind of
do that though.
The reflection and also what I think it
does,
one of the real good things that
meditation does is it stops momentum
because there's like a momentum of
shitty thoughts and bad ideas and bad
decisions and just anxiety and all these
issues that could fucking just
accumulate inside your consciousness and
they never went unaddressed.
They continue to like push it.
You from the back and it's like you're
just constantly in a state of momentum
of all the bullshit that's going on.
But if you have a time for real
reflection and just pause,
even if you're just concentrating only
on your breath,
one,
it seems to stop that momentum and give
you a chance at like a renewed
perspective.
Active.
Yeah,
that,
that's correct.
Remember at the time I had a spiritual
awakening in your house.
What happened?
What was it about?
It just hit them.
One day I was watching,
I was watching like a seinfeld interview
or something.
He was like,
yeah,
I do it twice a day.
And I was like,
man,
let me see.
This all went down.
I used to live with them so I use.
I went downstairs with my room and I
meditated and I came back upstairs and I
was like,
he was sitting on the couch and I was
like,
I was like,
Nigga,
I just had an awakening.
It was like,
what happened?
I was like,
oh no man,
but the first,
the first message I got was a,
you can't save the world,
but you could help.
He was like,
okay,
I'm going to back down in my room.
So when you do it,
what's your process like?
What is what it,
how exactly you practice tm?
A sit there,
cross my legs,
uh,
in through the nose,
out the mouth and through the nose,
out the mouth.
You get into the state.
Also though,
has the ability to completely clear his
mind like he's one of those people that
uh,
it takes me anywhere from
20 minutes,
so like an hour to fall asleep.
Even if tired,
it's still like,
all right,
there's a Gemara.
Could immediately,
immediately just like,
all right,
I'll being awake is over.
All right.
And then just fall asleep.
Like instantaneously.
He can clear his head really quickly.
Like focus on one thing.
You've got a high level of.
I don't give a very high level.
Yeah,
no you are,
you are.
So congrats for us.
So you go in through the nose,
out through the mouth.
And what are you thinking when you're
doing that?
Uh,
nothing,
nothing.
Just are you thinking about the
breathing?
Um,
well I think about nothing.
And then if I have a task or something,
like if I'd be like,
you could do affirmations,
you know,
like,
hey man,
I want it.
I want to be great on stage tonight or I
want to,
or I wanna I want to get this writing
done or I want to,
you know what I'm saying?
Or eat you can hype yourself up and shit
like that.
Like a big it,
um,
your intention.
It's just sad.
Whatever intention that you want to do,
you know what I'm saying?
You set that hey,
I want to,
you know,
whatever the fuck.
And then it'll be easier to complete
that task.
For me,
I have add,
I'm bad at focusing on things but that
really helps me.
You have add but you don't have a
problem meditating.
Yeah.
Because,
because it's the lazy,
it's really good at being lazy and it's
kind of lazy to like meditate them.
It's Kinda like I was like,
you guys are like to move in.
Yeah.
It just sit there and fucking zone out
and shit.
Like if you like mushrooms and all that
shit.
You know what I'm saying?
This shit is perfect for you.
It's getting high off your own dmt.
That's what it is.
It's just you on Dmt,
the spirit molecule,
all that shit.
I don't know if it's that because you
don't,
you're not tripping,
right?
It is,
it's an essay.
It's,
it's Kinda.
You ever do it right?
Uh,
no.
I,
I've gone through phases where I tried
meditation,
I shower for an hour,
15 minutes.
So that's kind of
already though.
Just kind of walk around and think,
yeah,
I,
I kinda,
you know,
I don't know.
I,
I've tried it,
but it's,
oh,
they eat work out though and it's,
you know,
those endorphins that you read,
you can just do that.
You could also do that by just sitting
there and just breathe in and you know,
focusing on the breath and then all of a
sudden your mind starts going into an
altered state and then you'll start.
Yeah,
I meditate.
I just don't meditate every day.
But uh,
I definitely feel it.
I think exercise does that,
especially cardio and especially yoga,
something about yoga classes that just
forces you into this state of mind where
you just are,
you're only concentrating on the
movements that you're supposed to do.
So if you could clear your head and stay
focused on the movements and not delve
into your bank account or your fucking
credit card debt or what's wrong with
your car,
what are the bullshit you have bounced
around in your head?
If you could just
take the time to concentrate only on the
yoga.
It has this like a cleansing effect.
It,
it really made you be like,
man,
fuck that shit.
Fuck that shit.
Most things,
most things are not worth freaking out
about.
Most.
The vast majority.
A good question.
I don't remember
reading is a,
just ask yourself what problems do I
have right now but genuinely like
problems and the answer may not always
be zero,
but it's usually surprisingly small.
When you think about the immediate,
you know,
not just the base level of maslow's
hierarchy,
you know,
like if that's taken care of usually
it's like Oh I don't re,
you know,
there are things that are ongoing things
to figure out,
but like things that you could define as
like a problem and then just kind of
staying in that space you have like,
you know,
like a control issue.
Like what's a real issue where there's
like immediacy,
like you know,
and,
and when,
when there are real problems,
you know,
a lot of times you,
you handled it well,
like instinctually the things like a lot
of times people get caught in those
intense situations,
like they can handle like real problems.
It's the anticipation of problems and
the anticipation of solutions that bass.
It's a very good point.
Yeah,
that's a very good point.
Yeah.
A lot of times real problems.
They also sort of enlightened you to the
fact that most of the time you,
your problems are bullshit.
You know,
you break your leg,
you're,
oh,
this is.
Yeah.
That's an immediate.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And so just staying in the space of
like,
you know,
alright I can,
you're in a control center.
You Go,
you know what helps me is a bit like.
Because Yoga is hard to do,
doing things that are difficult to do.
Make things easier,
make other things easier,
working out hard workouts,
make other things easier.
Yeah.
Running hills,
kickboxing,
anything give us context.
It gives context to everything drawn up
and makes Hollywood interactions easy.
There you go.
You know what I mean?
Like it,
it gives context.
Yeah.
What is the struggle was like,
well,
it's like,
you know,
someone by the time you get on stage
you're like,
well,
my body thought it was going to die this
morning.
Yeah.
And it didn't.
So this is fine.
Yeah.
Now this tag doesn't work.
Do you guys know very many people that
do Jitsu?
No.
Uh,
and by very many,
I mean,
uh,
you,
yeah,
that's the most chill people ever
because they getting choked all the
time.
They're fighting for their life every
day.
So there's,
so there's so many events to train the
killers trying to break their arms.
If the experience is not that cool,
then it's like whatever,
man,
I'm not worried about it that much.
Yeah.
We,
you know,
the world is pretty soft right now.
It's easy to get upset about nonsense.
Nonsense is the only thing that you have
that's a difficulty in your life.
Well,
it's,
and it's perspective.
The reward for complaints.
Hm.
Uh,
it's like a culture.
That's where we are rewarded for
publicly,
you know,
for having a public completion.
Me,
I'm well rewarded in the sense of like,
you know,
you get a,
you can get attention for,
you can get attention for light,
but I'm just saying by publicly airing
a,
you know,
a grievance about a project and I'm
speaking especially specifically about
how we respond to content is just like,
like a by publicly saying this,
you can speak to your respective group
and you have an immediate reward for it.
So it's like,
you know,
it's like,
I don't even know if we're more
sensitive.
We're just more outspoken about,
you know,
things well because we have a definitely
more outraged.
They're looking to get outraged.
That's,
that's a really common thing now that
just didn't exist a few days.
I don't even think it's,
I don't even think it's outrageous.
You know what I mean?
Like I,
I really don't think it's outrageous as
much as it cause outrage.
We've seen what outrage looks like at
the,
when at the peak of like the black lives
matter movement where people at a core
is by people outraged.
Yeah.
But that's the streets,
but that's what I'm saying,
but that's what,
that's what outrage is and I don't want
to confuse that with like,
you know,
ational outreach,
restoration or outrage.
Right.
And it's really important to draw that
distinction.
Right.
And so it's like,
it's,
again,
people are vocal about things.
Some issues real,
a lot of things we started getting upset
about there.
Like certain we get upset about certain
cultural appropriation things of the
week because it's a Sushi restaurant on
a college campus.
Like we,
we get caught up in those things but in
and not focus on,
you know,
like I dunno,
it's like real outrageous.
The thing that corporations or afraid of
is an outrage.
It's trending.
You don't want to trend negatively for
like whatever period of time when,
when people are upset with you and that
you've done something genuinely wrong,
they'll show it beyond.
It will extend that if it makes sense.
Yeah.
I think that a lot of what outrages is
like comedian trying out jokes,
you know,
you try out jokes and 30 percent of them
are just straight bullshit
fucking work,
man.
He'd try him.
They they stumble out,
you gave it a shot or you'll ad Lib
something in the moment on stage and
even after you say like,
what the fuck did I just say?
I think there's some of that that people
are trying to.
Like I was reading this article the
other day about some woman who's saying
that yoga is supporting white supremacy
because it's,
it was the dumbest shit ever.
Some Indian lady,
she was seeing the cultural
appropriation of yoga by white people is
supporting white supremacy and it was,
you know,
it's really fun.
What are we doing exactly?
What the fuck are we doing?
But that's what she did is she tried a
bad joke,
you know,
she's a,
she works on,
she's a professor at some bullshit
college where they're just drowning in
liberal arts and she just figured out a
way to say something outrageous that she
thought made sense in her own weird
bubble.
But this got published in a newspaper
and then the whole world went just
collectively.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Yeah,
but that's what it's like.
It's like you are.
I try and a bit late night at the store.
You Do,
you just just riff something and it just
goes into a corner and just get stuck.
Roomba vacuum cleaner things is bouncing
off the wire.
Like this is not working.
I've got to bail out of this.
Yeah,
know.
It's funny because it is people's
favorite rage.
It's a creative force.
She's like,
she tried to make outrage where it
didn't exist
and sometimes he catches right?
Like hoop earrings.
White girls can't wear hoop earrings
anymore.
Was scared.
Were hooping hearings because they're
getting called out for cultural
appropriation by which is hilarious by
Latina chicks.
This particularly Latino chicks are
saying and it's just all social justice
warrior bullshit.
But what's really funny is.
So I had.
Because I'm an asshole,
I had to google it.
Well who the fuck invented hearings?
The Sumerians,
the,
the oldest version of hoop earrings is
for 2,500 BC from Iraq.
So Iraqis are the only ones who really
can claim cultural appropriation.
People wearing hoop earrings,
not Mexicans.
So Mexicans settled down those white
girls alone because you stole it.
It was black girl.
Shit.
Shit,
it's like who invented pants?
Your culture appropriating.
You're wearing pants.
Who invented paper?
You're on a Korean phone,
bitching about people
talking about man,
it goes deep.
It's crazy.
People losing their mind,
they're looking for things get outraged
at and so that they're trying jokes,
they're taking swings,
you know,
the trying to pitches out there,
just spit balling.
Well,
I mean eventually if it's like,
if you,
you're gonna run out of ways to approach
it,
you know what I mean?
Like you run out of.
We're run out of places to stab the
thing.
Will they try some that don't stick or
some stick for like a couple of days,
like you remember Bossy,
they're trying to say you can't say
bossy.
No.
Why can't call girls bossy?
It's sexist crows.
Girls Bossy.
Don't call them bossy sex.
He was a thing where they were trying to
stop the use of the word
or the phrase bossy.
Bossy.
Sexist.
Yeah.
See?
But like,
like can I ask a question?
Where did,
uh,
when,
when did,
uh,
when did cunt become a bad word?
It depends on who's here in England,
man.
They don't give a fuck.
Is that lumping a herd the herd used
until,
I mean,
nobody.
I didn't grow up around it.
I didn't hear people saying this.
I don't even think I heard it used until
late.
I mean,
I was probably
like a Hollywood where it.
Yeah.
No,
it's a word that you used when you used
it.
You fucking really were angry.
Yeah.
It just,
I don't know where it came from.
It's like the new bitch.
It's not new.
I mean it was around a long.
It's been around.
So I was in high school,
but you called someone a continent high
school.
Mind you were ready to fight or brother
Shit would get deep.
You couldn't say con.
You could say,
bitch,
you're a fucking bitch.
You know,
like,
yeah,
you're up con.
Oh,
like would they be like,
what the fuck did you just say?
Ask?
Yeah,
I,
uh,
yeah,
I,
I didn't hear it a lot
and I could never imagine myself
casually called and some money can't.
But if you lived in England,
you could.
Especially if I lived in Australia,
they call someone a good con.
He's a good con.
Oh,
so it's a nice word.
Yeah.
He's,
he's a,
he's a good dude.
He's a good con.
Like people have,
uh,
my friend,
Israel at a Sandhya style bender,
he wears a shirt that says good con and
he just wanders around.
It's from New Zealand because they don't
want people.
They think it's gonna upset.
People get upset about.
He's a savage.
You'd better be careful.
Get upset with him
because he's a UFC fighter.
Oh,
okay.
All right.
Yeah,
he's a,
I mean,
he's,
he's from another country.
It means a different thing in New
Zealand.
If you say con in New Zealand,
it's a,
it's like,
I mean,
what's the equivalent will be equivalent
of con,
the way they said.
Good Dude.
He's a good fucker.
He's a,
he's a cool motherfucker.
He's a good client.
Were you asking because
their wears that everywhere.
No one says shit.
Yeah.
Well,
yeah,
but they sell those shirts.
Look good con.
I don't know
why censorship Hashtag fuck censorship.
Hashtag make gray together.
Well,
I was gonna say,
is it,
is it that,
uh,
we're just like,
people's reaction to it just kind of
bothered it.
Yeah.
I'm like,
that's it.
It's a terrible,
terrible,
bad word like that where it sucks.
Like,
motherfucker,
you don't like it,
but don't think it's fun to say,
you know,
rhythmically it's just trash.
It's like I,
I was going off it.
What?
Interesting.
Shit,
I don't know if you went to Australia
though,
they,
they would say it so many times.
It would just slip in.
Just gets normal.
Yeah,
I guess,
yeah,
it is just,
it's this one syllable like con.
It means dude over there sometimes.
And this fucking cat,
he goes over there and they'll start
talking about it.
Like this fucking dude.
They'll still literally say it in the
same way you would say this fucking guy.
It's just a different thing.
I mean,
look,
they're all just sounds to convey
expression in the world problems.
When you demonize one,
you say you can't say the c word
anymore.
Don't say the c word.
Well,
yeah,
I mean again,
it's just like,
I just want us to have like adult
arguments.
Yeah,
right.
Well it's hard to have adult arguments,
even forbidden words.
Well,
yeah.
Well because that's like the,
the shit that your sister got mad at you
about growing up.
Right.
You caught me.
You know what I mean?
It is kind of like,
that's the thing.
It's,
I mean you were saying intention
earlier,
but I mean there's always like
intention.
Like what do you mean by I get it,
I get in these types of my mom,
southern Christian woman in any curse
word that I say any curse words is very.
She,
she doesn't,
she doesn't like it and I,
I curse around all the time.
I'll always do just because we get into
the argument while simultaneously
respecting her views and beliefs.
It's also like,
you know,
these cuss words read.
Did you fucking kitchen lady
know I love her.
I love watching her,
like react to it.
Like it's like fun.
Yeah.
Because just like,
oh,
this through the filter of you,
like really,
you know?
See,
I grew up non suppressed.
My parents were hippies and they didn't
give a shit where we said we just
couldn't really say it at school,
but you know,
there was no like language restrictions
in my house and be allowed to say
anything.
That's great.
It was weird.
That was great.
And my friends would come over the
house.
Did you just say fuck in front of your
mom?
Like yeah,
fuck it.
I used to.
I,
I did.
You grow up around people that like used
to just talk shit back to the mall is
like,
it would never did that.
It was fun too.
I had a friend,
right?
Alex is still one of my favorite moments
of life.
It was just like we came,
I came to this house after school and
his mom's name is Patricia and she was
just like,
I'll take out the garbage.
He was like,
go to hell.
Pat says,
respond to calls,
mom.
Passion.
I caught it on fire.
Like my mind was blown,
told his mom to go to hell.
It was like amazing.
And she just argued back like it was.
Yeah,
single mama was a data around,
uh,
he knows that,
but he wasn't around,
but it was amazing.
It was amazing.
That's a struggle that.
Who's the man?
When did you start cussing around your
mom?
It's been a few hours.
No,
I probably started A.
I moved out when I was a teenager.
I probably,
I mean she's heard me say it kind of
throughout,
but just in income,
like not stopping it in conversation.
It's been years.
I mean I just always just kind of flow.
I'm low key,
still afraid because a lot from my mom
cuffs in front of my niece and nephew.
Just how old are they all have money.
I have an 11 year old niece,
a nine year old nephew,
a couple two year old twins,
three year old niece,
like just,
and I am myself and speak exactly how I
normally speak around it.
You're an adult longer than you're a
kid,
you know.
And so it was just like,
why am I going to pretend the world
sounds different?
Look,
I,
I'm with you.
But it felt like whose kids are there?
Your brothers?
My brother,
your brother and sister in law,
everybody cool with that or they get
upset.
A vague.
I mean they go like sometimes,
but it's also they get it.
They mocked my brother that they're very
understanding why they.
They get it.
They get that.
It's just like how people talk.
It's so.
Yeah.
I mean I think that's important.
Again,
like you don't want to.
That's the thing man.
Just like this.
No,
you fucked up.
If you're at a job where not on keen,
not swear,
but you can't swear off job with the
people you work with or does that tell
or they'll get.
Yeah,
you can get trouble.
Yeah.
He,
if there's certain jobs where people
have,
where they got off work and they went
out with some coworkers and they told a
dirty joke or started talking shit like
that will get back to human resources
and there'll be fired.
Bosses are now following their employees
online and shit like twitter.
That girl that got fired from NASA.
Fucking hilarious.
She got fired from NASA yesterday.
She was like,
Holy Fuck.
I got a job at NASA and some guy tweeted
her.
He said language and she said,
suck my Dick and balls.
I work at NASA,
and he said,
yeah,
and I am one of the people that oversee
something at Nasa and then it was
not.
Well she was about to be an intern
working at NASA and she was like,
here it is.
Everyone shut the fuck up.
I got accepted for a NASA internship and
look,
he writes language.
She says,
suck my Dick and balls.
I'm working at NASA and he says,
I'm on the National Space Council that
oversees NASA.
Come on,
first of all,
that shit is funny.
Suck my dick and balls and it's a girl.
Second of all,
we didn't even go to the fucking
the moon.
I saw you talking about that.
Yeah.
No,
I,
I don't.
I could.
I can be convinced.
I was convinced that we didn't for a
long time.
Now I'm convinced.
I have no fucking idea.
Yeah,
I don't really.
I,
it's,
I don't think we went to the moon just
off of base.
It's not rooted in science.
How much?
How much have you really paid attention
to it?
[inaudible].
I went down the rabbit hole for many,
many years.
I go off kind of like,
it's always like the social kind of
where there's smoke,
there's fire type foods of just like,
you know,
us being in a race and no countries
coming second,
uh,
you know,
other space programs not catching up to
1969,
19,
72 American technology,
you know what I mean?
Like,
uh,
every time we went was under the Nixon
administration.
That's a good one.
A,
these types of little things that just
make you go
like a flat earthers conference.
You've ever watched the press conference
when they returned from the moon?
Uh,
no.
Wait,
what,
what's,
what's the,
what's the clue in there or what's the
suspicious thing?
They look super depressed.
They look a super deceptive.
They look fidgety and uh,
they're,
they're talking weird and they're saying
shit.
They refute later.
One of the things they said,
Michael Collins,
who's actually never,
he's supposed to be in.
He'd never landed on the surface of the
moon.
Buzz Aldrin and Neil Armstrong did.
He stayed up in the orbiter and uh,
they were,
they were asking about stars and he
said,
um,
uh,
I don't recall seeing any stars.
And then years later he wrote in his
book about how magnificent stars look.
There's a lot of that shit,
but the press conference,
if you want,
and this doesn't mean anything,
I'm not a cop,
but if I was a cop and I was
interviewing them,
I'd be like,
these motherfuckers are guilty.
Something is wrong here.
Like they,
they seem like guilty people and you
could look.
You don't get to say,
hey man,
they were probably psychologically
distressed.
They were probably dealing with the,
the pressure of having come back from
the moon and all this fame that they had
never experienced their whole life.
They're not there.
Their astronauts,
they're scientists.
And now all of a sudden they're standing
in front of all these people and
everyone's asking them questions and
they feel super nervous.
But like,
Nah,
these niggas was lying.
Let me tell you everybody.
My favorite thing is when you,
when a [inaudible],
I'll say it very casually,
if people become like,
you know,
patriots and rocket scientists to tell
you like how we went,
I'm like,
you don't know either.
Well,
all this shit is bullshit because it
wasn't unit wasn't me,
so let's stop with that.
So we probably lied about it and we live
better than any other country on earth
and I'm proud of that.
There's a lot of weird shit with the
video footage.
There's a lot of footage where it looks
like they're on wires dangling from
wires and they bounced back up from
their feet in this weird way.
It looks they're being yanked up from
the ground.
There's a video where it looks like
they're on trampolines
is if you google astronauts on
trampolines.
I'm not even kidding.
It just looks like that.
I actually put it up.
It's a video that I found Google
astronauts on trampolines is a video on
youtube and you're watching them bounce
around and you're like,
wait a minute,
wait a minute.
You guys are on the fucking moon and
you're hiding behind the lunar module,
like you can't see their feet,
you can't see how they're doing this,
but it looks like either they're
bouncing on something or the being
yanked up in the air or it's one,
six gravity and it's just has a weird
effect on people will look at this,
watch this.
Oh,
how strange is this?
See,
look,
you just lands.
But doesn't that.
I mean even the way he's,
he's moving,
it's like he's being dangled.
It's very strange to see him bouncing
around,
but that also
just all the stuff we did at,
but we like playing golf with belts
around,
like the moon landing set was built by
the people who made the discovery zone,
but it also
could be.
This slide
just jumped up and fell.
That's so strange,
but it also could be.
This is just what your body does at one
six.
Earth's gravity.
You know,
there's a whole.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I'm excited to see.
Uh,
this one's weird.
Someone else going back to the moon and
then if it matches.
This is from a movie.
I forget what was the name of the movie
was,
but you could watch some of the NGO,
the show,
some special effects they use in movies,
but watch some of the weird shit go a
little bit further ahead of this.
Yeah,
right there.
There's some of the weird stuff where
you see these guys like fall down and
then it looks like they just get yanked
back up by wires is very strange.
Yeah.
I mean,
but the press conferences is trained.
It's the,
it's the social aspect of it cause it's
like I don't begin to know like how the
flag is supposed to look in the waving
and the shadows and the thing that a lot
of people argue about,
I,
it's just the political and so it's
like,
I kinda think I know when the government
is lying about something.
You know what I mean?
Like the history is there.
Watch this,
watch this,
watch how he gets up like you'd gotten
yanked up.
There's a bunch of those.
It makes it look like there are wires
pulled back up their feet.
Very strange.
But again,
have you ever been in one six earth
gravity?
I haven't.
No.
What that maybe.
Maybe it just looks fake because when
you're in one six earth gravity,
it's just how movement do you think?
We never ever been like up until day my,
my,
my conspiracy belief is specific to
thinking that a man has walked around on
the surface of the specific to the
crashing,
you know,
lunar,
whatever.
That's all.
One hundred percent.
Yeah,
of course.
It's specifically
man.
Moving
it specifically that you don't think
anybody has ever done this?
I don't think so.
No.
In life.
Like everyone's just saying we're the
only country that would have the press
conference,
some clips,
weird clips from the press conference
because the,
the press conference it,
trip you out and see and see.
Just like other,
you know,
countries who have the means to do it.
Like they're in intention about going
place in this place in medicine.
Go big screen.
Look how sad these guys look.
So we're.
This
was our pleasure to have in one great
adventure.
It's an adventure that took place not
just in the month of July,
but rather one that took place in the
last decade.
We all hear and the people listening in
today had the opportunity to share that
adventure over.
It's developing an unfolding
in the past months and years.
It's our privilege today to share with
you
some of the details of that final month
of July.
That was
certainly the highlight for the three of
us have of that decade.
They just went to the moon and they all
looked like they just saw the naked part
of it.
They also have a alliance.
You tell him,
Neil,
it looks so fake,
but again,
that could be just extreme nerves.
It can be people that don't know how to
handle being in front of press.
It could be a introverts that are forced
on the camera,
can be a lot of issues.
If you went to the moon and then you
came back and uh,
you were sitting at press conference,
would you be at the light?
Like what would your,
what would your actions be?
Would you be like?
Or would it be like more like,
like it would be,
it would look like a,
like,
like a lake was a press conference after
they want you back.
I have my hat on champagne.
Just pointing to reporters.
And why did they bring back like a rock
or something?
Oh,
they did.
They brought it back a lot.
Brought back many rocks,
but some of them turned out to be
petrified wood.
They gave one of them too.
Yeah.
They gave a moon rock in 69 or 72 hours.
The Prime Minister of Holland,
whoever it was,
whatever.
Who.
The person who runs Holland and a years
later they analyze it and it was
petrified wood who was not a moon rock.
In fairness.
In fairness,
I do get the,
like by the
time we got to Holland,
the gift basket is going to change when
I given away the real moon rocks to
Holland.
Yeah.
Like that.
Like you know,
England gets some real moon rock.
Yeah.
France gets a little rough,
but they get a little thing of the moon
rocks.
They the statute skill which you think
you got some dudes.
Did you think about this Mars mission?
Look,
that's all real rovers are real.
It's all the technology's proven and
legitimate and I don't think you'd ever
fake anything today.
Like you could fake things in 1969 if I
think,
if anything for sure.
What they did is it's been proven that
they faked some footage for sure.
Some photographs recorded over the
original.
Again,
those little things.
It's like you recorded over the irt.
Yeah.
The original in a world where even the
importance of syndication was known.
I think they also lost a telemetry data,
which is like the binary hard ones and
Zeros that show the distance between the
earth and lunar module and every step of
the trip they lost it.
Yeah.
They lost that Shit,
you know.
Then again,
you gotta realize like people die and
people responsible for storage and no
one's paying attention and there's
funding and the funding gets pulled and
this,
this plausible reasons for some of the
house.
I mean there are episodes of blossom
being guarded in a vault somewhere in
burbank,
episodes of blossom.
You could get fucking money off of
blossom.
He can't make any money off of these God
damn moon landing clips.
Look,
there's some people that absolutely are
convinced that we didn't go and I used
to be one of them and I would love if
they proved that it was fake.
It would make me more happy than
anything else in the world.
You know what a I'll would make me very
happy.
So I.
The the thing that keeps me holding on
to maybe we went is a tour at Nasa once
and they were nice.
That's probably it.
Then.
That was nice.
But you gotta realize those aren't the
same people.
You know when people say like no lies.
Okay,
but those were NASA from 1969.
These are different humans.
You know,
you're talking about 48 fucking years
ago.
These are completely different humans.
They stand on the backs of lives.
Yeah.
Well there was a list of NASA so we can
let us ask questions if you going to
fucking lie.
That's what you say about the tour.
Stop inviting those to NASA and allowing
us to ask questions.
If you're going to lie.
I don't think they think they're lying.
I don't think they're involved in,
if any.
If there was a conspiracy,
like say if they did fake the moon
landing.
No one today who's alive as a part of
that,
except Buzz Aldrin.
He's the only one still alive,
but you know,
he,
he just,
he punched the dude in the face,
punched some guy.
What did he said he was Bart seabrook
parts.
Seabrook made a move.
I had dinner with them.
Yeah,
yeah.
Dinner with him many years ago and back
when I was a full blown a moon
nonbeliever and you know,
I'm contacted them and got ahold of him.
Took him to dinner and
you use your celebrity for good.
It was
just like these real specific pockets of
people that you just want to talk to.
It's like,
yeah,
well I wanted to do that,
but.
So you can see someone doing interviews,
you could see someone in an edited
format and you kind of get a sense of
who they are.
You don't really get a sense of who they
are until you actually talk to them like
you and him sharing a plate of pasta.
What was this like?
What did he,
did he give you anything that's like
gives context so like that moment or
like just like why did it?
Uh,
he was convinced he was absolutely
convinced that it was a hoax and he
would,
he was convinced was that there was a
space race between us and Russia and
that it was a,
it was essentially a militarized space
race.
And what they were trying to do is prove
military superiority.
If you had the rockets that could get
you to the moon,
your technology was superior.
And the way he framed it is like the
United States had control over what was
aired and they put it on television and
no one foresaw the future.
No one foresaw that.
One day you would be looking at these
clips on youtube and analyzing them and
putting them in slow Mo.
They didn't even think that that was
going to be a thing on television that
works.
Yeah.
And They were going to show it in black
and white and they were going to have it
three d projected so that you would
project projected on a screen and then
people who were filming it would have to
film the screen.
Like they.
They didn't even get a live feed when it
was airing on television.
It was airing people filming the screen
that it was being projected on.
What?
Yeah,
yeah.
They broke it down.
So it looked more and more a grainy and
fake like they.
If you were trying to do something that
was not done to the technology of the
day,
that would possibly obscure some fraud.
They did it all those ways.
There's so many things that they did
that you would go.
it's,
it's in,
in terms of like conspiracies.
It's a conspiracy theorists wet dream
because if it is a fake is the biggest
fake of all time.
And there's so many things that are
squirrely about it.
There's so many things.
It doesn't mean it's fake.
Yeah.
But there's so many things.
So has anybody been to them?
No.
No one's been to the moon since 1969 to
1972.
There was the only trips they did.
Seven attempts,
six of them successful.
Apollo 13 was the one that wasn't
successful.
That was that big movie.
Um,
they landed on the moon and then came
back seven times 262,000 miles away.
Now here's where it gets crazy.
Or plus or minus depending on where the
moon's out.
And what's crazy is 260,
2000 miles.
It's pretty far.
Which crazy.
No,
no,
no.
My bad.
I'm
thinking about,
oh,
that's three zeroes
because I was like,
what map or you see,
interesting that no other human space
mission where a human has been a part of
it since then has ever gone more than
400 miles from the earth's surface is
that where the uh,
space station,
all the space shuttle missions,
everything.
EverYthing was outside.
It was further than 400,
400 miles.
So the guy you hAd dinner with did what?
For buzz aldrin to sock them.
He told buzz aldrin he was a liar.
He said you're a liar and a crook.
And buzz went pitch
popped him.
right.
The job.
Has anyone contacted them after that?
I mean,
I'd imagine.
I don't know what he's doing.
I mean immediately after.
No,
no,
no.
The guy bart cbo.
But I mean immediately after the punch.
Is there any type of.
Like.
I think he tried to press charges and
the cops told him to go fuck off.
I think it was one of those folks.
it was,
it wasn't the best punch either.
I mean if you go to the hospital from
that punch,
buzz was like in his eighties at the
time.
But he tried,
he followed,
he harassed a lot of those guys.
He harassed a lot of the astronauts and
tried to get him to swear on bibles.
he'd bring a bible and this bible that
you want on the moon.
Yeah,
I mean it was.
There was a lot of.
There's a lot of weird shit.
There's another one that's a 25th
anniversary of the apollo moon missions.
He gives a speech at the white house in
front of this group of honor roll
students,
like some of the best students in the
country near armstrong.
Gives us real weird fucking speech is
like we have here amongst us.
You want to hear it?
If I find
what makes it weird,
when you'll see it,
you'll get it.
It's just real.
It doesn't mean we didn't go to the
moon.
It doesn't mean that it's fucking weird.
It's really funny because I presented it
as like,
yeah,
I don't think we went and I didn't even
have half of what you're getting.
Oh,
I'll give you a way more.
there's a lot.
Watch this.
You're going to watch this and held back
tears as he spoke these brief.
This is from a funny thing happened on
the way to the moon part,
cbos moving,
but this is a real thing that happened
today.
We had
a group of students among america's best
to you.
We say we have only completed a
beginning.
We leave you much.
That is under.
There are great ideas.
Undiscovered
breakthroughs available to those who can
remove one of truths,
protective layers.
What he is the clock.
Okay,
well two things that mean a little
unfair to it and you add that fucking
wanker music to anything.
Everything sells incredibly creepy,
but it's true,
but it does sound like a one of truth.
You're trying to
get more cryptic and you also can't get
more exciting.
It almost sounds like seat theorists and
almost kind of sounds like he's like
into the child who actually figures out
how to go to the fucking moon.
They're great breakthroughs for those
who can remove one of truce protective
layers.
What would you.
What would you rather the the moon
confession or the art kelly confession,
if you had to pick one r kelly made a
song.
Oh yeah.
I need that moon confession.
Yeah.
I need that movie.
Art kelly.
I don't need that confession.
I'm good.
No,
that's up to the wall.
Now think the law is going to have a
piece of that,
you know,
are kelly seems to be pretty tough lawn,
but the moon confession would be
fascinating.
I will be be excited or like a moon.
Like I dunno,
I guess it's not on them to prove that
they went.
So I'm saying like,
you know,
just some type of light.
I may 19,
69.
It's a different world.
Nixon's president,
I don't know if they did lie.
I don't know.
Yeah,
I used to think I knew a.
Do not think I know.
I mean it's foolish.
I don't know jack shit about
astrophysics,
but I know if there was a lie,
you know,
if there's any president we would guess
would be down.
It'd be trump.
he did tell us about it.
Well,
know what I'm saying,
what I'm saying?
Like I'm saying like nixon just like it.
It is a perfect storm of like
nixon.
Yeah.
Oh,
he's the most deceptive president of all
time except the current one.
Yeah.
Um,
yeah.
It's,
uh,
I'm,
I'm it.
It's very interesting.
I,
I've shut down a lot of barbecues was
talking about just bringing it up.
Now you have more information.
And by the way,
this is a fraction of the shit that I
did.
I did research for years.
I debated a,
uh,
scientists on penn jillette's radio show
about it.
How did it go?
Pretty good for me.
Even though I don't even agree with some
of the shit that I said back.
Where does that argument end on just a
agree to disagree?
It was a time constraint.
I wouldn't do it far differently.
Now I think far differently now that I
did that,
I would not take this.
I know we didn't do it approach because
I don't know.
We didn't do it and that's the thing I.
I very casually go,
probably not,
but it just.
The things that don't add up to me don't
add up in a way that just makes me go.
Yeah.
Do you know about the van allen
radiation belts?
You know about all that?
Not enough to like there's a,
there's a belt of radiation,
like a doughnut shaped from just years
of.
It's just naturally surrounds the earth.
Oh,
you know what I'm thinking about?
I'm thinking about the.
Nevermind.
I'm thinking about the belt of from
years of like satellites and so there's
that shit too,
but that wasn't much of that in 1969.
Not near what it.
What about it?
The van allen radiation belts is intense
ban of radiation for miles that,
that surrounds the earth that you would
have to go through to get to the moon.
So they apparently though there's a hole
that you could go through and the top
with the radiation belt isn't there,
but the idea is that there was no
shielding to protect them from
radiation.
They just weren't in this aluminum tin
can you were touched or lunar module if
they have a.
There was a science exhibit I went to
once that had a,
a replica of the lunar module and you
can put your hands on it and it's like,
whoa,
this thing is,
oh really made a coke cans and it's like
nothing so weird looking.
There's also like photographs that are
fucking wanky lights that go at two
different angles and they say,
well that's possible due to uneven
terrain and you know,
things reflecting off of things,
all these different variables.
I also really enjoy just like playing
around and the.
It was this houston.
Oh wow.
Is that a space shuttle?
The shuttle.
I'm you see I have a music.
This is.
You've seen these.
You're another dude that walks around
with a phone with no case on this.
This is me on the.
Well,
you don't put a case on your phone to
lose jobs.
Died so that we could a sleekness you're
a risk taker.
I liked the feel of the phone.
That's neil degrasse tyson was sitting
in that seat 24 hours ago,
so the exact same thing he has is with
no case I need it.
I was like,
well,
we could only be here now.
He would go crazy on us.
He's one of the reasons why I dropped
it.
Talking to him.
I'm like,
yeah,
it doesn't really.
Yeah.
Why?
He's dedicated his whole life.
So the idea of it.
Well,
you know what else he hasn't.
He's dedicated his whole life to
science,
but I know but I'm just saying like to
the,
like the way that like that's part of
it.
It's part of like the kid growing up
there is an adult during conspiracy
theories.
He's got too much other shit to think
about this real.
He's thinking about actual real science.
Like he doesn't have time for that
nonsense,
but he will aluminate you on why he
thinks it's stupid and it would be an
incredibly difficult task to fake that.
But it wouldn't be as difficult in 1969
as it would be in 2018 if you tried to
do that in 2018.
Basically possible America.
I mean the tuskegee experiment existed,
you know what I mean?
Like it was just in a.
Was that the six?
It went on for 20 years.
It was like a,
I don't know the exact number,
but it was like 20 years of history
where this is happening in like,
not like so many things can just kind of
happened under the give people syphilis
or did this app.
What's that?
I'm given bLack men syphilis.
Just like kind of like,
I don't even know what the research was
exactly.
If iT's like monitoring its effects or
if that was exactly what it was.
Yeah.
And it was just a.
Yeah,
for like 20 years,
uh,
the,
the tuskegee hospital,
there are real conspiracies,
unquestionably,
undeniably real conspiracies.
Like a gulf of tonkin which got us into
the Vietnam war.
They pretended that a ship got attacked
by North Korea or by north Vietnam.
Was it north Vietnam?
Whatever it was by Vietnam in the south
pacific.
And this motivated everybody to get into
war with Vietnam.
Never happened.
It's fake.
Made it up.
Operation northwoods.
Nineteen 62,
signed by the joint chiefs of staff
vetoed by president kennedy.
It was a a signed order where they were
going to plan out fake attacks on
America.
They were going to launch a drone
jetliner,
blow it up in the air and blame it on
Cuba.
They were going to arm cuban friendly's
and have them attack guantanamo bay.
They're going to pay them,
arm them to attack guantanamo bay,
and then it would give us the motivation
to go to war with Cuba.
This was all signed by the joint chiefs
of staff.
They're going to sacrifice american
lives.
They're going to kill americans.
They were going to have people attack
americans and they were going to blame
it on the cubans and they were
orchestrating it all to get people
motivated for a war with Cuba.
And president kennedy came along and
said,
what in the fuck are you talking about?
And he vetoed it and stopped it,
and a year later he was dead,
was one of the things that he did.
One of the things that he did that lead
many people to believe that there was a
conspiracy that he was murdered.
That's a good one to the lee harvey
oswald case is a fascinating one.
Lee harveys murder Is the shady is
looking at
jack ruby.
It was like.
It was like a motion picture of like,
like just with a director,
like a b movie director.
Yeah.
It really was.
A lot happened with lee harvey oswald
captured by the cops.
He says,
I'm a patsy,
you know this just.
I didn't do anything,
and they're.
They're walking him.
They're holding onto them.
By the way,
he,
he's behaving like a guy who got framed.
He's not behaving like a guy who just
shot the president and they're walking
with him.
This is after he said he was a patsy.
They're walking with him through the
courtyard and jack ruby who was a mob
guy,
walks right up to him and shoot him in
front of everybody.
Jack ruby was a nightclub owner who was
shot to the model.
Look at the shot.
Yeah,
watch this.
He's walking.
They look how they have them too.
It's almost like shot,
bang.
Just walks up to him.
They grabbed them.
Hey,
you cut it out there,
mr.
It looks like it's playing on turner.
Classic movies.
It does.
So you could add music to this resident
with the edit,
like gimme some volume jamie,
and play that from the beginning.
See,
let me see him walking again.
Give me some volume.
We hear this,
but look at these.
You're walking them through.
But look how the cops are like way on
the outside too.
I don't know.
Shot.
They'll look how they're holding them.
Here's a man with a gun.
Never shot another round.
One round kills them
and that's it.
Very strange.
Strange place to even.
where did he shoot him?
The guts,
you know,
like in the movies.
It's just weird.
Even the way he drew his go was very
like,
yeah,
I think.
I think there's probably many people
involved in that murder.
Very,
very,
very likely.
You know,
this is a cruder film.
Didn't get played on tv to 1:10 years
after the assassination.
That was,
you know,
who played it?
Dick gregory.
Dick gregory got a out of that film and
he brought it to the geraldo rivera show
in like,
what was it,
like 1970 something as I think the.
The murder was in 63 and I think he
brought it on the geraldo rivera show
75.
How about that?
Hey man.
And you know what and knowing that it
played on a geraldo more than makes up
for the al capone's vault.
Geraldo used to be legit.
Man is a guy.
People don't realize geraldo was super
legit journalist who's amazing.
Dear dick.
Gregory was amazing.
I mean he was an activist before anybody
even knew what the fuck that man and as
a comedian for him to be appearing on
this show,
geraldo rivera,
beautiful hair.
God look at his hair and dick gregory
look young and handsome and he brings
this out and explains to people,
hey,
it is highly likely that the president
got shot from the front and look at his
head.
Go back into the left.
You see his brain spray and the blood
spray out of his head.
It's crazy.
When they played it,
people were stunned and you could
clearly see him grabbing his neck,
like you could see the whole thing.
It's a fucked up video and it's amazing
that if we didn't have this video,
we would probably have a completely
different narrative of what happened at
kennedy.
One guy with one camera opened up the
possibility that there was a massive
conspiracy that killed the president and
it led to the release of countless books
and so much speculation.
How,
uh,
how many files are still,
like,
what's the timestamp before all the
files were on the case?
Well,
some of them were released,
fairly came out like last year,
maybe even this year.
And I don't even remember it.
Look at that.
Boom.
Back into the left.
I don't remember what the conclusion
was.
Oh,
I just missed it.
Rewind it.
Yeah.
So greeny.
Here.
Watch back into the left.
Watch here,
eddie.
Here comes the spray.
Bang.
Oh shit.
Yeah.
The way his head throws back,
it seems very likely that he was hit
from the front.
However,
it's also possible that he was hit from
the back and that his body just spasm
that way.
You don't,
I mean,
no one really knows.
Have you seen jackie the movie jackie?
No,
theY captured.
He captures like that moment,
you know,
it's for the film,
but it in such a,
like,
it's a beautiful,
really beautifully captured moment that
he kind of plays throughout the film.
That's just for that alone.
I thought the movie was beautiful in a
very underrated,
but I,
uh,
but it captured it really well.
Yeah,
it's a,
it's a crazy
moment in history.
You know,
they assassinated the president.
It was caught on film.
But again,
if dick gregory didn't get that video
footage to geraldo rivera,
is this in the movie like,
oh jesus christ.
It's.
Yeah,
it's,
it's crazy.
was she picking up his mouth?
That's not true.
You know,
lenny bruce had a whole fucking bid a
little bit.
I'm juSt saying as they tried to say
that she was picking up his brain,
she was running away.
She,
she knew he was dead and she was
escaping.
She was climbing off the back of the car
to escape and then the secret service is
behind her and they tried to help her
down.
Yeah.
Crazy dude.
There's also the difference in the
autopsy,
the autopsy and the autopsy in dallas,
the way they.
The way they examined his wounds and
dallas versus the way they described in
bethesda,
Maryland when they flew him to that
hospital.
Completely different.
Really?
Yeah.
They,
they,
they turned the entry wound into the
neck,
which they said was a bullet hole.
They turned that into a tracheotomy
wound.
They change the way they thought.
The entrance wound to the head was.
Yeah.
There's a lot of weird fuckery that went
on between dallas and Maryland and then
there was also generals in the room that
were there that wouldn't allow doctors
to come and do certain parts of the
autopsy is a lot of weird shit.
Wow.
You mean also the president,
you have to realize the present United
States is shot.
It's top secret.
They didn't know.
Just like to not have the files lineup
up,
but then release both when.
When would they released?
Like,
there's a great book on it.
The book's called best evidenced by a
guy named david lipton and I fucked up
once and read this book before I went on
stage.
I was a,
I was working in philly and uh,
I was on the road.
It was like,
you know,
I was young and uh,
I didn't understand like,
you gotta put yourself in a good frame
of mind for you do stand up.
And I was reading this book,
freaking the fuck out.
I was like,
oh my god,
they shot the president.
ThIs is real.
They killed the goddamn president.
And I went on stage,
like super bummed out
at the club.
I'm like,
I'm so sorry tomorrow because I was
there for the whole weekend.
I'm like,
I read this book.
And she's like,
don't read that book.
Tomorrow's like,
I won't go on stage.
But doubt is the.
Go ahead.
Oh yeah,
that,
that before I went up.
I remember one time,
uh,
it was the craziest set.
I'm at baltimore,
a comedy factory,
which is already,
you know,
just with my style,
that club already shouldn't be a thing
that happens.
Whatever it up there.
And also my friend angelo had just
passed away and I was going through,
we were talking about like kind of
those,
the pr.
I was like trying to make sense of that.
Coupled with it was that right after
christmas and the holidays.
So I hadn't gone up for a few weeks.
So a rusty depressed after baltimore
cavity factor,
uh,
you know,
is a combination that lead to like,
it,
it almost,
uh,
I remember experiencing it from up here.
You know what I mean?
Like it's one of those things that you
experienced where you're just like,
you're just kind of looking down at it.
Just like
a
terrible.
Yeah.
No,
I mean,
especially if you're,
you know,
if who you are and your act is so
reliant upon having fun.
Yeah.
Or,
or a truth to,
you know,
the presentation is a certain.
It has a certain amount of truth to it.
Right.
Where you are right now,
you are on your mind,
which is,
which is also a thing always have to
guard for me because it's so a really
absorb,
absorb.
So like I'm reacting to it and by
exactly how I feel right now.
I worked with jb smooth once we were
working in a club or a college in New
Jersey and it was real hard to get to.
And this was back before gps.
We just had directions written down on
paper,
you know,
and he was real late,
like a half hour late plus maybe even
more.
And the show was supposed to start at
eight.
It was already 8:30 and he wasn't there.
So they said,
look,
I'm just have a seat in the green room
and wait.
And you know,
when he gets here we'll put them on.
So I go,
okay,
so I have a seat in the green room and
I'm watching this show and it's a
documentary on these fires in malibu
that devastated malibu back then and,
and fucking burnt all these houses down.
And these people are weeping and crying
and they're looking for their dog.
They're like rusty,
rusty,
and then this guy,
he's a firefighter and he comes out and
he didn't even lose his house.
He was just taking care of all these
people that did lose their houses and he
built this house and it was like his
life savings and he's just.
And his neighbors house has gone,
his house was spared and he's just
weeping.
This guy's just openly weeping.
And then the,
uh,
director of entertainment,
whatever it is for the college comes in
and goes,
well,
jamie's not here yet.
So I guess you'll just go on first and
when he gets here you go,
okay,
so we're going to bring you up now.
Okay.
I was like,
okay.
And I just went up and just a shit.
Yes.
So depressed.
Just thinking about this fire and all
these people burning dogs and you know.
Did you talk about that?
I was terrible at the time.
I didn't know what he was doing.
Some comedy is that moment when you,
when you're a young comic you want to be
doing.
At the time I had been doing comedy like
four years.
When you,
when I would go down with the ship for
years in,
there was no coming back,
like once I bombed,
if I was,
if I was doing pretty good and then I
started bombing,
there was no recovery.
Yeah.
I never recovered.
uh,
this was just like,
there's no.
I've already given you my best.
Well iT's also,
I just didn't have the,
I didn't have the mindset.
I didn't know how to recover and didn't
know how to step back and reassess and
thinking about these fires.
I was so depressed a lot.
It's a lot.
you just can't watch something like that
before you go on
stay.
Yeah.
I mean,
and then also,
you know,
it's also about learning thing of how to
find the best of where you are.
Yeah.
Type of thing.
But yeah,
before having that stay out of the weeds
man,
don't talk to anybody.
That's depressing.
I don't do anything depressing.
Yeah.
Well people like to talk like more than
that.
I'm actually more effected by,
you know,
I remember starting out and going to
clubs and like people,
you know,
the booker,
whatever likes to come in and give you
the rundown of the room and the whatever
and I'm really bad at.
I'm bad at like don't get me the info,
like again,
like allow me to react to whatever is
out there and whatever's going on and
you don't need that thing.
LeT it get in my head as I'm in my head.
You don't want to hear,
okay,
there's a bachelor party in table two
and they're really rowdy and we're going
to try to talk to them first.
So just just,
you know,
to react to that.
You do it.
Yeah.
They'll tell you this as you're being
introduced to hold your arm drop.
Just want to let you know we've got it.
We're going to handle it.
The bench party,
you've got it under control
like they do it on.
I mean if you don't,
you know,
you're doing press for certain things.
Like most things like try and do like a
pre interview and the thing and it's all
just these things that like just rings
anything,
organic realness,
spontaneity,
squeezed out by three interviews.
So just doing it with a producer and
like.
Do you have any stories?
Funny stories?
I don't know.
I'm not sure the worst you've ever gone
on one of those radio shows where they
want you to do your bits.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Oh,
there's somebody's record.
There's some great six.
Am me in Indiana?
Just refusing
bob and tom show.
Did you do that?
I think I did.
Bob and tom.
I'm pretty sure I did that too.
And the lady got very angry at me.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's like why would I,
why would I do that?
Yeah.
I think it was a lady might've been
dude,
but you know,
like it is,
but giving,
it all goes to like perception.
Like they,
what people make of comedians,
you know,
and what the expectations on when you go
out and you do these things like what
people's expectations are.
Like you gotta like you,
you,
it's up to you to like change it,
like to change that thing.
It's just like,
all right,
well look.
Hey bob and tom.
Yeah.
Nice guys.
People do the,
the bits.
That's just not a thing that I do have a
conversation now.
You need to attend to the conversation
can be interesting.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
Yeah.
And it's like a,
you know,
again,
like it's not even that they do it,
it's like it has to be tailored to you.
You can't do the thing.
You can't just fill into the mold of
comedian,
you know,
it was just going to make the exact same
thing over and over.
Well the art forms is very
underappreciated because it seems that
we're just talking,
you know,
it seems like exactly what I talked to
you talk,
I talk,
but you know,
it's not like we all play guitar.
So you see someone go up on your frIends
from back home.
they do a pretty good.
Exactly.
Because everybody's been funny at one
point in time,
we've all hung around with somebody who
said some hilarious shit and you know,
and that feels good.
Right?
It feels good when they do that.
Then when they say that and they get
that feeling like,
damn,
I just made everybody laugh.
We've all felt that chasing probably
felt that before we ever did comedy.
So they see you on stage and they see
you killing and they say,
I could do that shit.
He's doing that.
He's doing what I do.
I could do that.
Then they get it in their head,
their head to market,
do it.
Why the fuck can't I do it?
They get in their head like he's just
talking.
He's not doing backflips.
He's surfing waves,
but you know what I mean.
You what you're doing is stuff they do.
I had it.
I had a cousin like,
you know,
I'll bring it to her and jeremy,
our
cousins out,
whatever.
I'll bring them out to like the clubs
sometimes.
whatever.
Bomb to an open mic one time ain't no.
I go up and say,
hey man,
it's the open mic man.
If y'all want to go up,
I was like,
you should.
Yeah,
it was mostly my boys do it.
Whatever.
So uh,
my cousin jeremy was like,
yeah,
I'll do it.
Whatever.
And uh,
do that shit gets up and he does good.
He's a funny dude,
you know.
And I was like,
all right man,
do that shit everyday for 10 years.
Look,
the reality is some people are good.
I'm sure.
You know,
some comedians started just by me.
I can do this shit
great at great at it and
you know,
and like,
and that can happen.
It's just that uh,
if you are going to do it like,
like anything,
you know,
if it is like the,
what you're choosing,
it's just like make sure that the
articulation is yours.
An interest in,
you know what I mean?
Like I think that's kind of the goal.
Like what however you get into it or
whatever inspired it or whatever.
Like if you are doing it,
do it,
do it and do it at its highest level if
you can.
Yeah.
It's just,
I think stand up what you were saying.
It just doesn't get the respect that
other art forms get because there's no,
there's no like if you see someone play
guitar,
I play the drums or something like that.
You don't have any illusion that you can
go up and do exactly what they do,
but a lot of people have the illusion in
their mind that they can go on stage and
be funny.
Yeah,
because they're just talking to eva or
even just be interesting to be in.
You don't have to be anything in the
room,
but it's.
But a lot of it,
part of the reason for the perception is
the things that we accept.
Yeah,
it really is that like a lot of the
things that we accept contribute to.
Oh yeah.
Hey,
we make it like we allow ourselves to be
presented like court justice.
YeAh.
Well,
and it's also,
it's one of the rare things that anybody
can try.
Right?
You can go up open mic night and try and
while you're up there doing stand up,
somebody who's a professional might drop
in and popping,
you know,
chappelle might show up and do a set.
Jeff ross might go up there dot merera,
might show up,
people show up and do sats and share the
stage with you.
It's your first day,
right?
That's a rare.
That doesn't take place in music or
anywhere else where you get an open mic
night and there's 30 people doing three
minutes and anybody can be one of them.
It's weird.
It's soulless people.
Yeah.
A lot of homeless people.
A lot of sketchy fucking weirdos to
touch the same mic.
As you know,
mike doesn't change.
Nobody cleans that comedy store.
Mike,
you got an intense.
No one's taking a clorox wipe.
The fuck is clean in anything at that
place.
They barely cleaned the tables.
The place they just deliver drinks and
keep the party rolling.
That's part of why it's so good.
It's grimy gutter
layer of humor.
That's covered everything for sure.
I think when they changed out the improv
and they swapped that lab for that back
bar and they.
They put that bar in there and just like
it seemed like they like removed a body
part.
It's like,
yeah,
I got it now.
Yeah,
but I mean in the way that like got this
energy went away.
Yeah.
It was just kind of a kind of miami
infusion.
So I feel like a night club in encino
restaurant bar.
That's what it was like.
Yeah,
just with the sofas
and they're just like,
oh,
like,
you know what,
this uh,
this room needs a place for people to
lounge more.
Yeah.
It just,
well it's kinda,
they kinda figured it out now they've
got the little shows that they do there.
It's kind of interesting,
but it used to be cool.
Used to be like a room,
like a separate room that was just
comedy in arusha fears.
Whole storytellers show started out
there.
That's where he would do it.
He would run it there because it was
like a 70,
80 seat room.
When you're talking about the lab,
the lab was the bar.
It was the lab because they redid it.
It allowed you to add a couple of times.
I was talking about the mate,
the mate,
the redoing of the memory.
We have the lab,
the lab room.
Yeah,
I remember that.
But that could have a really good energy
when,
when it had like that really pink
curtains,
those factor.
Yeah,
I remember.
I feel like.
Yeah,
I remember doing like a montreal
showcase showcase that that was like my
first and only.
No,
I did it twice a year later that week.
Yeah.
The improv is a weird spot that,
that hallway when you wait and go on,
there's nowhere to hide.
You stuck in the hallway.
People walking by and they're like,
hey man,
let me talk to you about something.
Like,
I'm going on stage right now.
I got to go,
hold on,
let me get a selfie.
Like did they could touch you like right
before going on stage again.
You know,
that never happens with Gary Clark.
He's never about to go onstage and some
dude in the hallway with.
No,
karen,
let me get to stop.
Yeah,
yeah.
You woke up and stuff.
But that's part of the reason why it's
interesting.
It's part of the reason because one of
them,
but it's also part of the reason why
it's so fucking weird art forum.
Yeah.
No,
it is.
It is.
It's a weird.
That is best.
It's so interesting in like you get a
lot of perspective and thoughts,
so you're doing a lot of sets these days
wouldn't gone up really haven't gone.
I've done maybe two or three sets in the
past year and a half maybe.
Maybe the last time I was like,
why did you do like two minutes and walk
off?
Why?
It's just
not when it's not.
We're ideas are going now.
Where's your ideas going now?
Felt like it's a lot of film projects
and like some television stuff just
feels more normal to you.
Yeah,
it just feels like the way of.
I mean even,
you know,
uh,
before I had like a tv show I would do a
lot of thoughts would just go there and
I wouldn't do stand up a lot during that
and like,
you know,
I like to just focus in like put the
energy where you feel the most creative.
And so that's why,
I mean I could go up and you could,
I don't know,
something about stand up right now,
you know,
it's it simultaneously.
Like,
oh man,
there's some really amazing things
happening and just kind of as a whole is
just like a certain.
I think it's going through like this
growing phase,
like this kind of identity thing,
right?
Because it's like
I feel like there needs to be kind of
this overhaul and even one in its
presentation and to what the expectation
of performer audience thing because
there's a lot of like,
oh no,
I'll go and I'll see a lot of trump
stuff and a lot of things,
but it's not like new perspective.
And it's like,
you know,
it's a lot of civil rights leaders and a
lot of things and,
and you know,
and not even good.
So rising leaders just talking points
and just kind of preaching,
preaching the choir is.
And it's like,
you know,
the whole thing is this unique
articulation in this unique thing that
you're supposed to be bringing it.
It's show and tell.
Like it is like,
hey,
I have this thing.
I have this thought that I think is
unique.
I have this way of presenting this
thought that I think is unique and every
now and again it's profitable right now.
This is the bubble where it is right
now,
right?
If you go up and you
speak for your group,
for you speak in this type of way,
you can get rewarded for it and kind of
these immediate rewards are understand
it,
but it,
it really does kind of choke the art
form.
IT chokes.
What's interesting about it,
you know,
there's just so many people trying to
stand out and it's so difficult to do
that and they find these paths and one
of those paths is to be someone who's
like really moral and righteous and has
something to say,
but it's also under the.
It's under the illusion of being
rebellious in an edgy.
It's under.
It's under the illusion of these things
because it's like a.
You know,
there was,
when dick gregory said the things that
he said and the things we said there was
real danger in a conservative country.
There's real danger to a lot of things.
They says you get onstage and you're
like,
fuck trump in los angeles and New York
city honing his skills and it's just
like,
oh well,
good for you.
That unique perspective you bring about
how this is the worst of times.
Yeah,
it's a,
there's definitely a lot of that.
There's a lot of voices,
you know,
but there's a lot of great stuff to
know.
There is,
there are unique,
You know,
expect like that.
That's the thing.
It's just anything.
It's flooded right now.
Do you plan on going Back,
do you have aspirations or do you have a
thought in your head or do you just go
with the flow?
It's kind of go with.
I mean if I,
if I feel and I like thoughts come out
that fit or if I find a way to do it,
like a thing that maybe doesn't
necessarily fit in with that,
then maybe I'll do that.
I'm open to it.
I juSt don't know.
Yeah,
I don't really know what that is right
now.
That's beautiful though.
You have that sensibility.
Then you can just.
This is what I'm thinking about this.
What I'd like to do right now focused,
I've been in more music studios in the
past two years and have been comedy
clubs.
Really?
Yeah.
What are you doing with music?
Just kind of.
They're just like,
just hanging out.
Well,
just I like,
I mean I like to talk about it and you
kind of discuss it in the,
you know,
I've,
I've been lucky enough to kind of be
around some artists that I admired and
just listened to that creation.
Like I like the immediacy of that
process,
like a lot I liked it is what I was
saying.
What I like about even here it's like
it's,
it's an art space that you have here
where you can kind of create like in
this immediate space and exactly how you
see it.
It comes out in that way and you can
record it,
capture like that.
And when your mind is in that space,
you know,
you need to only do things that it can
be good at.
Yeah.
So it's a,
it's a good year.
It seems to me as an outsider is that
you found like your natural path,
you found a natural path like you've,
you've,
you've made it in,
you become successful,
you've,
you're well known now and you've got
freedom and you're just like,
let me just find my,
what am I into?
Well,
I'm doiNg what I hope
like all of us are trying to do.
Like the oNe thing that I've always done
is exactly what I want to do in the car
and,
and it's not just by nature,
it's not like,
you know.
And then I told her it's just by saying
not doing the things.
If it doesn't match then not doing it,
you know,
like,
and trying to have a vision of what the
thing is and just making that right.
And so like that's what like comedy at a
special.
Again,
the medium finds you,
it comes to you,
you don't go to the medium,
the medium is meeting you.
Like so many people are just like
conforming and just becomes the same
thing.
I don't know.
It's weird time.
Well that's a good outsider's
perspective.
Like you,
you're an inside of that.
It has almost an outsider's perspective
because you're looking at it like you
step back a little bit and watch all the
fucking hamster wheel,
watch all the scrambling
around this.
A lot of that men and there's a lot of
fake horse shit going on.
It's a lot of people grabbing at straws.
It's really noisy.
Yeah,
but so many opportunities.
There's so many venues and so many
comedians and it's also comedy so hot
right now.
It's like,
it's such an exciting time for standup
that there's so many people doing it,
so you're automatically going to get.
Just like when you try and out jokes,
a lot of them suck.
Well,
when you trying out comedians.
Oh yeah.
I'm
gonna make.
I mean this might be in terms of like
success to failure ratios,
one of the most brutal art forums you
could ever attempt to be a professional.
Yeah.
No,
definitely.
It's,
I mean,
because you go,
you're going out there kind of make it
with the thought in.
How many guys from your era,
like when you sTarted doing open mic
nights are doing well now?
Um,
guys or guys.
Uh,
uh,
right.
Really finding their kind of space and
guys just starting to get tv shows and
they're starting to get like guys that I
remember seeing it like mike,
so really starting to to do it.
It's in the past couple of years is
really kind of hit.
I was on this weird kind of weird path
trajectory type of thing.
I,
I kind of was just on the side of it.
I feel I feel like in this weird sense
and things kind of happened and I kind
of found an infrastructure that worked
for me really quickly.
You know what I mean?
But like announce around now is the
time.
I think that a lot of things starting to
happen for guys that have been around.
If you were around 500 dudeS when you
first started that you knew regularly.
Maybe three are working now.
Yeah.
Right.
Legitimately,
like if you counted all the mop over the
first 10 years,
you stand up career,
you've got maybe three that are doing
that are doing what they want to do.
They're doing what they want to do.
maybe.
It really is that.
Yeah,
it's fucking brutal.
A lot of comedians operate in this space
where it's like they don't know they
could do what they want to do.
That's a big wall,
a big wall.
I've seen a lot of people stop at that
while people that can,
that are just like still trying to
figure out how to write the confidence
to act,
the confidence to act on your actual
instincts,
to do what you really want to do,
which is so crazy because comedy,
you think that we'd be the ones that are
closest to it because it's so
instinctual and in such a reaction,
you know,
like a lot of things that you do have
such a real.
Like when you discover your funny
through like when you discover you can
sing by preparing to sink,
you know,
you go and you prepare the singing voice
and you give it a shot and then you
discover you're funny by just like,
oh,
what?
Right.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
Like you just got you a photo finish
chicken,
you know,
it's funny.
It was that.
Okay.
Or by like a hunch that you have so like
it's so instinctual that you would think
it would be more of that.
Like following your instincts,
following your gut,
forging your own path.
Also,
it's so scary in the beginning that once
you find shelter,
you hold onto that.
That's why those,
you know,
the saddest comedians,
the ones that they do stand up for five
years,
he developed a half an hour and it never
changes.
Yeah.
Found it claimed to that bitch like a
fucking life raft.
Yeah.
People listen man.
You know,
people don't talk about how comfy glass
ceilings,
you know,
they're really surprisingly soft.
Yeah.
Well listen,
I gotta get the fuck out of here.
Yeah,
this is great.
What do you got going on?
You promote anything you got?
Anything happens.
Oh.
Oh,
I got to talk about drew's special.
Uh,
I meant to send that to you.
I'll send it to me now.
I'll send it comes out this weekend.
It comes out a saturday.
It's really fun.
It's a comedian I love.
Um,
I'm excited for people to see him
directly to special data without an
audience.
Without an audience.
Yeah,
what do you do it?
We shot it on a stage just like sage who
kind of created the environment and uh,
yeah,
I,
I think the thoughts work removed from
it and I'm really excited to really
excited to capture like that.
Wow.
Yeah.
I don't even really know what you call
this thing,
but I'm,
I'm,
I'm really.
Because it was like when I first saw
him,
I,
uh,
is this trailer?
Yeah,
someone's got to get
real wild.
Like the thoughts.
Yeah.
I don't want to date someone I love.
I love my mom.
She's single soon.
Not that it matters when people are
like,
what?
And you're like,
oh,
August 25th.
That's interesting.
You know those shows,
those sitcoms that they,
when they first started doing single
camera sitcoms and they started doing
them without an audience.
People Are like,
what?
Yeah,
what the Larry Sanders show.
One of those,
like,
what the fuck is this?
There's no audience.
How weird.
Still funny though.
And people laugh at home.
Yeah.
You know,
some of my favorite shows he ever
watched,
the unbreakable kimmy schmidt.
I haven't really watched it,
but it's just fucking hilarious show,
but that's the audience.
That's the thing.
The thing is that it's like,
I think the thoughts,
you know,
stand alone.
They speak for itself.
It was like,
why not?
Yeah.
It's really exciting to just kind of put
that into beautiful living rooms.
See what people think.
Beautiful.
well gentlemen,
tomorrow as always,
thanks to both of you.
Let's do it again.
It's great.
We're in the neighborhood
this fun.