Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Boom.
And we're live.
Thanks for doing this man.
I appreciate it.
Thank you for having me.
Appreciate it.
You're the only guy I've ever had in the
studio where and when I showed up,
you were working out.
That's what I do,
man.
That's my life.
It's pretty crazy though.
I mean,
how much time did you have when you got
here?
I got here about an hour early.
Oh,
okay.
Okay.
I got a little early so I got here.
Shirt off doing chin of.
He's hilarious.
I didn't get my camera out in time for
you saw me.
I wanted to take some pictures or maybe
next time.
Next time we'll catch you after the
show.
Um,
you are a guy that for a lot of people
you sort of embody the idea of hardening
your mind,
right?
And figuring out a way to do things that
most people think are impossible.
That's.
You've sort of become that guy over your
life and you become that guy for a lot
of people,
including me online.
We've talked about you on the podcasts a
ton of times.
Right?
So having you in here has been a very
exciting to me.
I appreciate that.
Thank you.
How'd you become that guy?
You know what?
I grew up.
Not that guy.
Yeah.
So a lot of people put a title on me.
They went to a,
they see me now.
They see me now as the guy with his
shirt off,
we can do 4,030
pull ups and 17 hours.
You can run five miles and 39 hours who
can do all this crazy shit.
But when they don't understand is they
don't understand the journey that it
took me to get to this point.
And what got me to this point was I was
just the opposite of what I end the day.
I was that guy who ran away from
absolutely everything that I got in
front of me,
but not many people knew that I had two
people at the,
at like the real me was like this very
scared,
insecure stuttering got beat up by his
dad and all this kind of stuff.
And I built this fake person that walked
around like my shit didn't stink,
you know?
Yeah.
So that was,
that's kind of how I did it and I do a
process of time.
I realized that I was lying to myself
lying to people.
But it's a fascinating journey though,
because you are that guy now when you
genuinely are legit bad ass at one point
in time you were legit.
Terrified person.
Yes.
So what was the process like?
How did,
how did you step forth?
Well,
it's a,
it's a long process.
Um,
I,
my dad beat the shit on me and I was
growing up.
I was the first black betty born in this
hospital called Millard fillmore in
Buffalo,
New York.
My Dad don't skating rinks.
He owned bars.
He ran prostitutes from Canada to
Buffalo,
New York.
My Dad was big time pimp,
big time.
Anything bad about a person,
big time hustler.
He was American that I moved with them.
Denzel Washington.
He was at but not that bad,
you know,
he wasn't that big,
but that's what it me of.
He was that kind of guy and beat the
shit out of me,
you know,
I'll have my mom.
There was an incident one time when my
mom got knocked out and top of the
stairs and he drug her down the stairs
by her hair.
It at six years old on their.
Forget this in my mind,
I was always afraid.
My whole life I was afraid of.
I had this fucking voice,
this conscience that would always be
battling me saying,
hey,
you gotta get up and do something.
I didn't want to do shit,
you know,
I was just afraid,
but I would that,
that voice would force me to get up.
And my dad,
you know,
I tried to beat him up or whatever at
six and I get my ass kicked.
So this went on for several years and
have a big time.
Lauren disability can.
My Dad didn't believe in us going to
school.
So my dad,
it was about the business,
the skating rink and the bar.
So the skating rink opened by 7:00
at night and this time I was able to
walk.
So about five,
you know,
four or five,
six years old,
eight,
nine.
And I go to the skating rink is 7:00
at night.
And I worked the skating rink until 10
at night and then we will scrape the gum
off the floors and we cleaned the whole
skating rink up and then my dad had an
office in my brother and myself asleep
in the office and my momma go upstairs
and work the bar until 3:00
in the morning and then they cleaned the
bar up.
So after all that shit was done with
going to school,
rarely happened.
So when I went to school,
I was all kind of,
you know,
my,
my learning disability,
I had social anxiety.
I was just a jacked up kid from living
in this tortured home from the outside
looking in.
We lived in an all white neighborhood
and then we would travel to the ghetto
of buffalo in New York with the skating
rink.
Was that.
So we,
you know,
we worked around mostly blacks and I
lived around mostly whites,
but no one knew what was going on in
that house to,
onto a one paradise road.
Yeah,
I mean,
it's crazy.
But,
um,
my mom got courage to finally leave him
when I was eight years old.
We moved to a small town in Brazil,
Indiana,
and that's when the real war started for
me and Brazil.
Indiana is a small town,
great people,
a lot of great people.
And I say that because a lot people get
offended and I'm going to get to the
point where they get offended.
There was about maybe 10 black families
at about 10,000
people in town and in 1995,
the KKK march the fourth of July parade.
So this was a.
not everybody was racist.
It was a lot of good people in the best
people I knew was there,
but there was also a lot of racism
there.
So me being one of the few black kids
net in that area,
you know,
it,
it kind of haunts you.
I had stuff in my notebook,
you know,
Nigga,
we're going to kill you on my Spanish
notebook.
They had that on my car,
Nigga,
we're going to kill this early nineties.
And um,
so even though I showed it didn't hurt
me,
it was jack and me up.
So all the insecurities I have and I was
a kid with my father.
I've moved into this area here and it
just got worse and worse and worse and
it haunted me and that voice that talked
about it kept talking louder and louder
and louder.
I was doing nothing about it and I
decided to make moves and I cheated all
through school and it's kind of humbling
to top of my stories sometimes.
And this is,
it's also embarrassing,
but um,
it's real is who the fuck I am is what I
am as it's created me and copy from the
fourth grade to the,
to my junior year in high school on
every assignment and I want to get in
the military.
When I joined the Air Force and the guy
gave me as vap test,
it's like a watered down and sat and I
couldn't copy on it because the guy
beside me had a test a test b.
They got him a right tessie.
So I've looked the copy on this test and
I couldn't copy on her.
So I got like a 20 and I wanted to be an
air force pararescueman as guys that
jump out of airplanes and saved down
pilots.
It's a,
it's a special operator in the air force
and my score was so horribly low that as
we take it again and he said,
hey,
I got an 18 the second time,
even worse,
I need to get a 50 out of a [inaudible]
99.
And so my mom and I for a while,
we lived in a government subsidized
apartments,
$7 a month and also food stamps and we
slowly moved up to $230 a month place.
But at the time,
you know,
pretty poor.
But I'm,
my mom afforded enough money for me to
go to see a tutor one one hour a week.
So for four hours a month and had six
months to study for our last test.
I'm going to take the Asvab test three
times.
And I studied my ass off and passed it.
And I got in the air force and realized
there was more things in front of me.
I was afraid of water,
terrify the water and um,
I learned how to swim.
But what gets everybody in this training
and all special ops training is to water
confidence where they try to pretty much
drowned your ass,
you know,
all of our lives we've been breathing
and they take that from you and they
want to see how comfortable you are in
the water.
And there's only one percent African
Americans in special operations and I
didn't know anything about African,
like a lot of them are negative,
buoyant,
which I am because the bone density.
I struggled but I'm six weeks into the
program there was about 25 guys left.
I have about 150.
I was there and I was never.
I didn't go to sleep for six weeks of
the program and I wanted to quit so
badly,
but it quit everything in my life.
I copied through school.
I wanted to prove people wrong.
And so here I am in this air force
program starting to get a little more
confidence,
but this water was kicking my ass and
six weeks in the program that Dr gave me
a blood test and was I have sickle cell,
sickle cell trait.
Not The anemia but still kill people,
but so they pulled me out training for a
week and when you go from being very
uncomfortable in that water situation
and then now you're comfortable and I'm
sitting back watching the guys drown.
I'm not,
you know,
I'm not part of the activities anymore
for this week.
I wouldn't get back in that damn water
again.
So the fear overcame me and all my
insecurities from my dad from this small
town,
from everything started coming back and
even though no one knew how fucked up I
was kind of create this other person who
was tough.
I live with shit all the time,
so me not wanting to go back in that
water.
The doctor called me back up,
I thought to get like a,
like a medical kick out of the military.
So no quinten for me.
They kicked me out so I can have some
pride that Dr said,
no man,
we can,
you know,
we could put you back in the training.
And I was like fuck.
But after a week I'm like,
you know what?
I missed one week.
There's only three weeks left is a good
chance,
you know,
I could tough this shit out and go on,
but went back to the CEO and the
commanding officer of the program and
the sergeant said,
hey,
you guys start from day one because you
missed,
you know,
that,
that we could train him.
And I broke,
I broke.
I,
I couldn't imagine going back through
that again.
So I made up a lie and I said,
man,
there's sickle cell things really scare
me.
It was the fucking water wouldn't sickle
cell.
And I pretty much quit even though they
gave me a medical.
It was,
I quit.
So I'm from the age of 19 to age 22,
I went into the job called Tac p where
you control fast movers behind enemy
lines.
Cool job.
But there's no water.
I was afraid of the water,
so I avoided it.
And um,
again,
125 pounds in that timeframe,
I went from one 75 to almost 300,
two to 97 was my heaviest and I started
finding things that was comfortable and
the more things I found comfortable,
the more uncomfortable in my mind was
because that voice I was telling you
about it,
it always was there.
I was just trying to avoid that
conscience.
I,
I wanted to be left alone from that
conscious and it wouldn't leave me
alone.
So I got out of the air force and I
started working for job corps.
Ecolab re spray for cockroaches at 24
and I'm spraying a different stake in
shakes,
red lobster,
whatever from 11:00
at night at 7:00
in the morning.
And what changed?
I came home and watched this discovery
channel show,
um,
class to 24.
I came home from steak and shake.
I sprayed it down last,
get a big old large 42 ounce shake while
crossing the street and get a box that
mini donuts from 7:11.
Now I drive home for 45 minutes.
This big old fat guy who.
Yeah,
I worked out,
but I was fat.
I didn't run,
didn't it pt.
I hit the gym.
So I'm driving home,
turn the TV on and what comes on and
discovery channel.
So,
and that's where everything changed for
me.
I uh,
was taking a shower.
I walked out here,
these guys and I watched the show and it
made me reflect big time on the piece of
shit that I am and I'm exactly what
people said I was going to be.
So,
so what was on this show that really
struck home?
It was,
um,
I saw these guys going into water so I
was terrified of it.
I mean I can't even express have you
ever had a big fear and I know a lot of
fighters have fears and stuff like that,
but they get over them,
but a lot of us have these fears that
you just don't want to fucking face.
And um,
I have a lot of them,
had a lot of them and that's what
created the person who's in front of you
today and it will get into that.
But I'm just scared.
Bitch is what I was an but I was
watching these guys going through hell
week class to 24 and he's guys ringing
the bell,
quinten dropping their helmet down,
rolling out.
A lot of guys is leaving and it made me
reflect on my fears,
my insecurities,
and I saw real men wear,
I thought were real men who are staying,
who are overcoming adversity,
who were overcoming all these different
things that I had blamed so many fucking
people in my life.
My Dad met my mom for not being there
when I was 14 years old.
My mom was gonna get remarried to this
great guy.
He got murdered and then I moved back to
a small town in Brazil and,
and everybody was applying my learning
disability,
my,
my skin color,
you know,
meet me being everything.
And so,
um,
I sat there for awhile and I was like,
man,
I gotTa Fucking,
I've got it.
No one's gonna fucking come to help me.
No one's going to fucking come to help
me.
It's fucking me against me period.
And um,
so I had to man up and I said,
first it got started doing his face in
every fucking fear,
a half,
no matter what the fuck it is,
man.
And,
and,
and these things would keep me up at
night.
No one p people who are hearing this
shit,
they will never really understand and
grasp when you face these things and so
many things,
how they keep you up and haunt you at
night.
I think there's a lot of people out
there that know what you're talking
about.
I mean,
and um,
so that's what it did.
And I had two options to either be that
300 pound guy who's spraying for
cockroaches and made a thousand dollars
a month.
And at 24 years old knowing without 50
fucking years old,
I can reflect on this and think about
what guy never became.
Or I can totally just sack it up and
fail and fail and fail entire succeed.
So I started calling recruiters up.
I said,
I'm gonna.
Go be a fucking navy seal.
And every recruiter.
So there's a weight and height,
his weight and height limit for to get
in the military and I was six foot one
and two 97 and I had a prior service
which was a big deal.
So I called all these recruiters up and
all of them said,
hey,
what're you blah blah blah blah.
They got into conversation.
Steve Vai is even qualified and by the
time I got to my weight would hang up
pretty much like,
hey,
you know what,
call somebody else and they'll try to
get in the reserves.
So I tried to get the reserves and I
called this guy named Steven Sal job
recruiter up and he said,
hey,
come on in.
He saw me put me through the weight
standard,
all this other stuff,
and to get into the class I had to get
into how to lose 106 pounds in less than
three months.
So I was like,
fuck that.
I can't do that.
I grabbed my chocolate milkshake and
went back to Ecolab.
I'm going to back to work,
man.
This is my life.
So in this job you look,
you're looking for cockroaches looking
for rodents and stuff like that.
And this next morning or the next night
I went to work and I hit the all that
cockroach is too much.
I hit the mother of cockroaches and this
restaurant got full of cockroaches and
rodents and everything else and I sat
there and said,
this is my life.
I said,
You are exactly who the fuck this is it.
And I said,
this ain't going to be it for me.
So in that restaurant,
I quit my job,
left my canister in that restaurant,
my,
my spray canister,
got back in my ecolab truck and I went
home and I started working out like
somebody I was.
I became the most obsessed person on the
planet earth.
And I was basically,
I had to invent a guy that didn't exist.
I had to invent a guy that can take any
pain,
any suffering,
any kind of judgment,
be called nigger because whatever the
fuck in the world and be able to stand
in the fucking room and say go fuck
yourself.
And it built out to build this callous
mine and I built it through suffering.
I built it to downright fucking just
crushing myself.
If it was raining outside,
3:00
in the fucking morning,
it was snowing.
The fourth thing is don't go out there
and do shit.
My instinct was we got to fucking go out
there.
Anything that was fucking horrible in my
life that I would normally say no,
that was inhumane,
that most people I had to go do it.
And I started callous in my mind at this
point in my life.
And I lost the weight and lost weight.
And I went back to recruiter.
I got into that class and I went through
three navy seal hell weeks in one year.
Only guy to ever be in three hell weeks
in one year.
To my knowledge,
the first one,
I didn't make it through the next two I
did.
And um,
that I just didn't,
I didn't stop it anymore from there.
And I started realizing through this,
through this process that the fucking
mind is what you created.
And I started opening different doors
that I didn't think were even there.
They didn't think even existed in the
more doors opened up,
the more I started realizing that my
potential is damn near endless it.
And it changed my whole mindset.
So I went from David Goggins,
I created Goggins.
And that journey is a priceless journey
that is hard for me to even explain to
people because it sounds so quick and
easy that guys lost this weight.
And I went through three hell weeks.
I went to ranger school,
I went to Delta Force lex into whatever
it is.
It was brutal.
It's a brutal journey every fucking day
and every well,
are you happy?
If anybody knows my life story and I try
to give you a,
just a snippet of it.
Where I'm at today is in front of Joe
Rogan telling you my life to get
through.
I became to get through where I'm at
now.
There's nothing but prior to half for
myself that I can't really.
I can't really show people because I had
this face and his face that they see
like,
are you happy?
What's wrong with you?
I'm driven,
I'm obsessed,
and that's what you see said.
People need to hear the story.
This is a.
This is an exciting story for people
because there's a lot of people out
there that field trapped and they feel
stuck and they feel like they can't do
anything.
This is who they are.
You're a guy who felt that exact same
way but figured out how to not be that
person and be a person that you would
admire.
How did you.
What were the first steps?
Like you had some slips before,
right?
Because you.
You quit because of the water thing,
but then when you went back the second
time,
when you decide you're going to lose all
that weight and you quit that job did.
Did you.
Was it just straightforward from there
or whether there's some days where you
just failed and then you picked it back
up again?
So my first run when I decided to lose
the weight,
I was like I said to 97,
I was about 32 percent body fat and my
idea was to run four miles from my first
run.
I didn't know how bad it's going to
fucking hurt me.
I used to run before I was fat and I was
like,
fuck it,
I can do this.
I ran a quarter mile and walked home.
I walked home and sat on my couch and
cried.
I went to my mom's house who was about
40 about maybe 20 minutes down the road
and cried and getting her out.
Say,
man,
I can't fucking do this shit.
I don't know.
When do I,
uh,
just got somebody pregnant.
My life was this fucking.
I was making thousand dollars a month.
My rent was eight,
10 a month.
And my mind just kept fucking with me
and kept fucking,
you're not good enough,
man.
This isn't for you man.
These guys are bass motherfuckers on the
planet earth.
You're not that.
And um,
what it was,
and it's kind of funny.
I was obsessed with rocky,
rocky one in particular and now as a kid
I come everyday now watch this fucking
show rocky.
And I would fast forward with the little
vhs tapes to round 14.
Around 14 fucked me up like nobody's
business.
Why this song came on,
right,
so when I bought the pull up record,
I listened to the song for 17 hours is
two minutes and 13 seconds and I'm able
to visualize and dream like nobody's
business and I know that I can create a
vision that many people can't and I work
for it.
So the vision I had was when Apollo
creed beat the fucking shit out of
rocky,
beat the shit out of him.
He kept fighting.
He was a dumb fighter,
couldn't read,
couldn't fuck that was me,
couldn't write,
just punchy everything a bottom and
rocky beach or shelving.
He isn't at coronary,
but I was saying stay the fuck down.
And him getting up,
him getting up a poetry raises are
they've been fucking turnaround thought
he wanted to fight.
He turns around and sees this guy
getting up and it was the face of Apollo
creed that changed my life.
The face of Apollo creed.
It was like just by that motherfucker
getting up,
not winning just by him getting the fuck
up.
Apollo creed was champ.
He's best.
Rocky had taken his soul,
had literally taken his soul.
His head goes down,
he looks at him like,
who?
What the fuck are you?
I want it to be that not rocky.
I want to be the guy that people looked
at it,
I don't give you like me or didn't like,
oh,
I don't care,
but it said this motherfucker's gonna
keep coming after whatever the fuck is
in front of him.
I wanted that.
I wanted that worse than anything in the
world,
so that is.
I kept picturing me falling down and
getting up and every motherfucker call
me nigger.
I was dumped.
Even myself,
even myself,
I wanted to feel something besides two
feet.
I want it to go the distance and that
going a distance pushed me to a point of
where now go way past the distance.
So you go the first day you,
you run a quarter mile and you walked
back home and you're,
you're upset.
How do you,
how do you move forward?
So basically what I did was I came home
and I had a chocolate milkshake.
I sat down,
I gave up.
I said,
this ain't gonna fucking happen.
I can lose 100,
six pounds and I can't even go a quarter
a fucking mile.
I started being able to take negative
shit and be happy.
And this whole.
I say,
what if a lot.
It sounds Corny,
it sounds weak,
but it's true.
One of the recruiters said,
there's not many black navy salesman.
I was a 36 African American steel in
history.
It's an overset careers because the
fucking water,
you know,
I mean people get mad at me.
It's fucking true.
Just get over it.
And so I was like,
man,
what would it be if my fucking fat dumb
lie in to be friends with people?
Insecure ass can overcome this shit and
that would,
if mentality that,
that,
that dreamer mentality just with always
fuel me.
It was fun,
man,
what if I can be,
but if I can be a seal man,
what if I can go from wearing a quarter
of fucking mile now are going toward and
five miles.
What if I can go with just what if I can
go in and,
and what if,
how would that feel if I'm graduating,
kind of get at that graduation thing.
I talked about 2:24
that I like the video.
I sat down and watched this man officer
stood up and he said to the graduation,
um,
gas graduate graduating buds,
like 18 of them,
he said,
we live in a society where mediocrity is
often rewarded.
And he went on to say something about
these men detest mediocrity.
And I wanted to be a man that detest
mediocrity.
It all,
it got me a lot of trouble in the seal
teams and going forward in my life
because I just,
I started looking down on people for not
going hardest fucking shit.
And I started to create different
things,
but that's for a different day.
But I just believed that,
you know,
my whole mind changed.
That is a problem that a lot of people
work hard to have.
You get angry at people who don't work
hard to the point where you,
you know,
you want to insult them,
you want to,
you want to smack them,
and it's really because you're scared of
seeing that in yourself.
Yeah,
that's probably the truth.
That's probably the truth.
So I guess a lot of times month I would
see people and it probably was a direct
reflection of who I was and I would get
mad at them,
but in reflection it's probably just be
getting mad at myself for me,
100 percent when I,
when I see people that are half assed
and things,
I get terrified of seeing that in myself
and I get mad at them.
Right.
And it's,
it's not a good way to handle it.
No,
but it's natural because you're just
terrified of seeing that trait.
Right.
And it cost me.
So you come back,
you do the quarter mile,
right?
You walk back home.
How do you regroup?
So what I did,
I sat down there and I put rocky and I
got my milkshake rocky.
I seen what I was big time in rocky and
platoon.
Why Platoon,
I love to see people who were getting
beat down and there's scenes they're
scenes that this drove me and people in
my hell weeks,
you know,
I was in three of them.
They'd always hear me singing these
songs,
these songs,
humming these songs in torturous
situations when you're,
when everybody's quitting this fucking
code.
I would be somewhere gone somewhere
fucking gone.
If somewhere fucking dark as shit.
There's a senior platoon when he lies,
when Barnes shoots relias and you know,
they think he likes his dad and the
choppers are taken off and Charlie
Sheen's,
ask him,
you know Tom Berenger,
Rizzy,
Elias,
regionalized,
William Defoe.
Oh,
I found them back their dead somewhere
and through the woods the Viet Cong is
chasing he through the woods and shoot
him in his fucking back and all he wants
to do is get to the fucking chopper.
He's getting shot in his back is getting
up,
getting shot back.
He's getting up and you see this guy
who's fighting.
I love the fucking guy who just fucking
fights.
And so I put these things in as
reminders that you're going to have to
fucking suffer,
man.
This fucking point two,
five,
man,
this man,
you're going to have to fucking suffer
to,
to go from this fat insecure
motherfucker too.
One of the best guys on the planet
earth.
This journey's could take something that
is going to be incomprehensible to most
people and these different
visualizations.
How I visualize it in my self talk,
it became so nasty and dirty that I
almost liked the fact that I went point
two five.
So it became from being defeated too.
Like,
man,
all right motherfucker.
Maybe you know,
maybe the Marvin go point seven,
five,
you know,
it just became this different mindset.
I turn negatives into positives,
so I will,
I will take it like who?
Who would even think about doing this?
So I would sit in my car saying,
who had two 97?
Who can't fucking swim?
That gray,
who scared the fucking water?
We had the fucking balls,
little balls to fucking man up,
quit a job and go and it put everything
on himself.
So it's how I started talking to myself
and put myself in a whole different
category that would fuel me the next day
and I just kept using that as fuel and
fuel.
No one would do this shit.
You're the baddest motherfucker around
your bass.
Motherfucker ever live.
And I had ice kept fueling me with the,
with the right kind of message that I
needed to hear.
That was never telling myself.
And through time it became reality to
myself.
So you start out on the first day and
then do you start running again the
second day?
Second day we're wrapped back after it
again.
But I started realizing I can't run that
far.
Right?
So the idea was I became damn near a
professional cyclist with the miles.
I put it on the bike.
So I never,
we never watched TV.
I had to be doing something.
So I was riding the bike.
I rode a bike a lot to,
to lose the first initial kind of weight
because my bones were hurting so bad.
My bio is broken.
I learned to get over that also.
And I tried to swim a lot,
I wasn't a great swimmer,
but putting fins on kind of equalized my
body.
I wasn't so negative,
buoyant.
So I started fitting a whole bunch and I
spent hours in the pool hours in the
pool,
trying to get more and more comfortable.
Not because I was going underwater,
I was so scared of the water that I had
to live in.
The water had to become one with the
water.
So going into the pool used to scare me.
So I went to the pool an awful awful
lot.
And then the bike got easier.
I was able to run more.
I went from like one mile,
one mile was a great accomplishment to
miles and then from two to three was a
big.
And then I went from three to six and
then like they have a warning order that
they get people to get ready for butts
and the whole thing was running six
miles five days a week and that was my
goal.
And so I just kept.
I failed,
I go back to scratch.
I use some positive motivation.
I have like one day where I'm like
fucking defeated,
but I started realizing this is part of
the process that's a part of that
journey.
I had to realize this is part of my
process versus just saying like I used
to,
I'm just not good enough.
If I'm not good enough,
we always say that shit,
I'm just not good enough and then try
something else.
I'm going to fucking make myself good
enough and that became my mentality.
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna.
Make myself good enough,
and so I'm misunderstood a lot,
but that's.
That's all it came down to.
I made myself good enough and the days I
couldn't run that for the next week I
would do two a days,
so on the running,
if I ran a quarter of a mile,
I waited fucking couple of hours.
It haunt me,
bother me.
I tried to run a half mile.
Next time,
same day,
you can do more than this.
If I had to walk out and walk,
it just became just a process of
grinding and grinding and grinding.
Not even a good word for it.
It's not even a good word for it and
just just going further and further and
then when I got through running,
I go to the bike,
I go to the pool.
If I got tired somewhere and my legs
were tired,
I go to the gym and I developed this
crazy workout where I was doing volume
like two,
300 reps of like very lightweight.
People are saying how,
you know,
how come you don't have any loose skin?
My workout routine in the gym became
sick.
It became sick.
I was just doing two,
300 reps,
400 reps on my chest,
just like for one simple exercise,
the best press and a racket.
Get back on it.
Just rep it out.
Trying to burn as many calories.
I can't build that muscle mass and I
just became.
Just became obsessed with it.
So when you're doing this,
are you at all about repetitive stress
injuries or the fact that your body's
not conditioned for this and you're
basically taking your body?
Were you abused it and now you're
forcing it to live?
Like in an elite athlete?
I didn't care.
I didn't know any better.
I didn't think about it.
Wow.
I didn't,
I,
I didn't know that.
Working out that harbor.
Fuck you up.
I did it.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
That's one reason why I went through
three hell weeks.
So don't talk about a lot.
But um,
the stress of my life getting to 24
caused me have some serious.
So as it's used,
I know anything about this shit too.
So as muscles,
what we use as your hip flexor muscle
and basically under stress it starts to
tighten up.
And I wish I stuttered for,
from the time I was in third grade time
I was in seventh grade.
White blotches on my skin.
I was just,
I was a nutcase.
And so the insides of me or are also
getting fucked up.
So in this process,
um,
my psoas muscle got real tight to my
[inaudible].
I can show you the bumper in the back of
my head after this show's over.
But I had,
I started going this fucking like large
tumor looking bumper in the back of my
head from my body compressing.
So I'm six foot one,
but my muscles were like five foot nine
because I just started just the muscle
tightness for my solo as go into my t 12
hours,
just getting tighter.
My quads,
everything,
getting tired from distress to stress in
my life.
So the more I stress my body with the
workouts,
my lower body became out of balance.
So I had a bunch of stress fractures,
bunch of injuries going through buds.
And how I got through buds was they gave
me my third time was my last time going
through hell week.
I basically put a black sock on at 4:00
in the morning and I would get duct
tape.
I had at numerous stress fractures on
both of my legs because my kid,
my body was literally like coming in on
itself and my legs were like I was.
I was protonating really bad and putting
stress on my stress on my shins.
And so I would put duct tape,
duct taped my feet and I will show you.
The top of them will have pressure
ulcers that were the size of quarters
from,
you know,
how the ankle joint.
So the foot goes to the Shin and how you
move this,
where the tape was so tight,
it just created a nice ulcer right
there.
And um,
I just,
uh,
just kept going through it.
So you just use that tape to just
support your ankles.
Right.
So I basically kept myself and for the
first 30,
45 minutes,
the pain was excruciating,
but then it would go numb and I would go
numb and then that's how I got through.
Wow.
Do any longterm damage?
Oh yeah.
I've been out for five years,
so I retired from the 21 years in the
military at the time in the air force.
And I did about 16 years in the navy.
How old are you?
Forty three.
Seems like you're 30.
That's good.
And you really,
you look very young for your age.
Whenever I'm stressed I get after I
fixed,
I fixed was ever bothering me.
So I,
um,
basically over the last five years,
everything I've done in my life,
I did it being very unhealthy.
I,
I'd never talked about it.
I just kept going and it costs me pretty
much.
I was choking my insides out adrenal
issues,
tons of the general issues,
thyroid issues,
anything with inner consistent,
pretty much shut down on me.
Um,
my organs were pretty much shutting down
and I went from a guy who could run 200,
five miles to guy who couldn't get out
of bed and the doctors were trying to
search what was wrong.
That's what I figured out the soda as
muscle.
No one had figured it out and I hit it
by accident.
So I've,
I've missed two days of stretching out
in five years.
And so what happened was all the Shit I
did to myself,
the stress I was under,
her physical,
mental,
all kinds of shit.
It just choked me out from the inside.
And doctors put me all kind of
medication and the medication started
doing the exact opposite of what kind of
shirt I was on.
Um,
Dah da.
I was on some different things too for
my estrogen,
different things for my,
um,
I was on anything to do with your,
like with your endocrine system of
thyroid medicine.
I'm good.
God,
I was on quarters.
All kinds of shit to get my stuff and I
like this lump in my throat from like
the heart was always.
I couldn't run down the street.
My body was just jacked up,
couldn't sleep.
My whole body was just shutting down.
I could give you a lot more than that,
but just give an example.
I was fucking dying and so I couldn't do
anything.
I went from a guy who is this God,
you're a guy who can't do shit.
And Dr.
Like I don't know what's wrong with you
man.
You know your labs,
your.
This is what ptsd is it,
what's going on?
I knew what any of that shit.
So I sat in the bed one day and I
realized,
man,
my life is over.
This is it.
But it gave me time to reflect on
everything I had accomplished because
I'd never taken time to reflect on the
kid.
I was the man I am now.
So honestly the time I wasn't working
out,
it was the best time of my life because
I got a chance to really reflect back
and be proud of who I became.
I never took time to do that.
It was like one after another,
get the fuck after,
get after it after you ain't good
enough.
Motherfucker get after it,
get after it.
And um,
I got halted.
So anyway,
and this process went on for a while,
more medication.
This isn't working,
that's not working.
No doctor can figure it out.
I'm like,
fuck it.
I saw this dark about eight years before
this happened and he was like,
hey man,
you're so fucking tight.
I've never seen anybody in my life as
tight as you.
You need 50,000
hours of stress.
And he used throughout some crazy
number.
I was like,
whatever,
stretching,
you know,
stretching stress is bad for you.
So you thought stretch was bad.
I was just baffled that I read some
article,
you know,
I know man.
Fucking fuck stretching man.
You know,
I worked out so hard.
I'd have time to stress,
man.
I was,
I was running about 150 miles a week.
I was back in the mouse.
I was getting after it,
man.
I was working a full time job and I'm
stretching and doing that.
So my body was literally getting tighter
and tighter just from what I was doing
about this.
Because you ran this.
No,
I wasn't that man.
And so I said,
no,
I'm going to try and stretch out so I
don't do anything for like 10 minutes or
you know,
don't do the six minute abs bullshit.
So I started stressing out one hour,
hour and a half.
Long story short,
man,
I shaved my head almost every morning
and that bump does on the back of my
fucking head.
I started realizing it was shrinking for
some fucking reason.
I don't know why because I shaved my
head back and I was like,
it's getting smaller.
It's more that bump got healthier.
I got smarter.
That bump guy was like,
oh,
hold up motherfucker.
But with what's going on that.
So whereas most of us started getting
more and more stressed out,
more and more relaxed and over a period
of five years from the best shape of my
damn life right now from stretching out,
wow.
That's all it was.
I went from like,
I can't even count the medications I was
on.
Now I'm on a very low dose thyroid pill,
period.
Do you ever do yoga all the time,
man.
All the time.
And I,
I,
if I were to tell somebody one thing
right now,
man,
that's so as muscle and getting that hip
flexor opened up because we're all
stressed the fuck out.
It was much worse than others.
It changed my life.
Yeah.
Um,
how do you say nick?
Regardless,
how do you say his last name?
The a Brazilian jujitsu black belt from
England Greek fellow.
He has a great quote about yoga.
He said Yoga is a martial art you do
against yourself.
Yup.
It's a great way of putting it.
One hundred percent.
So it feels like when you're in there,
right?
One hundred percent.
And so you.
How many years ago was,
this was five years ago.
And how long was there a period where
you couldn't work out at all?
There was about.
So I always try to do something but I
couldn't run.
I could run maybe half a mile and all
that shit would happen and my heart
would get a fib and all kinds of stuff
would happen and I started just
stretching and also I try to do pull ups
every now and then.
But everything was just.
I didn't have the energy,
I didn't have anything.
I mean,
nothing was processed in right for me.
So do you think that you've just broken
your body?
You pushed it too hard?
One hundred percent.
I,
I sat back in that bed that night and I
had a lot of time to reflect and say,
you know what?
I was actually kind of proud of myself
in a very sick,
twisted way.
I,
even though people will understand it,
I had to do what I had to do and you
know,
and I did it.
Like I didn't tell you how I got into
ultra running,
you know,
there's a lot of things that.
So I,
I pushed extremely hard.
I went way beyond what I thought was
capable.
Like my first ultra race I did,
I was a,
I was heavier,
I was in Iraq,
you know,
the markets have trail,
lone survivor.
I was in buds,
I was in three hell weeks as you know,
as I said many times and I knew a lot of
guys that died in the operation.
I was at free fall school with mark in
the trail.
Who's his twin brother during the
operation where wings,
where Marketo was the only survivor I
knew marcus trowel and I was about 200
some odd pounds and I didn't run Harley
all at this time.
I was a seal,
but I was like a bodybuilder and I did
an elliptical trainer 20 minutes on
Sunday.
That's all I did.
So I.
Did I fuck that cardio stuff?
I was never about it until this
happened.
So that happened and I was like,
man,
I got find a way to raise money for
these families.
So I googled the,
I found the foundation,
Special Operations Warrior Foundation,
and I googled the 10 hardest races in
the world.
I knew nothing about ultra running the
first I'd ever run with 20 miles at one
time and so what came up was the
badwater 1:45
and 35 mile run through death valley in
the summertime.
I thought it was a fucking stage race.
I didn't know people could run to her
and 35 miles at one time had no idea was
even possibly in a stage race where you
run like 20 miles.
Oh,
camp out and then run 20 more until you
get her 35 miles.
Right.
So I want an ultra runner to know ultra
runner was.
I called the race director of Chris
Cosmin of the bad water and he said,
are you an ultra runner?
And I was like,
I don't know what that is.
He goes,
have you run 100 miles in 24 hours or
less?
I was like,
no,
but I said,
I'm a navy seal.
I was in three hell weeks.
I was arranged.
I gave him some resume.
He didn't give a shit.
He said,
I don't care.
You got qualified for my race.
And the deadline was up in two months
for this badwater race and basically he
said there's two more races you can do
to qualify and I might consider you my
race.
We select top 90 athletes in the world
and not even ultra runner,
but I liked your cost like what you're
doing.
He said,
uh,
I call him up on a Wednesday and he
goes,
there's a race on Saturday in San Diego,
San Diego one day when you went to run a
one mile track for 24 hours,
send miles.
You get,
you get 124 hours.
I will consider you in my race.
I did the math is 14,
seven minute mile.
Fuck it.
I can do that dumb shit thinking I'll
tell you that right now.
It was rough.
Verse Pain I've been in my entire life
was this race.
So I have my wife at the time,
she's now my ex wife.
We go to Walmart,
get a blue lawn chair.
Which crackers in mild plex.
That's what I'm gonna have for 100 mile
run.
So,
so,
but the start line,
this race,
it was an Aua national championships.
It's like the best ultra runners compete
against each other to Sydney Mazda and
get 24 hours and I'm this big
bodybuilder looking guy.
But back then I would say I was at least
2:30
at least it made them more than jacked.
Yeah.
I was ripped to fuck up.
I was a big old chest out there.
I was,
I was jacked up.
It was a picture of me.
He definitely didn't look like someone
who could run a hundred miles.
No,
not at all.
So basically I started running and I get
to about mile 40 mile 50 and I'm feeling
pretty good.
I get to mile 70 and it was the worst
pain in my life.
I sat down and this blue lawn chair at
mile 70 and my,
the Ritz crackers after mile 20 became
rich.
Cracker balls wouldn't hydrate and
correct it.
I didn't know what to do.
I was drinking mile plex from our
nutrition because I couldn't eat these
risks.
Crackers have very minimal water,
if any at all.
And I was just dying.
So I sat down this blue launch air as I
was watching these windows go around in
a circle that was all dizzy and
lightheaded,
hadn't gone to the bathroom.
It's been about 12 hours.
I'm at 70 miles,
about 12 hours,
which is good.
And looked at my ex wife now and I was
like,
I am fucked.
I started seeing like three of her and
once my body stopped,
my mind just went off and had to go to
the bathroom and the bathroom was like,
it was like 20 feet away from me if
that.
And I couldn't.
And so I sat there and pee blood down my
leg and started crapping up my back and
we're 30 miles to go.
I and my feet were broken.
I was just in the worst shape once you
stopped running.
Not running like that.
I mean I didn't run it almost a year.
I was just doing bodybuilding stuff and
20 minutes on the elliptical trainer.
No running at all.
I probably ran no shit,
no shit,
no more than 50 miles the whole year.
That wasn't my thing.
I want it to be like Jack,
you know,
I didn't want to be cardio guy.
I wanted to be ripped big navy seal guy
and I'm in the day before this race is
funny.
This guy named Joe Burns who put me
through my hell week's a seal guy.
He's one of the hardest guys out there.
He was in the gym the Friday before I do
this race and he was doing a full body
squats,
deadlifts,
power cleans.
Said fuck it,
man.
I don't know he,
he's a guy that approved me to do this
race.
He knew he,
he,
you know,
he gave me the approval to go do this
race and signed off on it.
So I'm in the gym.
I went in there,
did a full body hardcore squats,
dead lifts and everything with this guy
because I knew he was going to come
watch me in this race.
So I've always been about art,
man,
you're going to see me come in here and
Jack this weight and the memorial
watched me do 100 mile run where you can
think about that.
So basically I paid for it.
So he came out there with my favorite
thing,
chocolate,
you know,
mini donuts because he knew my story of
my past life and bought six mini donuts
out there and I'll have my hat pulled
down and at mile 70 man it was torturous
and with blood down my leg and 30 miles
to go,
I,
uh,
started reaching and cookie jars.
Man,
I started pulling off all kinds of
stuff.
I reached in my mind and a lot of us
when we have bad times in life,
even the hardest person where we forget
how bad ass we are during that hard
time.
I have a thing where I take a couple of
seconds to reflect on our.
Hang on,
man.
You've been through this,
you've been through that.
You overcame this,
overcame that.
I don't ever close my mind to the fact
that this can be done.
And I knew I had to get up and eat
nutrition and hydration.
I need to get it stopped being dizzy.
So that's the first thing I did.
I didn't panic on.
I had 30 more miles to go to get 100.
I started the process slowly but surely
I was able to stand up and I was
literally hobbling around this track
with just walking,
no running at all.
I couldn't run.
My feet were in the worst pain,
worst pain I've been in my entire life.
Nothing in any training is even
comparable to this last 30 miles,
and what happened was my ex wife looked
at me and she's like,
man,
we agreed I'm not going to make the
time.
I was going way too slow and at that
time at mile 81,
something clicked that I'll never
probably be able to do again.
When my mind,
body,
Spirit,
soul,
everything is connected in my mind knew
I wasn't fucking around anymore and knew
I wasn't going to quit and knew that guy
was dead and buried and gone and I was
going to die out here on his fucking
Walmart for whatever reason why I was
going to get through this motherfucker.
I don't give a damn.
It made no.
There was no fucking crowds.
There's no trophy.
At the end there was.
I wasn't even in a race.
In my mind.
There was.
It was nothing.
It wasn't about nothing.
There was no nothing.
It was a bunch of people didn't know who
the fuck I was.
It was me against me and I used all
these different dark places to start
bringing out light and just fucking go
in deeper and deeper in it.
The next 20 miles I ran 101 miles and I
ran the next 20 miles,
ran and about 10:30
pace and I did 101 miles in 18 hours and
56 minutes sat back down that Blue Porta
potty.
Now my chair,
that guy from Walmart and that's when
the body realized I was done and this
great feeling came over me,
but also the worst pain in my life.
That's when I took a humongous shit on
myself.
Literally like I like a fucking log up
my fucking back pissed so much plugged
them in.
My wife was,
she was a nurse and she was freaked out.
I couldn't get up.
I couldn't stand up.
She backed this camry on the knoll of
the grassy areas that,
and we were both lifters at the time,
so she was decently strong.
I put my arms around her neck,
she got into the backseat of the car,
left the windows down,
no like horrible shit,
and I had this poncho liner because it's
November in San Diego,
so I'm sitting her jack him back in his
car and she was terrified.
I need to get your doctor and you take
it.
The doctor says take me home.
So we lived in a second story or,
or the second deck of this apartment
complex in San Diego.
I got to the first deck so I,
I get a car and I can stand up,
but,
but with my arms around her neck,
so I just leaned down.
I was gonna pass out,
got to the SEC,
or I got to the first deck,
went down,
just couldn't stand up anymore.
Got to run her neck,
worked my way up the railing.
Government dominoes on her neck again.
Walked to the kitchen area,
which is right in the front door.
I was laying on the Poncho liner.
Crap was everywhere.
I managed.
She helped me managed to get into the
toe,
into the tub,
and it was like dirt was coming on my
penis.
This looked horrible.
It's just a gross thing.
The world is the worst pain I can ever,
ever,
ever be in in my life.
And the craziest thing I'd tell you the
story because right now I'm not
sadistic.
I'm not crazy.
People may think that they may want to
put a title on me after hearing me
because it makes them feel better
because he thinks,
wow,
this guy must be some special artist.
Fucked up crazy dude.
No,
I'm a guy that came from nothing.
Anybody's capable of doing shit like
this.
Anybody and I sat in that tub.
She put the water on me.
She called my mom up and my mom was
dating a doctor at the time.
The doctor,
the doctor said,
you need to get him to a hospital now.
She came back and all I want to do is
call Chris cost on the phone,
the race director,
Bob Waters.
I fucking did it.
So she said,
I'm taking to the doctor.
I said,
no,
let me sit here and enjoy this pain.
She said,
what are you talking about?
I said,
you know,
I go,
I need to go to the doctor.
I realized that,
but I never thought it was humanly
possible to do what I did.
I went 70 miles at 70 miles.
I was dead.
I was at 100 percent what?
I thought what I thought was 100
percent.
I went 30,
31 more miles after being in the worst
physical shape I've ever been in my
life.
It all the,
all that pain and suffering and thing
was going through my fucking body and I
sat in that tub and and the wires hit
me.
It was the most amazing feeling of
accomplishment and I want to be numb.
I want people to give me drugs and the
and the numbness,
fucking paint.
I want it to.
I did this over and as crazy as it
sounds,
it was the most amazing moment of my
entire life to overcome such to come
from this kid who was ms dot Lee himself
and was tortured to this kid,
to this guy.
Now who is able to overcome such amazing
odds and obstacles,
and I called Chris costs the race
director of bad water and he said the
idea of a 24 hour races to run 24 hours,
you only ran 19 a put doubt in my mind
that he would let me know badwater.
So a month later or so,
a month and a half later,
I went to this race called the hurt 100.
So how is it my race in Hawaii?
Twenty 6,000
feet of climbing was.
Ali said,
that's all I said.
That's so crazy.
I mean he,
he's a hardcore dude,
but he didn't know how fucked up I was.
Right?
And he said,
he didn't say,
well,
you know,
he,
he didn't say no,
I'm not gonna let you in.
He put enough doubt in my mind and say,
man,
I got to do more.
So I was broken.
I was broken bad.
And like,
how long did it take you to recover
physically?
The funniest thing about this,
I tell a story very often I'd signed up
for that.
I'm getting to that answer is right now.
I went into employment and me and my
wife,
my mom signed up for the first Los Vegas
marathon down the Strip of Las Vegas and
that incident happened.
So I ran a hundred miles before I ran a
marathon.
Two weeks later,
roughly December fifth was this marathon
that we all signed up for.
I couldn't walk.
I could not walk.
I was fucked up.
So 10 days or two weeks after this 100
mile in one race,
I did um,
this marathon,
December fifth in Las Vegas.
I said,
you know,
it's the first one I can't run.
Maybe I can walk with my mom.
So I try to go out to this little knoll
around our grassy area in San Diego.
Try.
I tried to run laser broken.
I said,
fuck,
I can't even.
I'm jacked,
can't do shit.
So I said,
you know what,
maybe I'll watch you guys do the
marathon and I'll cheer you guys on
whatever.
I said,
I'll try to walk with my mom.
December fifth happened.
That gun went off 2005,
14 days after I broke myself off and I
qualified for the Boston Marathon.
I ran a three.
Oh eight.
That's crazy.
And what's funny about it know people
hearsay's motherfucker.
Even when I tell you the story I
dropped.
I want to drop so many names.
Google it.
Look it up.
I don't give a fuck.
Like elmo.
Seems like I'm making my own story up.
It does.
It almost seems like a to you.
Like,
like when I tell if I were to hear
somebody,
like I said,
listen,
you listen to Joe Rogan's podcast.
I heard some black dude from fucking
Brazilian and talking about uh,
this happened,
this happened three weeks.
Ranger school ran a hundred miles,
broke my feet,
brought my body about this is the
biggest fucking liar on the planet or
ain't nobody doing shit.
He said,
even when I tell my story,
it almost sounds like some made up shit.
So you got crazies.
You ran a hundred miles before you ever
ran a marathon.
Right?
Then you didn't run again at all and
he's still qualified for the Boston
Marathon.
So you ran a three.
Oh,
eight,
right.
For the first marathon you ever did,
ever did two weeks after you ran 100
miles with no training and nothing in
between,
but it gets better than that.
You can see my training log that
actually posted up.
So that's when I started training for
the hurt 100.
So basically what happened was after
that I had about four weeks.
What does it feel like to run that
three?
Oh eight.
If you could barely walk when that gun
went off something off in my head and I
didn't feel that much pain at all
afterwards.
I did,
but something happened where I was like,
the gun went off and that thing came
back like,
all right man,
what if.
Because I wanted to qualify for Boston,
that was my goal,
but I was,
I was jacked up,
you know,
and I,
and I didn't run as much as I should
have had all over my Iraq training.
I hit the weights and but my job,
but my goal was when I signed up for it
a year early,
I want to qualify for Boston,
which was a three,
10,
59 and I was like,
what if you can qualify for Boston,
maybe just reading so we will help me
out.
I spent 101 miles.
What the fuck is 26 miles to me now?
So the mindset going into it was like I
ran 75 more miles in this so I use it to
my advantage.
So after that happened I ran a feet
pretty much broken out.
I will go to the physical therapist and
they had this compression tape,
compression tape help because my feet
were pretty bad off and I would run 70,
8,000
mile weeks and then I went to the hurt
100 race in Hawaii.
Twenty 6,000
feet of climbing over 100 miles.
Probably one of the top five hardest
hundred mile races in the world.
I wouldn't even have a real runner.
Yeah.
I baked a lot of miles by the last,
the last two and a half.
About two months that wasn't a runner
with out there and got through the race,
didn't 33 hours,
was the ninth place finisher.
Not many people finished that that year
and I qualify for badwater and got in
and I went on to lose weight and train
hard and I got fifth my first year and
went back my second year and got third.
When you see you,
when you lost weight,
like what will you eventually when?
So I went to the race about one 97,
lost quite a bit from the bodybuilding
time.
That's over a short period of time,
right?
How did you lose all that way?
Once again,
I just worked out hard.
I stopped taking my protein so much.
I got off,
I was on this stuff,
caught a nitrile tech and I got all the
protein stuff.
I just started.
I started hitting the weight so hard and
I just became a running fool.
Became the black forest gump man.
Pretty much.
Pretty simple,
man.
That's what happened.
Now when you say you were using
compression tape on your feet and your
feet with Jack Dot,
what was the extent of the injuries?
So basically because of my pronation,
I never figured out because my muscles,
um,
I always had issues with stress
fractures,
Shin splints.
So I put a lot of pressure on the inside
of my ankles.
And so that there's a tendon that goes
up the backside of your,
I don't know if it's just your fibia a
backside that,
that little bone back side of your foot.
It goes right up beside of that law
rather than inside that bone.
And that thing was just so fluid up on
both sides that even this flexing,
my foot was just killing me.
So I realized when you can,
when you cast that thing up,
Kathy,
my feet always helped me out because it,
it,
it locked my foot into position that
would've made me protonate as much.
So between the caffeine of that,
and if,
if he wants the badwater video of 2006,
you'll see me crossing the finish line
with this compression tape.
Literally like flying on my ankles
because I went to the race with
compression tape on my ankles and so
basically I'd have that on my,
on my ankles.
I had inserts in my,
in my shoes and also this wedge on the
back heel of my left foot so then it
would keep me from eating that heal so
much.
So I had all that on just to go run and
I ran my ass off and went to badwater
2006 and with a compression tape on my
feet and walked a lot.
But I got third place.
Do you always run with regular running
shoes?
I do,
yeah.
So now I don't have those issues
anymore.
All this stretching has opened my body
up to where you know how it should've
been.
So my alignment is pretty good.
It's not perfect.
So now I just run a regular running
shoes now.
Now no more compression tape number and
all that stuff.
So if you see now if you look down
there,
you'll see the compressed it and you'll
see my ex wife here in a second taking
their can present tape off of me.
She's doing it right now to see her
right now.
She said tape,
you know.
So that's the tape right there.
It had to wear everyday of my life to
run.
So as you see this story may be kind of
unbelievable,
but there some proof right there.
So that's how it was.
So painful.
Yeah,
I was pretty fucked up as you see right
now.
I'm trying to get all mad.
Yeah.
I'm,
I'm pretty destroyed right there.
What is the most amount of miles you've
ever run at one time?
Yeah.
Two hundred and five and 39 hours.
Nonstop.
Woo.
Yeah.
I've had quite a few people on or met
quite a few people now over the last
year or so that have run ultras.
Courtney Dot Walter.
You know,
she.
Is She wanting to Moab?
Yeah,
I heard about already rather than heard
about it.
Yeah.
She uh,
she beat all the men by 22 miles.
Something like that.
Some crazy thing.
She was first place winner.
She beat everybody else a second place.
One road.
And with her,
I mean he would never believe it when
you talked to her.
She seems so normal.
She drinks beer and eating.
Nachos needs candace ultra runner.
Man.
She's just silly and she's fun and does
no demon there.
Like waiting to meet a demon,
you know,
I'm like,
where's your demon?
Right.
Like how are you getting through her
demons?
A quiet demon.
It's,
it's there.
It has to be.
There's something,
there has to be.
There's no other people to everybody.
I know that,
that can do that as a demon.
A lot of us don't want to admit to shit.
Yeah,
we got them.
Oh 100 percent.
It has to be.
So when you do this and you qualify and
you,
you do that race in Hawaii,
right?
They just let you in after that.
No.
So the race in Hawaii?
Yeah.
I actually called the race director up
and there wasn't like a big time.
Like I didn't have 100 mile race.
I believe it's.
I had and see the 100 mile.
You did the Boston marathon or you did
the Vegas Marathon?
Yeah.
So I did a hundred miles.
100 more miles.
The Vegas Marathon with the hurt 100.
Did that hundred miler and all this is
in a very short amount of time.
Yeah.
So November was the first 100 miler.
December was the 26 miles in Las Vegas.
January was the next hundred miler in
Hawaii.
You know,
fucking crazy.
That is like say if I was your friend
and I called you up on October 20th.
I go,
hey man,
how many times do you run?
I run every now and they sent him crazy.
I know if you can pull it up or not,
but if you could pull up my race
schedule for 2007,
just pull up David Goggins race results.
You can see something real crazy.
And second they say this is good.
I gotta show you proof because why?
I know my story doesn't make any but
this.
Look at the dates of these races and
we're going to show it to you in a
second.
It's,
I'm just look at the hundred miles.
Fifty miles back to back weekends.
How many weekends there were between
races.
So if you look right here,
you can't really see it.
So we've looked at 2007.
Yeah,
go all the way down.
Keep on going and telling $70.
Racist there too.
That.
Okay,
get right there.
So hundred miler,
Hawaii.
Oh Geez.
Look up first.
Uh,
two weeks later,
three weeks later,
another one that's 50 miler,
50 miler,
um,
a month later you're looking at what?
Fourteen days later,
another 50 k 50 miler.
A month later they look at less than a
month.
Another 50 miler,
50 miler in June.
July was another hundred.
Miler.
Badwater was literally bad one.
It was a month after I did that 100
miler.
One hundred 35.
Our leadville was less than a month
after badwater.
They're playing 100 was three weeks
after leadville.
Um,
Angel's crest was to attend date a week
after that 100 miler,
the bear 100 was a what?
Thirteen days after that 100 milers.
She and then I ran the 200 and it said
two and three point five,
but I didn't ran towards his tour and
five miles around there.
But what's not in there was that
mcnaughton race I did in 2,850
mile race.
Also did in 2007 that wasn't listed.
So that was just my 2007 year.
That's insane.
Yeah.
So do you think that is what fucked your
body up?
No,
no,
because I still run the same mileage
now.
We're fucked my body up as hell week.
Really?
Oh yeah.
You don't go through three hell weeks in
one year.
So I.
So what happened was when I realized
that my body was really jacked up,
which I went,
I was a big time squatter,
love squatting,
and I went through the first hell week,
got messed up.
Second Hook I got all the way through.
Then third,
hope we could get all the way through.
And my third hell week we hit.
We had a guy die on Thursday and then
that whole weekend and I graduated 100
done pulmonary edema.
It was a code name was John Scopp Code
is fuck hell week.
The Pacific Ocean's never warm and it
rained the whole time.
The whole time was rain and he,
um,
pretty much just drown in his own
fluids.
Pretty much.
We were in the pool doing some
evolution.
He sunk to the bottom,
um,
his temperature was hot.
He,
he missed a lot of hell week for getting
pulled out for different stuff.
He wouldn't quit and um,
he ended up dying and he'll wait.
But um,
yeah,
so anyway,
after hell week ended,
um,
I want to go back to the gym,
you know,
second phase happened,
die phase,
like I could get back in the gym,
start jacking my weight.
I Love Jack and wait.
And I realized I couldn't squat.
So I went from squatting a lot too.
I couldn't even squat the bar because my
lower back was all fucked up and I was
like,
I don't know what's going on.
It was because there's this muscle so it
hell week your hip flexors are.
So I went through so many of them so
fast and so the hardest part of buds I
went through three times,
not,
not the hell week part,
one of the hardest parts,
but it was the initial part of the where
everybody sees on tv,
the log pt to Surf,
torture the Dag on boats over your head,
law,
all that shit.
I went through that person three times
in one year and um,
over a period of time my hip flexors got
so tight that is jack me up a jack me up
from my hip flexors,
so always been so cold and so stressed
out and everything led up to it.
But this really was the part that I
noticed I could squat before hell week
or before my first time going to bud's
after,
after Bud's,
I couldn't,
I couldn't squat anymore.
Do you just think it might just be
because your body was exhausted?
No,
because I,
I for 12 years,
so I would go back and tough it out.
Like,
like with Joe Burns,
he was squatting.
So I said,
fuck,
I'm going to squat with Joe Burns,
but I just couldn't squat because that,
that muscle was attached to your t 12.
So what was it doing to.
Is it locking up?
There was,
this is just pulling.
So it made my hips feel like I couldn't
sync my ass.
I couldn't think.
So it's,
it's incredible pain.
And then with the weight pushing me down
and then try to push up,
the pain was just too much.
So it was,
oh,
this is all range of motion.
Range of motion issues.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's an important thing for my friend.
Cam Haynes,
who doesn't stretch?
He's another friend of mine who runs
ultra races.
He ran that Moab to 40.
He's run the big foot two.
Oh,
five is when a few of those.
Right?
Um,
I know he's listening.
Go stretch dude.
He has support,
man.
It was.
Especially if you're working that hard,
right?
If you're doing that much.
Yeah.
You're,
you're definitely locking up.
He could barely touch his toes.
Yeah.
That's not a good thing.
That's not good.
No,
no,
no.
It comes back to her chin inside pretty
soon.
Now.
How flexible you now,
because I would imagine you probably a
fucking ballerina at this point because
it's sad when your brain.
I'm trying to get there.
So I stretch every night for these two
hours.
This is the thing that people said that
it'll always pissed me off because I'm
pretty flexible.
They said,
oh,
well,
you're naturally flexible.
People have a natural threshold.
Like,
no,
they don't.
Like a doctor told me that.
I go,
you don't know what you're talking
about.
I'm like,
you don't know what you're talking about
because most people don't push
themselves past that pain,
that stretch pain,
right.
People want to put a title on your man.
It's easier for them.
Just fucking natural.
Natural.
Exactly.
Now you don't work hard enough,
motherfucker.
Yeah.
People don't like.
Champs aren't usually flexible.
You have to,
you have to force yourself to do this.
Right.
And uh,
I know it because I had a friend,
my friend tom or dog now,
he was a football player,
Jack,
big thick dude.
Terrible flexibility was taking
taekwondo with me.
And over the course of a couple of years
I saw that dude eventually develop a
full split and you go.
And he just did it through his mind.
He just was.
Everybody else was done training.
That guy would be on the mat constantly
stretch and always working out because
he had built his body up so strong all
those years of squatting and lifting
that he just,
you know,
he was all tents and everything was just
like this super powerful.
Right.
But all like very tense.
That's why I stopped.
That's what I never stretched
because I wanted to strength.
Yeah.
You weren't that tight muscle,
but.
No,
I don't think it stupid.
Yeah.
I think you're not supposed to stretch
before you do big physical activities
because I think it does like we can use
somewhat,
but I don't think being flexible overall
makes you weak or not at all.
Not at all.
What certainly doesn't from martial
arts,
because you need that flexibility to
have leg dexterity to be able to kick.
It's got to be fluid where it's not
tightened up by restriction of the
motion of your body.
I get it.
It's truth.
I just think people are,
for whatever reason,
and A.
I'm one of those.
I drone on too much about yoga.
I'm like one of those vegans.
It's like you gotta do it man.
I get annoying like a born again
Christian or something.
It's like I'm getting that way now,
man.
I'm getting that way now for anybody who
does anything to hard.
Like you know,
if you do anything like with weight
lifting type shit or martial arts type
shit where it's just everything's
explosion.
It's lifting,
it's heavy,
it's push,
push,
push yoga to balance your shit out and
we'll,
yeah,
we'll really.
Well man and this all these people that
resist it.
Like there was some article recently
that was something along the lines of
hot yoga is just trendy nonsense.
I read that and then even in the article
it talked about that there might be some
benefits in terms of like the
strengthening your arteries and they
didn't even mention heat shock proteins
is a study going on right now.
I believe it's at Harvard.
One of my friends was telling me about
it where they're.
They're trying to find the benefits of
90 minute hot yoga classes because they
think it might mirror the observed
benefits of sauna which they already
know for a fact has big benefits because
of your body producing heat shock
proteins.
To deal with the heat.
That's why I put that song in here,
man.
I go in that fuck her all the time,
but no one can tell me it doesn't work.
It's big.
It's proof positive.
That changed my life.
It wasn't a medication or this or
address.
It was stretching.
Yeah,
it was yoga,
stretching.
All that stuff combined changed it,
but I just think it balances out your
body in those static poses where you're
just holding the pose and it just works
you out in a weird way.
They to percent.
You just don't get lifting weights or
hitting the bag or anything.
You're just not going to get that.
That kind of working out.
I can't agree with you more.
It's so difficult.
It's crazy.
Get your ass off.
You're enjoying housewives and shit and
be like,
this is like the silent struggle.
It's humbling it.
Nobody knows.
If you see like two doorways,
right?
And one of them is like fucking ct Ali
Fletcher's fucking super pumped iron
addicts gym,
which is hard work and then right next
to it is the yoga studio.
You're like,
well,
once you get done with all that hard
work,
you'll go over to that yoga studio.
No,
there's two different kinds of hard work
going on.
It's no joke.
Two different kinds of hard work.
Yes sir.
So what do you do now in terms of like
you got over this five years ago,
you're in this bad situation where your
body's not working right now.
Everything's working great again.
Well,
I had two heart surgeries also.
Whoa.
So
your heart.
So I had a hole in it so you know,
you're not supposed to have a hole in
your heart and be a ceo and it would be
born with it.
I was born with it.
It went undetected and me pushing so
hard.
So in 2009 I was training for this race
across America and um,
I,
I just couldn't go anymore.
Another pitfall in my life was the
whole.
And I was pretty much off active duty
seal for three years.
Then I had to harsh with them trying to
fix it.
So the whole was significantly large
account,
big it.
They say it was big as a quarter and I'm
like,
how the hell is big as a quarter?
Yeah,
that's a pretty big hole in your heart
because they had to helix patches.
I'm like,
that's impossible that the helix patches
there in my heart.
So the two stents,
what is a helix patch?
It is like a,
a little Mesh.
Very like what they do for Hernias.
Like something like maybe something like
that.
So they were in my artery and they
placed this patch.
But to go through your artery?
Yeah,
they went through my for more artery
with a camera?
Yeah,
with the other cameras down through my
throat.
Whoa.
And they put this catheter through my
artery that went to my heart.
They,
they went and they took this helix
patched that.
They placed it in there and then they
found out six months later at the whole
wasn't covered up enough yet because a
whole,
the,
the patch was very damn big hit.
So they put on and they go back in there
in 2010.
How's the patches adhere to your heart?
I guess your heart heals around the
patch.
So.
But how did they stick it in place?
I guess they put it with the holes that
and then it Kinda like inflates.
Oh Wow.
The whole is at.
And then that thing goes in there and
then it kinda covers a whole.
And then the heart.
So there's two things in my heart right
now that the heart kind of covered up.
Whoa.
Okay.
So here's the job.
Go.
Jamie's got a,
an image of it for us.
Whoa.
So it's attached to this little probe.
Right?
And then they put it over the area where
the injury is.
Wow,
that's insane.
Yeah.
Atrial septum defect was,
I had atrial septal defect.
So basically everything I had done I got
from Madison.
Oh Shit.
It's crazy.
I'll be done.
That's so crazy that they could do that.
Yeah.
So I was out for um,
I was off activity for three years,
so I stuck.
I was in the recruiting area for three
years trying to get back on active duty
and that's,
that was my life for three years.
So they put that patch in.
Yup.
And now your heart.
One hundred percent.
It's 100 percent.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's incredible.
I was losing blood and I was just.
I was a bad off.
Which is amazing that you were able to
do all that with a hole in your heart.
That's what the doctors were saying,
you know,
because they ain't know I was a seal.
So I went in and the doctor that found
the whole are,
he gave me ekg is all this stuff.
Once again man,
you as after I ran like 200,
five miles,
you know,
they made you're in great shape.
I'm like,
man,
I just don't feel good.
Like walking up the stairs is making me
jacked up.
So Dr Doc Shrek,
he's like,
you know,
gave me Ekg,
can go to the doctor,
get an echocardiogram.
So I'm in there getting echocardiogram
just chilling out in there and the guy's
talking to me,
he has his little one and my heart were
bullshitting the boss stuff and he,
when people get quiet,
fucking not good man.
So He's in there.
This head is one of my heart chilling
out.
Yeah man,
what are you doing?
Hey,
what's going on?
Like.
And he says,
I'll be right back.
He goes and gets a doctor.
Dr Comes in,
puts things on my heart,
the doctor gets another doctor now.
I'm just freaking the fuck out.
I'm like,
okay,
cause when it comes to your heart,
when that was a big deal.
So they come back in and said,
hey,
we can stop the echocardiogram when he
talked to yet in the hallway,
you have a hole in your heart.
And the guy didn't know that I was,
he knew I was a navy guy,
but I think he was a ceo because not
many black guys are seals.
And he had a conversation about,
you know,
we got fix this real quick.
I said,
yeah,
I mean then I came up,
I was the seal.
He said,
man,
you could've died jumping,
you can die diving,
you could have died and all this stuff
because basically the hole in your
heart,
if it gets plugged with something,
like anything like,
you know,
let's say you get a bubble from diving
or something like that,
you gonna die,
right?
So I,
I,
I call it luck.
I called look.
Wow.
So I uh,
I got through two surgeries,
they put it back on,
I lost the,
give you the first one,
and then when did they realize that it's
not good enough,
so they take you back and you can get a
bubble study,
a bubble test.
So they,
so they like literally send bubbles that
way,
safe bubbles that way to see if the
bubble goes through your heart.
So they have this,
this echocardiogram again and they hook
you up I think to id or something like
that and they throw these bubbles
through your heart and they see if it
goes through after six months when it
should have been healed up,
the bubble went through.
So I had to tell me then,
hey,
we got gotta,
you know,
you're not,
you're not good to go.
So I had to take a year before I can
have another surgery because one,
two,
because that patch had to be completely,
completely healed before they can go
back in time.
You knew you had a whole right?
So.
So they knew how to hold because of the
heart surgery all the time.
Like when you're waiting for a deal,
you know you have an extra hole.
Yes,
I know.
I have a whole what we're allowed to do
with your body then.
Well at that time they go,
you know,
do how you feel comfortable and so,
the whole is not going to kill you right
now but you can't die.
You can't jump.
You pretty much willing to steal
anymore.
So I was a recruiter for a period of
time.
Um,
so basically I was crazy about that is
before my second surgery I was actually
training for Delta Force.
I was,
I wanted to go to Delta and I was
rocking recruiting a lot and before my
second truck running and you're running
with a pack,
a pack on my back with some way on how
heavy the pack,
50,
60 pounds.
And you run with that on.
Well you're supposed to hike or hump
like rock hopping,
right?
I ran with it because.
Because,
you know,
that's what I did.
Right?
So the day before,
the day of the day of heart surgery,
I did a ruck run because I knew I was
going to be out of commission for
Awhile.
So fuck it.
Matter get my last one in,
dude.
Jesus Christ.
So I could do.
I have had my training log.
So after my second heart surgery,
all I could do was walk.
So I became an ultra walker,
walked my fucking ass off and I over a
period of time it took a year for that
thing to heal up the hill.
You know my first bubble study after my
second heart surgery came back negative
or positive,
the bubble went through again.
Oh No.
And they're going to crack me open.
Oh Man.
Over that period of time,
my heart healed around that thing
nicely.
And I passed the second bubble tests.
So the first bubble test was how long
after a year?
It was.
So the first bubble tests after the
first surgery,
six months.
And then you had to go through a full
six months after that totally heal.
Then you have the second heart surgery.
And when does the bubble test fail?
After the second heart surgery,
it was about six months,
Jesus Christ,
and they said,
and the doctor looked at me and said,
you know,
I'm sorry to inform him that we get the
crack your chest open the next time
they're really getting there.
So I sat back thinking this could be a
third heart surgery,
and then,
um,
that one,
they said we have to wait for six months
to see if this thing's gonna close up.
Right?
And I came back thinking,
man,
I'm about to get cracked the fuck open.
And that bubble got pinned up,
man.
They go through,
maybe forced it through with your mind
and visualize and that's it,
man.
That's something to visualize.
Holy Shit,
man,
that is crazy.
It's crazy.
One on a ruck run with a hole in your
heart to.
I did it for several years.
I said,
fuck it.
I might as well keep on going,
man.
That's amazing.
Now after all said and done,
everything's good now.
Yeah,
everything.
I mean,
I'm sure it must have popped up in my
fucking ass and not to do that.
You know,
everything's good right now.
I'm always waiting for the next thing to
pop up and I handled the same way I was
attacking,
but yeah,
as of right now,
I'm in the best shape.
My 43 years old just turned 43 February
17th.
I am in the best shape of my life.
I'm not knocking on wood because life.
Fuck it.
Life comes at you dude.
Fuck.
Knocking on wood.
Come at me.
I mean,
I would think that you would be a go to
guy for injuries.
Like if anybody's ball game.
I've had them all.
I've had.
When you broke the world record for Chin
ups,
then you rip your arm apart.
Pull ups.
Yeah.
So if you pull up the picture,
there's a picture of my hand.
You'll see.
I'll know what is the pull ups or pull
ups or here.
Hands our hands out and chin ups or
hands four hands forward.
So I failed three times.
I failed twice before I finally got it
the third time.
And um,
I,
the first time I rip the shit out of my
forearm.
And then the second time you'll see
there's a picture of my hand.
And it is a third degree burn.
So that's my hand.
Oh Jesus,
man,
what in the fuck is going to look at you
a bit by a wolf.
So what's funny about that,
as you see that,
uh,
that doesn't create after one pull up.
So if you can imagine the pain of
[inaudible],
you know,
you have one contact point I said like
running,
you can overcome it because he,
this big giant legs.
And it's,
it's different when you have these
little fragile punk ass hands touching
the bar.
Imagine 4,030
pull ups.
How many times you're coming on that bar
coming off now at 207 pounds at the
time.
So I was,
I was a bigger guy.
I'm like one 95 or 95 now.
So I was almost 22 pounds heavier.
So that was a lot bigger than I am right
there.
Bam.
You would prefer get that shit man.
So you were doing it in sets of five
testify.
So as you see,
you have these different people who are
witnessing you,
you have to have your,
your,
your number there to make sure that
you're,
um,
you know,
qualify for the guest.
A world's record.
That's 1415.
I have a long way to governor the 4,015
pull ups to go.
She's so.
Yeah.
And how long did you do this?
Over 24 hours.
It was seven.
So I broke it up 17.
Wow.
And I was fucking over it.
What did it feel like in the last chin
up?
You know what?
Actually there's a video that we have
and um,
I was chasing this guy named Steven
Highland.
So this guy named Steven Holl had the
record and the video is my last three
posts for a broken record.
I'm talking so much shit to this
motherfucker.
I'm like,
Hey,
motherfucker thought I wasn't gonna get
it.
Huh?
I told you bitch ass mother fucker.
I'm coming after you.
I'm here now.
It's just me talking shit.
It's a cool video.
But I felt um,
I felt nothing.
I was just happy I have to do anymore.
I just 67,000
pullups in nine months is training
record for 40,000
and the failures,
so I did the first time in September.
Failed miserably.
I was the day showed the 2,588
or something like that.
Failed miserably for millions of people
too much later.
November.
Tried again,
failed again.
Two months later in January 19th I
finally fucking got it.
So after I got it,
it wasn't like I'm happy.
It was like I ain't got to more fucking
pull ups anymore.
Roger that saw it was a fucking check
that have picked off man.
But you were doing them when I got here
today.
You know why?
Because now it's a part of me,
dude,
man,
I don't like doing it so we got to get
some knocks him out.
You don't like doing them so you gotta
do it.
That's my whole life isn't like someone.
Someone gets drunk at a certain whiskey.
Like if they smell it,
they'll get disgusted.
Like it's like yeager mice or something
like that.
They smell it.
Right?
Is that what it's like with you?
With,
with a lot of ups?
With a lot of things,
lot of things I don't like running on
like,
and people don't believe it,
but you know,
I was,
I was a big guy twice in my life,
so hence the reason why I just don't
like running,
man.
It hurts.
It's brutal.
Sucks going out and I'm going to be gone
for two hours or I am going to be gone
39 hours running a one mile track.
Fuck,
I'm not crazy,
man.
This sucks.
I mean,
you know,
people put me in this category of you
must be some crazy guy who loves it.
Nah Man.
Nah.
That's why I do it though.
That's the only way to couch your
fucking brain man.
One way to get hard and like people take
these classes on mental toughness.
Like even sales.
You have the class about visualization,
self talk,
eat an elephant.
One bite at a time.
Breathing control.
Yeah.
Roger,
that you got to put yourself in her lacy
situation.
It's a lifestyle.
How are you going to react?
How are you going to react to it?
Like all that training goes out the
fucking door when you're in the fucking
cold water and you're fucking miserable
as the first hour of a her and 30 hours
of hell week in that first wave goes
over your head and you're the curtis,
you've been in your life and your mind
goes from our one hour,
one fucking 30.
Oh,
that fucking self talking shit dude.
You Ain't thinking about getting the
fuck out of here.
But if you live this shit on a daily
basis and know how to calm your mind
down to self talk will help.
All that stuff will help.
But usually we react.
We have pain,
we have suffered,
we react and we react about get the fuck
outta here.
We gotta go.
It's those people were able to control
that fucking feeling of fucking flight
and say,
Nah,
motherfucker.
There's a way through this.
It's not going to be here forever.
I'm not cold right now.
I went through three of them.
I'm not coding now.
I'm in a nice warm studio with you.
You've got to think about that shit.
It's just gonna end.
It's gonna end,
but we don't know that.
We don't think that at that time it
could last forever and then you get to
sit back on Friday.
Everybody walking across the,
you know,
back on the grinder,
all the 16,
17,
18 guys that graduated hell week and you
get a chance to watch these guys
victorious,
and then you get the chance to think
about that.
You take that hot,
warm shower,
first name chemistry,
your fucking minds.
Why the fuck did I quit?
So what keeps me going?
I've quit several things.
I know what's on the back end,
the fucking quitting.
It's a lifetime of thinking about why
the fuck did I do that?
No,
I ain't fucking doing that.
There's something about talking to a guy
like you that a lot of people hope that
you're going to say some magic thing
that's going to click in their brain.
Everybody gets changed who they are,
like,
what is it?
What is the thing?
That's why people go to these self help
conferences and they take these classes
and they hope that someone's going to
say something that changes the way their
mind works.
It's hilarious to me.
It is,
it's kind of Larry's to me too.
But what is also hilarious is that what
you're saying is that you have to do
those things.
You have to suffer,
you have to live in it,
you have to be comfortable in it.
And then maybe some of that shit will
help you a little bit along the way
period.
And I went to,
I was a,
when I was a recruiter,
I got invited to mit smart ass
motherfuckers there,
man,
I'm not that.
I'm dumb and knuckle dragger and um,
there was this guy there,
I forget his name,
but he was like the top head head guy,
old white guy,
you know,
all,
all genius out and we were on this panel
and they were asking us all these
questions about the mind,
mental toughness and shit.
And he was answering them and I wasn't
answering any questions and I'll never
forget he was just answering them off of
theory.
He never put his fucking ass and shit.
You read a bunch of fucking books and
you think that you know how to fucking
mind works and shit.
I had gone through hill to a kid and
then all the way up until now.
Right.
So I know.
So that theory is bullshit.
Yeah,
there's a lot of good stuff out there
you can read from people,
but I had lived hill and when you put
yourself in hill,
that's the only time you can figure out
how to fuck to get through that
motherfucker.
You can't.
You can't read somebody else's book
about some theory on how to do shit.
Some guy who set up and they're a nice
warm office and read it and wrote some
book with a Nice Cup of coffee in the
fucking hair.
No,
I want to see that guy who put immersed
himself in fucking hell.
And he thought about quitting and
leaving and him and his wife and his
kids.
And why am I here?
Is this,
is it worth it?
All this crazy shit is still said it.
Found out a way to get through it.
So basically that's,
that's the bottom line of it all.
We all want to read about how we can
quickly get somewhere.
That's why there's six minute abs and
all this other shit.
So powerful.
Did you make it some results from it,
but they're not permanent.
The permanent result comes from you
fucking.
I say it all the time.
You have to suffer.
You have to make that a tattoo on your
fucking brain.
So when that time comes again,
you don't forget it.
You may forget it for a second,
but you can go back in the cookie jar.
I call it.
It's a.
it's something that we've all endured.
I call it the cookie jar and we often
forget how hard we are,
but you got to reflect back to a couple
of seconds.
Reflect.
I've been through this,
I've been through that,
and then remind yourself I'm a bad
motherfucker and then you can get
through that shit,
but if you don't believe it even endorse
shit.
You're just blowing smoke man and you're
not going to get through anything.
What was this guy saying like,
well,
what was his theories that he was thrown
out?
There is theories was about,
I forget exactly what it was.
Was it something about what the mind
does under stress and how we can't.
He said how we can't do something and I
did it.
I did what he said we couldn't do.
Like,
what was he saying he couldn't do.
It was something about if you're born,
if you're born a certain way,
if somebody,
you can't become this way.
It was totally saying that who I am now,
like I had to be born with some genetic
power or some,
some gift from God,
but I had to have some kind of special,
had had some kind of special gift.
I forget what set me off,
but it was that we had to be to be
somewhere you had a baby born with.
It was a concept and I know what I was
born with and I know the battle that I
had in my mind.
So when he said it,
I sat there looking at my face and some
of the crowd asked me a question.
I totally contradicted everything he
said and I was like,
Nah man.
I mean,
I know for a fact that you can be this
fucked up dude like really fucked up
dude and with the right mindset and
it's.
It sounds so easy with the right mindset
doesn't sound easy to know what you're
saying.
It sounds very simplistic answer,
right?
You can.
You can,
but you have to go into a dark chambers
that we often shut off and you got to
open them up.
You get to open up and fight that
fucking demon getting there.
Talk to that motherfucker and say,
what's up?
And we often take the.
We all like to take this four lane
highway.
The easy highway has has fucking signs.
It has restaurants.
We all loved that four lane highway.
We always step over the shovel and all I
did was I picked up that fucking shovel
and shovel.
I made my own path and you may have big
boulders and shit.
They may be getting towards your miles
up the road faster than you,
but going through this path of life,
this journey over here that you make
yourself,
that's incredibly difficult,
but comes out.
The other end of that motherfucker is
some glorious shit that you can't even
explain to people and we're afraid.
Bottom line is most of us,
even the people who have all these
theories and shit,
it's easier to accept the fact that I'm
just not good enough.
I wasn't made to do that,
and yes,
some of us can't be Lebron James,
but I'll tell you right now,
man,
we can do a lot of shit when it comes to
this pure arm guts and willpower and
getting through shit.
We have a lot more with a lot more than
we think we have the other
album with a guy like that,
with his theories.
His theories are based on results and
those results are based on human beings
and most human beings.
There are certain people that are born
with certain gifts,
like a guy like Lebron James,
obvious physical talent.
You Know Jon Jones and mma.
Obviously physical talent,
but there's.
When you look at someone who's super
successful,
you always assume that it has to be
because of some sort of physical gifts
because people look at themselves and
I'm sure this doctor,
this old dude probably had like a little
gut and probably says exactly.
I looked a little tiny arms,
weak shoulders and probably thought,
well,
there are certain people that are just
Meza morphic and probably broke it down
all the scientific terms,
you know,
they,
they just have a fast twitch muscle
fibers and they'll say all this crazy
shit that is true at the very highest
levels of the winners.
Right?
But it doesn't mean that you can't
become that.
No,
it just means that it's too painful for
most people to go through.
So very few people ever get there.
So if you look at the actual results,
he would be correct,
but he's not correct
because he doesn't take the shovel.
Exactly.
That's the moral of the story,
does not some easy lit up street lights,
wrath with nice smooth roads,
right?
It's a difficult motherfucker where
you're going to fail and you're going to
be in your head.
You can be saying I'm not good enough
and it's how you get through that is how
you get through that on a daily basis.
When that thing is st man,
I'm 43.
I've done so much.
You start to become civilized.
The refrigerator gets full.
You start making money and you start.
I'm not getting cold anymore.
I'm retired once in at 40 people.
Shouldn't it be playing basketball or
football or or,
or being.
You start to believe this shit and it
becomes in your fucking mind like
there's people who are retiring at 47
years old or 30 something years old at
43,
I'm still putting in hundred mile weeks,
still doing thousands of pullups pushups
because I'm not allowing myself to
become civilized.
The worst that can happen to a man's
You lose that fucking fight you,
you,
you lose that.
Why the fuck am I doing this shit?
I'm good.
You Ain't good man.
You ain't never fucking arrived and
that's just my mentality.
You may have more,
but you'd never fucking arrived.
You want to be uncommon.
I must uncommon people,
period.
Uncommon amongst uncommon peoples.
One of the greatest ways to put it,
that's it.
Like if you're the.
If,
if,
if you're like,
for me,
what got me in trouble with the navy
seals is I wanted to be one so bad,
so bad.
I fought my ass off and I saw them as
uncommon.
People.
Very uncommon.
But once you become a navy seal,
you all navy seal.
So guess what happens?
Your fucking common.
Again,
I wanted to be uncommon and months
uncommon people.
I want it to be the guy.
I don't care if you fucking light.
Okay?
If you don't understand me,
I didn't give a fuck.
Once I went through this fucking journey
and path of life,
you ain't got to enter a whole bunch of
fucking guys that don't fucking like me.
I don't give a fuck.
I'm a warrior period.
There's a lot of guys are spending a lot
more combat than me.
A warrior's not always at words that
mother fucker.
He says,
Hey,
I'm here again today.
I'm here again.
Tomorrow going to be here the next day.
I'm 50 years old.
I'm still fucking getting after it.
It's a person that puts no fucking limit
on west possible and that's what got me
in trouble a lot.
That's why I went to ranger school as a
seal.
That's what I tried to go to Delta force
twice.
You know I,
I've been,
I've been through all these different
training programs because I was looking
for in the military where I say all is
in the training.
These people get their ass handed to
them after they get out.
A lot of them get civilized.
I always wanted to go back into
training.
Am I?
We're always that.
I wanted to go back to war and the war
was in that training program where you
see guys,
you can quit.
Guys who are brutal guys who are
suffering,
guys who are.
You Go.
So as a ceo you don't volunteer for
ranger school.
I did.
I put in seven chips,
got turned down by eighth grade.
I got accepted.
I went at 28,
29 years old and they go,
why don't you go?
Because I started becoming civilized.
I started becoming complacent.
I,
I needed to get my fucking ass kicked
again.
And when you go as a seal going down to
you have no rank and ranger school,
you can be a major.
You just fucking Joe Brown,
you're nobody and you're not eating,
you're not sleeping.
So I always would put myself.
I really immerse myself and shit like
that.
Even our climb the ladder and I
intentionally fall back down that
motherfucker.
They said,
all right man,
getting soft dude,
getting soft.
Kick your fucking ass again.
And I,
you know,
it's kind of the process.
Did you find resistance from that
amongst other guys that didn't like to
make the.
You were making them uncomfortable
because that is something that people.
There's a natural instinct that people
have when someone's working harder than
them to somehow another diminish that
person.
Well,
I know that a lot of guys don't mind me
for a lot of reasons and I realized that
I am a guy that doesn't care if you
liked me or not.
And when you're an Alpha male and you're
against other offer males and we eat our
own alpha males eat their own.
And I loved that shit is fucking gold
man.
I want to eat.
Hey Man,
I'm all about that kind of mentality,
but I would sometimes take it to another
level and I wasn't part of a of a good
old boy network.
I didn't want to be part.
I wanted to be David fucking goggins for
too long in my life.
It got me in trouble for two on my left.
I wanted to be accepted.
Growing up.
I lied.
I fucking did what I could for.
If you fucking like UFC and identity.
I love it.
I love it man.
Let's go fucking watch them and be my
friend.
Be My buddy.
That fucking weak ass shit.
I found out through this path of life.
Who is David Goggins?
Who am I to go through all?
I did it alone.
There was no fucking trophy on the
fucking wall.
The mantle that trophies in my fucking
brain.
No one helped me get to know me.
Pay My fucking bills.
No,
I did shit for me.
No one random.
His fucking mouth was that fucking wait
when I suffered on my own and develop
this man who said to I man,
a very competitive,
ultra competitive.
Do that taking what you want,
man.
I call that personal sovereignty.
Exactly what not a lot of people that
have asked me and there's a lot of
people that change who they are
depending upon what people want from
them and that's.
That's me.
Yeah,
that's important man.
And most people struggled their whole
life to find out who they are,
struggled their whole,
their whole life.
To find out what defines them,
what they actually enjoy and what they
don't.
You start putting yourself in situations
that suck your find yourself.
Yeah.
You'll find out real quick.
That is the thing,
right?
And that's one of the things that I've
gotten from paying attention to you,
is that you,
what you're preaching,
what you're talking about is finding
yourself through struggle.
It's it,
it's the only way to find yourself.
You don't find yourself.
If you'd like bench pressing and you
bench press all the fucking time.
What are you finding out?
If you'd like to swim,
that's all you want to do is swim.
What are you finding out?
Put that you know people always are
people talking about tripled down on
your fucking strikes.
That's the fucking weak ass shit in the
world now tripled down on your fucking
weaknesses.
Found out something about yourself.
You know the the good shit.
You know the happy shit.
That's why my on my facebook page.
Why don't you talk about good times?
You know how to get to that shit
motherfucker.
You don't need a fucking year.
You don't need.
Want to tell you how to get through.
It's happy.
That's easy.
Shit.
I,
I would tell you how you can help
yourself get through the times that suck
real life.
This is real life.
Ninety percent of your life will suck.
Ten percent will be fucking happy.
You may be lucky guy and have a lot of
fucking money.
Have a great ass woman.
All this shit.
Trust me one on one with that fucking
guy.
He's missing something because life
still sucks that he hasn't faced
something that bothered him his whole
fucking life.
Some is still eating that motherfucker
up.
Almost everybody.
Everybody eating you the fuck up,
but maybe you found a good way how I did
growing up on how they ignore that voice
that's saying you ain't facing some
shit.
Period,
man.
I'm not special.
I just stopped listing.
I.
I listened to that voice.
It's why I talk so fucking aggressive.
People said,
man,
do you believe in God your customer
much.
When I say fuck it,
it's letting you know what I'm thinking.
If I try to make it all pretty and shit,
that's not what my life was.
It was a violent,
violent struggle daily to get where I'm
at today.
I'm not gonna water down.
Knock a water down.
Shit wasn't fun.
It ain't fun today,
but I'm happy.
Don't you think that your happiness is
probably elevated by the amount of pain
that you've gone through?
One hundred percent.
So the amount of suffering that you
understand,
the amount of pain that you've gone
through makes you appreciate the
happiness and the beautiful moments with
much more intensity.
That's what people miss about my story
week.
People hear this
kid,
I'm a god.
He must be miserable.
Oh my God,
what the Hell is wrong with them?
You're missing the fucking story.
You're not listening to the story,
man.
Look what I overcame.
If that is,
uh,
put some badge of honor tattooed in your
fucking brain for the rest of your life.
You can die today talking to Joe Rogan.
You're missing the story,
man.
Am I happy?
What the fuck do you think?
Don't miss it.
Don't misunderstand the passion in which
I speak for not being intensely happy,
happiest person in the world,
but I'm not done so I'm not gonna.
Speak to you like,
Oh man,
everything is great.
No,
I have a lot more shit to do.
A lot more shit to do.
Well,
this is in the same use of the word that
you used the warrior's mentality,
the warriors life,
right?
This is.
This is the way that you can keep
balanced and sane and keep a good grip
on who you are.
Period.
And like there's
a quote that was said.
I don't know who said it.
It was a great quote.
This guy said,
I'm going into combat going into war of
the 100 men that go into war tensioning
fucking be there.
80 of them are just targets.
10 do most or nine do most of fighting.
One is a warrior and it's a true quote
to life.
I saw it going through train.
I saw it everywhere I went.
There's so many people who just show up
to life that shouldn't even fucking be
around and there's few people do all the
work.
I wanted to be part of that nine.
I'm working towards being that one and
that's just how I live my life now.
What are you doing with your life these
days?
Right now I keep the same.
I'm very routine.
I get up every morning,
I run,
I go to the gym and then at nighttime I
stretch out.
I am.
I'm just trying to develop a business
costing me a lot of money trying to do
that.
I'm just getting out.
I'm A.
I'm an introvert,
so I never want to get on social media.
I'm not big on that.
I'm big on being with yourself.
I believe all these fucking cameras and
phones and shit,
it takes you away from the most powerful
thing in the world,
which is your fucking mind.
So I try hard to continue to grow that.
I'm trying to break a record again.
I'm trying to cross death valley as fast
as possible.
The top of Mount Whitney and I'm.
I'm constantly trying to put goals in
front me,
but the biggest thing that I'm trying to
find more of myself and the only way I
can find more as to silence the world
out as much as I can because it's
getting busier.
Everyday is getting faster and the
faster it gets,
the more you are missing who the fuck
you are.
So I track my own mind a lot and say,
look man,
I put my phone away.
I put shit away and I go dark.
I go dark a lot and it's because I have
to find out.
I'm on a journey of life and we all have
a different journey and I want to be in
my fucking pine box and I believe your
spirit is forever has to,
to fucking powerful.
No way in hell that thing is dies when
you die.
I want to be able to look back on my
life and I'm all dead and be so fucking
proud of myself forever.
This is all temporary shit to me.
I want to be forever proud of who I was
as a man and change who I used to be.
The liar,
the insecure guy,
the guy who can whatever I want to be
proud of,
and I if I died.
Now if I die at 80,
9,100,
I want to look at myself and say,
I'm proud of myself.
Don't you think that also like we were
saying that because you've gone through
so much struggle,
you appreciate happiness,
true happiness.
Do you think that you appreciate
discipline because you weren't
disciplined?
Do you think you appreciate the hard
work you put in because you used to be
weak?
Yes.
I appreciate self-discipline.
I never had in the crazy thing about
what you say that I didn't have a
motherfucker come wake me up at 3:00
in the fucking morning and say,
hey,
you gotta get your shit in.
I had no trainer.
I have a nutritionist.
It was the self discipline that I had to
survive,
not survive.
I was week to to,
to,
to thrive.
No one said,
hey man,
your tour in [inaudible] 97 pounds,
man,
I will help you out.
I'll help [inaudible].
You're fucking.
You're not smart.
I'm going to help you out.
I had to work at all this shit I had to
overcome and it,
it,
it subdisciplines everything.
If you don't have it,
I don't look at you right?
Because I know you're capable of more.
It's not discipline so much for me.
It's all on you.
The self part.
It was big.
We need someone to hold people
accountable.
Fuck that shit man.
Fuck that shit.
We count on people too much to get us
through shit.
And we looked to our right.
We look to our left and looking for help
and if you can build that self,
you can build that total accountability
and one self and it's not about being
selfish.
I'm trying to create a better me.
So hopefully people who are hearing this
are taking it the right way,
can say I can run a mile,
anybody running 205 fucking miles doing
fourth being and said,
hey,
that shit,
she doesn't matter.
I want you to see how fucking far you
can go.
And that's all it's about yourself and
that's where it all comes from
and I guarantee you've already done
that.
What you experience from watching a
television show and what,
what got you out the door,
what got you to sorta take the first
steps to change your life,
what you experienced by watching rocky,
what you expect,
those,
those moments of inspiration,
those are critical for people.
They need to know that someone's done
something,
that someone's done something that's
greater than they would they could
imagine themselves doing and they want
to take a step towards trying to be
better.
That that inspiration is gigantic.
And sometimes it comes across as corny.
You know,
people read too much of it online.
It becomes,
it drowns out you,
you lose the meaning gets lost.
I mean there's.
And there's a lot of,
posers has,
a lot of people are out there that are
pretending that they're trying to offer
up inspiration or a true honest account
of their experiences.
But really what they're trying to do is
say something that's going to get likes,
you know,
they're trying to say things that they
think people are going to go,
yeah,
double high five.
You know,
there's a thing that people are doing
where they're just trying to get social
cred.
I said,
your social media is,
man,
I'll paint you the picture of my fake
life.
Right?
I paint you a picture of my fucking real
life.
Yeah.
Period.
Like it or not,
man.
But that real life is fuel for people,
right?
It's fuel for me.
I,
I love that shit.
I live off of it.
There's a lot of people that I follow
online and you're one of them that I can
get something out of that I could watch
a short clip of you talk and I'm sure it
clips of this podcast.
People are going to play these clips and
go for fucking crazy runs afterwards.
Right?
Well hope so.
Fuck yeah.
So you don't even have to hope it's
going to happen.
That's good.
What is this business you're doing?
Well?
Is My own Goggins Llc.
Um,
basically I am invested in myself.
I'm investing in myself and I hope that
this story is,
can,
can change somebody's life,
not to be me because ain't about me and
I and I,
I,
I try to be as real as I can because
we're all fucking suffering in this
world.
We're all hurting and I tried to take
away all titles.
You want to give me that,
you know,
that I did not come from that shit.
That's,
I have to be so authentic and so real
about my own insecurities,
my own false ma.
This been a fucked up person.
I'm not the best at anything.
I'm not,
I'm not gifted,
I'm just driven.
And um,
it's all about trying to share that
message with people.
This is all about,
you know,
I speak to a lot of people and um,
that's what,
that's what I do now.
And how are you doing it as a business?
I do some motivational speaking,
but you know right now I'm not really
trying to make a lot of fucking money.
I'm just trying to build their brand as
authentic as possible because I don't
want to build it too fast because my.
My biggest fear in life is people can
rewrite through a motherfucker that's
not real.
I do all the time,
like a lot of people have these great
quotes and they and they and they mass
produce.
I can't mass produce something man,
and they had these great quotes and
shit,
but are you living that motherfucker?
What you just quoted in how powerful it
may sound?
Are you getting up every fucking morning
and about working out whatever.
Are you really getting the fuck after?
Are you just talking to motivate people
and I don't want to be that guy.
Or are you talking to pretend that
you're exactly after it and people make
this big money over here the side,
which robin made a lot and they,
they,
they talk this shit and they're off this
until it's gone.
Then authentic it all,
man.
You got all this shit and I read it.
I'm like,
man,
this guy,
bullshit,
man.
Fucking wake up,
get after it.
Live what you're saying,
and then it comes.
People can see when I talked,
the reason I talk,
so fucking,
just passionate because I'm reliving my
fucking life.
I'm reliving this morning when I got up,
I wouldn't do that shit.
I'm reliving everything I did and I
can't speak to you.
Like all calm and shit just sucks.
It sucks man.
So whenever I started talking about like
after this podcast,
you'll see man,
God,
you're so calm right now.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
I'm not going back through that shit
man.
I'm not.
I'm not going back through the suffering
and shit that it took to become who I am
today.
So I'm slowly trying to build this brand
to the point where I can slowly,
hopefully make people feel motivated to
driven because motivation is crap.
It's shit.
People right now maybe listen to this
shit.
They'll be motivated to go run.
If it's cold somewhere where they're at.
A lot of my friends will shut that door,
go back inside.
That's motivation.
It comes and go.
As how you feel if you and your wife are
good,
if you and your kids are good,
if you're good at work,
you're motivated.
I like the motherfucker whose life is
imploded,
ain't got shit in life.
It says,
still got fucking get after it today,
man.
To is about.
So that's when you move from motivation
to driven to obsessed and I want people
to realize once you get to this person
over here the driven obsessed part,
you're unstoppable.
This commitment that you have to
authenticity is one of the reasons why
people are connected to what your
messages.
That's one of the reasons why what
you're saying,
you don't want to grow too fast.
You don't want it to be bullshit.
You're terrified of that thing.
Just like we were talking about with
weak.
People are terrified of seeing that
weakness in yourself.
You know,
we all see that.
We've all seen motivational things that
are bullshit.
We've all talked to people that are
talking and you realize there's nothing
really that they're connected to.
They're not really connected to their
words,
the words,
just a bunch of words that they've
pieced together because they sound like
something that someone who's enlightened
on the subject would say,
yeah,
it does.
It doesn't,
it doesn't connect.
Oh,
so you're struggle now is to try to
figure out how to stay you and get the
message out,
but still be fully connected to that
message.
Right.
That's,
you know.
And it's not so much a struggle because
I'm not really about.
I'm not driven by the business.
I'm not,
I'm not doing by trying to be.
I make a very small salary from being
retired from the military.
That's all I need.
So I'm not fast to A.
I'm a,
I'm a minimalist motherfucker.
Give me a backpack of fucking ground and
sleep on and a pull up bar and a fucking
some running shoes in a subway sandwich
or some shit and I'm fucking straight.
So it's,
um,
I believe in patients.
I'm a patient dude.
I can watch the piece of grass grow for
20 years because I know that it is how
you get somewhere in life by being that
month like mentality.
And being able to watch something grow
very commonly,
patiently,
and that's all I'm doing right now.
It's not about money.
It's about people knowing me.
I'll keep you like me.
Whoever wants to hear this is out there.
It's also your,
your,
your goal is to grow this slowly,
very slowly.
And your goal is to grow this in order
to impact people.
Period.
I said,
it's not about me.
Um,
what do you get out of impacting people?
It's a good question.
I don't,
I don't get anything out of it.
I'm a tool,
but you must get something.
It must be personal satisfaction and
must be a connection to those people.
That must be,
it must be enriching to you.
It's hard to connect with people because
there's quite a few now that are coming
in.
It's my duty.
It's my duty to share my.
It's kind of like is somebody who
discovered a new earth,
you know,
and discovered that people in the water
source and the food source.
I discovered a whole nother part of your
fucking brain that a lot of people don't
even know about is my job.
I being a fucking on this journey of
being a discovery person,
being the person that maybe I discovered
this part,
I discovered a very important part to.
I haven't met many people that have
discovered as part of a lot out there,
but it's my job now.
Take these weak people in the category
that I was in and say I stopped reading
the bullshit.
Stop listening to the bullshit and if,
if my story of success can impact
somebody,
it is my job.
It's my duty to share the story.
As much as I'm not really fond of it,
I,
I'm not.
I'm the kind of guy that wants to sit in
the fucking room and just be me.
Just be me alone by myself as who I am,
but I have to get uncomfortable and tell
people all this shit.
I think it feels good to tell me about
it.
At a fourth grade reading level in high
school,
I stuttered.
I lied to people to be their fucking
friends.
It didn't feel good.
It doesn't feel good at all,
but maybe someone is doing the same shit
and maybe they can realize,
wow,
that motherfucker was a piece of shit
and he fucking now as a navy seal,
retired guy and runs these miles and was
297 pounds and pathetic fucker.
And Wow.
And people say,
why are you talking?
So it's the fucking truth.
I was a fucking pathetic motherfucker,
man.
People cannot say that to themselves.
This.
We have to choose these great fucking
magical words that,
that makes that make people feel good.
Tell yourself the truth is,
I'm gonna cause you fucking fat.
There may be bullying you,
but you might be fucking fat.
Some of cars you're dumb.
It's mean,
but you might be fucking dumb.
It's life,
man.
Take it for what it's worth and change
it and that terrible feeling.
When someone does tell you that you're
fat,
you can use that as fuel,
as fuel,
period.
And that's all this is about.
And,
and,
and where it goes.
If it goes somewhere and whatever,
you know,
I don't give a shit.
Well,
you said something that I think of when
I run and I said most people quit at 40
percent.
I said,
that's my 40 percent rule,
man.
I love that quote.
Forty percent rule man.
And I,
um,
I,
I really developed that through my heart
surgeries and I developed that through
that first hundred mile run.
And I thought I had given 100 percent
that was on that chair at mile 70.
I was fucked up.
I thought I'd give it 100 percent and
they go,
that last I go,
man,
there has this.
I wouldn't even near 100 percent.
So I came up with this thing called the
40 percent rule is basically where you,
it's like a car,
you put a governor on a car and they
said the car can go 1:30.
That governor stops the car,
91.
And your drive and thinking,
man,
I want to fucking Florida,
but I can't go.
I can't go any faster.
We do at your brain.
We put a governor on the brain
secretary,
feel pain,
discomfort,
suffering,
all those words that we hate to say
because we in this happy,
peaceful world we live in.
Now we stop,
we slow down,
and if you can get through these
different barriers and gain five
percent,
two percent,
three percent debt,
40 percent becomes 60,
that 60,
70,
80 and 90,
and then you'll hopefully one day near
100.
I don't,
I don't know.
Many people will probably add 100.
I mean we think we're there,
but there's so much more.
It isn't a 100 death's door though.
I really,
I love that.
I think is true.
I think that's 100 percent true.
I think when you were laying on top,
you'd knocked on a door.
That is a hundred percent true.
No one has ever.
That is 100 percent truth.
I didn't give 100 percent in that 101
mile run I did for the first time.
So that's the scary thing.
That's the scariest thing in the world.
I didn't die.
You probably gave 99 point nine,
nine,
nine.
I guarantee.
Guarantee Man.
Dude,
I don't know how to end this any better
than that.
So let's just wrap this up.
If people want to find your stuff,
what was the best place to go and look
for it?
I'm just at David Goggins,
man.
Social media or an instagram.
Facebook.
I don't tweet that much stuff out
because,
um,
I write these.
I write messages and always linked it on
twitter to facebook and Instagram,
but it's just at David Goggins is an
honor and privilege.
Thanks so much,
man.
I appreciate it.
Really,
really appreciate it.
Thank you David Goggins.
Ladies and gentlemen,
go after it.
You motherfuckers.
Come on.
That doesn't.