The joe rogan experience.
Dot.
I'm not,
I just don't have any room.
I look,
I watch professional pool.
One of those that you love going to
Canada.
I go to Canada and I turned on their
espn in Canada sneaker and it,
and they got like,
they got the darling,
they got curling may got stuff where I
go,
we would never show this bullshit cap
up.
Can I get a Kleenex man nasally and we
just ran out.
Here you go.
Nasally.
Yeah.
So it's not that like I don't,
I'm a caveman.
It's just,
I like what Jesus.
Sarah,
are you doing that on Mike?
I've got a big nose pushed up
microphone.
You,
but yeah,
but you're blowing hard with that Schnoz
old you go deep son.
You just made people throw up because
people listening to the,
it's funny how the fluid coming out of
people's nose is so vile that sound,
you know,
like when something like you on a
basketball court or something like that
and someone does a solid rock,
you see it like,
whoa.
And he tells me on Monday I got to get
out of the apartment.
So instead of going to look for a new
apartment over the weekend,
I go to my friend's Bachelor Party on
the Jersey Shore.
I'm at the Bachelor Party.
I'm getting a drink at the bar and I see
this girl.
I started chatting with her.
She asked me where I live.
I told her actually,
as of Monday,
I have nowhere to go.
She takes out a Napkin.
She writes her address on the Napkin.
I'm 21 years old and she says,
if it's an emergency on Monday and
you're stuck,
you can come live with me.
Monday comes,
I get kicked out of my friend's
apartment.
I have nowhere to go.
I'm like,
this is an emergency.
I take out the Napkin and I live with
this girl and her roommate for six
months.
It turns out that her father is a big
entrepreneur business man.
He owns a piece of the Yankees,
dislike monster mogul.
I write this song for the New York
Knicks called [inaudible] and it becomes
a big success.
You remember that song?
No,
no,
no.
Okay.
That's okay.
I'm not a sports fan.
That's fine.
It becomes a big hit.
And I just realized that there's an
opportunity to write theme songs for all
these professional sports teams.
But I don't have a penny to go in the
studio to do the demos,
to shop him to the team.
So I need money.
So I go to this music guy and he says,
I'll give you $10,000 to go and do these
songs for 10% of everything you make for
the rest of your life.
He wants to buy me like a style the rest
of your life.
I'm 21 he's like the rest of the rest of
your life.
Everything you do,
I will invest in you own an airplane
business.
He owns 10% yes.
Forever.
Yes.
You have to kill him then.
Yeah,
you have to kill that guy.
But I need the 10 grand.
So I say,
I'll take it.
So before I take it,
I go to this girl's father for advice,
this business mogul.
Then I'm living with her and I sit down
and I'd go to this guy's apartment
again.
I'm 21 he's got in his apartment,
he's got a swimming pool artwork like
fancy fuck women.
He's macked out man.
It's like,
I've never seen anything like this in
Manhattan,
in Manhattan.
I'm just setting the stage of the
conversation and I go in and I tell him
the story about the percent grant and he
says to me,
I would trade,
this is exactly what he said to me.
I will trade everything that I have for
you to get out of my daughter's life.
Exactly.
Outweighed everything I have for the one
thing that you have.
And I'm like,
man,
I'm fucking broke.
What he taught me,
I go,
what's that?
And he said,
youth,
because he had already gone through the
journey even though he had everything,
he already had gone through the process.
He wasn't that 20 year old that you're
talking about that whatever he had gone
through it,
he had it all.
He he,
he missed the process.
The journey of being you coming up at 20
and not know like you know here you are.
But it was the,
those were the years man.
The first fight,
the first this like that.
That's what,
that's what makes you like so,
and that stuck with me,
man.
At 21 years old,
it's stuck with me and realize that
like,
man,
I got to enjoy the process and it's
really never rubbed off on me in front
of me.
Oh,
well why didn't that guy,
how old was this guy at the time?
The old rich dude,
he was,
let's see,
he must have been his sixties.
What did I just do?
Shit to a bunch of shoot day lounge
around his fucking swimming pool did.
And he did.
He had an amazing,
he was 20.
He had an amazing life.
So what did you wind up doing?
Uh,
he said the SEC,
the second part of that conversation,
he said,
do you,
um,
will you make this work on your own?
I said,
I think I can.
He said,
I didn't ask if you can.
I,
I said,
he said,
will you make it work?
I said,
I will.
He said,
and then go tell the guy to fuck off and
make it.
And it goes and go make it work.
And I did,
but it was only like occasionally like a
party.
And I always felt like a loser for doing
it.
You know,
like everybody else would be getting
high and I'm but who?
And,
but I was probably already drunk anyway,
you know,
like when I was 14 or 15 or something
like that.
So maybe I smoked weed a handful of
times,
less than a dozen times until I was 30.
And then Eddie Bravo got me into it when
I was 30 years old.
We were doing Jujitsu together and,
uh,
he was telling me how marijuana was
helping his Jujitsu and helping his
music and his creativity.
It was like,
what the fuck is this guy talking about?
My Dude,
marijuana just makes it stupid.
Like,
don't,
you know,
and he's like,
just try it.
And he,
we got high and,
uh,
I remember thinking like,
Oh,
this is what it is.
Like,
wow,
I did not know
that feeling.
Like,
you're like,
why are you by yourself?
It's this,
no,
it's just me and Eddie.
Oh,
sweet.
sorry.
I can't believe this.
We went and got something to eat.
We're talking,
Oh yeah,
we gave go by crazy,
talked about all kinds of crazy shit.
And then I remember I started smoking
pot and getting on stage and got her,
it was her kitten.
Real quick eat with Mike,
my comedy and then smoking pot and doing
Jujitsu.
I was like,
I can't believe how zoned in and gets
you with training,
smoking pot and hitting the bag to this
day is like one of my all time favorite
things.
I get paranoid,
I get weirded out,
I get,
I get freaked out,
but I just fucking wrap up my hands,
put on the timer and just,
once that sweat starts flowing and she's
tall
and it's almost like the paranoia and
the weirdness of it all,
you just fight it off by hitting that
bag.
Boom,
boom.
You know,
and you,
you hear the bell that says 30 seconds
and your flurry in and then you get that
one minute off to think about life and
the future and the fuck can universe and
volcanoes and Guatemala and Hawaiian.
Oh God,
the bell goes off again.
You got another three rounds,
three minutes,
man.
It's one of my,
my like it's,
it's a psychedelic experience.
It's like a cleansing experience hitting
the bag when you're high.
I like,
I love shadowboxing.
When I'm hiring,
I'll take a rip out at home and just sit
there,
have a little mirror and I'll just
shadowbox don't even know how long.
I just can just shout a box for it.
Go.
Do you know what's weird?
Like you feel balance when you're high.
You feel like,
like maybe like if you got an injury,
you feel it more,
you feel like we're a laser off.
You know what I mean?
And like for me,
I,
I feel my transfer of power better when
I'm high.
Like,
like certain techniques.
I,
I really get the timing of when to turn
the hip over.
I feel it more when I'm high.
I like,
I feel the connection with all that
tissue,
all of it working together.
And I think that is,
that's what's happening.
I think that's what's happening with,
with this Allah phrenia thing,
if that's what it's called.
Um,
I might be remembering that incorrectly,
but this,
this thing that being around his
schizophrenia person,
like whatever weird error or brain is
making your,
your brain tunes into that air and you
start going crazy too.
As soon as that shit made sense,
I was like,
I gotta get the fuck out of here.
Cause he's done.
He's harmless.
He's never heard anyone,
but he still,
you know,
these days he's what he's prop guy.
He's probably in his sixties,
not in any kind of shape,
but back then when he still knew of
martial arts.
Oh he,
your stage,
your man.
But he never hurt anybody,
but he knew how to.
And um,
so one day there's eastern avenue in
Baltimore's,
for lack of a better term,
the Ventura Boulevard of Baltimore shops
everywhere and everything.
And there was this one woman that had
cut his hair one time and for him,
excuse me,
to touch his head,
was a big deal for him.
This.
So he immediately fell in love with this
lady.
Her name was Carissa.
So he went home and got his guitar.
And the thing about this guitar,
like this dude would pawn his bed,
his guitar,
everything.
But that guitar was always out of tune.
Exactly the same way.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Does that make sense?
Okay.
So always fucked up,
but always consistently fucked up every
guitar he had.
That's how he tuned it.
That's how he heard it.
Oh Wow.
So he writes her,
he writes her a love song and he wants
to go up to her shop and now sing it for
her.
So he goes up and he stands out in front
of the shop and he's gets her attention.
He's got his guitar and he's gone and
starts off where he goes.
He goes,
Chris,
I love you and Baltimore accents.
Car Name's Karissa.
But he says,
Chrissa Okay Chris,
I love you Chris.
I need you.
Then he goes,
Chris,
at all,
dogs of crystal,
all crack is not what a dye crystal.
And she's freaking out like,
what the fuck?
Yeah,
like your eyes.
So they call the police,
he gets arrested.
Oh No.
When he doesn't understand why he's
arrested in his mind,
what did I do wrong?
I just wrote a beautiful song for
someone I care about and I wanted to
share it with her.
So my cousins,
all of us were like,
we gotta go to court and watch this.
This is going to,
cause he's got,
he's got to go to court.
So they bring them out from the back.
Oh No.
And he stands up and it's a,
it's a female judge.
And um,
my,
his mom,
my aunt Margaret and my great aunt,
my grandma's sister,
rods,
extended family,
big time and we're all there watching.
And the judge says,
ask the girl her side of things.
And she's like,
well,
this happened.
And he's like,
she's like,
would you like to speak on your behalf?
And he's like,
I just don't understand what I did
wrong.
I wrote a song for someone I care about
and I just wanted to share it.
And she's like,
would you mind sharing some of the
lyrics of,
we're all like,
aw shit.
And he fucking,
Chris,
I love you Chris.
I need you crystal.
All crack is,
I want to die.
She goes,
okay,
that's enough.
That's enough.
And then they're about to let him go
because they understand I'm gonna put a
restraining order.
He's under supervision,
but they're about to let him go.
And she goes,
oh,
wait a second.
Oh,
there's a,
there's still an open charge here on the
books,
so we're going to have to take you back
to,
he starts losing his shit.
Like what?
Maya?
Marguerite stands up and to a judge,
she goes,
Hun,
we dropped those charges.
Everyone Calls People Han in Baltimore.
She goes,
[inaudible] job,
those charter.
That lady said,
first of all,
you don't call me Hud.
I am a judge.
You address me as your honor.
We're all like,
I am augury got skull.
And they fucking took him back and he
was screaming going on.
Did they put,
uh,
the family put a charge on him?
Yeah,
he had,
he would do things like,
he would show up to their place in a cab
demand.
They pay for it.
They didn't,
he throw a brick through the window.
So they have
for that Jesus Christ.
And they really did drop the charges,
but it was just a clerical error that
never made it to the paperwork.
And she's like,
I got to do what I gotta do.
We're taking you back today.
And he was,
they were pulling it back and he was
gone nuts.
Oh my God,
yes.
Okay.