Hello freaks,
the fuck's going on ladies and
gentlemen,
this episode of the Joe Rogan experience
podcast is brought to you by Luke
Massetti.com.
That again is.
That's not a dude,
by the way.
That'd be a cool name though.
My name's Lou lumosity.
That's a bad attitude.
Is that the Internet?
That helicopter?
No,
that's real life.
That's a sound effect.
They're looking for you anymore.
Don't say not now.
I didn't say shit.
Listen to Alex Jones.
Go after him.
Black helicopters problems and
solutions.
Ladies and gentlemen,
lumosity is a website that's designed as
a gym for your dome as we sit here
drinking miller.
Highlife lumosity is,
um,
it's essentially what they've developed
is games that increase your brain's
capacity to do things.
And what do I mean by that?
It's like it gets your brain in shape
and they don't come across as like being
work.
It comes across as,
as games.
It's really interesting and it's based
on the science of it's called
neuroplasticity.
That's the,
uh,
the idea behind it.
And there's a series of questions that
they ask you when you sign up and when
you,
uh,
you go to their website,
you click on get started now,
and then you start entering all sorts of
information.
Like what aspects of your memory are you
trying to train?
Like recalling the location of objects.
Can you not breathe?
Hold on.
What happened?
Oh,
I'm sorry.
The right into the microphone.
I'm sorry man.
I remember one makes you do things and
not realize you're doing it.
Lumosity a has memory,
attention,
speed.
Like meaning,
the speed of,
of recognizing things,
coming up with answers for things,
flexibility,
communicating clearly and thinking
outside the box.
And again,
all this shit is done in,
in games.
It's really interesting stuff.
I enjoy it.
It's fun.
It's fun to play.
That's ever been a guy that uh,
you know,
there's a bunch of 350 pound guys out
there that you know,
that all of a sudden they're one 90.
They get in shape.
They have been to the last year with
Robert.
Robert Bradley was 350 pounds.
It's 190 pounds now.
He's amazing because he cut out soda and
he started training Jujitsu.
So with this luminosity thing that
you've got,
what if,
what if you start like,
you know these dudes,
you know certain,
you know this guy joe or whatever is an
idiot and all of a sudden he gets into
these games and he's fucking
intelligent.
He's like Graham Hancock and shit.
You think there'll be guys like that.
I think it's possible to increase your
capacity slightly.
That's what I think.
I know how dumb I am,
so I know like when it comes to like,
have you ever talked to a mathematician?
A in sixth grade I've had conversations
with mathematicians,
just random guys that have met places
and start talking to them about that
fucking goodwill hunting
shit.
When they write on the chalkboard and
all those weird fucked up.
I knew what it meant and Algebra because
Algebra was kind of easy to me and it
was all that shit,
but I don't remember what it means now.
Well,
I think this is what it's like.
I think,
and I think this is where lumosity comes
into this,
is that when you do something a lot,
you get in shape for that thing and that
includes comedy.
You know,
I've been doing comedy for 23 years,
but dude,
if I tell you a couple of months off,
I get on shaky legs.
If I just try to go onstage flat,
I have to go over my material,
I have to listen to notes,
I have to listen to old recordings and
get myself in the groove because my
mind's not in comedy shape and that's
what happens.
Like that happened to me when I was
filming that show,
the Scifi show because I was doing it
constantly.
I got out of comedy shape like I could
feel it.
I could feel onstage.
I was awful little and I think that
mathematics especially is one of those
things that you get into and you build a
base,
you build a base and understanding of,
you know,
simple stuff like simple arithmetic,
simple subtraction.
Then you start dividing things.
Then you start getting into Algebra and
equations in Calculus and you need that
base.
You need like you to need,
got to be in shape.
You can't just get into a Jujitsu gym
and roll with Eddie Bravo.
You gotta have some fucking training
behind you.
You've got to build your conditioning
up.
You've got to get somewhere.
I think it's like that with everything
you do,
man.
Do I remember I had a multiply numbers
and Adam and subtract them and light
them up.
Right?
But the division,
you know when you put them in a little
345 divided into 17,000,
212,
like how the fuck do you do that?
You start over,
you start on the top of that house and
where do the decimal points go out?
I don't know how to do that shit no
more.
Yeah.
That's where it stops.
It's one of those things,
man.
Well you just gotTa do it all the time.
It's got to be a part of your life.
If it's not a part of your life,
it's too slippery with Jujitsu.
I think that's where the comedy.
I think that's the way with anything
hard.
I think most people forget that shit
like this division because I'm sure
you'll probably fuck up yo,
I fuck up.
Simple point of is there.
Is it important to learn how to do it
even though you're going to forget it is
does.
Is that just an exercise of the mind?
It's not the actual division process in
and all that.
It's just you're,
you're young,
you're 12,
you're 13,
you're working out the mind.
We know they're going to forget it when
they grow older,
but you need that workout.
Is it for that or are you supposed to
remember how to do that?
I think when you take time off of
things,
you just forget how to do them.
You know?
I went for a long period of time where I
didn't play pool.
You know?
I used to play pool eight,
10 hours a day.
When I lived in New York,
I was upset.
I wanted to be a professional pool
player.
I was obsessed and then I took like
years off and I started playing again in
like 2006 or something after I did a TV
show and I was fucking terrible.
Dude,
I didn't know what I was doing.
I just lost all my information.
I get it all went away,
but I was playing eight,
10 hours a day.
Man,
I was pretty decent.
I was a decent like b player and then I
just was Tara f player.
As soon as I came back I was like,
where did it all go?
Why did I forget how to do everything?
Methods,
the
methods of science thing right up,
right up on may have math.
Math to me is a.
it's a science.
It's very complex like I think you're
born with it.
It's a.
it's a serious set of skills that you
have to constantly keep working on it if
you're going to perfect it.
One thing about mathematicians,
they never argued with each other and
they're not,
oh no,
this is.
This is going to happen.
To be mathematicians are just like,
boom,
it's right on the table.
You can't argue the math is correct.
All this is going to do is look at it
and you'd be like,
Oh man,
that's correct.
The same thing with this lumosity,
which is so crazy because to me that's
like science,
science is basically telling you to put
your life,
your brain,
your neurological patterns,
your thoughts,
everything on a computer and I think
scientists are able to study that like
what do most people like,
what are they going to do this and
they're going to start putting it into
categories because there's these
scientists out there right now that are
basically learning how to control
computers through through one's brain
and they think that your brain is going
to be a part of the computer one day for
sure,
and it's all going to be that that
computer is actually going to be you.
And I think with this,
lumosity is a huge step in that era,
which is like a science.
It's a math,
I think it says building on computers or
the next.
You can't deny him.
You know,
we've grown so much through,
through computers in this and this
history.
It's only gonna get more advanced.
It's going to get a lot more technical
and a lot more bizarre.
Yeah.
And the idea of designing programs that
and he enhanced your brain the same way
you would design something that would
work out a computer.
I think you have a real good point about
mathematicians to because they don't
argue about shit.
It's pretty pretty black and white if
you can understand the math,
but it gets so squirrely that some guys
can't even understand the math.
Like it gets to this weird super complex
area like where they have these million
dollar prizes to solve problems.
Like there was this one crazy Russian
cat that apparently he wanted but didn't
want the money to remember that shit.
That story.
Some Russian dude is solve this long
term mathematical problem and he didn't
even want the money.
It was like a million dollar prize or
something ridiculous behind it.
But he was just obsessed with solving
these complex riddles of numbers and he
lived in that world,
the world of numbers.
How crazy is that?
That that is the pinnacle of,
of intellect.
We don't know shit about it.
I don't know what the fuck.
And that's like.
It's almost like it's almost to fully
understand.
No one knows exactly what we're about
and how the fuck we're why we're here,
but it's going to have something to do
with them damn numbers that they're
working on.
Right.
It's like the meaning of the universe
has something,
there's a connection and they're,
they're closer to figuring it out than
we are.
You know,
that's what life's about is really
connected,
you know,
as far as connecting to punch,
connecting to triangle,
the whole world,
not connecting the dots.
And math is the true science to it
because most people can't understand it.
So automatically like,
oh,
this guy's crazy.
So basically none of us in this room are
involved.
The true science of life.
We're just fucking shitting ourselves
and jerking off.
Yeah,
yeah.
When you look at people,
people,
reproduction is very,
very key to our species out there that
could look at science though.
They see the signs and they still,
they still wrote they're smart as hell.
They'd,
they look at the science and they still
don't see it,
but if it was put in this put in math,
like you put it in numbers,
you have to accept it.
Right?
Except the numbers,
all that shit,
but you know,
they'll,
they'll check to see if your theory's
Ryan.
If it isn't,
it basically becomes like a law of
gravity.
It's set in stone.
There's no arguing with it.
It's a,
it's a law.
If you throw something up in the air,
it's going to fall down and he's like,
so no bias in that.
You know,
in math there's no bias.
Interesting
point,
man.
You know,
and I want to get to this on the podcast
later when we're talking,
we're going to talk about some numbers
and some,
some,
some different things over this weekend.
Anyway,
go to lumosity.com.
Use the code named Rogan.
Let them know that I sent you in the
referral box and click start training.
Create your own program.
You could try it out.
It's a really,
really fascinating website.
I think it's a beautiful design.
I love the idea behind it and I love the
idea that you can do something like
this,
that you can create a fucking gym for
your brain.
It's awesome.
They owe you triple for this commercial.
This was 35 minutes.
Yeah,
but these commercials are entertaining.
That's the whole key behind it and we
need more of those.
Joe,
like the way you used to do it,
you're just blazing through them in two
minutes.
Sometimes 30 minutes.
That is true.
Sometimes I do.
They're going to expect it,
man.
You better slow down.
Damn,
you're right.
Dammit.
Eddie Bravo wife freaking me out,
man.
He had the Darth vader of I'm going to
give you commercials and they're going
to give you material to try to say this,
this dot.
Oh really?
Yeah,
he jokes.
I shipped a lumosity.
Got Go there.
It's the shit.
You'll love it.
Uh,
we're also brought to you by
squarespace.com.
Squarespace is
a new website that is designed to make
websites.
It's fucking awesome.
I'm a huge fan of this thing.
Everybody that we've turned on two
squares
base has,
has really enjoyed it.
Like my space.
Right?
Sorry,
it was adjusting something.
You are retarded.
No.
My space.
You pretty much used to build your own
website,
right?
This is way better.
This is not going to crash and I don't
think you use glitter tags.
You can set up a store on this,
there's no comments.
You can use it on iphone,
android,
anyone
thing it's pretty bad ass and there's
going to be,
we're going to do some sort of a
contest.
And the winner,
whoever creates the coolest website is
going to get,
um,
free squarespace with,
for a year or something like that.
Right?
It's free service for a year.
Um,
I'll let you know exactly what the,
uh,
what the contest is going to be,
but I'm expecting some pretty cool
websites because it's pretty easy to use
a dope like myself can use it.
It's simple.
And if you go and use the offer code Joe
and the number 11 because we're in the
month of November,
you can get 10 percent off your first
purchase on.
That's what's so funny.
What happened,
what happened?
It keeps on bringing that mix.
I keep turning it.
Eddie Bravo.
So your trend is doesn't have carved out
like a sleep apnea.
Mild a mild case.
It's snowing like a motherfucker man.
Me chills,
you know,
when my wife takes me,
she goes,
look,
this was the last night,
and I'm like,
Shit.
You know what a big part of that
memorable.
It's your nose and it's also your neck
grapplers get it.
A lot of sleep because neck is too big.
Dude,
I'm all over the fucking place.
I said,
do you sleep on your side?
I'm here.
I'm like,
I'm violently wrestling with myself.
I'm putting myself in the lockdown and
shit.
When I sleep I,
I wake up five times a day or night and
then I piss a couple of times a night.
I'm all over the fucking place,
man.
I never get A.
Anyway,
make a website on that.
Eddie Bravo.
Sleep patterns.com.
It just every night go man.
Tonight wasn't motherfucker.
That actually might be a cool video
series.
Like every day you wake up and talk
about your fucking sleep and Gopro.
The snoring.
I haven't elapsed time.
Elaborate.
Just fucking all over the place.
You can go to squarespace,
Eddie Bravo,
and you could make this website and you
can sell stuff.
You can set up an ecommerce site and it
works for musicians to.
This is a thing about squarespace.
You can easily sell music,
so it is right up your alley.
Digital downloads,
soundcloud,
man,
that's the shit like soundcloud.
Soundcloud is the best workout.
You got to get on that sound cloud,
get the free music,
every art.
It just seems like most artists,
even though they're signed,
they'll have their little soundcloud and
put their own remixes and shit on that.
I mean,
it's all free.
So go ahead.
If you want to go to squarespace
problem.
I'm sorry.
You're going to apologize for musicians
who want to sell music.
I guess it's pretty fucking hard to sell
music score days,
right?
Give it away.
That's a fascinating turn of events,
man.
The Internet is a weird thing.
It really is a,
you can connect your accounts to
facebook,
twitter,
all that shit.
And if you go to squarespace.com
and use the offer code Joe and the
number 11 because we're in the month of
November.
Uh,
if you,
uh,
you can get 10 percent off if you sign
up for a yearly plan.
And that discount applies to the entire
year.
So use the offer code Joe and the number
11.
Get 10 percent off your first purchase.
A new accounts@squarespace.com.
And use the offer code all one word Joe.
And the number 11 to save 10 percent for
a limited time only.
We're also brought to you by [inaudible]
dot com.
That's o n n I t if you haven't been
there for a.
We got a lot of new shit including
Zombie kettlebells.
That will scare the fuck out of you
while you're training.
You want to train for the Zombie
Apocalypse?
No better way than swinging around a 72
pounds.
Zombie head.
You will get some serious shapes on,
especially if you double up on those
bitches.
Put Hair on him.
No,
no hair yet.
That's Eddie Bravo that it looks like
you're swinging around the capitated
head.
I could think of no better way to kappa
bells.
I can think of no better way to prepare
for the apocalypse than to 72
pounds Zombie kettlebells sign.
You'd be ready.
You just gotta you gotTa.
Do what that do.
That extreme kettlebell cardio workout
series from Keith Weber do it with two
72 pounders.
No one can fuck with you though.
The zombies.
You just be cutting the heads off and
run into safety over and over again.
So these are real.
They're real.
Put that on your squarespace.
Set.
Your website and Pravo.
They're making a prequel to face that
facebook movie.
No,
I didn't know about my space.
Is it?
That seems like a show.
Justin timberlake.
Episode one.
They got to go back to friendster.
Friendster,
and then it turned.
Then everyone you ask friends during the
Ngo space was on live journal.
Remember that?
They should really.
I don't remember that at all.
They should really fuck with us and use
the exact same actors that they use in
the.
In the facebook commercial and don't say
shit about it.
The facebook movie use the exact same
actress.
Everyone who was in that facebook movie
now in the space,
but we let you know how fucking stupid
we think it has a bad ending.
The My might is when everyone started
abandoning ship going to facebook.
It's still up,
man.
I tried to delete my account several
times,
fucking didn't work.
Anyway,
go to [inaudible]
dot com,
check out any of our supplements,
use the code name Brogan and save 10
percent off any and all the supplements,
all the supplements we sell,
whether it's shroom,
tech,
sport,
which is the best if you want to talk
about a workout pre workout thing to
take.
The best thing I've ever tried ever for
enhancing your endurance is shroom Tech
Sport Shit.
It's cordyceps mushrooms and be 12.
And uh,
there's a couple other ingredients in
there as well.
But the idea behind it is that cordyceps
mushrooms,
they found that these high altitude
herding cattle people notice that their,
their cows were eating these mushrooms
and they were like more active.
So they started taking them and people
start using them.
China used him in the Olympics and they
got a bunch of gold medals with them in
1993.
The Beijing Summer Games,
uh,
the Chinese,
women's team was using,
uh,
they,
they figured out how to use these core
steps.
Mushrooms to run marathons says they
were running and impossible marathon
every day in preparation.
Several world records later,
the rumor was confirmed,
rumor doping test came up negative and
it was revealed that the secrets was
court has steps send Nessus sinensis,
sinensis,
s I n e n s science.
How would you say that?
How many fucking words are there online
that you know what they are when you
read them,
but you see you have no idea to say
that.
A different story because that story
isn't true story because how are you
going to check on the Chinese fucking
swim team or something?
Yeah,
you could just make up some shit easily.
You could go online and find that pretty
quick.
These supplements are the real deal.
I think man behind this quarter
mushroom,
it improves oxygen utilization and the
ATP production.
Two critical aspects of endurance,
the endurance athlete.
So it's,
it's,
it's a fantastic workout.
Top of it.
Makes Sense.
I could just like weed.
Weed is good in so many different ways.
It with nutrition and everything,
doesn't mushrooms,
you know,
they definitely put you in touch with,
uh,
the other dimensions that are all on
you.
So yeah,
some of them will kill the fuck out of
here.
You gotta be careful,
but it makes sense.
It makes sense that it does other shit
like physical benefits.
That makes total sense.
Totally does.
Anyway.
No one's trying to rip you off.
This is all the best shit that we could
find.
We sell everything that we use and we
have a very fair policy on supplements.
A 30 pill,
90 day money back guarantee.
You don't even have to return it.
Just say,
I tried this shit.
I didn't feel anything.
You don't.
Okay,
you're fine.
You're good.
You,
you don't have to send anything in.
You get your money back because all
we're doing is trying to turn you onto
some shit that we use ourselves and I
find benefit in it.
And I think that if you try it,
you're going to enjoy it.
You're going to find benefit in it and
you're going to realize why it costs,
what it costs,
what's involved in producing it.
What we're trying to do,
give you the highest level ingredients
available and do it like in a suit in
the most ethical way possible.
That's what we're trying to do.
Yeah,
for sure.
If you,
if you fill it,
you know it's real,
you know,
fill your performance,
peak up,
you'll feel you'll feel a lot more
healthier,
you know,
like more older you get and the more
better you feel you're going to start
filling a lot younger I think.
I think it does a lot of great things
for your men mentally,
mind,
body,
soul,
Spirit,
everything,
man.
There's a bunch of shit you can do out
there to benefit yourself and that's
what ana is all about.
It's a human optimization website.
We're trying to just find shit that puts
you in the best mood.
Like there's a supplement called five
htp and it helps your brain actually
produce chemicals that make you feel
better.
And serotonin development.
It's all from people been,
you know,
they've had these,
these drugs to enhance serotonin and
development for a long time and Ssri for
people who have depression issues or
five htp is a natural way to do that and
that's one of the supplements that we
sell it on and it's called new mood and
inside of new mood is five htp and also
trip to fan which converts to five htp
in your body.
The idea and being that it'll give you
more of a time release effect.
Um,
as far as what's controversial now,
I've never had one person say that new
mood didn't have an effect on them.
And I've never heard one person say that
shroom tech sport hasn't had an effect
on a positive both,
but there have people that said Alpha
brain didn't do shit for them.
And I don't know what that's about.
I don't know how.
I mean some people they work together.
Yeah.
The mood and the Alpha brain.
Some people maybe they're not as
sensitive as to what affects their brand
or doesn't affect their brain.
Maybe it didn't work on them.
Maybe they already have like a,
a high level of nutrients in their
system.
It didn't need a bump.
I know too many people took too much
night that nighttime night,
bunch of other shit.
Just give me the most crazy,
elusive wild dreams ever.
Amazing,
amazing dreams that I use.
This.
I'll take it to three times a day.
I'll use the Alpha brain.
I'll use the shroom tech ran and when
I go to sleep like sometimes like I
don't,
I don't go to sleep for awhile,
but when I sleep,
man I'm,
I'm out for the whole night.
I'm not getting up,
going to the bathroom.
I wake up in the morning just just like
sunshine in like it's great.
Every day is from knew.
Mood.
Knew mood in a alpha.
Beta.
Use them together.
Man.
I,
I sleep so good.
It's not like when you wake up,
you feel like groggy.
Maybe you guys took Nyquil.
When you're sick,
you wake up.
You're like,
oh my God.
Yeah.
Do you take this?
You wake up.
You're like,
man,
how you doing baby?
You feeling good?
Ready to get after it.
Like you just automatically in the zone
as soon as you wake up,
you know how to get that night.
The practices early,
I think.
No,
I do have new mood,
but you know,
I,
I would take it every now and then after
a late night podcasts and I'm all wound
up and I need to get some sleep.
I use it like to try to call it.
Well,
people who were into lucid dreaming,
they've been using Alpha brain people
who there's like a whole,
you know,
how people were into Jujitsu because
people were into Lucy.
I try to get it for a while.
I never tried it.
I got to work twice for me.
Railing.
Hell yeah.
There's all these different techniques
out there and lucid dreaming.
There's a lot of people who think lucid
dreaming is like dreams that uh,
everything is crystal clear.
And so it's like,
so like it affects them.
It's not really that lucid dream is
knowing that you're inside a dream,
recognizing that it's a dream and then
having the power to control everything.
The first two steps of the levels of
dreaming,
I think.
Right?
Like when you're your mind still half
awake,
it's when you realize you're dreaming,
you know you're in a dream and you know
you're sleeping and this is a dream and
you can control everything.
Then when you wake up,
you can look it up in a blood only that
you could fly.
You could do anything you want.
You are on the Matrix.
As soon as you recognize you're in a
dream,
you right.
You have to recognize that you have the
power to do whatever you want.
The only time I ever had a lucid dream
happen because of something I did was
something I saw in a movie where a guy
was saying,
when you go through a door,
you should knock on the door and say,
am I dreaming?
And do it every day.
When you go through doors,
like whenever you go through door knock,
knock,
am I dreaming?
So that becomes like a habit when you go
through doors.
So when you go through a door and your
dream.
I did this for awhile.
Then I went through a door and my dream
and I went,
Oh shit,
I'm dreaming.
I was like,
there's no door here,
and then I realized I was dreaming.
I remember this.
Normally when I know that I'm dreaming,
I'll just wake right the fuck up.
I normally can't hang onto it.
I always described dreams as being like
a really gentle bubble,
like a kids bubble where they blow
bubbles is a barely hold it in your
hand,
but dreaming on Nootropics,
whether it's Alpha brain or neuro one or
new boot or any of these.
I get these weird like rubber dreams,
like you can bounce them around and move
them.
They're durable bubbles.
I slept with dvds.
I got into [inaudible].
There's people that are really good at
it.
There's guys that could do it every
night that masters and they look forward
to dreaming while I was into this for
like maybe six months.
I got into it.
I got a couple of dvds and you sleep
with these dvds and they keep it.
They keep waking you up like every
couple minutes ago,
wake up and then it actually does you
up,
and then you go back to sleep and you
get used to just sleeping through the
white cups.
And then as soon as,
I don't remember exactly how it all goes
down,
but it's really,
really hard because you've got to keep
reminding yourself you've got to keep
thinking of a,
a,
a certain place and then you can do all
that other stuff where you knock on it
every time we walked through a door,
you asked herself on my dreaming in your
everyday life.
But that becomes really hard.
Like you forget,
you get lazy,
you don't want to do it.
So it's hard.
So I was able to do it twice a with
these dvds.
There's all these instructions and they
talk to you and they try to wake you up.
And it worked out of maybe 40 times that
I went to bed doing these exercises,
these mental drills.
Uh,
it worked twice and it was pretty
awesome,
man.
And then,
and the two things that everyone does
and you can do with breathing,
the [inaudible] you have fight or
flight,
so when you're all fight or flight,
so you get home from a late night work
out or you just beasts in the Joe Rogan
on it kettlebells feeling like a beast
and you're at night,
you could be tired,
but your body's still reacting to the
fight or flight mode.
We just did this workout.
What are we going to do next?
And if you actually take time and you
slow down your breathing,
you tell your,
uh,
your nervous system to,
to slow down.
Okay?
It's time to relax,
which actually releases natural
hormones,
which I'm sure you're capable of.
But in,
in dreams I've had dreams on,
on these type of supplements where I
felt like I could literally push off the
ground and I was flying in the air and I
was like,
I kept telling myself when I woke up,
I'm like,
man,
I got to remember that.
So I tell myself,
almost like you're knock on the door.
Remember that?
And I was,
I was transforming in these dreams.
Like I'd fly here and then I would go
somewhere else and when I remember that
I looked it up and it was like,
you're in control of your life.
Like you can control your destiny.
Right now it's like all about.
So sometimes I'd have like some good,
like positive results and then like
sometimes it's like a,
you got bit by something and then you
gotta like look it up and it's just
like,
oh,
you're just going through a rough one
right now.
And you're like,
we have no doubt.
Right?
So have interpretations.
They have interpretation.
Know what the.
I think they're guessing like a mother.
It's insane.
No way dude.
Grab,
grab a book of a,
of a dream book from anywhere and just
just try to tell yourself to either
knock on the door,
remember this dream,
wake up and either you can even Google
this dream interpretations and you can
really look up your dreams.
Some of them are like a little bit off
the ball,
but some of them you're like,
wow.
I mean,
I've had more than on both hands of
dreams that I can remember were like I
looked it up and it like maybe something
hit while you're talking about knowing
that you're in a dream,
dream,
and then he finds the interpretation.
What does it mean
in the dream going,
fuck,
I'm in a dream.
I can.
Once people realize their dreams,
the two most common things that they do
fly.
Everyone flies right away and have sex
immediately.
Like,
Oh shit,
you and the two times I did it,
I remember when the first time this DVD
worked,
I thought,
oh my God,
I'm dreaming.
Let's get to the podcast.
We're going to end this commercial.
This is a commercial.
Use a code name.
Rogan save 10 percent off finding this
up,
and I said,
Tom,
o n n and it will talk about this,
right?
I,
we'll
just go right into it because I don't
want people to mess us.
Hit it.
Joe Rogan experience podcast
commercial.
It was just too good.
I had A.
I had to stop and just make the podcast
live because on Sirius satellite radio,
none of that other stuff will go on
because it's all the commercials,
but talking about we were talking.
I'm here with Jeremy Stevens,
little heathen in the house and the
Great Eddie Bravo,
my brother.
Thank you for.
And we're uh,
we're going to talk about the UFC for
sure.
But right now we were talking about
lucid dreaming and Eddie was bringing up
the fact that you can,
you can,
if you study like methods,
there's books that they have.
There's exercises you can do where you
can try to figure out how to get
yourself in a state where you can have a
lucid dream.
And you did it a couple times.
And again,
lucid dreams.
A lot of people think lucid dreams are
crystal clear dreams.
Lucid dreaming is when you know you are
dreaming.
Not a crystal clear,
profound dream.
It's when you figure out you're
dreaming,
you can control everything.
Everything becomes super clear.
Like all.
Once I figured it out,
I was dreaming it and it worked.
All these,
these,
this DVD talks to you while you're
sleeping and then it wakes you up.
He's trying to wake you up in your
dream.
You're dreaming,
wake up,
you're dreaming,
you're dreaming.
Wake up,
control this DVD.
You're saying that,
so you go to sleep with this.
Is that what you're doing?
There's all these mental exercises you
do.
You have to think of a.
you're on an island with,
you know,
think about the person you want to dream
with and all that.
There's really hard.
It's easier just to go to fucking sleep.
What if you got to,
if it's a five DVD series,
you got to like DVD number five and it's
like,
and I'm going to come to my house and
you're going to unzip my
pants and you're going to suck my cock.
Like it's programming you program with
people across the country.
Guys blow jobs,
but the two most popular things,
there's a lot.
There's black belts at lucid dreaming.
If you have the,
the men.
It's a mental exercise and you just want
to go to sleep on at night,
so it's very hard to do.
You have to be militant and you have to
be sharpened in know while you're tired
and ready to go to sleep.
It's hard,
but it worked a couple of times for me
and the two things that most people like
doing or flying.
As soon as they figured out there in a
dream,
they go,
fuck,
I'm gonna fly,
come flying shit.
And then sex.
They go right to sex.
And it's true because the two times it
worked for me and,
and when I used to have lucid dreams as
a kid,
I actually had him when I was a kid once
or twice a year and I'm talking about
being like eight or nine years old and
the first thing I wanted to do with just
like find a girl and make out with her
and just like humber wasn't a weird
thing.
It was a weird thing.
It was,
I was a little kid.
It was a weird thing.
I wanted to go look for girls and I
remember these lucid dreams.
I remember a couple I'll never forget.
Amazing that when your hormones are at
your highest,
that's when you're the youngest and
dumbest and not able to.
When you're 13,
you're shit is killing you all day.
Baffled.
It's like you went through your whole
life feeling like pretty much the same
dude just slowly growing and then all
the sudden you hit 30.
You
get to a storm of confusion.
In high school we did is hard all day.
You don't know what the fuck is going on
and God forbid you find a girl's willing
to touch your Dick.
Oh my God.
You stick to her like glue.
Like she.
She's like,
you're a drug dealer,
you're a crack addict and she's your
drug dealer and you're hanging around
with it.
No matter what state became believe
different things to hang out with.
A girl when the fuck did that,
I haven't ever just make an out because
it's going to be making off while I'm
making it out.
Awesome.
You just want to make an offer.
I want to go to movies just to make out.
Just like whatever.
Fuck them over.
Just make out.
It's the only private spot at 13 that
you could find dark,
but anyway,
it's about these dreams.
I ended up doing it twice and that's
what I did the first time.
As soon as I figured out I was dreamed
that you are dreaming and I'm like,
I am dreaming.
Everything became really bright and
immediately I flew with my hands down
like that,
like fucking ironman through canyons and
it was so bright and all I kept thinking
was,
I can't believe this is a dream.
This is so clear.
That's just so vivid.
That's all I was thinking.
Dreams are amazing.
I'm flying through king.
It's like iron man.
And I thought,
Oh,
I'm going to have sex now.
And this is when I was single.
This is before I was married.
So I was a single man so immediately
from the sea,
I don't remember like a video.
I descended from the candidate into the
canyons and up came this girl hiker,
this hot girl,
and she just smiled at me like a dream
in a movie.
Like if this was in a movie,
I came down into the canyon,
she's hiking,
she's hot,
and we,
I take off her clothes and we start the
love making and I couldn't.
And I remember thinking,
I can't believe this is a dream.
I see this is soul real.
And then Bam.
I woke up with a vicious boner.
Yeah,
right there.
I woke up.
It was so crystal clear.
I just got too excited.
I'm like,
I can't believe like I'm having sex
right now.
That's always been my issue.
Coming all the time,
but not really been my issue with lucid
dreams that they go away too easy
because you get excited because I can't
believe you're dreaming.
Yeah.
And you know that all you gotta do is
open your eyes and then you start
opening your goddamn eyes.
Those supplements had,
uh,
hit the sprint program that we're on.
I'm telling you,
man,
you'll dream amazing sprint program and
you want just the alliance sprint
program.
What's the alliance print program?
It's a,
it's basically just for like the first
minute,
15 seconds,
like you're running by her,
by herself.
I got a 15 incline treadmill,
sprinting.
It's a treadmill,
sprinting,
and then we also do a 400 meters,
a 15 times,
so running around the track.
That's one sprint.
15 Times 55 52nd rest and then again
boom.
So this is something that everyone on
the team does pretty much.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's.
Is that unique to an MMA camp that a
team has a single a strength and
conditioning protocol that everybody
follows like a.
I think it's very important to follow a
set structure.
Yeah.
You know,
you know the,
you know,
the ground rules is kind of like how
we're talking about the math program the
other day,
the lumosity stuff.
You just basically just set a good
foundation if you have good stability,
good foundation I think.
I think it's,
you're a lot more easier to.
Can do a lot of MMA camps have
that,
like they have like a sprint series that
the whole camp we'll do every week or
you know,
strength and conditioning series that
the whole camp.
We'll do.
I imagine,
I think,
I think I've heard of Greg Jackson,
I think he's real famous for is a sandal
domes.
Yeah,
yeah,
something like that.
So I think,
I think that's,
that's a good one you see by like Carlos
condit and guys like that always hinton
some,
a high altitude and I know Diego Sanchez
is all being in the altitude so.
But I think I think everybody does their
own thing or at least there is some type
of structure where they do,
do Sam Dume.
So a lot of the big teams at least.
Yeah.
I think there's,
um,
there's a big benefit to a team isn't
there when you're a,
you're a fighter being is the most,
it's the most intimate individual thing
ever.
It's the most lonely,
separated,
selfish completely.
Yes.
Fish completely on your own.
But there's a massive benefit obviously
to being a part of a team because you
see like,
like at this point in time there seems
to be like a separation.
There's very few high level fighters
that are training like individually that
you don't know who they're training if
you don't hear about them training with
anybody.
Good.
It's very,
very few.
It's usually guys that are just sort of
just getting into the game and then the
fine.
Like when Jon Jones,
before he joined Jackson's camp,
he was up in upstate New York and you
know,
didn't have guys like his level around
there and went over to Jackson's and
then really started to catch a stride.
He was searching for that.
A coach.
Everyone package.
Yeah.
I think a lot of the fighters need that.
That's what I do with a lot of my time
and money was spent searching for a
coach and just a good camp.
Somebody that just fit me.
It took me a while to settle in and
then,
you know,
I think I found that at alliance and it
may be other stuff.
Gang had good camps in this country.
Now you know,
they're there at one point in time.
It was just like att and you know,
there's still good and there's getting a
lot of people.
I mean,
tyrone Woodley over the over the week.
Gotcha.
Do you know what?
This is what I think.
Here's what I think a tyrone woodley.
Tyrone says,
I'm watching a GSP and I'm watching
Johnny Hendricks.
I'm watching them and I'm.
And I'm really thinking,
I don't know.
This is a bad thing to say,
but I'm thinking like,
who cares who wins here?
Because Tyrone Woodley is going to come
and fuck these dudes.
Both these dudes up.
Well,
Tyron Woodley.
Just lots of jake shields.
Yeah,
but man that he got knocked out by named
mark too.
I mean,
I think tyron woodley is a bad
motherfucker.
He's an amazing athlete,
but tyron Woodley,
he's,
you know,
he really has to be cost check,
but he really has to face like the
really high level guys like Carlos
Condit and we'll see if he's capable.
I think he's an amazing athlete and if
he's not capable of beating those,
that caliber guy now or he wasn't maybe
a year ago when he fought mark warrant.
He's gonna keep getting better.
That's what I think.
The only reason I say that is just based
on that cost check,
like just based on that,
uh,
he had all the potential high,
high level wrestler and he had a,
he has a good striking,
but in that cost check fight,
I saw different human being ice.
I'd never seen anybody throw punches
that fast.
And MMA,
that's the fastest,
most powerful.
You see those right hands.
He would.
There was like several of them.
You're like,
what?
I just missed it.
It was just that you just saw a display
of immense power.
Like I don't see anybody throwing
punches like that.
What a system with heat,
how cost check.
But you know what I mean?
It seems like he finally is putting it
together.
I never did.
Did you notice that?
Holy Fuck.
That was fast.
Three different times.
I just want to caution,
same dude,
he came out,
he was wrestling people and everybody's
like,
ah man,
this guy knows.
He does his wrestling.
Next thing you know,
he was knocking dudes out with the right
hand because it's starting to feel a lot
more confident,
you know,
probably after the show he got into a
good camp,
which now like,
Oh man,
no,
I have standup skills.
I'm already an athlete.
I know I can rustle.
Next thing you know,
he started to believe in his hands
morning that I'd probably credit that to
like him being done at American top team
starting to train and to use his
athleticism because the dude's obviously
a freak of nature.
I think you see Woodley's fight with Jay
heroin.
I probably did,
but I like 90 percent of those fights.
I forget them.
Who was the first round knockout?
It was incredible.
It was just swarmed them.
Doesn't it seem like the way he threw
that right hand,
like no one will survive that thing.
If he cannot.
He's got that,
that's for sure.
You know,
and he's got the wrestling.
I think you know what happens with even
the Brazilian fighters to his high level
Jujitsu,
black belt still come in and they
definitely are not where they need to be
with our striking and some of them like
super high level guys,
they come in and try on the May and they
just haven't spent enough time with our
striking and they'll just leave mma and
just go back to Jujitsu because they
didn't get the striking was just too
hard,
but then there's some guys that stick it
out and they go through rough patches
and they lose because of their striking.
People will criticize them because of
their striking like Vodoun for instance,
and then after a while they just stick
it out and my Damien Maia,
they just stick it out.
People talking shit on their striking,
but they stick it out.
They handle some losses and as long as
they just keep going and keep the
consistency of all of a sudden the
silver dome is a dangerous striker.
Now all of a sudden Damien Maia has a
real legit stripe.
Could you find out what type of man you
are when you're.
When you,
you know,
when you're winning,
you're on top,
everybody thinks you're all good,
but then when you lose you're like,
man,
like I really got to work on some
things,
but you find out what type of man this
guy is going to be.
Is he going to go back out there?
Is you're going to work on things and
getting better?
Is he just going to go out there and
fold over and then that was it.
Yeah.
For some fighters it is a big confidence
hit that they never recover from.
They have this idea that there are
unbeatable from the jump and then once
someone beats them,
they have to sort of rethink their whole
paradigm and some guys don't ever do it.
Some guys come back stronger,
you know,
some guys come back from a loss and
there are different guy there.
They're more focused,
more intense,
more aware.
They cut out all the bullshit in their
camp.
They thought back on all the things that
they did that might've crossed
it's wisdom.
You know?
It's just like growing and getting
older,
making changes just even outside of
fighting,
you know,
fighting doesn't define half these guys
that are in the octagon because a lot of
them are real cool dudes.
You know,
everybody I've ever met has been been
like super down to earth.
Awesome.
You meet a lot of cool guys,
but it does.
It does play a difference,
you know?
Yeah.
There's no doubt man.
There's no doubt.
Do you think that you just cut down from
155 to 145 pounds and that's like one of
the big issues in mma,
the people keep talking about is the
amount of weight guys cut in.
How they cut it.
You know,
guy like Tyron Woodley,
he,
what does he weigh?
How is he won?
Seventy.
That's.
That makes zero sense.
I know I'm not racist,
but you ever noticed like black guys,
really,
really huge,
right?
I love when people say that and then
they talk about black people are racist
and having a perfect body and having the
perfect body.
How's that?
How is liking watermelon?
Bad watermelons fucking delicious.
Exactly.
And well,
they'll jump on this
scale and then they're like,
they're,
they're not as heavy or you know,
like their body's not as dense.
I remember this friend of mine back home
demicco and he was just this big dude
and we used to work together at the same
company and he would just eat whatever
chips,
hot dogs,
whatever.
And he was just always jack man,
whenever I understood it,
you know,
and I'm like,
I'm over here getting like a belly.
I'm like,
Jesus,
no way.
It's like that.
It's just having a mesomorphic frame.
That's what it is.
And that's what Tyron Woodley.
He's like extreme Mesomorph,
you know,
when you cut down to 1:45,
how much did you have to lose?
Man,
I'm probably one 76.
[inaudible] 77 right now.
My God,
I cut a lot of weight,
but I credit that to the fitness vet
diet that I'm on.
And George Lockhart,
who just knows how to weight cut.
And I was thinking about it for a long
time and the,
just the change is going down there.
I'm a lot faster.
I feel a lot more athletic.
Uh,
I'm working on my athleticism,
I'm trying to be a lot more precise and
just,
I know that the power is always there,
it's a lot more natural,
but I feel like I have just a better
mental edge.
I can,
I can use a lot more of tools at 145
pounds and you know,
I basically grew up inside the octagon.
I probably shouldn't have been there at
a certain time.
It's just that I,
my heart carried me through like a lot
of fights.
So like I said,
I was searching for this camp to help me
to help me and be like,
man,
let's get a hold of me.
I have,
I have talent,
you know,
I just wanted to get out of my hometown
after a certain why I can only,
which was,
which was des Moines,
Iowa and uh,
you know,
I was just like,
man,
I need to get ahold of some better guys.
I gotta I gotTa train,
get a higher level coaching,
just different type of stuff.
I didn't,
I mean I didn't even have a striking
coach.
I was just going to gym to gym,
whichever was the best I was there.
So I think,
I think it just credited that to like we
said,
you don't mind my coaches and then you
know,
making that cut.
I need the George Lockhart and fitness
vet because he gives me everything.
I mean I'm water load and a lot,
you know,
I don't want to give away too much of
this stuff,
but I feel oh,
I feel amazing.
And it's the,
it's the reload after the weight cut,
this stuff and the things that he has me
eat specific's and everything that I'm
calculating it.
It's amazing.
Phil.
So if you get down to 1:45,
what are you wearing when you walk into
the octagon?
About one slash 70.
That's crazy.
Oh my God.
Are you using
eating,
eating light?
Yeah,
I do.
How many ivy bags do you put?
I do too.
I do a one water regular water and then
I do like a warm temperature,
like a sodium bag
just to obtain.
You have to like if you didn't have
those bags it would make
a big difference.
Right?
Yeah,
hell yeah,
you can definitely tell people that
don't like,
you know that they don't want to do the
bags and I keep telling them at the high
level,
you know,
you want to rehydrate scientifically and
yeah,
there was a guy in the UFC that got
caught way back in the day because he
was taking blood out of his body to make
weight.
They went to his hotel room.
There was a doctor there and fucking
bags of his blood.
They took it out.
I don't know what they did.
They stored it somehow or another,
I guess they had a freezer or a
refrigerator there or something and they
put it back in.
His body looks like blood doping,
like blood doping.
Yes,
but I mean they're not giving them
enough chance to rebuild the blood
cells.
The blood being.
The way it works is your body rebuilds
all those blood cells and then you
reintroduce all this extra blood.
You've got crazy amounts of blood now
and your body is eventually going to
burn it off,
but until then,
enjoy the benefits of extreme production
of oxygen or utilization of oxygen.
That's what that epo stuff does to what
those cyclists keep getting busted for,
that he was going too hard,
too hard out there.
So this guy,
he cut the weight and then the last
couple of pounds he took out and blood.
Nice.
And then he put it right back in.
When he went back,
I'd probably,
you know,
some people will pass on.
I mean you already cutting down,
wait and then go to do that.
You know,
I guess depending on how much weight he
cut,
I've seen dudes that look like they're
on death's door.
I've seen dudes that are cutting weight
like Travis Luder when he fought
Anderson Silva.
I've never seen a guy look worse in my
life that's still alive.
He was shuffling.
He couldn't walk band.
He was shuffling towards the scale.
The second time he was making weight,
his lips were chapped as fuck.
His whole face was sucked in.
He looked like he was dying.
I mean he was dying.
He was essentially draining himself out.
But he just miscalculated.
You get down.
He was this close to beating Anderson
Silva.
He was all over at all.
The guys who are like super talented,
it didn't live up to their potential.
Travis Luder might be number one in my
book.
He's one of those guys.
You're talking about the training
himself,
trained himself.
He didn't like.
He was from Texas and he went to
Jackson's towards the last few fights of
his career.
I think he was at Jackson's when he lost
in the tall and I think that might've
been the last fight.
He's got some back issues though too
from Jujitsu.
Who doesn't know you,
you,
you know,
constantly training and enrolling and
you're going to get some back issues.
Ricardo Laborio told me he's got like
six bulging discs or seven bulging
discs,
something crazy.
These guys are all like a little bit
jacked up.
Their backs
need to get on the Lacrosse ball.
Man Medicine bond that Eric did.
I buy those a like it opens up my
posture.
If I start going like this.
I don't know if you've seen.
If people were watching,
like you'll start getting rounded like
vandelay does.
It can't throw a straight punch,
but if you get into Lacrosse ball and
you're able to break up your Pec minor,
your Pec major,
your lats,
your traps,
you know,
even even like your Scapula,
you're able to get into those knots that
your elbow is not going to hurt anymore
because you're,
you're elongating the muscles that need
to be in long gated if you're talking
about like a rumble roller or Lacrosse
ball,
cross ball or like a
softball or a baseball.
So hard like I get in my hip flexors
because a constantly running,
wrestling and being like on your thing.
Like my,
my knees will start to hurt so I'll get
on like a lacrosse ball.
I mean I'll break up everything,
every muscle down from my hip.
I'll,
I'll be the.
I'll start at the glue,
the,
the hip flexor and I just never
accidentally go up your ass.
Never,
never.
Did you wrestle?
Yeah.
As a,
as a kid,
uh,
as a,
as a kid growing up.
I did.
Okay.
It makes it better.
Grab it and move it towards you.
You can just do like this,
bring it towards you.
Nice.
Got It.
There you go.
Look at that.
Nice.
I actually grew up a wrestling as a kid.
My,
my,
uh,
one of my uncles,
it was my grandfather.
He was really big into like wrestling
and boxing and stuff like that.
So he,
uh,
when my parents were kind of going
through a hard time,
he's the one who encouraged me to get
into wrestling,
get involved in sports like that.
So I started wrestling as a kid.
How old?
About five years old until.
Did you wrestle in high school?
I did wrestle in high school.
I wrestled a one year in high school.
My parents had a complication so I was
Kinda,
I was transferring to like a lot of
schools so I was kind of wrestling but
like I was on like another side of town
that one week I was on another side of
town.
There's a recipe for becoming a fighter,
a bunch of schools.
So when I,
when I wrestled I wasn't like great or
anything.
I just,
you know,
used heart just out their stronghold and
people and,
and that's basically how I got involved
with UFC was through my grandfather
watching that.
So I do have a little bit of a wrestling
background.
I'd say my wrestling's a lot better now
working with a good guys,
Olympic level guys,
guys like dominick Cruz coaches pushing
me,
so I'm always in there with like a good
set of dudes,
you know better how long you've,
you been with alliance now you're in San
Diego,
right?
Training about three years now.
That's awesome.
Solid.
Yeah.
The first year it took me a while to get
to get used to it,
man.
We,
we train hard up there.
We spar hard,
we go hard.
A lot of drills.
A lot of technique.
And it took you like,
what was the biggest transition?
The hardest part of it?
Conditioning or what was,
it was hard to get used to just the day
in,
day out and just the,
uh,
I mean,
I say I hung in there,
you know,
I mean I have my good days,
my bad days,
but it's just,
it's just everybody's after the same
goals,
the same dreams,
but it's the day in,
day out,
you know,
anybody can fight,
we can go right to the Chevron,
you know,
and to start a fight,
anybody can just go fight.
But when you discipline yourself,
it's the day in.
You know,
the hardest thing is when you're sore
like you're talking about,
you're like,
oh man,
I gotta get up.
I got to go train and I,
you want to disappoint your,
your boys,
let alone do you want to lose the fight?
You know,
you got to give up who you are now for
who you want to be in the future.
Yeah.
George St Pierre was talking about after
the fight.
It was,
it was an interesting thing.
I don't want to hear nothing about
George St Pierre.
This podcast.
Can you imagine?
Imagine if we just made.
We should have,
we should have trolled everyone else.
And they're like,
you're right,
you're right.
You're right about that fight funnel.
Even that important.
I don't want it.
That's the last thing,
but he was talking about I can't sleep.
He's got a few personal issues
apparently,
allegedly that's being reported and
um,
unfortunately with his family's health
and what have you,
I don't know what's true,
what's not true,
but that's what this story is,
which makes a ton of sense why he saying
that he can't sleep,
you know,
he's having a real hard time.
He thinks he's going crazy and yeah,
he was talking about on the podcast,
he said he gets abducted by aliens,
but I think also it's just fucking hard
to keep up.
I think what you're saying about the day
in,
day out,
day in,
day out and intensify that even more
than you're the champ,
you're the top of a hill with a bunch of
hungry sharks nipping at your feet,
but he's stressed out all the time and
I'm telling you,
you gotta,
you gotTa have those types of Lacrosse
balls.
Like you got to keep your stress levels
down because if you're stressed out all
the time,
say say a fight week,
I'm stressed out all week,
I'm just,
I can't get my weight.
I'm stressing out.
I'm freaking out.
I'm going through crazy.
So my nervous system is going to become
like a radic.
It's like,
man,
we are stress and we're going crazy
right now.
By the time you go to fight and you need
all those hormones that you need to go,
like boost yourself up,
get yourself back into that mode.
Your body is used to be like,
no bro,
we're already tapped out.
You know,
we've been filling out.
So then like you're just like boom.
You just hit like a crash as compared to
if you're relaxed all week,
you're chilling out,
you're not really.
You're just thinking the good vibes,
you know,
weight's going down and things are just
going beautiful.
Everything's looking sharp,
but just keeping yourself relaxed the
whole time.
So then when you go to fight,
you're energized to the Max.
You're like,
boom.
It's all right.
No,
it's,
this is what we trained for it.
Yeah,
that's the adrenaline dump,
right?
I think the all week or few days leading
up to it,
a little tents,
man.
I think.
I think India is a relaxed bro and you
know like this.
This is the fight game where we have
small gloves,
isn't boxing,
you know where you're hitting yourself
with 16th,
which is even bad as it is.
These guys,
man,
some of these dudes that are swinging at
you that you know,
it could put you out any.
Any second
shit man.
How about your fight with honey?
Jason,
how about that shit?
You caught him within the first round.
Holy Shit.
Did you see that fight?
God Damn.
Dude,
let me tell you something.
That followup right hand was ferocious.
There was no hesitation.
You cracked him with that and you were
on autopilot.
You just launched that right hand on him
and that shit was perfect.
Pull that out Brian.
Pull that video up.
Jeremy Stevens versus Ronnie.
Jason.
Ron,
why you pronounce it haunted?
You need a poster,
you know would make a great poster.
That big right there is a poster of that
upper cut
mid,
upper cut.
Great poster.
Come on.
I'd have to give the posts away man.
I don't like looking at stuff like that.
I read this book one time and this
architect,
because people will come up to me like,
oh man,
like,
like what was your favorite fight or
whatever.
And I always tell them my next one,
you know,
because I just think of like
visualization visionary,
you know,
like always want,
like it was a cool knock.
I appreciate her but give me like all
the love but there's still more work in
the gym that I'd been working on,
you know,
and I've been,
I've been at this for awhile but I
really feel like I'm just starting to
like barely tap into my potential skin
better 20.
So 27 and I,
my,
my first on my 21st birthday,
it was my,
that was I fought Din Thomas.
You must've been some crazy motherfucker
coming up locally,
right?
For you to like for Joe Silva to take
notice of you.
You're 21 years old and go,
we got to put this fucking beast where
you Beeston people in Iowa.
What was going on?
Yeah,
I was doing the same,
I was hitting people with spinning back
fist,
a flying knee.
We're knocking everybody out,
knocking a lot of guys out.
Not Everybody,
you know,
I had a few,
a few submissions and stuff like that.
But what was your record before the UFC?
I think it was like seven.
One 81,
something like that.
Mostly knockouts mostly.
Yep.
Comes from not vicious knockouts.
Did you have a highlight reel of like
vicious striking,
like how to Joe Silva?
My highlight reel is so old because
anytime I put something for the UFC up
there,
they just take it down,
you know,
so I don't really get a chance.
Not A,
not a lot of people.
Everybody that I could probably like
youtube is made is probably like men.
This is old school stuff like where is
this?
You know,
but when you fight a UFC guy who had the
uh,
the honor to be like,
Hey,
can you send me over his tapes?
And then he got all the UFC tapes.
What do you think about that?
About how they do.
Here's,
here's the Kale right here.
This is the slow mo version of it.
Oh my God,
that shit is perfect.
And look at this code.
That might be one of the best one to
Zara.
Boom.
And blam.
That shit is for.
I'm talking about right there when they
sense for Osha,
if I liked that.
I liked that.
I liked seeing violence.
You know,
that I'm a big uh,
for violence.
I like watching it.
Uh,
but a fan of concussions.
Yeah.
But when we're talking about the
monorepo thing where he held on to tap
too late or too,
too long,
man,
I think he got.
I'm going to,
I'm going to get bit controversial on
this.
I think he got a bum deal on that
because I think what he held onto was
barely a second and yeah,
it's fucked up to do and he does it,
but he did it way worse in the past and
I think he's at least a little bit
crazy.
I think it's real hard to get that guy
to let go.
I think when he's trying to tap you,
it's some life and death shit.
He grew up on a farm he liked,
had no schooling.
He was eating pig slop when he was 13.
I mean,
I think you're not dealing with a
regular dude here.
Yeah,
that's a,
that's a very aggressive,
uh,
behavior to be living like that.
I'd never heard that about him,
but I imagine that's a little bit more
of an aggressive behavior than anything
but in a very,
very,
very tough environment,
but much,
much harder than I think most of us can
comprehend.
Listen,
listen,
that just blows me away,
dude.
That's crazy.
In pig slop,
he has a giant scar on his chest from
when they couldn't get.
He had cut open and they couldn't get a
medical attention,
so they use like crazy glue on it and
try to pinch it together.
He's a giant scar on his chest.
I agree with you though.
I think he got a raw deal because I
think that there's something wrong with
what he did.
Then there's something wrong with what
Dan Henderson did to Brisbane or what
you just did right there.
I love that show.
No,
no,
no.
I didn't get called off and that guy
could have jumped up.
I don't think.
Yeah,
it was bad.
Like I,
I happen to land the kick and then I
came right back,
right back to my base.
I kind of saw him go to get up,
which I thought maybe he was Tko because
I knew it was a good shot and I didn't
expect it.
I expected it to land in land heart at
least scaring boat.
He leaned into that and it was basically
all faints.
So then when I,
I kicked it,
I landed back on my bass and he kinda
like went to like get up.
Like almost.
It almost looked like he went to get up.
I missed a short split second that you
have to decide,
you know.
But like I'm a lion bro.
I have a family to feed,
you know,
as you said something about a guy like
Diego Sanchez.
That's what I think about when anybody
wants to stop a fight too soon.
I think a lot of garlic,
Diego Sanchez,
you can hit that dude.
He wants to go out on the sheet and hit
him with a media and he comes running
back at you even more power fights his
mouthpiece and starts fucking bought
those stories and you cracked him.
I mean,
I think that Shin might've knocked out
any human being on earth,
but it is possible that it got.
I mean,
Diego's been hit with some bombs goes
down and somehow under the recoveries.
Oh,
I've cracked them before.
And you do the same thing.
We've just done this in his backyard,
does it,
you do a video of it and we just start
throwing down and that's the type of
guy.
Diego isn't.
He does bring that out in you,
man.
I've had the funniest times training
with Diego Sanchez.
I owe him a lot,
you know,
for,
for me being here and getting to the
next level,
hit him and Josh near like one of my
inspirational dudes and I'm hanging out
with these guys when I'm young and when
he had a chance to invite me out and
train with them.
Like I,
I had the funniest time train with Diego
Sanchez.
He's a wild man.
It's okay.
A wild man.
He's the most,
in my opinion,
the most consistently entertained on
fighter.
Like maybe ever.
I got a question for you.
Who would you rather be?
Would you rather,
would you rather be Mike Pierce?
Would you rather be Mike Pierce?
Okay.
Or go through it and Mike Pierce went
through with it.
Who's smart boss?
You have to live through it or lifted
with a honey.
Uh,
Jason went through.
Well,
the thing Mike,
Mike Pierce can heal his knee up.
He totally replaced nothing towards
spring.
Disney,
you're,
you're absolutely right in that
situation when you do deal with the
consequences,
I think I would way rather be Mike
Pierce.
Way,
way,
way.
But the difference is that he has a
choice to let those submissions go.
It's not like a strike that's in motion
in during the middle of the contest.
Okay.
In absolute legal time,
he connects.
Jeremy connects with a perfectly placed
shin and then a perfectly placed right
hand right afterwards.
That is,
that is.
There's no referee stopping that fight.
There's no one he knows this
motherfucker's tapping.
He knows the referees touching them.
That's where it gets weird.
Where it gets weird is he fucking knows.
You know?
He knows.
I know.
He knows anybody's ever put a heel hook
on anybody ever in their life knows that
guy was tapping.
He knew he was tapping.
You knew the ref was stepping in.
He knew the fight was over and he still
held on.
But,
but this,
this is what I'm saying is when,
when it comes to submissions,
right,
there's,
you see the submission coming.
He wraps up his leg.
If you watch the fight that is right
there,
he sees the submission coming.
He's right there.
He's ready to go.
So as soon as he taps,
he goes,
okay,
stop.
And then he held on a little bit long.
When in these cases the referee is far
away.
So if the referee was right next to him,
he would stop the and that last part.
Well that's a good.
That's a good argument.
Logically.
The problem with that is that you're
dealing with a choice and when the guy
is holding onto a submission,
it's a choice.
No,
but let's say it's not a momentum there.
There've been fights.
Where do knock someone out and again,
I love the violence.
I love it.
I'm not saying cut it.
I'm just saying you can't knock with
some are perhaps because it happens a
lot.
When Dan Henderson bisbing in that
situation,
there is a chance,
I don't know exactly what was going on
in Dan Harrison's brain,
but there was a shower.
He knows he's out,
but I'm going to fuck them up one more
time.
The reps too far away to stop that shit,
but then he kind of knows like she kinda
knows.
He doesn't kind of know.
You talked about in the postpaid press
call,
he said he wanted to shut him up,
gave him that last punch to shut him up.
So there's.
That's all legal because the referee,
if the referee is not there,
that shit's on him and that guy is in
survival mode.
He's in full war mode.
I agree.
I liked that.
What I'm saying is what happened with
with smart barth is exactly the same.
It's not here's where it would be
different.
He made a referee.
If the referee told him to stop and got
in front of him and he pushed the
referee aside,
instill smashed him,
Dan,
that's happened before then it would be
worse than what he did because he's,
he's,
he's sitting and concussed fighter and
one the referees already stopped the
contest.
This was just a race and this is in the
rules.
That guy was talking shit.
He decided to crack them.
He saw him going down.
He's like,
you know what,
bitch,
I'm going to give you one more before
the referee gets here.
We all know what it was there,
but the bathroom was out of position
wasn't exactly the same because I do all
I am aware of.
The Rep did stop him,
but it was that the amount of time and
it's almost like you crack a dude like
that in sap and a bunch,
you know,
like the fighter.
No,
there have been times where a guy gets
crackly,
knocks out the guys out because I'm not
going to hit them again.
Stop it.
Rough.
What?
I mean,
you could do that too.
Mark meal.
So there's a choice there so.
Well,
those guys are friends.
Big Difference.
She machida and Munoz who don't get me
wrong.
I like it.
I would rather have the guy get hit one
more time.
I like when guys get Jack.
I like when guys get knocked out.
Enjoy them
though.
He.
This is where I don't agree.
I,
I.
That was kind of a stoppage.
You know what?
That could have been questionable,
but the guy has done it a couple times.
Yes.
So,
so now they're,
now they're going like,
okay,
what the heck?
But the guy actually made a statement.
He goes,
I couldn't fill the guy tapped because
the referee was on me.
Now that's it.
That's key.
That's a key point were like,
dude,
the referees on you're like,
what are you doing with the reference
checking to make sure that he'll hook is
applied correctly.
No,
he's not putting in your mouth.
That's such a Goddamn dumb statement
statement.
If he,
if he actually say,
that sucks that he got cut because he's
always amazing.
You know what every guy wants to be
because of he doesn't really listen and
he enjoys it.
He enjoys the reputation of being a guy
that rips needs a part because he's done
it before,
but he had to get cut.
I understand why Dana condom the condom
here,
but you got to have that animal back.
Bring them back,
let them suffer for a year and bring
them back because he's always a threat
to anybody at time.
Well,
especially at one,
17,
18,
there's no other guys like that.
There's no other guys that could jump on
you with heel hooks like that.
There's nobody that he says sort of
edema.
Esther was never as dynamic is that dean
lister fought in the UFC a few times.
He'd never had that kind of crazy,
scary performance.
Dean is very,
very good.
Don't get me wrong.
His grappling is world class.
He's.
He's excellent,
but dean never had that kind of started.
Kind of appearance in the UFC were just
attack someone like a fucking wild
animal.
He's very explosive and dean wasn't.
No.
Dean was known as a mall or like a
grizzly bear.
He wasn't known as an explosive.
There were supposed to do a Jujitsu
match and I.
I don't think it went down because I
think Paula Harris or somebody got hurt,
but I think dean lister would get like
an intelligent mauler that's a good way
of scarring.
Intelligent Mahler.
He's very technical and he just knows
exactly where to be in the right
position.
He's strong as fuck.
He's a beast dude.
He's crazy.
He like,
he'd always tell me he goes because I
trained with him and he's always like,
no matter what,
like even when I'm feel like I'm in a
horrible position and he's like,
there's many options here,
Jeremy.
And sometimes he doesn't even know who'd
be like go back there again,
do this.
He'll be like,
okay.
And then like he'll just come up with
something like right there and it'll
have an escape for it and he's so he's
such a big dude but he rolls like 125
pounds a bad motherfucker.
It's a real shame that gene list or had
to go into mma because like if there
was,
I think there should be a real
professional jujitsu on television,
like on espn the same way they have
tennis.
Anything else?
Figuring out how to do like an Abu Dhabi
style submission only thing.
Put It on TV.
Jujitsu would be for that too.
Maybe maybe to come in the future for
like maybe like a UFC Jujitsu and
submission.
Wrestling would be a solid basis by
itself.
I think just by itself.
Jujitsu is still very,
very exciting and there's some guys that
are just never going to make that
transition as striking.
So like we were talking about with um,
with some guys just don't,
they just don't get there and some guys
do like febreeze,
shiver,
doom or Damien Maia or what have you.
Or Mark Munoz guys would get better and
better at striking and become like a
dangerous threat on their feet as well.
But it's be nice to see them just do
what they're awesome at.
Like why should a soccer player also
have to learn how to play baseball?
You know what I mean?
Or something right in between like
combat Jujitsu.
It's right in between.
No striking standing.
It's wrestling standing,
but on the ground you could punch to the
face that makes.
It's right in the middle between Nogi
grappling and Nma.
It's not as quite as hardcore as I may,
but it's more exciting because on the
ground they'd be left stalling because
you could punch to the face,
hit Samba guys almost like,
it's almost like old ufc without like
all,
like maybe the violence that people
don't want to see.
So you have like this Russian Zombot
dude verse in this Brazilian in the
Olympics.
I think that'd be incredible.
You know,
like the wrestling,
the Jujitsu mix,
you know?
Yes.
We sick with people,
but they would,
they would cross train,
everybody would cross train and nobody
would ever do just Jujitsu versus samba.
Let's just figure this out.
What style is better?
Everybody would cross train,
you know,
you got to learn another guy's
techniques as well.
Your cross train but not admitted.
Well,
you know,
it's really interesting man.
His combat sambo because they're kind of
doing mma,
but then they're also doing judo because
they have like judo Kimonos on.
That's another inbetween Nma and
grappling.
That's probably the closest.
That's what I'm saying,
that those guys would face like a
Jujitsu guy because back in the early
days it was like a boxer versus this.
So if we got this in the Olympics,
I think everybody from some sort of
grappling with want to be like,
okay,
let's,
let's compete with these people.
Oh yeah.
And the safety level is amazingly high.
When you think about,
you know,
the,
the injury rates and Nascar,
the injury rates and fucking Polo,
you know,
I mean,
dudes get jacked riding horses,
man shows all the time.
Horse races guys fall off,
break their necks,
gets stomped.
I mean,
how many of those go a year?
It's,
it's.
But you got to know when you've had
enough.
Right?
For sure.
That's probably one of the most
important things for fighter to be aware
of.
Every fighter in the gym knows at least
one guy that didn't figure it out.
Yeah.
That's,
that's sad.
You know,
he has a lot of heart,
but at the same time it's kind of
stupid.
You know,
like if I,
if I felt like I was getting knocked out
like three times in a row,
two times,
you know,
I would just,
pay respect to my family,
you know,
it'd be like,
thank you for letting me enjoy this,
you know,
and that's not.
Eventually I would just walk away and
you know,
eventually open up a gym or something
like that,
but
super hard to admit that though the
guy's done,
they're always,
I mean,
you know,
as much as anybody that there's always
wonders after a loss.
Like if you'd done something
differently,
would the fight have played out
differently?
If you were trained with a different
coach,
would you have been able to see that
common?
If you had done this differently,
would that have happened and those
thoughts?
They,
they never,
they never go away.
You never get to
natural.
It's natural to fill those thoughts and,
and wonder,
because I actually been being clipped
before at a.
before that time,
I just thought I was,
it was almost like a Mike Tyson thing.
I felt like surreal and they're like,
I could just go in there and brawl and
just slug it out,
you know?
Then eventually,
oh,
I actually went to some community,
like bad problems and stuff and uh,
I got caught by Eve's Edwards,
you know,
he's a great dude.
But honestly I think I could have beat
them and I could have played that fight
a lot more different.
I was asking myself,
man,
you know,
it was,
my,
my weak Chin now,
you know,
I've been hit with solid shots but that
just didn't land.
So finally I just,
you know,
like I just talked to my coaches,
I talked to a sports psychologist and I
just pick myself up,
dust myself off.
I knew I was getting better in the gym
and the progress,
it just wasn't there yet.
And again,
like just,
we started lining things up.
Everything started connecting a lot
better and I ended up being a better
fighter from it.
Now if I was continued to going to,
and I still have fun with this dude,
I,
I'm still learning so much.
I mean,
we could probably roll right now and I'd
probably learn something new or just
like a different way,
a different route.
So I love that aspect about fighting.
I mean I'm sitting here talking to you
Rogan and youtube as well,
so I'm like,
I'm all pumped up,
you know,
I've never done this if it wasn't for
like mma.
So it's like changed my life and in the
moment I stop having fun with it and
stop learning.
Just like Charles Darwin said,
you know,
you have the most the longest or survive
was the one that to adapt to change.
And uh,
I just totally agree with that.
There's some young beast is in the UFC.
I'm a Sergio Pettis.
How old?
That kid?
He just wasn't.
He just looks sweet.
Awesome.
You know that that type of talent is
actually coming in.
So you gotta be able to adapt and
adjust.
You can't just be the same.
Stand in the pocket type brawler dude.
You got it.
That's what's going to make you great is
that attitude to that being in love with
the idea of learning things.
And one of the beautiful things about
mma and you know,
well even in Jujitsu,
it's like you never run out of things in
Jujitsu,
you never learned that run out of
techniques.
Now you add striking to that and you
know,
and then wrestling to that and it's like
there's a never ending ocean of
techniques out there.
These are.
Are you throwing,
are you working on like we'll kicks and
shit like that.
And spinning back kicks.
Yeah.
I've just seen his videos of him kicking
the bag.
Oh,
you're hitting spending back in.
I used to be a,
I was a taekwondo black belt.
You haven't seen those videos?
No.
No,
I never.
I never saw myself.
I never knew you did.
Yeah,
it was before I ever did that.
I used to teach taekwondo for a living
and won a bunch of taekwondo tournament.
But seriously,
seriously,
I'm not just saying this and everybody
knows this.
Everyone used to think I was kissing his
ass when,
when,
when I would try to tell people.
But now there's video.
Now there's proof.
Uh,
I've never seen anybody throw attorney
inside kick as hard as Joe,
like when he starts this coming up.
Yeah.
You gotta look at the way he is.
He's teaching Jordan George St Pierre.
I think it's earlier than that,
but that's one of the interesting things
about Joyce before this,
before this,
because this is what he's already asking
to record it.
How'd you get involved involved in like
fighting man,
you,
you have such a good grasp on things,
man.
Like I don't even go to bars and all
order a paper view dead broke.
And just a,
just to hear your commentating though.
Um,
no.
Well thanks man.
I really appreciate that.
It was a taekwondo guy when I was a kid.
I won the US Open and one of the
Massachusetts state championship like
four years in a row.
That.
And then I went from that into
kickboxing.
I had a three kickboxing bouts,
but it was doing that all while I was
still doing standup comedy.
And then I had,
I had to figure out what to do because I
was starting to lose.
I lost my last fight and I knew I lost
because I wasn't in good shape.
I was,
I was fucking around too much and doing
comedy.
I wasn't focused and I knew I wasn't
training like I was when I was younger
so I had to make a big decision in my
big decision was abandoned all that,
that whole world and just throw myself
into comedy plus there was no money man.
There was no UFC,
there was nowhere to go.
And then,
you know,
I went from comedy.
I was on a television show called news
radio and from news radio I watched the
first UFC when I was there.
It was like,
you know,
I first saw it and like I think it was
like probably like 95.
I probably caught it like year or two
after it had started.
I had heard about it and I watched it on
a vhs tape.
I don't have anything.
I watched the first one.
I think I watched UFC too because I
think the first one wasn't available for
some reasons or some copyright issues or
what have you.
I don't,
I don't remember what it hit the exact
reality was,
but I remember watching the hoists.
Gracie strangled the fuck out of
everybody going,
oh my God.
Like I felt first of all,
all my years of type window,
I was like,
Oh,
I'm helpless.
Like I thought I was just going to kick
dudes in the head and I'm like,
I didn't even realize that guy could
just,
just manhandled me like that.
So I went to,
I went to crossing Gracie's place in
[inaudible] 96.
I started training there.
That was back when Vito was making his
debut.
They used to call him victor.
He's convicted Gracie.
Like when I,
when I interviewed him on UFC 12,
I called them Victor Gracie.
That's crazy.
That's what everybody called him.
And then he was getting sued by Horian
or something like that.
So he had to drop the Gracie name,
but he was taking it because of Carlson.
So that's when I started.
And then I met Eddie and probably like
98,
I started John jocks.
I met Eddie around there.
And uh,
I started smoking weed about 99,
2000.
One was,
it kind of knows us before.
Fear factor though.
Yeah,
that was,
it was 2000.
You had a calm demeanor on there when I
remember this one time because I knew I
wasn't a big fight,
a big fight guy.
And then just the way there's this guy
having like this attitude and this crazy
and you're like,
whoa,
whoa Bro,
like,
chill out.
And then the guy like tried to like fear
factor one and he just had like a calm,
calm demeanor.
And I was like,
man,
Joe,
Joe's pretty cool dude.
Or you can just tell me like,
man,
Joe would have messed him up.
Actually,
you know what that guy was.
I was told about him before we ever did
the show.
They were telling me that this guy's a
kind of a loose cannon.
He attacked a counselor on one show and
he threw his wife to the ground on
another show.
Like he was of day alarm in the show.
It's fun.
It's exciting.
You never know what's going on.
They knew he worked.
Him and his wife were fucking screaming
at each other.
They were like screaming,
you fucking stupid bitch.
Like it was like there was really
entertaining because it was like the
most dysfunctional and violent
relationship I've ever witnessed without
being like.
They're like,
these motherfuckers screamed at each
other and swears and all the time while
this is going on is this little dude
from Johnny fairplay from survivor who
is fucking hilarious the whole time
they're there screaming,
where's the fucking flashlight?
Flashlight.
The flashlight.
Fuck Johnny fairplay is is yelling at
the guy like about the wife telling him
you don't need her.
She's dead weight.
She's ruined it for you.
He's like,
you don't need or Jonathan,
she's dead weight.
She's ruined it for you.
And like he would say that about her.
He would say that about him.
He was just constantly hackle it
constantly.
Haglund like,
you guys got this wrapped up.
You guys got it wrapped up.
Fuck Yo.
Shut up.
She comes back and immediately punches
this guy,
johnny fairplay.
I mean fucking punches him hard in the
stomach.
And I said,
hey,
just because you hit your,
your husband doesn't mean you can hit
other people.
You can't just hit people.
And so then he got in my face.
I thought he was gonna hit me.
So I just grabbed him.
It was like I pushed them away a couple
times.
They didn't show that.
And then the next thing you know,
I got them in the plum.
I just held onto his head.
Don't show this man,
always pull it up.
You're so stupid.
It was so stupid.
So he just told that it was a straight
hothead and the way you handled it,
I was like,
this guy obviously has
some type of martial arts,
like self control,
you know.
So he's working.
You're working on a lead leg side kick.
I conor Mcgregor.
You ever do that one?
Oh,
I mean that's been around a lot more
since connor mcgregor.
I want to give him the credit for it,
but I remember way back.
Yeah,
not too many people.
I mean,
who else?
Who's talking about an mma?
Like who was throwing that lead leg side
kick?
Like Jon Jon Jones did it on Jones says
it to the knee,
which is a very v towards the body.
He's got a legacy to the body and
dropped me to remember that.
It's cool to see that.
And I also use like a lot of stuff
because I trained with Alex Gustafsson
and he uses a lot of like real trickery
stuff.
Like he'll get like hip to hip with you,
like where you're standing and then
he'll just go hip to hip and then just
sweep you and just Kinda Kinda almost
makes you look stupid.
Dominick Cruz style down on your toes.
I mean he,
he purposely emulated dominick Cruz.
That's not a coincidence,
right?
That they moved the sign.
Just think he was just light on the same
coaches.
Yeah,
yeah,
for sure.
But just doing that dance,
is that Eric Delphia?
So he's constantly talking about being
on your toes,
being athletic,
smart dude,
smart dude.
Very distinct style.
That very distinct.
I mean,
Shit,
very few people can do that and
Gustafsson is pulling it off and he
moves around like that.
But does it attack enough?
Is Tim Elliot?
Did you see 10 million at this weekend?
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Got Great Footwork.
I think best is still yet to come with
that.
Yes,
I think so too.
That kid is stupid.
Strong's from Midwest area.
Was that super prelims?
A little guys?
Yeah.
I fast forwarded through that one.
Who'd fight big puncher?
Strong wrestler.
A lot of movement.
You see him definitely being a 35 or in
the future that people are going to
start looking,
looking at.
I think it'd be 35.
He's there.
Twenty five,
25.
Yeah.
Those are flowers.
A big 25.
Yeah.
You know,
you know who I'm a fan of 125 pounds
that I really want.
You know,
a lot of respect for Demetrius Johnson
guys.
Obviously talented but Joseph Benevidez
Bro.
I'm a fan of that little bastard,
you know,
gets down bro.
He just,
he just throws heat the whole time.
It's technically.
I mean he sets things up like I like.
I like istock amazed.
I've never seen that dude in the boring
for.
This is a perfect example of what you
were talking about before about someone
putting together a training camp.
Now they got bang Ludwig,
who's running their whole camp and he
runs a Alpha male and uh,
in um,
San Jose,
Sacramento,
and all those guys like,
look at Chad Mendez.
Look at how much better he got from
there.
They'll look,
look at how much better everybody's
gotten from,
from that camp and Benevidez and mighty
mouse.
They're going to have a rematch on Fox.
That's the,
uh,
the main event on Fox.
And then sacramento,
Danny Castillo,
he,
he's a,
he's a friend of mine out there.
He's a 55 where he's fighting a,
a good talented striker Barboza.
So I'm interested to see how Dwayne Bang
and Alpha male come up with a strategy,
you know,
because I like,
he's a,
he's a good dude.
You know,
he throws down,
he's,
he's getting better and you know,
now they have dwayne up.
They're showing a lot of cool stuff that
I do to vet that strategy for the
Barboza fight.
If I had to guess,
probably going to be.
Take that dude down.
Yeah,
you got to set it up.
Set it up.
Yeah.
He said he thought he was going to go
low and then caught them high.
Julie's got that long right hand too.
She.
She's fucking.
He launches that right hand at you.
Throw,
throws a lot of it and it covers a lot
of distance to.
Yeah,
it's like almost like a cost check back
in the day,
but caution with wing his a little bit,
but now you see in guys like throw the
straight right hand and catch guys
before they're able to hit the hook on
them.
Catch that Chin sometimes putting put
dudes asleep.
Yeah.
The Way Varner completes that right hand
is very straight.
It's very strict.
He landed that all through a set ups.
He was smart that time he immediately
came out,
take barboza down,
you know Barboza was going to get up.
So what does he do that next time acts
like he's going to go down.
Of course you got to respect it because
the guy just took you down.
Boom.
Righthand.
Yeah.
I'm a big fan of Johnny Varner.
I love a dude who like was the champion
at one point in time,
was wec champion and then went through a
bad streak where he's losing the guys
should never lose to lost his motivation
was going back to college and then all
of a sudden gets it back together.
He's event man.
Those world class realize you realize
shit.
W,
what choice do you have?
You're going to go back to regular life.
You're a superstar.
You're on TV.
It's right there at your fingertips.
You just got to get a couple training
camps together.
Get your shit.
It's right there.
A celebrity status and not waking up and
working at a factory or something.
You got to keep going.
You got to look at it as like,
you know what?
Maybe I will.
If you could look at it realistically
like maybe I won't get the belt,
but I'm going to fucking try my hardest
and then in the meantime I'm not going
to work a regular fucking job.
I'm going to try to parlay this into
some other shit.
This the excitement they miss that you
can't have regular days by him.
Regular Day job.
It's just a slow drone drawn draw.
I worked and it was just,
it was horrible.
And you know,
my,
my grandfather had a,
had uh,
told me to quit a job,
you know what?
I was kind of skeptical.
And then my old,
old girlfriend at the time,
like I remember one time I had to stay
at her parents' house just because I was
believing in this dream and I was just
starting out.
I didn't really have much.
I struggled a lot.
And then,
uh,
I remember her,
her dad was just like,
you know,
a fight doesn't pay the bills.
I remember just looking at this guy
like,
man,
some shit on my dream,
you know?
What'd you just do?
Okay.
Went away.
Oh,
is it a weird feedback?
I don't think it was your phone.
Where's your phone?
Oh,
that what it was.
I thought it was a feedback thing.
Um,
yeah man,
it's a fucking crazy dream to believe
in,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean it's got its ups and downs,
man.
I could imagine like all the crazy crap,
you know,
Varner and like half these guys,
he's probably mad,
you know,
what the hell.
And he was scared to death.
He admitted it.
He Barboza I mean,
but especially Barboza.
That guy's a killer dude.
He's like human shit.
Jimmy Carter said he was shaking before
foes are coming off of that.
Terry Edom knock out one of the worst
knockouts ever in the UFC.
I train with that guy a long time ago
down in Florida through Hermes,
Franco,
who I was hanging out with a back of the
day and we went to the armory and,
and uh,
we train with Barboza and I just
remember it just as more Thai was
really,
really good.
And uh,
and I was just like,
man,
what is this guy fight,
you know,
like,
this guy should be fighting here,
you know?
And I was already in UFC at the time
and,
and I guess they're like,
yeah,
he's working on his ground or whatever.
And he's,
he's really good,
good striking.
He's working on his wrestling,
he's explosive athlete and he's a big 55
or two.
Man.
That guy's a beast.
Yeah.
It's uh,
the,
the weight cutting thing is really
fascinating because when most people
hear that a guy who fights at 155 pounds
or you fight it 145 pounds though,
they assume you're actually 145 pounds.
Yeah.
They're like manual Jesus.
Fuck.
Does that work?
Like I said,
Tyron Woodley is the best example of
that.
There's no way that dude looks to be 170
pounds dense bro.
I don't know what the hell he always
when he gets him and Hector Lombard or
just going to take over the top.
I think that's just,
that's just,
that's just what I'm saying.
Hey,
you know,
that would be an amazing fight.
Hector Lombard versus tyrone Woodley
holder.
They're both American top team.
They probably never would find it or
they wouldn't fight until they became
absolutely coming back.
Dude.
Thiago Alves.
We're probably as soon to see him.
Scrap again.
Yeah,
I hope so.
I love that dude.
Great Guy.
Fun To watch sighting fighter.
But he's not an unfortunate series of
injury,
back surgery,
you know,
impress the shit on me is donald
cerrone.
Holy Shit.
Fight with Evan Dunham.
The coolest thing about that was Evan
Dunham.
He,
he,
uh,
deep.
Half some perfectly gets on top,
gets the triangle,
escaped the triangle,
goes right into an Omoplata,
gets the Oma plot the sweep width,
the past donaldson.
Ronnie's inside controls.
Just some amazing,
beautiful Jujitsu.
They get back up,
they throw down again.
Dunham ends up on his back again with
another deep sweep.
He gets on top right into another
triangle.
But this time he finishes them serious,
serious Jujitsu.
I heard them talking about going down to
145 pounds.
And I've actually fought serone.
And uh,
he ended up breaking my eye orbit in the
first round.
You know,
it wasn't like he hit real hard and you
know,
what I was feeling,
I was feeling as kicks,
but it was just a precise shot.
You know,
astronomy is more time,
man.
When he's on,
he's on duty.
He's a scary dude.
He's a big dude at 155 pounds.
And for him to go down to 145,
I'm like,
man,
you know,
I think he's going to do that.
He's so 30 is a big dude.
If he can make it and reload,
reload the right way.
And I imagine that he probably will if
he has a,
you know,
he's training with Jackson so he's got a
good camp and good team behind him.
He's going to drop.
I think that was a room I think I read
somewhere where he said no,
I talked about it,
but it ain't going gonna happen.
Usually people talk about cutting off or
they lose.
He just beat the shit out of Evan
Dunham.
Sam,
he looked good to window.
He had a brief window he could have
pulled out of that triangle where he's
taking a little break there and that's
when you just locked it up.
Evan Dunham is a tough motherfucker and
the tap him is even more impressive.
The train with them when we're dominant
cruises camp with Uriah Faber when
they're are on the show,
we're a team of lance was always over at
drysdales and we've got to change.
I got a chance to roll with Evan Dunham
and do it.
He was just.
He was ferocious on the ground.
Yeah,
his very good.
That's when he tapped Efrain Escudero.
That was a real wake up call for a lot
of people like this kid's ground games.
Right before Evan Denim made his UFC
debut.
I didn't know anything about them.
Just one of those dudes you've never
heard of Gerald to.
There's a guy named Evan Dunham.
He,
I think he fought.
I forget,
but he said he's trusted me.
Put all your money on.
I haven't done them.
I just rolled with them all week.
The guys trashed me.
Gerald's awesome.
But uh,
Evan Dunham.
So I thought,
okay,
okay.
Leave it.
Yeah.
When he fought Tyson Griffin,
one of his training partners,
I thought that was really good because
Tyson Griffin's real solid on the ground
too.
And,
and uh,
that fight Dunham was just had this bat
control that was crazy and control the
fight will just fall back control.
So you know,
on,
on top point.
Yeah.
He's very good man.
I just was completely blown away by how
good serone looked.
So Ronnie was just on fire
when he's on fire,
he's on fire,
you know,
I think I think maybe had a little
personal issue is that that fight with
dos Anjos and uh,
you know,
he just bounced back,
in Germany is one of those guys who
likes to stay active and get after it.
So it's interesting to see what he's
going to do.
Yeah.
Fuck yeah,
that's going to be really interesting.
Um,
what did you think about the main event?
Me Personally,
I think Hendrick's one,
I think he completed all,
all of what the octagon rules are about,
you know,
damage,
octagon control,
you know,
what he landed to take downs.
He busted up his face,
he controlled the fight.
He made it a great fight and almost he
almost knocked him out.
And then,
uh,
you know,
at the end of the day,
gsp one and that,
that's,
that's the decision.
But I think,
I think a lot of better things are gonna
come from that because Dana white and
immediately calling out these,
these judges and,
and probably getting things going on
that end.
So it'll be interesting to see what
happens.
But I think he needs a rematch.
The,
I think you're right about,
um,
the,
the judges.
I think there's also not just the
judges,
but the,
the judging,
when you look at the scoring system
that's currently in place is not that
crazy.
The judging is not that crazy.
It's not that off at least this fight,
but the scoring system's terrible.
The scoring system is terrible.
It doesn't work when you can have around
like the second round we're Hendrix had
GSP and all sorts of trouble and that
round and the first round or scored
exactly the same.
They're both 10,
nine,
one way or another on either judges'
scorecard.
That's crazy.
Those are not the same rounds.
One round.
You had a good struggle that I think,
you know,
one guy did more damage,
but one guy went for a submission.
It's a sort of debatable 10,
nine round.
But the second round was Johnny
Hendricks clanging.
George has wobbled,
hasn't been all sorts of trouble.
Johnny swarming on him.
How the fuck are those two rounds?
Quantifiably the same.
That's preposterous.
They gotta fix that and if they don't
fix that big nine,
eight and seven around that.
But I,
I think this may at least in some way
motivate the conversation.
I think if time goes on,
if you Ma'am and may last 20 years,
if we're lucky,
they're going to figure out that the
system needs to be overhauled and this
idea of 10 points every round is fucking
silly about where we're acting.
Like there's a thing in place that we
have to follow for a new sport and
that's fucking stupid.
You don't,
you don't,
you never know.
There's no consistency with these
judges.
Like you know,
one thing I did not want to do in Brazil
was go to a decision and I was like,
if this is closer and to give it to him.
When I went up and I had a close fight
with Sam style,
I thought they're going to give it to
him.
I was like,
man,
you know what,
you did everything I knew in my heart.
I wanted to fight.
You know,
thankfully I ended up getting,
getting that fight,
but don't just fights.
Yeah,
close fights.
Phil Davis,
I thought be Leo.
Machida two out of three rounds.
I was a very big controversial fight and
then people were just like,
Nah,
Leo,
Leo to one.
You know that decision down there like
in Brazil.
That's scary,
Bro.
You know,
you're like,
oh my God,
is he going to get.
Watch that again?
Because I thought that Machita one,
I would have to see it again.
He got the decision,
but yeah,
that's not a robbery.
You know that.
That's a close fight.
The problem with the Hendrix GSP fight
is like,
let's say people that are watching it,
that our mma fans that may not even
train,
they just enjoy the,
the,
the fights,
the joy,
the excitement,
the sport to them.
GSP got his ass kicked for sure.
It's pretty God damn obvious.
So the only way he didn't get his ass
kicked as if the scoring systems broken
because to the average person,
when you hear what is a fight about is a
fight about touching a guy is a fight
about putting a guy on his back and
winding up on top of them.
What is a fight about?
A fight is about doing damage one way or
another or trying to finish the fight.
And one guy clearly did that weigh more
than the other for sure.
If you didn't have a scratch.
If we're on the
we're on the street and that fight was
to go down and then you know,
after awhile everybody breaks it up and
no matter who's on top of whatever
happened,
big fight,
we stand up,
Johnny,
we stand up just and we're like,
okay,
we'll give that one to johnny on the
street.
But also that could.
That could be.
That could happen accidentally.
Someone could hit somebody with an
elbow,
cut them open real early in the fight
and even though they dominated the rest
of the round,
they looked the worst for rare.
That's fine.
True,
true.
You gotTa,
you gotTa take,
take in hand,
like what actually went down,
like how was he doing that damage?
What was he doing?
And it looked like johnny was actually
doing the damage,
not just,
you know,
he got a lucky punch and as I got
swollen,
you know,
that that could easily happen,
but he would just,
he was landing shot after shot,
you know,
and put it pushing a good,
a good pace where GSP was even wobbled
and he's just laying on him.
So I mean obviously you think,
you know,
if anybody was not even like a fan or
like your grandma was watching,
she'd be like,
wow,
yeah,
I think this guy's winning
the most shocked and disappointed guy I
think maybe I've ever seen after a fight
with Johny Hendricks Saturday night he
was Eddie Bravo.
Breathe in.
It's crazy.
He's going to sleep so good tonight.
Earlier when it echoed and you got mad
because I was going to echo his
breathing.
Make an echo.
So
that's,
that's ridiculous.
He accidentally talked and then Shit,
you fucked it up.
That's ridiculous.
Um,
yeah man.
I think that,
uh,
if you,
if,
if you look at the scoring system that's
in place and how it's been utilized so
far,
I could see the argument.
I don't agree with it,
but I could see the argument that GSP
won the fight.
I don't think he won the first round.
Everybody was thinking that he won the
first round because he went for the
submission and got the take down.
But he,
Johnny did a lot of damage in that
round,
fucked his legs up with those needs to
the legs,
which I don't understand why people
don't count those.
Like,
are you,
what are you looking at?
The big strike.
That's like a Charlie horse.
I don't know if you guys have been hit
in the leg or like you look at like a
one of those slug bugs and somebody hit
you.
You're like,
man,
that's a knee hitting you.
It's a lot harder.
Just because GSP is not responding
doesn't mean those are big shots.
He can tolerate the pain.
It was hard like fuck.
And those are damaging.
They take away your spraying.
And so in my opinion,
you've got people that should not be
judging that,
that don't understand what exactly is
going down.
Johnny did a lot more damage in that
route.
He hit him with some hard fucking elbows
when they were up against the cage.
But George is trying to take him down.
He had the single johnny hit him with
some hard fucking elbows and then when
they were in the clench and johnny was
when Johnny was bouncing up and down on
one leg,
he was tagging him with left upper cuts.
Those are all really significant.
The big,
the takedown in this submission attempt.
It wasn't close enough.
It wasn't like Johnny was screaming and
beet red and and then he got it out of
it.
Like you see him on his back and his dad
strangled.
It wasn't close enough in my opinion.
I gave,
I gave Hendrix that round and yeah,
I,
when I watch it,
when I'm doing commentary and I watched
as one thing when I watched it again
afterwards,
that's when I get a sense of what I
think actually happened.
Didn't happen.
Sometimes you're doing commentary,
just trying to be entertaining.
You're all caught up in the moment,
but why?
Why do you suppose nothing has been
done?
I mean,
this isn't the first time we've had a
main event and in controversial
decision,
like why?
No,
because the athletic commission has to
admit that they made a mistake.
Do you believe the theory that uh,
like you really should be the champion?
No.
Like,
no,
because there's a lot of those ones with
like Frankie Edgar,
Benson,
Henderson.
I tell them,
I think it's an even fight.
Some people are like,
oh,
you really got to take it from the
champion and be the champion.
I could see how you got to be,
have a look.
Any decision that's close,
you're going to have people that see it
for the other guy.
That's always going to be the case.
And in that way,
the idea of you've got to take it from
the champion,
kind of makes sense.
That's the only way it makes sense to
convince the people that this is a fair
and just decision even if you're not
happy that the guy that you were rooting
for last,
you still have to,
you know,
you still have to look at it honestly
and objectively,
guy got his ass kicked.
That's the fact that you're like,
okay,
here's a perfect example.
Second round of Frankie Edgar,
Bj Penn.
Okay.
The first fight was a clOse fight.
Second fight,
second round,
second fight.
The first fight was a close fight,
whereas very debatable.
Second fight.
Nobody was debating that cranky,
beat,
beat bj,
period.
So I think when you look out worked on,
he was more motivated.
He was in beTter shape,
pushed to hard pace.
That's a fight where bj penn has fucking
millions of fans.
they couldn't deny the fact that bj lost
that fight.
True.
So in that kind of fight,
yeah,
I could see that's one of those fights
where you,
you know,
you're really taking it to them even
though frankie was the champion at that
time.
But I think that you should start even.
You should start even for sure.
You got it.
You got to earn it.
Definitely.
And I think,
I think even gsps face a face like a
told,
told it all,
you know,
and uh,
it's crazy.
You know that actually,
uh,
one of our buddies,
Mike Chandler just fought eddie alvarez
and a sick fight,
saw that fight and it was just crazy.
Mike waS this going forward?
He's laying in takedowns,
he's getting out of stuff,
you know,
and he just controlling these rounds and
then such a close decision where at the
end of it,
if you look at this,
eddie alvarez is family,
looks worried they're not hugging.
And Michael Chandler is families like,
yeah,
and you know,
they're thinking confident,
but then boom,
there's this decision.
You're just like,
whoa.
You got to go back and look at things
like,
okay,
well what,
what happened?
Maybe something I didn't see my bias,
you know,
it's just those,
those crazy fights,
you know,
I need to watch that fight a second
time.
I enjoyed it though.
It was a wild fight.
Chandler is a bad motherfucker,
dude.
He's a beast.
So it's almost like that in the gym.
Yeah,
there was awful.
So you think nothing.
Nothing changes.
Because then that would mean the
commission would have to admit they made
a mistake.
Yes.
If you.
if you change things,
you have to admit that you should have
changed things.
I have To admit that if you are running
things,
if this is the correct way to do things,
why didn't you do this 18 months ago?
Why didn't you do this two years ago?
Why didn't you do this five years ago?
You've been licensing nma for so long
and people have been complaining about
things for so long,
but you've.
You've done the same shit over and over
again.
That's so then that's probably never
going to change.
That's like the definition of insanity.
Doing the same thing over and over
again,
expecting different results.
They can have people that are untrained
as judges
better or worse for the the casinos,
the people that are taken.
Is it better or worse if there is a
logical reasonable scoring system or if
there's a fucked up one,
what's better?
What do you think is better for them?
Well,
if this,
if the kids see,
knows are on the board in everything is
on the square than you know the house is
always going to win and almost every
game right when it comes to gambling on
fights,
they're pretty smart.
I'm sure they get really good odds
makers.
There was a few lines that I didn't
like.
I gave a few of my friends that were
betting.
I told them what I thought were like
good bats and not good bets,
but I think that ultimately the experts
of mma are,
you're not gonna be able to fool them.
They know who's going to win or they
have a 70,
80 percent chance that who's going to be
way better than 51 percent.
If the house is a 51 percent chance or
54 percent,
whatever it is in blackjack and mma
expert has a way better.
You know,
if you're gambling,
like if you were gambling on fines,
shit,
you're going to be 80 percent right now.
You think about 80 percent when you
guess
sometimes I get them all wrong,
but let.
Let'S.
Do you think there's ever been a point
in time in las vegas where they see the
people that are running the casinos,
who the fuck knows who they are,
have something to do with the
commission,
like they're tied in somehow and uh,
at there was a fight.
Do you thiNk ever that the,
the,
the casinos made a decision happened
because they didn't want to lose a
certain amount of money?
Who,
that's all speculation.
Who knows if that ever happens?
I don't know.
I'll tell you what I'm.
One thing I do know about casinos,
like they're not stupid.
They catch people counting cards.
They get rid of them if they catch
people doing things.
Like here's a perfect example,
professional pool.
They've never had a line on professional
pool.
You know why?
because they had a line on professional
pool wants and the underdog was this
dude named mike lebraun to win this big
tournament.
And so they dumped the shit out of this
dude.
Everybody dumped to the dude,
meaning everybody quit.
They played shitty on purpose and let
this dude when and they get all their
money on this guy winning.
So everybody just had his just driving
balls straight into the rail.
They're missing the pocket book inches
on purpose,
totally on purpose,
obviously on purpose and the other one
dude casino,
it's trial and error and those,
uh,
you can't,
you can't actually denied a casino.
It's just like the people that are out
there that are highly elite people,
they know how to make good decisions no
matter what it is that they're winning
for a reason.
That's because they're making good
decisions and taking advantage of those
people that are trying to cut,
cut this.
Do you think there might be a crazy
conspiracy where like the people running
the casinos have something to do.
Like every now and then they make the
call and they go,
that motherfucker loss no matter what.
If it's close,
you think there's anything like that or
you go to the casino,
they play their odds.
Very good.
Someone always making for some,
for,
for a judge to get paid off to do this
or that.
There's got to be someone with power.
It's the math that people don't
understand.
That's why those people that are
counting cards,
they understand a portion of the math.
You got to think those people are at an
elite level and are always winning
Because of their decision making so
their.
Their science and their math skills are
way better than you are so they can see
these small little snakes in the grass.
If that's what you want to call them,
like dirt bag trying to scheme on your
money.
Imagine if like that.
That's yours and you see this little rat
over here playing a little game.
You just want to go up and smack him.
Like,
bro,
you're cheating,
cheating.
It's.
He's just good at it.
It's so stupid that you can't count.
He caught onto the science of the math.
You know what I mean?
How crazy is that?
They tell you,
you can't be really good at this.
You can't.
You can't be good at it.
You can't,
can't figure it out.
They're playing it to the.
To the people that are juSt like,
man,
am I goIng to get lucky?
Lucky.
Imagine that,
man.
it's like only fighting guys.
You can absolutely be like,
could you imagine you would.
You'd never get a title shot.
Like the idea is ridiculous.
Anybody who's.
It's not like the battle between the
card counters in the casinos.
That should never goes down.
It's not really.
You know,
they make sure those guys can't work
like,
nah,
sorry,
we're just here to steal.
We're just here to extract it.
We're not here to gamble.
To actually gamble or something.
Been gambling.
When a guy gets like really good at
poker,
are really good at blackjack and see
kind of becomes like things.
Those dudes just make money man.
Really best dudes.
They make money.
They make a big risk.
Yeah.
They lose a little bit here in the
again,
but for the most part they wind up
ahead.
There's a lot of those guys that are
like professionals.
What do they.
What happens is these guys just get
funded.
Are they just playing in a basement
where these dudes come from?
It's crazy because they just see this
guy on tv.
You're like,
man,
does this guy even know anything?
But all of a sudden it shows like the
chip or the money count and you're like,
this dude's
well,
think about it.
THink about how much money it would
mean,
how much time and effort you put in to
get really good at mma.
Now think about someone who's doing the
same thing with card counting or with
poker.
They're just constantly playing moves
over there.
You ever see like poker dorks talk,
give her like have a poker door
conversation with people when they start
talking about night.
I had five night and he pulls king six
and I flopped with.
Yeah,
it has like a pig latin.
What the fuck is saying?
But,
but to them it's just,
it's almost like a chest thing.
Felt like they're going over the moves.
They're like,
oh,
I see.
Well why didn't you fold?
You know,
like why didn't you,
why didn't you do this?
Why didn't you do this?
and they're,
they're going over positions.
And I got a bad roll of the cards and
you know,
I believe in the role of the card is all
you ever.
You ever sat down like on like a,
what is it,
like a black jack table and then that
person's always hitting when they
shouldn't be hitting or not hitting and
you're just like,
I gotta get up,
I just lost 75 bucks to realize this
guy's an idiot and he's messing up the
whole table.
But you get on that table and you're
just hitting in your role and you're
slapping high fives with some person
from Arizona you don't even know and
you're just killing it.
So it's,
it's crazy
playing that to me.
How does it see,
I don't know gambling.
So if we're all playing say you mean
eddie,
you're playing blackjack together and
eddie gets crazy and he just fucking
said he hits.
He's a hiT me.
I got this is a fucking bitch.
Say I have like a low car,
like I'm at like a nine and he's hitting
on a 16 to try to get to 21 because he
wants to beat the guy.
You know you're supposed to let that
just pass and let let,
let me go ahead and hit,
hit and hit the bigger number instead.
He'll bust and ruined my car.
Next thing you know,
like all hit like two little cards and
I'm like okay,
I'm at like a a 12,
but they're showing like a 15,
16 to.
I got a hit and then boom I,
boston,
it just kind of just goes down the line.
But if you get the people that are
hitting on the right cars,
that'll actually funkshway and flow
really.
It doesn't make any sense.
It seems like he's making his decisions.
You're making your decisions.
Commercials.
The guy goes downstairs and they score
scoring.
Know
dante using like five decks now.
They're like five days.
I don't even know how many they use.
They use a Bunch.
You,
they have that big machine that like
just like.
So
the way you're looking at it as if he
gets a five that you could have used and
he busts because that five he fucked
you.
You have had that five and you would
have had 20 or something.
YeP.
And he would.
And he might've been.
Then the dealer might have busted and he
could actually one,
but he actually hit the wrong card.
Trying to be greedy too soon.
I think that's not a good way of looking
at it.
I think
that's like a defeatist logic because it
doesn't make any sense.
Like you look,
the numbers are the numbers.
If you have 15 and you hit,
you know,
you know what the consequences are.
If you have 17 and you hit your crazy,
there's some good ones that you're
supposed to hit on and that they tell
you not to hit on.
And sometimes the dealer if you'd like,
you don't really know what you're doing.
You're just starting out and they'll be
like,
you sure you want to do that?
You know,
but they can't tell you but they'll ask
you and stop you.
Which is pretty cool because I.
What if you don't know you're doing just
blacked out drunk and you're making all
stupid bets.
Solution money.
Well I would imagine too that if you're
a card counter,
it would actually help you to have
someone who's betting all fucking wacky
next to you because you know that he got
that certain card,
like key.
Instead of like him folding or holding,
he actually added additional information
into the equation he gave you like,
oh,
the seven just got used,
so now you have an extra number that you
can eliminate.
You know whaT I mean?
I mean,
it seems to me that playing with idiots
would be beneficial if you have the
right attitude.
It could possibly work out.
Yeah.
I guess if you're a card counter,
if you're a really good card counting,
and again,
I don't understand how the fuck card
county works,
so I'm just talking.
There's a movie about it,
but I still never.
It's hard math and math.
Ed norton,
right?
Yeah.
It's a crazy.
It's a crazy math to it that.
No,
no.
I think it was a.
No,
that's.
That's a rob the casino.
They robbed the casino.
Was there a card counter in those
movies?
Now?
There's a lot of others.
There's a lot of those.
Louise,
the were the dude.
Vegas figures out all these genius.
Whether the movie wasn't with a bunch of
genius card counters.
Does the college that they would.
Then the guy takes him there and he
wasn't supposed to Be in the building.
Yeah,
you guys want to do this?
They all got a suite together.
They're rolling around in cash and it
all goes bad.
Eddie bravo cards.
Would you rob the system where if you,
if you do a little bit like say you knew
the math and you just sit down and
you're like,
you know what else?
I just want a couple extra hundred.
Let's real quick,
you know,
and then you would you sit down and do
it.
Don't be scared of a system.
But I didn't realize that I was an idiot
and I was going to try to make some
money and taco and then realized,
oh shit.
How much did you lose before you figured
ouT?
Well it's just,
it's like 21 and roulette.
There'S reddit.
You can just bet red and black.
You could put chips on the numbers or
you could just put chips on red and
black.
So I figured,
I figured that if you put a,
you know,
if you had a.
Yeah,
I have a lot of cash to put $500 on red.
If you lose,
you just keep putting.
You keep doubling it until finally read
hits.
But you got to have a lot of money to
double.
But there's a limit.
So they already figured that out a long
time ago.
So they limit you that you can do that
shit.
So I thought I had it.
I didn't realize that they already
figured it out.
So I'm in,
I'm going to do this shit.
I'm just gonna.
I'm just gonna win once when 500 bucks
and I'm done.
That can be an expensive method though.
you better come in with some staff.
You've got to have like $10,000
if you hit that,
I'd be so awesome.
He's like walk away.
Yeah,
you got to walk with.
The key is to walk away when you your
$500 back.
So everybody's thought this through.
It's hilarious.
How many conversations have been had
across the country?
People figuring bro.
I was telling people I got it bro.
I got it,
but I'm not going to get crazy.
It's just going to be $500 a day.
It's a system to get you could.
You could live nicely just once a day.
He just got up.
What's interesting,
if you want $500 a day,
they would fucking kick you out.
They'd be like you to keep switching
casinos,
bro.
Yeah.
That's the move.
right?
But don't keep winning.
Did they offer you stuff to keep you in
that environment for the hotel?
Might bring some pretty girls over to
and they give you a bottle of champagne.
Like you're the man broke two days.
I love vegas.
I love the idea behind vegas.
Just let people do whatever the fuck
they want.
Let him gamble.
Let a decision may open.
Stay open 24 hours a day with alcohol.
Fuck yeah,
I like it.
I like vegas.
I liked the freedom of vegas.
you need people like some seedy parts of
the seedy parts everywhere.
If you get 100 people together,
one of them is going to suck.
It's good to have fights.
They're too big.
It's too hot to live though to be.
If you were like rolling ball and like
carrot top and you had some giant
mansion and henderson,
you know,
you keep your bitches doesn't pull his
fucking.
Is he rich?
Fuck,
are you kidding?
He's not like corey feldman.
No,
he's got a.
He's got a long standing show in vegas
at the luxor,
so he's got like 10 million carrot.
Top has been performing celebrity in our
store for all the law.
It was like a vanilla ice cutting.
No way.
Dude.
Countertop has been a successful
performer in vegas for more than a
decade.
He's been killing it,
killing it in vegas for a decade and he
puts on a great show.
You know,
a lot of people give carrot top a lot of
shit.
But look,
there's people that like the monkeys and
there's people that like slayer,
right?
Everybody's got their own thing they
enjoy and if you'd like that kind of
comedy,
carrot tops a funny dude and he's
basically essentially taken over that
entire market.
What exactly does he do?
Magic prop comment.
She's a prop comedian.
Brings out a bunch oF prompts.
They used to.
They used to be a style prop prop comedy
used to be a style of comedy.
It was like puppet guys who eventual
requests those guys,
those guys who would do impressions and
there was prop comics.
There was like a style of comedy and
it's not anymore because carrot top was
so dominant.
he was so big.
Was the biggest prop comic of
autologous.
A prop comic.
Yeah,
but gallagher is like a a fake prop
comic,
like smashes fruit and shit.
It's a little different.
He has,
I shouldn't say fake.
I would say he's got his own branch of
prop comedy,
but he owns as well.
if you went on stage and try to smash
watermelons,
they'd be like,
bitch,
are you fucking kidding me?
You can't steal from him.
Gallagher's shit.
You can't smash fruit.
What aBout andrew?
DIce?
Clay is hilarious.
the man,
he still does.
He still make a lot of money.
He never really.
He just had the swagger of just coolness
around him.
You know?
He just lives.
We've had podcasts a couple times now.
Went to see him in vegas.
I saw him back in his height live,
man.
That was a massive,
where it was a big play there,
pacific amphitheater or so,
orange county during the height.
Oh my god.
And then did some insane amount of
theaters across the country with more
than any comedian.
Yeah.
He's probably the most successful
comedian of all time.
Like as far as money.
Oh,
George Lopez.
Cool dude.
At the right time.
He just came through the right era and
just smashed it.
He just had the perfect act.
He had an act that you could play back.
That was the thing about is act like you
didn't mind if you knew the jokes.
It's almost like music,
like if you want to go see the rolling
stones,
you don't want to have your new song,
bitch.
Come on,
get it out of the waY.
You've got new song.
I want to hear.
Stop me up.
You know,
back to the classic comedy comedy
comedy.
You have to have new shit except dice
clay.
Dice clay.
What's in the bowl?
Bitch?
The whole crowd would sing it along as
if they were like,
yeah,
it's a different candidate.
It was a different thing.
He figured out something different or
stumbled upon something different,
but that's something different.
Became massive.
People wanted to see those rhymes.
They want them to hear those rhymes.
Little boy blue.
Oh,
he needed the money and the whole crowd
would sing it along.
What's his act like nowadays?
I haven't heard a.
He almost seemed like he was just
keeping it real.
He doesn't give a fuck.
He's.
He's worth a ton of money.
He's got a hot wife.
He is very few people that legitimately
don't give a fuck.
Andrew dice clay legitimately doesn't
give a fuck.
It's still smokes.
A ton of cigarettes.
Still wears rest,
fucking weightlifting gloves and cut off
sleeves and whereas a nice fannY pack
prompts,
I learned about the roots fanny pack for
him.
It's an excellent choice.
If you're going to get leather.
Fanny pack doesn't give a fuck.
I love ford failing.
I was such a big andrew dice clay fan
that ford fairlane was still one of my
favorite movies.
I love that.
Fucking loves.
Last time You saw his comedy,
long time ago too,
we saw him.
We saw him about two years ago in vegas.
Was a year ago,
two years ago,
was about a year ago.
Did you ever ask them about what the
reasoning behind that?
The day the laughter died,
what was that about?
Like I didn't give a fuck.
He went on stage anD he was like decided
that he was too big or something like
that.
So he went on stage at danger fields and
decided to just talk nonsense for two
our jokes and then release it as a dvd
and it did great.
So fucking hundreds of thousands of
copies.
It was a joke.
It was what he wanted to do.
He just wanted to do whatever they call
it.
The dAy the laughter died.
She did die.
He did whatever the fuck you wanted to
do and what he wanted to do was just
show up and start recordIng shows where
he just starts talking and maybe comes
up with jokes and maybe not.
Some of the things were funny,
like you'd get something funny.
Really 15,
20 mInutes.
I took that seriously,
man,
I,
I didn't get it.
I think I was like 22.
I took it seriously.
I thought it was,
it was just,
he just sucked on purpose.
I think he got so big.
I don't think you nor I nor anyone in
this room could ever imagine what it's
like to be that famous when.
And this was famous before the internet,
so it was a weird fame,
you know,
it was a,
like,
people couldn't believe there are seeing
you.
There's a lot more exclusive as famous.
Everybody knows that.
I don't know how you go through life.
Everywhere you go,
people are going,
they're fucking joe rogan everywhere.
That's got to be fucking crazy.
But they're nice man.
People are almost universally nice to
me.
It's not hard.
You know,
people go,
what's up joe?
I go,
hey,
what's up?
It's not hard.
It's not like.
But when people are staring at you,
like at restaurants,
I'm a nice guy,
man.
You know,
they say hi,
I'll say hi.
You know,
it's uh,
it's not that to me,
it's just a bunch of people that are
being nice to you.
If I was known for being like,
here's a perfect example,
if you were like George Zimmerman,
you know,
like that's kind of the trick.
Shooting trayvon martin.
If you were that kind of famous,
that would have to be.
That would be very disconcerting because
you're famous for something horrible or
that egg incognito guy.
He just got arrested again last night
for punching.
Is allegedly allegedly signed cognito?
No,
no,
no.
Zimmerman mean,
look,
you're gonna you're gonna run into crazy
people.
No matter what you do in this life,
whether you're famous,
whether you're not famous and you know,
if you're a friendly person being famous
as long as you manage it correctly,
as long as you don't think it's,
you know,
you don't believe it.
Can't believe it can't,
but you have to enjoy like you come,
you come from basically worked hard.
You deserve it.
And I like,
it never seems to get old.
People were like,
man,
do you ever get nervous?
I'm like,
no man,
that's so cool.
You know,
maybe you inspire a lot of people.
I mean,
you're everywhere so people maybe feel
inspired and is like,
man,
thanks joe.
Keep.
Keep on going.
That's cool.
I mean you get.
Well,
if that's the case,
I'm happy to do it.
You know,
I think I've been inspired by a shitload
of people in my life,
so if there's ever anybody that I can
inspire to me that's a huge gift to be
able to turn that back around.
You know,
for sure.
I think we all,
everybody in this room's doing that in
some way,
shape or form and I think doing a
podcast is doing that,
you know,
having a podcast is like,
literally inspiration in a digital form.
A lot of them conversations with people
that you might not ever get to sit down
with and you're,
you're talking like I had graham hancock
on last week and you know,
I mean,
can you start smoking weed again?
Not yet,
not yet.
He freaked out because the biggest donor
ever he was,
he was off the rails.
He was looking,
he was smoking every day,
all day.
That's way too much.
I never vaporizing too.
So when you're hitting that vaporizing
bag,
god damn,
you're getting a lot of thc.
No big deal.
Don't take a daY off here and there and
you know,
what else is good about?
We do it with someone that you like,
you know,
like eddie bravo and I will get together
with smoke a little weed.
There were never,
you know,
it's a cool,
calm,
collected situation.
It's gonna enhance the conversation.
We're going to have a nice time by
themselves.
Big bags of shit.
Some people just trying to get on that
spiritual level and it could be a
spiritual way of just chilling.
Relaxing.
Yeah,
it is.
It's a part of the earth.
It's.
We have a relationship with.
If you're waking up hitting the ball,
that's too much.
Well you know what?
Maybe you need it,
you know,
I'm not saying what you need or what you
don't need,
but if you don't need it and you're
fucking out of control,
then you got to deal with your shit.
And that's the out of control thing.
It's like a psychological balance.
And as a fighter,
I think you probably have the most
difficult job in all of athletics,
entertainment,
sports.
You have the most difficult,
solitary,
lonely,
dangerous,
crazy job
I think.
I think athletes just in general have
that because look at the exposure that
we're getting on twitter and stuff like
that.
That stuff wasn't happening with Michael
Jordan was for.
This goes back to what you're talking
about when people were a lot more
exClusive than because they couldn't get
into your day to day life as if like,
you know,
I'm a fan of joe rogan.
So I'm like man,
what's,
what's joe doing when he's in like
Brazil or london or something like that.
So then keep up on you a little bit more
exclusively.
So then when they see you,
they're like,
oh hey,
well that's also a different thing in,
in what we're talking about,
about like people coming up to you.
Like people coming up to me are
universally friendly.
Like um,
I've avid,
very few people come up to me.
They weren't friEndly.
Even if someone didn't disagree with me
About something that come up and just
start talking to me and we can have a
nice conversation about it and there's
never hostility,
but online when you're dealing with
anonymous people,
horrible shit,
internet tough guys because that's.
It's not even.
They're not even,
it's not even a real thing they're
saying because they don't really mean
it.
They would never say it if you were in
front of them,
fake the words have no.
What if those people spend half the time
off the internet or off their cell phone
talking so much and they use that same
energy that they do on this side,
but they go to the other side,
you know,
a much more positive.
How much more inspirational possibly
like how much more like ambition they
would have him,
you know,
maybe successful in that aspect,
but some people spend that same amount
of energy as you would over here on the
good side.
Spending it on the negative side if
you're able to just to turn it around.
It's the same effort.
Yeah.
I learned that very early in life that
even though there's a real big pole
to think about other people and dwell on
other people and be angry about other
people and look about their success or
compare it to your success,
that shit is all flawed and dangerous
because it robs you of your time for
time you spend,
even though it feels natural to hate on
somebody,
that time you spend hating on someone
robs you of your own time.
You are literally hating on yourself and
you don't even realize it because you're
a smart person.
You only have a certain amount of free
time and your fucking day because if
you're a smart person,
you find shit you love to do.
Whether it's a relationship you love to
do,
whether it's a sport you love to do,
whether it's a job you like to pursue,
you don't have much time and anytime you
spend on some nonsense and gossip and
stupidity,
when you see these gossipy websites and
people talking shit about people where
you're like,
why would you even write that?
What are they doing?
They're distracting themselves from
their own failure reversals.
It's amazing.
There's some people that ain't even on
that level,
you know,
lost a lot of friends growing,
growing up and getting to where I'm at,
but it's probably a good decision
making.
Some people just don't ever get it.
They don't ever know how to flip that
switch and realize that it's the same
amount of energy that you spend doing
bad as the same amount that you could be
spending doing good.
It's all goes to the decisions and
momentum.
They get on momentum.
They get caught up in this wave of
hating,
hating on people or gossiping about
people.
We're talking about someone that you
don't even fucking know how many people
you've ever heard like talking about
like reality stars on tv,
talking like tmz,
people like their job.
There's three types of people in this
world,
man.
There's,
there's talkers,
there's watchers and there's doers.
You know,
and if it wasn't for like people like,
like real famous people or whatever,
teams,
people don't even have a job because
they don't know who to go follow anymore
and be like,
oh,
what are they doing now?
Are like system.
Think of when I made a tmz guy that he's
just a cool dude and transitionary job.
That's My approach.
I like to think that right now he's
taking a camera in front of people's
faces at the airport.
But hey man,
I'm just trying to make some money.
I don't know,
dude.
I used to deliver newspapers,
you know,
I don't,
I try not to judge anybody doing any of
that shit,
you know,
but it's a job that exists.
It's not his fault that that job exists.
The problem is there is a demand demand
for their,
for nonsense.
And mom,
I'm guilty as charged man,
if I see,
cause there was a fake video apparently
wasn't really kanye west,
but it was a,
it was saying the kanye west was
knocking out these,
um,
these people that were paparazzi and
austin and mean whoever this dude was
that looks like kanye west,
but it wasn't.
Kanye west is just uncork and lefthand.
The video has been removed,
just bombs on these dudes.
And it's,
he obviously has skills because he ducks
under a punch and connects with a punch.
He hits hard and he knocks these three
dudes out and it's video.
I watched it three times.
What the fuck am I watching that for?
Like wHy do I give a shit if kanye
west's getting brawls?
Turns out he wasn't even,
but if he was getting in browser
photographers,
there's a new thing going around the
internet called a game called knockout
supposedly that I think the east coast
was doing these like young kids are
knocking out old people,
just innocent people.
There's going up like,
hey,
having a conversation.
Boom just hits them and they're calling
this game knockout or something like
that and let's go find those faggots and
choke them out and break their arm.
A squadron of guys going out to look for
these motherfuckers and so can you
imagine that you're walking down the
goddamn street.
You could be a lady at fucking man with
kids at home waiting and these dudes
combined punch you.
Do those.
It should be totally legal to take a
baseball bat to those fuckers fixing to
chill out.
They don't.
You know what?
There's a lot of dumb kids out there
that are not raised right.
They don't get any guidance in their
life that live in a terrible
environment.
They're terrible.
They're broken.
I mean,
I'm not saying you can't be fixed,
but god damn.
That is a utter lack of respect for
humanity.
If you just strike someone for no reason
for.
Yeah,
there's a.
There's a point where you grow up
though,
you know,
because you can't,
you can't blame.
You can blame it on the parents,
but there comes a point where you get to
a certain point where you're like,
okay,
I can make a decision for myself to make
either a good choice,
like I don't have to live like this for
the rest of my life.
I can go
on and do this,
but just the fact that you would use
that as an excuse,
like bad parenting and I'm going out and
I'm like bashing people.
But granted it does start with the
parenting.
You know,
that's,
that's very important.
I told the guys that are involved
because it's always.
It's one dude.
There's like a group of five or six of
them in one dude.
Just clocks this man passing by and that
the people in that group,
man,
there's got to be one per group,
is,
has half a heart and can call the cops
and report this fucking bastard before
he does it again.
Use.
There's gotta be there's gotta fuck you
talking about his group.
So we need to.
Right?
Okay.
Yeah,
yeah.
Come on.
That's ridiculous.
Or rats.
Rats are bad.
That's a good rat.
Yeah know it's incredibly cowardly move.
But it's also like they're looking for
some excitement in their life probably.
And it's exciting to do something
horrible like that for all the wrong
reasons,
but still exciting.
How about getting paid $100,000
to get into a gym,
you know,
dana white stone out,
big bonuses,
you know,
get some.
So that's the real knock say to people
when people talk to me about fighting,
you know,
they're like,
why don't you go find them and mega,
what are you talking about?
Like,
do you understand what fighting is like,
yo man,
you kicked somebodies ass.
I always say this like,
you think fighting is kicking someone's
ass.
Know that happens sometimes,
but it's fighting and everybody wants to
kick someone's ass,
but nobody wants to fight.
Nobody wants to have a jon jones.
Alexander gustafson where you sanchez
gilbert were,
you have,
you know,
you're letting it all hang out in there
and if that is
not your sole idea of what to be doing
with your life,
you shouldn't be fucking doing it.
Exactly.
Because there's a dude like that out
there.
There's the alexander gustafson out
there,
there's the John Jones out there,
there's a Jeremy Stevens out there.
There's dudes out there that that's what
they do.
Those guys are fighting for real man.
You're,
you're born with like natural talent.
Like with those guys,
you know,
they just made the decision to take it
to a whole nother level.
You know,
and you're right man.
You find out a lot about a guy when you
hit them,
isn't going to just fold over.
Let me just beat him up to the rough,
pulls them off or is he going to take a
hit?
Keep coming back fighting strong,
you know?
and that's,
that's where that class comes in.
Like we're at the end,
at the end of the fight,
as soon as that buzzer hits and they
know it's all over,
all the training,
everything.
And they just give each other a hug and
people are just like,
man,
that's amazing what those two fighters
have.
Like,
they know each other better than anybody
at that particular moment.
They're just,
they're just on one.
You know,
they have so much respect for one
another,
you know,
they're able to go to war and plus it's
entertaining for the fans and they just
see something that's,
that's almost priceless,
you know?
Yeah.
No,
it's most exciting sport of all time.
you know,
there's no sport that gets closer to the
raw nature of,
uh,
of a fight to the death of fight or
flight,
of being able to test your will,
your heart,
your courage.
You're willing to put it all on the line
against another persons.
And not just in that moment,
but in all that time that you spend
preparing for that moment,
the guy who was more willing,
that guy who was more enthused,
the guy was more disciplined and
smarter.
All those things have to come together.
And now also you're dealing also like
what we were talking about,
these super athletes,
these guys like hector lumbar,
these guys like tyron woodley,
thEse,
these guys that are coming along like
jesus christ,
sergio pettis to little 20 year old kid.
You know,
you can name all those guys,
but then you gotta you gotta think here
before too long there's going to be some
little kid right now thAt he's going to
turn 18.
And he'd be like,
no,
this is what I've been training for.
This is what I do.
And by the time he's 19 years old,
could be fighting in the ufc and be one
like tyson bad dude like tyson.
Exactly.
You remember those days we used to watch
tyson on espn and see the highlight
some zoos.
Why in a body shop to a write up or you
just admitted that he was on coke during
those fights?
No,
no.
The later fights after prison.
Yeah.
After three is he had like 300 million
people were taking advantage of them,
but just beginner days poses.
It was after,
so it wasn't during the ferocious days.
I think he was saying that it was at,
let's find out tyson had immense hooked
on cocaine
because it would make sense because if
you look at his early fights when he was
just destroying people.
That makes sense.
He looks like he's on coke.
I think he was just so,
so crazy,
but he had so much power in such a gift,
but he.
He would like cry before his fights.
Dude,
like that's.
That's a scary part when you're about to
go on stage and you're in the back and
you're just waiting.
That's the crazy part.
Like normally a fight.
You know what's funny is you're talking
about that one documentary where he's
crying before the junior olympics where
it goes out and knocks.
It did not.
I found out through frAnkie lyles
because they're good friends and he did
My podcast when I get allows,
former wba champion.
He said that he was on this whole time,
I thought Mike Tyson is Crying outside
of his.
His coach has to come out and get them
teddy,
teddy atlas and it appears that he's
talking them through it,
like saying you can do this,
you train hard for that,
and then they come back and that's what
it looks like,
but according to frankie lyles is really
good friend.
He said that no,
he was crying because he knew he was
going to kill the guy and it was going
to be so much fun.
He couldn't believe he's finally going
to be.
He's gonna win this junior olympic
thing.
That's why he was crying and teddy out.
This was going,
come on.
It's just like,
let's go get it,
go do it,
and then we can celebrate later from
2007 from the rent in 19 in 2000.
Our loose alvarez,
he was high and he was on coke and
that's when he started using a rubber
dick.
He started using a wizard later.
What year was this?
This was 2000 post prison and he did
test positive for marijuana after a
fight in 2000 with andrea gelada.
He got,
they find them 200,000
bucks.
He said he didn't have a chance to get
the wizard from,
from a member of his team was hold this
rubber dick.
That's crazy.
He said he lost his mind,
but back then he said,
uh,
he said that he was,
um,
he bit lennox lewis when he was high on
cocaine in two,
two.
All that shit.
Well,
I'll fuck you in front of you.
I'll fuck you to you.
Love me.
Faggot.
That was a great.
Maybe the greatest thing anyone's ever
come on.
Fuck you to you.
Do you realize man enough to fuck with
me?
Do you realize how long that will take?
Years old.
He was insane.
Do that ferocious attitude and he would
just land blow after heavy blow and he'd
be like,
I just keep punching because he knows
he's just breaking you.
And those guys would just.
Well,
he was high when he was fighting and he
wasn't training.
Yeah,
he even mentioned he got knocked down
before the buster douglas fight and in
buster douglas.
Actually,
that's a crazy story about him.
His mom died like three weeks before
that fight and he still took that fight.
So you know,
that dude's just like unlike another
mental level because that already he
would just been really screwed up,
but he obviously seemed like he was on a
whole nother level.
Listen to this,
he wrote his memoir.
The history of war is the history of
drugs.
Every great general and warrior from the
beginning of time was high.
Who put the rug that that's what he
wrote his memoirs.
And you know what?
There's a lot to it.
When you find out the bushes brought in
more cooked in the state and the states
than any other drug cartels combined.
Could you imagine if we find out that
the military industrial complex,
just a bunch of coke heads.
Oh dude,
dude,
it was,
it was chosen.
TheY call them the,
uh,
the angel of the or the lord of the
skies.
There was this old cocaine dealer
before.
They'll chapo guzman.
They called this guy the lord of the
skies and my spanish isn't that good to
even remember what it was,
but this guy was one of the,
he was the richest and probably no one
else will ever top the guy,
the lord of the skies.
What he,
uh,
he basically bought out all the police,
all the government and was paying top,
top dollar.
I mean,
he was born,
he was in Mexico,
he was in Mexico and he's flying and
drugs to theu ,
s and was using all of these resources.
So there's no doubt in my mind,
you know,
I,
I'm not disrespecting anybody,
but there's no doubt in my mind that,
that stuff is,
is very for sure.
And people,
cops,
governmental officials are getting paid
off.
Have you ever seen the clinton
chronicles?
It's on youtube.
It's a documentary now.
What is it?
Watch the clinton chronicles.
It's on youtube.
It's free.
It's,
it's a history of bill clinton,
man.
And when you find out why he became
president and what he did in Arkansas,
governor,
that dude was more 10 times more
gangster than any 100 times more than
john gotti.
What about the bush and the family and
stuff like that?
They,
they,
I remember bill clinton was working for
George Bush.
Dad,
they're all tied in this,
uh,
this family bloodline of bush goes back
to the guy they called dracula in this
dracula guy.
Would he,
would those people that would fight him
or that he's tied into a bloodline of
just deep war roots in that it goes all
the waY back to that.
But none of them are like rob ford,
rob ford still on top.
The toronto mayor guy.
According to the clinton chronicles man,
all the stuff that the media was,
there was a media blackout at all the
shit that he,
that he went through an Arkansas.
Jeez,
you've heard you've heard,
uh,
other shady shit around them.
I've always heard that that was a lot
about seals and the mena Arkansas.
But when you look into exactly what he
did and how it went down,
it's like a two hour documentary.
It's insane.
Bill clinton is,
according to this documentary,
the clinton chronicles,
he's a super cool kid.
Him and his brother rogers,
super coke heads.
they were.
They were the ones that were allowing
the coke to be dropped off from latin
America,
from columbia.
They drop it off.
Arkansas was the hub.
Mena Arkansas.
look that up.
Google,
mena,
Arkansas.
That's where it all came through.
Bill clinton let all of the coke come
through during the Iran contra thing.
They got busted doing this.
Ronald reagan.
And is there any evidence that he was a
coke head,
like saying that he's a coke head like
that dude.
According to this documentary,
according,
according to the documentary,
who was the documentary?
Biogen.
What's it called?
It's called the clinton chronicles.
Trust me on this one.
This will blow you the fuck away,
dude.
He had everybody on lock.
Dude.
Everybody.
All public officials.
You know what I love doing?
Those people that are the reason they're
in powerful positions because of their
decision making and some of the stuff
that I imagine that they have to do.
I mean you,
you read about like royalty and this
crazy stuff that they'll,
they'll do to kids for power and and all
this crazy stuff.
Man.
I like the bohemian grove type shit.
Yeah.
But there's even stuff like over in like
this in europe,
there's like this castle where they talk
about these like little kids that,
that they basically like do these crazy
axon,
almost like molestation for like their,
their power and like they're,
they're crazy.
Like an adrenaline.
Like when they skull and bones type
shit,
it just gets way.
De freemason type shit gets bizarre,
you know?
Do you ever do,
do google,
like when you see soMething like the
current and cargoes,
do you ever google the clinton
chronicles debunked?
I don't believe those doors.
You look at the wikipedia that there are
so many people paid to put up those
debunk websites.
I can't believe any of that shit.
I need to see the alternative media.
That stuff.
That's all the official story of this is
what the mainstream wants you to
believe.
I already doubt anything maInstream
sometimes.
Sometimes.
Sometimes it's facts though,
man.
You got to look at both sides.
There's a.
There's.
There's a lot of fact and the clinton
chronicles man,
there's some serious times caught it
discredited due to its weak
circumstantial evidence in coincidence.
Exactly.
That's of course they gotta.
We gotta host.
Awesome black helicopters.
Yeah.
Watch it.
Trust black helicopters if you believe.
man,
where does the documents?
It's insane,
man.
I mean,
have a document that's official stuff
like Washington post.
They're bought and sold.
Come on cnn.
They're and sold.
You can.
I'll show you the bitch.
Yeah,
some of them for sure.
There's definitely a lot of fuckery
going on.
Some of those things.
You know,
the problem with documentaries is almost
anybody can make a documentary about
mena Arkansas.
That shit went down.
I ran contra back down.
You're right about that,
but who knows whether or not he's
actually a cokehead.
I wonder if the dude's doing blow and
getting crazy and witness.
You know what I'm saying?
You know,
what I'm fascinated with right now is
there's so many ex cia agents come and
clean and talking man,
and there's a bunch of them.
Yeah.
Do you ever watch homeland?
No.
People are going to start dying and
great trades in car crashes and there's
a lot of deaths.
Man there happened in nine slash 11.
You,
you hear about like loose change and all
the other documentaries that we're
talking about.
Then they're like,
all of a sudden,
like,
this guy died in a fire at his house.
Chronicles is hard because anybody that
comes forward as a witness,
they all get their heads blown off and
then the corner put suicide.
She,
the sofa body after body after body.
People die.
Tila tequila.
Who's dating the johnson and johnson.
What happened is the girl,
the tila tequila,
uh,
she was dating,
you know,
like baby johnson,
the shampoo and stuff,
or she was doing her like her lesbian
thing with the daughter and the daughter
had ended up dying.
Well,
like tila,
tequila come out in this crazy,
uh,
youtube videos was talking about
illuminati.
It was in this.
People are trying to give me the
shutters on her.
No,
I don't.
I'm not for sure exactly what's out.
Anybody do anything but laugh.
They found out that if I was the
illuminati,
I would want to look tequila.
Talk about the illuminati.
I'd be like,
hey,
I send her a fucking dossier with
everything in it.
Everything we're doing at tell that
bitch to start our website.
He was doing a good job there.
She started doing that and then they
would go,
yeah,
yeah.
Tila tequila told you that.
Okay,
we're done here.
You just release all the truths and just
give it to tila tequila.
That's the way when she starts her show,
you'd be like,
what?
What tila tequila is edward snowden?
Tila tequila is julian and his size.
No,
it's fucking tila.
Tequila.
Stopped bitch.
you think?
Look there.
That's ridiculous.
That.
That's just crazy though.
Using her.
She's.
She's a pawn.
The documents,
they can find a better spokesperson for
tila.
Fucking tequila.
She went off tila.
Tequila are lovers let's.
Killers died seven times.
Sure.
She has to shut that off.
Stop.
Is that what it says?
Exactly.
Talking about,
you tried talking to neil tyson or you
know sam harris,
about what tIla tequila told you.
They'll fucking eyes to glaze over the
conversation he'd done in 10 minutes
stop and nothing wrong with tequila.
She's a very pretty girl.
Maybe she's got some good points.
My point is you could get they they.
Oh,
that's the thing about homeland
homelands and interesting show.
It's on showtime.
It's about cia.
I really enjoy it.
The fascinating.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's about the cia and fighting
terrorism and people turning terrorists
and soldiers turning on the government
look good.
No,
no.
It's a good show.
It's a really good show.
It's.
It shows how difficult the intelligence
businesses though,
and it shows how much they set things up
and they create fake stories and they
released fake stories to the news.
It's god damn fascinating.
Really.
That far?
Yeah.
Because when you watch It and you go,
huh,
I wonder what they actually do because
this is purely fiction,
so I wonder how much,
how much is actually going on,
how much is actual narrative,
how much they create,
but for sure they create.
Some of it for sure,
for sure.
If there's some shit going on and they
want to cover up operation mockingbird,
that's not a conspiracy theory.
How about operation midnight climax.
That's not a conspiracy.
No,
that's,
that's a fucking real thing that they
did with the fbi.
Put brothels in New York and san
francisco and they got people fucked up
on lsd when they thought they were going
to get a hooker and then they monitored
them and checked,
um,
did studies on them.
They,
they do.
They would go in and get the dick suck.
I'm tired of fucking my wife.
I'm tired of my life.
I'm tired of everything,
but I scraped up 200 bucks.
My wife doesn't know about it.
I'm going to sneak off this brothel and
I'm going to blow a lot.
It's going to be glorious and say,
would you like second a lot of baby
before we get started,
I'll tell you a glass of water that I
drink,
a little glass of water and all of a
sudden,
doo doo,
doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
The fucking guys in the suits come in
with a clipboard and the big glasses and
they're freaking the fuck out and asking
you questions,
and these poor guys,
man,
they they,
they did this for years and indeed
these,
these unbeknownst to them studies on
these dudes and it was after the
government couldn't do it anymore to
soldiers just like mine.
Mine warping them and figuring out their
mind.
First they were trying to figure out
what the fuck lsd did and for a long
time they thought lsd when Robert
Hoffman,
Albert Hoffman rather,
when Albert Hoffman created lsd.
Once the Intelligence community found
out about this incredibly potent
psychedelic drug for the western world,
it was one of the first psychedelics
have people aware of.
it wasn't until gordon watson discovered
the psychedelic mushroom,
that people knew that it existed in the
western world.
The information for what have you,
even though there's thousands and
thousands of years of use,
had kind of been lost to the modern
intellectual.
Well aCid came along by accident.
Albert hoffman discovered acid and then
the government initially when they found
out about thought that it was going to
be a truth serum,
they thought,
well,
we're going to do is we're going to get
these enemy guys.
We're going to give them acid and
they're just going to tell us everything
turned out didn't work that way.
It was just there were too fucked up.
They couldn't make any sense.
They were talking about butterflies
stealing their underwear and you know,
there were,
there were madness,
tripping,
tripping hard,
and by the way,
they didn't know what the doses were
like.
The way I've heard it described acid
biochemically,
it's a fascinating description,
but terrence mckenna said it best.
He said
acid is so strong and the dose is so
small that an aunt could destroy the
entire empire state building in 30
minutes.
Like that's literally how powerful acid
is per size per dose.
That and the analogy would be an aunt
destroying the empire state building in
30 minutes.
So it's,
it's so intensely powerful.
And they were given these people large
doses so they weren't getting any truth
out of them.
So then they thought about and said,
well maybe this is the opposite,
this is what we'll do.
We'll give it to our soldiers.
And tHen when they get captured we say,
hey,
pop this shit in your mouth to tell
anybody shit.
Yeah.
They would give them like a fucking,
like one of those juice boxes filled
with acid.
They would suck it down when they were
in the trenches and then no one would be
able to talk at all.
Yeah,
for sure.
Just mine warped.
Then mind warp to.
Well they did a lot of tests for sure on
people where they didn't know about
acid.
They did those.
They did a lot of tests on soldiers,
both United States and the arm.
The britiSh armed forces did that and
they also have the United States did
tests on unbeknown towns.
They did these clandestine operations
where they just,
they took this town in France and they
put acid in their bread,
you know,
and like people died.
Like people freaked out.
They did crazy shit.
I mean they,
they got like seriously dosed acid in
bread.
Yeah.
This ex cia agent talked about what he
did personally.
One of the,
one of the things that stuck out in his
head is in Cuba.
They would find,
uh,
the truck route to like elementary
schools,
hijack the truck,
filled the milk,
throw cement.
This is what he said.
He could be totally crazy in this
documentary and saying,
but he's saying he's an ex cia agent and
this is stuff that they wanted a cost
chaos.
They would infiltrate Cuba.
They wanted to,
they specifically targeted to blow up
bridges where they'd be women and
children.
So people would freak out.
They wanted as much cash as possible to
start a revolution.
And in the chaos that according to this
guy,
they would cause the cast and that's
when they would come in and take control
of the drugs and sell the arms to the
rebels.
Like that was the formula.
Whether it's a latin american country
like Nicaragua or wherever,
I mean El Salvador or wherever that was.
The plan is to go in there cause chaos
arm the rebels,
sell them arms and blow shit up,
blame it on the commies,
start a revolution.
Try to assassinate,
again,
according to the cia agents,
they're saying try to get the dictator,
assassinated,
and then the chaos.
They take control of all the drugs on
natural resources,
oil and uh,
and selling.
That's,
that's what the cia did according to
these guys.
That was the job master do it.
TheY do it in,
in asia,
they do it in latin America,
they do it in the middle east,
cause chaos.
they want the cast.
And then once the country's decimated
that,
once the economy collapses because of
all this chaos,
the international bankers come in,
boom,
and then they become the saviors.
They come in and save and then they,
they,
they put in their own dictate and
pulling out of control.
That whole country basically bankrupt
and then swoop
over.
So it makes sense,
right?
Like these gangsters and Arkansas with
the state,
this is not a conspiracy theory.
Went down with the Iran contra hearings.
They got busted.
Ronald reagan and george senior,
the head of the cia is the vice
president.
They get busted doing this and they know
Arkansas was whatever.
Bring it in.
And this is not a conspiracy theory,
this is exactly what happened.
So who was the governor of Arkansas
when,
when all this coat came through in the
eighties,
bill clinton,
he was the one letting it all happen.
And then who takes over as president
after george senior,
the head of the cia,
once he steps down after he invades
Iraq,
bill clinton is the president.
They're running together.
Bill clinton is hooking up george senior
by letting them use Arkansas and he
becomes the president.
And then you watch their debates,
you go to youtube and watched their
debate and they're talking about sending
jobs overseas and,
and uh,
and they're doing this with their hand,
like they got this thing,
man,
this is,
I don't know what this is,
but this must mean something to make a
point.
PresideNts really likes this.
Well,
you don't want to do this because this
is aggressive.
This is like,
you can trust me,
but you're not hitting anybody like
this.
Not a fighter.
I'm going to,
I'm going to lower taxes and we're going
to create more jobs stamp on.
You hear them talking about this.
Sometimes you can gently do this.
Yeah,
and knowing,
knowing that their main Business is.
Bill clinton was hooking up george
singer knowing this and then now they're
talking about the fucking balancing the
budget.
It's hysterical.
It is like pro wrestling.
It's like their buddies behind the
scene,
but on camera they're pretending like
they're enemies,
but it's insane conspiracy story.
He was a cia agent,
1951 in France.
Suddenly,
mysteriously people struck down with
mass insanity and hallucinations.
At least five people died.
Dozens were interned in asylums and
hundreds of flicked it.
That's the facts.
And it was assumed that the local bread
had been unwittingly poisoned with a
psychedelic mold,
which happens.
And that's what they're saying was
responsible for the salem witch trials.
They said the salem witch trials,
they've,
they've narrowed it down to,
um,
apparently when there's an early frost,
when you have a wheat harvest,
early frost can trigger the growth of
god.
Or god is a type of fungus that grows on
wheat that has many of the same
qualities as lsd.
So when you consume this bread with this
[inaudible] got a wheat that has this or
god in it,
you trip your fucking brains out
naturally,
naturally in a scary way because you
imagine taking massive doses of acid in
your brand.
Even back then when your children are
tripping out,
your children are freaking out.
Everyone thinks everyone's haunted and
they just start drowning witches.
They're like,
you know,
that's insane.
Or something like that.
Netflix about salem witch trials.
So it was crazy.
We got a lot of people just thought that
they were being thrown under a spell,
know they,
they literally didn't realize what was
going on.
So this,
they had blamed this shit on earth until
and now they,
they believe that what's going on was
that the cia had cia documents that,
uh,
this guy found while investigating this
suspicious suicide of a man named Frank
Olson,
who is a biochemist working for the sod,
fell from the 13th floor window two
years after the curse bread incident in
France.
And one onenote transcribes the
conversation between the cia agent and a
sandoz official.
Santos is the people that eventuallY
started producing in mass quantities,
lsd.
They,
uh,
mentIoned the secret point st a esprit
experiment,
a point esprit st [inaudible] was where
this all went down.
So they had mentioned it in a memo and
explained that it was not at all caused
by mold,
but by diane hamid that d and lsd said
they had,
they had injected this shit into this
town's bread supply just to watch it,
just to sort of,
just to absorb what happens when you get
a whole town on acid in 1951.
They dIdn't know any,
you know,
they didn't really have all the data in
1951.
It is.
I don't know anything about that,
but you're telling me that it's like
they're fucking criminals.
Yeah.
Well,
some of them were,
some of them are,
you know,
some of them back then.
The,
my hope for real is that the internet
provides such an access to information,
such a,
uh,
a boundary dissolving thing between
people and the truth that anything that
happens from now to the future or from,
you know,
five years from now in the future,
everyone will be so accountable for
their actions because it'll be so
obvious and clear that they just won't
be able to run things.
Businesses usual,
the corruption will slowly morphed down
to a very reasonable level because it'll
all be transparent.
Yeah.
Like I remember,
you know,
there's so many different conspiracy
theories and,
and,
and you just don't have time to really
look into them all.
And I remember you being really into jfk
and I never really spent that much time.
It just seemed like when someone would
tell me that was,
it was an inside job,
I just knowing what these criminals do
and they're like,
okay,
I believe,
but I just haven't looked into it.
But recently,
just recently I've been obsessed with
the jfk case.
It's amazing,
man.
To think,
to think that all the stuff that I did
spend time in,
that it's all connected all from world
war ii,
prescott bush,
george singer,
jfk,
nixon,
all the way up to george senior becoming
vice president,
ronald reagan,
bill clinton,
bam,
george w.
How dId that happen?
And then obama,
all of it is all connected and it all
has cii running right through it.
Part of the average person on the
ultimate,
the underground right now.
Go ahead.
What the fuck are they talking about?
Conspiracy theories where Jeremy Stevens
on the pod training and diet and
nutrition.
We do what we want to hear about this
stuff
man,
because honestly if it opens up a lot of
people's eyes to really stuff that's
going on and you bring up a lot of good
points,
like why aren't we seeing documents like
that in school that says,
you know,
george senior was cia type stuff and
some of these events that were
pretty much history.
I mean he was the head of the cia.
That's,
that's history george sr.
That alone is.
It's again,
that's not a conspiracy theory history.
That's insane.
Well,
way more disturbing George Bush,
but that's not,
that's kind of disturbing,
but George Bush senior being ahead of
the cia's and natural progression going
from one big top office to another kind
of makes sense.
What doesn't make sense at all?
And it's really scary is the dick cheney
halliburton connection.
The fact that dick cheney was the ceo of
halliburton.
He leaves.
Halliburton becomes a vice president.
I had states.
Then halliburton starts getting these no
bid contracts to rebuild Iraq.
I mean these huge multibillion dollar
con,
these contracts to rebuild Iraq,
a war that dick cheney's trying to get
us into.
That's the tip of the iceberg.
To think that that's only happening
because of george senior.
When ronald reagan got busted,
they got busted wide open selling arms
to the contracts.
They got busted in all the coke and
nobody went to jail.
You think that stuff's going down over
north?
Took the oliver north,
I think.
I think that stuff is me.
I live.
I live close right down.
I mean,
I lived in vista and uh,
chula vista,
you know,
it's real close to the alliance chat,
but it's basically a true lawana and
when you go down there and then like you
hear all these crazy like homeland
stories about decide these drug cartels,
this net selling guns where they're
getting these guns from in chula vista,
no one hunt chula vista in Mexico.
They're getting like an american guns
and,
and they're able to like,
you know,
basically like go down there and come
back up here.
Then they have like state stash houses
and just like all this crazy stuff that
goes on that,
you know,
you don't really think about what's
going on right here in America too.
Ross,
he was on your show.
He was saying that.
Yeah,
I remember being 22 and some and I
worked with a couple mexican gang banger
type dudes and we're deep in,
in,
in uh,
in the hood and mexican mafia.
And I remember them saying,
oh,
you think you don't think the government
brings in the drugs?
I Was like,
the government brings it.
I go,
you can you think we got airplanes?
How do you think the drugs get it?
And they looked at each other and
laughed like I didn't know.
And I go,
you guys are insane.
The government brings the drugs in,
are you crazy?
And,
and,
uh,
it turns out that that's real.
And that's not a conspiracy theory
that's documented.
You see that tunnel that they found
recently in san diego that goes all the
way to Mexico.
Super sophisticated.
The one electricity,
white lighting,
air conditioning,
hiring a new one.
They found many of these tunnels.
Yeah,
go to big corporations or place where
they can just pick up the drugs and all
this stuff.
This stuff goes down.
It's insane.
You live in san diego.
What is it like in san diego being so
close to Mexico being there?
It
honestly,
you don't even knoW the difference to
you go over there.
It's like we're over here paying for
like this crazy market.
It's like
100 bucks.
You go to downtown san diego,
you go 30 minutes into,
into tiawana.
You get the best fish your life for just
dollars,
you know?
So it's,
it's a lot cheaper.
But you know,
the,
the culture is way different.
There's a lot of different things.
Like san diego has a way laid back vibe.
Everybody's cool.
It's like nothing going on.
But realize that like a half hour away,
there's shootings every day that's going
down and just their buildings look a
little a lot more ghetto and just the
way they live,
you almost when you go back and you have
that type of experience being over
there,
you almost just appreciate going into a
clean neighborhood,
you know,
driving by.
That makes sense.
What is it like being that close?
You never think about it.
Do you ever hear about it?
Spilling over.
You hear about kidnappings,
you hear about,
you hear a lot,
you hear a lot of stuff,
you know.
And then like sometimes there's like
helicopters flying,
like have you seen this guy?
Whatever,
blah blah blah blah blah.
So kidnappings because it's easy to get
back into Mexico.
Yeah.
Getting back into Mexico is like human
trafficking in drugs that you know,
people that are stuff that people are
making movies on and making millioNs of
dollars,
you know,
that's,
that's all cool.
But that stuff really goes down.
You know,
there's a big war on drugs and,
and like you said that,
you know,
you hear about people like governments
funding and this and stuff.
I mean where do you think they're
getting these type of guns in this type
of muscle?
Because the drug cartel will basically,
they'll,
they'll buy,
they'll buy like say like say joe rogan.
You're,
you're like an army general guy and you
know,
you know,
some secret stuff on weapons and you're
only getting paid $100 a week to feed
your family and they're like,
tell you what,
we're going to pay you $100,000.
We're going to put you and your family
and in a,
in a house,
whatever.
but if you mess up or if you do anything
wrong will kill you.
Your whole family.
And then some,
you know,
so they'll,
they'll take like head corporate people
that know how to build like a,
they'll building submarines,
they'll get these people in the jungle
that know how to build this stuff and
then they'll submarine hundreds and
millions of dollars of drug cartel and
it's,
it's insane.
You know,
and this stuff actually goes down.
I wonder if.
Can you imagine if there was like a map
I can overlay of the United States.
We could just theoretically watch like a
highlight of all the cocaine both
come in on daily basis,
but there's a big shipment right there,
joe.
As crazy as that is
forcement couldn't see it.
But you can see it.
law enforcement gets paid off,
not see it or they do are they?
Well,
it's crazy as that is and that all does
exist.
All these cartels are real according to
these ex cia agents and all the stuff
that was going on in mena,
that's a small,
tiny fraction compared to what the cia
is dumping.
And they're bringing in giant fucking
military planes filled with tons and
tons of coke and the,
the,
the carton.
Then every now and then they'll bust a
little cartel,
put it on the news and say,
look,
we're,
we're doing our best to stop this.
Watch the lord,
lord
of the skies,
that documentary,
like you're talking,
I'm going to go home and watch that
clinton chronicles.
But,
uh,
I'm not for sure the spanish word of it,
but a checkout the lord of the skies.
That guy was that he was the most
biggest powerful drug dealer.
And uh,
there's another guy down there right now
that's a,
that's coming up,
but no one says that there's anybody
like this guy.
They called the lord of the sky.
This guy barry seal,
sky funded the whole government and the
government was protecting
them.
He was buYing police.
That's gotta be barry seal's.
He's the,
he's the most famous biggest.
You're talking about a guy that's the
live now?
No,
he's dead.
I guess like,
he came over here for surgery,
like in san diego and was into plastic
surgery to,
to change his life,
look like.
He's like Iran type crazy stuff.
And uh,
he died during the surgery that
supposedly.
But then there's like comparisons,
conspiracy theorists that are like,
no,
he didn't die.
He escaped.
You know,
because I'm sure you heard of el chapo
guzman who escaped from a high security
prison,
escaped and quotes escaped a high
security.
You got billions of dollars,
man.
Billions.
And then that.
That's funny.
Have you seen the documentary,
the two escobars?
no,
I haven't got to see the two escobars,
one of the greatest documentary bro.
Fucking glory.
You see how he picks up when you're
talking about conspiracy theories about
pablo escobar,
but this is not.
It has nothing to do.
Conspiracy.
This is one of the biggest drug lords
ever.
Pablo escobar.
And it's about him and how he got
involved with soccer and columbia and
how he,
he'll,
he almost became political,
but then there was a backlash of the
things that he was doing because they
loved him like a god down there.
Like he was feeding The poor.
Like he was doing this crazy stuff with
like his,
his drug money.
But he just didn't want anybody messing
with his family.
But he was feeding the poor.
He was doing so much for politics.
Well,
there was a lot of killing going on,
which,
which is involved in drugs,
you know,
a lot of families were dying so then
there was a big retaliation toward him
and the things that were going on.
So then like the politics,
like cut them off.
I was like,
well we can't be associated with that.
Not not like if people know you like
this,
so two weeks in a month.
That's it right there.
Yeah.
What he did,
what he did was alert is a.
They wanted,
he was,
you know,
obviously he was helping the poor and he
was building houses and he was really
into soccer building,
little soccer field all over the ghettos
and he raised a bad,
a bad ass soccer players.
That's why columbia ended up going to
the world cup because he raised them all
the,
all the guys on the colombian soccer
team that made it to the world cup.
This I think was 93.
They're like,
why is pablo escobar in the audience?
Why does he have like vip?
No one really knew that.
I just thought it was just they,
when you looked into it,
he knew all those guys.
He raised Them up as kids.
He was really super into soccer.
You ever had anybody try to get you to
dump a fight?
And pablo escobar type gangster dude.
I bet a lot of money because I was like,
I'm always into like,
you know,
conspiracies.
I watched your stuff and,
and I always liked his pick and choose
and like I get into stuff like that.
But one thing that's always interested
me and I've never been involved in it
was just drugs,
drug cartels.
I actually,
you know,
I grew up from a family where were,
there's a drug problem in the household
and which is the reason why like I,
you know,
I kind of live porn in the ghetto and
stuff like that.
So then when I hear about these Drug
cartels and these big billionaires that
just come from nothing,
these guys come from like you'll hear
her talking about being poor,
helping their parents,
parents farm and they never wanted to
live like that.
They wanted to live large and they had
these dreams of just envisioning this,
ah,
this stuff.
And they're on their way up,
you know,
they
got to do some crazy things to get,
you know,
heavy wears the crown they say.
So it's crazy.
Some of the,
some of their stories and interesting
facts and,
and I,
I kinda like it,
you know,
so
yeah,
they wanted to the us one or to
extradite him and throw him in jail in
the states for all the shit he was
doing.
And uh,
pablo escobar went to the government and
said,
I want you,
if you rewrite the constitution or
rewrite the law that says you cannot be
extradited,
I will go to prison here.
I will,
you,
you can have me in prison and build own.
And then they said,
fuck that.
And they,
they,
uh,
they thought he killed a lot of
politicians.
I was like,
wars on the street.
And there was so much bloodshed that
they finally said,
okay,
we are changing the god damn law.
We,
you know,
now go to jail.
So he goes to the jail.
And meanwhile,
that whole time he built the jail,
he set it up,
he had nightclubs in their tunnels to
escape.
They had no idea that he went to his own
jail.
He was part,
he was leaving anytime he wanted.
This is all in the documentary.
So when they finally figured it out
because they took it,
they uh,
arrested his rival rival drug cartel,
they send them into prison and he was
right there in his own prison.
So they murdered them.
So once they find out that they figured
out the,
oh shit,
he's running this jail.
They went there and he was gone.
Dude,
he had escaped tunnels to get a
nightclub there.
He had his soccer fields.
They,
they,
uh,
you know,
he ended up dying later,
but they chased them down.
Right.
And killed him.
Assassinated him.
Yeah.
Apparently columbia's awesome now.
Apparently columbia,
like the drug problems,
like a thing of the past.
It's like a nice safe place to be.
It's interesting,
man.
Columbia,
it's crazy.
Yeah.
It's interesting how that,
that can have a hot box out there.
10 planet budding kia.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Those guys are savages.
Isn't it interesting that,
you know,
places can go and come and I wonder what
the fuck's going to happen in the
future?
Mexico,
because when I was a kid,
man,
Mexico was a bad ass place to be.
Yeah,
you could go over there a lot easier to
go to cancun.
People always want to cancun.
Everybody need never heard anything
about violence in Mexico.
Mexico was like a nice chill place.
He thought of people with fucking
margarita is chilling on the beach,
you know,
he didn't think of dudes.
Cut and do the heads off.
I was worried.
Beautiful places like not saying that
it's like bad,
you know,
bad or you know,
Mexico has some pretty cool ancient
stuff like over there with like line up
with the stars,
you know.
So I'm noT dogging on Mexico by any
means.
Mexico,
they,
they're very humble people.
You ever noticed that?
Mexican people always take care of you.
You can.
You know,
you go to a mexican families house,
you know you're eating good food there.
Their manners and others are trying to
take care of your family or a quarter
mexican.
I'm a quarter mexican,
my girls 100 percent mexican come
from a mexican background.
Nice.
Yeah.
I love it.
And they take care of me.
Great mexican fighters,
man.
You want to talk about one nationality
that has produced incredible boxers.
pretty good.
Fuck yeah.
He looked great.
he looked like he's improving for sure.
Cain velasquez,
do you know that?
Do it well.
My mother was born in America son.
Finally we got a mexican heavyweight
boxing american born here,
a cello favorite.
Taylor
refined them.
He turned to him pretty good.
I imagine about being a director.
Tell,
so
I don't think he would mind knowing what
kind of a beating he's going to give
child the end of it.
Cain valasquez would do in boxing.
Oh,
who knows?
I mean he would have to get really good
at it.
You know,
there's a.
There's a big difference between a guy
like,
like let's say andre ward.
See andre ward's fight this weekend.
He fought this dude who was a serious
knockout.
Punch her,
I forget the guy's name,
but a andre words.
just box circles around them and it just
cracked him.
Hit him with some big shots,
you know,
like basically dominated him,
but this guy was a bad ass fucking boxer
and he's a really high level box guy.
Was undefeated,
a big knockout record.
Just a big difference between a guy
who's a guy that's good at boxing and
mma when there's all these other
techniques,
especially guys like king is such a
great wrestler.
I mean his name is all about
transitioning from striking the take
down,
take down,
striking meaningful.
If a boxer wanted to fight him and then
maybe he would kill him,
kill him,
but he would have to really absorb the
game of boxing to compete as a box.
Has the best chance to be came to.
And that's fine.
No man,
I don't know.
He's been knocked out.
I think travis browne coming up.
Yeah.
Try like travis scott and josh.
Josh barnett,
catch them with the submission or
something that would be a guy that,
that uh,
would eventually,
you know what josh can take came down.
Who knows my most likely no,
I don't know,
but I think that would be good range and
be able to.
Russell and russell,
I'm off them.
Then maybe take them down.
Who knows what josh barnett is gonna
show up,
you know this guy,
this guy,
you know,
he's.
He's dealt with a lot of past stuff,
but I think when you get back in the
ufc,
especially not this time,
I think he might be rejuvenated in this
fight with travis browne is a huge
fight.
Travis browne is definitely young talent
to do it on his way up.
He's hungry.
I know he's working hard,
so these two are really going to set the
standard.
Who,
who wants to take It to that next level
and go up there and challenge came for
that belt.
so great fucking fight,
man.
Huge freshly coming off your foster.
Let me tell you something,
man.
There's not a lot of heavyweights on the
planet.
They have stood that beating that he
took in that first round from
just insane doodles,
but I forgot.
I need like that bro.
I just give me a second.
His knees are so much harder than
everybody else's.
He throws him so different.
Unlike anybody.
He's like one tuesday and then just
bombard you with this knee.
The ruthless.
It's crazy.
It's like getting hit over and over
again with a battery graham.
But somehow or another travis browne
gutted through that shit.
Literally got it through it.
He's amazing.
Yeah.
They got up in front,
kicked him in the face and the same
round.
I mean crazy.
You know what man,
if you get kicked in the face one time
you'd be like,
okay,
you got me.
I'm,
I'm still a lot,
you know,
if you're still conscious.
But he kicked him in the face like two,
three times and he was just leaning
toward it,
you know?
I was like,
don't move.
Just shot his wife.
He just,
the snap kicks to the chest into the
jaw.
That ain't no joke.
You see,
you're seeing them a lot.
You didn't see them two
years ago.
How about all,
are you throwing those snapchat
and his last fight and try to throw them
at me and I was push and I was like,
hold up.
You know,
like they're,
they're deceiving because like all of a
sudden this guy,
I normally look at the chest when I
fight because I can,
I can tell where his hips are going to
be.
I could see his base and I can see his
feet and I could see where his hands are
lined up so I know I want to keep like
good range,
but those,
those kicks,
they're deceiving because you got to
raise them with like your knee,
so it's like your elbow going through
first to hit like a baseball.
So the elbow always leads just like the
knees so the knee pops up.
You don't know if he's still in like a,
like maybe a fake back knee,
but it happened so quick and it pops
right in your face
quick.
It's amazing that we've gone this long
in the ufc and we just figured out this
old basic ass karate party is actually
really useful.
We're nobody practiced it.
Nobody bad.
And then they,
jim after mma gym was.
They're striking coaches telling their
students not to throw those.
Oh,
those don't work time after time we see
how much of a follow the leader thing is
going on in mma because a guy like
anderson lands that front kick and
knocks out vittorio and the whole sport
changes like overnight.
Everyone's thrown in front.
Josh thompson storing them like a
motherfucker.
Anthony pettis is throwing crazy kicks.
Crazy knees like I do.
I think.
I think we know now that all these crazy
kicks do work.
You just got to have good balance and
good wrestling and you got to make sure
that if you get taken down that you can
pop right back up or you have good,
good.
You just said the only reason they
weren't working because the only people
that knew how to throw all of them
didn't know how to fight on the ground.
so we went through a dark period where
we have to take away these,
these techniques going to disappear for
awhile until the wrestling and the
striking merge as one.
It's just so interesting to see these
guys that are coming up that are
throwing these games,
throwing these techniques at people that
you never saw like [inaudible] landon
that we'll kick on.
Luke rockhold do.
They're throwing.
We'll kicks all the time.
I guess like a jab.
It's good even in my stryker,
but in my opinion,
it just seems that if you at least throw
me,
even though the heartland sometimes,
but you throw them,
it takes a guy off his game was like,
oh,
this guy's willing to throw these
motherfuckers.
See jorge mosby doll and rostom tom
hobby lobby.
I saw the fight.
Don't remember it.
Hobby live.
We'll kicked him in the neck like out of
nowhere.
Near hobby.
Lava.
Rock them though have been badly hurt.
Take it man.
But he caught him in the neck with a
wheel kick like out of nowhere.
And uh,
nowhere like straight grappler.
That's what catches him as people.
People willing to take the risks.
A lot of people have a lot of good
arsenals,
like in their tools,
but they're like in the fight,
man.
They'll just stick to the basics.
Are not willing to risk it,
but those people that when somebody
throws something spinning at you,
you almost like look at him like,
all right bro,
this guy wants to risk everything.
Okay,
I like that.
Let's get after it.
You know you're willing to
throw down like,
okay,
this guy's willing to risk risk trying
to knock me out and I've got a risk risk
something,
but if you just sit back and let it
happen,
you're not really taking any risks.
You're not really getting any reward
either.
One thing I want to say about gsp is
yes,
I think.
I think he lost and yes
it was a bad decision.
Just look at his face,
but I admired gsp for going forward,
sticking to his game plan.
He was throwing down the whole time he
was going forward.
He got rocked and he backed up a little
bit,
but generally in that fight he was stone
head kicks like a motherfucker.
He was throwing big right hand.
He was.
He's a true warrior,
ms dot proud champion.
It seemed,
it seemed like in the.
It really seemed like after the first
round,
he already started gassing,
but he was breathing really heavy,
but he kept going forward.
You hit hard.
Yeah.
I've kind of felt bad for him in the,
in the press conference,
you know,
there's no taken away gsp that he's not,
he's not a gamer,
that he's,
he's willing to do what it takes.
And uh,
he,
he almost seemed like he's just like,
man,
you know,
he doesn't really care.
He's just like,
man,
I just,
I left it all out there for you guys.
Like,
what do you want me to do?
Oh,
you knoW,
I'm not,
I'm not a judge.
I'm a fighter.
I went in there and do this dude who
Johnny Hendricks is throw some serious
bricks is hitting me in the freaking
face.
Of course,
you know,
but he,
he did,
he did fight through and he did.
He did finish the fight.
He didn't,
he didn't give up.
I didn't need it.
Is that bob?
You man,
there's a lot of insensitivity in how
people view fights and fighters after
fights happen.
I mean,
I've seen guys come.
I,
I've seen guys come up to people and say
rude shit to them.
Like,
what happened man?
Why'd you get knocked out?
like I've seen guys say that and it's
just like rashad evans was talking about
some dude who came up to him at an
autograph signing and try to get him to
autograph a picture of him.
You know,
that famous picture of him after machida
knocked him out.
He got stuck in his face like smile and
laugh and they make you autograph this
and you know,
rashad crumpled it up and tell him to
get the fuck out of here.
Like rudeness and not respecting the
fact that this guy,
they think that it's because he gets
paid for it.
He should be able to deal with your
douche.
Baggery a man,
he's a public guy.
Isn't a public guy.
Classless attitude,
man.
That this is horrible.
Well,
sports fans are used to talking shit
about athletes.
They've always done it with baseball
players.
They've always done it with football
That's a big part of a basketball games.
People behind this,
the basket talking shit to the player
while he's shooting a three pointer,
you know,
talking shit wise on the free throw
line,
given them those fucking things like
blocking them in front of his face.
I think that's.
It is kind of funny,
but there's a difference.
They need to understand and appreciate
the difference between the loss in that
sport.
That's a shitty feeling to lose a
basketball game and I lost an mma fight
which is a life changing proposition now
you're in a completely different
categories as far as your expectations
for your future.
You have to rebuild.
you have to.
I really,
really think like the other day when I
actually was in the float lab and
actually by the way I got some shirts
for in the car.
Did you like that?
That was amazing.
You're talking about this journey that
people deal with,
like people use a lot of meditation and
I thought that float lab just like I
just re redid all my finances.
I just redid my whole life.
Then I just took.
I just went on this freaking trip where
I was just.
I felt like something was pulling me out
of things and I was like,
I was just dealing with so much out of
there,
you know,
like mentally and are distinct that
some,
some people you know,
like when you get setbacks like that,
some people dig deep and come through
some,
some groundbreaking news like in their,
in their mind where they'll,
they'll,
they'll change,
but then some people just stick to that
pattern,
ended up falling off,
you know?
Yeah.
Well there's the reality of self
examination is that you don't always
like what you see and you can either
change it or you could just ignore it
because it's too much work and you get
tired or you get into that sort of
deflecting mindset with fetus,
the fetus,
elitist attitude.
And a lot of alcoholics get that.
They just keep getting back on the wagon
or they keep getting back drank and they
can't help it.
That,
that happens all the time.
They just,
they can't,
they're not strong enough to pull,
pull through and it's too much work.
It's hard,
you know.
And the thing is,
it's 80 percent mental and 20 percent
physical.
I really think that you have to have
your mindset to the top peak if you're,
if you're going to compete and do stuff
like that,
because if you're going in there with
like a,
uh,
you know,
maybe something going on right at home
or you know,
just anything,
maybe the family members die,
maybe just something ain't going right
and you go into a fight,
you know,
that,
that wears and tears on you mentally.
And it's mentally taxing.
Been the toughest fight for you to go
into because you've gotten into fights
with like legal issues hanging over your
head.
You've gotten into fights with a lot of
bullshit going on with that.
That'd probably be the other part of it.
In what the eaves edwards fight,
which is where I got clipped.
And I was like,
I told you before,
I was like,
man,
I feel like a,
like a young,
like young specimen and,
you know,
I can take anything,
whatever.
And uh,
you know,
in the gym I was actually working on my
athleticism.
I was feeling a lot more better,
I was a lot lighter on my feet and then
when I went to that fight all stressed
out,
I felt like the old me,
I was just all drugged up.
I was tight,
I was just going for it.
And there was just really no excuses.
That's my style of fighting is a,
is uh,
I'm willing to risk it to get,
uh,
you know,
I want to make bank bro,
and uh,
and I was going into that fight,
but it's not a clear head.
I didn't have my head on my shoulders
and I was just gunning for it,
you know,
I needed the money.
Like I just felt like I just got robbed
of so much.
I got robbed in my freedom.
I got robbed them,
like my,
my kids putting food on the table for my
kids.
I was like,
man,
this isn't right.
You know,
you,
you had some sort of illegal situation
where somebody accused of assault and
it was just someone accused me of
basically just assaulting them and
beating them like real bad,
I guess.
Like the person had like stopped
breathing,
but the,
are they missing identity or a mistaken
identity case?
No,
it was just a classic fact that I had
through an after party at like a smaller
bar.
And to be honest,
I didn't even see a fight break out in a
fight had broken out and it carried on
outside.
And uh,
there was,
uh,
there was a miscommunication was with
people I guess,
like the bar owner was trying to kick
this drunk guy out who from what I know
he was at the bar.
He got kicked away from the bar and he's
like,
give me my credit card.
And he's just being disrespectful,
groping on women,
you know,
just being obnoxious,
drunk guy needed to go home and just
take a chill pill.
Will keep in mind this guys like in the,
in the army,
you know,
he,
he's,
he's like a,
somebody you think that you would look
up to or had some of respect and uh,
he just gets,
gets drunk.
Basically.
The bartender kicks him out and then he
ends up like kicking the owner and the
nuts for trying to get them out,
punch some dude actually.
And the dude had hit him back and like
self defense than he had kicked the
owner and the knots gets,
gets thrown out.
So they're like,
hey man,
this is like a private party.
You got,
you got to leave.
He starts,
he starts getting into it with another
guy and then that's when it happened to
be my after party from,
from a fight that I had and that's where
my name had got got brought up.
And I was actually uh,
I actually called down to the police
station the next day was like,
hey,
I heard you guys were looking for me,
like,
what's going on?
You know?
And uh,
my,
my management team was there.
He actually seen the fight and he knew
he knew a lot about what was going on.
So we were just like being proactive.
So you didn't have anything to do with
it at all?
No,
nothing at all.
I didn't even see a fight even break out
or the fact that the dude got knocked
the fuck out and he thought you did it.
He got,
I guess he got beat bad.
And like then people were like
mentioning my name.
It was my party and the guy who actually
did it turned himself in to the police.
Oh,
what a trip.
So I ended up getting in trouble like a,
almost a year later for something I
completely didn't do and I was actually
in des moines and was calling down to
see if I needed to be questioned.
They're like,
oh no,
there's nothing to be questioned here.
So it was just something that you were
on the hook for for awhile that you had
nothing to do with.
Nothing to do with cost you a shit load
of money in legal fees and just a lot of
mental stuff.
And now that I look back at it,
it's crazy.
I'm a lot stronger of a person from it,
you know,
I,
I really watch who I'm hanging out with.
No,
I don't go out,
you know,
I mean,
I have kids,
you know,
there's a time to have a serious fucking
career now too,
man.
I mean,
they're highly ranked.
That honey jason knockout was a big wake
up call for a lot of people in 145
pounds.
Thanks man.
I've had two fights there now.
Yeah,
I'm,
I'm a discredit to my coaches,
man.
My,
my team,
my family.
Thanks for ufc and dana wife who really
believe in believe in me.
And I was just like,
man,
I had nothing to do with this dude,
you know,
like I,
and I just got,
I just got robbed the so much,
but that didn't,
that didn't define me as a person to
person that I was becoming in the gym
and uh,
you know,
it's just going to show now.
Now's the right time.
I think everything's really connected in
my career,
thanks to my coaches and,
and everybody's so support me,
I think.
I think right now I'm really starting to
grow because,
you know,
when,
when I first seen you,
I was,
I was just turned 21 in the ufc and I
really kinda grew up inside the ufc and
fought guys that I probably shouldn't
have been fighting that or it didn't
really have a chance and I'd go out and
I'd win,
you know,
so I had a young career,
when I was 22 years old,
I had like $100,000
in my bank account.
I didn't even know what to do with it.
I was just enjoying myself.
You did the smart thing,
man,
you realize that you have potential and
you went down to a serious jim,
you know,
alliance san diego without a doubt is
one of the best gyms in the country's
excellent move.
The,
the perfect thing for you to do and
look,
it's,
it's a beautiful thing to see,
right?
Yeah.
Work and reaping the reward.
Go feral man.
He's the man dude.
He's like a.
He's almost like a sports psychologist.
He just really knows how to click with
me and knows what to say.
How to work with me and I was looking
for that for like the longest time when
I was traveling,
I'd went to Florida with hermes and it
had some run ins with some bad
management and like I was getting
screwed over there,
so just didn't really have the right
people around me at the time.
And I was just searching for somebody
just to grab a hold of me in this mold
me into something,
you know,
I knew I had all the,
all the skills and talent.
I just needed that type of coach.
And I think I've really found that with
coach eric del faro,
man,
that guy,
he's a,
he's creating a monster and I love where
he's going.
What's next for you now?
Who he fight next?
Because I know that there was going to
be a quick turnaround because your fight
was quick.
Yeah,
fight was quick.
I'm healthy as a personal goal of mine
to uh,
to get in there and get after it,
get a huge win.
And uh,
I'd set some goals for myself,
you know,
I see them everyday.
They're hung up on my door and this is
one of my goals.
I'm going back close to my hometown,
which is a chicago January 25th lane.
Josh thompson,
benson henderson is on that card and uh,
my,
my hometown's is right next door and
this is a real huge fight for me.
I'm fine.
Oh,
I'm finding a darren.
Darren elkins.
That's good.
Fight.
Yeah.
He's,
he's,
he's a tough wrestler.
he's from the midwest guy and uh,
I really just think that I have all the
skills to beat him.
I'm just gonna.
Keep this ball steamrolling.
Nice.
Think is going to try to take you down.
Yeah,
I think so.
I think elkins is tough as fuck dude.
He banks with everybody.
He does.
He does,
but he also,
he's very smart.
He utilizes his wrestling.
He's a,
he's got good,
good ground and pound.
He's lengthy.
Knows how to use his range,
but I see a few holes in his game.
Man.
It's gonna be a great fight.
It's going to be a fun fight and I think
he'll,
he'll bring out a lot of viciousness in
me by,
by his attacks.
Yeah,
I Think that's going to be an awesome
fucking fight and that card is sick.
I love that.
Benson henderson,
josh thompson fight.
I like the fact that josh thompson,
even though he's in life for a title,
you know the champ gets her and he's
like,
who else?
I like that.
I liked that about fighters,
man.
I don't,
I don't believe in waiting around
mendez.
Go ahead and just prove kenny florian.
I actually,
somebody I actually looked up to a long
time ago,
he was just beating these guys.
They're like,
man,
Florida,
what's next?
TItle shot?
And he's like,
no man,
you know,
I just like,
I just tell you what he's like,
just bring,
bring me whoever.
He's like,
oh,
I'll beat anybody from top to bottom
just to prove that I deserve this title
shot.
And he's like,
I just want everybody to know that.
And I was just like,
what a piece,
you know?
Yeah,
I love.
I love the fact that thompson is coming
into his own,
as you know,
after a long history of being in the
fight game,
but he's as good as it's ever been.
That fight against nate diaz was
fantastic and his fights in strikeforce
with gilbert were fantastic before then.
He's really improved as
he's always been an athlete,
you know,
even back when they cut the ufc,
he was fighting eaves,
you know,
he ended up getting a vicious kick,
he's throwing to backfill and is getting
caught,
but he's had a long,
good,
successful career and he's very
athletic,
very skilled and he's like really coming
into his prime right now.
Yeah,
he's been around for a long time,
man.
He's like true,
true vet,
but a real smart,
skilled,
very skilled,
smart.
He does a lot of sneaky shit.
Those trickery,
trickery of those trips that he hit
gilbert with,
I loved those.
He grabbed your neck and trips you and
shit.
He does a lot of weird shit
and then he'll start.
He'll,
he'll,
he'll do.
He'll do like a take down and right away
he'll pop up just to strike and throw
elbows at you.
If he's really interesting to watch.
He's,
he's,
he's a fun guy to watch.
He's real.
He's real active at 55.
Yeah.
He's such a good fucking way.
Class men 55 or so,
some crazy.
There's so many good fucking talent
filled weight classes now.
Five stack,
30th five stacked.
I was impressed.
You know,
it's like a josh thompson,
rashad evans,
all these guys.
They're like wood that he went right
through jail.
Man.
That was a different.
It was a different.
Rashad,
I think he's on a different level.
We got to wrap this up.
Unfortunately,
we're almost out of time at three hours
were run out of gas.
We turn into a pumpkin.
Ustream can't handle recording.
It's one three hours long for whatever
reason.
My point is a real quick robbie lawler,
another one.
All of a sudden he's.
He looks vicious,
man.
He's throwing kicks now.
Like,
holy shit.
He's just sticking it out.
They just keep sticking out.
Keep grinding.
It takes years to get your striking
together.
It takes years and a lot of fighters
quit before they're striking gets down,
so just focus and maturity and really
putting in the side of the octagon.
Him and even diaz diaz was like,
what?
18,
when he found lawler and rory macdonald,
end of the fight on top elbowing robbie,
so props to Roy Mcdonald to shit.
It was a great fight.
Alright,
Jeremy Stevens.
We got to do this again.
Yeah.
Thank you guys,
man.
I really appreciate it.
We are in la,
man.
Let's do it again.
It's a lot of fun.
Let me go get this wind man.
I'm like nine and a half weeks out from
a camp right now,
so I'm gonna.
Go back and then I'm going to skin and
enjoy myself.
Man.
It's gonna.
Be fun for all your success,
man.
You've been really doing great.
It's beautIful to watch you improve.
It's awesome to watch your hard work.
Pay off.
Appreciate man.
It's pleasure sitting here next to you
guys.
Thank you.
thanks brother.
It was an honor.
All right,
thanks.
Thanks eddie.
Bravo as well.
Go to 10th planet j.j.com
and learn some jujitsu son.
10th planet headquarters of the tap out
jim and los angeles.
the master eddie bravo teaches there
himself on a nightly basis.
You dirty bitches.
I got.
I'm going to 10 planet san francisco
this saturday.
Go to the nea bureau form on [inaudible]
dot com for all the info this saturday
and it's in san francisco.
Eddie bravo on twitter and Jeremy
Stevens is little heathen l I l he then
that's his nickname.
Don't ask.
He'll fuck you up.
Little heathen.
Thanks also to squarespace.com.
Go to squarespace.com.
Use the offer code [inaudible] all one
word joe and the number 11 to save
yourself 10 percent off,
no credit card needed.
Just try it out and start building a
website.
It's a fucking beautiful service and if
you like it,
then you put in your credit card.
You can use it,
you can make your own website.
You could start your own business on it.
You can have your own online store.
It's so easy.
Even a dummy like me can do it in easy
and awesome way for anybody to design
their own website.
Thanks also to lumosity.com.
This is the correct website,
lumosity.com
forward slash joe.
That's lumosity.com.
Forward slash joe.
Click the start training button and
start playing your first game.
That's the special offer you can try.
Lumosity is a fantastic way to get your
brain in shape based on the science of
neuroplasticity.
So go check it out.
Enjoy it,
love the fuck out of it like we do,
and thanks also to [inaudible] dot com.
That's o n n I t
use the code named brogan and save 10
percent off any and all supplements will
be back tomorrow with lorenzo from the
psychedelic salon.
What are my personal favorite podcast?
He's going to be joining me and then on
wednesday the great brian kaylin will be
here already.
Freaks.
We love the shit out of you and we'll
see you soon.
Big kiss.
Give him a big kiss,
jeremy.
Go.
Yay.
Bravo.