Four three,
two,
one dude.
First of all,
what possessed you to want to swim
around the entire UK?
How many thousands of miles is that?
Yeah.
Uh,
2000 miles altogether.
2000 miles of swimming.
Yeah.
It seemed like a good idea at the time.
And then half way round I realized how
big Great Britain was.
You,
you've done some long swims before,
but
not like nothing even remotely.
Like what's the longest swim you did
before this?
I did.
Um,
oh,
this is a bit of a strange story.
I did.
Um,
I tried to swim between Saint Lucia
Martinique to Caribbean islands.
Um,
it's only 40 kilometers from point to
point.
And,
and for charity,
I was trying to swim from point to point
with 100 pound tree attached to my
trunks.
Um,
so I was pulling the hunch of foundry,
a six foot waves crashing down and,
and I actually didn't make it from point
to point.
I was like five kilometers from the end.
And when I didn't make it,
I decided to swing back the other way.
So I ended up swimming over a hundred
kilometers with a hundred pound tree.
It took me 32 hours,
but still didn't make it.
So,
so what,
what,
what went wrong where you didn't make
it?
Tides currents,
you know,
and,
and I,
you just get swept away.
Yeah.
And especially attached to a tree,
right?
How big secrets his tree.
Uh,
so a hundred pounds,
but I mean,
it floats,
but it was more of the drag.
So if there's any influence from tidal
currents and it's pulling you in one
direction,
I mean,
I was basically gonna Miss Martinique
know I was heading to Cuba,
you know,
somewhere like that.
And then on the way back down,
and they turned to me again and they
said like,
you're going to miss St Lucia,
you're going to end up in how to net
whatevers further south than Saint
Lucia.
Um,
and I think I realized this as
physically fit as you are.
Um,
the ocean just,
just doesn't care,
doesn't care.
And so after that,
this was last year,
this was November last year.
Um,
kind of felt I had unfinished business
with the ocean.
Um,
came back,
came back to England,
a rung up from friends of mine at the
Royal Marines.
I said,
guys,
look,
this is going to sound so,
so strange.
I said,
but I just,
I need to get out of my system.
I just need to see how far I can swim in
48 hours.
So I swan 40 hours.
Um,
I can't remember.
It wasn't there and it was 160
kilometers,
something,
something like that.
And I finished and I had basically
trench foot.
So where your,
your,
your feet and your hands are.
So kind of,
I've got so much water in.
This one was going moldy,
you know?
Yeah.
So I had 21,
I'm sort of sitting there,
nursing,
nursing my feet.
And uh,
one of the,
one of the offices,
uh,
a good friend of mine and they came over
and they just said,
uh,
you know,
real English royal.
And they said,
you boy.
And I said,
yes.
And they said,
oh,
what do you,
what are you training for?
And I said,
uh,
oh.
And I'm training for a potentially
attempting the world's longest current
neutral swim.
And then just paused and he sits his cup
of tea
and he looked me up and down.
He just goes at,
just sounds a bit lame.
I was like,
okay,
what would you want me to do?
And he pauses and he says,
you just need to man up.
We need to man up and swim around Great
Britain.
And I was like,
Whoa,
I can't,
I can't.
I couldn't say no once the agency,
why don't you swim with me bitch,
motherfucker,
that's a crazy thing for someone to be
asking you to do.
Now I know,
right?
So I said,
fine.
Once the idea stuck with me,
I mean,
you know,
we've got this real history and heritage
of,
of British eccentric explorers.
And for me growing up,
there's a story of Captain Web.
So the first guy to swim across the
English Channel,
and for those who don't know English
Channel,
uh,
you know,
the tides,
they believe what?
We're too strong.
The water was too cold.
They said you just can't make it across.
The English Channel isn't possible.
But captain web refused to listen and a
1875 August across the English Channel,
and this is the part I love on a diet of
beef broth and brandy in a woolen
wetsuit.
He swam,
I think it was 23 hours breaststroke
with his head out of the water because,
and I quote front crawl was
ungentlemanly like and there was that
element that I just thought that's so
amazing.
Front crawl,
what does the front crossbar,
so it's a basically that's front the
regular one.
Yeah.
But way back in 1875 it was like,
no,
that's sorrows and gentlemanly the
movement itself themselves.
Yeah.
It was still being developed as a
technique.
Whereas you know,
if you are a gentleman and you were a
swimmer,
you swim breaststroke,
you know,
exactly.
Head out of the water the whole time,
the whole way.
23 hours.
And again,
like th the,
the,
the support boat was saying,
you know,
get out,
you're not,
you're not going to make,
you're not going to make it.
And he just refused and 23 hours.
So you know,
that's part of a night swim as well.
Had out the water just all the way.
Why Brandy?
Is he getting fucked up or just a little
bit of brand?
Do you know?
I don't know,
maybe it might have been a bit of Dutch
courage,
but I think there was certainly back
then sports nutrition isn't what it is
today.
Right.
So I think there was an element,
he was even like lubing himself up in
goose fat,
you know,
this is waiting back and make himself
slicker,
slicker.
And I think there was an element of warm
for that was the,
certainly the belief.
Right.
So the Tour de France guys,
didn't they drink wine?
That was like a big thing back in the
day.
Way Back.
Yeah.
I mean it wasn't too long ago.
It wouldn't be me and Jamie would just,
just,
just talking now about football back in
England and it wasn't till,
you know too long ago,
I don't know,
maybe a hundred years ago.
They used to just keep brandy in the
dressing room in case you needed to warm
yourself up real and out.
Oh yeah.
Wow.
So they play soccer drunk there.
Yeah,
kind of just slope with a little bit.
Like I said,
just turn it over.
Wow.
I think,
you know,
people don't understand that it's taken,
people like Captain Web,
maybe me to a smaller extent to just
raise the bar,
push the boundaries and,
and you know,
you've seen that,
I think our generation have seen that
with the UFC with mixed martial arts
that has evolved so fast.
I'm always remember
forrest griffin used the kind of a
likened himself to the basketball
players just shooting three pointers
with the ball between the legs,
you know?
And that always resonated with me
because I was like,
yeah,
the evolution that we've seen and what
sort of Bruce Lee had the foresight to
predict is amazing.
And I think in a,
in a much,
much,
much smaller way.
Again,
to go back to sort of British athletes
and adventurers.
Roger bannister first nights running a
four minute mile people said couldn't be
done.
And he was a medical student at the time
leading physicians that he can't do it.
Your lungs will explode,
your legs will fall off.
All sorts.
But no,
he said,
you know,
Oxford laced up his trainers and ran a
four minute mile similar right now to
what I think we're seeing with Kip
Shogi,
you know,
and,
and the two hour marathon.
And so that's why,
and again,
in a much,
much smaller way,
when I had that conversation about
swimming around Great Britain,
everybody said it can't be done.
Yes,
it's 2000 miles.
But there's giant whirlpools in Scotland
called the Chorea Vecan pentland firth
renowned around the world.
If you get that wrong,
you'll disappear in backwards at 10
knots.
You,
there's no way you're swimming against
that.
And 10 us,
that's a dolphin speed.
She was 10 knots in miles per hour.
A basically 10 miles per hour,
10 miles per hour backwards as you're
trying to go forwards basically.
Yeah.
Penn versus the top of Scotland,
the currents that go across there.
So it's running at a good clip,
but yo,
yeah.
Yeah.
I mean we got it good.
We managed to basically predict it so
well that I,
I think that was probably my top speed,
which I did 8.7
knots is 8.7
miles per hour.
I was basically cruising along the top,
which is wow,
we just like a dolphin.
So you were having the waves behind you,
pushing you almost and see now that's
what's interesting because I had the
tides and currents with me,
not necessarily the way I said it wrong
and when you get bit,
but actually you made a good point in
terms of when you get windover tide.
So if you've got 10 knots going this
way,
but he even got a little bit of wind and
waves going this way,
it can get choppy again and again.
Sort of looking at west Scotland,
windover tide,
you can get 40 knots coming straight
down the barrel,
but you're trying to swim with the tide.
Yeah,
the wind is coming at you,
but the tide is going the opposite.
And as you can imagine that,
oh my God.
Yeah.
So how do you predict this,
this,
this tide that you have to get right?
Yeah,
I mean it's,
it's in completely in theory.
And this is what I realized when I sat
down and we started sort of plotting the
great,
what is this called again?
What is the,
the issue that will push you back?
Oh,
just the title.
Yes.
What is it called?
That area.
Oh,
so you got to get right.
so penn unferth pending for the panel
and for Pendleton for,
yeah.
Yeah.
And that's that,
like I said,
renowned around the world.
But equally,
if you imagine the shape of Great
Britain,
there's all sorts of kind of compression
where the water would just come rushing
through.
And as well as the panel and firth,
you can get,
you know,
six knots around whales.
There's an island called Scoma.
And if you get that right,
you are disappearing,
you know,
and you're winning,
you get it wrong again,
you're going backwards.
And for my,
for me to do a continuous stage swim,
if I'm going backwards,
I've got to start where I was going
backwards.
So for me,
getting every single tied right.
And that's why so far the team were
amazing.
There was a,
uh,
the Captain Matt was just incredible
that every night the homework,
are we okay here?
No.
Did we crash?
All right folks,
if you're listening or watching,
we had a little technical difficulty,
so this is not streaming live will be
uploaded later.
We were just going over how you
predicted you had to,
you and your team had to predict how the
tide was coming because if it went wrong
you'd get pushed backwards and like 10
miles an hour.
Yeah.
Basically.
And the,
and this is the thing,
I think with the great British swim,
we were kind of taking swimming as most
people understand it and we were,
we were removing it and putting it in an
arena that was so different.
So I think that's why it was,
it did so well kind of online as well as
the community around it because
obviously swimmers were interested,
but you know,
surfers started to get involved because
they understood the waves.
Um,
sailors,
fisherman,
you know,
all sorts of people started to say,
sometimes in Great Britain it's not safe
to take a boat around the top of
Scotland.
In it,
for instance,
nevermind a swimmer.
Um,
so that's,
that's why it was amazing that,
that on the entire series it became,
uh,
a melting pot and exchange of ideas
because nobody knew how to get a human
body around the coast of Great Britain.
It wasn't just about swimming and,
and that was what was really cool.
How,
how do they know,
like when the tides are going one way or
the other,
how do they predict that?
Yeah,
I mean,
tied to so predictable.
So in theory,
they change every six hours.
when we sat down and we looked,
and we know that if you do six hours on
six hours off for 157 days,
you'll make it around the coast of Great
Britain.
You know?
And,
and,
and that was the theory.
So you do this by phasic sleep and you
swim for 12 hours a day.
But that's all theory.
There's times when,
as I mentioned,
a giant whirlpools or,
or the tides might not necessarily,
if you imagine sort of,
that's Great Britain there,
the tides don't necessarily go always
like this or they're not that
predictable.
Sometimes if there's kind of like this,
like that's kind of whales there,
the tides will do this.
So you're,
you're doing all these different things
that people are not going to see instead
of listening to it on audio.
So just try to just describe it.
Right.
It's a basically rather than the tides
just going up and down and working with
you,
sometimes they cross cross.
Yeah.
So you'll just kind of getting slapped
across the face.
My tides essentially.
And it's not just helping you,
you're going to basically zigzag all the
way up the coast of Great Britain.
So it was predictable as tides are.
We found those so much stuff that when
we're out there we were like,
oh,
it wasn't meant to do that.
Or a giant whirlpool wasn't meant to be
there,
but it is an,
and that was what was pretty,
yeah,
pretty sketchy.
It sometimes,
you know that when we were out there,
if a whirlpool just decides to appear,
you've got you,
there's not really enough time to say,
oh,
hang on,
that wasn't on the map.
Can we look at that?
Can we speak to the Met Office and talk
about,
you know,
weather reports?
No,
you just,
you,
I've had to swim through it or,
or try and get out there as quick as you
could.
So when you encounter something like
that and you get stuck,
do you pull out of the water and try
back again later at the same location?
You do.
But quite often if it was there,
it's still gonna be there.
Oh,
it's just,
it is what it is.
Yeah.
So sometimes there's this notion and,
and perhaps the best example of this,
I mentioned it for,
it's called the Chorea Vecan.
So,
uh,
sort of west coast of Scotland and it's
a giant whirlpool.
And,
and Matt,
the captain turned to me and said,
look,
Ross,
you know,
I need you to swim and I need you to
swim hard.
You know,
you need to swim six hours.
You just need to be clear this
whirlpool.
Um,
so as we were swimming past it,
I set my watch and some hard for six
hours,
but about three hours in,
um,
I got stung by jellyfish and I've been
stung by jellyfish a lot before he sees,
you know,
it's painful,
but it was,
it was bearable.
Um,
but this one particular jellyfish,
it just,
it was searing into my skin.
It just,
it wouldn't stop throbbing.
And so I carried on swimming,
three hours passed and it was just
unbearable.
So I popped my head up and I looked at
Matt,
the captain from the boat.
I said,
man,
I'm so sorry I've been stung and,
and you know,
I'm going to have to stop.
Um,
I've been stung by a jellyfish,
pitched the pain's just not going away.
And as,
as I said that to him,
he looked down at me and he said,
yeah,
I know,
cause the tentacles still wrapped around
your face.
So I'd basically been swimming for three
hours with a jellyfish on your case,
wearing a jellyfish.
It wrapped into my goggles.
So I took my gold,
unpeel this fat,
tend to call,
threw it away.
Um,
and then like I said,
I,
I'll show you in a minute.
I'll ever,
there was a picture where my,
my face sorta change shape and the
goggles wouldn't fit on my face anymore
because my eye sockets were so swelled.
And,
but I knew that again,
for all of this happening,
the cory of Eq and the giant Walpole was
still to my left.
So Matt was like,
you still need to swim.
You still need to swim.
So I ended up paying the goggles over my
face and to try and get them to seal,
I just punched them into my face.
So you just had these perfect ring and
then I managed,
you're a sore.
Swollen.
Yeah.
So you're a push them through the
swelling basically.
Yeah.
John.
So you swim.
Um,
I made another hour.
We got clear the cory of Atkins.
We managed to clear this giant
whirlpool.
I collapse onto the boat and um,
and this is the thing,
it was at that point that I collapsed
exhausted face.
Now a different shape to when I started
that particular swim.
And,
um,
and the team looked at me and they saw
how bad I was,
how be it an upper was,
but they also knew that the sea just
doesn't care.
And in six hours the tide was going to
change and I'm not going to have to do
that all over again.
And it was that kind of brutal lesson
from nature that,
that from a sports science background,
I'm interested in,
you know,
Rehab,
rest,
recovery,
nutrition strategies,
all of this.
But with sending around Great Britain,
it very quickly became apparent that the
seed just doesn't care.
It just doesn't care that you need to
rehab your shoulders.
It doesn't care that the ligaments and
tendons in your shoulders are hurting.
You might get impingement from swimming
too much in none of this.
And,
um,
that's why it went from swimming as I
understood it and how a lot of people
understand it to something completely
like surviving basically in the water.
So you're swimming schedule,
it'd be six hours on and then you would
try to rest.
When would you eat?
Uh,
during the swims or,
or between Erin?
The swims.
Yeah.
Yes.
I quite often just,
you know,
throwing bananas at me and just multi
bananas basically.
Yeah.
Just so deep or not.
And you'd eat and while you're in the
water.
Yeah.
Wow.
Cause,
cause again,
going back to what we're talking about
with the pen and firth,
you could get out and you could get on
the boat,
but sometimes in a really good tide,
if you are just in the water,
you could be making four knots.
You don't have to swim.
But if you'd get in the freezing cold
water Scotland and you are quite happy
to getting hit in the face by a 10th,
cause you can still make four knots.
And so that's why so often it became
about something different than swimming.
It was just,
it was just mental fortitude.
It was physical fortitude.
It was,
um,
basically,
I always remember actually,
yeah,
First Day of autumn,
um,
I got up,
it was two o'clock,
so it was a night,
2:00
AM two o'clock in the morning and I left
my wetsuit out to dry.
And I had to scrape.
It's just a thin layer of ice off the
wet suit before I could put it.
But if I didn't,
if I didn't get in and I didn't screw it
that,
that way I see it,
then that would have been,
you know,
15 miles potentially that we would have
missed out on.
And if you miss those 15 miles,
that the window of opportunity to swim
around Great Britain because of the
British summer being notoriously
unpredictable and quite short.
Um,
we wouldn't have made it round because
even towards the end there was two
storms,
a storm elements storm Cali Allien
Callum,
who kind of stopped us for those two
days where we couldn't swim because you
just couldn't swim in a storm.
It wasn't safe.
So when you were swimming,
this was all during the summer?
Yeah,
yeah.
Uh,
freely the autumn.
And then we finished November the
fourth,
which was going into the winter as well.
And you started what month?
Uh,
June.
The first.
So for,
since June you've been swimming
basically?
God Damn,
man.
That's so crazy.
Yeah,
it's interesting too.
You're not built like a guy,
I'd expect to be doing this.
Right.
You're building a tank like does not
normal like your big jacked guy.
You look more like an MMA fighter or a
powerlifter even.
Right.
You don't look like an endurance
athlete.
Yeah.
Which is,
and we were just,
we were speaking about it cause I,
I love the episode with unct Fletcher.
I love that guy.
I love that.
And,
and,
and you know,
as a big fan of,
you know,
Kathy,
you are,
look at this fucking picture dude.
Get the fuck out of.
If someone said that guys get a swim
around grape Linda,
I was going to swim for half an hour and
he's going to have a fucking heart
attack there.
There was a lot.
Yeah,
I know I'd probably be inclined to agree
with you.
But what I find interesting is when you
start looking at a strength and stamina
for so often,
people believe the two couldn't coexist.
And Robert Hickson and his,
his sort of research ran concurrent
training that,
um,
basically saying if you train for
strength and stamina,
you dilute the potency of the stimulate.
So what what I mean by that is if,
you know,
we went into the gym just now and uh,
meet me,
you and Jamie walked into the gym and we
were like,
okay,
let's,
let's go and see what we're doing on in
the squat rack.
You know,
that's strength,
your body's ability to generate force.
And we trained that and then all of a
sudden it's like,
okay,
no,
no.
Now let's go over to the rowing machine
or let's go for a swim.
Let's go and swim 10 k.
Then all of a sudden our bodies are
going to go,
well,
hang on.
Which one do you want us to adapt to?
Looking at molecular biology,
which one do you want us to adapt to?
Strength and stamina.
And again,
you dilute the potency,
that stimuli.
However,
there's the theory that if you separate
them within the laws,
I'm going off on a little bit of a
tangent here,
but please.
Thank you.
Good looking at,
um,
Verkishanski.
So one of the greatest strength and
conditioning coaches to ever exist.
He talks about this idea of adaptive
energy,
saying that in any given day you have a
certain amount of adaptive energy and if
you are able to fit both a training
session,
that that,
like I said,
causes your body to adapt to both
strength and stamina.
You separate them under those
conditions,
they can coexist.
So you separated them by how much time?
As much as needed for optimal recovery.
So,
so yeah,
if,
if we did,
and this is the,
this is what I find fascinating about
mma because you're essentially saying to
an MMA athlete,
I need you to be strong fast,
quick,
I need you to be muscular and Jord,
but I also need you to apply a metric
speed,
strength and their body's going,
you want us to be all of those things.
Right.
You know,
and that's why quite often it's the
athlete with a higher work capacity who
can adapt to those looking at like,
you know,
the Diaz brothers who just do triathlons
for fun,
you know,
they have this insane work capacity.
So that's kind of your,
your body's ability to perform and
positively tolerate training of a given
intensity or duration.
So if you have the Diaz brothers and you
say,
okay,
we're going to now do weight training in
the morning,
but by the afternoon I also need you to
swim a 10 k their bodies could tolerate
that.
Whereas if you have another athlete who
perhaps doesn't have that work,
pasty,
their body's not going to positively
tolerate it.
Right?
A person who's used to working out maybe
only an hour a day.
Yeah,
absolutely.
So,
so that's essentially how I would,
would,
uh,
approach anything like this.
But what I found really interesting when
you were talking with,
with ct Fletcher was when you look at
strength and stamina,
it's,
it's so specific.
So you know,
said principle specific adaptation to
impose demands.
You know,
you get good at whatever you continually
practice.
And when you look at endurance in
weightbearing sports absolutely know,
you can argue that that running for
instance is,
is just,
you know,
power to weight ratio.
It's a series of successive jumps and
when you start looking at that,
there's research that will show adding,
and we did this with the Royal Marines
back in England.
When you just add one keeler of extra
weight in a backpack,
it's effect on pulmonary ventilation,
lactic threshold,
time to fatigue,
all of those things.
Just one,
one kilogram.
That's it.
And so that's why when you see tour de
France and people like Chris Froome,
Bradley wiggins unit from team sky,
they are just looking at the body saying
okay your vo two is what it is.
Your power to,
your power to weight ratio.
That's what we need to improve.
We need to treat you like a formula one
car.
We need to take away anything,
you know.
So when you look at Chris' room in an
unbelievable athlete and they said,
well you don't need biceps,
you don't need triceps.
So there we'll remove those controlled
muscular atrophy.
And how do they approach that
intelligently?
I,
I suppose looking at anything from,
you know,
a calorie deficits are not to pick
anything up ever.
Kind of.
Yeah.
And it's just exactly,
that's crazy.
There is,
there you go.
No triceps.
They don't,
they went away.
Exactly.
But I mean that is,
that is the perfect example of,
you know,
said principle specific adaptation to
impose demands that all he does is he
lives on a bike.
So as a result,
his body is,
is a byproduct of what he continually
practices.
Got Bike muscles.
Yeah.
And so,
so looking at that and sorry,
going back to strength and stamina,
when you look at running,
you could argue that you know,
being jacked and,
and being heavier.
Yes,
absolutely.
Your power to weight ratio is going to
impact you.
So for instance,
I like to run but I don't stand a chance
against some of my friends who are,
you know,
fell runners and they way,
30 kilos less than me,
however ritual.
Exactly.
Yeah.
And lean longer.
You look at him,
unbelievable specimen of a man.
You Go,
yes,
you were built for endurance,
but as soon as you go in the water,
things might start to change a little
bit because now it's non weight bearing.
So the power to weight ratio is a little
bit different.
So then you could not,
and this is all theory for the moment,
but looking at the body shape to swim
around great brim cause no one's ever
done it before.
So you can say,
okay well what does that body type look
like?
And when writing down a checklist,
you say,
we need someone who can swim in,
you know,
40 knots of wind,
wind over time that we're talking about.
So you're not going to break.
I'm on top of that as well.
You can start to look at,
um,
all of a sudden we need someone who's
never going to take a day off.
So I wasn't sick for out of those 157
days.
So then you start looking at adaptive
energy and,
and work capacity there would just spoke
about,
and then all of a sudden you can start
getting real into the detail of looking
at,
okay,
someone with a higher muscle mass,
if they're able to effectively swim and
the biomechanics are,
are on point.
So that's not,
you know,
this muscle mass isn't interfering with
their biomechanics.
Could it be argued that that's stored
muscle glycogen can almost turn them
into a human whale.
You know that.
Yeah,
you're right.
You put me into the pool with Michael
Phelps and he,
me,
you know,
he to look at him swim,
it's unbelief.
He looks like a dolphin.
It's beautiful.
But when it comes to something like
seminar in Great Britain,
it's just,
it's just an eating competition,
you know,
with a little bit of swimming involved
and you just need to make sure you don't
break.
And that goes back to the tides as well.
Your body working with ties.
If you can just keep getting in the
water for 157 days,
12 hours a day and not break,
you'll make it wound Great Britain by.
So you think the muscle mass aids you in
that way?
I would argue,
yes.
Yeah.
I mean,
and this is purely anecdotal and I'd
love to actually do more research into
this,
but,
but certainly with a lot of athletes
that I train with that it's almost like
a bell curve.
So if you can imagine,
you know,
for those listening like a bell curve
like that,
how would you describe that?
Just to sort of like a horseshoe?
Yeah.
So you can argue that here around
endurance.
So if you've got somebody who's you
know,
to use rich rituals,
example,
an amazing swimmer,
the over 10 K he's going to be amazing
because there's efficiency in
everything.
But then pass this point.
So when we start looking at the mileage
that we were covering,
so it sort of English Channel Swim is 20
miles plus a day.
At this point,
this leaner swimmer's going to start
running out of muscle glycogen is
biomechanics might break down because he
doesn't have the strength to hold that
position continually.
All of those things,
the waves start crashing and he's
starting to swimming to 40 knots of
wind.
What's going to happen?
Are you going to be,
would you favor the,
the lean a quicker,
more streamlined swimmer or would you
argue that the guy who have more muscle
mass here is going to continue to swim?
Not necessarily at the same pace,
but would continue not to break?
I think it depends on who the man with
the muscle mass is.
Because a lot of guys with muscle mass,
they got that muscle mass are doing very
low reps,
high weight.
I mean what,
what kind of exercise do you do that
gives you a bill like that?
See and that's a good point.
I mean I loved what you did with them
with Dorian Yates and um,
I think when you start looking at the,
the three mechanisms to build muscular
hypertrophy,
you start looking at metabolic stress.
So metabolic stress being exactly what
you just said.
Lots and lots of reps during yes being a
great example of that.
That is more muscular hypertrophy,
bodybuilding centric work and that's
metabolic stress.
Lots and lots of reps.
But then you can also look at mechanical
tension to that's more your power
lifters,
you know,
really,
really high weight,
lower volume,
just real strength.
Your body's ability to generate force.
That is what I do.
Um,
and yes,
it's shown to induce muscular
hypertrophy is to increase muscle mass,
but arguably more functional than when
you'd be looking at a,
you know,
bodybuilding,
Mr Olympia,
something like that.
And then you have a muscle damage,
which has more eccentric contraction,
some more arguably sort of crossfit a
bodybuilder to achieve their physique.
Besides using steroids,
they have to use lots of repetitions.
Yeah.
That's it.
So,
so when you say what do I do?
I specifically use,
it's more mechanical tension.
So more power cleans,
deadlifts,
things along those lines.
He's exactly,
yeah,
yeah.
Cause you're not billing a bodybuilder,
but you're,
you're built like someone was very
strong.
Yeah.
And I think that's it where you start.
And that's not to say,
you know,
when you look at,
to use you as an example.
So if we had you in the sports lab,
we would say,
okay,
what is your strength deficits?
So your strength deficit is,
is I say we had you on the leg press and
we said,
Joe,
we want to,
we want to look at how much force your
legs can generate with you.
Just using basically your training
strength training strength is defined as
the strength that you would use.
Just leg pressing,
not getting you all like to cite of
preworkouts smelling salts,
none of that.
We would just say Joe gun leg press and
you'd just leg press and that's what you
can generate there.
But then in the sports I back it left
for university,
we would start using,
uh,
basically a lecture basically using
electrical impulses to,
to make the muscles contract beyond what
you could generate yourself.
So that is what your body could generate
without you trying to send those
impulses.
Buddies,
you the actual,
the actual potential muscle,
the strength of the muscles themselves.
How do you determine that?
Like I said,
basically,
um,
a lecture,
cheating their muscles and stimulating
it in voluntarily and through that they
measure it.
How so?
Oh,
so then that measures your,
uh,
your maximum output with you not trying
to use it yourself.
It's involuntary.
So that is something that you wouldn't
have control over.
What do they,
how do they do that?
Like essentially electricity cheap.
What kind of,
what does it like electrodes and slap on
your legs and they force you to extend
your legs.
Yeah.
You would have seen it.
Yeah,
exactly.
That you lift a weight with that.
Yeah.
You can do,
yeah.
So that's what they do.
Yeah.
I've never heard of such a thing.
So you would be sitting in a leg press
or engineering quad extensions and,
and make your legs extend.
Yeah.
Wow.
So they would monitor your strengths.
So the difference between that,
so all of a sudden they'll say,
okay,
this over here,
go training strength is what you could
do,
Joe,
when I was just saying,
okay,
lift that right.
And it's what you were going,
okay,
I'll lift it.
And then over here,
when it's involuntary,
that is what you could actually do.
That's the potential of the muscles.
What's usually the higher number?
Oh,
absolutely.
Well,
so it's always involuntary,
really?
Always.
Yeah.
Yeah,
absolutely.
How much what?
And that's the strength deficits.
So do you see what I mean?
So,
okay,
so over here,
this is what you could generate when
you're just going,
okay,
one,
two,
three and I'm lifting it myself.
Ah,
okay.
That done.
And over here is what we do when it's
involuntary now and if there's a big
deficit,
okay.
So if there's a huge deficit between the
two,
that means you're a pussy.
It means your worth.
No,
it means if there's a large deficit
between the two,
it means that you have muscle mass but
you're not fully using it.
So you might see a large deficit between
the two.
If you had,
um,
a bodybuilder for instance,
cause they've got a lot of muscle mass
but they're not using,
does that make sense?
So why aren't they using it?
Because it's,
it's strength is functional.
So they've got all this muscle mass,
but they're not recruiting it.
They've not actually trained strength
because strength is neuro muscular.
So when a bodybuilder does like high
repetitions,
and what was the type of load that you
were calling that?
How they were,
that was causing hypertrophy range.
So that's metabolic stress,
metabolic stress.
So just a sheer number of sets.
Yeah.
Just constant repetitions over and over
and over again with not that high await.
Yes.
Yeah.
And that's meant about,
but then mechanical tension is when,
um,
it's more powerlifting us.
So there's your difference between the
two.
So the reason being is met.
So when you start looking at mechanical
tension that might produce an athlete
who has a smaller strength deficit,
right?
So when again,
using you as an example,
if there was a smaller strength deficit
between what you could voluntarily leg
press in a leg extension after
extension,
and then involuntary,
there's a smaller deficit,
it would like it,
I would have likened it to,
okay,
Joe,
you have this much muscle mass,
but you're using a lot of your
potential.
You're using it already.
It's almost like you've got a formula
one car with a huge engine,
but you're using it to its full extent.
You know?
And,
and this is why I'm going off on a
slight tangent here,
but this is why when you start looking
at bodybuilding centric work,
so this idea of increasing muscular
hypertrophy,
it can be a good thing when you
understand that strength deficit.
So you might have an athlete who you go,
okay,
you have a small strength deficits,
very small.
So for the muscle mass that you have,
you're using it to its absolute full
potential.
It's like you have a very small car but
you are just pushing down the
accelerator so hard and it can't go
anymore.
It's just red line.
Exactly.
So the option that we have is to
increase the size of the car.
The option we have is increased the
size,
your muscle mass.
In some sense it does.
Yeah,
it does.
Um,
what kind of training were you doing to
increase your capacity for work while
maintaining the mass?
Yeah,
and this,
this guy's that is a bit of a strange
story.
So this goes back to something I always
call.
Um,
you know,
horsepower programming,
which I think is,
it's so often lost now.
I think training is very specific when
you're going to the gym or you're
training for strength,
speed,
stamina.
Whereas horsepower programming I almost
borrowed from Soviet Union principles,
you start looking at a general physical
preparedness as it was,
as it was known.
And this is this just idea of you take
an athlete's only a younger athlete and
you're trying to increase their work
capacity by nonspecific movements.
So you'll get at,
you're an athlete,
you're handed you a magic,
okay,
you're young,
a kid just growing up and your parents
hand you to me,
I'm your coach.
And I say,
okay,
I don't know if Joe's going to be big
strong.
I don't know if he's gonna be able to
run far or fast.
I don't know.
So what we're going to do is just
create,
increase your sort of neuromuscular
efficiency and work capacity.
And so by doing
that,
it's kind of jumps,
throws nonspecific,
these natural movement patterns,
and we get you to do lots and lots of
this.
What that's doing is work capacity,
your body's ability to positively
tolerate training and given an intensity
or duration.
And I think from the great British swim,
when a lot of people will say,
how was it that you are able to tolerate
those 12 hours a day?
The jellyfish things and everything.
It it for me,
one of the biggest things was going back
to,
and this is gonna sound so odd,
but I um,
I ran a marathon pulling a car,
uh,
three,
three years ago I think now.
Um,
and so that is almost the perfect
embodiment of horsepower programming in
that,
that shear stress on the body.
But it's not a specific skill.
When you say you run a marathon behind a
car,
pulling a car,
pulling out in front of a car.
Yeah.
Not behind a car.
No.
Yeah.
So it was um,
you pull the car and ran a marathon.
What the fuck do they said?
Yeah,
I seem so normal.
That's what's so confusing to me.
Like if I met you,
there's something about a lot of these
endurance people.
Well how,
I guess not Courtney Courtney door.
Walter,
she's so carefree and silly,
but your very loose and relaxed.
I always considered like those people
are dark.
There's some darkness to those extreme
endurance athletes.
Yeah.
There's darkness that they're running
from some darkness.
You know what I mean?
Now I do,
I've had this conversation with a few
people cause they said something similar
and I think it's,
um,
I mean,
you know,
to slightly go off on another tangent
here cause I think we've covered the
physical aspect and,
and work capacity,
the which,
which I've addressed.
But I think,
and this is one thing I genuine just
wanting to almost quiz you on and get
your thoughts on this is uh,
certainly the Frat,
the great British swim,
it subjected my body to a fatigue like
I've never experienced before.
It was just yes,
sleep deprivation,
just ligaments,
tendons in my shoulders.
Just wondering what's going on.
And um,
for me,
your most developer,
a split personality in that,
there's times when I would quite often
say you need to swim with a smile
because you know,
it's 157 days if you're stressed or it's
like a marathon where you grit your
teeth and you try and get through it.
Um,
I think we're very aware that,
you know,
the body is this complex biochemical
organism and if you're stressed cortisol
levels,
spike inflammation,
your immune system,
everything's affected.
So for me,
I was treating it not like a marathon.
I had to treat it,
swim with a smile,
you know,
think this is,
this is life now.
Right?
Let's see.
Um,
but then equally there were times when,
you know,
I wouldn't swim with a smile.
It was just,
you know,
Korea vet can be being a great example.
You know,
I sent him,
he wasn't all that happy then.
And,
and for me,
it's those times when I say,
you've got to just get feral.
You know,
you've really just got to a good friend
of mine,
you know,
back in,
back in England,
um,
ses trained,
and he said to me,
Ross,
your,
you're really nice guy and everything,
but there's gonna be times when you just
need to,
you know,
no smiles and just get feral.
Which,
which I thinking about it an end,
cause I had 12 hours to think at bay.
I was mulling this over in my head.
Um,
for me,
it goes back to Tim noakes central
governor theory.
Um,
looking at how fatigue is,
it is an emotionally driven state that
we use to pull that physiological
handbrake.
So,
uh,
you know,
for those listening sorta 60 miles into
a marathon,
you might be saying,
no way,
I can't keep putting one foot in front
of that.
There's no way.
And then all of a sudden 25 miles in
your family and friends are clapping you
and you get that second wind and you
start sprinting.
Um,
and for me,
looking at that,
this sort of central governor theory,
I found that in complete exhaustion,
like when when you absolutely have
nothing left,
you almost go into this feral state,
you know,
so like,
uh,
like an like an injured dog,
you know,
where a lot of people will say,
Oh,
you know,
remember why you started to think of
your family and friends.
And I was like,
no,
no.
I was at a level of fatigue where I
wasn't thinking about,
you know,
family and friends.
It,
I was thinking almost,
you know,
maslow's hierarchy of needs,
where it starts with just food,
shelter,
oxygen.
I was at that sort of level where there
was clcs.
I mean,
my next kind of healed now,
but you know,
there was times when chafing on my neck,
my,
my tongue was falling apart.
It's fine now by the way,
Jay Thomas fire part my tongue from the
salt,
salt water.
Yeah.
And,
and falling apart on the house or it is
what it's called,
salt tongue.
And after 12 hours in the water every
single day,
um,
your,
your tongue would essentially start to
disintegrate.
So Jesus,
yeah.
No.
So I was,
I woke up and there was parts of my
tongue on my pillow.
And this is,
is there any concern of this is
permanent or it was prominent at the
time?
Were you concerned?
Absolutely.
And I think that that's bad,
but that's what goes back to that,
that hierarchy of needs where you're not
thinking about family and friends or
what motivates you and what you know,
you know,
you're thinking,
I want to keep my tongue.
You know,
you're like,
man,
because no one has really,
has people have gone on long swims
before?
But has anybody done six months?
I don't think so.
There there,
there's Ben La,
compton,
the moment who's going across the
Pacific,
but he is using a snorkel.
So he kind of cleverly thought about
that.
Whereas for me I thought,
no,
this has to be done without properly.
Where you thinking about the guy who was
just doing the restaurant and saying,
well if he did it,
fuck get done.
Well and this is it.
Yeah,
it was wow.
So yes and no that and it was at that
point that I think,
um,
you what you are feral,
you're just thinking I five one,
one arm in front of the other.
Keep going.
Keep moving.
Exactly.
That you are soldier pieces of your
tongue.
This is a video that you made or pieces
of your tongue.
We're falling apart.
Wow.
The fact of salt buildup on the tongue,
and this is on Ross's instagram was,
which is Ross.
I put it up on my instagram too.
I re retweeted or reposted one of your,
uh,
things to let people know about this.
Oh,
that is so nasty,
dude.
You can see the taste buds on it.
That's how so was it fucking with your
taste buds?
Oh yeah,
yeah.
The way you tasted things.
Oh yeah.
And that started to have an impact on
you need the food as well.
Cause I mean like Granola,
I was eating so much granola,
but when that happened it's like rubbing
sandpaper on an icon.
Yeah,
right.
He's the grit and the the oats.
Exactly.
So,
and that was how we had to just adapt on
the day.
So it's during that,
that video is great actually.
I mean that was in the cabin and I
remember just thinking like now I'm not
thinking,
you know,
family and friends to,
to talk about those.
As you just said,
those,
those darker moments.
I think now it's very easy for me to be
very grateful.
I'm warm sitting in the studio view.
There's,
there's no jellyfish,
but there's times that where,
you know,
it was dark with my neck as well.
I mean my neck was bad,
but we didn't actually catch that.
The moment was probably the worst on
that where I went to bed with this open
wound from the wetsuit,
chafing basically.
And,
um,
as I woke up,
the bedsheet had fused to my neck.
Oh.
So I just had to rip it off,
put it on the pus.
Jesus Christ.
Right.
And then you had to get in that salt
water,
which was the felt great.
Right?
Yeah.
Fuck man.
What was it like when you finished?
What did it feel like when the last
stroke,
what did you got out of the water and
you're like,
Holy Shit,
I just swam for six months.
It was,
yeah,
it was,
it was so strange because when we left
in June,
we came back obviously to the same point
and we left in the British summer and
everyone was on the beach and,
and then our came back round.
People are putting up Christmas
decorations and I was like,
I had been gone for so long at sea.
It was just so crazy.
How many days was it a total?
157.
Oh my God,
that is so insane.
It just is so much change in,
Oh,
here.
Yeah,
here we go.
That was the finished.
So this is swimming,
but then this is your the or who are
these people?
These fucking hangers on following you
around.
Pretend they did it too.
So I felt that it was such a team
effort.
Those people are waiting for you.
My legs was so shaky,
Joe,
at this point I'm thinking,
don't fall over.
Don't fall over.
Wow.
Because it has,
I mean this is the thing I think I
stumbled in.
Aluminum does such madness,
man.
Yeah.
It's such a madness and you crossed the
red bull finish line.
I've got a trident.
That was pretty cool.
Wow.
That's at home at the moment.
Oh,
they hooked you up?
Yeah.
What's that made out of?
It was really sturdy.
I don't know.
I think it was like a bronx style thing,
but blue,
all these fucking phony do it with them.
I said,
I was like,
I feel that the way that it captured
everyone's my age just only felt right
to do that.
Do you swim?
Yes.
You do.
Christina.
Pool come and get involved.
I didn't even know about it.
You know how I found out about you?
Because I was,
I,
I was reading on the Internet and I
found out about it and I sent it to all
my friends after sober October to show
what pussies we were.
I was like,
guys think what we did was hard and we
did ain't shit.
I sent it to Tom and burden our,
and we were all just like fluff because
whenever you hear about someone doing
something crazy,
there's always someone who does
something far crazier to one up the
crazy person.
And then it keeps going and going and
going.
Like there's a race that courtney doe,
Walter,
who's been a guest on the show before,
she won the Moab to 40 which is a 238
mile race through the mobile APP
mountains.
And it's just an insane race.
Not only did she win it,
she wanted it by more than 10 hours
ahead of the second place guy when she's
just a fucking straight savage.
So she recently entered a race and she
came in second place and this race,
they would run for four miles in an hour
and then they would stop when the hour
was over.
They would stop and then when the next
hour started,
they would run another four miles,
like four point something miles.
And they do it for six days.
That's crazy.
They did is still like the last man
standing.
And then at the very end,
one person one like,
it's like,
who's going to drop out last?
So they just kept doing it.
So the guy who created this race,
see if you can find anything on this guy
because he's apparently very sadistic.
And his idea was that people run these
100 mile races or a 50 mile race and if
you just finish,
you feel like a winner.
And he's like,
well bullshit.
He goes,
there can't be a winner if,
if somebody comes in first place and
then your your second place,
you're not the winner.
It's like there's one winner.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
He's apparently chain smokes too.
He's amazing.
So this is the Berkeley marathons,
you know about this.
Did you see last same guy he ran,
he created that race.
And this is another race he created.
He's amazing.
So did you see,
I think it was last year,
Jamie,
is it right then?
It's the Berkeley Marathon.
What does the Berkeley Barkley,
Matt Barkley,
Berkley or Barkley,
the Barkley,
the one that nobody could figure out how
to Mark Lee at the Barkley guy with the
weird one.
And I think it was if you searched his
jamie's well,
I think it was last year or the year
before,
I believe it's the 24 hours or 40 hours,
but the guy missed out on finishing it
by,
I think it was a minute rant and then at
the end and you see him on the floor,
he's absolutely devastated and he
didn't,
he may take a wrong turn somewhere along
the line cause it's really difficult to
follow that path.
Yeah,
admirably.
He just got and he shook his hand
and just said,
I just want to thank you.
You know,
for that he said sometimes,
you know the Barkley Barkley Marathon
wins,
but you know that that takes something
different.
Well,
definitely takes something different to
see a final,
if I'm correct in how they do it.
I retweeted the courtney daughter water
one.
I retweeted it from Courtney where it
says it's like getting punched in the
face very softly over and over and over
again.
Yeah,
that's exactly,
yeah.
I compare it to being punched and put it
up.
Put the article up version of the
article.
I don't know if it's the exact one.
Yeah,
yeah,
that's exactly it.
So if you scroll down,
you'll see the,
the the specifications.
Yeah.
And this is what I find amazing because
then it becomes about something
completely different.
I mean we were just talking now about
Kyc Shogi and the two hour marathon,
but it's like if you pick,
put Kip chokey into this,
you know who's going to win?
It says they had an hour to complete the
4.1667
mile loop and then they finished within
15 minutes to spare the bell clangs
again,
it's 7:40
AM they run it again and then at 8:48
AM they run it again.
At nine 40 they were running again.
So every hour you run this 4.1667
mile loop.
And then the bell just keeps clanging
for forever.
Why do you,
why do you think there's more people
doing these events now?
Well,
I think it's the same thing as
everything else.
The same thing as if you buy a car
today,
you wanted to accelerate from zero to 60
in two and a half seconds.
Yeah.
A few years ago that was unheard of.
If you buy a computer today,
you want it to be 3.8
gigahertz and five terabyte hard drive.
And that's,
it's the same every year.
We want improvements.
And I think when you hear someone's
going to run a 100 mile race,
you go there,
yeah,
that's cute.
Uh,
but I'm gonna run 200 miles.
And they're like,
that's not even possible.
The same as the four minute mile,
right.
Someone runs a 200 miles.
You're like,
Holy Shit,
I can't believe a guy rants for three
days.
You were in 200 miles.
And then someone like courtney comes
along,
goes,
I'm going to do it in two days.
And then she runs,
she runs it in two days.
And then someone,
they're talking about now doing a 500
mile ultra marathon.
Yeah.
But,
and what I find amazing,
who,
what's the athlete look like?
Who completes that?
Do you know what I mean?
He's,
and he's very thin.
She's very light and very thin and you
know,
she's not the type of person that would
win a regular marathon.
This was what it was interesting.
My friend Cam Haynes,
who also runs these,
he ran the,
uh,
he's quite,
he's pretty Jack.
Yeah,
he works,
he lifts a lot,
but he cuts a lot of body weight when he
does those.
Okay.
But the way he does it is he's a hard
man.
He's what I was talking about,
like the speed have darkness.
Yay.
He's got some darkness.
He just like,
he'll burn 3000 calories,
eat 2000.
And so he'll force his body to eat
itself.
Right.
And so he drops down to the hundred and
60 something pound range.
And then that's what he likes to weigh.
When he normally walks around like one
85,
it's pretty built.
But then he drops way down.
He'll lose like 20 pounds of muscle
cars.
He's always lean.
He's not losing body fat.
He's just forcing his body to literally
eat itself just through mental
toughness.
But he's still quite big.
Even when he's tending up on the start
line and he's lost that.
He's still big for a year for an
endurance athlete.
Amazing.
But maybe that's one of the reasons why
he doesn't win these things.
He comes in like third fourth you mean?
And also,
you know,
he hasn't been doing it as long as them
and he's 51 years old now,
but he's an animal man and this is just
that,
that kind of mental fortitude that it
takes to do one of those things where to
do what you did.
It's a very unusual kind of drive and
people are very excited by that drive
and they're very intrigued by it and
it's very attractive.
It's very attractive to attempt to do.
It's very attractive to pay attention to
and watch cause everyone knows how
difficult he said.
It's undeniably difficult.
Like if someone says,
you talked to someone who doesn't know
how to run it all does,
they don't do anything.
They just sit on the couch.
You Go,
hey man,
get up,
get up.
We're going to run three miles.
Like fuck.
At the end of that three miles,
they will collapse the lay down their
back.
Their heart would be pounding the chest
to be heaving so they know that's hard.
Everybody knows that's hard.
Everybody at one point in their life has
run until they were exhausted,
whether it's 500 yards or five miles or
whatever it was every from when you were
a kid.
There's always been a moment where we
tested ourselves,
so we're familiar with that feeling of
not being able to go on.
So when they see a guy like you who went
through that feeling for six fucking
months,
or was it five months total?
Five months,
five months,
man.
Five months is an insane amount of time.
It is now upon the June,
July,
August,
September,
October,
November.
You're into the sixth fucking month when
you stop.
That's insane.
But,
but what you just said,
they're like,
do you think,
and this is again cause I had 12 hours
to think every day.
Do you think is unusual or do you think
that we now think is unusual because
society has got real comfortable,
you know,
and I maintained that stuff that I was
doing with salt 10 and everything
ancestors.
Do you not think they would have just
thought,
yeah that's,
that's just Monday.
You know,
just,
I don't think anybody ever thought that
was just Monday.
No,
I don't think they would have forced
themselves to do that because there's no
biological or evolutionary need to do
that.
It's not like you could swim for 12
hours a day and get across the channel
and get to a place where there's better
fruit.
They know that are,
I don't think our ancestors ever did
that.
I think.
I definitely think they did.
What does that type of a hunting,
there's,
there's actually a term for it.
Sharon's hunting.
Well they run an animal down,
I don't think it's called endurance
hunting.
I think it's,
there's another term for it,
but they will literally,
like if you take an antelope,
they don't have sweat glands,
so they can run far faster than us,
but it comes a point in time when they
overheat.
So if you just stay on them persistence
hunting,
that's okay.
I named it right when you pulled it up.
Damn.
Um,
persistence hunting is in,
you see it in these,
a lot of these African men who go on to
be phenomenal endurance runners.
I mean,
they win marathons left and right,
and his particular parts of Africa that
produce incredible runners and they
think a lot.
There was a really,
there's an cut and run is a fantastic
episode of radio lab that details these
men from this one certain part in
Africa.
I forget where it is,
but see if you pull that up.
But this,
uh,
this episode detailed the horrific
circumcision rituals that these men had
to endure where they cut their Dick and,
uh,
they,
they stick a stick through it and then
they make them crawl through thorns
naked,
right?
Yeah.
So I sold it.
There's a guy a back in,
uh,
I think it's at Bruce Paris.
He's an adventurer.
He has done everything you can think of
every tribal initiation.
And that's the one that he refused to do
it for him.
Keeping Dick tact dealt those crazy
guys.
Cut Your Dick.
The sand or the oldest inhabitants of
southern Africa where they have lived
for almost 20,000
years.
The term San is commonly used to refer
to a diverse group.
Diverse group of hunter gatherers living
in South Africa.
Share historical linguistic connections.
Many now except the term Bushman or
sand.
Is that,
that's bushmen hunting.
Is that from the radio lab thing?
That's what they call themselves.
You see article here,
which I would imagine,
yeah.
Is it the same?
But is that the same with the uh,
the horrible circumcision ritual?
I'll double check.
Yeah,
the hall,
it's fucking horrible.
But they were arguing in the,
the,
when they were discussing it and one of
the guys who was on and who had actually
been through it and now I believe he
lives,
he lives,
maybe he lives in America,
but he was saying he would never have
his children go through that.
But he,
but it made him who he is.
And the idea was that not only are these
guys physically gifted,
but they also have unbelievable,
unbelievable pain tolerance and mental
endurance and just mental toughness.
And that this is one of the reasons why
they become so successful is that the
ability to push a pace for two plus
miles or whatever it is,
their marathon time is not just
dependent upon their physical ability,
but also dependent upon their ability to
endure pain and to force themselves
past,
you know,
anyone could kind of trot along at a
really leisurely pace and it's not
painful,
but if you're going to hard,
no,
you're really going hard.
This is the radio lab.
This Kenya.
Yeah,
it's the,
yeah.
Cut.
Pogie I think is,
ah,
here we go.
So,
um,
before you,
uh,
I mean,
well I've,
I've kind of described it,
but they describe it even more detail
in the podcast.
It's,
that almost crosses over to,
I mean,
again,
I'm not advocating what you just
genitalia mutilation,
I'm not advocating that.
But there's that idea of adversity
training that like if you're ever in the
gym,
he's like,
what you training?
And it's just like strength,
what you're training speed.
And this is why,
you know,
I'm a huge fan of Wim Hoff because so
often what he's doing when he's
submerged in ice cold,
it's like,
well I'm training my cup.
Hilary's,
yeah.
What do you mean you're training your
cup?
Hillary's and it's,
these were atrophying,
these age old inbuilt mechanisms.
So again,
I'm not advocating,
you know,
what general,
but do you remember king tolerance,
teaching tolerance?
Do you think that I that's maybe
missing,
I mean,
again,
looking at mma like maybe that you,
you see,
you know,
whether it's uh,
moo tie and they're like kicking trees
and stuff.
Yeah.
Granted that's,
you know,
making denser bones and stuff.
But do you think there's that element as
well?
And when you look at,
um,
what was it?
Um,
I forgot what it was now,
but you just start looking at just
putting people in high stress situations
just to see how they're going to cope.
Like John Fit.
He was like notorious for letting people
almost try and submit him and then they
tie themselves out.
He was just completely calm.
And then
that really depends on who's choking
you.
Cause Josh Kirkman choked him completely
unconscious.
Okay.
Yeah,
yeah.
You know,
Berchmans got a hell of a guillotine and
John Fitch shot in on them and Berkman
caught them and the good team to sleep
and the first round,
right.
I think it,
there's,
there's guys that can just put you to
sleep.
Right.
Okay.
If you think that you can get away with
that shit with like a Marcello Garcia,
you're going to wake up going,
what happened?
Okay.
Yeah.
Most guys won't be able to choke you.
So to that point,
you know,
and again,
I'm catching up on 157 days.
If you have c in his life,
it was actually out at sea with the
Mcgregor and could beep.
But on that note,
do you think he tapped premature?
Do you think there's not asleep?
Mcgregor went to sleep.
Oh,
that in that fight,
I thought you meant John Fishing net
crank,
right?
No,
he did not tap premature.
Um,
he did not defend it though.
K,
here's the deal.
He was done.
He was beaten down.
Khabib fucked him up.
Could be smashed him.
But there was a lot of people that don't
train and this was very frustrating to
me.
Like there are as many people that don't
train that think that that was something
that you shouldn't tap to there.
They're out of their fucking mind.
Okay.
That is what's called a fulcrum Cho.
That's okay.
It's,
it's not necessarily a choke,
but it is.
It chokes you,
but it really feels like you're fucking
head's going to pop off.
What he's doing is he's wrapping around
the face and you don't have to even go
under the jaw.
You can get it on the chin,
especially if you're as strong as could
bead.
Then you clamp your hands together and
you're pressing your forearm against his
back.
So you've got this and you've got the
forum against his back and you're doing
this.
Just leave his fucking head.
It's just like it's,
and Khabib is so strong.
His Greg,
he's been grappling since he was a baby.
All of his muscles are designed to
squeeze and crush smash and he gets a
hold of your neck in that position and
he's got that forearm pressed against
your back.
See if you can find an image of the
actual submission.
You could really clearly see what he's
doing.
And then there was a video where dean
lister and my friend Hans Molan camp
described it as pulling that up and it's
been taken off instagram for that video
to Hahn's Molin Camp Dean lister video.
Well maybe someone to re posted it and
that link is gone,
but yeah.
Huh.
Um,
did you tech Dean listers?
That's so weird.
Wonder why anybody would take that down.
Anyway,
there's guys who could fuck your face up
without even going under the neck.
A good example.
Here's another good example.
Just pull this up.
You got it.
Okay.
The one from right after the fight,
but he's still describing it.
Oh,
okay.
this is perfect.
This is perfect.
So Dean lister,
who's a world champion,
Brazilian jujitsu black belt,
as legit as it gets,
and this is my friend Hahn's Moline
camp.
He's also Brazilian Jiu Jitsu black belt
and see,
see,
this is exactly what could be.
Did see how it's forearm is pressed
against the back and the arm is under
the chin.
See,
the differences with Dean is doing,
he can't even help himself.
He's immediately putting his arms,
his hands on the arm that's choking him.
That's what you're supposed to do.
Now,
if you look at what connor did,
Conard just waited until he couldn't
take it anymore and tapped.
Right?
Right.
When you see conor,
both of his arms are down,
he's getting his neck crank and he
doesn't do this.
That's what you're supposed to do.
He's supposed to do two on one and then
you dropped out.
Like,
look at this,
see what he's doing there.
He's tapping.
But see where his left arm,
his left arm should not this you.
You can't,
you can't do that.
See,
that is a perfect example of the fulcrum
choke.
See how he's doing that?
Pressing his forearm against the back,
squeezing the head.
It's,
it's a neck crank.
It's a choke.
There's a lot of shit going on there.
It doesn't have to be under the chin.
It could just be on your face and you're
going to get fucked up.
So all those folks out there that were
saying that it wasn't a choke need to go
have someone apply that to them.
They need to start training Jujitsu and
stop fucking talking about MMA
submissions cause they don't die that
you're going to tap bitch.
Don't say you're not going to tap.
You get a fucking tap.
Right.
Not everybody's going to tap from that
because other people,
unlike connor,
are going to be better at defending
that.
They're going to get like you get a hold
of a worldclass Brazilian Jiu Jitsu
black belt who's also an MMA fighter
like um,
like vinny magallanes.
He's going to grab a hold of that.
He's going to defend properly.
He's going to adjust.
He's going to try to get out of that.
He might have to tap if someone gets him
in it.
I mean he people tap,
but he's,
he's not going to just have one arm
posted.
That's just not the right way to handle
it.
But I think that's because connor had
eaten
bombs when I was about to I,
so that's all technical.
So you,
so there's that almost as a,
as a,
I don't know,
like a continuum.
There's technical,
which you've just,
you didn't bring it.
And then,
and again I should point out,
you know,
again,
I'm a complete layman when it comes to a
mixed martial arts,
but I find it fascinating the,
this adversity training aspects.
So you were just saying he was eating
bombs before that would have,
would it have helped you know that if he
wasn't,
do you know what I mean?
Where,
where does it cross over from being,
it would help if he wasn't as tired.
So like if that choke was applied during
the first few seconds or minutes of the
first round,
I think he probably would have had a
good chance to survive.
Okay.
What's going on,
put on dean lister as equal.
Chokan is not,
it's not being done well,
but this is a diff,
this is not an exact,
you'll choke.
This is,
this is a,
what this is is,
I mean it's kind of an Ezekiel,
but see where his hand is.
You got to really get underneath.
See his left hand.
That left hand's got to go,
not just there.
It's got to go under the chin.
That's not good enough for a guy like
dean.
You got,
I'll get now it's pretty fucking tight.
Now it's tight and he's got to get
further and further.
And the further that left arm gets into
jeans,
neck,
the more more.
There's going to be a possibility of him
choking.
But Dean has been fucking choked his
whole life,
which is,
but I do have to say that Josh Barnett
bade him tap and Josh Barnett is like
one of the few guys that's made dean
lister tap.
And I think the first time he tapped in
a decade and Josh Barnett got him in a
scarf hold.
Um,
and that was in Metamorris.
And Josh Barnett who is a,
he's a catch wrestling specialist.
Yeah,
go to the very end of it here.
Josh Barnett gets a hold of deans.
He gets it.
C in this position right here.
He's inside control,
which is just impressive enough that
Josh was able to do this with a guy like
dean lister,
but then he gets him in.
What's a,
I don't know,
he probably has a different name for it,
but it's a,
we used to call it judo side control.
It's quite a bit further down on this.
You've got to keep going,
keep going,
keep going all the way to the end.
So he gets a hold of his,
he's got a head and arm choke.
Here it is.
So he's got his head and his arm trapped
together and Josh,
who's an enormously powerful person is
really neck cranking him as much as
anything.
And then dean was forced to tap,
but this is at the end of a long match
and you know,
it could have been exhaustion,
might've played a part in it.
It most certainly was josh.
His skill and his ability to apply that
technique.
But the point is,
is a guy like dean lister,
you,
you're not going to tap that guy easy.
But this is an,
again,
again with sort of holding my hands up
saying I'm so sort of naive,
a huge fan of Evan May,
but not necessarily any of the technical
aspects.
But what I love
is when you look at someone like you
know,
Nick Diaz,
all Michael Bisping,
you know,
people don't understand his conditioning
and he will just wear people down.
Massive mental toughness to would
bisping has is just insane mental
toughness.
You know,
bisping basically has one eye.
If you look at his eyes,
his one of his,
I actually,
and I hope he can get surgery on it now
because he has retired,
he has oil like embedded in his eye to
protect his retina because it's been
torn so many times been torn.
He had surgery on it,
he had a repair torn again.
His right eye is fucked up man.
And one of the reasons why he retired as
he started to see some irregularities in
his vision in his left eye.
So as good I was fucking up too.
But I mean,
Michael Bisping is a fucking animal.
I mean he is,
he is about as tough as it gets.
And he's not like a spectacularly
physically talented guy like a Jon Jones
or Yoel Romero who was just this
unbelievable specimen.
Michael's a,
you know,
a really good athlete unquestionably.
But it just taught just fucking tufts.
So to answer your question,
there's,
there's this in,
you could speak to this because what
you're talking about,
the ability to overcome adversity like
some people when you were talking about
that fatigue is an emotionally driven
thing that there's this feeling that you
get and you can give in to that feeling
where you're like,
oh my God,
I'm fuck,
I fucking can't do this anymore.
And some people are more susceptible to
that than others and they give into it
quickly.
I mean,
for a person,
here's,
here's where you can experience this.
Like what is,
whether or not your mindset can affect
your,
your endurance,
get on a treadmill or a stationary bike
or whatever you want to do for cardio.
And then listened to a really kick ass
song and put on headphones and that song
comes on and you just can't fucking,
Eh,
you could just go,
there's something about that.
And even if you're tired,
even if you're tired and you've put on a
good song,
like fuck that,
we're going to keep going like that.
Nothing has happened.
You haven't taken in any kind of a
supplement or any kind of a stimulant
that you haven't gotten an injection in
your body or you're not sucking on some
kind of new gas.
Your body's exactly the same.
But through the motivation that you're
getting from this music,
the emotional stimulation,
you're just like,
fuck that.
We're going to keep going.
Yeah.
And you can keep going.
And not only can you keep going,
you can go faster,
you could push harder.
You can find these reserves.
So the idea is that these reserves are
always there.
You have to be able to achieve this
state of mind that you achieve when you
hear a really good song.
You know,
and that's true that I think people
don't understand.
You are the outcomist of your own body
that you know in terms of
neurotransmitter's chemical signals in
the brain,
you can impact though sometimes.
Yeah,
you need extended liveness his music,
because you spoke about sometimes you
know caffeine,
but
when you start to control them,
yeah,
it can be so powerful.
Some people do it naturally,
I suppose,
and they've just got it in built.
But when you start to trend,
and I think it's only now that we're,
we're going down that route and looking
at that as a,
you know,
until previously it was one of those
intangibles that you,
you,
you kind of under appreciate it in any
sport and now we're going,
oh,
okay.
Yeah.
You know,
that person over there is,
you know,
that mental fortitude or what you're
talking about there is maybe their
ability to alter their own chemistry,
biochemical reactions,
the body and yeah,
there's something real that happens,
right?
Yeah.
When you hear a song and you get
excited,
like whatever that hair,
whatever that that burst is.
It seems like a real,
like if that was a pill and you took it,
you be like,
oh this works.
Absolutely.
And the thing is is it's been around
years when you look at like um,
you know Marcus Aurelius Meditations
will stomach philosophy and they're
talking about you know,
dialogue being both external,
internal.
So the,
the conversations that go on inside your
own head to just as important as the
conversations that we have with other
people.
So we've understood this for years,
but it's only just now that we're trying
to kind of apply a little bit of science
to it,
looking at the psychology in this mind
body connection,
but the fact is yes,
some of the greatest ancient stoics they
were trying to figure out as well.
And when you can start to tap into that,
where that can become and,
and it might be a particular song,
you know,
might be a bit,
is something,
you know,
if you get into,
you're going to a gym or that you've got
a friend that can bring the out of you.
Again,
you knew my training back home.
So you know,
Andrew Bolton,
who was the,
the first guy to dead lift a thousand
pounds.
I mean,
cheeses.
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean thousand pounds.
Yeah,
I mean the,
the clip when you see it and he pulls a
thousand pounds per se.
It's since been being by Eddie Hall who
did a half the time.
So he did lift off.
Fuck.
Editing isn't a half a ton of thousand
pounds that a little bit less.
So I think thousand pounds.
What's that for?
I thought a ton was 2000 pounds,
isn't it?
So yet,
uh,
Eddie,
what's a thousand pounds in kilos?
Oh,
you're trying to kill us.
Sorry.
The two.
So yeah,
there was two metrics there.
So Andy Bolton,
which was a little bit 0.2
kilos per pound.
No 2.2
pounds per kilo.
Yeah.
And then,
yeah,
and when you see him,
I mean this is what I love when you
start looking at Jesus Christ as this is
Eddie,
that's his,
that's his half a teller fucker.
His knees staying together.
Right there you look at is,
if you look at how big his body is and
how normal sizes,
knees are,
look at the bones in his knees.
They look so normal.
Yeah.
I mean that dies fucking people I know.
It's unbelievable.
Unbelievable.
Oh my God.
So when those guys retire,
how fucked up or their bodies,
how would,
do you know Eddie's law?
What's brilliant about the bees tattooed
his inside of his arm.
So he's going to argue with them.
Yeah,
you're a fucking beast.
And he's nose was bleeding.
Oh,
that's right.
Right.
His nose started spraying blood while he
was without him or another guy though I
think you on another video,
Arnold,
I forgotten his name.
He was
Russian and just shit.
But I mean Eddie against the strength,
especially with the dead lift such as
simple movement and,
and you know the dead lift is just
strength is your body's ability to
generate force in.
So it's neuro Musculus like what your,
your brain is telling your body.
So that goes back to that strength
deficit that we were talking about.
Your basically santee or your body
recruit every single muscle fiber
possible and working conjunctions with
ligaments and tendons and then let's get
half a ton off the floor.
Exactly right.
But when you look,
and certainly with,
with Andy Barnes,
a thousand pound lift,
he had his friend in his face and he's,
they're going to come,
I go and he's hitting him in the face
when we were talking earlier about
against strength deficits is,
is that sort of deficit between what you
can voluntarily contract an involuntary
contract that was him obviously
voluntarily can drag there.
No one was alleged human that pretty
particular one.
But they're there and you do anything
that you can before you actually step
out onto that platform.
And now,
I mean,
he would have just been completely
written off after that,
that sort of Adrenal dump afterwards.
He'd,
you know,
emotionally,
but,
and so you have to,
you have to think about that.
Have I forgotten who said it now?
It might have been prevail,
but they said,
you know,
a safe fatigue for competition.
And I know you've spoken about that
before,
so,
um,
I can't remember.
He was speaking to levels are
fascinating guy with his concepts.
Amazing.
Yeah.
So,
so ahead of the curve,
and I know you were talking to,
I can't remember who it was now,
talking about farmers strength and that
ability to stop short every single day.
So never necessarily going to complete
failure,
but it was for us,
for us a hobby,
I think it was.
Yeah.
Um,
talking about continually kind of
avoiding that exhaustion phase and
solely existing in the adaptation phase.
So,
you know,
I mean,
this goes back to sell you sort of 1936,
a Hungarian physician who found,
you know,
you give a,
it took some lab rats,
give them a lethal dose of poison.
They kill over and die.
But he found by giving them a little bit
of poison and a little bit more,
a little bit more that they built up
this intolerance to it.
And that was the general adaptation
syndrome.
But it was from that that we discovered
stress and stimuli is the key to any
adaptation.
And it wasn't until the strength and
conditioning community cottoned on to
that.
And we started to think,
okay,
how can we apply stress and stimulate to
the body to bring about a desired
result.
And I think certainly now,
I think that's kind of overlooked in
sport,
but certainly the Wida fitness industry
that,
you know,
it's,
it's easy now in very sort of marketing
driven to say get fit in,
you know,
five easy steps or you know,
whereas the reality is,
you know,
it's get fit in eight months after a lot
of stress and stimuli,
but then get fit in five easy steps is
really just for,
it's just a gimmick to get people who
don't actually work out to get involved.
It is.
And,
but,
and that's why I love what you
broadcast.
And even with the sober October and
stuff.
I mean,
I'm a huge fan of burt,
but people,
and I know he's,
he's so funny and loves Berg,
but
he's a beast as well.
I mean,
when it to rock up and just do a
marathon and again,
that's a power to weight ratio.
What he did was amazing and I've say
he's really fat.
I'm not saying,
I would never say Oh was okay,
wink wink.
Gotcha.
I get it.
He's a burly guy.
He's a well built a nice way.
He's a well built mail.
Somebody took a picture of my face,
I'm burns body and I was fucking threw
up or what if I were there?
I'm like,
no.
Yeah,
he likes
drink and he's still,
he's,
he is a beast because he,
despite the fact that he doesn't look
like rich roll,
he's still can keep going.
Um,
people,
I don't know.
He was,
he was very entertaining.
We did the marathon and stuff,
but I was actually watching that as the
sport's scientist in me was like,
that's amazing.
And no one's talking about that.
His,
his power to weight ratio and he's still
running that raffin something that and
and yeah,
so first as funny and as entertaining
it,
it was to watch,
I honestly was like Bert,
that's amazing.
What's more amazing is Ari honestly,
cause Ari really didn't work out.
Ari came in second place and he came in
second place by only a thousand points,
which is a one day I got a thousand
points in a day.
So he was really only a thousand points
behind me but it's a crazy day.
That's like a seven hours of work in a
day or so.
At least six and a half hours of work in
a day and a lot of it at 80% of your max
heart rate.
But he still,
he wasn't doing anything before this
thing started and he was the first one
to figure out that you get the same
amount of points for 80% of your Max
heart rate as you do for 90 I thought
you'd get more for 90 so I was just
trying to kill myself every day and then
I was only being able to come out with
like 230 points and and similar along
those lines,
because I was,
I would max out,
it was doing like 90% of my max heart
rate for like 30 35 minutes.
I was like exhausted.
And then Ari figured out that 80 points
pays just as much.
Right.
And so he started watching movies while
he was on an elliptical machine and that
that just turned the whole thing into
this sort of steady,
not fast marathon,
which was really fascinating because I
never exercised like that before and it
changed my endurance radically over a
month.
What's interesting is that changed my
endurance in things that are explosive,
like kickboxing.
Okay.
What's it say having that aerobic base a
lot?
How did he
set in?
So I would do,
I would do,
after a while we were doing so much
exercise and I had to do different
things or I would get bored.
So I would do a circuit of the
elliptical machine and then I would
follow the elliptical machine with,
um,
a war.
Or I would do,
I would run on Sundays,
I'd either run elliptical machine,
kickbox,
and on other days I would do the echo
bike,
which is an airdyne machine that rogue
makes.
And then I would do the rowing machine
and then I would do the versaclimber
and then I added in that air runner
treadmill,
which is,
what is it called?
Air Assault,
I think.
Air Assault.
Treadmill.
Yeah.
Which is a treadmill that you power
yourself,
you,
your feet pushing on it and pulling it
is what makes it go fast.
It's not like a treadmill that you keep
up with.
It's actually more difficult than actual
running.
Great.
Right,
right.
13% more difficult and actual running on
the street.
So I d I was going crazy.
I couldn't do the same things over and
over again.
So I kept mixing them up and when I
would mix them up by the end of the
month,
my kickboxing was,
I had way more endurance.
Like I could do 10 hard rounds going
three minutes each round and then I
would recover in between rounds.
The one minute in between rounds I'd
recover quick cause I'm wearing a heart
rate monitor and watching my heart rate
dip.
It was dipping really quickly.
And then I had all this energy and
madness like everything was changing.
Like my,
my capacity for work changed,
everything adapted.
I got a little dehydrated one time and I
had pissed.
It looked like ice tea,
which is not good.
So I started panicking and wondering
about things like rob dough,
my locis kidney failure,
but I didn't have anything wrong with
that.
It was just a little bit of penetration.
But what's interesting to go about,
what we were talking about that you've
just perfectly described,
that idea of,
of given a clear cellular signal to the
body.
So polarized training.
If you know the 80 20 that you do,
80% of your,
you know,
your work,
your training in that aerobic realm
where you can keep doing that,
it's,
you're not going to overtrain there,
you're going to avoid that exhaustion
things he says,
Salvia indestructable rats,
you know,
you're not going to keel over and die
from a lethal dose of stress and
stimuli.
But then over here,
you know you would that 20% it was
powerful.
It was kickboxing.
So there you're working technique but
you're fresh.
So you're drilling motor patterns that
completely fresh and not fatigued
because you're doing this 80% on an
elliptical trainer while watching a
movie.
So you teach,
you're keeping the two completely
separate.
Yes.
But considering the body in its entirety
that when it comes together,
you've created a more powerful version
of yourself.
And I think it was interesting what you
just said there about recovery between
bouts as well.
So when you start looking at a strong
man training,
you know,
the,
some of the strongest guys and that one
of the strongest guys in the world all
understood the benefits of,
of cardio spiritually training.
You look at you again,
geoff capes.
Um,
two time world's strongest man was
running fell racism marathons at 25.
So fillery's fellow races.
It's,
yeah,
it's quite specific to England.
So it's kind of trail running,
but we call them fellow running because
you're going to going through bogs and
marshes and felled trees.
Not,
not necessarily fell cheese,
but just kind of the terrain is a little
bit different from Troy said he was
doing that.
When you look at our Bill Kasman again,
well the strongest man a power lifter,
but understood the benefits of,
of cardiorespiratory trying to improve
his recovery between sets.
Brian Shaw as well.
One of the,
uh,
you know,
the sort of,
uh,
you know,
the newest as sort of strong man and a
former basketball player,
you know,
so he had that cardio respiratory
endurance that base the aerobic base,
and then he built this incredible
strength on top of that aerobic
foundation goes back again to whether,
you know,
they knew it or not,
they were almost creating an athlete.
Like they were creating athletes back
in,
uh,
the sort of Soviet Union era when they
were taking athletes going,
right,
you're giving me a kid and I don't know
if he's strong,
quick,
good at running,
running fast or running fight,
I don't know.
So we're going to build this aerobic
neuromuscular base and when they show
any sort of genetic potential to be
strong,
quick,
whatever,
we're going to hone in on that.
And that's only when we're going to get
specific.
And you're almost doing that now,
you know,
and certainly Brian Schorr did it again.
You look,
you look through all of the best
athletes in the world.
They've all followed this blueprint,
but it's only now that we're kind of
dissecting that and saying,
okay,
I'm making it a bit more purposeful.
Who's this gentlemen?
Here we go,
there's Brian Shore.
He said,
yeah,
bass run with his legs were all swollen,
but I mean even now I tell you what
Jamie,
if it's possible,
actually,
I mean Brian Shore,
he accidentally,
you must have seen this clip set,
the indoor rowing record.
I think it was for a hook in this size
of this mother fucker.
Oh my God.
And he rocks.
Converse.
All stars.
Look at that.
Cool.
He set the visit visit clip on Youtube.
That memo man's wearing chucks.
He sets,
there's a clip on youtube where he sets
the,
the rowing record,
the indoor rowing record and it was just
because he,
yeah,
there we go.
He didn't know he was setting in.
So these basically down there,
he's rowing and it sounds like someone
started an engine like this.
He go and we're here at this,
said this,
they've just looked at how he rose to
the mountain.
These look the whole thing.
They have to hold it down in the end
cause he's coming out of the floor.
Jesus Christ.
These guys are standing on it.
It sounds like,
like just an that's a jet engine,
right?
We're all that power from it.
Exactly.
Well no and he's bad.
I mean that technique as well.
I mean I hope Brian doesn't mind me
saying it's not necessarily,
you know,
Olympic rowing technique,
but he doesn't need it cause he's just
got silly power technique.
So the hundred well there's a catch
phase and it's more,
you're almost treating it more like a
dead lift where you're using your larger
leg muscles where,
which is
look at him go,
there you go.
Oh my God.
Fuck it.
Savage.
Oh crazy.
To Watch.
Unbelievable amount of force he can
generate.
He looks like a very tall man too.
He's huge.
How big is this guy?
Six eight,
six,
nine.
So that helps too.
Right?
Cause the long stroke.
Absolute.
It's just pure power.
But anyway,
so they found that they,
during this session,
I believe what happened is they said,
well you know a rower shouldn't make
that sort of noisy.
He goes six ways that he's basically two
put together for what?
401 600 8,425
that's two big guys strapped together in
one body.
He's almost 200 pounds above the UFC
heavyweight limit.
Deon saying that is UFC heavyweight,
limit it to 65 he's almost 200 pounds
too heavy to fight heavyweight division
of the UFC motherfucker basketball,
basketball background.
And,
and he's still,
look,
he didn't know that he was going to set
the world record for rowing.
So the rowing record,
they go,
here's one was 12.8
I believe it was 1308 broke the wrong
record.
But because he had that neuro
neuromuscular background that they said,
Hey Brian,
you're big and powerful,
just this is a rowing machine.
He went,
oh,
okay.
And it's like,
oh,
there you go.
Congratulations.
There's a world record.
So it's that base that I think so often
I've heard you speak about,
and certainly Eddie as well talking
about,
um,
breakdancers making great.
Yes.
And again,
whether you knew or not,
they had that neuromuscular foundation.
They understood proprioception,
where the ligaments,
tendons,
everything should work.
Whereas if you had someone with a
similar work capacity or someone at the
same age,
everything was the same,
but they didn't have that neuromuscular
efficiency,
you'd say,
okay,
and again,
this is me.
So naively,
again,
I certainly don't claim to know anything
about Bjj,
but you go,
okay,
this is an arm bar.
This is,
I think they kind of go,
okay,
let me try and figure this out.
And you can see them.
It's like a Rubik's cube.
They're trying to piece it together.
But you get someone again,
like Brian and you go,
okay,
this is Bj Jay,
or something quite complex that requires
you and he,
I'm not saying he wouldn't even fight.
It's too,
it's too heavy.
Then I have to open up the super heavy
division,
but he was doing a similar movement to
dead lifts,
which is very common.
It is.
And when he's used to that movement,
it is.
Yeah,
But I suppose where you saw him,
you know that wasn't actually,
there was no extension of the back.
He was bent over.
Just repeat.
There's another one again,
even to use Brian is an example where he
does,
uh,
I believe,
I can't remember the name of the ward
now,
but he went up,
um,
and four as well.
Another strong man did a,
uh,
I think it was a,
I might clean and jerk.
There was a ward that was predominantly
clean and jerk and there's this amazing
crossfitter technique was beautiful,
disappearing under the bar,
back over his head.
It was amazing to watch and I think it
was thor or Brian Shaw went in and just
instead of a clean and jerk and Joe,
honestly,
he just basically upright rows,
the whole thing and complete.
And they were like,
well that's not clean and jerk,
but you just set a record again.
So there's that element.
And to use an example as well with,
with the,
Oh,
here we go.
Here we go.
Oh my God,
it's insane.
Wait,
hopefully it is a crop.
That is insane.
Okay.
There's another strongly,
but there is,
there's another one of those where you
see the crossfit or with this amazing,
beautiful technique.
He's so far from his justice crazy that
he's doing it like that.
And what is that 225 pounds as though I
don't actually know what everything from
the fucking
shit that is so crazy that he could do
that.
Look at how he's doing so many reps.
Right,
right.
That is insane.
But he doesn't have a pause.
No,
but back he said that's meant to be a
clean joke.
I know.
So that's what I mean about that neuro
muscular efficiency that he's gone,
okay,
here's a new sport.
Come and get involved.
And he's going,
okay,
I see the rules of your sport,
but I'm going to do it my way and it
doesn't count.
Well,
yeah,
I suppose,
I mean if that word is just put the
weight above your head,
um,
like duck,
I did it normal that time right there.
That's it.
Yeah.
But there's,
there's,
um,
if you put in,
you know,
thor,
uh,
versus crossfit there,
then it will probably come up and you
get to see an amazing crisp technique.
And then equally,
um,
thor is basically doing what,
what Brian was doing just there.
I'll you go.
So this is their keep putting on weight
until one of them.
I believe that competition as you keep
it or not.
Yeah,
they're your crossfit versus a mountain.
It's an amazing technique.
Disappears under the bar,
you know,
incredible.
And then I think,
you know,
thor would eventually come in and give
it a go and basically just I'm upright
rows,
here we go.
So you saw that,
you know,
disappears under the bus,
speed of movement.
Amazing.
And then all come,
come and have a go at this and a,
this is what he,
he produces.
So there's that neuromuscular
efficiency.
There was just mad strength.
It is.
I mean,
you could do that too if you just had an
empty bar.
You know what I mean?
Like that kind of person.
The kind of person that can do that.
When you think about him dead lifting a
thousand pounds or any of these guys who
can deadlift in insane numbers,
just the whole machine can generate so
much force.
Yeah.
And that,
and that's it though.
It's,
it is.
They're able to do that again because of
that foundation.
They body can generate that force and
then you say,
here's a new movement and you can see
them look like for that example of a
case.
So that's a clean and jerk.
Okay.
I can't figure that out.
I think I've found a way,
lends credence to the concept that dead
lifts is like the mother of all
exercises because it really does work.
All your muscle groups and if you can
get really strong at dead lifts,
I mean it really does enhance almost any
single athletic endeavor you participate
in.
Yeah.
And I think again,
that's sort of been lost a little bit
along the way that they're getting the
joints,
ligaments,
muscles,
everything to work cohesively.
And when you do that for your training,
you can pretty much apply to anything.
So I think that's why,
I mean I again,
I used to swim ages ages ago,
way back in the day,
but I was never going to make sort of an
elite standard.
I'm five,
nine on a good day,
maybe I'm built like a hobbit.
So
everyone else is just great grace for,
yeah,
so
I ended up,
again almost accidentally going into
strength training.
I played water polo in the end,
um,
to a fairly good level.
So I was doing that.
But again I just got beaten up.
I was 16 playing in the senior's league
and you just big guys with beards just
beating me up.
It's interesting what you were talking
about earlier in terms of mental
fortitude and your ability to adapt and
your ability to overcome.
I wonder if we're ever going to figure
out a way to measure that.
Like to measure in d mental endurance or
measure mental capacity or mental
stimulation.
You know,
you can measure your vo two Max and you
know what the body's capable of.
But I wonder if there's a way,
like when someone does hear a great song
and it kicks in,
whether it's through Fsri or any other
type of detection device where they can
figure out a way,
oh this part of your brain is firing,
let's concentrate on building up the,
the activation of that part of that
brain of the brain.
Like,
like muscle when like,
think of that endurance or think of that
motivation as like maybe even a mantra
that you can call upon.
Cause he call upon it all the time and
he can recreate that state.
Yeah,
I mean,
I think on,
on that point,
certainly over in Britain at the moment.
So,
um,
uh,
basically,
a women for the first time can actually
apply and be in the special forces.
So at the moment is really,
really interesting because I'm speaking
to you certainly the Royal Marines,
they were saying,
we've got hundreds of years that if you
hand is 500 young fit men,
we can say they need to be this weight,
this tall.
And if you give as them,
we've got years and years of experience
of putting them through this training
system of mental and physical fortitude,
everything down in lympstone,
it's the,
the,
the training center of the Royal
Marines.
And we go on this insurance costs,
we go on a 30 mile young with a
backpack,
everything.
And by the end of 32 weeks,
that's what it takes to be a royal
marine to get your green baret after 32
weeks,
we can take you from being completely,
not sedan tree,
but unfit to being a royal marine.
And that's one thing they pride
themselves on.
But now what they're saying is
obviously,
you know,
females can apply to the special forces.
And what they find so interesting is,
and I certainly do as well,
is what,
what does that look like for a female
role marine?
You know,
what does that look like for the themes?
And again,
to go back,
I mean,
I wrote an article ages ago,
um,
run like a girl and I was saying,
I want to run like a girl.
You know,
some of them,
some of my best training partners are
female and they,
their perception to fatigue is
unbelievable.
That's purely anecdotal.
But also as well,
when you look at the top tier of ultra
marathon runners and swimming as well,
Diana Niaid first to go from Florida to
Cuba to Florida,
you know,
incredible.
Like she was getting stung by Portuguese
manowar's and stuff.
Just unbelievable.
So it's purely debts,
but now the saying,
you know,
w why is it that that certainly my
athletes have a,
a greater tolerance to pain.
And I think to your point,
if we can start to quantify that,
because there are biological
differences.
If you take men,
high testosterone can have an impact on
high hemoglobin,
generate muscle force,
all of these things.
But,
but I think if we could quantify why it
is
that certain female athletes are
dominating the top 10% of ultra
marathons and an open water swimming,
what is it that they're doing that would
be amazing?
I think the ability to endure pain,
and this is not my thought,
honestly,
I should just say this has been
theorized before,
has to do with their ability to endure
the pain of childbirth,
child labor and childbirth.
I mean just the fact that they're
forcing a baby out of their vagina.
Yeah.
I mean that is insane.
I mean,
we aren't too.
Have you ever seen the machine?
They do.
They've taken these electrodes,
they put it on men and recreate the pain
of childbirth Ed and watch these men
funding to fall apart.
Like fucking turn it off.
Yeah,
it's,
I mean obviously I haven't given birth,
but it's supposed to be unbelievably
painful and women are biologically
suited to this.
This is like,
so I think their ability to endure that
pain is just,
it's probably just,
there's an evolutionary advantage to
having this more higher capacity.
But I also think one of the things that
I learned from teaching martial arts is
that women,
they learned technique better many times
then men do because one,
they listen and two,
they don't try to muscle things.
So women have less of a problem with
learning something from a person.
And this is also true about archery.
My friend John Dudley,
who is an archery coach,
says his favorite students are always
women because they listen better.
Um,
they don't have as much of an ego.
They don't have to pretend they already
know something.
They don't want to just try it without
it.
They follow it to a t better.
Like generally,
obviously we're speaking in
generalities,
but um,
they also don't have the uh,
extra muscle that a man has.
So men,
when they're strong,
we'll try to just force things,
muscle things where women will try to
follow what's being described to them,
what's the proper technique and they do
it properly all the time.
And then they develop this pattern of
proper technique.
I noticed this with taekwondo and I
think my friend John said he,
oh,
he noticed this with archery.
I think this,
this,
this benefits them in sports because
like if you learn Jujitsu,
you really the best people to learn from
our smaller men or women because they,
the smaller people,
they don't have the physical strength to
pull it off on a big guy.
So what they have to rely on is correct
technique.
But if you learn Jujitsu from a big guy,
man,
big Guy Jujitsu's weird because they
could just grab your wrist and you can't
get go.
You can't let go and they can get away
with things like,
okay,
you go risk control and throw the legs
up.
Risk Control.
Okay risk control on who try risk
control on that big mother fucker that
was rowing the world record.
You ain't getting shit man.
You're going to go flying through the
air that was controlling it or work.
Right.
You're going to have to go against his
strength.
You're going to have to figure out a way
to move around it.
You don't have to go,
you're not going to go through it.
Right.
That big guy,
if he was teaching Jujitsu who I just
grabbed her neck and on your squeeze
he's,
he's got the kind of horsepower that a
man like you know a normal man can't
imagine.
Yeah.
Do you think that's changing again to
bring it back to the UFC I suppose.
Cause now,
I mean with what call me,
he's doing and,
and you know John Jones coming back then
the lightweights,
we're all moving up to heavyweight.
Do you think,
you know,
gone are the days of the huge dude who
was just a physical phenom and now the
smaller technical dues is that there's a
thought with the 265 pound weight class
and the consensus thought seems to be
that somewhere around 240 pounds is the
magic number.
That's what they think.
They think that 240 pounds is the amount
of weight that you have where you're
strong enough that you can knock out any
man,
right?
But you have more endurance than a man
that may be ways to 65 or heavier and
cuts down to two 65 okay.
Now this is not been substantiated.
The problem is there hasn't been a
really super powerful world championship
athlete that weighed 265 pounds.
There's been brock Lesnar,
but brock Lesnar's enhanced,
right?
You're dealing with a guy who tested
positive for steroids.
He probably has had things and then this
is a new world.
He's also 40 years old now,
so it's impossible to tell what he would
have been like at 30 if he was clean.
And then you have guys like Francis and
Ghana who was 265 pounds,
massive knockout artists,
natural 265 pounds but doesn't have the
wrestling base got exposed and his fight
with Steve Bay Meo church and you can't
knock you out.
He's kind of doomed and he tired out
after the first round.
Okay,
so it's hard to say cause there's never
been a 265 pound version of Cain
Velasquez.
Okay.
Cain Velasquez,
my humble opinion,
when I look at all of the different
heavyweights that I've personally seen,
fight cane stands out as the best.
The reason why Keynes stands out as the
best is because he has super human
endurance.
Yeah.
And his ability to put a pace on guys.
You would see these guys just wilt under
the pressure of,
and I think with cane,
this is where it gets really
interesting.
What did him in is probably what also
brought him to the top is his mental
toughness because his body started
breaking down.
He started having all these back
injuries.
He needed back surgery,
multiple back surgeries,
shoulder surgery,
knee surgery,
everything was getting fucked up.
And I think it was getting fucked up
cause he was working through pain and
because he has the ability to tolerate
pain that most people don't have and
he's just a fucking animal.
But that's also probably what led to him
having this insane endurance is the same
kind of mental toughness.
I'm sure there's some genetic advantages
as well because they would talk about
how he would take months off and come
back still fuck everybody up because
he's just that good.
But then also can be attributed to the
cardio base that he had from competing
for many,
many,
many years at a high level and being
known for that insane endurance and
perception to fatigue.
Going back,
if you could quantify that,
you'd put cane up there with one of
those people.
He has that in abundance.
Yes.
Anyone else in the heavyweights then
would you say your core?
Me a for sure has tremendous,
uh,
fatigue,
ability to tolerate fatigue and for
tremendous endurance.
And he breaks people,
you know,
they call him the king of the grind.
And,
but on top of that,
they,
what they both have is tremendous
wrestling technique.
The tree,
the wrestling technique as well as the
endurance.
Everything plays a factor.
Jon Jones fits into that camp as well.
Jon Jones has tremendous wrestling
technique as well.
Striking technique,
massive physical skills,
but also mental toughness.
His mental toughness is an
unchallengeable.
You like you,
you absolutely have to give it up to
him.
He's had his arm fucked up by Vito
Belfort,
completely hyper extended,
refuse to tap and then went up tapping
vietor with uh,
with uh,
uh,
Americana.
I believe it was the next round and a
toe against Chael Sonnen.
Oh,
I was told was fucked up and even notice
it until I was interviewing him and I
was interviewing him.
He looked down,
I like,
Oh shit.
Look at my toe.
And he started going to shock.
Was it as bad as it was turned upside
down?
It was completely turned upside down.
I mean,
imagine that.
I mean if he wound up going into the
next round,
if he didn't stop Chael Sonnen and his
toe was that fucked up and he wound up
losing to chill son because his toe was
bad.
That's insane.
Um,
he also went through that fight with
Alexander Gustafson where he wasn't
really training very hard for that fight
and Gustafson one the first couple
rounds and then Jon Jones won the last
two to take it away.
And,
and I watched that back obviously with
all the promotion at the moment,
and I think it was winkle,
John Jackson,
when he starts shouting heart hearts,
you know,
shout out to,
and that was the,
that was the design.
I mean that's again an,
but that was the deciding factor that
you come out and you produce that.
Yeah.
Also in Jon Jones,
his favor,
I believe he has to fucking super
athlete brothers and they used to
apparently beat the shit out of each
other all the time and his brother's a
bigger than him.
Right.
I think that is a factor because I think
that there's mental toughness that comes
from being around that kind of combat in
the household all the time.
Yeah.
I think it's a bunch of different
factors,
but it's,
it's Ho you,
I don't know.
I think you can teach that.
I don't believe that mental toughness is
something that you either have or you
don't have.
I don't believe that.
I think you can teach it,
but you got to want it and you gotta be
willing to learn.
You got to be able to bring yourself to
a state of mind where you're
unbreakable.
I think it's possible.
I really do.
And some people just have that that is a
b.
And I think they've developed it over
long period of time.
And once they finally got to,
whether it's wrestling or Jujitsu or
mma,
they
already had it.
And then they accentuated it and,
and,
and added onto it and then it got
stronger and then they become known for
it.
Like that guy is just an animal.
He's just mentally strong.
But I think that mental strength comes
from many life experiences.
And probably probably the guidance of
their parents or some other role model
in their life that also showed them
incredible endurance and incredible
discipline.
And this,
this mental fortitude.
I think you can teach it though.
I think,
you know,
I said I don't,
I don't believe that it's something
that's just either have or you don't
have,
I think you either have it or you don't
have it,
but you can get it.
That's what I think.
I,
you know,
I'm a huge fan of Dan Hardee.
We've been chatting since the,
the swim and I always go back to that on
Bob with the George Saint Pierre Ev.
Everybody would its hat.
Oh yeah.
And,
and,
and I couldn't get my hat and I can't
wait to catch up with Dan about that and
sort of exchange notes on this idea of
mental fortitude because how he survived
that.
I mean,
it was,
yeah,
I was cringing watching.
Well,
Dan's a savage.
I mean,
he's,
and he's an intelligent savage and you
know,
he's,
um,
he's not like a thug or a brutish guy.
He's a very well read,
intelligent,
thoughtful guy.
Um,
but he's also a guy that knows how to
dig deep,
you know.
And you know when he fought George Saint
Pierre,
that was his big shot.
You know what I mean?
His big shot was against a guy who was
at the time was in his prime and it was
the greatest welterweight arguably of
all time.
I mean the argument is a,
it's between him,
Matt Hughes and I believe now tyron
Woodley isn't that camp as well.
It's like the greatest welterweight
ever.
But you,
what you get out of Dan Hardy is a guy
who's thought things through.
I mean it really comes through in his
commentary.
This is a very,
very intelligent guy.
Would you say he's the same sort of cut
from the same cloth as call me a them
because I know Brendan's spoke about
this recently saying he's the most
intelligent fighter on the UFC roster at
the moment.
Carmia.
Yeah.
But in his approach and his approach and
how he will break people button again,
you know,
when you watch he in a UFC embedded in
and stuff like you can't help but love
calling me such a nice guy.
But,
and this goes back to what I suppose you
said about the swim,
you know,
when it was like,
oh you're,
you're,
you're very smart and stuff.
But I see that in call me,
he's the nicest guy,
but I would never get in the octagon
with him.
He don't know fooling anyone.
No,
he's a sweetheart until you're locked in
a cage.
Fuck you up.
The difference between him and Dan
Hardee though is that he's a world class
wrestler,
right?
I mean,
he was a two time Olympic team member
and just one of the best wrestlers to
ever compete in MMA.
And you really see that in a lot of his
fights,
like the Derrick Lewis fight.
Derrick had no chance,
no chance,
you know,
and Derek just knocked out Alexander
Volkov,
who in a lot of people's eyes,
including mine,
was one of the dark horses in the
heavyweight division.
But Derek just did not belong in there
with Cormier who was the light
heavyweight champion.
And he carries a lot of fat on him.
Yeah,
he's mean.
And I think if,
if he wanted to,
if Daniel cormier really dedicated
himself,
he could drop down to 185 pounds.
I really believed that.
But he's just,
you know,
easy.
Why would,
he's a fucking heavyweight champion.
That's the difference between him and D.
There's many differences between him and
Dan.
The success ratio is very different.
You know,
courtney has been extremely successful.
The only guy who lost,
who is John Jones,
you know,
so,
but,
but I find that with rest,
and this is on a complete tangent here,
but when you talk about that mind body
connection,
like so often they're seen as separate.
You're over an intellect or you're just
a physical phenom.
Like it's rare that you see the two.
But when again,
ancient Greek philosophy,
you look at Plato,
like Plato was an accomplished,
celebrated wrestler.
I think he said something along the
lines of,
you know,
you should wrestle to find the answers
to that.
Philosophers seek.
It was,
it was something like that.
It was such an advocate of it.
And,
and I think,
and again this is coming from a,
you know,
sort of my limited background because
obviously in in Britain we don't have,
have wrestling like over,
over here and stuff,
but there's something about wrestling it
seems,
or I suppose my question to you is like
that it just teaches that like mental
fortitude yeah.
Physically,
yeah.
Neuromuscular efficiency and stuff,
but it seems to just produce this breed
of humans that,
you know,
it did you think is it's,
there's something about being face down
in a matter.
Somebody just trying to contort your
limbs,
you know,
so that took to go back to stress and
stimulate,
you know,
it's also building up that progressive
overload and your own head.
Yes.
That and what you just said there about
experiences that that quite often now
when I go swimming,
I'm like,
it's not the courier Vecan I'm not
wearing the jellyfish tentacle on my
face.
You know,
it's not that bad.
And I think what did do you,
that's where my question is.
Do you think it's the same with
wrestling that you like?
I've been in a worse position than this,
I think for sure.
I think there's the,
the strength that they have,
the intellectual strength and when I say
intellectual strength there is actually
solving puzzles and whether people
understand it or not,
you look at wrestling,
you think,
oh,
it's brute force and strength and
endurance,
but they're solving puzzles,
right?
There's setting traps.
They're trying to set up techniques and
they're doing this under heavy workload,
right?
They're exhausted,
their heart's pounding and they're
resisting 100% with another person is
resisting 100% when you see guys tie up
and throwing each other around and
they're fucking digging their toes into
the mat and wrenching as a tremendous
amount of force that they have to keep
up for minutes and minutes at a time.
And I think a lot of that has to do with
your ability to maintain intensity.
And a lot of that has to do with your
ability to tolerate being exhausted and
tolerate fatigue and to force yourself
into an in a highly aggressive and
efficient mindset and to be able to
maintain proper technique under
fatigue.
That's a good point.
Technique and intelligence.
I believe again with the Royal Marines,
we can be a Wa when training with them.
I find that it's crazy how you,
you will have the cognitive functioning
of a five year old,
you know,
you are compliant,
right?
You're in a 30 mile yacht with 50 kg on
your backpack and somebody asks you some
really complex question and your
dislikes,
you know,
I don't know.
And,
and I think it's certainly going back to
the swim,
uh,
there's times where I said to the team,
I was like,
please,
like when,
when I'm six hours into a swim through
the night,
I need just really clear instructions,
just like raw swim this way.
Ron's Rosslyn that direction.
And again,
purely anecdotal for the moment,
but you know,
I love cowboys serone and there's times
when he's just in his corner and he's
just having a full on comedy.
So relaxed,
you know?
And it's just like that you,
you could see somebody probably fatigued
and they're panicking and he's just
sitting on the stool.
Like he's got great deference to that.
That helps.
That certainly helps his ability to
recover and rounds.
And you see his fight this weekend,
I've got to catch up on it was
sensational.
The best he's ever looked.
But he was on the bottom when Perry can,
when,
yeah.
I mean,
Perry took him down,
but he said to me,
he goes,
he started taking me down.
I was like,
Shit,
I'm going to let him.
He said,
I'll let them take me down.
And then he reversed them immediately
and got him in an arm bar and,
and broke his arm.
He snapped his forum and half he sent me
the x rays.
No,
I don't think anybody's seen this.
I don't,
sorry Donald,
I'm sending us from not supposed to send
us.
Oh Shit.
Um,
yeah,
we'd been going back and forth and you
know,
for him,
I think it was a matter of rekindling
his excitement.
Here it is.
Yeah.
It was a pretty emotional person.
Oh,
that hurts.
Right.
Can you see that?
You want me to send it to you or I'll
send it to you,
Jamie?
Um,
also I think with Donald when it comes,
we were talking about stimulation and
motivation.
He has a son now is a little baby son.
And he brought his son into the octagon
with him and celebrating with his son.
He just seemed different to me.
He seemed different in his poise,
completely in control.
The guys fighting Mike Perry is fucking
dangerous.
It's fucking dangerous.
He hits really hard.
He's very aggressive.
And a donald just handled them.
And,
and Perry took him down I think because
he didn't like what was going on standup
wise.
He just snapped that shit.
But that,
but you mentioned there as well.
We saw Bernie talking about his son and
it was such an emotional post that he
posted on instagram.
And I loved it.
And,
and,
and going back to what you said about
finding something that,
that alters your biochemistry,
you know,
and now that he's fighting for something
and you know,
he's,
he's got his kid.
Do you,
did you think that's,
that's what we were talking about music
before.
We were talking about getting his
mindset.
It may be use caffeine,
like whatever it is,
but something you think is now different
in serone because again,
it's love.
Yeah.
The love of his children,
his children,
he has something that he,
what
he said was,
um,
I never knew what I was fighting for.
I said,
now I have something to fight for.
I think he was fighting for excitement
before for thrills cause he's a,
he's a thrill seek,
you said wild motherfucker.
He likes jet skiing and jump and
snowmobiles off the side of mountains
and he's an animal week before a fight.
But yeah,
he doesn't give a fuck.
He doesn't,
but this is a different thing.
What he's doing in,
in this fight in particular,
I think this is a different thing
because he's fighting for his son.
I mean he's got this family now and it
means the world to him and he looks over
at this guy like this guy is trying to
take food from his family and he just
wasn't efficient assassin.
It was just,
it was beautiful to watch.
It was like,
I think the best performance of his
career.
And you know,
maybe Mike Perry is not as good as
Darren till or is Hofeld Asan Joe's or
some of the other people that he's
fought in the past,
but it's fucking dangerous and he's a
legit welterweight were Donald's not
donald can fight it 155 pounds.
It's one of the things Donald said after
the fight,
he said,
Khabib,
he goes,
I'm back.
I'm coming for you.
So he wants to drop down to one 55 and
fight could be,
do you think he might know something?
It's different.
Do you think you didn't think he could
make a taller one?
Well,
it was a man.
Khabib is the motherfuckers.
All motherfuckers,
you know,
I mean,
who's going to beat that dude?
But that dude molly was aspirin maybe,
but aspirin is a different weight Class
C aspirins 70 and could bebes 55 if
Khabib and ask an agreed to a catch line
is fine.
That is absolutely a possibility.
And absolutely a possibility that ask
him could best him.
Because if someone's going to beat
Khabib,
it's going to be someone who is a
superior wrestler and ask her,
and it is a mother fucker of a wrestler.
But is he better than can be?
We really don't know and we will not
know until he,
they,
they fight.
But I do have to say that Khabib in the
training camp at Aka,
this is coming straight from [inaudible]
and a bunch of other people that are
trained with him say that he trains with
Olympic caliber wrestlers and fucks them
up.
That's how good could be Biz Khabib is.
He is.
He's so God damned good on the ground
when he gets a hold of guys,
they look perplexed and I always bring
up the Edson Barboza fight cause a
moment in the Barboza fight in the first
round where he'd that thousand yard
stare where Khabib had taken him down.
He was mauling him and he looked over
the distance like how the fuck am I
going to get through three rounds of
this shit?
Yeah.
And that's the thing with Barboza.
I mean Terry added that kick.
He just want,
yeah.
So to see that it was just,
I mean it felt like if I was to do mixed
martial arts,
did you just,
I know you spoke about it before,
you said if somebody doesn't know you
know what they're doing like,
like me,
it's like drowning and,
and that's exactly how I would feel.
I think it was just humbling and it's
something that you
learn.
See the thing of what you've done in my
eyes,
what you've done is so difficult.
I think you could do anything.
I really do.
I think what you did by forcing yourself
to do that shit for six hours a day,
take a break six hours again to do 12
hours of swimming everyday for five
fucking months.
That kind of mental fortitude,
if someone just taught you,
I mean you obviously you're very
physically strong and fit.
If someone just taught you technique and
taught you how to grapple and taught you
kickboxing,
you would be a motherfucker at it
because your mind is so strong like
that,
that you know,
there's a different mindset to have that
same kind of mind strength with the
adversity of another human being.
Trying to kill you.
See,
that's the thing.
How well do people deal with other
people's,
like there's something about a person
breathing down your neck that's trying
to choke you.
That's very disconcerting.
But if you can get past that and I think
you could,
you would be a motherfucker at anything
you did.
And that's actually the thing.
I mean,
even at the moment now I'm used to,
uh,
just training for 12 hours a day.
So right now I'm still sort of in Bi
phasic sleep.
So I've only been on land really a week,
so that's crazy.
Yeah.
So were you sleeping in a boat this
whole time?
Is Six hours.
What is it like to have the ground not
move the hog,
the standing boom?
Honestly,
when I go on I was,
I mean I was doing media interviews and
everything was swaying like they said,
but even even that night,
my first night,
the,
the bed,
it sounds so weird,
but the bed was just a bit too stable.
It's a bit too comfy.
Wow.
I woke up in the middle of the night,
I was with my girlfriend and I'm looking
for my goggles,
you know,
thinking of the time is about to change
that to jump back in.
Wow.
She's like go back to bed.
And like,
honestly I say it now like sort of
joking,
but there was a real element of,
you know,
just that you'd been conditioned and all
I really cared about.
Soon as I woke up,
I want to end just to know what the
tides were doing.
You know,
what's,
where's it running?
How,
when does it start?
When does it,
how have we got good title,
bad side does it spring tides or neat
tie.
So spring ty's been stronger,
neat type spaces and that was my
currency.
That's all I cared about.
And it was really strange that you to
try now and integrate back into society.
You know,
even just walking through La,
the cars,
everything moves very fast now.
You know,
when you kind of come back and it's um,
it's a bit of a shock.
It's a real,
real shit.
You're in an alternate universe or
something like to go through five months
of one reality and then to come out on
the other end.
Yeah,
it does.
So what I almost,
but then even it's an intrinsically or
something,
my body's used to work in hard for 12
hours a day and just getting battered by
waves with the moment,
you know,
I'm sort of sitting here and I've been
doing media,
we can spend amazing,
but there's an element of me just kind
of go in,
I need to use this work capacity.
And so I am sort of training at the
moment.
The first session I did,
I was in there for like six hours and
hours and they were like the gym shut.
He knows.
And I was just like,
oh,
okay.
Crazy.
There is the element.
So one of the things that we all talked
about after sober October was none of us
had ever done anything like this before,
but we're worried now that we're going
to go back to our sedentary ways and
then we're to lose all this work that we
put in.
Right.
Because at the end of the month,
Ari,
who had never worked out before,
ran 15 miles road,
five kilometers,
and then got on the bike for a while.
I forget what he did on the bike,
but I think he did at least a mile on
the bike.
And this was a four plus hour workout.
But he had never done anything before.
I mean,
he had,
did you Jitsu?
I,
uh,
bought him some Jujitsu lessons.
I bought him a year at 10th Planet Jiu
Jitsu,
like 10 years ago,
but he went for a while and then he hurt
his knee and stopped going.
But he was 10 years of nothing and he's
fucking 40 something years old and he
forced himself through mental fortitude.
So he's shit.
I mean,
we're,
so like the human body I find is so
lazy.
Like we love homeostasis.
I habitual level what we're used to
doing,
you know,
that status quo.
And then so when you do shift that,
and it's all relative because you know,
it can be,
you know,
swimming for 12 hours a day and stuff.
But it's relative.
And I think when you do shift that,
um,
it is hard and I think you have to be so
conscious of that.
So even now are like for instance,
my legs at the moment,
um,
you know,
shrunk,
but not just my legs.
I mean I essentially skip leg day,
you know,
for 157 days,
your arms must be jacked is kind of it.
So we went into the gym the other day
and because of the ligaments,
tendons,
but not only just generating force like
a bench press,
but if you imagine like 40 knots of
wind,
you know,
windover tie that we were talking,
my shoulders are used to being contorted
in ways that they shouldn't be shoulders
a resisting the winners.
It's coming towards me.
So your exactly your shoulders.
Yeah.
And the amount of times I would take a
stroke and then,
uh,
when,
I mean there's times when the waves hit
me so hard,
I thought I've just hit a boat,
you know,
I hit something and that would be
pointless.
It was that resistance as well.
So,
um,
on the bench press it was just kind of
like took one 60,
you know,
I'm not saying it's necessarily just as
a sort of sports science experiment.
I kind of unlifted and then just took
one 60 kilos just for a ride and it just
kind of felt,
okay,
what's the one 60 kilos,
what does 160 kilos in?
Sorry Jamie.
But then equally my legs,
you know,
in the Scott Hunt barely lifted my own
body weight,
53 53 58 reps says he,
it's that,
that sort of strength and muscle you had
lifted weights in five months and yet
your upper body.
But,
but,
but lower body.
No,
you know,
and it's not even that though.
Like,
you know,
my legs,
it's the,
it's my feet as well.
So right now genuinely,
and a lot of people afterwards were
like,
what are you going to do next?
You know,
what's the next adventure?
And I said,
I've got to learn to walk again.
And everyone laughed and I was like,
no,
no.
Like the,
the arches in my foot of collapsed,
those ligaments.
And so
it's,
I mean,
I think a lot of collapse just from not
standing.
Yeah.
I mean,
yeah,
you got to think 12 hours in the water
every day.
But even when I was on the boat,
I was probably eating or sleeping.
Whoa.
I didn't even think about that.
So your load capacity,
like your ability to like hold your body
weight up as diminished.
I almost entered into this small group
of people like astronauts where you've
been in a non weight bearing environment
for so long.
So I joke and when we watched that video
back and I'll say,
Oh jazz,
you know,
try not to fall over.
They're genuinely,
I was thinking,
please don't just fall over with all the
counter and laughing.
You know the thing that intrigues me is
you're a young guy,
you're,
you're not,
a lot of these endurance guys are old
angry people.
They get older and they develop this
ability to just fucking fuck the world
and,
and push through things.
How old are you?
33 yeah.
That's very young to do what you did,
isn't it?
Yeah.
And I think you're right,
actually.
I know that that would be a really good
point to make that,
that I always think when people say I'm
too old now to train and stuff,
I'm like absolutely no when yes,
granted,
when you're younger and plasticity and
your ligaments,
yeah.
Higher Testosterone,
muscle mass ability to uh,
you know,
increase my semesters.
I've absolutely,
but when you're older,
and to your point there,
Joe,
when you look at these,
you know,
backing the fell running,
which was talking about you get these
guys who just look like they live in the
mountains,
you know,
whether they faces,
their carbs are just like this just
thick carves and they have that
cappelary density that like
mitochondrial efficiency,
movement efficiency.
So they're cardio risk spiritually.
Durrance has just been built up from
years and years and,
and these sorts of people as well there.
They almost,
they loved the mountains and,
and running so much that they don't care
that they're overtraining or like they
need a rest.
That mother Fucker,
there we go.
Honestly,
she's crying when I'm throwing an rm
getting lapped,
you know,
by John Nailer that that's fell running.
Yeah,
I run into a gay bath house.
Other wasn't a short shorts,
no shorts.
So you get bed fell running shows you
have to wear those shorts.
They're not compulsory.
Seems like it is.
And you've got numbers next to your
deck.
That's where too.
I would have brought you in Paris.
Come on Bro.
Those are,
those are shorts or the girls were in a
porno movie there.
It makes sense,
Jim and uniform.
Oh,
okay.
I mean if he,
if he's possibly Jamie,
there's the um,
uh,
it's called the Bob Graham.
So there's a famous fowl race going back
to sort of the bog march.
There's a famous fell raced back in
England called the Bob Graham.
And uh,
you know,
legend has it.
There was a guy,
Bob Graham,
and he sort of said,
you know,
I,
I can do 44
peaks in the Lake district and under 24
hours and there were an internet,
that's not possible.
It's not possible.
I said,
yeah.
So it was like a bet in a pub.
And they were like,
yeah.
And sure enough,
that's what he did.
And so there's this race now called the
Bob Graham,
and it's amazing and that it's,
it's steeped in history and heritage is
that there's a hall in Kazic,
which is a small town.
It's called Moot Hall.
And if you were standing there,
Joe,
and you're in your running gear with
those shorts,
but you were running though with your
running gear and you had your hand on
Moot Hall and you were looking at your
watch like that,
runners would walk past you and just be
like,
oh,
he's,
he's about to do is Bob Graham.
You know,
they'd come over and there's that real
solidarity,
that good luck,
good luck.
And then you have to do it in 24 hours.
Um,
and uh,
billy bland,
who was the one who,
who set the record,
which is only just been beaten by Kilian
jewel net who uh,
uh,
recently ran up everest as well,
but I think he,
I'm fucking Saturday.
Yeah.
So many savages.
Our base.
So this,
and what I love about this is,
um,
oh,
there you go.
Is that,
yeah.
Kilian yeah,
there you go.
Killing and your net.
So the guy behind in the blue,
um,
set the record and then it says there I
needed to suffer.
So Kilian join net after breaking the
record that it stood for 36 years,
36 years,
I needed to suffer.
But,
but these guys and it,
and it goes back to,
you know,
too often it's sports science,
sports,
nutrition.
Let's look at,
look at your gait analysis,
running biomechanics,
what footwear are using minimally shoes
on and everybody.
Whereas with this with fell running,
it took 36 years for somebody to get
close to that record.
Just like,
wow,
what were they doing so far back?
Granted you need to know the terrain.
Like you could on this descent,
on this picture for instance,
you could be running down their
struggling down the rocks and you might
not know that just,
you know,
50 meters to your right,
there's a perfect sheep trail and that's
kind of the concept of,
of,
of fell running.
So it's just a matter of getting up and
above and over it no matter what path
you take.
Yeah,
yeah.
But certainly efficient if you know of
something.
And so that guy in the front there is
pacing him basically because it's very
easy to get lost on the duracell know a
specific path that you have to take.
They have to get over it.
There's certain points that you have to
get through.
But then in terms of the terrain and the
[inaudible] no,
not really.
So it's just point to point to point to
point.
But how do they mark those points to
they have a cones and we'll,
I mean this,
yeah,
we'll be long established that to do the
Bob Graham you need to do that point,
that point and then you come back to
moot hall,
you know,
within hopefully 24 hours and if you do
it then you have your have your bob
grounds.
These guys look like a guy that would do
that.
Whereas you don't,
right.
This is my point about you and
endurance,
like how your physique,
you don't see a guy with your physique
doing this kind of stuff.
You think that you could do this kind of
stuff running.
I mean,
you know,
I always say I'm not self deprecating.
And how much do you think at the moment
about a hundred kilos,
which is a lot considering our 20.
Yeah.
So that's about 220 pounds.
So I,
yeah,
the Bob Graham is something
complete different than that goes back
to what we were talking about about
power to weight ratio in a weight
bearing sports.
It was something like running,
cause you're so heavy.
Yeah.
You have a lot of power.
Do you think it would be possible if you
put,
if you added more power to,
obviously not now because you're getting
off for five months on a boat,
but if you built your legs and your feet
back up,
do you think you could do this?
Yeah.
And do you think this is possibly,
I'm sorry,
but no way near,
I mean killing Jeanette.
What?
He's amazing.
I mean with Kilian he um,
I believe don't come out that he's,
he's almost sort of semi nomadic.
He grew up in the hills,
semi nomadic.
Most of for him,
he would run a marathon to go and get
his,
you know,
carton of milk in the morning.
Oh Geez.
You know,
so when you are lining up on a start
line,
I mean if you're racing at Kenyon,
you look over and you've got a guy like
that.
Fuck yeah,
you just,
you just get a lot.
I'm out,
I'm out.
You can't beat that guy.
But he's,
but he has built for that.
That's my like so you,
but you don't think that guy built for
swimming.
Like if that guy had to do what you did
swimming wise,
he would be at a disadvantage over a
certain difference going back to the
belt,
right.
Somebody like that.
And in my experience when I've raced or
swum with,
you know guys who are doing in a 10
kilometer,
they,
they will be quicker than me over 10
kilometers.
But then it gets to a point when we're
like 30 kilometers in where their
biomechanics just because of muscle
endurance that starts to break down
maybe as well.
And this is so often overlooked
actually,
but you've got to train your digestive
system.
So again,
this is mainly anecdotal,
but you know in strength based sports,
you know a lot of guys won't think
anything about putting away 15,000
calories a day,
which is what I was doing.
So I'm doing that while you were
swimming?
Yeah.
15,000
yeah.
calories.
A lot of it.
You were sitting down once you got
inside the boat.
Yeah.
What were you eating?
Just the,
it was so intuitive.
So it was,
it was kind of strange because the diet
was calorie dense so you have to make up
for your category and climates that day.
Also looking at nutrient dense cause you
got to care for your immune system but
equally palatability.
So when my tongue was falling upon,
you know I needed to look at that.
And even seasickness you're not really
spoke about it as well,
which is kind of like you need something
that hits those four points and that's
15,000
calories a day.
So for me that was quite often just like
porridge oats in a mixed with honey
mixed with almond butter.
And then even looking at,
oh here we go.
Yeah.
So this is a serious,
what's that?
Oh,
there might be on there somewhere.
Yeah.
What is that in that bowl?
Beans mostly.
Yeah.
And this is why I'm,
it just got to the point where it was
like what can you just like what he's
going to say?
I was just eating out of the pan.
Just trying to shove it in your face.
Yeah.
So like what,
what,
what would you eat?
Like what were the fool?
This is probably quite a good one.
Yeah,
that play.
So yeah,
there you go.
Like in terms of,
so essentially as a nutritional sort of
in theory,
the framework you get,
what was that?
Mass.
Oh,
so that was to stop the jellyfish.
Oh Jesus.
Yeah.
No,
but it doesn't matter.
Like even the mass,
cause the giant jellyfish have Scott and
then there'll be a pitch on there
somewhere.
They're kind of like six feet long.
So when you're swimming at night and you
can't see them,
the tentacles will,
they'll just kind of,
they'll get you.
And so I got like,
they go in your mouth and your ears.
I've got one in my ear.
I've got like what will lead by a
jellyfish,
she just kind of like got me there.
So it's like that,
that,
yeah,
there's a,
the China find and adapt the same way
with a mass,
but nutritionally,
um,
as well,
but also looking at as a framework,
you having your protein,
which is pretty stable,
you know,
1.7
grams per kg of body weight per day,
you know,
that kind of stays the same.
So then for the rest of the 15,000
calories,
you basically need to make it up with
your two energy yielding macronutrients.
So carbs and fats.
And so for me it was very carb dependent
because when you are swimming for a
giant whirlpool,
you can't say,
can I have some fats,
which the body has to go a certain
process,
it's going to take longer.
No,
you just need fast acting carbohydrates.
But then equally,
um,
looking at,
uh,
MCTs,
so a medium chain triglycerides as well,
which are a fat,
so they have the calorie density of a
fat,
but they're treated more like a
carbohydrate rather than long chain
triglycerides.
So,
um,
there was a certain amount of science.
There are a lot of people would say,
you know,
our 15,000
calories that mean pizza and everything.
It was like,
well,
you know,
yes to an extent,
but then place too much emphasis on that
and you're not caring for your immune
system as well.
So to get 15,000
calories,
I think,
yeah,
I always point out that it's using
things like mcts,
which you'll find in coconut oil,
and certainly,
again,
not to get too much on the science,
but capric and caprylic acid,
which are converted to ATP,
Adenosine triphosphate.
It's a molecular energy.
The muscles,
when you understand how to use mcts like
that,
it can be quite easy to make up 15,000
calories,
but you try and make up 15,000
calories of vegetables and fruit,
right?
Yeah,
exactly.
Especially you like have like protein
and then fruit and it requires a
different digestive enzyme and then
you're going to tell me to go and swim
for a giant whirlpool and roll on my
stomach for 12 hours a day.
It's just like with seasickness,
it's not going to happen.
Yeah.
You just,
you,
you must need a lot of regret,
really dense foods.
Yeah.
And,
and that's the thing that it goes back
to,
again,
this,
this bell curve that I've spoke about,
but,
um,
you know,
quite often a lot of endurance athletes
that are trained with who were amazing,
they're unbelievable.
They're sub three hour marathon is,
they're incredible.
You know,
they're,
they're the guys that will go and run
the Bob Graham,
but quite often they say,
but Ross can just eat.
And it's just like,
yeah,
that's often overlooked.
You know,
that my body,
I,
you know,
I didn't have a sick day for out the
whole swim.
That's what it was.
The attribute,
and I popped,
I started at 92 kilos.
Um,
you know,
when you,
when you look at the pictures from the
start to the finish,
I just look like,
just like Harrier.
Yeah.
But just also just bulk because you are
asking your body to just swim around
Great Britain.
So it's not just the,
that you are,
you don't want to be in a calorie
deficit.
Can you imagine how much microtrauma the
body's going to go through?
So you're essentially just trying to
nurse the body saying,
look and know this is horrible.
I know it's cold.
I know I'm asking you to swim for 12
hours a day.
I know there's going to be jellyfish
toxins.
I mean,
not some that off stung like in a 20
times in one night in a single tied,
you know,
so it got to the point where I talked
about my face or changing shape.
Equally,
the toxins in your body,
your heart would start beating faster
and you know,
so there was just this idea that just
eat just to,
to,
to look after the body.
So when it comes to nutrition and were
you taking any supplements or you taking
vitamins?
Yeah,
lots.
And,
and that goes to,
like I said,
that calorie density,
but also to make sure that you're making
some new system.
Yeah.
Taking everything from super green
shakes,
you need to multivitamins to,
to protein shakes,
just to make sure that you were
supplementing that calorie density.
I think it's so often overlooked.
The higher turnover of like
phytochemicals,
enzymes,
micronutrients.
What about fish oil?
Anything along those lines?
Mega threes.
Yeah.
And that's what,
just anything that you were thinking,
well this is even to to glutamine to a
higher turnover of amino acids.
So after,
uh,
for instance,
after training as well,
you can have all the protein in the
world,
but if it has a,
a low biological value,
so I can't,
I'm going to try and keep the culture.
But if you look at,
you know,
immediately after a workout,
your body's basically saying,
look,
we need protein to repair and regrowth
protein synthesis and your muscles are
saying please.
But if you don't have a high
concentration of Leucine,
specifically sub branch chain amino
acids,
leucine within that is what will trigger
to your motor receptors to basically
repair and regrow.
So quite often you can have all the
protein in the world,
but if it's of a low biological value of
it's not very good quality protein,
your body is not going to assimilate it.
So it's not about the protein that you
eat,
it's about the protein you assimilate.
Right.
So you would take branch chain amino
acids postworkout yeah,
yeah.
And specific.
I said Leucine,
just to make sure that I was kickstarted
that whole recovery process because soon
as you got out of the water,
after six hours,
there's always the temptation just I
want to pass out,
I want to just go to bed,
I want,
you know,
and it's just like,
no,
you've got six hours to think.
Because when your backend now what about
your protein?
What you're getting it mostly from a lot
of whey protein just because of
efficiency and also as well,
you've got to think in terms of the boat
and stocking food that like perishable,
you know,
food.
So you know,
as as much as I love my barbecue ribs
and everything like that,
that wasn't going to happen on this
small galley that we had on the boat.
Right.
So you get any fresh food,
eggs,
anything along those lines?
Yeah.
When we could stop in a harbor,
you know,
the team would go out.
I'd never touched land,
but they could go and quit your
provision from land and bring it back.
But ultimately,
yeah,
it was,
it was trying to find a way that was,
was sustainable as possible,
but within the
parameters that we had,
you know,
and that,
that was what was tricky.
What about your joints?
I would imagine repetitive stress of
swimming would wreck havoc on your
shoulders.
Yeah.
And that's why,
again,
this goes back to,
I suppose this goes back and I was
trying to rich roll about this actually
where um,
one she developed that sort of
horsepower program,
that work capacity that was talking
about before from when I ran the
marathon pulling a car.
It was um,
Eh,
this is such a strange story,
but I then that again,
to raise money for that,
for the teenage cancer trust,
I am,
I climbed a rope,
but I think it was a 10 meter rope.
But I repeated the climate until I
climbed the height of Everest.
So it was a 8,000,
848 meters.
And it was that that actually taught me
that movement efficiency play such an
important role in terms of endurance
because you,
you could be,
you could have the best muscular
endurance,
the world,
cartier,
spiritual insurance.
But if you can imagine with a rope
climb,
if you're solely relying on your
muscles,
your arms,
like your bicep tendon is just,
you know,
and then you can be the fittest guy in
the world.
But within that kinetic chain,
something's going to give like the
weakest part.
Um,
so you're right from that I had the,
the work capacity from the marathon,
then from the rope climb,
I certainly understood movement
efficiency.
And so sort of transferring those skills
over to,
to swimming.
I knew that you couldn't swim like a
conventional swimmer.
Everything that had taught you,
especially in waves and everything.
So I ended up developing quite a weird
technique.
They look really slow and comes from,
I also,
I almost looked to sleep,
but you know,
it was really rolling and that's why I
asked you about swimming and even
looking at,
uh,
Bert again to use him as that.
But I know he does his triathlon,
but for everything that is taught about
swimming,
it's probably for someone who looks like
you know Michael Phelps or you know,
an amazing specimen at swimming.
So you're saying births fat.
It was always saying I am silly.
I'm saying that.
But for the record,
Jamie,
for the record,
I've heard it as a repeated diapers.
I for the record on record,
I think he's a specimen of a male.
I was like well listen,
we are photographic evidence.
That photo of him with his belly hanging
out,
it's the most ridiculous is after he ran
a marathon,
is this pre or post as sober October
cause he's really lost a lot now though.
He lost 18 pounds during sober October.
He's the only one that lost weight.
I gained weight but there was that video
cause he was dancing in his bathroom
recently,
wasn't it?
Where they look at this photo denim
pants,
that's not even the worst one.
I love.
Why is Bert Kreischer Chrysler so fat.
That is,
that is a fine specimen of that.
That's the one that's one basie,
because he wore those for the way in is
he got me sober October.
He has got a bunch of those.
He's got more than one spot.
That's what he wears.
I love him.
I love him more.
The fact that he ran a marathon with
that body that's like,
yeah,
running Lamont's in a pinto fit neat
doesn't get enough credit.
I think that's,
it doesn't get enough credit Karma and
everything that you have that's not
real.
It's not that big that's in photoshop or
something.
It would be the same.
It'd be the same with you that if we
were looking at your swimming technique,
there'd be certain everything that you'd
probably learn probably wouldn't be
applicable to you because of how broad
you are,
how things that you could actually use.
So I was basically really engaging the
lats,
the traps,
the larger muscles of the back.
Going back to,
uh,
the,
the video with Brian Shore when he was
just ripping,
yeah.
Was just,
or ripping out the floor and,
and I knew that I couldn't necessarily
do that.
Looking at Delta high catch high elbows,
we're going to do high elbows for 150 70
days for Tava right new.
So everything that I'd learned and
certainly you know,
great friends of mine who are in Liam
tank got 50 meter world record on a back
stroke in a carry on paying double world
champion 10 k.
These are amazing athletes.
I'm not one of them.
So you developed more efficient,
slower,
a style that you could continue for five
months and you just end up,
it's like moving meditation.
It just became like,
you know,
the limiting factor was just like I was
just getting bored.
I wasn't actually breathing thinking of
this is the thing,
I mean you had to,
at any given time,
any tied,
you had to think of something that was
going to be more powerful than the
thought of stopping or fatigue or clcs
like getting deeper into your skin.
And so sometimes it was real easy
because you were swimming with dolphins,
minky whales.
I swam with a basking shark.
Did they come over to you going,
what the fuck is this dude doing?
Yeah.
Like one it was,
yeah,
there's a,
it was a video of the ages ago with the,
uh,
the main keywell and d I was filming 12
hours across the Bristol channel,
so that's kind of England to Wales.
And,
uh,
this was,
this was without doubt for all the
hardship that I spoke about it.
I just want to say there were some
amazing moments this one particular
moment swimming across the,
uh,
the Bristol Channel and all of a sudden
minky well,
kind of about as big as this table
breaches right next to me.
I was like,
Whoa,
like Tom's rise.
I,
I turned to Matt,
the captain,
I was like,
man,
am I safe?
Like what's going on?
Like should I get out of the war?
And he said,
no,
you're absolutely fine.
And I was like,
okay,
cause it's a minky whales,
the find the friendly.
I was like,
okay,
fair enough.
So I keep swimming and then for the next
five miles,
the minky whales circling me,
it was breaching over the top.
It was coming under me and swimming like
that.
I turned to him and I said,
Matt,
what's going on?
And he said,
I've never seen this.
He's been sailing like 40 years.
He says,
I've never seen this.
He said,
but what I think is happening is I think
it's a female,
and I tried to fuck you.
Well,
I,
I said,
it's not mating season is it?
He was like,
no,
no.
It's fine.
He goes,
what are these hats?
Even you for later?
It was one for four months in the
swatter.
I'm gonna fuck
her mating seasons probably right around
the corner.
She's like,
if he sticks around,
I know.
I always like,
you knew what?
That was a concern of mine that was a
kitchen.
But no.
Matt said,
no,
no.
I think it's a few more.
I think that she thinks that you're an
injured seal five miles.
She basically guided me all the way to
the shallow water and as I got there,
it was literally the depth of the water.
Matt said,
Yep.
Yet much shallower water.
And we turned,
we were breached one more time and then,
and then swim off as if to say,
you know,
you're safe now.
Wow.
Amazing.
That's incredible.
Yeah.
So for all of the hardship and
everything that I described,
there were moments and sunsets and,
and swimming with seals and,
and it was amazing.
And also that's the basking shark.
Is that what you encountered?
Yes.
So that was in the actual one you
encountered?
I don't know if I can't,
I mean also in behind,
you could swim in that.
I was,
I was concerned about that one,
but they didn't know.
So that's a basking shark.
So they're friendly.
But the Mac,
can you imagine seeing that?
Like assuming free Scotland,
not mountains,
either side of you.
And so,
so to your point about asking what you
think about,
it's very easy to swim when,
when you know this dolphins and
everything,
but there's times when you are lost in
this moving meditation.
But then you see something like that and
you very quickly got to get your wits
about you.
Cause,
cause they were killer whales as well,
up,
uh,
you know,
coming from sort of Iceland around the
top of Scotland.
So that was,
that was a concern.
Were they interested in you?
Thankfully we didn't see any,
but they wouldn't attack you or
anything.
Well,
so this is it.
So we were speaking with marine
biologists at the time saying,
look like what's,
what's the situation here?
And they said,
well,
you know what's really interesting
there?
So intelligent.
You know,
killer whales are so intelligent and
they've never been known.
This was what they said to me.
They've never been known in the wild to
attack a human.
And I said,
okay,
fantastic.
And they said,
however,
if they're going to attack a human is
probably going to be you because no
one's ever spent that amount of time in
the water as well,
you know?
So I was like,
right.
They said,
all you need to do,
all right,
company.
So they just said,
look,
all you need to do is make sure that you
don't look like a seal.
Cause they might mistake you for a seal,
but they might bite you.
But then they will go,
oh Whoa,
did that,
that intelligent.
They'd be like,
oh,
that doesn't taste like a seal.
So they might,
you know.
So I was just trying my best not to look
like a seal.
I think when they have attack people in
the wild or toys or in captivity,
it's always been trainers.
Yeah.
So it's been an anger,
frustration.
Yeah.
You know,
and that was my experience with the
Minkwon,
everything it was,
people said like,
how'd you swim at night?
Because certainly around a west of
Scotland there was,
it was a debt for 200 meters.
So you just,
you can't,
you don't know what's under you.
So,
um,
there was that element but,
but I think having swum with the minky
well around the Bristol Channel,
I was very aware that in the hierarchy
of the sea,
I was very low down the pecking order
and,
and if it's comforting in any strange
way,
I was like,
look,
if I was going to be eaten,
I'll be eaten in the day just as much as
I'll be eaten at night.
You know,
it's just,
it's just one of those things darkness.
Yeah.
Just like you can't,
you can't see the hand in front of your
face.
It's like the Maury first for instance,
we will a 40 Mars away from land and
this kind of cutting across this huge
bay across the top of Scotland.
And um,
it was clouded over so there was not a,
you can even see anything cause there
was no moonlight or no stars and it was
a you in that complete sensory
deprivation.
You can hear everything and it's just,
if you hear a noise,
a reporter,
you're like,
I really hope that's not a killer whale.
But then you've then got six hours to
contemplate whether it,
so it's this,
and again,
like I said,
Marcus Aurelius,
meditations,
stoic philosophy that the conversations
you have in your own head are just as
powerful with other people.
And I certainly found that all the way
around that you just,
um,
there was times when you were just like,
what am I doing out here?
I'm like,
seriously?
And that comes from,
I think,
you know,
this,
this idea of you have to be doing it for
the right reasons.
And,
and I've I again to,
to bring it back to mma,
I suppose it's really fascinated me.
You know,
some fighters in a ladelle coming out of
retirement,
we all tease and certainly,
you know,
Mcgregor is made so much money,
what would get him back out of
retirement to come and fight mayweather
and,
and you know,
again,
I've been out at sea so I didn't quite
understand what was going on there with
the,
his kind of going over to as a Japan
fighting.
And it's like,
what does he need?
He's got so much money.
Yeah.
What would warrant a,
whether they were the spends money,
spends money like crazy.
He was gonna fight tension,
tension.
How do you pronounce his last name
correctly?
Not Sue Cowell.
No.
So I've been at a seat,
so I didn't really see what was going on
here.
Yeah.
Let me see if you find that on my
instagram.
He's out of his fucking mind.
Would that have been a bad idea?
Horrible.
He would get head kicked into a coma.
But you,
but you kind of ask like what?
What,
what are the reasons?
And I think,
okay,
I think he spends a shit ton of money.
You think they're trying to get it back
on track?
I said floyd had been duped into
agreeing to the contest.
Look,
they will do him.
By the way,
they are very different if those,
if this happens,
believe you me,
he's going to get kicked in the head.
They're going to,
they might say,
no,
no Kiki,
listen man,
you get in the ring with tension.
He's going to try to roundhouse kick you
into another fucking dimension.
So it was,
it was a special bounce.
So there's gonna be no kicking.
I don't know if they agreed to the
rules.
Wow.
Okay.
But tension not Sukarno was,
I think he's 20,
I think he's 20 years old.
He's a really fantastic talent.
Wow.
Yeah.
I mean,
he really is,
but it,
but it fascinates me.
So I'm catching up on all this.
Like I said,
so I've,
I've missed
all of this for 157.
They'd look sad.
I even missed the mcgregor and
[inaudible] and stuff.
Go do a striking breakdowns on
instagram.
Lawrence tension has a,
he's done a bunch of breakdowns as is
Brendan Dorm has done a bunch of
breakdowns to on tension,
but,
uh,
he's,
Lawrence Kenshin has this really
fascinating video of him fighting this
world Moitai champion.
And uh,
he wheel kicks him in the head,
was more like a jump,
spinning back kick to the chin.
But the way he did it,
it was like a really weird angle and you
could see them setting it up.
He's really creative and he just found
like a weird opening a for this guy and
just kick this guy into oblivion.
Right.
He's,
he's nasty.
And he's really sneaky,
like the kind of techniques that he
lands.
It's very clever with his reads and his
understanding of distance and in what's
possible.
Right.
Do you see it striking breakdowns on,
on instagram?
Might not be the name of it.
Huh?
But yeah,
it's with this,
you know,
how much money does he need?
He can call on spend that much.
That's a good question.
I think he can,
but,
and this is what I love.
Again,
I'm only just catching up on this,
like set out you,
I should point out I have been at sea
for 157 days,
but with everything that happened was
treating breakdowns.
No,
on that.
I just got to it.
Striking breakdowns.
Good.
What?
I typed it,
man.
Start coming out.
Nope.
Maybe there's something wrong with
instagram.
Hmm.
I Dunno.
I got it right here.
Here.
I'll send you the link.
Okay,
so we could see a,
yeah,
here we go.
I'll send you this.
They're toppy link.
Sorry folks.
But this is a,
I don't know how much they were offering
him,
you know,
so I don't know how much I'm okay.
I just sent it to you.
I don't know.
I mean it has to be millions of dollars.
That's the only way he'd be willing to
do it.
But if they offer,
and he also,
tension is quite a bit smaller.
I think he weighs one 30 and floyd walks
around,
I mean he's fought at one 54 one 50 ish
and mcgregor was at 55 mm is this,
this kid is fucking nasty man.
But he does a lot of wild shit.
Like there's a,
there's a video here or the see him
fight this Moy Thai guy and he hits them
with this crazy.
That's when he was a little kid.
Like see how he does shit like that.
Like sneaky shit under the sip,
sip and it,
he was young.
He was this,
we got this crank.
Oh this is the one with the World Moy
Thai champion.
Boom.
Puts that due to sleep but the way set
it up.
That's a weird angle for that kick.
Very tight.
Yeah,
very tight clothes.
And it wasn't around.
It was straight.
So it was basically like a jump,
spinning back kick to the chin,
which is hard to generate force.
Oh No,
no,
no.
This power.
Yeah.
No,
as long as he can get extension on his
legs,
it's just he had to jump and talk and
spin.
But the fact that he chose that angle,
it's like he realized that the guy was
going to see things that were coming
around.
So instead of coming around,
he had it come up and,
and through the middle,
which is,
which made it much sneakier but that's
it.
What we're describing now is it never
intangible,
right.
Creativity.
Yeah,
exactly.
I mean,
I,
I'm what I find it so interesting when,
you know Mcgregor Diaz and I was just
say I'm a huge fan of Ido,
poor towel.
So when they use their own,
but I was just like,
look,
and I think it was,
um,
I think mcgregor was on,
I want to say Kimmel,
but I don't think it was,
he was on a chat show and he was talking
about that spinning cap aware,
a crescent kick.
And he actually did it.
He performed it.
And I was like,
look,
if he lands that,
you know,
the same way with Aldo,
it's be like that is the movement is it,
you know,
you can forget cardiorespiratory
endurance,
strength,
everything that we talked about that the
metric saying,
you know,
heavy where you gotta be two,
four,
five,
you know,
whatever.
No,
it's just movement.
He would have reinvented and again more
and I could be wrong.
I think we do yet he did try it,
didn't it?
And it missed I think,
I believe he did look through it through
it.
I think he threw it.
The thing,
you know,
that technique is a legit technique.
Obviously we'll kicks most certainly
work,
but it's not a high percentage technique
doesn't,
there's only been a few.
We'll kick knockouts in in the UFC.
The first one was Edson Barboza over
Terry.
Adam.
That was number one.
There's been a few since then.
Uh,
Vitor Belfort shocked Luke rockhold with
the wheel kick.
It's,
it's happened before.
Right?
Um,
but it's just not a high percentage kick
and it's usually a kick that's,
you know,
it's
nowhere.
You don't expect it.
Right.
But that's a bit,
but can you tell when someone has it and
doesn't cause it's an intangible.
So if you said if it there started the
Barboza and atom fight,
you said,
you know,
knock out by timing or creativity you'd
st like why would you mean?
You know,
but if you could foresee that the same
way that you could quantify that sort of
mental fortitude.
I think you start opening the door in
sports performance into something that's
just this whole other realm that you
don't talk about weight as a metric.
Strength,
cardiorespiratory endurance.
You can start talking you.
Is that hard to see again?
Take well yeah,
with creativity,
especially in regards to striking
technique.
Yeah,
that's,
that's a crazy intangible because you're
essentially deciding when to move and
what to do,
right?
Like you can throw a jab,
you throw a front kick,
you could throw a roundhouse kick,
you could throw a wheel kick and you
throw a turning side kick.
You could throw an ax kick if you're
crazy,
you know,
and this is a lot of different things
you can do.
So do you decide to do and why do you
say to do it?
Is it because you have a style like some
people style is like conor likes to hop
in and out and he throws like a little
front leg sidekick.
He throws like that for movement.
He likes to keep his arms wide.
It makes his tennis sideways stance.
Some guys like to hold up like this and
the Moitai Shell and they move forward
lifting the front leg up and they move
forward and,
and challenge with leg kicks and
striking technique.
Some guys just like to wrestle.
They,
they'll,
they'll pour at you and they look to
shoot like Ben Aspirin,
you know,
he's not looking to stand up and strike
with anybody.
He's looking at taking the ground beat
the fuck out of you.
That's what he does.
So it's all,
and what do you decide to do and why do
you decide to do it and when do you
decide to do it?
When do you engage?
You know you're throwing some faints,
you know,
you don't want to be the guy who makes
it obvious that you moving forward.
Cause then like connor clipped Aldo,
you get rocked.
You know it's a,
it's a crazy,
crazy sport is,
but you,
if you enter into that realm and even
start applying more sweats again,
we talked about that sort of strength
deficit as well.
That if you get someone um,
you know,
trying to like,
like John Jones who,
you know,
move up to heavyweight,
is it going to be,
will it benefit him winning with
strength training for instance,
I can't remember.
He's dead lift,
but it's pretty impressive.
It's an impressive,
I think it was 600 pounds.
Big Dead Lift.
Yeah.
So when you look at that strength
deficit,
Jon Jones,
very lean,
was using neuro muscular.
He was recruiting voluntarily,
all of those muscle fibers.
It was unbelievable.
But if it means that to it,
it would it be,
would any more muscle mass be
functional?
And I think when you start the question
looking at when should he do that?
That's another good question because
you're beating your body up to do that.
Yeah.
And is that conducive with a high
aerobic capacity training,
like multiple rounds of sparring and bag
work and pad work,
and you're all the lower back muscles
that are getting stressed.
And does that lead to potential
injuries?
Is the potentially damaging his discs,
his knees,
like there's a lot of a lot of things to
be considered.
And when should you do that?
A lot of people that you think you
should do that when you're nowhere near
camp.
Yeah.
Like you win a fight and then you decide
to,
to build up in between camps.
Yeah.
And I think that's so awful.
Even a Darren till,
you know,
who is a huge,
huge,
huge currently,
but he's moving to middleweight and now,
yes.
Yeah.
He's missed weight and his title shot
against Tyron Woodley and then he got
rocked put away.
So if you're moving up,
how do you do it?
Do you do it intelligently?
Do you?
Yeah.
But then there are guys who were just
like,
they say training is the real
realization of one's genetic potential.
And when you get someone like,
you know,
rumble Johnson,
it's just,
you know,
now you never met.
He fought well tomorrow he made,
wait,
I'm sorry.
He made weight against Tyron Woodley,
didn't he?
Yes.
He made waves with it.
He didn't make weight against Donald
terrone.
Right.
That's what it was.
He came in very heavy and sounds around
him.
He's a big motherfuckers.
What he is,
you know what I mean?
He's so big for welterweight.
I think you'll be way better off at 185
pounds.
But I think many of them will.
I think there's a point of diminishing
returns where they are significantly
depleting themselves to make that
weight.
And then when they don't have to do
that,
they have more energy.
And we've seen that time and time again.
Exactly.
But when you did rumble Johnson,
he fought at welter weight.
Right?
He's so big like gone and then all of a
sudden mood a mood and then,
you know,
it was,
it no guerra.
I mean nowhere.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
When he just bounced the fight.
Heavyweight,
he did fight heavyweight successfully
in,
in um,
the Pfl he not,
he broke Andrea Orlowski his jaw.
He fucked Andrea Lawsky up as a
heavyweight.
Right.
And that's what always fascinates me is
that,
and I suppose when I see this,
that God given kind of power yeah.
For all of the training it seems,
and it was someone like,
yeah.
Johnson and he,
cause he said,
am I right thinking he said he's going
to come back for heavyweight if DC and
Jones go up.
He's thought about it.
Um,
you know,
I think he's,
uh,
he's in the weed game right now.
It's making some money selling weed,
which is legal now.
So He's,
he's doing that.
What?
Wow.
Right.
Because the size of him now.
But he fought hardy,
right?
Yes.
He fought hardy and um,
he took him down,
which was interesting.
He didn't want to stand with them.
Wow.
Back in the day it was a different
thing.
I mean,
they kind of made an agreement to stand
with each other and then he was like,
bitch.
And he took him down and he won by
decision,
but that was a different rumble.
Johnson,
I think the rumble Johnson at one 70,
he had no fucking energy.
He was on death's door.
He was just always exhausted.
He would lose fights.
He just,
he got choked out by Josh Koscheck.
He was just too tired.
And I think,
wait king as well,
obviously,
you know,
there's been certain changes now,
but even now,
and I love Max Holloway,
but,
uh,
I think it was ufc embedded where they
flew his favorite cupcake's over from
Hawaii and he was like,
yeah,
I love cupcakes.
I've made weight.
And then he was just,
you know,
nailing cupcakes.
Smart.
No,
and I think there's just that element
now that,
that I think as much as MMA has,
has evolved,
and,
and again,
this is someone who doesn't understand
the technical aspects,
but as someone who loves,
uh,
kind of sports history,
you know,
and I've watched it and I'm just like,
that is amazing.
But it's still got so far to get.
Again,
we were talking earlier about,
you know,
football or soccer isn't in here back in
England and the warming up of the
brandy,
you know,
in the,
in the changing rooms,
I think even now it's crazy when you
have someone so gifted like that,
but they are rehydrating and re carb
loading on cupcakes.
It's,
it's like,
yeah,
there are better,
there's way better ways you've caught
weight.
Your body is basically in fight or
flight,
you know,
you've subjected it to a form of micro
trauma,
you know,
bodies kind of sitting there going,
Whoa,
is going on and um,
then you're going to get Hago he loves a
cupcake.
She made weight.
Yeah.
So I find that really interesting that
you see some of the guys who,
you know,
was it [inaudible] tobacco?
Isn't it,
who
just like,
it was so big.
It was,
he got into,
it was like he said that he'd weigh in
and then it would be like he sent his
older brother in like they were
unrecognizable.
Um,
and,
and I think it's really interesting
that,
that physiological puppetry,
if you know how to do it intelligently,
it can be so powerful,
but you do it for the wrong reasons,
but even if you know how to do it
intelligently,
there's still a demand that it places on
your organs.
That's,
it's there's consequences,
right?
And over time your body resists it.
And this was the thought behind Max
Holloway's last weight cutting fail,
is that when he was trying to cut down
on short notice to fight Khabib Namaka
Madoff,
he was cutting down only to one 55 and
he couldn't make it.
And they pulled him out of that.
And then he started suffering some
significant problems when he was getting
ready for Brian Ortega.
And they think that when he was ready
for getting ready for a Tayga,
what was going on was his body was
reacting to the fact that he was trying
to cut weight again.
And it was like,
fuck you,
we just got through this man.
Right.
You know,
and he was like really messed up because
of it.
Right.
And he had to go through a battery of
tests before they approved him to fight
again.
So his body had to like fully fully
recover months off and then get back to
training and now he's okay again.
But,
but I think it's changing.
I mean now,
I mean Frankie Edgar was almost the
fest.
He would wake,
you have to fight like five pounds.
He wouldn't even cut weight.
He wouldn't cut any weight.
Yeah,
that was his way.
Well there,
this is what they say,
Frankie,
although was the 155 pound champion and
now competes at 145 pounds.
Really?
He should be fighting at one 35 and then
one 35 is where he could be at his best.
That's what everybody says.
Wow.
Especially people that know like weight
cutting and they look at what he walks
around and like,
look,
20 pounds from 55 ain't shit.
You know those guys do it all the time.
Especially you get a guy like a George
Lockhart who really knows how to do it
and put that weight back on you,
you know,
and how to do it correctly.
Scientifically,
it's a big W we're seeing that now
across all sports.
I think this evolution that we're
understanding,
I skin Carlin aisles,
he's one of my favorite.
So he was a,
a good American sprinter.
He was,
I believe,
you know,
top 50 you know,
he was,
he was amazing,
but it wasn't quite making it,
you know,
he's not a Usain bolt,
he's not adjusting Gatlin.
So they just said,
Hey Colin,
here's a,
here's a rugby ball.
And again,
it'll be on youtube some ways like,
you know,
why do you regard as the fastest route
comply?
They just handed him,
you know,
and now there's one of my favorite clips
because he,
it was one of his first games or
something and I think it was an
Australian commentator and he just ran
like rings around everybody.
Scott as score to try.
And then the commentator was like,
was,
oh my God,
it goes,
I cannot believe this.
Can you believe?
Here we go,
look,
here we go.
Here's the ball.
Oh my God,
look at him.
Go Goodbye.
That is insane.
This is rugby sevens.
Oh my God,
they're all quitting.
But like,
look,
the guy chasing gave
that guy,
there's more,
this is absurd.
I love corners.
And,
and he ran past him like the guy was
ahead of them.
This new law,
I'm not even going to sites that you
because I don't,
he,
it's like he doesn't even respect their
speed.
Look how much faster he is in those
guys.
That's hilarious.
Was that all in many ways,
right?
Isn't it like that other guy who broke
the world record by rowing and he'd been
doing something else and gotten so much
power and energy in his body that he
could translate that to,
to rowing.
And we're seeing that now,
but,
and that was what was amazing there with
we call him.
I was,
like I said,
he scored her,
he's got to try.
And then the commentator,
there was two commentators talking and
said,
I can't believe he's only been playing
in a number of months,
and that they were like,
yeah,
no,
that's amazing.
And then the other commentary you said,
no,
I can believe it.
He's just tried to give the referee the
ball and he didn't know what to do.
He'd scored a try and he was walking
around and he gave it to him.
No,
no,
no.
You know,
kick it.
it was amazing.
They didn't bother teaching them.
They're like,
just listen man.
Just run.
But what do I do when I get to the,
I just get to the end and then we'll
talk and I'll tell you what to do.
It'll take about three minutes.
They do.
And you just run baby.
You're seeing it.
And I think it's incredible.
You spoke about this not too long ago,
but I think you might've mentioned
Lebron James saying if someone like
that,
I was taught mma.
Oh my God,
everybody would be dead.
What would happen?
And I think we're seeing that now that
you know,
sports now there's more money,
in mma and it's evolved to what it is
now.
It's amazing that if you get,
you know,
some unbelievable phenom as a kid,
you go go into mma.
Yeah.
But it's not as
peeler is basketball and it doesn't pay
as much money as Lebron James makes.
Lebron James,
what does he make?
$100 million a year,
something crazy just from basketball.
It's like 35 or so,
35 million just from basketball.
And then sponsorships,
like unless you're conor Mcgregor,
floyd mayweather,
you're not gonna make that much money
from fighting.
They can make that much money from
fighting,
but they're so rare.
And then connor could only make that
much money from fighting if he box
floyd.
Like even though the fight with Kobi was
the number one mma paper view of all
time,
the number two paper view in the history
of paper views just behind a floyd
mayweather versus Manny Pacquiao.
Right.
It got more paper view bys then floyd
mayweather versus conor Mcgregor,
I believe.
I believe that's true.
Wow.
Look that up.
I think it was 2.2
million for floyd mayweather versus
conor Mcgregor and then 2.4
Khabib neurohacker grumet off.
I think it was number two of all time.
Why?
Just behind the floyd mayweather or
manny Pacquiao fight,
which is just incredible.
So they must've made a shit ton of money
from that.
But how many times can connor do that?
Don't,
you know,
I mean look,
the Irish support him,
but people thought he had a chance of
winning that fight and then once he gets
smashed like that,
I don't think they're
going to think he has a chance of
winning again unless he does something
significant.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
He has to beat somebody like he has to
fight like Kevin Lee and fuck him up.
You know,
if you fought Kevin Lee or Tony Ferguson
and fucked him up and then you know,
said look,
I had two years off,
I wasn't ready for could be,
but I'm ready now.
Fuck the mayweathers and he said
something like that.
People,
he's got to have some success though.
Floyd Connor was 6.7
million.
Floyd manny was 4.4
million and then it would have been
right around the next one,
which has been Oscar and floyd,
which is 2.4
so he has to say 2.5
2.4
so I've been right around number.
So it was number three then number three
overall,
number one,
mma,
number one mma.
But number three overall it could be
tied.
So what would the one of the boxing
numbers again,
what was it,
6.7
for the floyd conner,
4.4
for floyd.
Manny.
Wow.
That is so crazy.
6.7
for floyd connor wide.
My numbers off big time.
But the amount of money that that will
it,
it's so interesting that you know,
with that phone around this kind of
extrinsic motivation,
money,
media fame versus intrinsic motivation.
And,
and in a,
in a strange way with the swim,
you know,
when we got around John Groups at the
top,
it was a,
everyone was like,
yeah,
you just set the land's end to John
O'groats record,
well done.
And those cameras.
And it was amazing.
And then I was just swimming across the
Murray firth getting hit by jellyfish
in,
you know,
six degree water.
It was just horrible.
And,
and,
and I think,
I think right now as well,
and Khabib fascinates me that,
you know,
and I don't know the logistics again,
I've been at sea so I'm still trying to
catch up,
but he was offered so much money for the
rematch,
but I believe he turned it down.
It could be no,
there was talk of a rematch,
but the UFC did not offer him.
Right.
Financial.
Some of those rumors,
they hadn't even talked,
they were trying to figure out what to
do next.
And in fact the UFC said that most
likely next was Tony Ferguson.
Okay.
So that's,
that's the current,
the last time they talked about someone
fighting for the title again,
but it was a while ago now again,
it might be UFC embedded when I,
and I think it was when,
could be years ago now,
met George Saint Pierre and could be,
you know,
said,
oh I'd lovely to meet you and then just,
and then it could be with smiling and he
said,
Oh,
you know,
my dad has always said that he'd love to
see me fight George St Pierre.
And for me that was really interesting
because it could be some motivation
seems to be intrinsic and putting his
skills against the best people in the
world.
You could offer more than money in the
world,
but he just wants to do something.
When he talks about his dad,
his family,
and it's a different beast.
And that's what I find really
interesting.
That,
but,
but I'm not saying different as in
better,
worse,
good or bad,
because ultimately mayweather's never
lost.
But when you see someone like
mayweather,
you think easy,
just an extrinsically motivated.
When he's saying it,
if it doesn't make money,
it doesn't make sense.
You kind of look at him going,
well,
you're extrinsically motivated,
arguably.
And I don't know,
I've
never met the guy and stuff.
But you,
you're,
you're extrinsic motivator but you'd
never lost.
So which one's more powerful?
I don't think he's completely
extrinsically motivated.
I think that's a lot of it is an act.
Do you think he's too good,
too good?
There's,
I mean,
there,
there has to be some,
some deep emotional connection to his
work.
There's gotta be some connection to his
legacy.
What he's been able to do the way he's
been able to retire undefeated as a
professional boxer,
which is almost unheard of.
Right.
Cause I want to believe that.
And I hope that's true because,
because you're almost taught like
intrinsic motivation did it for the
love,
you know,
in sort of unit the sweet science.
I want to believe that may wave is there
and he's studying it.
If it may be,
he doesn't want you to see that side.
He's too good.
Right.
He's kind of have a love of boxing.
There's no way he's too good the way he,
he's artistically taking guys apart.
Like you go to the Canelo Alvarez fight.
The way he was like it was slipping away
from Canelo was big shots and then
popping them with the jabs like pitch.
Yeah.
Not Today.
Not Today man.
Good enough for this.
And it was intelligent in his approach
to that fight too cause he made canelo
drain himself to get down to 150 pounds.
Right,
right.
That was a different thing cause he
forced Canelo to cut a lot of weight to
get down to his weight class.
But it'd been,
floyd really realistically is 147 pound
fighter.
I mean he's only fighting in these
higher weight classes cause the money's
there.
It's a fucking wizard man.
He's a wizard.
But that's what I mean about like that
that will start,
you know,
he's playing with everybody's head.
You talk about like psychological
warfare,
you know,
the art of war and everything like that.
And he's doing it on a mass scale like
we've probably never experienced before.
Well,
what was fascinating was connor was
doing it to him and was screaming in his
face with a hard on,
by the way,
at the way in.
So I don't know how he generated a
harder one,
but uh,
you know,
he must have played with his deck before
he got out there.
It took some Viagra or something.
I really think that might've been part
of the psychological motivations that
just screaming in his face,
I'm gonna fucking kill you a little puke
you piece of shit.
And flow is just like this,
just dead face staring at them.
Right.
Didn't scream back dead face stayed
comms like tomorrow I am going to fuck
you up and there ain't no god damn thing
in the world.
It's going to change there.
Right,
right.
Well Connor was like the first guy that
floyd ever fought that could fuck him up
in a real fight though.
Right.
That was the,
there was a different element of danger
there because there was an agreed upon
rule set where connor wasn't going to
kick,
wasn't going to take them down.
What's going to strangle them.
So because of that,
floyd knew he could win,
but he also knew without a doubt,
if they were just going to fight,
fight.
If there was no gloves,
if they just put the gloves aside and
just had a street fight,
connor would fucking kill him.
I mean there's not a question on my mind
is not that not,
there's not a doubt to be had.
Connor would kick him from a distance.
He would probe him with
front kicks,
kick his legs,
floyd would start to limp.
Connor would step in,
tie him up,
elbow him,
take him down,
smash his face into a bloody pulp,
do whatever you want it to him,
strangle him,
rip his knees apart with leg locks.
You can do whatever he want it to them.
If they were going to just fight,
fight,
you know.
And he said that to him and he's like,
if this was a fight at fucking kill you,
he just looked right at him.
And he's saying that to him.
Floyd had to just eat it,
but it didn't matter because it wasn't a
fight.
It was a boxing match and he didn't have
a chance.
But do you think that worked with Aldo
for instance?
Because,
and again,
this is me kind of just talking more on
the,
the mental warfare side and not really
understanding the technical aspect.
But that world tour was fascinating to
watch and the whole way round.
And,
and again,
um,
this is me not understanding all that
much about him and maybe being
fascinated with a mental aspect that,
uh,
and again,
George Saint Pierre,
when he fought Nick Diaz and,
and they were saying,
you know,
we're going to,
he's going to talk to you and he's going
to talk to you.
He's going to walk you down.
Don't be effected.
And George St Pierre,
was that across?
Yeah,
I won't be.
And then he was talking so much that I
even said it just invoked again,
actually going back to what we were
talking about,
you know,
our bodies,
as much as we like to think about it as
black and white,
the complex biochemical organisms.
So when I,
and I'm not saying that,
you know,
the Diaz brothers necessarily think like
that,
but they,
but I'm going to talk to you and I'm
going to mess with your mechanic.
Do you know the,
the chemical reactions within your body
neurotransmitters and making you fought
the mind?
Fuck you.
They're doing it for sure.
They're dumb.
They're not stupid.
When Nick's doing that too,
he's like,
what bitch?
Which going to a bitch?
He's fucking with your head,
man.
I remember the first time he did that to
Robbie lawler.
Robbie was like 2021 years old and nick
was young too,
and they're both standing to the,
they moved into the cage and they closed
it and nick has just started saying,
stockton motherfucker,
Stoughton bribee Laura was like,
what?
And he's like standing in front of them.
That's against Carlos condit.
He drops the best one was against
Anderson Silva.
He fell to the ground and pretended he
was sleeping.
He put his hands together like he's
taking a nap and laid down and I
couldn't stop laughing.
I was like,
this mother fucker is so crazy.
He just like right there,
drop down instead of relaxing,
go to the back,
go back.
That one's better.
Yeah.
So when you see him lay down and leaned
on his head like,
I'm just going to take a nap here.
Like what are you doing bitch?
Anderson Silva did forrest Griffin and
has done all his career,
but he's doing this to a guy who's the
187 85 pound rather best ever.
Right.
And he's not even 185 pounder.
He's really a one 55 pounder.
I mean,
Nick Diaz,
when he was a champion in strike force
or lead xc lead XC,
right.
He was a 155 pound champion.
Well,
what's amazing here is everything that
we talked about in terms of intangibles,
mind,
body connection.
Nick is imposing his mind,
body connection on Anderson in that he's
going to,
I'm going to mess with y'all fucking
with head for sure.
What
will,
was he the champ?
Why am I not remembering it?
Was it elite Xc or strike force that
Nick Diaz was the champion of?
It might've been strike force.
Okay.
Why can't I remember?
Sorry.
Yeah,
why?
Well,
why did I think a leader Xc,
see,
no,
he,
I'll use the fought elite xc.
Did he?
Oh,
okay.
Now I remember because,
That was because mayhem Miller and uh,
jake shields had a brawl in elite xc and
Nick Diaz was a part of the brawl.
They're all piled on each other and that
was chaos.
But Stripe,
that was him pull daily,
that knock out.
But also just kind of like fell and,
and uh,
so it's,
it's so strange that this intangible,
this thing that I'm now fascinated.
We've liked men,
Kj noons elite XC.
So he did fight him in a next,
see?
That's right.
So he finally Dixie and then became
strikeforce champion.
That's why I'm confused.
Wow.
Yeah.
Um,
that whatever mayweather did differently
to Aldo might have been granted
different sports granted,
but there was something that mcgregor
was like,
it's not working the way that when he
pinched,
you know,
de has neck and shoulder,
I turn around and you know,
again,
without understanding the technical
element there was,
for me,
it was so fascinating watching the two.
And like you said,
mayweather stood there completely stoic
Aldo was not comfortable with it and he
lost his composure and he attacked,
he attacked connor in a way that exposed
him.
He,
he got exposed to a counter shot.
He was,
he wasn't patient.
He was very emotional and he just wanted
to fuck that dude up and he just got
clipped.
Right,
right.
You know,
and look,
connor played in perfectly played them
like a fiddle.
Yeah.
Hey Man,
I've got to wrap this up.
It's already five buck.
We just went three hours.
Believe it or not.
No,
don't be sorry.
It was awesome.
I really appreciate it.
And uh,
what you did is beyond impressive man.
I mean,
it's fascinating stuff and I feel like
we could do a hundred of these kinds of
conversations.
Don't so sorry.
I'll often even in Los Angeles.
Uh,
no,
this is my first time.
Oh,
we'll come back and visit again,
man.
Next time you gonna to swim to the moon,
let me know.
This is here.
I honestly like next time we'll get,
we'll get burton again for the record.
He's an amazing physical specimen of a
fat guy.
Right.
We'll go swimming or like,
okay,
we'll do something.
We'll,
let's,
let's definitely do another podcast.
That's be amazing.
Thank you.
So really,
really,
really appreciate it.
Thank you.
Alright.
Oh,
tell people who your social media,
how did it get to you?
Oh bless.
Yeah.
Um,
so yeah,
instagram,
just a raw sedgley spell please.
Yeah,
I know it gets difficult.
R o.
A same on twitter.
And same on facebook.
Yeah,
so far.
Thank you.
Thank you,
brother.
Thank you.
All right,
folks.
That's it for today.
Bye.
Okay.