Doom,
doom,
uh,
data.
Um,
and we're live Josh steps I didn't even
notice.
And then I took a sip of coffee and then
my mouth was full of coffee.
Perfect timing.
Realize.
All right dude.
Should have had a count down to five or
something instead of three.
What?
Jamie was doing this thing with his
fingers.
Yeah,
he was.
I saw him over there,
out of the periphery of the corner of my
eye and I wasn't sure what he was
dealing with it a countdown.
Was it a wave?
Gang signs.
That's his gang.
Fucking james and Jay are gang throws up
the three,
two,
one.
Will you teach me after the show?
Jamie?
Some of the signs after the show.
You can even talk about it.
Dude.
Sorry to keep on the DL.
First rule of jre gang.
You got talk about January.
Perfect.
Time to have you in the fucking world is
literally about to go crazy.
What's going on?
About two to half.
It's just the bubbling.
I think we,
we think it has,
but here we are and this wonderful
office park in the valley in California.
Everything's fine.
Go outside,
there's birds chirping,
so the whole world hasn't gone crazy.
It's true,
but there's spots that are going fucking
crazy.
Yale has gone crazy and pay attention to
that.
The students did my whole show up at it
last week on my new podcast.
Which way can I do an episode on Josh
Jumps?
Podcast,
cozy called Hashtag.
We'd have people live if you live.
He's like down with the hip social
future.
You gotta get with it.
I do hashtags or something.
I only use like in jest,
you know?
Well this is sort of tongue in cheek.
It's also a cool way of like if people
have searched for you,
that's probably a bazillion way that
people lives podcasts,
but there's only one that's going to
start with a Hashtag.
So you put it in a Hashtag and as well.
Prison will be the first to come up.
I use it for the UFC only like Hashtag
UFC 91 93.
If I'm talking about like an event.
Yeah,
do that.
But hashtags are interesting because if
you ever go to Hashtags,
you ever go to like Hashtag black
twitter?
Yeah.
I never do it.
Jesus,
it's,
it's made.
That's where he spends 23 hours a day.
Well,
you know how sometimes sometimes you
don't need to go to them because they
come to you,
but can you say something?
Then you get taken out of context.
Then you can end up by some blog and
then all of a sudden,
like all over the weekend,
I've been getting all these tweets just
out of the blue about what fascism is.
I was like,
what?
Who are these people and why they
tweeting at me?
I don't even know.
I didn't even know that I said anything
about fascism.
Well,
it's because breitbart picked up
something that I did on a segment on
huffpost live last week and write
something up about it,
about how apparently I implied that
Donald trump was a fascist,
which actually didn't mean because I
don't think that he is,
but.
And all of a sudden I'm in the Hashtag
like I'm part of the Hashtag about
fascism without even choosing it.
I believe that most people who use the
term fascist or fascism don't really
exactly know what the term meant.
You're totally right,
so let's help them out right now.
Let's find the official definition of
fascism because I think most people get
it wrong.
Fascism means and authoritarian and
nationalistic,
right wing system of government and
social organization,
so people use that.
There's other definitions of of course,
but extreme right wing authoritarian.
People use that for a lot of like non
fascist reason.
That's true and I probably used it
sloppily myself in the context in which
bright pub was picking me up and they
would have a point if,
if I do come across as saying that
Donald trump is a fascist,
but all the people who were tweeting
back at me with saying,
fascism isn't right when you idiot,
it's left wing and slept way.
Socialism is the real fascism.
You don't understand the meaning of the
word,
so I just responded with an with a link
to the Oxford dictionary,
which also includes the wood right wing
in it.
Like,
yeah,
it's mostly considered right when we.
When people are using it in the left
wing circles now or about left wing
circles because they're using it and the
authoritarian context because that is,
I think that's applicable because a lot
of what is going on in like really
extreme social justice,
leftwing type organizations or groups is
that they're trying to control behavior
and they're trying to mitigate
criticism.
Like you can't criticize these concepts
because these concepts are supported by
social justice.
And um,
I've got an interesting study on that,
but I wanted that I brought for you.
And before I get to it,
I want,
I don't want to forget what I was just
thinking when you were talking about how
here we are in the valley village
outside.
Chirp,
sunshine trees.
Very good.
That's a very good.
Betty Jo.
Thank you.
Practiced that all day.
It was not a little one.
I want to hear it again.
I'm going to put that as my ringtone.
I do it too.
It will never hear your phone put up
really,
really loud.
So I was in Beirut briefly a few months
ago and he was standing on the rooftop
of this swanky hotel looking out over
the Mediterranean and looking at
evidence the houses and I was like,
he's just like an idyllic,
beautiful part of the world in terms of
its natural beauty and I could
practically swim from here to the Greek
islands,
help people.
Ah,
basically,
right.
The refugees and I had just been in the
Greek in Athens as well,
which is like geographically,
physiologically Italy,
Greece at the same as these fucked up
parts of North Africa and Israel and
Palestine and been Lebanon and not to
mention Syria.
And I was like just struck by how
capable we are a fucking things up as
paypal because the actual geography is
the same.
Like those waves at the same waves as
the ones on the Italian Riviera.
But the Italian Riviera is the Italian
Riviera and this shit hole is this
shithole through no difference of
climate or some old.
The booties are still there.
The booties are the same,
but religion and politics just has an
endless capacity to,
to screw things up.
You could call it religion or politics,
but it's really just power.
It's human beings trying to achieve
power and you could do it through
whatever modality you choose,
but the reality is it's just people that
are trying to control other people and
trying to gain things,
but I think it's in particular tribes
trying to control other tribes and
politics and religion make you much more
likely.
It make it much easier to be tribal,
much easier to not be an individual
story,
but it's sort of.
But isn't the argument against that.
What we were just talking about one in
terms of social justice warriors and
people calling people fascist mean that
you're,
you're in a tribe.
If you are on the extreme left or the
extreme right,
you're in a tribe.
You know when you talk to right wing
people,
they're almost incapable of not bringing
up liberals or the liberals think they
don't just bring up their own concepts
in their own thoughts.
They'll immediately disparage liberal
ideas.
Like immediately,
you know,
they'll tell you,
well,
you're a liberal,
you know,
you,
you believe in this and this and that.
So you're a liberal and then like
immediately like downplay your ideas.
That's a tribal.
Absolutely.
That's politics.
It's religion as is.
And social justice worries will do the
same thing.
They'll do the same thing about.
I mean my,
you know,
the first,
the first time I came to your attention
was with that interview with.
So he parked the cancel Kobe activist.
Right.
And convincing still one of my favorite.
When you just broke it down to her,
you're like,
this is so fucking unbelievable.
And you could tell she was just like
devastated that you even had the balls
to question her to people that hadn't,
hadn't seen it,
that she wanted to have the,
have the Kolbe a report canceled because
apparently it was racist and I did an
interview with her on huffpost live.
Well,
it was nice for people who don't even
know the show.
Kobe plays a character.
He plays an extreme left wing kind of
goofy character,
excuse me,
extreme right wing,
kind of goofy character.
And in that context of that character,
he made a joke about racism.
It was a joke about racism and in that
it was a funny joke.
Do you remember what the joke was?
Yeah,
I do.
It was Dan Snyder,
who,
who's the head of the Redskins,
right?
Who was saying that he.
He said that he didn't have to change
the name of the redskins because it was
racist.
He was going to set up a charity for
native American and causes and Stephen
Colbert and his right wing persona said
that sometimes he'd been accused of
doing jokes that could be considered to
be offensive about Asian people,
so in return he was going to set up the
Ching Chung Dingdong Foundation for
sensitivity towards orientals or
whatever or whatever,
and she found that offensive.
Not really.
I don't believe she really did it.
I think she found it.
It was a green light for her to attack
and to use hashtag activism and to get
them get some publicity.
There's one story that's making the
rounds today,
a Kansas City University professor who
in a class I'm about racism,
a discussion about racism and
discrimination.
She used the word nigger and in using
the word,
all these students are trying to get her
fired and she's been removed of her
duties right now.
She's been temporarily suspended under
review or whatever their processes,
but in just saying
the word,
not saying someone is like,
this is a word that people have issues.
Let's discuss words that people have
issues with.
What are the origins of these words?
Why are they problematic?
What is,
you know,
what can be done about this?
I don't remember.
I'm not sure exactly what the context of
her classes,
but they.
I'm sure it will.
I'm sure the context wasn't.
Let's go around accusing black people
have being absolutely not.
Absolutely not,
but this is the same kind of thing.
I don't believe anyone in that class was
actually hurt by that.
Well,
we sort of found the green light and
they attacked.
Yeah.
Don't we learn what to be offended by
it?
Yes.
So it's possible that that someone felt
like an initial kind of reaction of,
oh my God,
I just heard that word.
That's good.
I've been told that that word is
completely unacceptable under all
circumstances,
and I've been told that I'm allowed to
be offended.
Yeah,
that's right.
And in in date ought to be offended.
Yes.
And so like I was amazed by the power of
that word when I first came to the
states because they're only here is,
it does,
do we have this demoss would the end
would like that phrase?
Yeah.
That's.
I mean I'd never heard that until I came
to the site.
So in Australia it was completely
unacceptable to ever to ever use the
word nigger against somebody.
You would just never do that.
I was taught since the earliest days
that racism is terrible,
but you could talk about it in polite
company.
I mean you,
if you.
If it came up,
you'd be able to discuss the existence
of the word and nobody would ever say
the word,
but you guys have racism towards
aborigines.
That's pretty.
That's pretty real over there.
This is towards black people,
right?
No,
that's right.
But there's this.
There is a much,
much,
much bigger awareness of the kind of
tragedy of the original sin.
Of what happened when Australia was
settled than there is here towards
native Americans.
I sort of regard native Americans as
being the people who've really been
screwed in this country.
I mean not to,
not that it should be a competition of
like who's you know,
who's suffering was worse.
So like I'll put my slavery genocide
more,
right?
That's right.
Because I always hate it when,
when we get into those games.
But um,
nobody even talks about,
like in Australia,
if you go to an award ceremony,
for example,
if you're at the grammys,
every single presenter will come up and
they will begin by saying,
I want to start by acknowledging the
traditional owners of this land that you
had a windy people,
uh,
you know,
they'll,
they'll at least give a kind of
politically correct nod to the fact that
we occupied the country and basically
wiped out an entire people.
And you know,
you'll see aboriginal flags flying on
Parliament House alongside the
Australian flag.
What the,
I don't even know what the night of
American flag is.
Still even have a flag.
I don't believe they did.
I mean,
if they did it,
noted aborigines back then symbols,
you know,
they,
they certainly had symbols that were
indicative of different tribes or
different regions.
But I don't,
I don't,
I don't think they had flags.
I could be wrong.
No,
but I mean aboriginals didn't have
flags.
Aboriginals didn't even have metal,
so.
Yeah.
Right.
Okay.
I mean they were at the time when the
British settled Australia and I always
get accused when I say things like this
have been politically correct,
social justice warriors of imposing onto
traditional societies.
I have an idea of human civilization as
being better if it's like industrialized
than if it's not industrialized.
And because I'm like a white man who
liked,
totally thinks that like the 21st
century is better than the fucking 15th
century.
Let me back up because it is better.
Yeah.
They have,
we have computers and the Internet,
we have books,
we have a lot of things that are better
than like flint knives.
So let's just having said that,
you're such a wide,
you such a white man,
Joe.
Uh,
having said that,
if you think about like the,
the traditional anthropological
conception of human evolution going from
like the,
you know,
the,
the discovery of fire and farming and
then up through the bronze age and the
INA agents on average and he's when the,
when the British settled Australia were
the least advanced civilization in the
world by far.
I mean we're talking a mosque and again,
I like the politically correct.
Pardon me?
It has to keep qualifying.
They had been around for over 100,000
years.
So they were doing something successful.
Like it's only been 2000.
Jesus.
Well,
let's rabbits are doing a good job.
Did you just compare aboriginal
Australians to rabbits?
Did it in that context?
Okay.
I like,
I like you for that because I like
analogies and I like being able to
accept analogies without thinking that
the person is saying that the two things
are the same in every respect because I
always get pulled up.
Like I made a Hitler analogy the other
day about I was talking to who was at
Donny Deutsch.
Do you know that guy?
Yes.
Um,
and uh,
he was talking about how he likes trump
and I,
and,
and I might some parallel where I was
like,
he was,
I was simply saying that like,
he was like,
he's popular,
he's touching a vein.
I was like,
yeah,
but is that the only reason to respect
somebody hit let's touch the vein as
well?
And he was like,
he got all outraged on the air at the
fact that I would like say Hitler.
He was like,
you can't do that.
Like,
how dare you.
I'm Jewish.
And I was,
I was like,
I'm not saying that trump is the same as
Hitler,
you idiot.
I'm saying that saying that the
criterion by which you were judging his
success is floored.
And I was using an analogy to do so.
Well,
he should be,
he should be ashamed because he's doing
the exact thing.
We're accusing the extreme left up.
He saw a green light and he went after
it.
That's right.
And He,
does he really think I'm a Nazi
sympathizer or that I'm like shitting on
it.
And then.
So then I was like,
Hey,
my grandmother was in the concentration
camps and I pull a juke out on me and
then I just moved right up.
Fuck yeah,
Donny.
So anyway,
area aborigines didn't,
didn't have like metal and stuff.
No,
they were,
I mean they were extremely primitive so
far removed from what we consider to be
advanced civilization that Australia
felt it was okay to actually take their
children and adopt them.
And this was recent.
This was in like the fifties,
you know,
until you know,
until 19,
69 aborigines were classified in
Australia as foreigner.
Whoa.
In other words,
they want
not flora,
it might've been a couple of floral
aborigines,
but uh,
they were mostly like in the same
category as Kangaroos now you couldn't
dark,
you couldn't kill him.
He couldn't know.
But I mean they weren't officially
classified as full and it's just that
they weren't classified as human,
like they weren't considered to be
people in the.
So like you can't kill a chimp either.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's a recent thing.
But it's come a long way in the past 15,
20 years now.
I think there's a general consensus
that,
that we really fucked them over a hope
so kids are fucking babies no matter.
I mean no matter how not to defend it,
but this was at the same time that Jim
crow was going on here.
Right?
I mean it's not,
it's not like we were in a lightened
our.
Well,
our forefathers were enlightened in the
fifties about rice.
Yeah.
Well the,
everybody was pretty fucked up back
then.
I think it's very difficult for us to
understand in 2015 what it was like in
1950 [inaudible] I think we assume that
they should have known better.
They should have been like us,
but 100 years before them they were
cowboys.
That's they.
They had horses riding trains and that's
it.
And 100 years before that they didn't
even have fucking trains,
you know,
in 100 years before that mean you're,
you're in the dark ages.
Yeah.
I mean you're 1,514
hundreds,
a few hundred years removed from gingiss
con.
It's fast and it's like,
I don't remember whether I've spoken to
you about this before,
but I was when I was in grace on the
trip and I was just talking about,
um,
I was standing at the,
you know,
the Acropolis in Greece.
I was expecting to be wowed like Altura
PSA by all the Shia age of this thing.
Oh,
I'm at the birthplace of Western
civilization.
And instead what I thought was,
I'd actually just been back to New
Zealand because my grandma died.
She was one day shy of her 100th
birthday.
Damn.
Almost made it 99 and 364 days.
So she was just born premature.
She would've had that mean when you were
born.
So arbitrary.
I think labor,
yeah.
That's a good way of thinking about it.
If you take her from like the,
the third trimester.
Oh yeah.
She made it.
She made it from the quickening.
Yes.
She made it from the yes soul made it
100 percent.
And what I was struck by at the
Acropolis,
the Parthenon was not like how old human
civilization was,
but it was like my grandma,
her lifetime is a manageable period of
time in my brain.
I can think about that in a way that
when you talk to me about something that
happened 50,000
years ago,
it's just meaningless.
So when you talk about the size of the
cosmos or a light year or something,
it doesn't like I might be able to
understand it intellectually,
but it just washes off in my head.
I don't know what I'm talking about,
but the lifetime of my grandmother,
that's a manageable span of time.
I can imagine.
A hundred years.
Yes.
And you know what?
This acropolis at the dawn of Western
civilization,
before humans had even invented anything
that we would recognize as being
civilized in terms of laws and
procedures and technologies that only
100 of my grandma's.
Yeah.
How about this one?
Sorry,
it's 40 140,000
users.
40 of my grandma's.
Jesus was 20 of my grandma's a nuclear
weapon.
My grandma was born during the
[inaudible] campaign and World War One.
Hitler wasn't even a name that her
parents knew when she was born.
The depression hadn't happened.
The bomb hadn't been invented,
let alone computers.
How faster things going pretty fast.
Like how recently was it over the span
of geological time that we would
monkeys,
effectively,
they believe to 100,000
years ago.
Human beings,
we're in this form,
they're bullied,
but it changes depending upon the fossil
record.
Like when they add new evidence,
like they just found a.
like within the last couple of weeks,
they've recognized a new subspecies of
human beings and ancient subspecies.
They found a giant tooth,
so they're.
They're.
They're finding fossil records that
pretty much pretty much coincide with
the established belief that people are
200,000
plus years in this form.
Like you could take a person from
200,000
years ago,
they'd probably be considerably smaller
than us because they didn't get a lot of
food and you'd put them in a movie
theater and they would look just like
you were.
I maybe was teeth.
Yeah,
long.
They kept your mouth shut,
you know,
we showered them,
trimmed whatever fucking weird hair they
have.
You know,
they're probably just very strangely
Harry,
but you know,
obviously in the fossil record we're not
getting too much.
It's very rare they find skin and hair,
so they're just kind of guessing what
they looked like on the outside,
what they believe that about 200,000
years in this form,
give or take 100,000
years.
So that's pretty recent.
More than what we have than take.
Yeah.
Not really good.
Give and take
what's most,
what's most sort of frightening to me is
how recently technology has become as
powerful as it is,
especially nukes and superimposing
technology that was invented within the
lifetime of my dad.
Think about what we just said,
just that.
What's crazy?
Call it 300,000
years ago.
3,000
of your grandma's?
Yeah,
that's it.
And we're monkeys.
Yeah.
Just 3000.
Like a good size of theater show.
Yep.
Like you go to the Chicago theater,
that's 3,700
people.
That's a good spot to look at those
people in that audience.
If you get a full Chicago theater of
3,700
people,
if every one of them lived birth to
death to stop and think about that.
That's fucking crazy credit,
isn't it?
That's crazy.
It's fucking crazy.
That's 300,000
years
and you don't even need to go that.
I mean you didn't even take it that far
before the kinds of lives that people
will live living and the kinds of
concerns that they had to concern
themselves with was so parochial and
they knew so little.
I mean even just back to the Middle
Ages.
I mean think about having 50 of my.
No,
sorry.
Five
of my grandmother's get us back to the
Middle Ages.
Five of them.
That's crazy.
50.
Get us back to before we had before the
Parthenon.
God,
I mean we are hairless apes who just
just now,
just for right now,
just tap into to have discovered the
Adam amazing technology than the theater
thing is really free.
That's a good one.
I like that.
I love that was freaking me out because
that's monkeys.
I mean,
we go back to like,
we're basically fucking like the scene
in 2001 when they're around the
monolith.
That's what we're talking about.
So we're talking about say how many
people,
how many people do you fit in a big
stadium?
One hundred,
hundred and 50,000,
something like that,
like 20 and football stage.
And like the,
uh,
the place that we did in Australia for
the UFC I believe is 70,000
people.
And that was an enormous.
Was that the MCG that was at a,
at a hod,
they've started sponsoring everything
since I left.
So I don't even know what that would be
now because I don't know,
the big airline back then was in Sydney
or Melbourne.
Melbourne.
I'd probably be the,
uh,
the cricket ground rent formally.
The probably.
It's got a retractable roof.
Yeah,
that's right.
It was the site of the biggest UFC ever
and it was 70,000
people and that's an enormous,
enormous place.
But they have football places like Jim,
you're a football fan.
What's the biggest spot?
Uh,
I don't know if it's the exact biggest
Ohio stadium in Columbus for the
buckeyes plays like a 110.
They can fit in there and fill out eight
officially thousand.
What is that like when it's filled?
I must be insane.
Super loud.
A I,
the way they have the sound going into,
it's a little bit of bounce off each
other being in it.
So it's,
it's an insane.
That's good.
We've got to be with the colosseum was
like ingrown and half,
half white,
but there's,
there's crazy people are drunk as shit
yelling at each other and there's fights
all over up into huge stadiums that are
like a hundred hundred and 10,000.
So let's say 100,000
stadium.
Right,
right.
It's a big place,
but if you do use your analogy of
Chicago.
My grandmother analogy,
that's 10 million years.
Oh my God,
what were we 10 million years ago?
We were rodents.
Well,
when did the dinosaurs die at 75 million
years ago.
Apparently we were a type of almost like
a shrew looking road and that's what we
were.
That's the current.
That's what really makes evolutionary
deniers angry,
you know,
the people who are just shitty little
rats telling me that I was at Ohio state
football game filled paypal a go.
I wasn't true.
The crazy thing is that the science
deniers,
the evolution denies other ones who are
more monkey like than the ones who
believe in science.
True.
That was an old bill Hicks bit is he
just do think about people being
uninvolved,
the people that don't believe in
evolution or the most looked the most
unevolved.
Exactly,
yes.
Right.
Yeah.
Well it's,
it's too hard for us to.
I mean,
we're sitting here,
we're not science deniers and we're
looking at the age of your grandma 100
years and we're just going back a
few grandmas and we're like,
fuck.
Well this is the first time.
I've been amazed by that though because
I.
Although you know,
when else I had this feeling was Richard
Dawkins has this cool analogy where he
says,
imagine he's talking about how evolution
denies.
I keep wanting to say climate deniers
evolution.
Denies we'll.
We'll talk about how there were these
gaps in the fossil record.
Right?
And how like,
well,
what happened to the species that were
interim species in between the species
that we find Richard Dawkins tries to
make the point.
The whole concept of a species is
something that we sort of retroactively
superimposed onto things because lots of
animals,
because the vast majority of animals die
out and don't manage to succeed in this
world.
The vast majority of mutations fail.
But he says,
imagine getting a book.
Imagine getting a picture book like a
high school year book and it's got your
photo in it on the last page and the
page before that is your mother's photo
on the page before that is her mother's
photo in the page before that is her
mother's photo.
Right?
And you go back and back and back and
back,
all the way back to the first dawn of
life.
Hundreds of millions of years ago.
And each,
each page is going to be,
is going to basically look like the page
before.
It isn't going to be a point at which
like the shrew becomes a monkey.
Or like,
you know,
some amphibious creature becomes a
shrew.
Every child looks like it's parent,
but as you flipped through the pages of
this book,
it's such a thick book.
The overtime,
like one of those little cartoon figures
that you could draw and it looks like
it's moving on the page.
You just stopped morphing back,
back,
back until eventually you're a fucking
fish,
but it's.
Well,
you know,
your great,
great,
great.
Grandma is just adding enough grades.
Yeah,
and that's what people don't understand.
It's just has to be a really,
really,
really big book.
Well,
our concept of time is just,
it's too hard.
We'll look at it this way.
Look at the changes that a person takes
over the period of their life.
Look at a person from,
you know,
think about a child and then turn that
child in your grandma before she died.
That's a very different physical looking
thing as age sets in.
Yeah,
sure.
You know what I mean?
Like there's a lot of changes that go on
nature,
like the growth of animals,
death of animals,
of plants and things along those lines.
There's all sorts of growth and death
and all sorts of changing and while
we're looking at it in a static form,
you'd,
if you go outside and look at those
trees,
they look exactly the same as they'd
looked yesterday and it takes a long
time before you recognize like,
oh,
this fucking things,
growing,
feeling that,
feeling that myself kind of for the
first time,
like my birthday yesterday,
and uh,
I've gotten to that age where,
you know,
I don't really care about.
I didn't really know.
Like when I booked this trip,
I didn't even know that it was my
birthday.
How old he is today,
38.
That's when you start denying it.
I'm 48.
So really start denying it,
denying what getting older and attention
to has not
even important to me.
Why I'm concentrating on the present.
I live in the moment,
Joshua,
he just sees it.
It's a comforting bullshit as well.
When you get to be like 78,
just like,
what do you do?
I mean,
what are you going to not parasail
because you're 78.
No,
that's right.
But I think that the most of it is true
though,
that like,
you know,
age is on the inside because I can feel
that now at this age I just have to do a
ship more work and not to feel crappy
and 20,
22,
it's just everything is great.
Your body is just automatically
functioning exactly as it should now.
Like my ankle will just occasionally
hurt.
You know,
that didn't happen when I was 22.
I remember that.
I actually remember the first time in my
life when I was getting out of a car and
as I got out of the car seat I went.
I was like,
what the fuck was that just grunt as I
was getting up and you wanted to,
you know,
just a very small like just to get out
of a car seat.
But you know,
just like,
like you might,
it's not a big deal.
It's just like a young teenager never,
never just leaps out of the cost seat
was an old person.
Gets out of the car seat going.
That's a good point.
I might notice when I,
for the first time,
yeah,
it's like I'm old,
I'm getting old,
got to exercise into my thirties and I
see other things.
Nature is trying to kill you and in
nature would like you to give in to the
same decay that you see in animals and
the forest and what have you.
It would like you to just accept the
natural process,
but us in our clever little minds have
figured out how to mitigate that process
at least slightly with exercise and
nutrition,
proper rest and supplementation,
hormone supplementation and going to the
doctors and new inventions and cryo
therapy and all this crazy shit that
people figured out how to just put the
brakes on this fucking have it
inevitable demise.
I know we're living way too long for
nature.
Nature loves us up until we're in our
late teens,
early twenties.
Yeah,
but by now I've been like,
I've been coming sperm for decades.
Nature's like you must have had kids by
now,
right to you.
Too much information.
I think everyone can.
Everyone can figure out that.
I've probably been able to come since I
was a teenager.
Maybe gone tantric,
you might be one of those dudes to come
inside them and re re,
re vigorous there.
Is that a real thing?
Do they.
Can you actually consistently orgasm
over a long period of time without
coming?
The problem with all that,
and I'm sure I'm going to get tweets
about this,
is everyone who practices it is a
fucking lunatic so
you don't know because you haven't
actually tested it out.
Yeah,
so if you talk to them,
you know,
they'll tell you,
yes,
I completely come inside.
I come internally,
I absorb,
I reabsorb and the energy that I get
from that,
it's so much more amazing than the
energy that you would get from an
external orgasm and then they just get
like really into talking to you about
tantric.
Annoying.
You know,
I mean they do it,
but is it by contracting that muscle,
the muscle is topped with a paid his
name.
I'm forgetting between your bowls and
yet know there's a.
there's a particular muscle there which
apparently if you,
if you learn to build it up,
like be doing exercises throughout the
day,
then it can.
It will compress and it will push
against,
uh,
the,
whatever the,
that tube is called.
I'm not really medically today,
the decor.
So it's like a mail key goal,
right?
Yeah.
Have you ever seen that Russian lady
that can pick up?
I think she can carry like 32 kilograms
for the pussy.
It might be more than that.
More than 70 pounds I believe.
I haven't checked.
Yeah.
She has this ability to like,
I guess they put like a ball and then
attach a string to a ball at the end of
the string is a weight and she puts that
ball inside of her pussy and just locks
down on that motherfucker and then can
literally lift up like 70 pounds of
weight.
It's impressive.
I've been,
I've,
I've stood,
I've stood at one end of a strip club
and had a in Bangkok,
had a tie stripper five dots from the
other side of the room out of her pussy
and pop a balloon that I was holding it
in my head.
Wow.
And she was,
she could find those things with such
aim.
I don't know why I was so stupid because
I could have gotten taken an eye out,
but what kind of speed?
Speed,
speed.
Like uh,
what?
She must have been a good 10 meters,
so maybe 30 feet away from me.
Oh my God.
She's firing him across the room fast
enough to be able to pop a balloon with
accuracy,
with accuracy.
That's insane.
Now how is she doing this?
And she have like her elbows to the back
of her knees and she's got her like her
pussy up in the air.
No,
she was standing up.
I'm trying to picture exactly what
position she was in.
GSG was sort of kneel,
kneeling and standing.
Kneeling.
Oh wait,
no,
sorry.
Not,
not kneeling.
Bent.
Knees bent.
Standing Upright and with the thrust of
the hips for shooting out what?
Bent knees.
Standing up or facing you?
Facing me.
Wow.
That's crazy.
That doesn't even seem like that's like
shooting a gun in the air when you're
pointing at the ground.
It didn't even make any sense.
How did she do that?
She might've had a hands on the ground.
To be honest,
Joe.
I wasn't focused on her fucking
position.
I was focused on whether or not she was
going to take my.
I had my eyes closed most of the time.
Well,
if she had her hands on the ground now
it makes perfect sense.
So she's like a table table sitting
upright.
Yeah.
How's she getting the air to launch that
thing?
That's what's confusing about that.
It was so many things that she was doing
like that.
They have all kinds of tricks.
They will concentrate.
They were pink.
It started out with ping pong balls,
you know,
all the classic things.
Also razorblades.
Oh,
it's not pleasant.
It's an amazing what people will do if
you're confronted with a town filled
with drunk tourists who have already
seen everything.
They've seen more.
Thai kickboxing fights were 16 year old
kid's a fucking Shinde each other in the
head until they go unconscious.
They've seen legalized prostitution
everywhere.
Ladyboys everywhere.
Everything is chaos.
Just fucking scooters with 37 people
piled on him.
And what do they got to do?
Do they have to adapt to its evolution?
It's adapt or die.
You know,
you have to adapt.
You have to figure out how to,
how to,
how to stand out.
Well,
you got to shoot a dart out of your
pussy,
honey.
Just tips his head.
Yeah.
There's,
I mean,
you want,
you want to make the argument that
people are malleable.
That's one of the best arguments.
Like put that.
That's
not to mention like,
I mean I've been to shows there where
they're just like,
I remember the finale to one show where
it was like they were about how many do
you go to Thailand?
Thailand is,
I like to say that Thailand is sort of
our Mexico.
If you're Australian,
it's nearby.
It's cheap.
It's beautiful.
Uh,
they were great beaches.
How far is the flight?
I mean everything's sort of far from for
most Australians because Sydney and
Melbourne are located on the southeast
coast of Australia,
so there's a lot of Australia to fly
over.
Australia is the same size as the
contiguous United States.
So you basically have to do the entire
flight from like the equivalent of Miami
to Seattle before you start entering
Asiana air space.
But from so from Australia,
the country itself,
it would probably only be two or three
hours to Bangkok.
It's only like an hour or two to
Indonesia and Singapore from Sydney.
Then you've got to add on an extra six
hours just to get out of Australian
airspace.
That's amazing that you guys are the
same size.
That Australia's the same size as
America as far as the continental or
close to it.
But there's only 20 million people,
so there's less people than California.
We have half.
We have,
yeah,
mean two thirds of the population of
California in an area the size of the
United States.
If you get rid of Alaska.
So bad ass country.
I fucking love it there.
I was just there.
I know you were.
Yeah,
that whole upset.
I had a great fucking time.
I did stand up there to the Palais
theater.
It's fucking gradable.
I love it up there.
Down there.
Wherever the fuck it is.
Depends on which way you go.
Exactly.
If you go north you can get there.
You'll get there eventually the gloves
round chair spinning.
The fucker doesn't stand still.
But uh,
it's,
I love Australia.
It's an awesome country.
Really is.
It's great.
They're cool as fuck.
Yeah.
Policies are nice.
It's great.
That's the,
that's my number one go to spot.
If the apocalypse happens,
if north the North America falls apart,
Australia is pretty much self
supporting.
It's a democratic really cool.
Nice people.
Yup.
Last spice,
plenty of animals to eat.
Plenty of land to fish.
She,
I mean you've got the whole South
Pacific right there.
Yeah.
You just can't.
You got to watch out for your fucking
killer jellyfish.
Everywhere you turn you have something
that can kill you.
That's true.
They have.
If people don't know you got to look up
this thing called box jelly fish because
they have,
they get a bay filled with box jelly
fish and they'll say don't go in the
water,
the box jelly fish or they're instantly.
How do you say?
Straight off.
Kelly.
Australia off.
Yeah.
And they will kill you instantly.
Like there's just paralyze you.
When you go into anaphylactic shock.
Dead,
you're dead.
I mean some people survive if you get
hit with like one or two tentacles.
But you're fucked man,
for like years.
Yeah.
We'll get in the water.
What the fuck does that mean?
God Damn water.
But in all of the areas of Australia
first start,
they're only there during certain times
of the year.
So you were there in summer and they're
not.
They're not in Sydney or Melbourne,
so didn't have to worry about them.
They're,
they're only in.
Did you must have gone up to the Great
Barrier Reef or something?
No,
no,
no.
I was just talking to people.
I didn't go in the fucking water.
I'm not retarded.
You can go into the water and melons.
They move around the water.
I don't know if you know,
it's just like,
it's all connected.
They could just travel to,
you know,
that's like saying that you're going to
get eaten by a great white shark and
Alaska,
Alaska don't go in the water and Alaska
if it's connected to where the great
white sharks live.
So just never.
Anyway.
Water.
It's the same water.
We're talking about gigantic distances
as far as we know.
As far as we know,
they don't go there,
but they could.
It's like,
no,
they couldn't be too cold for him.
If you knew that the woods,
the woods were filled with werewolves,
but only in a certain time of the year,
would you go during the full moon?
No,
you wouldn't answer for you.
Depends on what is that?
What you're saying is basically like you
shouldn't go hiking in Panama because
there are bears in Canada.
That's exactly what I'm saying.
Yeah,
there you go.
So we've got a,
we've got a,
uh,
Jamie's just bring up the fingers are
brainstorming is a dangerous.
Don't swim in these waters between
October and May.
Severe box jelly sting you.
So what do they emergency treatment?
Oh,
that's one of those.
They have a bucket of vinegar and so it
doesn't,
you're still fucked.
There's a,
um,
there's a species called the era Kanji,
which I can't remember whether it's the
same as the box jellyfish or not.
Someone's going to tweet me now that
I've said that,
and it was a case where these scientists
on the Great Barrier Reef that was
studying the ecology and they're almost
invisible.
Every tiny small little jellyfish with
extremely long tentacles.
And um,
they do the same thing as the box
jellyfish if they're not the same thing
as the box jellyfish.
And they had,
they had a,
uh,
like a cotton bought a bottle of era
Kanji in water and they put it in the
fridge and a dude came in and drank the
water drinking water and died instantly.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
What a label on it.
You already get fucked up fucking skull
and crossbones on that Shit.
Yeah,
there you go.
There's an energy that is,
that little tiny thing will kill you.
Yeah.
What the fuck man went bad and us?
No,
you need to clean your water out of is
filled with the enemy.
Those are murderers.
She gets.
Some government is saying that we're not
going to let any or congee into the
country anymore.
That is insane.
It's insane.
That little tiny thing can kill you.
Yeah.
That is unbelievable.
I made only Americans.
Mike,
a big deal out of how dangerous things
in Australia is.
You fuckers are used to it.
It's like the lady with the ping pong
balls coming out of her pussy.
That's normal in Thailand.
I mean the reality about Australia is
everyone's.
We've,
we've managed to export this.
Steve Irwin,
the crocodile hunter,
vision of Australia as big as if we're
all like a rugged outdoorsman who live
in the,
in the bush,
in the outback.
Duality is almost half the country lives
in to big cities and we were all sitting
around swilling shodan and drinking
lattes,
complaining about property prices and
sitting on yachts and going to the
beach.
A very few Australians live in the
outback.
We're very urbanized country.
We don't.
I mean America is much more,
has much more regional variance in that,
like there's no equivalent of the south
in Australia,
in the Midwest statement.
Melbourne is a.
was incredible as far as like the food.
The food was amazing,
isn't it?
Yeah.
Coffee and the food and the wine.
Oh my God.
Like you.
They know how to live.
Yeah,
we're doing it right yet,
but get killed everywhere,
but that's my point.
Jelly fucking not coming into the hub.
A couple of those brown snakes as well.
They're not coming into into downtown
everywhere.
You can find them.
My friend Adam,
my friend Adam Green tree,
he lives out there and he told he he
works,
uh,
he,
his uh,
business and something involved minds
and uh,
they'll,
they'll be working like digging holes
and um,
you know,
uh,
doing stuff out in the bush,
I guess you guys call it the bush and
they'll just find these brown snakes
which would just fucking kill you.
They bite you and you're dead.
Yeah.
Well,
we'll find them.
Actually people haven't died from a
snake bite or a spider,
but I don't think since all of the
antivenoms were discovered in the early
eighties because every,
every local medical center has the only
antivenoms.
How long does it take for a brown snake?
Achillea Alice.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah,
you've got a little bit of time and most
Australians are trained in knowing how
to basically,
you know,
obviously put a [inaudible] on so that
you can,
maybe you suck out the venom and spit it
out and identify what the snake was.
Well,
I find rattlesnakes on my property out
here all the time.
How long do they take to kill you?
It'll kill you.
It'll take a few hours,
but it'll fuck you up.
I've had my dogs bitten three times.
I've had to have them go and get
antivenom.
And for people if you're broke,
it's fucked because you don't have any
money.
It costs thousands of dollars.
This antivenom stuff and you know,
otherwise you're going to watch your dog
die because they swell up.
Like the only way I found out they got
bit because I knew that they were
barking and barking and barking.
So I went outside and said,
ah fuck,
there's a rattle snake.
And so I killed a rattlesnake and then,
um,
they seem okay,
but then all sudden I see some swelling
on their face.
I'm like,
God it.
And so that I have to take him down
because they'll rattle.
Snake will bite them and then pull away
and still be alive and invite,
bite them again.
And so their,
their face just swole up like cartoon
and just like water balloon.
Now they're finding a day or so.
Yeah.
Good.
It's just expensive.
Um,
I mean if a person gets bitten in
Australia,
obviously they don't have to pay because
we have communism.
That's a good,
that's a good communism,
you know that I get really pissed off
when people talk about healthcare and
healthcare in America and this,
this idea that somehow or another it's
better to not have people covered with
medical insurance and then there's
always been medicaid and there's always
been,
for extreme example,
people have had medical issues that have
put them in severe debt and this
doesn't.
I don't,
I don't think that we shouldn't have
private private care in terms of like
the best doctors and the best surgeons
should be allowed to be compensated for
their excellence.
I mean,
I don't think there's anything wrong
with that,
but the idea that we don't have some
sort of.
I,
we have roads that are taken care of by
our taxes.
Why the fuck do we not have medical
insurance or or medical care?
That's just standard and this is exactly
what we're going to talk about on my
podcast.
Hashtag we the people live which is to,
which we're going to do immediately
after this because I want to talk to you
about Bernie Sanders and I want to talk
to you,
but if you're talking about right now
too,
we can do it,
but we do it later now.
Whatever.
Freaking people out there like what the
fuck I got to download something else,
but it's.
I just think that a country that cares
about its people,
one of the most important things is the
safety and the health of the people.
Like,
okay,
well we shouldn't have.
You shouldn't have to pay for the
police.
You shouldn't have to pay for the army.
It shouldn't be something that comes out
of your check.
Like,
you know,
Oh,
you want to call the police?
Well,
we're going to require a credit card.
No,
no guys breaking into my house.
Well,
uh,
do you have a current credit card?
Like,
no,
no.
We need the cops.
I mean,
I hear people like rush limbaugh saying,
should we buy everyone a car?
Yeah,
he was a fat fuck.
Well I don't listen to him.
Do you remember fucking pill popping
asshole Al Franken was on,
was on lead them and promoting his book
about a rush.
Cold.
Rush limbaugh is a big fat idiot.
Remember he wouldn't be able to write
that book today because he'd be fat
shit.
That's probably true actually.
And let him in.
His first question is uh oh.
That's an interesting title.
How'd you come up with that title at
all?
Goes well for a start.
He's,
he's very,
very fat.
I love Al didn't even lose a lot of
weight though.
When he got on Oxycontin's it's taken
like 99 pills a day.
That fills up a lot of whole,
like,
you know,
you think about how many 99.
Oxycontin.
That's a good handful of mass.
Was He,
is that what he's done?
No,
no,
no.
It's fairly standard for like severe
junkies.
Like it's they just start building up
two and three to 12.
This is why you then you then graduate
to smack and why?
We've got the heroin epidemic that we do
in places like too hard.
You got to shoot it.
Like it's really easy to swallow those
pills.
You can snort it,
you can smoke,
but you're also.
You're getting this inexact amount.
When you just take a pill,
you have one pill,
you throw it down,
your fats do 99.
That's a WHO's taken a lot.
Pull that up Jamie.
Find out exactly how many he was taking.
He was taking so much that and granted
this was told to me by Alex Jones,
so I don't know exactly if I can
authenticate the brasses particular
states like that quote,
but he said that that was why he went
deaf because do you remember rush
limbaugh was going deaf,
but he had like a real medical
explanation for when you overdose on
opiates.
When you take massive amounts of
opiates,
it affects your central nervous system
in such a profound way and it affects
your life,
like your entire physical body in such a
profound way that it's possible.
You could induce hearing loss.
I mean I have sympathy for the guy just
because he's caught up in what is a
problem beyond any individual's sort of
control,
like the,
the,
the problem of over prescription of
opiates in America and like drug
addiction.
Did you see that study,
but it wasn't.
He wasn't overprescribed.
He was actively seeking out these
prescriptions.
He was in Florida,
but it's an.
It's an.
I mean,
it's an addiction.
It is an addiction,
but he was also a massive hypocrite.
That was totally,
totally bad.
People really disagree with almost
everything he says.
I have a grudging admiration for him as
an entertainer and a broadcast because
they think he's so great.
Well,
he speaks very confidently.
he's so good at like saying at getting
you into a position in which his
bullshit sounds reasonable and like
drawing a kind of a line of logical
fallacies in such a way that you end up
thinking,
yeah,
this guy's making a lot of sense.
What's interesting is that he was really
hamstrung and broken down when he called
that a woman,
a slut who was trying to get birth
control,
like she was trying to get a.
She wanted birth control to be covered
by her university.
I'm sure it's some sort of insurance and
you know,
he started calling her a slut and St
Louis terrible things about it,
but I believe she needed birth control
because of another medical ailment.
It wasn't just.
I might be wrong about that,
but it might weigh the weigh what his
argument was and it's a perfect example
of what I'm talking about where he
starts with something simple.
He's like,
what do you call it?
A woman who wants to be paid for sex.
That's a pretty good.
You've got to get rid of the Australian
accent.
I'm not saying I do rush this.
I wouldn't do.
I wouldn't say I wouldn't claim to be
and trough so,
but like he ended up getting two slot
because his logical argument was right.
She wants to be paid for something that
is only needed.
If she wants to have recreational sex.
Well what do you call someone who we
paid to have recreational sex?
A prostitute.
Jamie,
find that out if you get a chance.
But I do believe that she needed it for
another reason.
There's other reasons why women take
birth.
True.
Absolutely.
Like they,
like women with severe acne take birth
control.
Um,
there's a lot of,
there's a lot of other things at birth
control can help,
but either way he's a fat fuck of a
dummy.
He is not that there's anything wrong
with being a fat fuck.
Some of my best friends are fat.
Fuck.
Nothing wrong with being overweight.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Well,
there's something wrong for you.
It's not healthy,
but you know,
you could fix that.
It's hard,
but you could fix that.
Just as easy as it is to get off of
heroin is easy.
It is for rush limbaugh to get off
heroin,
he'd get off sugar and simple fucking
carbs and all that stupid shit that
makes you balloon up like that.
Maybe just walk on a treadmill for 30
minutes.
Tara morning,
Tara hard for people to change their
patterns.
It's hard for people to get excited
about doing something that's difficult
to do.
That's going to be ultimately beneficial
for them because it makes,
it drains your energy in the short term.
You know,
you work out if you're out of shape,
you ever seen an attache person workout?
Yeah.
Fuck man,
horrible.
I've taken people to the gym that don't
work out like come on,
come to the gym with me.
We'll just do a little bit of a workout
and you get them on the elliptical
machine and just go,
we're going to do 20 minutes
and the elliptical machine and you look
over five minutes in there,
ready to fucking die.
I mean there they turned white like
their face turns flush.
It's crazy.
It's weird to watch.
You watch them struggle and then you get
them to the weights and they just,
they can't do anything.
They're so tired.
Did you see the study that came out
recently about the huge increase in the,
in the death,
right?
The fatality rate of white people
between the age of 35 and 50,
I think it was.
No.
So there's a spike which epidemiologists
are saying is as noticeable in the data
as the aids epidemic was in the 19
eighties and there were three causes.
Lattes?
No,
I thought it was going to be diet.
Like when we're talking about this,
I thought it was going to be hard to
say.
So something that's related to diet and
exercise,
it's suicide,
it's booze and its drug overdoses.
Wow.
And this is the only demographic group
in America where the numbers are going
up.
Well I think there are,
there's a lot of people that live a very
unsatisfying life and they got roped
into living this unsatisfying life
because someone told them that they have
to make a living,
that they have to make tough choices and
they have to go do things that they
don't want to do and then,
you know,
find a good job with a fucking plumbing
supply company or some stupid shit they
don't really want to do when they really
want to be a musician or whatever.
And then they just lived,
pressed and there's.
I think that's a giant percentage of
people.
Yeah.
And it's getting worse.
I was talking yesterday on facebook to a
buddy of mine in Australia,
Jacobstein.
Hey Jack.
I'm sure he'll be Liz Taylor.
He's a big fan of yours fucker.
About hell,
but now we just stopped.
Just ripping out fuckers a good thing in
America.
We call each other fuckers all the time.
Yeah.
It's like a blue in Scotland would be
like,
he's a good cop.
He's a good con.
Yeah.
Uh,
but,
uh,
we were talking about how like,
you're not allowed anymore to have any
feelings as a white man that had
anything other than guilt about being a
white man.
Well,
firstly,
acknowledge your privilege.
Privilege,
your white privilege before you even
talk about what white people that's
foreign aren't around.
What about his gender?
People of color.
Okay.
Uh,
I was just listening.
I was just listening to a,
you know,
Sam Harris,
right?
Yeah.
So it was just listening to the latest
episode of his podcast where he's
talking to this Guy Douglas Murray,
who's this English conservative,
and Douglas is saying that,
uh,
that when the,
when the,
when the nuke.
Finally,
when the Jihadi nuke finally goes off,
what we're all going to be talking about
his transgender pronouns.
Right.
It's like that be the discussion about
whether to called them.
He,
she,
they was a at the point when like real
shit's going down.
Like we're so distracted by so many
little semi little cultural pieces of
bullshit at the moment.
We're losing sight of the big picture.
I think it's because it's too easy to
get by these people that are looking.
I think again,
it's.
It's very easy to live today,
much easier than it has been in an
important time and I think also it's
very easy to communicate today much more
easy than it has been at any other point
in time and before.
Before this era,
the era of instant communication,
if you had an idea,
it had to be really good to get it out
there to the masses.
It had to be really good.
It had to go through editors and
publicists that had to go to publishers.
They had to print it.
People had to read it and recommend it.
It had to be verified.
It had to be excellent.
You know,
if you were a hunter,
s Thompson,
like there was a lot of jumps.
You had to go through lots of hoops,
a lot of ladders he had to climb before
you can publish,
you know,
a fear and loathing in Las Vegas today.
Any fucking dipshit can start a hashtag
activist,
you know,
some sort of a.
You could start a tumbler blog or
anything and that it can immediately be
picked up by also by people that also
want to be outraged and they'll go on
this goddamn rampage and it's confusing
as fuck.
It's because it's so easy to get by.
It's we,
we were,
we were like spoiled rich kids in a way.
Spoiled,
spoiled,
rich kids with our ability to
communicate ideas.
I mean,
I think the lowering of the barriers is
a good thing and a bad thing,
right?
I mean the,
the flattening and the fact that I don't
have to go and talk to a network
executive or radio station owner about
doing my podcast.
I can just do the show that I want to do
and put it out there is great,
but you're right that like we've become
the Douglas Murray.
There's this British conservative
columnist was saying he thinks that the
problem is that there's a lack of.
There's a,
there's a supply and demand problem
between social justice warriors and like
racists because there aren't enough
racist anymore.
Right?
So like the left used to be agitated by
fighting all of these big good noble
fights,
but the like the fascists and the rice,
it's an older people who they wanted to
bring down have basically been
vanquished.
So now they're not totally,
but now they have to talk.
Now I have to accuse people like me of
being racist.
I was accused of being racist the other
day because I used the phrase to call a
spade a spade.
Whoa.
And in the 1920 you got called a racist
for that yet in Harlem,
in the 19 twenties a spade was a bad
word for black people,
not just the 19 twenties.
So that's like pretty recently.
Was it because not in,
not in Australian language.
So even in like the seventies and the
eighties,
people would use it a disparaging the
spades.
Okay.
So I'd never heard it,
but apparently on racist now.
So because there aren't enough actual
racists to keep shouting it,
so they have to stop shouting it.
But it's a spade a spade is a card term.
Yeah,
that's right.
It's a term about playing cards to call
a spade a spade.
It's like a club or a spade or a heart
like that is so fucking stupid.
I see.
And also I posted something on facebook
about did you see the Brouhaha about
Meryl Streep's tee shirt,
you know,
so she's just finished shooting a movie
in London called suffragette way in
which she plays Emily Pankhurst,
who was one of the great women's rights,
uh,
you know,
campaigners back in the late 18
hundreds,
early 19 hundreds.
It's about the birth of the feminism
movement.
And in 1913 pancoast gave this speech,
his famous speech for,
for women's rights in which he said that
the women's rights movement will survive
so long as there is a woman alive to
hold up the flag of rebellion.
I would rather be a rebel and a slave.
So they do this promotional thing in
which his meryl streep a wearing a tee
shirt.
I'd rather be a rebel in a slave,
meaning I'd rather fight for my rights
then be downtrodden as a woman in the
early part of the 20th century.
Well,
the Internet blew up with how racist
Merrill is because she's not
understanding the context of that.
I mean there.
Uh,
and then so I put a suit or like,
here are some of the tweets.
I can't believe this is real.
This is real.
Someone said with a link to it that the
word rebel is juxtaposed with slave in
that quote,
just,
I can't fathom this.
Someone else says then someone else
tries to school.
I'm says,
the quote is from Emily Pankhurst who
said it in 1913,
Rally for women's rights to which the
social justice warriors respond and I'm
letting you know that it doesn't matter
who said it,
the quote is trash and another person,
white women have said a lot of terrible
things over the course of history.
It doesn't mean you wear it on a shirt
and it just goes on and on.
And I put it on facebook and just said,
I'm glad that we're focusing on what's
really important.
And like a black friend of mine said,
you know,
just started attacking me for being an
apologist for racism.
Black friend of yours,
who would black friend is this.
Well,
I'm going to name him.
We don't have to name them,
but fuck him.
He knows you're not racist.
That's stupid.
This is damn it.
The problem is there's not enough
problems.
That's kind of what I made about supply
and demand thing,
right.
There's not enough actual problems for
them to focus on.
So like,
so no.
I think what I said,
what I wrote on facebook was political
correctness is exhausting and he wrote
being black as exhausting.
Okay.
And I.
Yeah.
And I wrote,
right?
Fortunately that tee shirt has nothing
to do with being black.
And then he went off onto this thing
about how like everything,
you know,
people that you have to understand how
other people are gonna perceive things
and you will have to be cognizant of
always using the right words and it just
ends up spiraling down into this
situation where all of a sudden I have
to be censoring every single word that I
say in case some idiot misinterprets it
and doesn't understand the historical
context that we're talking about.
The women's movement in like early 20th
century Britain and not the fight
against slavery in America,
like buy it,
don't buy it.
I don't think people really offended by
it.
I think it's a green light issue.
I think it's agreed.
They look at Meryl Streep and that t
shirt and if they understand the context
of what she's trying to say,
like if you.
If you quote the original piece that it
was taken from [inaudible],
they still have a problem with that
they're doing is just finding a
greenlight green light.
Like that's.
I can go hit the gas.
Yeah,
that's what it is.
Yeah.
That's all it is.
It doesn't make any sense.
When she's.
She's posting something or she has a a t
shirt on rather that's taken from a
historical quote.
It's really simple.
If you have an issue with those words
because those words can be used in other
forms.
Well that's your issue.
It's your turn to make a big deal of it
and that you have to be more aware and
you have to be because being black is
exhausting or being Chinese.
We built the railroads for you to ride
that railroad and not acknowledged the
fact that Chinese people died during the
making of that real fucking Christ
enough that what we need is wolves.
We need wolves at the gates.
What we need is a fucking winter.
We need winter's coming.
We need to fucking black,
but we've,
we've just had Paris,
the Paris attacks.
Let's focus or in Paris.
I bet it's like that,
you know,
nine slash 11 and after September 11th
in New York,
New York was fucking amazing and I hate
to say this and it turns like this is
not minimizing the victims or the
families of the victims and horrible
tragedy without a doubt.
No one,
no one's denying that,
but what I'm saying is we were in New
York City,
me and some friends when we were filming
fear factor and it was about 10 months
or 11 months after nine slash 11.
My memory might be bad,
but the point being people were
noticeably more friendly,
noticeably more,
more like they were engaging.
They would say hi to each other.
The firemen came.
I had a friend who blacked out because I
gave her some California weed.
We were,
uh,
were hanging out in front of this bar.
It was all these people that work for
fear factor and uh,
you know,
and uh,
I busted out Joanna go,
you guys want to get down or why?
What do you want to do?
Come on pussies and these,
all these producers,
they're like,
okay,
we'll try.
We'll try some.
This is fucking space.
We'd just the deepest,
blackest whole space we'd,
right.
She takes a deep pit and you see her
eyes start to flutter and roll behind
her head.
And Luckily I was in a position to catch
her and I moved in and we grabbed her as
she was like,
she was literally just blacking out on
the concrete.
That's some serious shit,
serious weed.
But it's apparently it can happen to
certain people if you don't smoke a lot
of weed.
And she just decided,
fuck it,
let's give it a shot.
Just took a big hit and you see her eyes
fluttering and she just gave.
So we called the fireman.
The fireman came and it was like,
like a nobleman on a knight on a horse
had arrived.
Everybody was so happy to see the
firemen.
First responders got so much love.
It was amazing.
It wasn't hundreds of colleagues had
just died.
It was also the fact that people
recognize the importance of having first
responders having farm and having
policemen and that they really felt it
like in a deep real way.
Like,
thank you.
Thank you for what you do.
If it wasn't for what you,
you do,
we will be so much more danger.
You're like,
it's having a very real memory of them
stepping in and risking their lives and
helping people and seeing them covered
with dust as they carried people out of
the buildings.
And we,
we,
it was like,
it was solidified and people's memories.
And then over the past decade or so you
go back and it's back to being New York
again.
People don't look at each other.
Fuck you.
Like there was,
there was a feeling of vulnerability
that existed because we had recognized a
real problem and we had gone through a
real uh,
but they had gone through a real moment
of intense adversity.
Did you do,
did you see in the wake of Paris,
one of the things that I found
interesting was this conversation around
tragedy,
hipster,
trap,
tragedy,
hipsters.
Did you hear about the hipster tragedy?
Hipster is someone who the moment
something like the Paris attacks
happens,
a start shitting on people who are
pouring out sympathy online or changing
their face,
their facebook profile pictures to the
French flag or something by saying,
well,
where will you,
why weren't you out route outrage when
there was a roof like,
this is like this.
I've got an article here in the
stranger,
which is the Seattle blog,
entitled why putting the French flag on
the space needle is racist?
What by Charles Modality?
It's November 16.
Why didn't anybody acknowledged the
attacks in Lebanon?
Why didn't anybody acknowledge the
attacks in Nigeria?
That was the point is,
well,
there's a real racist aspect to that and
I think there's a real argument for.
So I figured,
I think we have to be allowed to allow
people to express sympathy.
Yes.
Uh,
I also find it a bit fatuous when
everyone starts pouring out,
you know,
all of it.
There were certain fashionable things to
care about,
you know,
it's a bit like the Kony 2012 phenomenon
or something where all of a sudden
everyone just jumps on some social
media,
Social Justice Bandwagon.
But I feel like Paris is a bit
different.
Yes.
People should pay attention to Beirut.
People should pay attention to Nigeria
and Boca.
Harambe,
yes.
People should be more aware of what's
going on.
But as a Bama said in the wake of the
Paris attacks,
it is understandable for people to have
a more instinctive,
sympathetic reaction to a city that they
know the city that they've been to a
city populated by people like them who
are doing things just like them going to
see a soccer game sitting in a
restaurant.
Um,
then they offer parts of the world where
they think that violence is more
commonplace.
Like Nigeria,
I don't think you can be belittling
people for genuine expressions of
sympathy.
I certainly don't think that you should
be accusing them of being racist.
I agree with you wholeheartedly.
I don't think you should accuse people
of anything negative for expressing
sympathy,
but I think that culturally when you
look at the news and when you look at
CNN and the people that are supposed to
be responsible for letting us know
what's happening in the world,
that's where the issue lies.
Like why are they concentrating solely
on Paris?
Why doesn't CNN have all this coverage
of Lebanon in Nigeria that,
that mirrors it.
So you get this broad perspective of the
actual world itself and say,
look,
this,
this isis issue is not just an issue
that happened to Europeans.
This is an issue that's been happening
all over the world for awhile now.
Absolutely.
And CNN is fucking awful.
I'm definitely not going to defense,
can it?
I mean,
CNN is the worst example I think,
of just following the most predictable
line on everything.
They try not to alienate anyone by being
too left or too right and as a
consequence they just a mush of
ignorance and like parochialism
do you do?
If you are Jeff Zucker,
if you're the guy who runs cnn,
what the fuck do you do?
But you put Anthony Bourdain show on.
That's a good move.
Well,
what else do you do?
I mean how the fuck do you.
Do you cover the news and like a broad
way and also make it a profitable
entertainment enterprise,
which is what
I would like to think that there's a
market for smart conversations about
things,
which is what I try to do at huffpost
live and we don't get small numbers.
I mean things oftentimes I'm surprised
when I have a smart conversation about
the relationship between Islamism to
Islam and the plight of poor Muslims in
the suburbs of European capitals where
unemployment is 35 percent and the
demographics of the types of people in
Iraq who are joining isis who were 14
years old during the US invasion and
have just endured all of the rest of
their lives basically being full of
civil war and people being beheaded and
strung up in the streets and who hated
Saddam,
but hate America and hate the West now
for everything that they've been
through.
Like when we talk about a lot sort of
stuff,
some people are actually,
you know,
significant numbers of people were
actually interested in hearing about it
instead of meanwhile on CNN should the
mayor of this city and in the midwest
that has a majority Muslim population be
afraid,
how can we can do that?
So good,
but you can't do a rush.
That was a total American accent.
No,
you're right.
I can.
You know,
it's.
People are problematic and it's very
difficult for people to separate their
motives from,
from the reality of the situation that
they're reporting on to.
Also,
you're dealing with commercial
interests.
You know,
you have advertisers,
you have all these different things that
have a say or at least an influence on
what gets said.
Whereas you don't have that.
There's also the difference between
broadcast and selective media.
Your,
your.
You have a selective media outlet which
means someone finds out about Josh Zaps
from one of your many wonderful
appearances all throughout the world and
huff post live and all these different
things.
They get to know you.
I like this guy's perspective.
He's very intelligent.
He's very articulate and then they seek
you out and they find your thing to
subscribe to it and then they go to it
because they becoming a josh eps fan.
Whereas CNN is at the fucking airport,
you know,
I'm waiting for my flight the other day
and they have CNN and they're.
They're showing these people doing these
things and it's just.
It's on.
There's a difference between something
that's broadcast and something that you
select and I think when someone gets
excited about something like what you do
is someone who has chosen to go seek out
your perspective and your point of view
or it's very difficult to do that on a
show like CNN or a network like CNN.
We have to be able to do better than we
are.
It like 60 minutes for all of its faults
occasionally hits the nail on the head
and does a good job and certainly used
to and people watch it and watched it.
Still cronkite used to direct John that
there are good.
PBS does a does a great job.
Broadly.
I think NBC news does a great job just
as a CCO as a whole collection.
So Williams with the exception of Brian
Williams.
Although I mean like,
who gives a fuck?
Yeah,
exactly.
I never be a robot.
A robot.
That's right.
Who gives a shit what he's to do his
job.
That's what they should do exist.
You just have a fucking laptop there,
but he is on your.
On your point about what people are
gonna Watch and seek out,
there's a good piece in vox by Max
Fisher after the all the criticism of
like why didn't,
why didn't the media cover the Beirut
bombings?
Because like one of the most popular,
one of the most retweeted tweets the day
after the Paris attacks was a tweet
about why is the media covering this so
much when they didn't cover Beirut?
And uh,
so Max Fisher says we did and nobody
clicks on it.
We do.
And nobody ever clicks on it,
clicks at it or no one clicks on it.
Then they just let it go and they just,
at some point you have to at some point,
if you're interested in having a
thriving media business,
you have to give people what they
actually want,
which is judged by what they click on.
So,
so they put Beirut at the very top of
the page and then you know,
what you get doesn't even register as a
blip on the number of clicks.
So then they downgrade it and then it
ends up falling back onto the world
section of the site.
But I think you just nailed it because
it's a business and that's where it
becomes a problem and that becomes a
problem is that it's an entertainment
business.
Like CNN is an entertainment network.
Yeah.
But they,
they,
they entertain you by showing you the
real reality TV,
which is the news,
but much like reality tv,
you know,
if you live in a house with a bunch of
people and they,
they filmed six hours a day and then
they water it down to 44 minutes on
television or 22 minutes on television.
When they do that,
then they're gonna.
They're gonna do it the way they want to
show it.
They're going to chop out a bunch of
other shit that you're not really
interested in.
And they're gonna paint a picture and
they can edit it and paint that picture
and a variety of different ways.
But they're going to do it in a way that
they think is going to be the most
salacious.
It's gonna be the most compelling for
you to tune in so they can sell you a
Toyota truck so they can,
you know,
advertise tide laundry detergent.
You know,
that's really what it's all about.
Exactly.
And I think that's,
that's a real problem when you combine
commerce with the dissemination of
information.
Oh,
he was,
he is the tweet.
By the way,
Jack Jones TV,
uh,
has a picture of an explosion in Beirut.
No media has covered this,
but rip to older people that lost their
lives in Lebanon yesterday from Isis
attacks.
Let's see how many retweets.
So it's got that,
that's been reached.
Twenty,
57,750
times and like 43,000.
One hundred and two times.
The picture is not from the bay route
attacks.
It's from 2006 during the Israeli war
against Hezbollah.
And it's absolutely not true that no
media has covered this.
The New York Times covered at the
Washington Post,
the Ip,
a hue and Ella was sent to cover the
blasts.
The economist had a piece on it,
CNN even seeing ended it,
the daily mail.
So that's a fake picture that's
interested in.
That's right.
That's from nine years ago.
Long picture the picture that Angelina
Jolie
tweeted too.
She tweeted it.
Yeah.
She tweeted it about the Lebanon attacks
as well,
so get on the fucking ball.
Angelina,
stop adopting kids.
Those.
Those are the tragedy,
hipsters and investigated the veracity
of the photographs.
You post young lady,
how dare she hashtag outraged.
I'm Hashtag [inaudible].
Hashtag racist.
How about that?
And now I don't know what to talk about.
About,
about,
about Islam as well.
Like the difficulty is what are you.
I'm afraid of all of the,
all of the right wing is taking.
My greatest fear about terrorism is that
we end up living in like a quasi fascist
state because we overreact so much that
every,
like I got a little nephew who's two
years old when he's 18 and he's
traveling around the world like I did.
Is he going to be able to sit outside in
a cafe and,
and relax or is he gonna have to walk
through a metal detector every bloody
place.
He goes like,
it's a good question.
And is he gonna?
Is He gonna have any privacy or is the
NSA going to spy on everything that he
does?
And uh,
we're gonna let it because we're so
afraid of having a text like this.
And is he going to live in a pluralistic
society or are we going to be so cowed
either one way or the other way?
Either we,
we take out trump ID and oppress
Muslims,
which only exacerbates the problem.
Or on the other hand,
we become social justice,
justice warriors who were like,
this has nothing to do with Islam.
Islam is a religion of peace.
There's nothing to see here.
You don't have to worry about the
Islamists,
which means that we end up with mini
theocracies in our own cities where you
basically have a liberal communities
that don't respect women's rights and
don't respect gay rights,
you know,
don't respect but actively suppress.
Yeah.
I mean isis is throwing gay people
bathrooms.
Yep.
Yeah.
And I don't know how we talk about this
is the problem way.
And I by make,
by way I mean people like me who are
broadly sympathetic to minority rights
and who abroadly pro civil rights and
want everybody to be able to live life
however they want to.
And I'm pro high levels of immigration,
uh,
and I'm not intolerant,
I'm not as in a phobic,
I'm certainly not racist or
Islamophobic,
but how do we talk honestly about the
fact that at the fringes of Islam there
is a big fucking problem and not yield
that territory to the right wing because
you've got this,
the rise of these right wing.
Can you imagine if there was an election
this election,
there is an election in Paris,
in France next week.
And how many more Paris is Paris attacks
would you have to have before the
National Front,
the anti-immigrant racist party,
one pallet in Sweden.
Now the third largest party is a party
that wants to close the borders
completely.
Well,
I mean,
you practically already got that on the
gop side here.
Well,
no,
not even.
Not even remotely.
Actually.
I take that back because they want to,
they want to close the illegal border,
but they still believe in having a
moderate levels of.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's don't believe in having people like
me coming in.
Yes.
Yeah.
So how do people that speak well with a
cool accent?
Yeah.
You educated.
Sure.
Come on over,
probably more educated than we are.
Yeah.
I think what we have here is a human
beings classically react to tragedies
and massive events.
Uh,
we have problems and then we have
solutions and there's the solution is
being debated and there's the extreme
right wing answer to the solution to
these problems which is close up.
The borders are more military,
more guns attack Isis.
Let's go to war.
Let's do this.
Let's do that.
I think we're also dealing with people
like trump that are gigantic egos that
have these platforms where they want to
step up and they want to gather all this
attention to themselves and point to
themselves as the solution to this issue
with their hotline stances.
And I think what's going to happen is
technology as it becomes more and more
pervasive and invasive,
and as we become more and more
symbiotically connected to the ability
to express ourselves through phones and
through the Internet,
I think the next level of this is
ultimately going to be some level that
allows people to communicate in a way
that it's not just typing things down
and it's not just watching a video
online.
I think we're going to be able to
communicate with each other in some sort
of a neural transmitting manner.
There's going to be some next step level
of technology with it,
whether it's a decade from now or two
decades from now.
There's gonna be it's gonna seem
pointless to have phones.
It's going to seem point.
The idea of having a physical thing when
you have to go to in order to access
information is going to seem absolutely
ridiculous.
And once that happens,
we're going to see what we see right now
in the world where I think w,
I think it's regardless of how crazy the
world is,
I think at least in America right now,
this is absolutely the safest time ever.
So when all this social justice warrior
shit they were saying and all this
craziness about outrage and Hashtag
racism and Hashtag this and that,
it's bad,
but it's good.
It's good because it's all about
sensitivity.
inclusion.
It's good because it's all about
eliminating anything that's disparaging
or racist or anything where you are
marginalizing groups based on something
that they can't control like what they
look like or their sexual preference.
And I think as we get deeper and deeper
to this interconnectivity that we're
experiencing right now,
we're going to absolve a lot of our
differences in grievances through our
ability to communicate with each other
and connect with each other.
And I think we're experiencing like this
adolescent sort of angst before we get
out of the fucking house and go out onto
the our own.
I mean,
we're,
we're becoming adults as a civilization
and along the way we're experiencing the
fucking teenage hormonal rage that you
know,
a 14 year old has when they're still
trapped in their parents house with the
freedom that human beings are going to
have in the future to communicate and
express themselves is going to negate a
lot of this Hashtag college racism or
Hashtag college activism.
I think what that's coming from is this,
this feeling that a lot of people have
that their,
their,
their ideas and their opinions aren't
taken into consideration.
That they're not taken seriously and
that that's why they're overreacting and
freaking out and walking through the
fucking,
the hallways and Dartmouth and the
library.
Black lives matter,
black lives matter.
Like what?
What are they doing?
What do you have a greater ability to
nail joe to communicate with each other
than we ever have already.
So recent.
It's so recent.
I mean,
I take your point with certainly in the
adolescents of our,
of our species and,
but I do suspect that you're looking at
this through the prism of a mind that
spends a lot of time thinking about
things and a lot of time having
experiences that,
uh,
that are uplifting and transcendence
stay through.
I'm trying to,
trying to find a way of saying drugs,
just drugs,
but not just drugs,
a float,
tanks,
meditation,
whatever else it is that you've,
that you do in order to gain a
perspective on things that is beyond
your own little tribe.
My concern is whether or not there is a
direct correlation between upgrading
our,
uh,
the means of communication with you.
That obviously the way that we currently
communicate is going to seem completely
antiquated in decades to come.
But what we've seen happen when,
like when the Internet began,
you sound to me a little bit like people
who I would listen to in the 19 nineties
who would say when once everyone is on
the line,
there's going to be no need for
difference anymore because everyone's
going to be able to communicate
everything.
And everyone's going to be able to be
exposed to so many different ideas that
you're not going to be able to be nclr
anymore.
You're not going to be able to be
parochial anymore,
trapped in your own little circle of
beliefs.
Because with the Internet,
everything's going to be available at
everyone's fingertips.
So some people,
yeah,
there a futurist who was saying that of
course what's happened is we've had the
opposite effect that that the,
the availability of communication has on
a widespread scale has actually enabled
people to silo themselves into little
self thinking like communities of
Sameness so that we're actually more
divided than we've ever been because you
can seek out only the information that
comports with the way that you see the
world.
So I don't think that a technology is
necessarily going to drive an awakening.
I think the awakening comes from drugs
and spiritual epiphany's and then the
communication can be a tool to enact
that,
but I can just as easily see some
communication revolution being
manipulated by jihadis,
the way that they currently use the
internet and twitter to coordinate
terrorist attacks.
I don't think it's an either or.
I didn't.
I,
I definitely think that there are groups
of insulated people that searched for
confirmation bias and they,
they stay within their tribe,
but I think one of the reasons why
they're so active now and there's more
of them is because they're recognizing
the inevitable future and that you
really,
you're not going to be able to insulate
yourself in the past like you better get
it in now while you can better stockpile
that fucking food because the famine's
coming.
I think what you're going to experience
in the future is going to be more and
more deterioration of these insulated
little tribes and I think that that's
where we're.
When people have to apologize for
things,
they would never have to apologize
before people like w what we were
talking about,
like the Al Franken saying,
rush limbaugh is a big fat idiot.
That was just a few years ago that he
wrote that book.
Maybe a decade ago.
You,
you can't write that book today.
You couldn't put that book on the
shelves.
You wouldn't,
wouldn't be supported.
It wouldn't be supported by Barnes and
noble,
like you calling something a big fat
idiot is fat shaming now and I think
that this,
this increased outrage is also increased
sensitivity.
It's also increased understanding and
once the dust settles in the argument,
then people have to like do you have to
take into consideration the validity of
other people's opinions?
Whether or not you agree with them or
not,
you have to understand that it's just a
matter of this,
this broad range of people expressing
themselves will slowly.
It'll slowly come down to an
understandable vibration.
I hope so.
So let's just unpack two things that
we're talking about.
Someone not conflating two things,
right?
One is the social justice warrior debate
here in the United States and the other
is Islamism,
and we're sort of kind of having two
parallel conversations about that.
At the same time in terms of social
social justice warriors in the United
States,
I think I hope that you're right,
that what they think that they're doing
is being an extension of the great
traditions of civil rights in America.
In other words,
that they being motivated by a sense of
understanding.
I just found a passion and an outrage
against what they perceive as being
outrageous injustice.
My concern is that what they're also
doing is buying into a long tradition of
intolerance and a lack of respect for
pluralism and for other people's ideas
about things for other people's right to
express ideas that they regard as being
incorrect.
There's A.
I mentioned earlier this study that I
thought you liked that I bought.
Let me just find it because it's good.
It's so.
There's this,
uh,
there's this professor called April
Kelly and she's a professor of political
science at Elizabeth town college and
she's got a chapter in this new paper
called the end of the experiment,
the rise of cultural elites and the
decline of American civic culture.
And it's,
it's this study which is called the
General Social Survey,
which looks at how tolerant or
intolerant particular demographics of
Americans are.
Right.
So they stopped by on.
I'll get tangled up in my microphone
here.
I was getting too relaxed listening to
you talk.
I was like kicking back.
I was like,
getting out the popcorn,
listened to Joe.
Uh,
so in the general social survey,
they,
uh,
they propose a bunch of different groups
and they asked people how much they
would like or dislike that group of
people,
right?
Just to establish who we really,
really don't like.
The least liked group included in the
survey was Muslim clergymen who preach
hatred against the United States.
Right?
That's understandable.
And the second least liked group among
Americans,
people who believed that blacks are
genetically inferior,
so racist.
So then they ask people how tolerant
they would be to,
towards those,
a person from that class of people
giving speech,
a public speech in their community and
people in their forties,
a more tolerant than people in their
thirties and people in their thirties
and more tolerant than people in their
twenties when people in their forties,
the proportion who say that a member
that a Muslim clergymen who preaches
hatred against the United States should
not be allowed to give a public speech
is 43 percent people in their thirties.
Fifty two percent people in their
twenties,
60 percent.
So if tolerance means not like,
oh,
I support black rights,
or I support gay rights,
I support Trans Rights,
but if it means respecting the right of
someone who you really disagree with,
to express that opinion,
then young people are actually more
intolerant now than older people.
They're more tolerant towards
homosexuals and atheists,
but that's because they like homosexuals
and atheists more than older people do.
Right?
That's not tolerance.
Tolerance is,
is not a measure of liking someone,
but a willingness to extend political
freedoms to people who you disliked when
young people are less,
less willing to do that.
Well,
I think what you're saying though is
they're less willing to accept hate
speech,
which they think are dangerous or
dangerous conversations.
They think that someone who is a Muslim
clergymen,
who wants to express the hate of
America,
it's dangerous because he could promote
terrorist attacks.
Someone who thinks that black people are
genetically inferior to white people is
dangerous because they could promote
racism or they could promote someone
confirming their racist beliefs and then
instead of becoming educated,
are becoming enlightened.
They go with the initial racist
instincts and they go,
I was right.
You know the white man is superior,
you know,
and they're,
they're,
they're worried about hate,
right?
We're just talking
both.
Both those things are about hate.
This is Meryl Streep's Teesha at saying
better,
a rebel in a slave about,
hey,
because it is to,
is to a lot of people in their 20
people.
How many people?
Well enough people that she has to put
out a press release about it.
I think like,
I don't think there's anything.
I think we are better off living in a
society where bad ideas are exposed to
conversation.
I mean,
you know,
sunlight is the best disinfectant.
You want bad ideas out there.
You want a big roiling conversation
where people who are stupid or
ridiculous ideas about the genetic
inferiority of,
of,
of black people are able to be exposed,
be argued with,
be contented because racists aren't just
going to go away.
If you bend them talking,
they're going to go onto ground.
They're going to find out the
communities they gonna they gonna
increasingly self segregate into their
own little communities online.
You want,
I think you want free speech to be a big
roiling debate.
You don't want to be censorious and
judgmental and intolerant towards people
whose eyes you just you whose ideas you
disagree with.
You want to take them on and expose why
those ideas are wrong,
and hopefully through that,
through that wrestling match,
that intellectual wrestling match,
you will end up progressing forward your
progress forward by simply banning ideas
that you think are are objectionable.
That's agreed.
You know that's a very important point.
I think
what they're worried about though is
these people going to schools and
indoctrinating very gullible or very
impressionable young people and that's
a.
that's a legit thing because they
didn't.
That reinforces the Gullibility,
right?
Because you don't get it,
you haven't been exposed to any other
right,
is that they themselves have been
indoctrinated into the idea of
liberalism and liberal thinking by a
charismatic people with interesting
ideas that they believe in
wholeheartedly and they're very
confident in what they're saying,
that they speak very well.
Those ideas become infectious and
sometimes those.
I've expressed this before on the
podcast that I listened to these Islamic
clergyman speak,
and although I have zero desire to
become a Muslim,
there's something intoxicating about
people that extremely confident about
their ideology and that's dangerous for
people.
It's dangerous.
You have a person like me who's done a
lot of fucking drugs,
who does a lot of meditation,
is involved in martial arts.
I'm a free thinker.
I'm a non theistic sort of a thinker,
but I watch these people have these
conversations with these massive crowds
and they're saying all these crazy
things about Islam being the truth and I
feel I have a fee.
I feel an understanding why people would
be drawn to that.
I'm not saying that I'm drawn to it
myself,
but I understand it like I feel that
the.
The compelling idea behind someone
joining a group like that.
I think that's right.
I think it's because certainty is
intoxicating.
Yes.
Like if you're.
If you're discombobulated,
if the world is complicated,
if you'd done what to make of Shit,
especially if you're in a situation
where you feel like you've been on for a
lot of time,
which is what a lot of these followers
of these extremists do feel like a.
Then it's nice to just have clarity
that's just have someone who knows what
the truth is and who knows what the
right path is.
A perfect example that is country music.
I guarantee you
if you'd asked to list five things that
you are going to end that sentence with,
it wouldn't have country music would not
have been top,
top 50.
I know a lot of people that I love
dearly that liked country music and they
lead.
They read the least out of all the
people that I know.
All the people that I know that are like
really into like really dumb country
music.
These motherfuckers on aware of shit
that's going on in the world.
I have good friends that I love,
but you know,
I have to talk to them.
Especially for like from the hunting
world,
like the hunting world has goddamn
hilarious because I've somehow or
another become a part of this world
because I've expressed this idea that I
think is very important that we should
be aware of where our food comes from
and then uh,
and I've become someone who gathers
their food from a hunting way,
but then you connect yourself with these
people that are also in this,
which became very religious.
There's a lot of really,
but,
but it's weird kind of religion.
It's,
it's,
it's almost like a hashtag activist sort
of religious idea where they don't
understand the texts they don't like.
They'll have religious tattoos.
Like,
Hey fucker,
you got to read the whole book.
Like the book says,
don't Tattoo yourself just like it says,
don't blow guys.
Like you can't be.
Like,
I've had arguments with people but
pretty much more explicit about the
don't get a tattoo then don't blow a guy
blow a guy.
Beat is always nebulous about like lying
with another male Wilson
the no tattoo on his knees and sucks my
desk.
There's no lying.
The the tattoo thing is very clear,
but when I got into it with these people
was when that woman from Kentucky
wouldn't marry gay people and I wrote
this piece on instagram and facebook and
it got millions of likes and all these
people traded it back and forth and I
got all this blow back from the hunting
community because all these people that
are really into God or really into
religion and then you know,
they're,
they're also recognizing them.
So like they were getting pressured by
friends who are in the hunting
community.
We're getting pressure to talk to me
about my stance on God.
Like,
this is hilarious.
well,
how much do you guys actually know about
the scripts?
How much have you guys read?
What?
How much do you know about the origins
of the scripts?
And it turns out very little.
Most of them,
very little,
but there's this need to simplify things
that appear to be very complex.
And the way to simplify things is put it
all in God's hands.
It's all about Jesus.
You know Jesus.
Hell,
I'll tell you why I'm going to vote for
him because he's on Jesus.
This comes back to the problem of
tribalism that we were alluding to
earlier in the show,
right?
That there is no greater way of
encouraging people to be tribalistic
than religion or political affiliation.
Loosely,
loosely understood.
Right?
So there's a,
you know,
Dan Collins History podcast.
Man.
I love the best.
Just incredible.
Have you had him on the show?
Oh yeah.
A bunch of stuff.
Fantastic.
I have,
I missed those episodes.
I've just,
I've just been listening.
I've almost finished getting through his
world war one thing,
which is like five episodes of three and
a half hours.
Eat Right.
This is like Rogan esque duration
podcast,
but way more,
way more like produced way more.
I mean it's brilliant.
It's like there audio books.
Yes.
I mean it's like a 20 hour explanation
of the first world war.
It's so good.
And so one of the things that he's
talking about is when he's talking about
the Bulcans,
he's saying like when the bulcans
imploded in the 19 nineties and we had
the collapse of Yugoslavia and united
Bosnia and Serbia and all that,
he's like,
you go there even to this day and you
talk to a Bosnian Muslim,
will you talk to a Serb or you talk to a
cro at about the problems that they've
endured.
And every single one of them will point
a finger at the other groups and say
they've been doing this to us for so
long and that back in this day.
And they did that and then they did
that.
And then they did that.
It's like the Israelis and the
Palestinians or something.
Because like,
oh well,
you know,
10,000
fucking years ago,
my ancestors got massive,
goodbye blahdy Blah.
And it's so easy to think of ourselves
in terms of aggrieved groups,
whether or not.
And my problem with religion is,
and my problem with this is this is sort
of a weird parallel that I'm drawing
just as I'm sort of thinking this up
right now.
But there is a parallel between jihadis
and social justice warriors in the sense
that they ate.
You're able to take an off the shelf
prepackaged kind of identity instead of
beliefs about things and gain certainty
from it and be part of a tribe and be
part of a community and be fighting the
good fight against people who disagree
with them.
They'll hold beliefs that they believe
are objectionable.
Whether that belief is that the west is
at war with Islam,
which is what your do you think that we
want,
or whether the belief is that,
uh,
that racist racism is okay,
which is what social justice warriors
think that all white people think right?
There are these easy off the shelf
categories.
So think independently.
People
thinking independently is a good idea.
Um,
I don't know if I'm with you on that one
though.
Just the stories of the Jihad.
I see where you go in with it.
I think
world,
their worldviews that are self
reinforcing and their cliques that are
soft supporting.
Right?
So you don't have to ask a lot of
difficult questions.
Right.
I totally understand what you're saying
in that sense.
I think extreme liberalism is a a sense
may like extreme conservatism is a
religion in a sense.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I think so.
It's an ideology.
Ideologies are very dangerous ideologies
where you have locked into a
predetermined pattern of thinking that
you just have to conform to,
I think becomes very problematic for
people because the world is fluid.
It's.
There's a lot going on,
lot of weirdness to it,
and I think that there's also an issue
in communication through language and
communication through words and the
ability to express yourself through
words.
It's sometimes difficult because you're
trying to do,
as you're trying to express intent,
you're trying to get someone to
understand how you think and view things
and you're trying to say,
well,
why don't you express and view yourself
like I do,
or why don't you see things?
How I do,
and maybe you're talking to someone who
has a completely different idea of what
those words mean and completely
different idea of the context of this
particular scenario that you're
discussing.
It's hard.
It's,
it's clumsy.
Isn't that very difficult
because you've got this kind of platonic
ideal in your head of what you want to
communicate and then you have to just
rummage around in the scrabble bucket
for for the closest approximation to
what it is
you're trying to impart.
That's why podcasts are so unique in a
way because you know one of the
beautiful things about it is that you do
sort of search for the correct way to.
I mean you hear us do this sometimes,
but this is like this is what we're
doing is we're just trying to figure out
what's the best way for me to express
this idea that I've got bouncing around
in my head where I'm trying to
understand how,
how this thing sort of lays out to
everybody else.
Like how do I,
how do I,
how do I broadcast it?
How do I get it out there in a way
where,
you know what I'm actually saying what
I'm actually thinking instead of getting
outraged,
it's something that's not what I meant.
Like this meryl streep thing.
Yes.
It's not what she meant.
She obviously didn't mean I don't want
to be a slave,
I want to be a black person in the 1800
clay and there are certain triggers that
are really hard for people to get beyond
in communication,
but we have to find a way to get beyond
like the,
I think the most pressing form of
communication that we have to grapple
with now is how do we speak to the
Muslim community and to one another
about the Muslim community and about
jihadism without either being bigoted
towards Muslims or pretending that there
isn't a problem of Islam,
Islam that has some relationship to the
Muslim community and that has some
relationship to the text of Islam.
Right?
Because the moment I say anything
remotely suggesting like the day after
the Charlie Hebdo attacks in Paris,
how uh,
Dayne went on morning joe on Msnbc and
said,
these guys are about as Muslim as I am.
Well,
that's bullshit,
right?
I mean that's obviously not true.
Are more Muslim there arguably a lot
more Muslim than most Muslims.
I mean they are very phonetically
Muslim.
At least they think they are.
Right?
So we can't keep litigating whether or
not they're theologically correct or
whatever,
like there is obviously a cancer at the
extremist fringe of Islam that has to be
dealt with and has to be talked about.
And the more we just talk about it,
the more the left talks about it in
terms of well it's just a problem of
extremism in all faiths.
It's got nothing to do with the faith,
the less able we are to actually have a
conversation about what needs to be done
and how to win over moderate Muslims and
how not to alienate them.
Because if we,
if tolerant people can't talk about it,
then the only people talking about the
problem a right wing xenophobes or
fascists.
Right.
And so what we have to do is find a way
when we talk about like those off the
shelf ideologies,
whether it's jihadism or Social Justice
Warrior Ism,
we have to find a way to win over
moderate Muslims and make them not feel
like they're being alienated and judged.
We have to not be,
you know,
sending southwest flights back to the
gate as it were the other day.
Because two people were speaking Arabic
and watching a video about what's going
on in like the wake of the Paris attacks
or something and people freaked out
because they don't know who I think will
Arab is a terrorist or something.
You have to make sure that doesn't
happen,
but we can't have that not happen as
long as everyone is pretending that
there's not a problem with Islam,
right at the edge of Islam and I don't
know how to have that conversation
without sounding like I'm intolerant.
Keep
talking.
Everybody's gotTa.
Keep talking.
The arguments against it come up.
You talk about the arguments against it
and it just just takes time.
I really do believe that.
I believe it just takes a lot of
discourse,
takes a lot of communication and the
clumsy type of communication that you
get through language through,
through talking.
I think the more this happens,
the more this gets discussed,
the more people gained an understanding
and again,
like we were looking at people aging or
like trees growing.
It is a slow process that in the middle
of it,
it doesn't seem like any progress is
happening at all.
But ultimately,
if you look at the world today versus
the world of 10 years ago,
you see a big difference between what Al
Franken was able to publish with that
book and what you're able to get away
with today.
And I think that sort of in a weird way,
for lack of a better analogy,
it highlights the growth that's going
on.
It highlights this very strange era that
we're currently experiencing.
And with that,
let's end this and do your podcast so
that we'll,
we'll get to.
We're going to keep talking folks,
but we have to end this because I got to
pick up my kid and a little bit,
but we're going to do an episode of we
the people live Hashtag we,
the people lashed out with people like
Josh Safran's podcast and it is
available on itunes.
It's available cloud.
Or you can just follow us on twitter at
WTP underscore alive underscores what
these fucking under WTP love to know
what it is.
Why couldn't you just get weed?
The people the whole thing or is that
too many letters?
I think it was too many lists.
Okay.
All right.
We're going to do that and then we'll be
back.
But Johnny Depp's on twitter follow him.
He's fantastic and we're going to do his
podcast and uh,
that's it.
You Have Fox and we'll be back tomorrow
with bill burke hollow.