Okay.
What?
Huh?
Cool.
[inaudible]
ladies and gentlemen, brothers
and sisters. Lovers and children.
Dana d mom does in the house.
Give it up for Dana.
Dana and I are e pals.
We tweet each other back and forth,
but this is our first time actually
meeting each other in real life. Cool.
You're very funny.
You say some funny shit on Twitter and
you said you had a really fun thing where
you broke down this Jennifer
Anniston. Uh, again. Uh,
what's his name? Adam Sandler
movie. It was really funny.
Yeah. If you haven't seen it, you can
get it done. It's on youtube. On your,
what does it, does it say just don't go
with it. Just don't go with it. Yeah,
I'm really funny and really
like you, you, you know,
you broke it down like comic would
break it down like how ridiculous it is.
First of all,
I thought it was hilarious that you
said that Jennifer Aniston was the human
equivalent to okay.
Meal meal
like perfect.
That is absolutely perfect.
Nutritious. I would've said
grilled cheese sandwich thing.
I would have called her a grilled grilled
cheese, grilled cheese sandwich truck.
You don't see an oatmeal track anywhere?
No lines.
I would give her more credit with meals.
What I'm saying,
I think you being a little unfair.
I will.
I'll give her a little more than oatmeal,
but I know what you're saying. You know,
I'm wondering,
I got this no love for Jennifer Aniston.
She's just a chick trying to get
some money doing her acting things,
viral smartwater video and she's trying
to like be with all the youtubers and
like make a viral video
to go smart water thing.
She ain't hurting anybody. Yeah. Yeah.
It's easy to get caught up in hating
someone for no reason. And she's,
she's not somebody.
Well why her Jennifer Kell go after
Kadafi Kadafi is going to leave her dash,
go off the car, gas, you know, NASA. Do
you feel about that? But then you know,
I mean it's also, you know, if you live
in a glass house, don't throw rocks,
like live your own fucking life. Who
gives a shit? But you're right. Her stuff,
what she's doing, it's all like, God
damn bitch, don't you have enough money?
They want to do some
interesting now everything you
fucking do is like the same.
Goddamn Laurie.
You know those romance and did the
worst date movies ever. Because if you,
you're going on this date,
if you're a guy you're already giving in
to the fact that you're doing whatever
you can to fuck you're,
you're gonna,
you're gonna pretend to be someone
you're not. You're going to like,
I would never ask a check to go see some
crazy fucking stupid werewolf movie if
they weren't into it. You know
what I mean? I would've never,
but women can ask a guy to go see
some wonky ass date night bullshit.
Jennifer Aniston. God Forbid Sandra
Bullock movies. Those motherfuckers, Huh?
Sandy [inaudible] Mars.
Every little sandy you love.
Say that because of what happened to her.
Yeah. I was just gonna say exactly why.
Right. I was going to bitch about no
strings attached to cause Natalie Portman.
You have an Oscar, but still making
bullshit like no strings attached.
Poor me.
I'm the most attractive person ever.
Me and Ashton Kutcher were going to
have no strings attached sex. Boom.
They can fuck anybody anywhere,
any day of the week.
A new person every single day, and they're
going to make a fucking hat. Yes. Oh,
we're just going to be friends and
have sex and it won't get complicated.
I wonder what's going to happen?
Well, do they fall in love?
You're the girl. You have to understand
what happens. She, she's sitting around,
her agent calls them, this is what we
have for you. It's a big movie. It's blah,
blah, blah. Everyone's all hyped
on it and next thing you know,
like I've read for shit that I really,
I'm happy I never gone.
He could just get talked into going in
on these things. The next thing you know,
you're in an office. Next thing
you know you're signing the papers.
Next thing you know a movie set and
you're doing this fucking terrible movie.
You know boo hoo cry for you. No big
deal. But I'm just saying they're just,
they're just out there doing their shit.
She looks fantastic
pregnant. They should do that
movie though, where it's like,
it's sold like that where you know
exactly what's going to happen.
They're going to fall in love and cheap,
but then it's actually
like he murders her.
Larry's his body, like an
alien. He only wants her eggs.
That would be a good idea for
a movie trailer. I saw, um, uh,
what was it called? Um, bureau. What
the fuck's it called? Adjustment Bureau.
I am so behind in movies right now.
I don't even know what this is.
God Damn decent. It's a based
on a Phillip K. Dot. Dick novel.
So it was really weird. It was really
trippy. I like really surprising.
Like I thought it was just going to be
a s uh, a typical dumb movie and it was,
there had a lot,
there's a lot of dumb elements,
but you kind of have to have some
dumb shit and a lot of movies.
Just to wrap up a complicated premise
inside of two hours right now you've got
to have some one guy that's
that thing. It's also like,
what is his motivation
when he's ridiculously in
love with her and you know,
barely, you know, well why is
this going on? Really? Wow.
I mean C'mon really,
I mean your dwell on this shift three
years later because it's meant to be and
it's all written down somewhere. It
was fascinating. We went about it
wrack my brain over back to the future
and that's like from 1985 and I'm like
still things bother me about it so
much like the time or almost nothing.
The rape part like so we've
been back to the future. Yeah.
Beth tries to rape
Lorraine and that's right.
And the alternate future that really
don't have them like wash his car,
the stuff like, you know, it's weird in
that time you tried to wake me up. Great.
I like, I like it bothers me some really.
I never even thought about that. But yes,
that again I do take a lot of medicine,
kind of hone in on that kind of stuff.
What about the rapes?
I don't remember anything about
that movie. I, you know, I'm,
I'm finding as I get older,
like I've definitely used up hard drive
space and deleted a lot of files because
I would watch movies now and it's
like I never watched it before.
I watched a simple mind
the other day, the, the uh,
the Russell Crowe movie about that
genius mathematician, Beautiful Mind,
simple mind,
beautiful minds and it was fucking great.
I had no idea what was going to happen.
I literally didn't remember the movie,
but I know I've seen it. I'm
just, I've known amount of
space. I got no space, man.
That's what,
like that's social network.
That's what's going to happen with
that movie to me and like 10 years,
like it was a great movie, but that's
not a movie you'll remember at all
are so many movies, man. If you
really stop, you know, it's like,
and I was going to ask you
this because you, you do porn.
Like why the fuck are they
still making porn movies?
There's just no way you
could've seen them. All right?
There's no way you need a new one
if you're really just beating off.
There's no way, unless you're
fixating on very specific actresses,
which a lot of guys do,
but if you're not,
if you're just beating off Jesus Christ,
that's when I seen them all.
That's one thing I've noticed though.
It is the characters. It is you've, you,
you like a certain actress and
you start wanting to see it.
Like before horn was always
to me porn was jacking off,
but then I never really
got into characters since
like Twitter where now I'm
following people on Twitter
and stuff that now I'm starting
to get them though I wouldn't see
a movie with that person. And Yeah,
so I see that now that Twitter is helping
it at a little bit. Yeah, that's, that's,
that's definitely what's become a mean.
It's become that with comics as well,
you know,
it's like people reaching out and you,
you develop like your fan base and then
you all communicate with each other.
And then I guess when some dudes walking
off too, it's like much more personal,
you know, are more fun. Kind of
feel like they own you a little bit,
a little bit disconcerting. Did people
get douchey with you because of that?
Like I'm a fan.
Like I demand this
even like today coming here,
um, people are like, uh,
it's Joe Rogan going to fuck you.
And I'm like, I'm a person. Like,
you know like you have your thing.
Isn't that when you're done that in the,
you know,
it's just like this isn't a movie.
This is real life and you have your
real life and outside of comedy and your
podcast and MMA stuff and TV and movies.
You have your own personal life.
Right?
Me Outside of my Twitter feed,
my bath aid,
but my bathtub thing
like what's your mouth?
I just spend like five
hours a day in the bathtub.
You just sit around the taking not get
clean enough or are you one of those?
Oh all I've done so much porn constantly.
Just never ever cleaned.
Do it on like a Webcam or
something? No, I just like, no,
I'm looking bad to be in the tub.
You should do it on web cause there is
there a psychological thing there or are
you just like to do it?
Yeah, just comfortable. Just
feels good to be on the top.
Yeah. I'm not wearing clothes
and gives me from eating,
taking food in the Bathtub is growth.
He's get an isolation tank that's part
of the cat man. That'd be awesome.
When the cat in the hat comes back.
That's where he starts trouble
each cake in a, in a tub.
See that's where it's all done properly.
That mother Fucker,
those little kids in trouble almost and
then he pulls it out with magic at the
very end.
So yeah,
most people don't eat in the bathtub
while you're up to date with your cat in
the hat. Shit son. I have
a two and a half year old.
I know she loves the cat in
the hat and I love reading it.
Like I get all enthusiastic about it.
It's fucking great writing.
That's a cat in the hat.
Especially the cat in the hat comes back.
That one is the shit medicine Shel
Silverstein yet. No Man. What?
Just like walk in and get that. You
will fucking love it. It'll be great.
You will read that shit as a kid.
The chat and the hat seems awful.
Psychedelic magic kind of has
got a crazy hat and magic.
Fuck Michel Silverstein.
I'm not about,
I'm not interested in man.
You're talking nonsense.
I'm telling you about something awesome
and you're telling me about something
else that I have no idea what it is.
Very similar.
Let's talk about what's awesome.
I don't want to hear about the chivalry.
Chad the how does the shit son,
he's a cat with a magic fucking hat.
He pulls his cat off and there's little
cat, a little cat a pulls his hat off,
there's little cat B look at,
see and it gets all the way down.
A little cat Z and little cat Z has volume
and you don't know what the fuck loom
is,
but boom fixes everything.
And when it gets down to the little cat
z with the fucking shit hits the fan.
When the cat fucks everything up,
he gets to the tub dirty.
He gets pink shit out in the snow and
on the $10 shoes and on mom's dress and
everything is a fucking disaster.
And he keeps pulling out little hats so
other cats can help them and they just
fuck shit up. Worse and worse until
it gets a little cat Z and little cat.
He's got the reset, reset switch.
He pulls out, boom and boom,
just bang. No matter what and
you look at Czi is so small,
you can't even fucking see him. He's
not visible to the naked eye. Okay,
so they're going macrocosm
on your ass band. They're
going quantum physics, right?
That's how bad ass cat in the
head is so fucked. Your stupid.
What was her name again?
This is shell silver's.
Shel Silverstein construct the cat
in the hat's car. How about that?
That's what I got to say. I need to,
I need this. The cat naps is a shit.
I need to have some kids because I
haven't read this shit in a while.
You know when you don't have kids.
The idea of reading kids cat and that
story sounds like fucking painful
punishment. People. I've, when I've been
in the position where I didn't have kids,
where I looked at people at kids like, oh,
you trapped fucked. Like, oh my God. Oh,
you're doomed. You're stuck to that trip
forever. There's no way not to. We not to.
It's normal if you don't have kids.
That's how it's supposed to be set
up until you have them. Of Your own,
you're supposed to like to, to complete
your mission in life. Like your,
your motivation and your goals are
to be as uninstalled as possible.
So when you see entanglements
and other people's lives,
you recognize them as disgusting things
you never want to see in yourself.
That's why like you see,
like if someone's acting like an asshole
or someone's acting selfish or jealous,
those feelings that you get from seeing,
they'll be like, oh, it's so gross.
That's a message to you that's
you're supposed to learn from this.
And you're supposed to never
ever be what that person is.
I guess they're there for you.
And when you see people with kids,
if they're not yours,
you get to this a screwy message.
You get this message of all,
look at this poor fuck.
And you think about all the worst aspects
of all your relationships and how you
know you could possibly be entangled.
Some other person.
And then there's a fucking kid wants
stop crying at all you're doing.
But when you have them, all
of a sudden it's like, Whoa,
there's this little human and they're
your little friends. And it's you like,
it's not really another person.
It's a part of you that's
become its own individual.
You love it literally more than you love
yourself and then reading to them and
playing with them. It's fun. It's fuck.
It's like you've got this little pal,
like she makes me laugh all the time.
She shows me her dumps.
She takes these giant shits.
They're fucking huge.
They come out of this little tiny body.
Can't believe how big are shits are.
You should start twittering.
It's her twin. No Way.
It would be jerking off to my baby shit.
If they fixed that, they
fixed my cock. Oh, of course.
There would be at least like five guys.
If you showed how big your baby shit was,
what else could I fit in that ass?
They were thinking about stuff in their
kid's poop today, Joe. Exactly. There's
at least one guy who's going to say that,
but she thinks it's hilarious.
She goes,
I just made a poop log and poop is what
she knows is funny because it's funny
coming out of a two year old,
so that's like the Goto word.
Yeah, no. Whenever you know.
What does it smell like? Poop.
Everything smells like poop.
Like she'll say everything smells
like poop and laugh. That's awesome.
You gotta get, you gotta get her in on
it. There's a show called a venture time.
I highly recommend it. It's like a,
it's like a trippy show for kids,
but if you're an adult you will fucking
want to get high and watch it. Amazing.
Yeah. Really? Yeah,
it's the next Maria Bamford on it.
Steve Agee said that
he did something on it,
like a bunch of really talented people.
It's really cool to flapjack a flapjack
got canceled, so now he's on it too.
Fucking awesome. Would you ever
do a cartoon voice? I think,
I think that would be one of your ideal
things. I think I have, but we did it.
You did a family guy or American dad
or something like that, you remember?
Well, I did it. Yeah. I did a cartoon
voice on family guy and I did um,
fuck what else I had done
with the little kid. Shit.
I feel like I've done something before.
I've read some books or read some books
that we became like books on CD long
time ago with Mario Lopez. Oh no
way. Yeah. It was kind of fun man.
Cause you're reading a Kid's story and re
yeah,
it's hot as fuck. Um, and I
always remember like, you know,
like how much I was a little kid to like
listen to like a sat of someone tell a
story. Right. It was like fucking cool.
It'd be tucked in bed and you hear
some really exciting story, you know,
so it was fun.
It was fun doing,
speaking of Lopez,
you remember when we had Alison on she,
she was a extra behind Mario Lopez and
she was just staring at him like she was
like the terminator with this really evil,
well she's done it again,
but this time she did it even better.
Like at the beginning they like high five
when they come back from a commercial
Mario Lopez and her,
and then she immediately goes right
back into the character and she's just
staring at him down and looking,
but she overdid it. This, she might,
she's overdoing it this time.
Just acting. Be Crazy on TV,
so it's middle of what is going
on with that chick. Exactly.
Exactly.
The first time I met her
and she was a Brian, she's
very nice, very nice person.
First Time I met her I'm like, dude, is
that girl angry like what's going on man?
I feel like, did I upset her? Then
I say something rude and I'm like,
I don't even remember. I remember
interacting. She's got this mean face,
but then she's super
yes, because the person that every, she
just gets lost in overthought I think.
You know, like she's constantly, you
know, just thinking about things and then
she looks angry. It's called
winning, winning, winning,
winning. It was Charlie Sheen. Meme
was hit a, it's turned a corner.
Turned a corner. I watched the podcast
and also this is not fun anymore.
There was, there's two, there's three
now, but there's two different versions.
There's one where he actually
tries to do like a talk show.
It's very strange and it's very cocaine
because everyone in the room is like all
happy and laughing at nonsense and there's
this one guy who won't stop playing
fart sounds. It's like, you know,
he probably listen to the Howard stern
show up twice and you know and said,
oh well this is probably all it tastes
fucking fart board and this guy's blown
off farts in the for no reason
whatsoever.
And Charlie's like reading off Cue cards,
just trying to have those synapses
fire in some sort of a reasonable and
understandable sequence cause it
just cocaine madness in that brain.
His brain is ravaged,
dude,
he's got blow out holes in
walls and water's leaking out.
No one knows what the fuck happens.
Your brain,
when you blow seven fucking gram rocks,
you're,
you're snorting them and smoking
them for years and years. He's fried.
He's barely trying to keep it together.
What if this is all a set up for a movie?
It would be a million fucking this
movie. Yeah. I mean maybe not. Maybe not.
Maybe the best way. Never ever be on
Charlie Sheen Bandwagon. Fuck him.
Why? Why is he there? I Dunno. That's
the best way to get people mad.
I think it's just to be like I'm
not into what you're into. Fuck.
You actually have not been watching
or following any of it. I feel like I,
there's no reward in that for me. But
there was a real board and following it,
there's a reward and studying it.
Like he's some fucking Lewis and
Clark of cocaine and whores, you know,
he's like out there in the woods and you
know and shit in the [inaudible] been
around for very,
very long time,
but no one's been able to rock it like
2.2 mil Olia about two mil a week is how
you discover something new.
He's got radical amounts of
money, syndication money.
And when you have that kind of money,
that's how there's dudes show up with
briefcases and shit and you know,
and there's 50 girls in the
room. He's, he's doing it,
he's doing other level shit cause you're
not supposed to get that rich and still
have this crazy appetite
for cocaine and horse. You,
you're not supposed to
be that open about it.
You know it's supposed to be that
public about it, but that's what,
that's what's crazy is that,
that's exactly where TV's going.
This whole shit is supposedly supposedly
this is the realist you can get for
reality shows.
Now it's having a use stream channel and
seeing somebody's about to die except
maybe you know.
Oh yeah.
The whole thing is fucking fake something
and directed by Shel Silverstein and
this is going to like the next biggest
movie ever. Dude. It's fucking,
it's so scary when you look at his
body and its face like the latest ones,
the latest two. It looks like he
hasn't eaten or slept in days.
Like his skin is loose on his face.
He looks like an old man. Yeah, I'm,
it's because he's lost all this
weight. How old? Look at them.
It looks like older than
me and I don't know.
I know I don't look like
I did when I was young.
I look at myself when I was young
and I'm like, wow, how weird is that?
Like that's me. I'm decaying,
you know? I'm like, my body
is morphing and changing,
but I look better than that dude.
Yeah.
That looks like Hugh Hefner to Hugh Hefner
right there. Yeah. That's an old man.
There's like a 60 year old man,
by the way.
We're looking on Ustream that he has his
whole, all his videos and channels. Uh,
his name is w y t r on Ustream.
And uh,
this is Wy TV, Bro. TV,
you know, here's the,
I think that's just one of them that's
on, I mean I think you can, you can watch
the actual Charlie Sheen went
on Charlie Sheen's channel.
This is the guy who was a re re
competent. Oh. It looks like,
but this one almost has a million
views, so yeah, this might be it. Okay.
Maybe it is it, but, well, here's
what disturbs me. Look at it.
The pointiness of the shoulder. Look at
the bones. Yeah. That's weird. He's dying.
He's dying. Yeah, that's, that's real.
You know, he's dying and he's winning.
Yeah. He looks like he looks like
Steve Jobs right there. Yeah.
Oh, livers. Friends playing.
Yeah. Maybe that's what it is.
Maybe that's why is all this horror.
Isn't his house there?
He's like Madison or Oregon.
I'm on Zubich Charlie.
I used to say that about Dick Cheney.
Dick Cheney probably has like seven secret
service agents but only six are real
circuit service agents.
One guy was just some dude who's
got his blood type waiting,
harvesting Dick Cheney to die so they're
going to cut this dude open like a fish
harvesters.
One guy behind them with a truck with
ice in it and it's ready to throw the
heart in there while it's still beating.
What blood type are all those whores?
Do you guys know what you are?
Okay.
I don't even know what blood type I
think I have like a cat blood type or
something. Okay. Oh positive. Positive.
[inaudible] is the only one here
that's not high. She was scared.
She didn't want to go deep.
We'll nervous.
I am a little nervous.
It's very hard to be.
Same Room with people who are
professionally funny because not funny.
I could just fucking open my
ass and like accepted huge cop,
you know and then everything will be okay.
Things will pan out for me.
Everybody would like you.
Yeah.
Hello. Say Well I'll wait to go. Yeah.
Cause I can fall back on just, you know,
being pretty enough. You don't have to
worry about anything. Just be yourself.
You don't have to be funny.
You don't have to be just right back to
you because I like to be in. You are,
but you know what,
no more than you have to be like the,
the beautiful thing about this podcast
for real is that it's like a conversation.
You know,
it's like when people get a chance to
see is it's like you get an in on, uh,
an interesting conversation, you
know? And so just for yourself,
so you're all good. That's enough to just
be funny. But you are, you are funny.
And if you haven't seen that clip,
it's very funny.
Have you ever thought about doing comedy?
Um,
I don't know cause it's kind of hard
because I'm like already socially,
uh, social and marginalized
by being a sex worker.
And then people kind of
expect you to be like sexy.
And then I already had this conversation
with Brian about female comics and how
it's like,
that's already,
you're kind of a run down on the
ladder because you, you know,
my boyfriend, my period, my
cats, you know, kind of stuff.
And it's really hard to get out of
that. It's uh, that is a business.
It's very hard for women and
somebody like me coming in,
uh, like being pretty and
being a porn star and you know,
being like having a
dirty mouth or whatever,
I feel like I'd be kind of painted into
a certain corner of being expected.
How can you be painted more
than you are ready? I know.
That's why I'm so as a porn, how could
do and be in a female comic, which is,
I mean arguably the general consensus,
it would be a notch many notches
above on the social ladder.
Like how would it possibly fuck you up
by being funny as well as doing what you
already do. Maybe I'm just afraid
of failing to be that right.
I mean it's, it's very
intimidating. Like, I,
I do like your comedy bits for videos
and stuff like that and people can have
always call me cause they need like a,
a pretty girl or a naked girl or someone
will do a full frontal and whatever and
I could explore and I get jokes
and stuff like that. But um,
you know,
I don't know if I can just be like,
here are my series of jokes and then
try to like change it from, you know,
I feel like it would have to fall back
on being a porn star for the basis of my
comedy,
which is something that is kind of
counter productive to what I do as a porn
star because I sort of market myself as
a girl next door and a normal person,
you know?
So it'd be like folded in on it.
No.
Would,
I really don't think it would because
you would just be yourself on stage.
I need that.
That's fine. Maybe we're
not the same light, I think.
I think what you said or you
know, saying, I don't know,
I was going to help you
just reading your tweets.
I think you're fucking hilarious.
And even if you just took,
what I do is I usually think of a tweet
that I really like and then I've tried
to write a little story around that tweak.
Is that pretty much is
the meat of the goal
are, or though, I'm sorry, what was that?
Opened that up so we can see what we're
seeing. We're, we're doing just in case.
Yeah,
but that's like the meat of a joke,
you know, like a tweet it tweet.
It pretty much is the best part
of a joke usually, you know?
So I think you'd be really good at
it. Just based on your, on your,
what a tweet is, is just
140 characters. Just writing
material, you know? It's just,
it's, it's just, and, and not, and not,
that's the beautiful thing about it.
Sometimes it's just whatever the fuck
you think about anything. You know,
like I was talking about like I,
I made a tweet last night that I was
watching this Charlie sheen thing and then
he sounds like hunter s Thompson
[inaudible] boys, you know,
he's got this crazy nutty Gonzo thing
going on. I'm like, wow, this is weird.
Like now I'm stuck.
Is that like a drug thing?
It's not like you just go too far
over the edge and you just, you know,
everything's firing all fucking goofy.
Is that what it is?
Well Charlie Sheen has been famous pretty
much all his life and he was like born
into a famous family too.
So I mean that kind of sets you back a
little bit to begin with because you're
already scrutinized and being watched
pretty closely and you're in a bubble
because you're rich or poor from the
moment you're born basically. Yeah.
What standup comedy makes
you do is be real as fuck.
You can't fake it. You can't pretend
something's going on. It's not going on.
And what's happening is happening.
And when you're talking about something,
you better be actually thinking about
something or those little animals out
there are going to smell it.
But I know and it's not going to work
like me. Fucking happy heckler. I'm no
worse. Yeah, you heckled Mike Young.
I know it so funny though.
It was entertaining to like the 11
people that were there. Well listen,
Mike Young needs it. He needs it just
as long as you don't do that to anybody.
Good. And don't do it. Just calming.
Sometimes we bomb when we're
trying to work something out.
Like when you are working things out,
I'm sure you can. I'm sure you, you,
you just felt insulted by
what Mike Young was selling.
I know that feeling
miserable. You can, you can, you
know, guys can go down a bad road.
It's loud.
You can come do a Joe show tomorrow
if you want to do a five minute set of
reading your Twitter. Where do a
show tomorrow. Yeah. Um, before I,
even this weekend is comedy
and Magic Club. Um, so, uh,
this a Friday and Saturday where the
comedy Magic Club in her most of the beach
and uh, tickets or there's, there's
still some left but not much.
And then next week,
Friday night we're going to a,
Gotham is beating me and the wild Jew
and a at Gotham at a nice feeling,
a flashlight, the alien.
And that's next, uh,
next Friday night and then Wednesday
tomorrow sounds, sounds comedy hall.
And how like Tom Segura,
Christina and a lot of people
licensed Lessinger either to,
a lot of people are going,
it's going to be really fun and
that's a great place to fuck around.
I came up with two new jokes last time
I was there really just on stage. Yeah.
That's awesome.
Because it's such a little intimate
environment and everyone knows that.
It's like you're there for that,
you know,
it's like everyone
knows that you're there.
I do my material but I'm really there
to do my, I want to entertain you,
but I also want to like go down crazy
roads to see what happens completely free
ball.
And you can't do that in a big crowd.
You need to do that in like an 80
seat or in 90 seater, then you just,
you really know what's
funny and what's not.
You can't get off any tricks
and an intimate environment
are really small room.
You can't get off any tricks.
It's like it's either funny or it's
not and it's very truthful, you know?
And you could do that. I'm telling
you, you can do it. So when you're,
when you're talking about not
wanting all these other things,
like not wanting to be,
to me,
you've already managed to avoid that
in the most demeaning job possible.
Yeah, seriously. I don't feel
like it's that demeaning.
I think that there could be
forced fuck anyone. Yeah.
Judges, judges, anybody,
the son hurting anybody.
If anybody just not hurting anybody,
whatever you're doing. Wow. How weird.
It may be.
What makes you happy?
I'm brainwashed or maybe I need
to be rescued or maybe I just,
I was raised in properly or you know,
or I'm still going to be heat then
or something that I'm just, you know,
I need the right person to slap some
sense into me because big damage
for most people, that's the case
for most people in your business,
that's the case.
I mean,
it's not an irrational reason for them
to think that it doesn't account for all
variability. There's a, there's a
lot more variables, variabilities,
there's a lot more variables.
It doesn't count for all of them.
And there's people can be,
you know,
into all kinds of things
for no fucking reason.
And to say that it's all from
abuser. Yes. So you were happy,
you were happy growing up,
happy for her.
Yeah, very. You know,
mom, dad, brother, cats,
everybody
just really open about sex in your
house. Like how did you become? So,
uh, I don't know. I was like,
I'm weird and I've always been weird.
Like I asked my mom what would I like
when I was a kid and she was like pretty
much exactly the same way as you are
now just shorter. And I was like okay.
Then like it was kind of neurotic,
silly person for a very long time and
I never had like any sex talks with my
parents.
I think at a certain point they were like,
it's really normal to experiment with
sex and drugs but you probably shouldn't
drink. And I was like, well
I'm going to go get drunk.
Cause if my parents think
that drugs and sex are cool,
they must suck or be nerdy or whatever.
Like I they,
I kind of went Alex p Keaton on them.
Right.
Little little flip man.
That's something you got to really
be aware of when you're raising kids.
You can't just tell them
what you want them to do,
right?
No you don't.
Yeah. You gotta kind of figure
out a way to trick them,
trick the little monsters
and yeah, that's right. Yeah.
So you just gravitated towards
the alcohol to be a rebel.
Yeah.
I was like,
have like a really bad drinker when I
was younger and I went through phases
where I would not drink at all,
but then like pick right up and like
be a drunk person until I was like 23.
Wow. Yeah. I was just like,
ah, I didn't and like sex. Oh,
I mean I wasn't like
super interested in it.
Like I had boyfriends and stuff and like
my parents never tried to make me feel
bad about sex, but the men that
I was with always dead like
that made you feel bad about it.
About like having how many people I've
had sex with or like what I'm into or
whatever. And I would just like, I
always found it to be pretty strange.
So I guess like my parents
raised me to have good, um,
ideas about sexuality but really like
wasn't really pant like laid out for me in
any way
for men.
You know,
you want to know how many partners
because then the likelihood of her leaving
you becomes assessed.
Like how long are you sure.
That is such a sensitive thing to say,
which I think is really interesting
because I think that a lot of people would
say, you know, you know,
and to see if she like a whore or slutty
or if she was like disease or whatever.
Okay.
She's gonna get me herpes. There's that
too. There's that. She's not special.
That's pretty, yeah. Pretty interesting.
Yeah. Well what the fuck is
your, your uh, a comp. You're,
you're an accumulation
of all your experiences,
sexual or wherever the fuck you
want it. I mean, maybe you may miss,
the only problem is it becomes like you
find out about like trains that were run
on her and like how many times damn
bitch. Like how many gang bangs? Three.
Fuck, you know, and
then you start thinking,
how can I ever think that that's what
sex is special between us? You know,
how could I ever think that,
uh, that this is, uh, this is
real worthy of my love. Real Shit. Yeah.
It's not what I seen in the movies.
You know, it's not what I see
in Sandra Bullock's movies.
Sandra Bullock never
gets a train run on her.
She doesn't go to work and get fucked.
Me asked me to come home and want to
cuddle with you so she could fucking do
whatever now.
No.
Yeah. Not for a woman. She
can go full on vanish. She's,
she's one of the verge of vanishing
already. She's 40 years old,
43 years old or something like that.
She is very cute,
but you're not going to want to see her.
And she's 60 in a romantic comedy about
alone trying to find her way and she
coached a bunch of black guys that are
playing football and she learns. Yeah,
like in the blind side movie,
she was a little bit of a like a mom,
not like a girlfriend or sex a boss.
It's so funny how we identify with someone
who's going through some crazy stripe
on television. Crazy crap. She didn't
deserve that. She seems nice enough.
Yeah. But I do wonder why she was married
to that Jesse James and that seems
completely tattooed all over the planet.
What is that about?
I never really understood that.
Is that like a,
they both enjoy cocaine or
something or he's a charmer
charmer. There's some guys that
are charmers and I think, uh,
he was very obsessed with being famous.
Listen to me, I'm like, Okay Nancy Grace,
what do we have here is a charmer.
He is a bullshit artist and he's
getting this girl to believe him.
Now we have a dead baby in Florida,
which talks about this a dead baby in
Florida. Nancy grace is on that shit.
You'll look for this story on
cnn.com you will find nothing. Whoo.
Here we have the mother come home from
war boss cigarettes with the baby in the
car now. I love it. She
hates the Anthony so much.
Casey Anthony killed her daughter. Kaylee.
And why was she seems cool, but no,
but like the thing is she's not like
ever trying to present herself as like an
impartial news part.
Like and Casey Anthony,
they will figure out the truth about
you cause you murder your baby. Well,
he's like I said,
that's totally bias.
Well, she's not alive. She's not
supposed to be a news person.
She's like a discussion person.
No, but she's a former prosecutor.
I guess the interesting part of her case,
she's got to figure it out.
That's a crazy thing is like when she's,
when she's talking about tiger woods,
like, whoa, Whoa, Whoa,
settle the fuck down. Hooker.
I thought you were all about
dead babies in Florida.
What are you doing about black athletes
that like the fuck like really?
You're gonna,
you're gonna spend three weeks working
on black athletes that want to fuck.
Like really? That's all.
Who are these girls?
Where do they come from?
How did they get his phone number?
Well, Nancy grace. Grace
with love. So black cock.
If anybody could use some black caucus,
Nancy grace, I could see her enjoying it.
[inaudible] I paid for that.
I could see her enjoying it.
I can see her getting stuffed.
Somebody who just finally fucking treating
her like she's really sexual and hot
for the like the first time at
2030 years. Oh, she'd get into it.
Big Man.
Dango Ebony sward
that's the word. Yes and no sound.
Annunciated the w s ward. Oh,
here's a dead man.
[inaudible]. See that's fun
colony right there. That's timing. You
could totally be standup comedian there.
You're good.
You could totally do it.
I'm telling you the same real comics
and comics and porn stars are very,
very similar.
We all come from some fucking weird our
ways where we didn't get what we were
supposed to get where a young and there's
a hole and you know you fill that hole
up however you want with jokes.
It's the same thing. There's
room for both. My whole, yeah,
I'm telling you could do it.
You could fit hands in there and shit.
People didn't clap. You got five
minutes tomorrow at Sal's comedy hosts.
Oh my God.
You don't have to do it. No
pressure. You don't want to fuck.
Look what happened with her with drinking.
Do that dude.
You can't push her in a direction.
She's going to push back.
We're going to take your bullshit.
So he says, yeah man, he's just
fucking trying to trick you.
I saw the funniest photo of
you. She has, by the way,
she has a accessing with trainees
like she like is addicted to trainees.
I sold one of his big black tie,
seven to like seven to seven,
four or something.
He was giant.
I look at you say she was
that kind of huge girl.
She said funny. How was it? She
was that even a turn on that?
I just thought that she was
like really owning her shit.
She just like work in the room like it
must be fucking like I'm five eight and I
feel like I'm a little bit too tall
and you know, under five, eight. Yeah.
I kind of like a trainee. Like sometimes
I'm in touch with my inner training,
inner training, my masculine
side, my masculine feminine side.
They've a your boner.
It's a fem bone on bone or Lesbos.
It depends what it's for.
Yeah, I dunno. What does that
look?
Are you guys talking about why but is a
terrible time to get your balls caught
and your pants and you have to adjust?
This conversation is going on my like
the last thing allows anybody to think
that I'm getting a hard right
now, but I'm shifting my balls,
pant,
Federer moment or I'll put a black bar
over there talking about like femme boner
or something and I'm like, God damn it.
I didn't have to adjust my boss. Uh,
looking terrible timing.
I'm very obsessed with Rupaul's drag race.
I've been watching it for all three
seasons and I really like the drag drag
queens.
They used to hang out with drag queens
a lot when I lived in group session.
Just you find it cool or interesting when
people are just really being themself,
right? Even if it means like dressing
as a different gender or whatever,
it's just because that's
like what they feel. Right.
It's very ambiguous and I really
like that. Why not, right? Yeah.
Why the fuck not like I used to go out
and like pulling drag looks with drag
Queens in Florida and P and I
like blended with them because
they thought you were a big woman,
a dude dressed as well just
as a dude dressed as a girl,
some pretty next level inception type
of shit. It was the next level shit.
Yeah, your hands are too
small or too small. No Dude,
you were really one of those people
that were supposed to be born a woman,
you know? Wow. That would be the worst.
So it's way better to be a woman
who looks like might be a tranny.
Then a dude who looks like a woman
that are like the like girl,
like a gin.
They're like jeans are just messed up
and they just ended up with a deck but
they're like really more woman.
They have like a whole different,
like if they want to do trainee porn,
they,
it's a very niche and that they look more
like women than like someone that may
be started transitioning later in life
and it was more masculine and so it opens
their door to like be like the best
transsexual prostitute or a porn star or
whatever. Like they could really like
cash in on that. You know, people you
really want to do to make their sex,
like an issue going to be the best
possible to compete. And
who's the best training? Yeah,
they've like training yours.
Bailey Bailey.
Jay got the best transsexual
performer followed the trainees,
trainees follow me and
I followed them back.
And I think they're just hot girls.
They're probably just happy that
someone accepts them. You know?
I figured anybody except the Joe Rogan.
Exactly.
I think there's a broad
spectrum of human behavior.
There's a huge spectrum
and all I care about
that fighting stuff or like fucking stuff
and we're teaching people real values.
Well, I mean that's what this, this thing
is about. This is just a conversation.
Yes. You know, we, we, we, it's
so easy to judge people valuable.
What's the good
confused and we would naturally
gravitate towards teams.
And if you're not on
team dress like a guy,
all of a sudden there's
something fucked up about you.
But if you're a fucking guy who
really loves dressing like a chick,
who the fucking mind, who's anybody to
say there's something wrong with them?
Why not?
80 girls dress like guys all the time
and you never have a problem with it.
I mean,
I don't want to dress like a woman,
but I don't give a shit if you do
really strikes hot Hilary swank,
Hilary swank, and I think she's
hot. I think Hillary's is, I got,
if I've heard dude say that they think
she looks like a man, I'm like, I dunno.
Maybe you need to get a
certain amount of man in you.
You mean to be a certain amount
of masculine to appreciate
a beauty like Hillary
swearing,
which is a little on the manly side.
You need to be more dominant,
more masculine than her. Yeah.
You don't want to be like a frail
man and you want to Fuck Hillary.
Swank shall mount you
and ground and pound you.
I am actually probably more
masculine than Hillary Swank.
The person I would have to the
two of you together because
when you see someone in real life,
like people always telling me
when they meet me, God damn,
you're so fucking short. I never
thought you showing. No, it's true.
Five eight but on TV, yeah, but
on TV, you know, you look big,
you know you're on television.
Then these people meet me and they're
like towering over me and they're like,
well, you know, like you meet a guy,
he's like six four and like, oh,
I thought you were fucking taller.
Like you don't know what anybody's like
until you actually meet them. I mean,
you'd have to,
you'd have to like see like I've met
celebrities that I thought were like these
big people and there's these little
tiny people and look at Conan O'brien.
I never knew he was that
tall. Very tall, very tall.
Which I'm sure it makes it awkward when
he does his show because he's a tower is
over all these people and he wants to be
unassuming and you know, you know it's,
it's, it's, it's interesting thing. So
who's more manly? You are Hillary Swank.
She would have to be
sitting right next to you.
Cause when she did million dollar
baby and she played the boxer,
she's like pretty fucking manly. All
right. She was, but she was yoked.
Do you remember that? I couldn't work
out if I didn't love not working out,
but she already knew she already did it.
So I'm pretty sure she's more
masculine than, you know, look,
if you were together right next to each
other and shape doesn't mean they're
like masculine the fuck
it doesn't. Yeah, it does.
It's all directly related to how
difficult it would be to rape you. Yeah,
exactly.
That's what it is. You look like
you'd be a tangle, like kind of. Damn.
I couldn't even get hard to fight,
fight for my life here.
If a man feels like you could
just absolutely run away with you,
like grab you and
tortured people on their balls.
I don't think I would have
any like problem like trying
to like punch someone in
the face or rip their eyes out or
kick them in the deck or something. I,
I've been like very aggressively
sexual towards men and shame them.
So I feel like that would be an
advantage of our rapists rapists out.
Nobody tried to rape me cause
I can kick your Dick and balls.
All I'm saying, why are you
trying to get people to rape me?
You know your followership
don't Rape Dana please.
And if you're thinking about it,
please stop thinking about it.
What I'm saying is that's when a woman
becomes a manly looking when she looks
how diff. Very rude. Very right. It's so,
it's so inconsiderate. I wanna fuck
you. Even if you don't want it.
This girl I was talking to
the other day on a, she sits,
she was raped twice and I'm like,
I'm like,
which one was the better
one to break that down,
write that down. That's a bit like if
you had to choose one, which one was,
you've got to do that tomorrow
night at south 100%. That is a bit,
no doubt about it.
That's really funny.
I think it's really funny. The bts of
porn movies, they'll try to be like,
when did you lose your virginity?
And some people just full on.
I was like how old were you?
Yeah, the behind the scenes. Oh
that's one for our size.
I thought you were sitting like a
message board, like a bbs bulletin board.
Like the little behind the scenes
but it's just people are like,
how old were you?
They show you guys like
Duchenne and cleaning up.
I always try to trick people into like
watching me p and Douche and stuff cause
they're not really supposed to film like
peeing because like the distributors
have like a problem with it.
Well my bloody getting on people.
Some places I've seen, but um, I did
a movie called girls lie for vivid,
all directed by you MCI and it had a
girl taking a pregnancy test and she peed
on it on the toilet and they can show
it because it's like in a medical
environment. Yeah, like a normal
environment. Like pp goes in the toilet,
not in Dana's mouth.
I saw that's what you think.
I saw a guy pissed in someone's
mouth live. It was really funny.
I think it's funny, I think it's more
hilarious than anything that, you know,
somebody like they want to jack off to
the movies and I want to see naked people
and they want to see some weird shit.
But then also kind of like when a laugh,
I think
it was a, there's a guy that used to do
it called extreme Elvis and he, I met him,
I met him.
Yeah.
He's buddies with Doug Stan home and Doug
was opening up for him at this bar and
the guy goes up there, he's fat as
fuck. And he's a really good singer.
Like he's really good and
the band is tight, you know,
it's not just a bizarro show. And then
the guy takes his clothes off and he goes,
Michael Salus,
I'm a complete micro Phallus.
I mean it's like to the point where
people are laughing hysterical.
I believe it's still up on my website.
I believe I took a picture of his dick
and he's pissing in this woman's mouth.
He goes, who else drives gangs?
Purse, let's go. Goes. I do. I do.
And she gets her knee and I took
pictures of the whole thing.
I told you I took pictures of them
pissing in her mouth, pissing in a glass.
She drinks the glass
like is fucking crazy.
He comes off stage and he's in the crowd
and some woman tries to stick a beer
bottle up his ass. You
can like pee on cue. Yeah.
Some woman tries to stick a beer
bottle up his ass and he goes,
that's the wrong holes right here.
Get it right here.
Like he helps her stuffed as beer bottle
up his ass and she panics and just
drops the bottle.
Or she panicked,
like she thought she would stick her beer
bottle up this guy's ass and he would
freak out like, Hey, what
the fuck? Right. But he goes,
you can get in the wrong hole, honey.
It's right here. I'll guide you in there.
And he starts helping her. I stick a
fucking beer bottle up his asshole.
But that sounds like this
guy's real ready to go. Yeah.
So I run into him and I think that's
art. I run into him, Paul Provenza show,
ah, I run into him at the Paul Provenza
show and now he's no longer extreme albus
and I think he's like clean and sober now.
He used to get hammered as fuck
before he did that show. And you know,
I was talking to him,
I've met him before a while ago,
like at the bright spot or something.
And I was talking out in the proper vendor
show about a guy that I used to know
who was a male feminist. That's how he
would describe himself as a male feminist.
And it was just, it was just as
like really sad, weak guy. And
yeah,
it was very savvy and he was this guy
like this really like a bag of Jello as a
human being. He was just like, and
eventually she left him and so anyway,
I was mocking this whole idea of like,
how the fuck could you be a male feminist?
And after I get off stage, he goes, well,
I'm a male feminist. And I'm like, oh wow.
I would love to debate you on that.
Like we should do some TV.
I'm like, you just said it.
You just said exactly what
I said. Like, uh, the,
a fleshy ball of Jello with a micro
Fallis and you're a male feminist.
Well of course you are. You have to
lady. Well basically, no, no offense,
you're,
you're a bad motherfucker and what you
do when you do that crazy Elvis thing.
But like, you know, talking
about being a feminist,
like be whatever the fuck you want to be,
but you can't tell me it's not
ridiculous. You're, you're,
you're like really into the female
of the species. Like you're,
you're really like thinking of them first.
Like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
How about being a God damn human.
I'm going to be in a human across the
board sexually, whether it's male, female,
gay, straight trans, who gives a shit?
How about being across the board?
Not a fucking feminist. You
dumb ass. You can't defend that,
but you only want to help
women. You only want to promote women.
You fucking weak, bitch. That's weak shit.
I don't even call myself a feminist. I
wouldn't say. I would say like, I'm not,
not a feminist. Things I can
get on board with and whatever.
But you know,
there's so many different
waves of feminism that people
will come behind you and
just be like,
Eh,
is this grouping everything together?
Stupid at the beginning? Yes.
All groups are stupid,
you know, all of it. Yeah.
Were you looking out for what I mean,
you can't fucking fix the world. I mean,
there's some things that you have to have.
Like you have to have some sort of a,
uh, an a group that's there to investigate
claims of racism when it comes to jobs
and stuff like that. I mean you have
to have some groups, but as possible.
That's good. Sure. Dominated
as little as possible,
as little goddamn groups as possible.
Yeah. That's the key. You know,
people get on fucking team mentality
mode and they start just going after it
almost team Stroup. Oh, more tune queer,
you know, Oh, I'm on this, I'm on that.
They can't help it.
I like it.
I like it all just everybody's got
to lighten the fuck up, Right Dana?
Yes.
Isn't that the key to this world?
He does say that we'd cook could
fix the world probably for real.
It sounds silly.
It sounds silly coming from a fucking
comedian and a porn star and a a video
comedian.
Real
obviously. Yeah. Maybe people listen to
us because maybe we were a little bit more
formed.
I read this post on a message board the
other day about this dude who talked
about he had smoked pot for the first
time in like seven years and he was
absolutely terrified to his core.
And then it brought up all these crazy
thoughts of childhood and he could not
handle it and it would open
up this fascinating discussion
because um, you know,
some people were saying that's
normal. Some people were saying, well,
you got some shit.
You got to deal with his fucking with
you in the back of your head and you're,
and you're sober life.
You're not addressing it.
But that's why we eat is good for you.
You're supposed to look at everything
all the time. And a lot of us don't.
We like to burry shit in the back of our
hand and try not to address whatever's
fucking with us.
And we just turned a light on that shit.
Whenever you have in your life that's
fucking with you that you're trying to put
deep in your subconscious, marijuana
does not allow that. It doesn't allow it.
So people say, Oh, it makes me paranoid.
Not Know. It's making you think about the,
you need to be thinking
about,
you should be fucking paranoid.
You should be aware of how vulnerable
you are. The world is very fucked up.
I had to like move because people were
stealing my mail when I live in silver.
Like I had to like move to a high
security building. I couldn't feel,
I knew where you were. Yeah.
Fans like that's, and I was like,
I did think I was paranoid, but I was
like, no, these people are for real,
like know who I am.
And it's kind of trippy.
Did you have a happy child on you
think? Oh yeah, absolutely. Really?
I um, my parents were involved in
everything. A PTA girl scouting.
I was a figure skater or they
say finger skating. How does,
how do your parents deal
with what you do now? Um,
I don't know. I don't know if
they deal with it. I Dunno.
It's not really something
that is a non issue. An issue.
Yeah. Really. They're like no
big deal. You're just, yeah.
Having sex on film. Yeah.
Wow. That's fascinating. Pretty much.
Well, they also see that, yeah, you know,
I have a reasonable, uh, you know,
amount of following and fan base and
people who appreciate what I contribute to
the porn industry besides just being like,
just you personally more holes in a
bunch of fake hair. It's, you know,
just uh, so you contribute being
your personality and your assumption.
Yeah. Yeah, definitely. Yeah. Um, but my,
my parent's respect my decisions,
which was maybe kind of a very foreign
concept for most people because the
people, people's parents tend to,
you know, tell them what to do.
And My, my parents are opposite. They told
me like, were they religious at all? No,
my parents are religious. What
is their background? Oh Man,
my,
my grandmother is from Germany and I
don't think that my mom was raised with a
religion because my grandmother was
like a new agey dad do for a living,
whatever.
My Dad does a kind of weird shit like I,
he works with at a catering company now.
Um,
but he was like an onsite security manager
of a storage facility and he used to
be a CEO of a software company.
And he quit that to be a fish farmer and
then he like went to like ranch cattle
and Oklahoma. Like my dad is just
kind of all over the place. Wow.
That's Kinda cool though. My Dad is like
kind of like a genius at free spirit.
All, all sorts of things.
But like for that amount of
time, you know, he just like,
yeah,
he's like turbo thruster,
like short change careers and your life.
My Dad does all the time
and my, my mom works, um,
at a company that makes stuff to
blow up Brown people in Florida.
Wow. Wait a missile company like
some, yeah, some form of arms.
Yeah. It doesn't have to be Brown. We met
Jackson, yellow people in North Korea.
Sure. Keep talking shit talking
shit. But motherfuckers,
we got some shit for you.
Hey,
my mom has been like in her
job for a really long time.
A bunch of people got mad at me,
people
MMA forum because I, uh, there was a,
we were in Kentucky and there was a,
some fights going on and
this kid who was a wrestler,
a was fighting this other guy who's a
kickboxer from Italy, right? And uh,
he lives in America, but
they were chanting, she will
suit you. And I was like,
really? Kentucky? And I'm like,
that guy lives in Miami. All right,
we're all immigrants.
All right?
Everyone in this fucking country descended
from immigrants and no one was here
10,000 years ago. It was all
ice. You Fuck, all right,
that's the whole deal with America.
This guy actually lives here and
you're yelling USA. And you know,
people were like saying like,
you know,
there's nothing wrong with patriotism
and you're in forcing your beliefs on
other people. I'm like, no, I'm, I'm
making fun of Shit. I think it's stupid.
You know, you're being colored
commentary silly. You're yelling at USA.
What did just watch these guys for their
goddamn technique and their courage and
what the fuck they're
trying to accomplish.
And the difficulty of the task
is a great God damn fight,
which again is all American wrestler who
beat Phil Davis and Ryan Bader is bad
ass fucking wrestler and this Italian
kickboxer he's trying to get his ground
game together. It's a great
fucking fight. And he's dildos you,
you if they spit all over the back of
the person's head in front of them.
This dumb fucking mouth breathing cock
suckers how a cell and they get mad at
you for being upset at it.
How else did you feel about that your
your time over in Kentucky? Because I,
I grew up around there and I going
through Kentucky was always a fun time.
It always is great dude.
Louisville's a great city.
The comedy club was fucking fantastic.
The people there are super cool.
The people that worked there
were super cool. It's like,
it's got this weird southern sort of
like almost hippie thing going on.
There's like a lot of
like young people there.
There's a lot of like open minded people
there and then there's a lot of old
money and then there's a lot of ghetto.
Yeah.
So it's this weird combination of shit
scar. No, not Alexi. Not In Louisville.
Louisville is the old money.
It's like,
it's a rare part of the
south where it's like,
there's a lot of like really establish
like social clans and groups and social
lives. A lot of money, like really,
really old money down there.
But a lot of educated people too.
But they're on that show.
The first 48 they're on
that show all the time.
It was getting jacked in Louisville.
I got a Uverse are real dead bodies.
That's so creepy. It's dark. It's really
weird that you can show, um, you know,
anybody getting shot in a movie, but you
can't show people really fucking, yeah.
So amazing.
Or like a, a woman experiencing
sexual pleasure. It's like, okay,
if it's like the dude,
go ahead.
But like not fan of a guy just
down the girl having an orgasm.
It's very not done.
Yeah. Right. Does it ever
happen? Yeah. He never,
you never said like the girl coming.
So even if it's the guy,
and it's usually like for Congress,
private parts and the girls,
like on the speaker. Um,
like having an orgasm. Right. Howard
was making the noises and stuff.
I remember that was so shocking when
that came out. Like that was so, yeah.
When that movie,
fuck yeah, that was hot.
You're sitting on the speaker
and he's going to
microphone. Yeah, that was,
that was cool.
That's interesting that it's not thought
of as being very important if you come
because it's all leftover barbarian shit
and we used to hold you down by your
hair and just shoot a load and you
and run away. That's what it is.
That's how people made babies back
then. Let's grow. It is gross,
but it's the reason why men are stronger
than women. Why aren't you strong too?
You're not strong too, so we can rape
you easier. It's really that simple.
There's no logical reason why you
wouldn't be like [inaudible] tall. We're,
we're stronger to fight off other men
that want to fuck you and kill the babies.
That's what we're strong.
That's totally right.
Strong to rape you and
to fight off other men.
It says you're supposed to be strong too.
Why aren't you strong too?
Sky Is wrestle each other so they get
off out of their system instead of trying
to rape me.
[inaudible] haven't even considered Yo to,
haven't even looked into this so deeply.
They're scared because of
social constructs. Right.
We had a Ras,
if you're on his own podcast,
had a gas that was addicted to going to
bath houses or, I mean massage parlors.
Yup. To get late. Did you see, did he say
his name? No, no, no. All right. Okay.
Do you have a mom with a mask on him
yet? A Spiderman mask on. Oh yeah, dude.
I almost said his name. Yeah, I know.
Yes. But anyways, that was
close. Sorry. This is live.
Maybe we should consider not having this
line. Even Charlie Sheen edits to shit.
Uh, but so anyways, he, I never
knew. Like I always heard the,
the hand job thing where
they say they say handhelds,
but he was talking about how
there's places here in la,
many places that he can get just like
fucking full on hooker sex. What?
And he says that he's gotten to the point
where he has places that has favorite
places with his favorite. He's like, yeah,
this isn't like an la 10 at this one
place and it's $150 and you just fucking
there sit there and fuck after you do
a 15 minute massage. Whoa. And he says,
he says and yeah,
even bring out the women so they can
look like the bunny ranch where they,
they all call her and say hi and
stuff like that. Wow. Massage Parlor.
Is there a thing where you
can get a massage part of
your sex massage at the end?
Yeah,
like more relaxing the wind down.
They give you a legit and massage and
then they jerked you off at the end.
The massage at the end though, I'm
crazy thing. Is that sterling? Yeah.
Fast out the gate and then I would get
like the wine down. Oh, I see. Yeah.
So you would go, wow, that's interesting
for a guy. I think it's the opposite,
right? Give me a massage first and
then beat me off. Don't be, yeah. Yeah,
cause actually beat me off. I just want
to go away. Yeah, I'm done. See Ya.
And I don't mean to massage. That's good.
I feel good. I'm loose. He also got,
when men have an orgasm,
there's a fucking instinctive need
that you have to overcome to just run,
to come get away. It's true in real
life, fucked the movies and real life.
When a guy comes, I'm telling you he wants
to run away. I mean you want to stay.
If you will love your wife
or your girlfriend and you,
you know you have this relationship
together. But if you don't,
if you don't know each other that well,
then all sudden you fucking like get me
Outta here. What have I done? The snuggle.
Snuggle.
Sometimes,
sometimes if you really love the job, but
there's a lot of times when you're not,
there's a lot of times
when you just want a raw,
especially if you're drinking,
if you're drinking and you
know that somehow or another,
you've loud the alcohol and your penis
to talk you into some unreasonable
situation.
And then as soon as you orgasm that it
just becomes clear what the fuck happened.
And then you want to run away,
get me Outta here.
So what I'm trying to say
is it's way better to get
massage first. He loosens you up then
drug. I'd be like, good, we're done.
We're done here. We're done. Thank you.
You also said that how he got an escort
once and it was in this weird like small
town. It was like three o'clock
in the morning and uh, he, he,
he only had two options and like on
the Internet you've found like their
websites and one the lady was
already out doing something else,
but the other one,
you know like would show her eyes only
and then it will like show like her leg
or something like that cause it couldn't
show the whole thing. And so he's like,
fuck it, I am, I do this. And she
had a really nice or you know,
it seemed really nice on
the phone or stuff. Then she
comes over and it was like,
she, she was just like, had
to like stab wounds. She like,
her teeth were all fucked up and her
voice sound like PJ Stansberry was like,
hey,
come over here and stuff like that.
And he said it was so bad
that like he felt like he,
it was impossible to fuck this
girl. So then he's goes, uh, yeah,
I have this thing and I like to do,
it's where you give me a blowjob,
I put a blanket over you, why watch
porn? And she's like, alright, you know,
and then afterwards she's like,
do you mind if I finish myself up?
But you got me all hot and bothered and
says he just puts one leg up over on and
it just starts fucking masturbating.
It's called skeptic tank to a rx.
If you're a skeptic, take to a desk,
squad podcasts. But listen
to that, that's so sad.
Friend that has been addicted to go into
those massage Polish forever and he's
never had a girlfriend as
long as I've known him.
I've known him for more than 10 years and
more than 10 years that I've known him
all, all this guy does is he's a, he's
not a very good looking guy. And he's,
he's not built very well and he went
bald really young in life and he's never
been successful. Right. And
just has a real hard time.
He gets real nervous around checks. So he
just goes, he's Asian massage place is,
it just gets whacked off all the time.
Yeah. So a good percentage of like,
it doesn't make a lot of money.
So the good percentage of what this guy
makes every week goes to just getting
whacked off. And then he takes
them out on dates sometimes.
He was talking to me about it once we
were playing pool and he was talking to me
about it. He's like, yeah, well, you know,
I'm taking her on a date this Friday
though. What you get. Oh, okay. All right.
So like judge up Joe, I'm, no,
no. I'm saying, do you think,
is she going to be your boyfriend? Are you
going to be her boyfriend? Like what's,
what's going on? Like you guys get, yeah.
Um, romantic comedy, right.
Wax Off dudes all day and then Thompson.
But I felt like I felt like
the way he was telling me,
it was almost like he had talked her into
doing it cause she didn't want to lose
him as a customer. Right.
You know, times are tough,
you know when you get that steady
700 a week coming from one dude,
you know he's thinking about it.
Do it himself like
every other day or something. Yeah. Kinda.
He'd like to say fucking find a fat chick
with a mustache and just be like, look,
we can fuck each other once a week,
but I have to get really drunk every
time I do it. It's just like, okay,
you can get jerked up by cute Asian girls.
What are you talking about?
It's ridiculous. Option.
Plateaued on a higher
human nature son.
You're talking some unrealistic nonsense.
It doesn't work that way. Right.
That's right. Joe, back to you.
And the traffic today is
sponsored by flash lights.
You totally can be like waiting
for the entertainment tonight.
Right now we've got you as a
comic and we got, yeah. Yeah.
Mary Hart got to light my legs
real nice. Oh that's, you're right.
It was her legs raise them up to this.
He had a leg greaser for
sometimes it seemed like,
like sometimes it would go like Mary
hearts legs were just like greasy,
like she just signed Nana
oil and shit like that. Yeah.
Isn't that funny man?
Gosh, we're gonna have her own show. Yay.
Makes sense to you. Being
a woman, being a woman,
seeing like men like freaking
out about body parts and zinc.
Like that's all you need to like sell a
car and some woman with slinky legs like
folds them over and gets
in the front seat. Yeah.
Everybody wants to buy that fucking
Cadillac. There's policy demand car.
There's some crazy connection.
What is it like though to
be a professional woman?
Like how to be a professional sex symbol?
Like dudes are they,
they look at you and 99% of
them are thinking about sex.
So thinking about sex that you've
had and what you're selling.
If I wasn't in the business I'm in,
I feel like people would probably
look at me that way anyway. No.
Yeah,
because I'm always like,
I'm trying to talk it out with my
coworkers and stuff and I'm like,
I think this guy just wants to
fuck me because I'm a porn star.
And then like men welfare, I
looked at me and goes, no idiot.
They want to fuck you because you're
hot. And I'm like, oh, okay. Yeah.
I can make up whatever backstory.
Even if they've seen like uh, like a,
a digital image on their computer or not.
People can,
like when you see a
hot girl, you are, have
your whole, your imaginations run
wild. If I worked with your team,
everybody works. I would want to fuck
you the whole time I was at. Right.
Body works. Why would I
work at I am not, I've just,
this is information that I've acquired
from my thesis. Is that what you said?
You're being honest,
but it's also very possible that he
wanted to fuck you because he saw you fuck
people on film. Right. I
know. I've never watched,
I've watched her fuck one time on
film now. That's fine. Yeah. Was just,
you have to stop looking at me
naked because we're friends now.
That's just not the way that
it goes. Funny. There's,
there's no social taboo
between you watching porn
that I'm in just because we're
friends.
A lot of people that I find important,
it's kind of strange there.
There's lines of the draw, you
know, there's very distinct lines.
Like I remember this couple that I met,
we were doing the man show
and this couple came on.
They were talking about
how they're allowed to fuck
other people while they work.
They're both in porn,
but then off work,
you're not allowed to just go random my
fuck people. Right. And I was like, wow,
that's a, that's a weird
distinction. Like how do you,
how do you figure that one out?
I'll get your okay with him
fucking whoever at work.
But that was the other thing.
Like one guy was on the set and his
girlfriend started sucking this guy's Dick
when the camera wasn't running.
Right. He's like, Hey, what the fuck?
And he got all mad.
How are we creating new? That's where
I'm crazy is that he's like, fucking,
you guys aren't even filming and she's
just sucking his dick. What's up?
What's up?
I've actually,
I've worked with people and to have the
same kind of thing where it's like, uh,
they can do whatever they want on camera,
but the guy has to like stroke himself.
He's like getting ready to go. Like
the girl can't help it. Like there,
it's like maybe they might be the same
people. I don't know. Isn't that crazy?
But yeah, it's just they're
socially monogamous. Have a rule.
There's a line that you
draw. Well, I of fun.
I used to date a guy in the business and
outside of work we didn't fuck around
or whatever.
No.
And he did some things that I found
were questioning them all and he was,
and he was like, there's a camera in
the room. And I was like, you're a fuck.
That's fucked up. That's not the same
thing. Right. Oh, that's hilarious. Yeah,
just like one doesn't count.
No, no, no. But I mean, it just,
your,
your boundaries are your own
and it doesn't matter what
you do for a living just
because you're a comedian doesn't like,
no one's allowed to tell jokes
in my house besides, you know,
just that's just not the way
that life works. Right. Um,
but you, if you have a, like some kind
of contracts like marriage or you're,
you're with somebody and you say,
okay, well we live together now.
So like I don't want you sleeping with
other people even though I do porn for
living. Do you know what
I'm saying? It just,
because that's what you've
arranged between the two of you.
That's a weird thing though.
Why Range? Anything? Why?
Why make something that someone can't do?
If you're allowing the most
sacred of sacred things,
you're allowing this person to fuck
other people right on, on film.
Why not just allow it to be themselves?
Why put any boundaries just here,
come here at night and,
and this is where we live.
Cause I dunno if sex is not
that sacred to some people.
Maybe because maybe like
the people that I work with,
they don't have my address.
Right. You know what I mean?
And maybe that's a little bit more my
privacy and my security is more sacred to
me than the actual physical act of sex.
That's true.
Right? Yeah, that's true.
It's like pleasure. It's like,
would you get mad every
time you masturbated to the
video or you know what I'm
saying is why put a boundary on it
though? Why put a boundary and not, not,
not necessarily. I see what you're saying.
What do you want to like letting people
Virgo and they were just, you know, they
want things to be a certain way, you know,
in our realm of comparability.
Do what the fuck they want to do and
find someone who you're compatible with
instead of trying to morph
someone to your expectations.
That's the number one problem
with audible. Yeah. Meet people,
find people that are incompatible with
them when they try to make them fit and
it doesn't fucking work that way.
Right.
One person is a control freak and
the other person's anal and whatever,
they don't move.
They don't want to do the thing that
they've agreed that they don't want to do.
You know, like it's not compatible
what they've agreed like, yeah.
Negatives in there.
[inaudible] they're compatibility.
Oh he that they both, you know,
for what reason or another thing,
it's okay to do porn,
but outside of work they agree to sleep
with only each other and they come to
that together.
That's definitely a compatibility.
Yeah. Good point. Yeah.
If they're all agree,
if it's not based on necessarily
judgment or whatever,
I'm not saying there's
anything wrong with it.
I'm just saying it's an odd thing that
you don't have a boundary and someone
fucking people on camera,
but you do have a boundary with them
doing it for pleasure on their own with
another person.
Well, just because that might
be emotional art is, or what,
right. It's, it's understood when
you're, when you're fucking lame film.
Exactly. Porn is acting and
athleticism. Athleticism.
What they're calling it these days.
You should,
yeah. I'm a crazy person and you
know, and it's not comfortable. It's,
it's not for you. It's for the
camera. It's, you know, it's,
and it's hard to do something
that does not feel good. Right.
And Act like you feel
like it feels good to,
you literally get fuck sideways sometimes.
It really fucking hurts it just,
do you ever stretch it out
before shoots? You know, I do. I
need to. I have like a
huge butt butt hole. Mongo.
Is it easy for you to Poop poop?
Matt,
can you just sit down and like take
care of it and like three seconds.
[inaudible] got Danny Line
launcher
toilet.
Just have an airtight toilet.
She puts her,
squeezes her legs together and cover their
snatch with her hands so they'll ship,
doesn't blessed off through
the bottom of your legs.
Just blows out.
Broken a firearm.
Just hang it on.
She has to take a shower every time
she shit, this is the back of my legs.
Looks like she went
skidding down a muddy hill.
His no containing your shit.
They're assholes like the Lincoln tunnel.
It looks like the back of it looks like
the back of your shirt when it's raining
outside and you're on your bike
and the mud is skidded up the bat.
Oh,
oh.
Because I'm disgusted.
I'm discussing it myself as well.
So as the, but you're not, you're
not in the bud section. Real life.
Just are you good at sex in real life?
Like is it the same as, is that the same?
Are you quitting? Because I like
to exaggerate my movement. Right.
Why don't you do that in real life? Lazy
Bitch. Very stationary. Are you like,
I'm only on the top. I'm only on the
ball down and like are you serious?
Down into tempurpedic
bed?
Yeah. Yeah. Well, Hey, I, uh, a
little bit. Yeah, it makes sense.
You're a big fuck off. Does it
make sense naturally, genetically.
Danida a strong man to turn your arm.
Like being,
you want to let you want to feel that
if this guy wanted to take it, yeah,
he could take it. Sure. That's what it is.
It's natural. You're a big girl. Not Bad.
Not in a bad way. You
are a good specimen. You,
if you wanted to make warrior children,
you'd be a good specimen for your children
with flexible buttholes, you'd be,
you have the perfect DNA for it.
Yes.
Is it hard to, to, to be, to date people
as a porn star, do you find or does,
is it like more of a challenge?
Yeah,
it depends on the person.
I did it a guy a couple
years ago and when we met,
like he knew what I did and stuff like
that and I did not want to be involved
with him.
And then
we started sleeping together
after a really long time.
We kind of like worn me down a little
bit and then after that it was like kind
of fucked up. It was, we weren't off to a
good start. Um, I'll admit, but you know,
I get bored too.
Um,
so after we like started dating
or are fucking fucking in dating,
he then like looked at porn that I was
an and decided that he wanted to be a
spazz about it and be like,
I don't know,
like knowing you do those types of
things, I don't know. And I'm like, yeah,
you already knew.
But now that now you want to be bothered
because you're a drama queen has
nothing to do with what I
do. It's just that, you know,
feelings were awesome feelings. We're
also getting, you know, starting now,
they'd be four.
It was like zero feelings.
I just want to fuck you now
the now it's starting to cut,
like love gets involved. You know?
I think that's probably a Max
process of wearing you down.
It's like I don't judge you like I think
it's fine and it's like really great
because you're really successful. And
then I just kind of nose dived into like,
ah, yeah, you do those things.
I think for a lot of men
it's very important when
they meet a girl that they're
sexually attracted to,
they want that girl liked them and I think
that is the root of a lot of bullshit.
And the guys don't even realize
they're doing it. It's a genetic thing.
It's a predisposition to wanting
to be sexually attractive.
And so they start pretending
to be someone who they're not.
And then they get into the relationship
and then it's a couple months in and
they're relaxed and comfortable
and they're like, why am
I with this crazy bitch?
I don't even, I'm not even into this.
And Yeah. Yeah. It's like there's a,
there's a lot of dudes that are
just trying to put it together.
Like they don't have the luxury of like
actually being honest and trying to like
meet someone that they actually like,
they're so caught up in the game of trying
to fuck a chick and it's so difficult
for them. Then when they finally get
one they tackle or they get it in there.
Yeah. They're like, ah, got one. Good.
Okay. What did I pretend to be doing?
Do this.
I'm not a fucking Vegan.
I want us to start wearing
the beads and stuff.
You know,
they meet a girl that's willing to fuck
them like once every couple months.
They got to work hard
to take it down so they pretend to
be someone and not using plates.
Just sex for lie. We,
we do together is love.
That's just
a movie you're making, right? Oh yeah.
That same drama guy. He was like,
yeah, I was like being really depressed
or something like that. And he,
he would like one of the lay it on me.
Like,
you can't live inside your own pain
and I love you. And I was like, Huh,
get the fuck out. You're
creeping me out. You can weird.
I don't know where you heard that
shit. Fuck out of you in here.
This is something that you think,
yeah, I was like, you're full of shit
out. Never had come back the
worst. Leave my phone number,
sexually unattractive thing ever is
someone's full of Shit, which is so gross.
People are full of Shit. Like, Oh
God. It's such a, such a bummer.
You know when you hear someone say some
nonsense and then you have to mock them
and then they get mad at you for Maka
them and it all fucking falls apart. Oh,
I used to date this girl who used
to write poetry and it was nonsense.
It was nonsense.
It was,
I mean it was her form of expression,
but it was so clearly affected and fake
and just designed to like fucking fire
off all the rights and it was
just so artificial, so clear,
so clear that it was just a bullshit that
she was slinging. It was so offensive.
Or you a poetry snob though?
Or do you like it just like high quality?
I love the counseling. You know what
I love about Koski and you know,
I mean it's a lot of his stores are like
really dark is a little poem, but it's,
that's a fuck with that guys
thinking about for real. Yeah.
That is his real life and switch thing on.
That's all require of an artist with what
inflames me is when I think someone is
trying to pretend to be someone else,
whether it's a human or a singer
or a comedian or an actor.
If I feel like you're bullshitting me,
I feel like you're bullshitting me.
It's offensive. Yeah. Read me.
You're fucking crazy. Poetry Hooker,
the felting tier intelligent.
You're,
you're mad at me that I'm
laughing at this nonsense.
That was a horror story
from vit doing porn. What's,
what's one thing that sticks out?
Just you fucking like,
just awful experience. Did
you ever like say, okay,
never again.
Um,
I used to do a lot of like
BDSM stuff where I was a sub.
That is, and I will get beat. Explain
that to everybody who's not crazy.
He DSM, most people don't
have any idea what that means.
Bonded.
Well,
it's like sadomasochism
s and M is sadomasochism.
When you say a were the one that they
tortured, sub submissive and dominant.
So it's bondage and dominatrix.
No, some shit like that. Yeah,
it's like a code, I dunno. Whatever.
Right. It's like being in the army. Yeah.
Easy. Yeah. It's like the same things.
You try to invent little
short things of them.
So um, yeah, it would,
it'd be like electrocuted
and tight and like, you know,
hit with different, your nipples, nipples,
like in your body with like pads
my pussy inside and said my boss,
oh my God. Like while in like very
strict bondage and stuff like that.
My God, Whoa, Whoa, whoa.
Challenging.
You know?
And it was something that
was really legitimately
interested in when I was in my
early twenties and it's something
that I thought that maybe, you know,
so I consider myself to be a kind of
a tough person and I felt like if I,
if I've met these challenges, it
would prove how tough I was. God Damn.
Wow.
Yeah,
I dunno it.
Inside your pothole,
what percentage of the population is
ever been electric unit inside the there?
I mean,
they produce like the tens unit,
send the, I mean they're sold like as
medical equipment and stuff like that.
I'm sure a fair amount of people
have gotten their hands on them,
you know? So I don't know. I don't
have the numbers in front of me said,
well let me stick this thing on my
full battery on your asshole.
[inaudible] when you're about
to calm nine up your ass.
Oh,
iron man loads.
You don't know though. Oh, I think I do
have a penis.
Makes the guy shoot longer,
loads more experience with more penises.
You don't know that.
There's no
more than willing to
submit to you on those
outfitting the entire room.
Me.
So how long did this whole session take?
Weather electrocuting your
vagina and your asshole
man. It was a first that
called wired pussy.com. Yeah,
so it's all electric shooting pussies.
There's a site
female on female sub dom and the electric
policies play like you play games,
like who can take the most electricity
or they'll chase blindfolded and partially
tied up women around with a cattle
prod. That makes noise. And
you could either go toward
it or away from the sound,
but if you go away from the sound,
just when I thought get in trouble,
some of the darkness. Yeah, no, that's,
that's where I started. That's where I
stopped. Ever had your pee hole fucked.
Whoa.
There's videos out there of guys.
Fucking girls is really small and
it stretches just like your asshole.
I'm very sensitive in my whole
life. Don't, don't say never.
You got to reach goals.
You gotta you gotta
of my body.
I went through a phase of like piercing
and stuff like that when I was younger.
I did some tattoo above
the cookie.
I do,
but I'm having it removed and that is so
fucking painful than any like butthole
electrocution I've ever gotten.
Really.
Laser Tattoo removal
is so painful. It, um,
like agitate the Inca molecule and
your skin and makes it explode.
And with each treatment it just gets
smaller and smaller and it grow.
It metabolizes out of your body.
Right?
You have to wait a couple of months in
between sessions just like long enough
that you could forget how
much fucking pain you are in.
You have to go in and do it again.
Fuck that.
I'm just keeping waterfalls. Just kissing
it. Got An old tattoo. Tramp stamp.
Yup. Yup. It's around my belly leading.
I'm going to sleep on my right arm and
I have an old tattoo up here that I have
to get removed, go off just
yet. Just get black black box.
But it's just black flag.
How much,
how much worse is it than
the actual tattooing?
So much worse because you have to go
like 20 times and it mines and it's like
just like a very,
uh,
it's like you could feel like the impact
of the laser going into your skin.
It feels like being snapped to
the rubber band really hard.
It instantly burns that it makes
your skin swell up and lot.
Why when you get a tattoo, it's kind
of scratches the surface of your skin.
When you get lasered, it's like
effecting the color inside your skin.
So the blood kind of
seeps out like a sponge.
No, I'm going to, I'm going to wait for
technology to get a little bit better.
He just turned me the fuck off.
Don't do it.
And thinking about cooking my arm
like that, I'm like, what am I doing?
Like that you could damage your skin,
right?
No, I mean it's safe. It
doesn't scar. Doesn't know that.
I mean that's the purpose of it being
such a long, slow process. I mean,
you could just cut it
off if you wanted to,
but I wouldn't say that
that's the best idea ever.
Right.
So let me ask you this.
And wired pussy.com calls you
up next week and says, Hey,
we're looking to do a shoot.
And you're done with that. Yeah.
Yeah. I would top, I've, I've
gotten back to be the dom.
It's a portrait girls from
snapchat because I feel
like I can confidently say I
know what I'm doing and I wouldn't do
something to somebody else that I haven't
had done to myself, but I know
what it feels like. I know.
And if they're not a bad ass bitch like
me, then they don't get to fuck me.
Would you ever do far porn? Yeah. Yeah.
For all the time and my
movies in your movie,
it's just like when you
get fucked in the ass,
like your butt is open and gaping is like
the big thing where they want to see,
they want to see her lower colon,
they want to see it all in age 13
I don't know why people like it,
they just do and I, you know, and
just whatever. So like the air,
it goes into your calves out and then
you have to kind of fight it out and not
look I far like I'm eating
can of beans like a Hobo.
Right, right. My farts on fire
accidentally ever sprayed?
No, no. I think I've,
I've accidentally peed on
people at work and then be like,
I'm squinting or whenever.
And I dunno what is squirting exactly.
Is it really when in the movies,
girls like shooting. All right.
Obviously you can see it coming
out of her pee hole. Right? I'm,
I'm assuming that a lot of people that
watch these movies don't know what a
vagina looks like or anything and
they don't know that where the,
all the liquid shooting out of
the girl's vagina area or her,
her love zone or whatever nerves call it.
Yeah.
But isn't that he,
hey,
but hold on a second because that's where
it would come out anyway because isn't
a pee hole like literally like when a
woman gets her testosterone treatment,
it become a man. Her clit grows.
I become like a small penis,
Pussy Boehner and that the penis is
obviously where any sexual ejaculate would
come out of. So of course it's
going to come out of where you pee.
I don't know.
What is it?
Is it real?
I mean this is did I used to date a girl
that fucking juiced on me and it was
like in my belly button, like a puddle and
it was, it wasn't p though. It was just,
it was like,
because a broth,
you know
when the woman's vagina gets moist,
it's not dripping over pee hole.
It's coming from inside. I don't think
this is moistened it's not lubricant.
That's,
that's what squirting is supposed to be.
And when you'll see it
coming out of the pee hole
p Whoa. Yeah. That it was supposed to
in a lot of times where you see like
Spiderman like trick that they do when
they like finger the pussy and I like
press like on the outside of the man.
So he does his web.
Yeah.
This is like the axle Bron method.
I watched instructional videos and
I was like, what are they doing?
And they're basically just like pushing
on the bladder and just forcing people
to come out. Jesus Christ. Yeah.
And then just exactly what it is.
Like if you had to force piano somebody,
that's exactly how you would do it. Wow.
So that's what all that's
spraying is. So there is, yeah.
So girls are spraying on dudes.
They're pissing all over him.
Yeah. Unless they have like an extra
juicy g spot or something like that.
Like I'm not going to say like,
I'm not going to say female ejaculation
is a myth because I'm not a doctor and I
can't say that.
I mean and you know,
put these get wet and some pussies
are wetter than others. Yeah.
We're talking to an expert here. Dan
D Armaun here. 11 I'm not a doctor.
Not a doctor all in.
Now can you put,
can you put a condom on a dick with just
putting it in your mouth and doing that
trick? I cannot even remember the
last time I used a condom. God Damn.
Wow.
Do you ever worry about diseases?
No. I get tested every three weeks. Yeah.
So how do you keep clean when you're just,
everybody gets tested every three weeks,
right?
Then you have three weeks for a
porn star though. Jesus Christ.
How many you don't do like,
sorry.
Dick's can you be exposed to like I
worked with mark would twice last week.
So it's like the same, same wiener,
same, same wiener. Same Week.
You guys develop like a relationship
when you have like on screen?
Yeah. Uh, I mean I think the
people I work with are cool.
It's not like I'm like, Ooh, like I'm so
horny for you. Let's do things after that.
How many of them long? He's
married Francesco Lay, you know,
and they were fucking awesome.
And I know both of them.
I've worked with both of them.
Dudes that are in porn wanted
to do mainstream things.
We couldn't make it and have like
some sort of a weird thing where they,
I don't know.
It seems to be like a lot of guys are
musicians and they're all like trying to
get together like a band with
all the other dude's Dick. Yeah.
Soon as you call it,
that'd be a bad ass name for a band
playing and Dick Dick. I mean I don't,
maybe I'm uh, I dunno. Maybe
I'm just like, Oh, I'm at work,
I'm doing my work things.
But I didn't really ask people too much
about their particular with Tyler night.
Yeah.
Tyler was a very good friend of mine.
We were actually just both on Star
Trek, the next generation. Oh really?
A triple x parity digital says
in revelation snacks coming soon.
And that was like a bitch. He
was Jordy. Yeah. And I was,
she's a huge star trek fan.
I'm a nerd. I was stoked.
I called my dad and I was like,
I'm reading for the part of Ensign Rao
for the star trek parody. And he was like,
that's so cool. And I was like, no dad,
if I don't get this part, I'll die.
Like super seriously. Like, no, I need,
this has to be my part
or I'm freaking out.
Tyler is a friend of mine from
Jujitsu and he's a really good writer.
Have you ever read any of this stuff?
No.
He's got a blog online and he's
very smart. He's such a cool guy.
He's smart and he's very polite.
Yeah, he's very well spoken.
He was on the podcast,
but we had him on and he's a very,
he's a fascinating dude,
but I already knew that from
talking to him at Jujitsu and stuff,
but his writing is great.
Really interesting stuff.
And his writings about the porn business,
he's got this one story that he wrote
about a gang bang that is, she's like,
you fucking feel the loads on the floor.
Like as you're reading it,
you feel like the sticky room, you feel
the heat of all these guys behind him.
He does a masterful job of describing
this fucking incredibly Gonzo bizarre film
that they're doing there.
The me,
you would get paid 50
bucks and you wait in line.
You're like one of a hundred
guys waiting to, you know,
and you're jerking yourself off as you're
getting up to this girl who was just
covered in loads.
There's loads all over the ground.
Everywhere you walk there's loads,
right?
It's just like slippery and wet. You're
stepping, become everywhere, clothes,
everywhere you go.
There's this little signs that say
slippery when wet that they have to put up
around the woman.
Who's the first person
do that.
Was it Houston?
Was she the first or the week before was
probably before I was born because the
numbers keep going up, you know, at
one point in time it was like the,
the most people and I think she had
sex with like 200 Annabella Chong
and she's got a, it's a fascinating
documentary and like you,
she's very intelligent. She's
very unusual. Um, she was, uh,
I think she was a student at Ucla. I might
be wrong, Ucla or USC, but she was like,
she's an intelligent person and she
just had this weird desire to test the
boundaries of, of Er, you know,
acceptable sexuality by doing a gang
bang film. But it was really interesting.
Like it was a, it was cause it was, you
know, they're really like got into her,
her psychology
and who she is and like thought this is
a complex sort of a fucking case where
this woman wants to experience
the ultimate taboo. You know
and my agent called me
one time when he was like,
what's the most number of coffee all back
and one like one time and I was like I
don't fucking care, you
know. And he was like, no.
How about 11 I was like hi.
And like what difference does it make if
I fuck 11 dudes and the same day or in
pairs of you know one's
two's and three's on
I have to like the third
or fourth giant black cock.
You're numb lips when
started getting numb. No.
In your head though is 11 cock days.
That same amount of time
when you stretch your mouth.
I don't like that shit.
Would that seems like it would make
your lips number? Yeah, the huge mouth.
I do have a huge one.
It's good for my career comes in handy.
Now did you know that you wanted to be
a porn star when you were younger or is
this
no, I, I did.
I actually did like part of this as like
a bit of a with the midnight show go
guys. They did this your life.
Bob Guccione the midnight
show guys. What is it?
The UCB. Okay. You know,
how, how redneck and stuff.
And um,
I was like, oh, this is your
life Bob. Guccione and, and
I come out and I'm like, Oh,
I've been such a big fan of
you for forever and stuff.
Um, because when I, with,
uh, like in the first grade,
probably six years old,
I found a stack of playboy
magazines that were in the woods.
[inaudible] they were my uncles.
My uncle stayed with us part time hours,
you know, they were just like out in
his room. And I, and I remember I took,
I took one of those magazines to school
all to first grade and I was like,
this is what a naked lady looks like.
You know, I was like such a boy.
I was at a tomboy when I was that
age, but I, but even then I was like,
this is like what a sexy lady looks
like and I want to grow up and this is,
you know, I want to turn out like this
sexy lady. Like that's kind of like,
that appealed to me. I thought,
wow, she's, she's gorgeous.
She's all made up, she's,
you know, pretty and
naked, thin, nice boobs,
you know. And I was like, yeah, that like
really appealed to me. From your room
girls before you started doing movies.
Yeah. And I, and I also thought like
if I'm, if I don't turn out to be this,
I had like a fail safe in my brain.
I was like,
if I don't turn out to be a sexy lady,
I would at least want to be it with one,
like have one like us, my
girlfriend or like just, you know,
be in the presence of that because
it was appealing to me and I found it
attractive. Hmm. I'm a gay,
I came on your show because I want to say
that I'm out a big pussy Boehner and I
have a placebo owner and I take it.
So how did you get into your first film?
How did it come and get a hold of you?
I shoot seven years,
seven years,
24 when I got in and I'll be 32 inches.
Before that I was a stripper.
I was a drunk stripper too.
And how did, what did someone approach
you and say, Hey, I like the way, yeah,
no, absolutely not. No,
actually quit drinking.
I think I already told
this story on your show.
Maybe I quit drinking and I got fired
from being a stripper and I had been
thinking about applying to this porn
site because at fucking machines on it,
and this is how I got into the business.
I just have sure like morbid curiosity
of fucking a robot and just really
thinking about it. And he's like
masturbate in the shower, right
in a robot and a robot on the
inner. I heard it too. Totally.
And I heard it's awful, by the
way. What was your experience like?
Fucking Michigan. A lot of fun
to talk to girls. It's fucked.
Robots actually talked about
it today. No joke. Really bad.
It comes up all the time for
the face that people feel like they
can approach you and talk about fucking
robot.
Seems like the guy gotta be in it and
you were really kind of in a nerdy thing,
one of those spaces.
So yeah,
I just ended up applying to that site.
And that's how I got to do all that
bondage stuff is because it's the same
company ran hog tied and wired pussy
and all these holes and they even have a
female wrestling say ultimate surrender
where they have women wrestling. They,
the market cornered on kinky
pain shit. Yeah, absolutely. Wow.
What a weird business. Zimmer by the
armory up in San Francisco, they,
it's basically like a castle.
You know what I saw that
online or on a television show,
whether there was some sort of an expo
say on it about how much money they make
and how big their businesses enormous.
But they also,
they really improve that neighborhood.
They give back to their community. They
do a lot of stuff. Um, you know, they,
they open their uh, Joel Court to, uh,
you know, when they have parades and
shit. Like people can set up their floats.
They opened their,
their private business to the community
to do things or have swap meets inside
there.
So Nasco,
it's like a crazy jungle of naked
people running around and like
fucking right, like the people
in offices, like on computers.
San Francisco's
as a place where that would be accepted
in San Francisco's, in my opinion,
it's the most open minded
city and the whole,
you'd be surprised there were in the Wall
Street Journal I'm talking about like
people are there, we know there's
people fucking in there and yeah.
What does it matter? There's always
going to be some people like that,
but the amount of people that were sick,
where do you think their
neighbors came from?
Well that would support,
it would be much larger in San
Francisco than anywhere else.
Of course you're always going to come
across people that are very vocal that one
of the fight something,
but all in all San Francisco
is the most open minded city,
I think in the whole country.
Hmm.
Steady on that. I mean, could
you imagine that happening? Sure.
Cargo where there's a whole block filled
with people that are tying people up
and fucking them with
rubber robots and shit.
You know, that can only take
place in like San Francisco. Yeah.
I don't think there's any
other place that could,
that would accept something like New York
maybe. I mean, it seems like New York
has a lot of fucking of the bondage clubs,
New York and La,
or would it be only other options?
I think,
and I think that'd be met with a lot more
resistance in New York. La, Europe. Yeah.
Anywhere. Yeah. Berlin,
Budapest. Who was in, um, uh,
Berlin and I turned on the
television and um, no, not Berlin.
Oberhausen Oberhausen and I turned on
the television and there was no gang bang
on TV. Just a full on gang
bang. Let's just, no warning.
Just flipping through the
channels. Wow. The, yeah,
there's 10 people fucking in a
room. I'm like, wow, this is wild.
Like they have a totally
different attitude about it.
They just show the Shit on television.
It's pretty intense.
What are you doing it right?
Looking at,
I just looked at the basis for
Alice in chains died when Mike Star,
I don't know. Yeah. So you don't care.
He was on celebrity rehab.
I don't know if you remember him.
They found his body in Salt Lake City.
Well, Charlie, Shane lives winning.
He doesn't have tiger blood. I
don't know. I'm a Tanish DNA,
just not a freaking rock star from Mars.
Well,
I guess that guy probably didn't have to
pay girl $30,000 to have sex with them
either. Is probably has. He's got a lot of
money. Shit, I don't make things happen.
He's a rockstar.
Tracing is Charlie's Socom doughy like
slippery sweaty guy with five kids.
Charlie,
Charlie Sheen.
I would rather pick a rock star then
like somebody has fucking five kids.
But the crazy thing is the Charlie
Sheen calls himself a rock star,
but he's on this.
I like forgot that he was like the longest
family Sitcom, you know? I mean it's
like this really bland, you know,
kind of do it out to the walk. You
know? There's no edge to it. The egg,
like really vanilla, you know? And
it's, yeah, it's the number one comedy.
For some reason I talked
to my friend today,
he's watches it every week and I'm
like, really? You Watch that show
Charlie Sheen?
And like a gay guy?
Yeah, yeah. But he's like, well, it's
like, it's the exact same show every week,
you know? It's like the same premise
every week, but he's like, it's, it's,
it's one of those shows you could
just kind of watch, you know,
and it's easy to watch is smooth and
smooth and it's funny enough. Well,
you know what man?
I mean reality television has proven that
you don't really need to be that funny
to get people to watch it. Yeah. You
just need to, people people need,
it needs to come a part of their
everyday existence. They get like,
let's see what's going on.
And ice road truckers, shit.
The boys are on a slippery road.
Again, it becomes an ice road.
Truckers, there's a show about
slippery roads. Yeah, I mean,
and if that can exist,
you can have a show about anything and
a sitcom that's like been around for
awhile. It's fairly decent. It's
got a few good laughs in it,
but I bet for Charlie Sheen it's like
he's smoking coke and banging horse and
then he's going and doing this
super bland television show.
I bet that built up inside of him.
I bet that like made him
go more over the edge.
His character was pretty much himself
though in the, in that show. I mean,
it might've been a vanilla.
She'll be,
he still was a drunk guy that just
fucked a bunch of chicks. I mean, it
was like, it wasn't, he wasn't really off
his wrote a little sure. No, no, no. Sure.
It was, what can he acts like? Oh yeah,
you're gonna see Petunia
Wall Street trolley.
She didn't get out of his fucking ass off.
I didn't see Charlie Sheen back
motherfucker when he was young man.
Does he? Yeah. He's at
the office and he's like,
he's like the really hot guy that's in
trouble and the girls there with them,
she's original nose and she's
all excited about them. Yeah.
What was the movie that Charlie could
have kept that knows, right? Yeah.
There wasn't a bad,
it's just that's your nose hooker.
What was the movie that Charlie
Sheen shots. He was in scary.
You might do three or four.
Yeah.
What was the move that he tried to play
a played himself, but it played like him,
like he was friends with
the main character. Anything
get a John Malcovich. Yes.
John Malcovich.
That was an awesome
a cameo with him in it. Do you remember
that? No. Badly. As far as I can tell,
it closes itself, I think. Yeah, I
dunno. Charlie Sheen, you see platoon,
he's about him on the phone.
She Wall Street.
All fucking good. You know
what holds up dude? What?
Silence of the lambs holds the fucker.
Yeah,
I watched silence of the lambs Hila night.
It's a good goddamn movie still.
It's still holds up in the basket.
Yeah, it's good man. It's, it's,
it's well written. It's
well do girl. Dude.
Fucking Anthony Hopkins was a bad
mother fucker in that movie still.
You know, he's become like this guy
who does like these movies. It's sock.
You played the Wolf Man, Dad. You know
what I mean? The wolf man. Dad Demon
in every movie. You didn't
see the wolf man? No,
but there's also in Super Mario brothers.
It wasn't,
he was in something
fucking retarded like that.
Even in the wolf man, which is a terrible
movie. He's still like, has these scenes,
these moments where he's just
this bad motherfucker. He just,
he just doing crappy ass movies,
but you go back to silence of the lambs
and you realize what he's capable of.
If he gets a good script,
if he gets a good part,
Anthony Hopkins just smashes it out of
the ball half that Mu fucking smashes it.
Dude. He's so on like it crackles like
it makes you nervous for her while she's
talking to him like you fucking believe
a 100% that dude has murdered in his
mind when he's talking and he's talking
to Anthony Hopkins is thinking about
eating her.
He's thinking about cutting up.
He's allowing himself to go to some
crazy dark place where he's acting,
where you could tell like, that's really
what he's fucking thinking about, man.
He could turn it on. He can go
to that dark, crazy, psychotic,
worst case scenario, human example.
He can go there and his mind.
That's the difference, man. It's just
like comedy, man. It's like you, you,
you have to really be fucking
thinking about what you're saying.
There's not just the words and the noises
that represents certain things to me.
I got to know that you're thinking about
these things as you're saying them,
you know,
and that's the difference between a great
performance and a performance that's
just kind of mediocre and
can trick dummies. You know,
if someone's really nailing it.
I told her 22 year old actor
that just got here from La.
I was like acting as
pretending like you don't
know what you're going to say next.
And he got so offended and he
ended up moving back to Tennessee.
You can't take the heat, stay out
of the kitchen, bitch. Listen,
if that's all that set, this
fucking kid off. I bit on porn,
start telling them that acting is fake.
I've always said that if you can lie,
you can act and if you could
lie to a crazy girlfriend,
you can act under pressure. It's
not that hard. It's just pretending.
The hard thing is auditions.
Auditions are way harder because you're,
you have to pretend that it's happening
when you're in this really unrealistic
scenario. You're sitting in his office
and there's people in desks, chairs,
and they're facing you
with paper in their hand.
They're reading off the paper and you're
responding like it's really like this
is just, I'm good that you like, this
is just too strange. It just doesn't,
it doesn't ring real to me.
I don't really do well on
those types of scenarios.
Have you done any three d
movies for real? Yep. Yeah,
I just did three powerhouse
movies. And how did they, do they,
how do they differ from
like doing regular moves?
Do they make you do weird angles?
Like you have to spread your lips out
towards the cameras or something disrobe
or something.
You have like sort of throw your clothes
toward the camera or kind of like put
like one leg off the bed, like cut and
tangling toward the camera or something.
So what about
guy shoot loads? Do they shoot them at the
camera? I don't, I don't really notice.
I'm like kind of like in the zone. The
building, we'd have a pillow behind you.
You don't want to smash
your head on the headboard
to be like eight feet away for, for
the three d effect to work. Right.
So you gotta you gotta like clearly
you've never seen very far away. Hmm.
Never seen the distance very,
very far. What about some do,
what did some dude's eat like Peter
North and what does that guy eat?
So much sperm. So ridiculous
supplements. Is that what it is?
Zinc and I remember my boyfriend told me
also PC exercises like the muscle that
you use, like Stop Your pee. Oh
right. You know like, like a key goal.
Like a woman has a keigo muscle,
like the PC muscles.
What guys have I guess and
apparently if you just do that a lot,
it can strengthen the muscle
and you'll shoot further. Yeah,
that's in it right now. Practice it. Some
people just drink egg white egg whites.
Yeah. It looks like loads.
Loads will come out more
type shit. Yeah. Yeah. That's
probably the logical man.
It's probably some placebo effect. Right?
It's like the secret but with loads, yes.
Secretly did it on your vision board
you believe hello the longest load ever.
What do you think is the furthest
anyone's ever shoot a load?
Because I remember hitting hit myself
in the face once when I was 16 and being
shocked that it's shut off and I pulled
out and you know my, my high was down.
I was looking at it last me
right in the face. Don't do that.
I make it rain all the time.
Like I fucking why is this squirting on
my forehead out of nowhere really far.
Like what's the furthest
anybody's ever shot a load?
Spiderman was the furthest is
even five feet. I would be more,
I would say so I to be able to arc?
No,
it depends on like if there's a
headwind how long your Dick is.
Cause he guy like you know,
some giant Dick John Holmes type
would have a massive advantage. Yeah.
He's got a six inch reach advantage.
It's like John Jones as long arms loses
some pressure going through with that
launch mood. I like the way you're
thinking scientifically. Yeah. I like
but maybe a shorter barrel
you got it makes sense.
Right?
Like a 38 special but it seems like a
rifle would be much more accurate. Right?
Yeah. Here's a little tip, by the way, if
you put it a little bit of green again,
just the bumps out with like Saint
Patty's Day, you know Saint Patty's Day,
this is awesome. St Patty's, they put
a little bit of green of food coloring,
render dick before you have stacks. And
when you shoot out it actually is green.
Yeah,
that's good.
And what if you make a baby and it's
fucking looks like the Hawk baby cause I
could asshole.
What have you ruined the baby?
What if it gets to the SPERMATOZOA and
the spermatozoa get some crazy green
signal and shoots it into the egg
and some under the kid becomes great.
How would be fucking awesome? I wonder
if it's ever happened before. I mean,
I mean if any,
not that,
but I mean if anybody's ever like done
something where like the kid came out of
funky color because of that. Yeah. Hmm.
The fear that people will probably been
tricked to think that like maybe a white
woman having a half black baby
recessive gene back in
the old days. Right.
That's the story of Jesus.
Right?
I mean the story of Jesus most
likely is it marries a whore, right?
That's the story of Jesus, right?
Immaculate consumption. Right?
It's come on bitch. Yeah. What
kind of crazy shit is this?
But back then in the biblical days,
you just had to accept it.
Maybe she was raped by one of those
strong men. Maybe she'll want to rape her.
She asked you dressing
like that fucking robes.
I see you wrote it,
but she got a dirty ass too,
and back then the only lived to be like
30 days. You got to get your rapings in.
Why you could, oh my gosh, this
is horrible. You guys listen,
you had an electric charge inside
your asshole. This is horrible. Oh,
it's very so as this conversation,
yeah,
we've all agreed to be here and so
these people who have agreed to today,
I don't know,
2,360 of them right now are regretting it.
Oh,
you guys
cool. No, that's cool.
That's a lot of people.
It's actually going to be
a lot more than that one.
She wanted to hold thing
watching this right now.
You've done other podcasts before,
right?
You've done some do you
do Marin's to death squad
Marin?
I just did a the Nerdist podcast.
Oh, see you're, that's
what's fascinating about you.
It's like as far as like girls
that are in your business,
you're much more known for your
personality than any of the other ones.
And I think a lot of it is
those videos that you do,
you know where you break the Adam Sandler
video, you're breaking things down.
Yeah.
Like what else did you have a mail bag?
We read people's emails or
respond to them. I space
when I, when my space was before
it was like just a spam graveyard.
I would get like this really super
heinous hate mail that was so just so many
different levels of wrong and rude and
misspelled and English and English.
Yeah.
Just like really mean like I have you
get fucking cancer in your brain and dive
aids cause you're a whore and you
should accept Jesus in your life.
And it was like, that makes
no sense, right? Jesus Christ
would not fucking waste his time
to wish me dead of AIDS and cancer.
Like
try to help you out.
You Fuck Jesus Christ.
Ignorance as well.
There's a lot of that out there. You
know when you're allowed to be anonymous.
It's a very unknown,
normal situation.
It's an unnatural situation in human
behavior. We're supposed to like we, we,
we get rewards and we get pleasure and
we get all this from interacting with
each other.
But when you're interacting with each
other completely anonymously through like
wires and it's all ones and zeroes,
dude, I get it all day. Get
it every day on Twitter.
It was always some douchey due to so
something and I'm just block them like I'm
not,
I don't have time.
I'm not gonna argue with you so we
can't spare followers and have 237,000
something that I would rather have
one that falls me. That's nice.
Let's say 280 million people want it to
be cons. I would stop being on Twitter.
You know? It's fun though.
The, the cool people way, way,
way outnumber the shitheads. Yeah. And
like you get like really cool interacting.
Like last night I wrote on Twitter that
that Charlie sheen was reminded me of
hunters Thompson,
the way he's talking and I said we were
right outside of Barstow and the drugs
began to take hold and then I got like
hundreds and hundreds of tweets of people
quoting hunters Thompson lines from
the book. It was fucking great.
It was really good.
Let's get down to brass tax,
how much for the ape and they just kid
just kept coming over and over again.
I'm like,
this is fucking awesome.
Like this is like a really interesting
thing to interact with like minded people.
I have a message board and I want you
to be a part of it because you would fit
in like a fucking love.
It's a great message board and it's all
psychos and Weirdos and your moderator
board. It's on Joe Rogan. Dot.
Now we'll make you a rock.
I'll make you a moderator for sure.
We need more women.
We only have like a couple
of women moderators.
I've got to make sure that you
can, you can handle it. At first,
you can't snap and go crazy. Yeah.
You can't get a mortgage to people.
It's not worth it.
But when people are Douche bags,
I send them to the retard room.
I have two rooms I have like,
well one is like the main,
the main forum you can go to.
There's a combat sports for flick MMA
stuff. And then there's a, um, uh,
a regular forum and then there's a
podcast form and then there's special ed.
And Special Ed is if you're a douchebag,
if you act like a shithead,
you're stupid. Yeah. You want to insult
people all the time for no reason.
Get in the fucking toward been
dummy. Yeah. But because of that,
we've established a pattern and accepted
like levels of communication and
everybody's really cool there. It's
a fascinating fucking shit. Yeah.
And fascinating fucking shit
comes out of there. You know,
there's so many interesting,
there's this story that I read on there
the other day about these new fun guy
that they found in the Amazon rain
forest that turns ants into zombies,
takes over the ant's brain. Horrible.
Anyway. Well that's why they're there.
They're there to to keep
the amp population of bay.
This fungus grows inside of dance
body wires right out of its head,
grows out of its head after it's dead was
a amp juice out of it.
It also causes other ants to cannibalize.
They cannibalize each other and the,
there's four different types of them and
then when one bullet ant will find that
this fungus has infected,
they will have their own way and take a
deep into the woods. Even in the jungle.
No, it's like they, they
know what the fuck does.
A fascinating shit on life narrated
by Oprah Winfrey. Really. I think the,
I think that was, it was like the
generic version of planet earth. Okay.
Badass bitch.
I was watching,
I watched the Oprah
network fascinating to me.
I watched it the other day.
Yeah.
I got a TV in my gym and I
was working out in the gym.
I was on the window and I was watching
the Oprah network and I was watching her.
She was just that.
She was considering whether or not you
should have Nadia [inaudible] on our show,
whether they should help her and they
decided to get someone to come on and help
her financially help her answer.
Interesting. No, it's interesting.
Elixia into Oprah like how she talks and
how she thinks like you get behind that
woman like she's like,
she really is all about reaching out and
helping people be the best person they
they they can be and love. Like that's
really what she's into it, right?
Like it's so easy to criticize her.
It's so like the Cliche,
she's on TV all the time, you know? She's,
it's like she's an easy target but
when you look at like what she does,
like she is bad mother fucker. Yeah, sure.
Oprah is like,
everyone would hate the shit out of her
if she was like with the amount of money
that she has, if she was, if she was
like being like Charlie Sheen is,
people would be like fuck you,
you black bench.
I got this bitch life. Imagine if she
was talking about that rock star. Like,
I'm like a freaking rock star from Mars
with my friends. If anybody's a
rock star from Mars, it's Oprah.
You know what I mean?
She has some man that's just like in
the shadows and shuts his whole that God
isn't even talking less spoken to
Steadman sits around and waits.
He waits three paces behind her and he
doesn't say shit unless she asks him a
question. I bet Oprah has a
very big area anymore. Yeah.
I don't think they are. Kale
finally forced it out. Yeah,
I think that full Gail.
That's the, that's the rumor, right?
That's what's up. That's cool. I mean the,
the Odin station has like
a bunch of gay friendly,
they had a great show the other day.
I was on the Oprah network and it
was all about transsexuals. Yeah.
It was a very eye opening
man to look into it.
Cause I have a friend whose son
is, uh, becoming a transsexual. Um,
his son is about to change
from Amanda to a woman.
And it's really strange because it sounds
about the change for a man to a woman
and his son is like into girl still,
so sun is like becoming a lesbian.
Very, very bizarre. And
he's going to go apparently,
I don't know if he's going
to go through the operator,
I don't know what the
entire full story is,
but they had this whole show dedicated
to it and they had some kids,
I mean there was a boy that
was like a little boy. Okay.
He looked like he was like seven or eight
years old and he was wearing a dress
and he wanted to be a girl
know and I'm like, whoa. Like
does the younger you start,
the more convincing you be if you
just avoid going through the
whole male puberty thing,
you stand a chance of being a more
convincing women after your transition.
Yeah, maybe. I mean if you can really be
sure of your choice at that young an age,
but it's God,
you talked to the parents and it's like
very convincing what they're saying.
It's not like it's so easy.
If you're a normal gender oriented,
you're like seven years old and you're
like, I'm challenged, I'm transgender.
It's not a phase.
It's not a fucking,
I agree with you,
but who knows if it's a part of what's
going on as you're young and then as your
hormones kick in as you become 18 and
19 maybe. See, no, I'm just a gay man.
You know? Maybe. Maybe
it's like that simple.
Maybe like you have transitioned
straight man. Right.
What I'm saying is I don't,
I don't think you should
really necessarily be fucking
with your hormones until
they settle in. I mean, I can understand
someone being a grown adult and saying,
okay, I want to be a woman.
I've faked this long too long.
This is what I want to do.
But when you're a child, shit,
I don't even know what the
fuck I was gonna I mean, God,
could you imagine if you had a chance,
you know, like that's probably normal
for straight dudes. You know, what,
if I turned out to be like a
completely straight person,
I probably wouldn't have been like lusting
over nudie magazines and like showing
them to people and being like thank you
have to cut a little gay change like a
little gay gay girl.
When you were talking about
children, I think you have to
account for change, you know,
I'm not saying you should
completely dis this, you know,
just credit the idea that this is
really a girl trapped in a boy's body,
but I'm saying you have to account for
changes like as far as like adding to
their body and stuff like that.
Seems like a really radical choice.
And one of these kids
was like 10 years old,
crazy medicine and their kids and there's
like whatever, you know kitty pro.
Right. You know, which is
another fascinating good.
It's better. I think it was,
would it be better if a child was like,
I know this about myself and instead of
like some going, my kid is unreasonable.
Like because they let the TV babysit
it and then pump your kid full over the
lend because they're hyper,
they're just maybe undisciplined.
They used to live down the street that
was riddling up their kid and it was
[inaudible].
That's probably fucking your kid up more
than listening to them when they tried
to identify their sexuality
or their gender, right?
The kid was on a bad kid there. The
parents were terrible. They were terrible.
A parenting and the kid was lost and the
kid always seemed to me like they just
wanted someone to tell them what was up,
give them a hug,
tell them what was that they did.
There were two of the most lost kids
ever because their parents were a fucking
holy wreck right here.
Would yell at each other in
public and it was just a disaster.
And they started picking their kids up
and it was like I was living next door to
zombies. It's like looking
at us like did the Zombie,
but these people have
been taken over by spores,
I mean that those pills might as well be
the fucking spores that Jack those ants.
Right.
The same thing it just takes,
so it's a chemical thing that happens to
a kid where it takes over their brain,
rewires it and makes them think
and behave totally differently.
And then all of a sudden these kids were
like these little slap jobs on base.
I was like, wow, they don neuter their
fucking kids brains. Yeah. Yeah. You know,
it's fucking crazy. Crazy how easy
it is to have that sort of, that,
that sort of power to just do that to
your kids. I know to another person,
I know his kid
is not fucked up and he's got his kid
on some sort of riddle and shit because
his kids too active
cause his kid is fucking
alive and they're older.
They didn't have the kid until they were
like in their 50s they adopted them.
They can't keep up at all. So they
have this fucking can't medicate it.
We want to treat him to the stove,
whatever kid is nothing.
It's nothing wrong with this kid.
I've talked to him.
He's just a wild little motherfucker.
Sure. You know, and so what are they good?
They got him all pilled up. It's like,
all right, good luck. What
is, how many generations?
If we had of people that were pilled
up like this though? Oh, forever. No,
I don't think so.
We're social engineering mean PROZAC
came into to mind when I was a,
I believe when I was
in high school as well,
first time in the first war, that was like
institutionalizing people in the body.
Lobotomizing people in shock. There
should be like a blue iris. Right.
But she was never normal after that,
but it's never reached extent to,
but the lawyers get, she had
electroshock therapy repeatedly. Oh Wow.
Didn't know that.
Try to cure a porn.
Yeah. A lot of people don't know who blue
irises. She's on the Howard stern show,
like an old school porn stars and
what she did and she passed away.
She passed away. Yeah. Yeah.
But this is a difference between the
few people that are so completely out of
control that you need to
be institutionalized to
people that don't like their
job.
So they give you a pill so you don't feel
like shit at the end of the day every
day. Because there's a lot of
people that are just doing that.
They're physically not healthy,
their diet sucks,
they don't exercise and they do a job
that sucks and they wonder why they feel
depressed at the end of the day. I mean,
it's real simple. You don't need Prozac.
You need a new fucking life. I
mean, that's what you need to do.
You need to eat to figure out what the
fuck you really want to do and realize
that you're only here
for x amount of years,
so the more time you spend not moving in
the direction of your actual interests,
the more you're going to fucking hate
yourself. You're going to be depressed.
It's just natural. But they don't say
that. They give you some fucking pills.
There's a lot of people that need those.
Totally shutting Robin take over Charlie's
shit. That's why I joined our call. Oh,
you want to do,
you want to be and you can totally,
that might be something
like that wasn't water
funny checks and you're totally invited.
Yeah.
If you want to be in our call at anytime,
definitely are called is a deal is just
don't be a Douche bag. It's so simple.
I don't know kind of one of bags. Will
you do our little, but it's natural.
Look at what you do. Look at how
many people are yelling at you.
Look at how many people point at you
and sending you shitty emails all day.
It's national to be on the defensive
and start fucking with Jennifer Aniston.
I think it's so funny cause Cha Chelsea
handler was like Angelina Jolie is a
current because you're like with
Jennifer Aniston. Oh really? I was like,
Oh look at Chelsea handler's
sticking off with Jennifer instead.
I'm like Chelsea forever.
Oh my God.
Since the early days of a, I wrote one
of the, um, the reviews of her book,
her first book was a my
horizontal life. Yeah. She's a,
I'd love party girls. To me. I think the
party, it takes every kind of people.
If this is on,
can the people do,
when are you going to
get her on the podcast?
We needed to get in front of way too busy.
I wouldn't even ask her.
She's got a sitcom going on.
She's got some sort
of a reality show going on about her
show and then she's got her show.
She's way too,
it's already a show show,
but she's got a show.
I mean that's what it
is. Why not? Fuck it.
She's got an interesting people behind
the scenes. She wants to showcases it,
including our friend I
really good friend Eva.
She's on that show from Denver. He used
to work [inaudible] assistant. I thought,
Oh yeah,
he was the best. I love that check.
I haven't talked to her forever.
She was this really cool trick that
worked for the Denver comedy works,
just super on the ball and super friendly.
She used to take us to media like one of
the nicest people ever and then became
friends with Chelsea and
she was just such a diamond.
It was just waiting for someone to come.
Malonga Scoop Robert.
Like I told her like if she moved to La,
I would give her a job as an assistant.
I'm like, you're the coolest chick ever.
I've never even thought about having
an assistant because it seems so
preposterous that you really,
you can't wait. What the fuck?
You got a business manager. You
also need the assessment. You could,
you'll get me a latte. You get Outta
here. That's ridiculous it for her.
I would do it. Just the two year old.
Get Your Latte, watch what happens.
Come back screaming and covered in burns.
Two year olds,
load, dishwasher. Sure.
Mow the lawn. Have Fun. You know,
get 'em a riding mower. Right. My
brother loved that when we were a kid.
My parents bought me this thing so I
could mow the law. I could ride at,
I can drive this thing. He was
so, he was actually working well.
We love done mowing the lawn.
There's an aesthetic sense of
pleasure and sense of accomplishment,
like you've created something visually
that's pretty, it's kind of an art form.
I used to work for a landscaper.
Did you? I fucking hated my hardest.
I only worked for a landscaper for a
whole week and he let me go because I kept
burning too many lawns.
What I mean is that you fuck up,
you don't know how to new
use the lawnmower that well
and you scalped along and
I scalped a couple of
lawns and he got mad at me.
It was hard fucking work and what it
paid pretty decent for what it was.
But you worked every God Damn
Day from six 30 in the morning.
You showed up at work and you work till
three o'clock in the afternoon and there
was a gang of fucking house system Mo.
You had a whole route of houses and you
got to mow their lawn and chop trees
down. Shit, it's backbreaking fucking
war and everybody's a douchebag.
You working with mostly like there was
like a few guys that were kind of cool,
but there was a lot of like,
you know,
there's a lot of resentment to anybody
new that was coming along that might
possibly take this shitty job away.
It was real weird man.
Terrorism, junkyard dog type of Shit.
Labors and hard man getting a job
as a laborer in any sort of realm
construction or that's one of the most,
the best ways to get motivated to
get your shit together as a guy.
Get a fucking job carrying bricks
around all day and you know,
get a job where you realize
what work really is.
When you realize what it really feels
like to be exhausted for $5 an hour,
$5 an hour, and you're
carrying bricks all day. I have
no idea what that would be like.
Ever worse. Yeah, but it makes you,
I think about that shit all the time.
If I ever think about like not writing
or ever think about not working out or
not getting the tank
or anything like that,
I don't think about working on a
construction site and carrying bricks and
cinder blocks and bags of cement.
I'll think about a hard,
that wasn't like what I have to do.
I just gotta get up and work at something
awesome. Just get up bitch. You know,
it's like this is a lot harder things
you could be doing if you don't have that
experience though. Some fucking
terrible thing. You know,
like for you when you were done with
all the electrocution is up the asshole
like going to regular porn, it
must've been like, God damn,
this is a cakewalk I'll have
to do is blow some money.
Well yeah,
no actually there's a little bit of a
transition that's happening in porn right
now where uh,
they're kind of going away from that.
Like my blonde wife is getting fucked
by six black guys to like more of,
wait a minute, why are they
stopping as well? That's been
phased out now. Like man,
a cheeseburger at a, at a
taste. They're making parodies.
They're making romance movies that
are like Romance, Romance, novel,
like Romcom type of, how many
vampire points are there? A lot.
They did true blood
parody at new sensations.
I mean the twilight parody they made,
I dunno,
they made a parody of
absolutely everything.
Yeah. Some dude on my message board
as an Avatar parody and it's a girl.
She's got the Avatar of face and
she's getting her mouth fucked. Yeah,
and that's his, his, his avatar. Yeah.
They're going to do a new avatar is going
to be underwater. You heard about that?
Should I lately?
Have you seen the preview for this new
movie where it's a bunch of chicks with
guns on the poster? Sucker
Punch? Yeah. Yeah. What the fuck?
I haven't seen the preview it, but those
posters look amazing. Watchmen. Ish. Yeah,
same director. It looks
complete fantasy, you know,
crazy comic book type.
I liked that man meets,
you don't need to be a movie to be
realistic. Like when people go like,
why do you like like fantasy movies
and monster movies with my kids.
That's what I want to be entertained.
I don't want you to depress me with some
real story about a girl's parents get
killed in a car crash. Like stop.
Stop pissing on my parade, Dude.
Show me some monsters and some lasers
and some spaceships and aliens.
Did you ever see Scott Pilgrim?
Did you ever end up? No, I
haven't seen it yet, man.
Did you see it? Yeah, I rewatched that
the other day. Fucking loved it again.
That is just a fun fucking movie.
Really.
I don't know if you would like it though.
I don't know if you would like it,
but I was like,
they don't even like each other movie
recently that you liked it. I didn't like,
can you even think of
one? Uh Oh ma'am. No,
I didn't really love enter the void. But
yeah, I wasn't in the end of the void,
but that's also because I've actually
done DMT and I'm like this is the
representation of it as
soul. So simple. And it was,
there was a lot of
problems with that movie,
but I just thought it was cool
with the visual effects. Yeah.
What I thought was cool was
the first person perspective.
I thought that was really
interesting. Yeah, I thought that was,
I felt like I was really that guy,
you know, if you really got into it.
I mean I like seeing it through like
almost like a video game with first person
shooter perspective. Yeah. I
thought that was kind of cool.
And there's parts of it I liked,
but it was just too much.
I didn't see anything that was
like Oscar movies. I didn't, yeah.
No,
I think king speeds.
Is that about Martin Luther King
or what the fuck is that about?
What is it about?
It's about a dog,
the barks and the fog named king ice.
Where's the biggest fight card? It's
a talking dog. Maybe Brian Roberts.
The rottweiler. Yeah. I don't know
what the fuck. It's fine. I don't care.
I want to see, I don't want
to see any movies. I'm waiting
for cowboys and aliens.
I don't want to see any movies
that are real. This, this um,
movie that I saw on the adjustment
bureau. Totally. Science fiction.
Crazy fucking man. Good, good. Give me
more on that. Give me more fake shit.
I don't want to see real shit.
I know this is not interesting to me.
Like here's a relationship that
they had yet. Maybe if you want,
throw me some crazy godfather
type gangster period piece
where it's not today's
reality. So can I can get into that
kind of, it's a long time ago. Reality,
you know?
But I don't,
I'm not into any real movies where people
get depressed in real life. Like stop.
I don't even watch movies that
have people in them anymore.
I just stick to just say animation.
Yeah.
Like in that Mega Mind Three d movie,
Tina Fey was like really hard as the curt
tune. Right. And it was just like, cool.
I can like think this girl's really
super high instead of like the sticky,
like I'm, I'm not hot Tina Fey.
Haha. I wear glasses. I'm not hot.
Right.
First Co animated movie that I ever saw
that was an adult movie was wizards.
Did you ever see what it was great man.
I had it on DVD,
like really kind of recently.
I T I can't find it.
I was looking forward to my house. It's
a Ralph, what is his name? Bach Bach Ski.
Yeah, the guy. The guy's name. The
guy that did def dealer. Right?
No wait. Am I thinking of
somebody else? I don't know.
It was just really cool science fiction,
sort of futuristic animated
movie. You know, they don't,
they don't do too many of those, but
they're pretty dope. When they do like,
do you ever see heavy metal? Oh
yeah, absolutely. It's bad ass.
I love with that chicken.
That movie were you? Yeah.
No. It's even funnier or awesome.
Or is the heavy metal, uh,
inspired a south park where they did it
did don't like pretty much heavy metal
style cartoon and like the whole
animation will look like that.
Do you ever see that episode?
Fucking it?
No.
I need to catch up on South Park's man.
I heard that they're going to
do a Charlie Sheen, a parody,
which I cannot fucking wait for. Of course
they're going to, they couldn't not.
They love making fun of people. Did
the best at it. Are you on that? No,
I haven't been. I think they
made fun of you on that. Maybe.
Maybe. No, I don't think American dad
has. If they did, I would be honored.
As long as they weren't too cruel. Please.
Gentle. I'm a gentle soul and a big fan,
but what they did,
the Crossman Sia was the most ruthless
shit I'd ever seen in my life.
They beat him to death with a baseball
bat and shoved frozen fish sticks in his
necklace. So awesome. But
they were broken down like
I know it can be a comedian.
That'd be funny.
It was this the most ruthless
takedown I've ever seen.
The Kanye was even funny to the gay
fish. Their genius man. The fucking,
how about the Tom Cruise trapped in the
closet? Shit. Yeah. God Damn Dude. They,
they, they break everybody
down, but they're the past man.
There's nothing like that.
So we all agree. Didn't win.
Didn't they get, um, didn't,
what the fuck's his name?
Isaac Hayes. Didn't he?
He was the one he used to be the
chef or is it as a case? Yeah.
Didn't he stop doing it when there was
some sort of a show on Scientology? Yeah.
That is so crazy.
Isn't it fast?
It was okay when they made fun of
everybody else's lifestyle and religion
forever. He, he now he's
dead, so fuck you. I the case
maybe. Maybe it wasn't even that
great. Dan is here. Mom surfaces.
At the end of the podcast,
she shows a true colors.
We're going to turn it around.
Dana,
we're going to put you on a positive path.
I'm going to be a successful
standup comedian. Ouch.
I'm going to be a year from now.
We're going to be looking back at this
moment and then what? I did the podcast,
that's when it all fucking came together.
Yeah, you're supposed to be a comedian.
It doesn't let you be goddamn
invulnerable up there.
Everything that you've done and
how you've exposed publicly,
you should be goddamn in vulnerable
up there. You got to be a goddess.
You have control and dominate.
This is the d,
the beginning.
Today we launch.
It's so hard to heal. Better way
to end this fucking show. Uh,
we will be back Thursday with
a young and talented Andy.
Dick will join us on the podcast.
He's doing it from this studio.
This is Rogan is not excited about
Auntie Jackie House, so we might have to,
but he has been sober for like four weeks.
I don't know.
Oh yeah,
we'll do the thing about Andy.
See you just never know when you're gonna
run into it with whiskey on his breath,
you're like, fuck. He was at the Avn
awards. He got tossed out. Right.
Was He fucked up?
I don't know.
I saw him and he was just like Wednesday
raw or whatever. So he was hammered.
Oh,
that's right.
I guess I can only assume like we were
doing some kind of a mirroring exercise.
Andy Beck and I were doing
the exact same thing.
He talked about it on the
Greg Fitzsimmons show.
He talked about it on Greg Fitzsimmons
is a serious show. Yeah. And he said,
you know,
that he just got out of control and it
was like the wheels fell off at the end,
but it was a great time before that.
But then it looks so bad when
people are looking back on it. Yeah.
One other thing,
he had a really,
we got to pay attention to what you're,
what you look like.
People know who you are, you know,
basically if people know who you are.
Yeah. But once you, I an addict,
you know, but I go like, am I,
are both my shoes on or like am I,
have I said anything offensive
or or anything to anyone.
Like how am I controlling myself? Like
when you're partying? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I drink like five whiskey drinks and
I was wearing a gown and like I waited
until no one was around and I took my
dress off and the mirage or the pumps
parking structure and I threw it in the
back of my car and went back to my own
hotel naked.
I like just put on whatever is in my car.
You carry clothes around with you and
just all the time. Yeah. You never know.
Well we were like in Vegas, so
you know, you got shit everywhere.
I'd have like a baseball hat and
experts just like a where I slept.
I slept in a bowling alley last
night in Canoga Park. What I had,
but it's a long story.
What's Andy Dick?
No bye bye bye.
It was so great because I had,
not only did I have wore a coat
because it was cold kind of cold.
I had sleeping bags.
I had airplane pillows from
traveling so much and it was her.
She slept in a bowling alley parking lot
of bowling alley. What the fuck, Brian?
It was great. It's just
good night, huh? No, no.
I actually didn't even drink last night
is I think young lad. It's and love,
I think. No, no, no, no, no. It's not
even that. No, no. It wasn't even that.
So it's some girl had bowling alley.
No long story.
It's young love and a parking lot.
That's when you,
you don't mind sleeping outside
when you're in love. Yeah. But
practical when you're in love,
Dana, I'll have to tell you that.
I'll never experience it.
I mean, they were right.
Those motherfuckers, it was all right.
Ladies and gentlemen, this weekend,
Friday night and Saturday night, we were
at the comedy and Magic Club next week,
Friday night at Gotham in New York City.
Um, Brian also has a podcast of his own,
it's called the death squad.
You can subscribe to it on
Itunes and Dana has been on it.
Sam Tripoli's on it all the time.
It's a,
a plethora of young talented comedians
and they do a bunch of different
podcasts,
so it's not just one.
And you can go on the iTunes page and
find out which they are or go to desk
squad.tv and just subscribe the death
squad on iTunes and it's a very highly
ranked now. It's like in the top
20 of iTunes comedy. So it's good.
It's really good too. It's
really interesting. Um, so,
uh, we'll be back on Thursday,
like I said with any Dick.
Thank you everybody for everything and
thanks for tuning in and thanks for being
just cool motherfuckers.
All right, I love you. Oh,
go to a flashlight.com
and go to Joe Rogan. Dot.
Enter entering the code name Rogan.
Get yourself some discounted
jerk off material.
Do you have a rubber fleshlight yet?
Um, no, and I've been bringing
it up every time to with
them. Well, can I? No, no, no.
I'm all rejection letter from
flashlight will make this happen. Dude,
you just got in with the
right crowd. Oh, okay.
It could be like the extra
extra big flashlight. Giant.
Roxanne. Thanks. Thanks. This jihad
[inaudible].