Freak bitches.
Yeah,
like the duke boys are supposed to be
like these heart of gold moonshiners
don't want to fuck their cousin.
I'm not buying it.
I would be like,
we're cousins.
Look at this bitch.
She's nobody's fucking daisy.
Okay.
She can't get a goddamn boyfriend.
She's running around her because she
likes.
She cleaned.
She likes cletus.
She could.
She make it more obvious.
She's cut the legs off short so you can
just finger her swing.
She's there for you.
She's.
She's hacking in short.
It's like no girl.
Ever ever done that ever.
Even now it's like God damn.
And she was doing it when no one was
doing it and she was wearing a men's
shirts like she just got done fucking
touch a man's shirt on like your shirt.
She could be wearing your shirt buttons
down to the fifth button.
Tied off on the bottom.
Come on son.
She's got a man's shirt on.
Why is that super hot girl have almost.
That ain't number one.
Bonus number two,
dare you.
You don't even know your history.
So we're the number two boats.
That's,
that's him.
And it's been a while.
Tom Wolf,
PAC man,
that hair.
Those are the number two.
No,
these are still.
People Go God,
look at those shorts.
Cry.
She was hot pink.
This makes me nervous.
Just looking at him.
You could see their fucking junk in
their pants.
Yeah,
they're dicks was hard as rocks.
Oh my God.
And they're not even related to her
because not.
Does she have camel toe on that?
She's got at the beginning of one.
Just the beginning of badge.
Outline everything.
You could see the slice.
Yeah.
They had grandma panties back then.
Oh,
guess who doesn't care about me?
Are you a panties guy?
What do you mean you like?
I like when girls with dogs don't like
granny panties.
I think girlfriend.
Nothing.
Say it.
Somebody got
constraining yourself.
So they were moonshiners with a heart of
gold but never got any pussy.
And they were beautiful man.
Beautiful men and their hot cousin.
It was a show where no one fucked.
It was the most ridiculous world.
That was way more ridiculous in the fact
that they were shooting arrows with,
with lightning,
with a dynamite at the end of it,
and they didn't have guns because they
did time for fucking running moonshine,
but the man should let them do what they
do down here and Hazard County.
We got our own rules,
man.
That was nobody.
Nobody fucked.
Yeah.
You think fucking boss hog would have
had a slew of hookers.
Did she should have all do that,
move that show now in reality like this
is what it would be like.
Well,
let's think about her.
She was the only hot girl in the show
ever.
Look who she should have been one of the
grossest women of all time.
That's his wife.
How dare you.
He would have been here for a woman in a
gray color.
Fucking or he would have been fucking
her uncle.
Jesse would've fucked.
Everybody would fucked to cletus
scooter.
Boss Hog definitely would.
I definitely would have had her on the
payroll.
She'd been right next to him.
That cadillac with the bull horns on the
front of it,
but she came on to the other guy.
Oh,
she was always coming on as gay as fuck.
And he was comfortable by it because
Jesus was strong in his life.
That's why cletus didn't want to admit
it.
When I was a kid,
my dad was rich and he would carry like
$15,000 around in his wallet.
He's like ball and big money,
you know?
Did he have like crazy shoes?
And like he wore,
he wore a lot of like stupid looking
silk shirts and shit.
He looked like some kind of decadent
Roman emperor and he always had like big
orgies at his house to.
Who'd you dad is cool.
He was cool.
What did he do for a living?
He was pretty much a con man.
Whoa.
Really?
Where,
uh,
he started as a diploma mill called
Lasalle University.
Did you?
Shit,
I don't believe you,
but.
No,
no,
they uh,
he just started.
He started a fake university degree
mill,
you know,
I mean,
it kind of,
you could say in some ways maybe it was
fake or maybe it was just a precursor to
things like Phoenix University of
Phoenix that just,
you know,
but his real problem wasn't the school
it,
they've never.
The government never went after him and
said,
you're running a scam school.
The government went after him for,
for,
you know,
committing mail fraud and for um,
a tax evasion was the big one because he
didn't feel like he had to pay any taxes
they felt otherwise.
So he ended up in jail for um,
you know,
three or four years over that.
Well actually it was sentenced to five
years,
but then he claimed to be a drug addict
even though he wasn't,
never did drugs and they gave him some
time off his sentence from enrolling in
a drug treatment program.
God,
that's awesome.
He was always looking for the angles.
I wish I had that ability like my dad
did.
Is he still around?
No,
he's dead.
Is your mom still around?
Yes.
When you talk to your mom about him,
like,
like how long were they together?
Uh,
you know,
I think about maybe eight or nine years.
Wow.
What a,
what a blessed be like to be a woman and
to have a child with a crazy man who's
running around just scamming people and
hustling.
You know what I mean?
It wasn't like he was really scamming
people.
He was actually helping people to scam
employers if point they know that the
degree is fucking bogus.
Right.
That's a good point actually.
So they.
And actually it was crazy because when
it was exposed there was like
congressman and you know,
uh,
they got their degree,
like ceos of major companies that all
had degrees from Lasalle University.
Super successful even with fake degrees.
Yeah.
That's hilarious.
Well,
you know what I mean.
Degrees are bullshit anyway.
Well,
they certainly are not the only limiting
factor in someone's competency.
Yeah.
I mean,
especially not for like business or
something science.
Maybe that's a different story.
Oh,
for sure.
Medicine.
Yeah.
You want a real doctor?
I don't want,
you know,
a doctor with a Lasalle medical degree
with an incomplete ideas.
I don't think he,
uh,
he,
he issued medical degrees though.
Well,
either way,
that's not the most egregious example of
someone being a con person.
That's not.
I mean,
uh,
there's probably way worse things,
but you know what I mean.
Yeah.
But he was interesting guy though.
Yeah,
there he is.
Robocop.
Wow.
He had a dope outfit to the new robocop.
I never saw.
I wasn't really into the new outfit that
you just didn't see.
This is the new one.
Did you watch the new one?
No,
I didn't know either.
I think that is the new one.
I met that dude.
Yeah.
See why?
Why does he have his hands covered?
I'm gonna.
Chop your hands off.
We've got to have your hands covered.
How come your mouth isn't covered
either?
I'll shoot you right in.
The mouth.
Will have identified the weak spots.
Yeah.
You don't want to have a,
an exposed mouth hole.
Yeah.
Why would you ever have your exposed
mouth?
Yeah.
He's got his whole face.
His whole faith is ready to be shot
because I'm assuming there's a brain
back there,
right?
You've got skin,
so there's no.
I'm gonna.
Shoot the right through your eyeballs.
I your brain.
So stupid.
You know,
like he's got like a regular human
mouth.
Why would you have that?
When everything else is protected,
you can't project.
You'll have some sort of a speaker on
the outside.
There's so many veins and important
arteries that run around the neck here.
How's he going to eat with no teeth
going to get shot in the face with a
Canon in Detroit to do,
you know,
and it seems like the best place to put
it in today.
It is.
Yeah,
right.
No one seems to have seen this movie.
It must have been a robo flop.
Yeah,
he out.
He had it.
He delivered it.
You were stunned and now you're
defensive and now it's not true.
I actually went and saw the movie and I
eat a lot of popcorn during it.
I was a Robo slop.
Come on,
Robo stop.
He doubled
Queen Anne House in here.
Somebody grab us a Robo.
Oh,
get your guys' expectations are too high
here.
Robo.
Putting,
battling,
gross paddle,
but red badges.
One to year.
I lost one to me.
He did.
Oh,
how?
Why do you keep making do with
what I do?
I go,
how would you like me to react?
I'll do whatever you like.
I don't know.
Oh,
la La,
la,
la La la La.
Oh no,
that's the pun.
Laugh right now.
Could you imagine
cracks upon onstage and the whole cargo?
Ah,
LA,
la,
la.
That would be awesome.
Dude.
You're fucking manifested.
You better be careful what you wish for
full,
but you wishful young Tony.