The joe rogan experience.
A Gal that I was dating once said to me,
never trust a girl,
doesn't have any girlfriends.
And I said,
why do you say that?
And she goes,
because,
okay,
every girl knows that guys want to fuck
them,
right?
Yeah.
And I go,
yeah.
And I go and the girls don't want to
fuck yet.
Right?
And she goes,
yeah.
She goes,
well,
how come they don't like you
girls don't like that girl.
She doesn't have any girlfriends.
So it's one or two things have happened.
Either you just moved into town or you
fucked everybody's boyfriend.
Shit.
And I just looked at,
I'm like,
this bitch is too smart.
I'm an 18 at least 18% more chimpanzee
though,
Dude,
I've gotta get Outta here.
Fuck you.
I'm a kiss on the cheek.
And then the other cig Ma don't hit me.
I got to go.
That should be a short series,
Joe Rogan's defining moments
a moment like that.
That was a good one,
man.
Some serious knowledge on me.
She dropped some serious knowledge on
me.
She looked me in the eyes when she said
it too.
It's like a really strong move.
She goes,
don't ever trust a girl who doesn't have
any girlfriends.
And I remember seeing him,
cause I,
I remember saying to our goal,
I was like cocky because I was 24 when
she said this.
And I was like,
why?
What the fuck you buy?
Well,
who is say,
you know,
what about,
some girls are assholes.
And,
and then I just,
you know,
when she,
after she said that,
she's like,
the girls know who you are.
They know who you are.
And I just went,
wow,
that can't even argue with you.
Um,
the only equivalent I have to that,
and I hate to use his name twice and one
podcast,
Anthony Bordain,
Patrice,
I fucking wish I anymore beautiful trees
said to me one night,
I was talking to his black dude,
and we're sitting in the back of the
envelope,
the Boston comedy club.
We're sitting down,
there's a bench in the corner by the
window and we're sitting,
talking,
we're sitting talking,
and he's watching me the whole time.
And I'd just recently tried to grow a
beard for the first time.
And,
uh,
we get up,
the guy gets up and he moves and patrice
sits down next to me was the fuck you
doing talking to him.
I said,
what?
He goes,
don't ever talk to a black man that
doesn't have facial hair.
What's this have to do with it?
And he goes,
man,
he's trying to fuck you.
Any black man
has facial hair,
facial hair,
fucking great.
And then I started looking around at
every black dude I knew how facial hair.
It was like the greatest little fucking
patrice didn't even believe that.
He was only saying that because it was
the funny thing.
It was a bug with me.
And at the same time he goes,
you got to learn how to trim your lip.
Yup.
Cause I,
I was white guys.
We'll let the hair grow into their lip
and black guys don't do that.
Dates up on the lip.
But uh,
yeah,
these people,
one of the weird things about
psychedelics is people always,
even if it was one,
the most profound
experiences ever,
and one most amazing experiences ever,
people would tell you.
Yeah.
But it was just your mind playing tricks
on you.
Like it doesn't matter and you can go.
Okay.
But it's whether it was,
whether I really did travel to another
dimension and communicate with infinite
beings that were made out of love and
understanding who told me the secret to
life is positive energy and positive.
Even if it was just my imagination,
I still experienced it.
I experienced it as if it was real.
So whether it was real or whether it
wasn't real,
I get the exact same result.
Something happened that was unbelievably
incredible.
It took me to someplace that was
infinitely beautiful and then something
happened to me.
Like either that happened or it didn't
happen.
Well definitely happened.
It doesn't matter if it was imaginary.
It doesn't matter if it was only inside
my head.
The whole world comes out of the inside
of your head.
When we were kids,
I remember when I was a kid,
they would say like,
ah,
he's got such an imagination.
That's one.
It was talking about kids who were
liars,
you know?
That's how people treated the
imagination and the kids were just
fevers.
You know,
because that's imagination to some
people.
You know,
some people they didn't think it was
something to be encouraged,
but it's really where everything comes
from.
And that's the weirdest thing about it
is the imagination conjures up an idea
in which becomes a laptop.
It conjures up an idea which becomes an
airplane.
It all comes from the imagination,
whether it's artistic or whether it's a
song,
whether it's a joke.
That's the weirdest thing ever.
And everybody wants to pretend that it's
so normal.
And so normally just thinking shit up
out of the middle of fucking nowhere and
creating nuclear power.
You know,
what did you do it?
You sat down and what?
You wrote some stuff on some,
a pad and then you figured it out.
Where's this all coming from?
Where's the idea to even do that coming
from?
Where's the idea that some,
some guy wants to be like a fucking bird
and put wings on and figure out how to
fly.
And he eventually figured it out and now
we just travel all over the world and we
don't think anything of it.
I mean,
the imagination is crazy.
The imagination has done some amazing
things for human beings in this world.
And yet we still don't give her the
credit it deserves.
It's,
uh,
it was kind of shocking.
You know,
imagination is like the most underrated
thing of all time,
and yet it's the foundation of our
advancement in evolution.
Are you hopeful about things when you
see like Arab spring,
people were rising up and trying to
remove dictators and what happened in
Egypt?
Getting rid of Mubarak?
I am hopeful and I think it's,
I think it is happening all over the
world and I think the Internet has
played a part with it and it's happening
in America.
Um,
you know,
I,
I come here as a,
as a foreigner,
I'm British.
I come to,
I come to America often.
Um,
I have family here in America.
I feel very closely connected with
America.
And America is a paradox.
You know,
it's a huge paradox because on the
world's stage,
uh,
America is a very dark and malignant
force,
which,
uh,
which does tremendous harm,
consistently and has done for a long
time.
But at the individual level,
there's a tremendous spirit of awakening
in America.
Look,
just what's happening with cannabis laws
in America in the last,
the last 10 years,
that's unimaginable in Britain.
We can't make changes like that because
we don't have this spirit of
independence.
We don't have the structure where
individual states can make decisions on
key issues like that.
And,
and of course in America there's a
conflict between state law and federal
law.
You know,
the federal government is not always
respecting state laws and is seeking to
persecute people who are,
who are using cannabis.
But you know,
I think that that in itself,
the fact that a number of states have
decriminalized or even legalized
cannabis,
uh,
is a sign of a,
a sea change that is underway at the
moment.
And what it reflects is an awakening of
the American people.
So even though,
you know,
huge negative forces are still at work,
and I still sitting in the seat of
power,
I think,
I think there's a tremendous hope for
the future in America.
And that comes from the,
the awakening to consciousness of the
American people.
And maybe it's small right now,
but it's growing and in that sense,
far more than any other,
I believe America is leading the world.
That there is this,
that this possibility for awakening
here.
And maybe it goes back to the,
you know,
to the founding fathers on the frontier
days and just the,
the,
the sense that that people should be
able to make decisions about their own
lives without government telling them
what to do.
That's the step we all need to take.
We need to move ahead.
We need to set aside our commitment to
these large monolithic religions.
large,
monolithic states.
We need to run our own lives and make
decisions for ourselves.
And it just happens that that is very
close to the heart of what America is
all about.
[inaudible]
freaks and geeks level.