The general gun experience.
No.
One thing that exists now that really
didn't exist when Obama was running for
president is the impact of social media.
It's just tenfold what it used to be.
But with that also comes this reality
that we're living in right now where
there's only a few companies that are
controlling the discourse in this country.
Yeah. I mean, you really have
essentially a Facebook, Google, youtube,
Twitter, and Facebook owns Instagram.
That's right. And there's, you know,
a couple of other small ones, but
that's the bulk of our discourse. Yeah.
What concern do you have about these
private companies controlling the vast
majority of communication
between people on social media?
It's extremely dangerous. It's extremely
dangerous when you think about it.
And there's a few things. There's, gosh,
with Facebook and Google for
that matter. You know, they,
they can set their algorithms,
uh,
Mark Zuckerberg with Facebook and said
his algorithm to control what information
is coming across our
news feed in Facebook.
What are the stories that we're seeing?
Instagram, same thing with Google.
They can control.
When you punch in something,
what are the first stories that you're
going to see a on the first page that
pops up?
Uh,
when you think about that kind of power
of influence that has on the American
people literally being held within the
hands of a couple of people unchecked and
without oversight or transparency,
it's incredibly dangerous.
Talk about free speech.
There's just been news recently about
Facebook banning certain individuals,
uh, from having Facebook
accounts because of their speech.
They disagree with the
speech that they're,
they're using are the things
that they're talking about,
the ideas that they're pushing forward,
unchecked first amendment rights
going completely out the window.
And the argument is a don't apply because
it's a private company, right? Yes.
But they're trying to get
the best of both worlds. Um,
the fact that that, you know,
they're claiming to say, hey,
this is a free space for open
communication for everyone. Right.
While at the same time going and
saying, actually, you know what, Joe,
I don't like what you're
saying about this.
So we're going to ban you and
whoever your friends are from,
from this conversation. Um,
I think that's, that's a
big problem. It undermines,
it undermines our first amendment rights.
When you look at privacy,
the privacy concerns of all
the information that they're
collecting and Facebook
from us, all the information that
they're collecting from us, uh,
with Google and how they're monetizing
that and selling or sharing that
information with other people with really
without our knowledge or agreement.
Or You, you're fully sober
guy did not sober guy. Yeah,
I was a mess. I mentally,
I felt like a mess.
I mean I was, I never killed anybody
or anything, but I was at, I mean,
I'm an alcoholic.
Yeah. I shit in the girl's
shoe and yeah, I had some fun.
Oh yeah. Girl Shoe. Why
what'd she do to you? Uh,
nothing just invited me to stay at
her house. I don't remember doing it.
I was in a blackout or
whatever, but um, yeah,
I was all fucked up and then I woke up
and, uh, I had to Piss so bad. Like,
I just woke up in the bed and I was like,
I got a Penn and I was like,
I don't know where I am. I actually
had a flight, I had to cross.
I was going to the Seattle comedy
competition. Did you ever do that? No.
It was like, it's like a month long
competition and uh, yeah. And it's not,
they call it Seattle, but it's like
actually all over Washington state.
It's like a, you drive like three hours
a night. It's pretty crazy. Yeah. But,
um, I had to like be there
the next day for a month.
I had like a 10:00 AM flight and I woke
up at like nine 20 in the morning and
this girl's bed and I was like,
I gotta get the Hell Outta here.
But first I gotta Piss. If I piss in
this woman's bed, it's going to be,
it's going to be horrible.
So I ran to the bathroom and found the
bathroom pissed for like a half hour,
you know, those. And I've tried to like
put my shit to get my, I'm all fucked up.
And then I came out into her living
room and her table had been like,
smashed like a Chris Farley fucking table.
And you're that feeling
when you're fucked up,
we are looking at something and
you're like, that was definitely me.
I can just feel like, ah, I'm pretty
sure I'm responsible for that.
And then I was like,
I gotta go find my clothes.
So I went back into her room and uh,
on the way there I saw like
kind of like footprints of poop.
And then I came in and she had a high
top Nike sneaker that just had like a big
yeah.
And there was some little pieces around.
And then there was like a big puddle
of urine too. Like I didn't just,
cause you never just shit.
So I like pissed and shit,
but I got it inner sneaker, like I
fucking nailed it. Purpose. Well I think,
I mean I was in a blackout so by,
but I think what happened was I thought
it was a toilet because that's not like
my sense of humor. I'm not like a, I've
never been like a take a shit places.
So I think I just saw a cylinder twin.
Well if it's dark,
it looks it's black and it's a whole,
how big is her fucking choose
real big feat. It was, um,
it was a big woman now, so I shit
in there. And then what did what,
did you lose contact with her
after this or no, so I was like,
I gotta get Outta here cause
I gotta go catch this flight.
So I took my sock and put it on like
a, like a puppet, like a hand puppet,
a sock puppet and just kind of picked
it up that way and then turn the sock
inside out. Right. Which is like,
like almost like a shit in
the sock and threw that away.
And I tried to wipe up as much of
the, she asleep? No, no, they're gone.
Oh my God. I thought it's
like nine 30 in the morning.
I thought I just went so crazy
that they all fled their own home.
So then I get in the cab to go to
the airport. I'm missing my flight.
And I texted the girl and I was
like, I'm so, I want to kill myself.
Like can never I can show. Sorry. Did
you tell her that? I shouldn't know.
I figured she knew. So she wrote back.
It's okay. Yeah. Uh, it was, it was crazy.
Crazy night. It was fun or
whatever. And I was like, man,
this girl must fucking party. Like,
she's just like, okay, with the shooting,
I was like,
this woman's wild.
Historically there's been
bears. I mean, he's got,
they've got like 40 or 50 bears in
this little confined space. I mean,
there's nothing,
there's no more,
no greater abomination of nature
that I can imagine than a solitary,
largely solitary animals. So the confined
to a bunch of them of the species.
And then historically they have ripped
each other apart. And Dude, it's crazy.
I can actually delve into marine
lens history deeper than I can. Uh,
you get to hear the full spectrum of
some of the things that happen in bear in
mind. And it's important to note. It
was a different time, different times,
different things happen. And that's
just, that was the, that was the,
that was the norm. It's, it's, you know,
starkly contrasting time to
when marina and started. So,
but the stories are like really,
um,
it's jawdropping it's really
jaw dropping stuff, but
it's on one hand when you have children
and you bring a child to the zoo,
on one hand it's really fascinating to
watch this little person look at all
these different animals and freak out and,
and see how amazing it is.
But that's the only pro is
introducing human beings,
like little human beings in
particular to these animals.
Everything else is a con except for the
animals that are like really endangered
and they protect them and help breed them.
And then sometimes they were responsible
for some reintroduction efforts.
But other than that, it's
an animal prison man. Weird.
I don't take the position or ideal,
I don't,
I'm not at this person that's trying
to represent an ideology necessarily.
I'm not against all zoos,
but I have to say that there's nothing
more sad than seeing elephants. Cats,
bears. I mean, cats, man, the cats, when
they're pacing back and forth, I mean,
just get him out of there. Who
serve, whose purpose are you serving?
Is that good for you? I mean, seeing an
animal that's got zoo coast, this, I mean,
it's a, it's, it's,
it's a mental case and we don't know
what the fuck's going on in their head.
So we have no idea who those
people just to watch and think,
this is just maybe normal or something.
Right. A lot of people were not.
See because the veil is only now it's
sort of coming off and people are started
now getting the truth, uh, on the matters.
You start to see things for what they are.
Like if Tom Cruise decided to come out
of Tom Cruise is gay and he decided to
come out,
like that'd be a real problem.
You know what? I was talking to somebody
about this the other day, you know,
it would be a hilarious movie idea,
a gay couple because Tom
Cruise and John Travolta,
John Travolta,
John Travolta gets kidnapped and gay.
Tom Cruise has to save his gay husband
John Travolta and, but other than that,
it's a real action movie.
Wow. It's just gay. I like it.
Would that be fucking cool?
Like just a straight get,
if anyone out there's a screenwriter
that have addict cause I'm never going to
write it.
Would that fly when people enjoy that?
Like if it was really good like
John Wick style? I think it would,
I really think it would if it was,
if the guy does kick,
it's not like gay guys are like a feet
and if I know plenty of like rough gay
guys that will whoop your
ass bro. Bears Bro. They got,
they got their own ground. That's how
fucking bad these guys are. Uh, yeah,
I too really it would be fucking so cool.
Like,
and he was gonna yet cause that's how I
feel with someone like drunk coming out.
I'm like, I don't care. Okay.
I know it's never come up are we've
been good friends for a decade.
Just never came up. Yeah. Like it. He
didn't seem that interested in women,
but I don't,
I also don't think he's not introduced.
Just maybe there's definitely a spectrum.
Right. And so people are Joseph.
Yeah. And that's fine too.
Yeah. Yeah. I'm also not Matt,
like if I were on the spectrum, I
think I would absolutely do it. Yeah.
I'm just not on the spectrum like I,
but in terms of opportunity,
there's a lot of nights a year, Joe.
Oh yeah. There's 365 nights a year.
Oh yeah, you can, you're not going
to do the Pussy Dick Pussy. Yeah.
Go back and you go back and forth.
Same Nice. Split it up. Dahmer.
I had the best joke about that.
He goes, he goes, I, he goes,
this is how little I give a fuck.
He goes,
I wish I was gay just so I could
come out. Yeah. It was, I wish,
I wish I had a secret like that.
Yeah.
That's how little I give a fuck.
It's true.
It's like his joke about I'm
gaining weight for a movie.
I don't know what the movie is yet,
but it's fucking great joke.
Um, yeah, but the gay action movie
would fantastic. I like it. I do too. I,
within a year or two,
people would be definitely ready for it.
You want to hear the scariest Ai
Story? I know. Oh, it's old, right?
It's like an dim the
lights from the catalog,
but it's from like the early
days and gather round children.
This is like early days of Darpa.
Okay.
And this is when we were really seriously
afraid that the Russians were going to
send,
you know,
a hundred thermo nuclear warheads at
Washington and take out the whole country.
Okay. Right. So Darpa sets up this
station at the top of the world,
um, to monitor the Soviet
launch. So that, you know,
cause it only takes 24 minutes for an
ICBM to get from the launch pad in Russia
to hit New York or Washington. Okay.
So we set up the station up there,
um, and to monitor this. So we would
have some kind of a jump on this. Okay.
Like we'd learned at about eight
minutes. My God, the, you know,
it was a radar station.
That station called the [inaudible] site
or Jay site is connected to the no rad
station in Cheyenne Mountain, you know
the one from the movies, right. Okay.
And it's like the first week of business
and the guys that are sitting there in
the station looking for the alert are
sitting there and they've been trained
like the alerts never go off and all of
a sudden the alerts go from one, two,
three, four. Number
five is end game. Okay?
So information that the technicians
are getting is now 1000 Soviet thermo
nuclear missiles are on their way to
Washington DC with 99.9% certainty.
Actual story. Okay, the guy panics but he
trusts, he says, wait a minute, you know,
cause he supposed to
now give a launch code,
let's try and get the
generals on the phone.
They can't get the Pentagon
general in charge of no Rad.
They get a Canadian guy named general
Sleeman and slim and you know,
my God, we should we launch, should
we launch Slamon's like wait a minute.
Human thought.
He remembered that the night before he
thought he saw Chris Jeff on TV at the
UN. You know that him, he's famously
banging his shoe and he says,
where's Cruise Jeff? Right now
they check. He's in New York City.
Why would the Soviets send a thousand
nuclear weapons are way while their own
leaders in New York. They
said, I don't know sir,
but the radar returns are reporting this
and they're so someone had the idea at
that be mu site to go outside
and lo and behold,
what was there a big full moon.
The system was reading the moon moving
and misinterpreted it as a thousand
nuclear thermonuclear ICBM.
BMS coming crummy didn't launch.
So we came that close to the
end of the world. I mean,
and it's an astonishing story.
The documents are now declassified,
but is this an actual indication of
why that element of human intervention,
why trust, why other information like, oh,
I think I saw Khrushchev on the TV
last night is so important because the
machine said with 99.9%
certainty this is happening,
you ma, we must launch in
retaliation. True Story.