Hello Freak bitches.
It's kind of weird how it took a long
time for three d me to come back.
I they think I really
made it come back either.
Well Dude Avatar in my opinion,
the admitted combat and I saw it in imax
three d that's like an experienced man.
I had a smile on my face,
that whole movie and when I heard
all these people that were like,
oh the movies to the plot was very
transparent and like oh my God,
shut up.
Shut up.
Stupid.
How could you not enjoy that?
Oh you're telling me the
big blue aliens aren't real.
Whoa.
Get out of here
after Avatar.
People reporting depression like,
but yeah,
cause they liked our
depression is a real thing.
Yeah,
it's a fucking is now there's
no color and after Avatar.
I wonder how it's recognized.
I wonder if like psychologists
are behind it as well.
You have avatar depression.
It sounds like you've got a
bad case of Avatar to press.
That's not outside of
the realm of possibility.
Oh I'm sure.
Yeah.
Well,
I know the depression that comes from
playing a really awesome video game and
then going out into the world.
You know what I mean?
Like we were driving
here and we'd go back,
we'd go by this mountain of rocks and
he looks out the window and he goes,
oh,
that's like,
what does that look from our,
oh,
I'm like,
I don't even know what that means.
You have a fantasy environment.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Well,
I just got this Imac.
I just got this like giant Imac,
like the biggest monitor I've ever had.
So I was like,
well,
aren't those awesome?
I've got to see what works.
Suck.
Mine died today.
Yeah,
but it's probably just a hard drive.
No,
I hope not.
Oh God,
I'd got to back your shit up,
dude.
There are,
there are things back.
Not that,
not that computer,
because I use that
computer just for audio,
like you know,
for podcasts and slap a
fucking one terabyte drive
on it and one time timeshare
full drives.
I just keep on running
on of hard drive space.
Wow.
That's incredible.
Fucking sucks.
That shouldn't needs to go away.
What happened to,
I remember when I worked
at gateway computers,
I don't know if we talked about it
as anyway he's telling him come on,
design it back.
It is awesome.
I know you were saying that your shit
died but it is awesome and what were you
going to say about that?
I was going to say it's like a fucking
window and do an alternate universe.
When you've got a really good video
game and you're looking at it,
it's like these,
I think the word video games,
you got to go down the
tube is man because you,
you,
someone hears,
you say,
I love to play video games.
They're like you fucking nerd.
But it's like hey cause
you know it's like what,
what it's turning into.
It's not really,
it's going to get to the point where
it's not video games anymore where it's
something else.
Like I feel like it's
like world of Warcraft,
starcraft,
all these like a portal.
What we're,
this is the very first surge of water
and this virtual tsunami that's about to
come subjectively sweeping over everyone.
Because that thing you say about like
maybe our neurology can't resist movies
cause it's so overpowering.
It's like I think that there's
gonna be some truth to that
because these games are missing
a few components and this is,
this is what I think of when I'm
stoned playing world of Warcraft.
If I could smell like,
if there was a sense of smell involved
in this and also they've made it,
there was a sense of like,
I mean it's,
they've made machines that do that and
I don't think it's going to have to be a
mind thing.
It's a mind machine thing.
I think it's going to have to be,
so it's going to be a little
stimulate some part of your mind.
Maybe you can wear some,
maybe everyone's going to
have to shave their head.
Like real players.
The view,
you know,
you're going to have to do like a
horizontal Mohawk thing real plus I,
you know like this dude's legit,
he doesn't give a fuck.
It was up to club,
but this big stripe shaved on his head
and then you put this thing on skin to
skin on your head and it,
it has precise,
like you line it up on the video game,
it'll show you how to line
it up with the exact cortex,
exact portion of your brain.
And then it sends signals
that show you like burning,
meet,
smell,
and show you that.
And then,
but then you know what
else it does while you're,
and this is really weird while you're
playing the game and our races,
your memory of your previous life.
So the moment that thing goes on,
you'll have no more past your,
just the memories of the
character in the game,
rushing through the game,
playing the game,
completely unaware of the fact that
you used to exist as a person too.
And then you know what happens,
you're doing a podcast,
you're like,
oh fuck man,
my heart feels weird.
And you suddenly wake up and your
futuristic apart and you're like,
ah man,
that game was awesome.
So right now we're playing a game.
Yeah.
Like,
yeah,
like that with a lot of people say this
could be like some alien simulation,
you know that we're just an alien and
involved in a really high powered super
advanced bad ass video game
called planet experience.
The lives of billions of
people all individually.
I wrote something once about
maybe the life that we're living.
Maybe the reason why it seemed
so fake is cause it is fake.
And what we are in is some sort of a
reality simulation of the roaring twenties
of the technological age.
Like maybe we live in some time where
everything is all scented candles and
perfectly lit white rooms and no one has
a muscle car and no one's getting their
dick sucked.
And you know,
and maybe there's like a simulator that
you can run when you run where it's just
chaos but chaos that's
entertaining as fuck.
He's like every time you turn around
there's some new thing Christina Aguilar
fucking up the national anthem,
2 billion people tuning into the wedding.
There's constant shit going on to
keep you entertained and you are,
you are in this biological ride canister.
Yeah.
And you're going through this
thing and you're in this,
you're the,
you're a portal to this ride is
your skin and your flesh pops.
It pops through into this
dimension and you know,
it sounds like you're advocating fantasy.
It sounds like you're advocating,
well,
you know,
so you want to look at your life as
if it's some sort of a simulation.
Just live it as a simulation.
Yeah.
I'm saying yes I am.
Yeah,
why not?
Right.
It's very empowering.
Yeah.
I think the first person ever
heard suggest that was Mckenna.
I think Mckenna was talking about you.
How did he say it?
He was,
and he was quoting someone else.
So I'm doing a third hand quote,
but he said you should
view your life as he's,
say it
as a conspiracy or as view your life as
it's as it's as if the world is run by a
select group of people and that group
of people is you and your friends.
Yeah.
The,
your,
your somehow or another secretly in
charge with running the world and running
the university and the most
important things in the university.
She,
you and your friends cause it's the
most empowering way to view the world.
Well yeah,
because what's the cause?
What's the other side?
The other side of it is this kind of like
pseudo empathy for like strangers that
you don't know.
Like so many people wander through
their day just frothing with terror or
whatever they've seen on the news.
And so for them the world's awful,
but then they're real situation
is usually pretty good.
You know,
like the,
it's like a fucking,
uh,
Bill Hicks has that
awesome joke about CNN,
CNN watch the news and then outside
it's like beautiful and the grass is
growing.
So there's this mental pollution that
comes pouring out of every information
device that we have.
And that like corrupts your mind and you
begin to think you're in a horror story
when your real reality is one
that's usually quite pleasant.
The,
that experience,
the [inaudible] experience,
the mushroom experience,
you know,
everybody,
everybody that is religious
wants to believe in God.
What I'm telling you is I can show you
something that represents God for sure.
You can meet what God is.
And I'm not saying it's God your meeting,
but you can meet what God is,
what God is is perfect and all knowing
and all embracing and loving and wise and
and constantly around you all the time.
Well when you take mushrooms,
that's what you feel.
That's what you feel.
You really feel God.
And I'm not saying that it is God that
you're communicating with or what God is
or what are the what
even the concept of God.
When you say God,
all of a sudden it's this male hierarchy,
a point of you know,
point of reference where you think
of like one alpha that controls all.
But it's not that God is
more like everything I,
it's like a super dimensional
glob of its efforts.
It's
an intelligence,
it's this,
it's always,
and also it's,
it's constantly changing.
That's the other thing like it's,
it's like trying to even talk about it.
It's like trying to talk about
like a spinning slot machine.
It's like,
it's constantly like morphing and
shifting and it's so fucking potent.
Whatever it is that we're runoffs of it.
Like when you see water running
down your windshield and like,
streams of water will break
into little globs of water.
That's what we are.
We're just little broken off globs of
superintelligence that have taken on these
personalities and think that
we're individuals and you
know what else breaks off
in that
fucking thing?
Elves,
hyper dimensional things that
aren't necessarily out to love you.
And like there really is like there
are beings out there that are,
um,
I don't know man,
like superintelligent toddlers,
I think Mckenna talked about it.
They're like,
they're like baby God or something.
Okay,
here's the devil's advocate point of view.
Please.
How do you not know that those thoughts,
those demons just represent thoughts
in your mind and perhaps what that
experience is entirely is you contacting
your own thoughts and ideas and dreams
and hopes and expression without the
context of reality attached to them.
Sure.
So without the idea of,
you know,
what you did that you're
embarrassed about,
that made you weird about your
underwear when you were 13 you know,
instead of that maybe it manifests itself
in almost a living thing and almost a,
you know that project you're seeing these
when you're saying you are beings out
there that are fucking with you,
maybe those are things that
you've let grow in your mind.
Well yeah,
I mean I think that that's the modern
take on it and I think that that's one
useful handle to like get her get,
get to,
to like grab a hold of an ideal.
I'd be considered that
when you were in there,
when you,
you said you had an experience where
like these are projection mechanisms but
this the yeah,
that what you're seeing literally is
like that thoughts are live there.
They're real things that they look,
you ever heard the possibility,
I mean the discussion rather of the idea
that aliens will come through the mind
and that they're not going to
manifest themselves in a real form.
And that when you think of the imagination
or when you think of dreams and what
we have is some weird,
slippery sort of experience that
we can't completely control.
But what if that dimension of dreams,
that sleep dimension that you tap into
when all your neurochemistry starts
flowing between the blood brain barrier
while you're in heavy rem sleep,
what does that is in fact,
another dimension would have
that is in fact a world.
And that is where aliens
will contact you through.
They will contact you through this
spiritual dimension instead of a physical
dimension.
Yeah.
Well,
if that's the case,
and if you think about
taking mushrooms and these,
these l show up,
it is possible that negative things
that you've created in your own life,
shitty choices or bad energy that you've
set forth and then nurtured and and
repressed and put it down and tried to
deny it and all these different things
that people do to sort of rationalize
creepy things that they're doing in their
lives.
What if those things manifest themselves
as living organisms in the free pool of
your mind?
Yeah.
You know,
that's actually,
I think fucking Carl Young said that
exact same thing that you met Carl Young
this weekend.
I'm at a crazy guy who took ship 6.8
grams of mushrooms and told me he was Carl
Young.
This guy comes up to me and goes,
he goes,
I need to talk to you.
I have information that I'm
sure you don't know about it.
I go,
how can you be sure?
And he goes,
I just know.
I tried to talk to Brian,
read Ben about it,
but he replied to my email
with some stupid joke.
You go,
that sounds like Brian.
I want
to give you nuggets for that.
So that whole boy goes,
I really,
I've been doing psychedelic research.
I need to get this information for you.
I listen.
It's going to sound crazy.
I used to be in another life.
I was Carl Young.
I go,
how can you be sure?
And he goes,
I've seen things that you've never seen.
I go,
how can you know that this is ridiculous?
So you get to confidence
on get out of here.
I remember that guy have is,
do you remember?
Yeah,
I got to find that email.
That's crazy.
I talked about them on the podcast,
on a plane with Sam Aaa.
I did.
But that podcast might suck.
I'm not even going to release it.
I might not release it because we were
both hung over and tired and we're
talking about stupid shit.
So I'm not sure if I'm still hung over
from fucking Joey Diaz giving me a banana
cake.
Yeah,
I got a text from Brian in
capital letters do not eat.
Joey Diaz is banana bread.
You can never eat edible
marijuana that Joey Dee has given.
Know as you have xenon hand,
don't take that list.
You have a fucking big hypodermic filled
with adrenaline that you get stuff into
your chest.
Where vein?
Oh Dude,
you,
Joey Diaz gave me a,
um,
once gave me like some breath strips I
guess is the first time I'd taken breath
strips and he was like,
eat two of these.
And I'm like,
no,
he really tell you,
hey,
I don't tell anybody ever
detect more than a quarter.
I hold their hand.
I go,
dude,
listen to me Bro.
Listen to me.
I love you.
Don't take more than a quarter.
Joey likes the tour knowing Joey Diaz.
That's what I did.
I only took half of one of these knowing
him and I was driving home on the
interstate and uh,
was like,
well it's,
it's definitely the
apocalypse world is ending.
I see that clearly now.
I'm when the last days and uh,
and um,
there was a McDonald's and I was going
to stop my car and to the Mcdonald's to
get a burger because
traffic wasn't moving.
That's how bad the logic
was working in my mind.
I just get a fucking,
I know I can make it there
to get a diet coke and back.
But anyway,
I get home,
I'm having the most
terrible marijuana trip.
I'm laying in bed.
I'm like,
oh my God,
the world's in my heart's
pounding phone rings,
phone rings,
Joey Diaz,
I answered.
He's like,
welcome to my house mother fucker.
So he's thought you took all two of them.
He knew the number you're
going to get a quarter.
Yeah.
Fuzzy.
Just surmise that he's so crazy.
My best buddies got the little Listerine,
the acid thing and there was like a few
of them in there and I guess they all
melted together.
Do you remember that?
I did that.
I did that once and the guy took
like a bunch of them ever did.
He never smoked weed.
You never eat wheat.
And he was like as first time trying it.
So Joey,
you know,
gave him some,
and there was like a lot in there and
they had melted together into one and you
got a massive panic attack.
I think the guy called an ambulance
call called nine one one you had a panic
attack.
Yeah,
we'd see.
That's the thing,
man.
There needs to be a special nine one
one like when you press a button on your
phone,
when you get directed,
like,
have you eaten edible marijuana?
Press Cherry Garcia.
Somebody can calm you down.
Yeah.
Okay.