Oh Shit,
we're live beatboxing.
Brian Cowen shows another hidden skill
and this last weekend we just learned he
speaks fluent gay rapist.
French said play when I'm in the hardest
things I ever laughed at.
Is You doing your French rapist
character?
Yeah,
I'm talking to Steven about.
Explained to him how to.
I'm assuming you were saying tightened
up his ass because you are going to come
inside of it something.
You're doing it all.
Did it all in perfectly.
Enunciated French.
That's right.
I think he shocked him.
I think he did.
He was crying.
He was laughing so hard.
He was actually the does the camera guy
who the camera guys who are pros.
These guys are Goddamn pros.
They.
They keep it together.
The guy gave in and was laughing out
loud while holding the camera,
like he couldn't help it.
We were all crying and also he knew this
was never gonna.
Get on the fucking sportsmans channel.
It's not going to get on channel,
but I wish they would release it on the
web.
The ravine comer.
Why don't we have the we there?
The footage is there.
I think there's some concern that the
hunt and folk would abandon us all
because French rapists folk don't like
these Goddamn comedians coming in and
gang up are fine.
American pastime,
hunting folk,
some of the hunting folk look,
most hunting people are like most
people,
most people are cool as fuck.
I maintain this.
I really do believe this.
I believe that most people are great.
It is a very small percentage of people.
It took me a long ass time to figure
this out.
Just the sheer numbers.
It's just that when something goes
wrong,
it's so disturbing for us that we get
upset and we lump all other folks into
the same category that that person came
from almost to protect ourselves and we
know it's a prejudice and like having a
prejudice towards people who live in the
south or having a prejudice towards
anything.
It's all the same.
Any kind of prejudice like it's not
going to spend another 10 team.
Their fans is not a nicer prejudice
because they just have a southern accent
and they lived down there and you just
think it's cute to think they're
retarded.
No,
that's Goddamn prejudice.
Those are people,
right?
If you thought they were tardy because
they were black,
you'd be as a piece of shit.
Right?
Right.
But you can think that they're retarded
just because they talk like this.
Like some of them that talk like this
are actually super intelligent people as
they choose to keep their accent.
I've spoken to professors that are like
a strong Houston,
Texas accent and guy was genius as fuck.
Exactly smarter than me.
We are.
We are tribal.
People are just trial and it's really
easy to do that.
Those guys over there,
I don't like people from West Virginia
or whatever.
I don't like them.
God Damn.
Comedians are smoking weed and they're
talking hunting and that's not what
hunting is about.
What hunting is about is how I do it.
I get up in the morning and I faced the
east and it was that Muslims.
Now that's Muslim.
See now you're a trader and now you just
expose yourself.
No,
no,
no.
I meant I praise Jesus to the east,
west,
north,
and south.
You said ease major.
I'm not an.
I swear to God.
I am not a pale face.
Terrorists was that expression.
There's an expression,
oh,
clean skin,
clean face,
clean,
clean skin,
and terrorists.
I don't know.
I haven't heard of that.
Expression is for like the Timothy
Mcveigh,
the ones that you don't see coming
because they look like,
like fashion American boys.
Yep.
What is the term so you can find with
that term?
As chairman?
Alicia is a good thing.
It's called clean skin terrorist.
That's what they.
They think of as like some homegrown
nutty dude.
I was listening to this fucking radiolab
podcast about these dudes.
These white supremacists do that.
We're planning this mass murder and they
were infiltrated by the FBI.
Jesus.
It was fascinating,
man.
God Damn that National Public Radio
podcasts,
radio labs.
One of the best things ever.
Not just like on podcasts,
but as far as like as move.
If it was a movie,
it would be one of the best things that
it was a TV show.
It'd be one of the best things I you.
You turned me on to.
Things were haunting Dan Carlin's
hardcore history.
I'm obsessed.
By the way.
Do you want to talk about a guy doing
the world of service?
If you want to learn history and you're
talking to a history major,
I read all the books,
blah,
blah.
I take courses from the teaching
company.
If you want to learn history,
go to Dan Carlin's.
Hardcore history.
I have never.
I've listened to great professors.
I've never heard anybody kind of break
down the history as a story where you
just can't wait for the next podcast and
then radio lab,
which I've always listened to npr and
sometimes they have those on there,
but radiolab is pretty amazing.
It's off the charts.
Amazing.
It's so good.
So it is cleaned skinned.
A clean skin terrorist is a potential
attacker with a spotless record whose
documents don't arouse suspicion.
Wow.
Well you gotta think like every
terrorist,
every dude who blows a fuse,
there has to be like there's a moment
where you could get to a certain age,
you can be like pretty nutty and get to
a certain age without a criminal record
and then you all the time.
You're like building up for the one big
nutty event.
Those are the scary guys that inside
live inside and then they're just
waiting for action.
Yeah,
they.
They're terrified and they just.
They're fantasizing that going over in
her head,
going over their head and then they
finally explode.
Now how did those guys get made?
Is that nature and nurture?
Isn't that?
Isn't that the ultimate question?
Because if we could stop all people that
would wantonly want to create war for
profit.
If we could stop all people that would
act in the name of global aggression for
financial gain.
If we can stop all that,
we would all do it and then we'd have a
way crazier world if we had a world
where everybody was basically really
nice.
Yeah.
I mean,
although,
although you're,
you're suggesting in the way you framed
that as you're.
You're assuming that people that are
aggressive or create aggression or the
are the aggressors are doing it only
for.
A lot of people think this only for
certain
negative things like a money conquest
territory that the problem is that
aggression,
a lot of times can be fostered in groups
of people if they think that another
country is actually going to hurt them
in the future.
It can be very much useful in a self
defense capacity or at least justified
that way and always has been.
Absolutely.
And so I don't think you'll ever get.
I don't think you'll ever get rid of
aggression and you probably shouldn't.
I think it's part of the order of the
universe I bought.
What I think you have to do is this.
The biggest threat is,
you know,
one thing that's always kind of
confounding about life is that it takes
so long to build something.
It takes so long to build a complete
human being.
It takes so long to build something like
the Sistine Chapel and it's so easy to
destroy one motivated fanatic with a,
you know,
a large enough bomb on his back.
He could blow up,
you know,
St Peter's Cathedral or could kill.
I don't know how many people.
And that's what's so hard is that the
things that take so long to build are so
easy to destroy and it,
as technology grows it,
it's going to become more and more a
factor in more and more of a reality
where one person or a small group can
get their hands on devastating
technology to destroy,
you know,
something impossibly huge.
So that's the bigger question.
I think aggression is always going to be
around.
And when you say,
you know,
I wonder how those people are made,
I don't know that it's going to be done
by that one.
Crazy because one crazy can't get his
hands on massive amounts of weaponry.
He's usually one guy and he carries a
gun and he does enough damage.
Well,
how about these kids in the Boston
bombings?
I mean,
they were fairly clean skinned.
They were and they didn't.
Do they,
they killed,
I think six people.
I can remember what the thing is,
but that's always tragic.
What I'm saying is that the,
the bigger threat is less aggression and
more sort of warped ideology then moves
and motivates a large group of people
into aggression.
Right.
That that's what I worry about and
that's where I think,
you know,
when you say aggression,
you don't mean aggression,
like hostile takeover of countries type
of aggression.
You mean just like male behavior?
Like what do you mean when you say
aggression?
Aggression in this context is a military
sense.
Something that causes massive
destruction,
irreparable harm to infrastructure and
two populations and for example,
what's going on in Iraq with them,
like with Isis,
right?
When you hear the news,
if you just listen to the news,
Isis is this terrible group of fanatics.
Yes they are and they kill lots of
people.
It's a much deeper problem.
You know,
they're talking about what do you do
about isis?
Well,
do you bomb the shit out of him?
Problem is they're,
they're ingrained in the Sunni towns and
population and they have a lot of
support by the Sunni's.
Why?
Why do these fanatical guys have support
from the Sunni population?
Has nothing to do with whether those
Sunni people who are good people,
like you just said,
most people are really good people.
They are.
They are giving support to a fanatical
group of people because they are their
best hedge and their best bet against
what's called Shia aggression in their
eyes.
So the Shia,
the Shia who dominate the south of Iraq,
who sit on most of the oil down there.
If the Sunni's don't cut out a little
place for themselves using this crazy
group called Isis,
they could be left in there in the
future,
in real fucking trouble.
And so again,
now we're talking about they're using
aggression as a form in their eyes as a
form of self defense.
If you are a Sunni Iraq,
you'd have a very different idea and
context of what's,
what Isis is as as opposed to uni who
get our information.
And again,
there's nothing to admire about those
guys.
They are ruthless killers,
but it's just interesting that you and I
look at that as aggression on a ones.
You know,
one side is a lot of those people using
ice as his health defense.
Aggression is justified.
Yeah,
they're terrible.
But we need them against the Shia.
So it's hard for someone who lives in
California in 2015 to wrap their head
around what's going on in other parts of
the world right now,
unless you.
I mean even what I've seen of it,
I haven't seen enough.
My,
my,
my seeing of it as all two dimensional.
No,
I couldn't imagine I couldn't fucking
mansion.
It's one of the biggest problems we were
going to have with people that have seen
it and don't have to imagine it anymore.
Trying to forget it.
Trying to be normal again.
When you ask a fucking hell of a lot of
people and,
and how do you help them through that
and what kind of counseling?
Mental health counseling.
I hope it's comprehensive.
It's a really good question because they
always say after a war and after the
revolution and after whatever happens in
a country settles,
everybody always forgets about the
victims.
There's never really any kind of
infrastructure to help people in Sierra
Leone that got their arms hacked off.
That's the other kids killed in front of
them and stuff like that.
Is it possible that because of the
ability that we have right now translate
languages so quickly,
you know,
it just really unprecedented something
that people don't think about that much,
but there's all sorts of software now
just on a regular phone that can look at
images and translate them into English
on your screen.
The you could have asked questions and
have those questions immediately
translated into Spanish.
There's all these programs they have now
like it's way easier to understand under
other languages than it ever has been
before.
To decipher actual texts in real time
that really never existed before and
that kind of technology is going to
slowly but surely break down a lot of
barriers and a lot of ideas that we have
about each other.
Well,
let's.
So language and I think more so the fact
that we can not only see suffering and
realtime with cameras and the Internet,
but we can also.
We are also starting to see the
cultures,
whether they're Indian or South Korea
are really similar to Americans,
you know,
with,
with K pop.
I mean Korea has got all their k pop and
stuff.
More importantly,
when you see their artistic expressions,
they're making movie slumdog
millionaire.
You see an Indian kid who has the same
dreams and aspirations as anybody does.
I think that goes a longer way in
bringing people into sort of a
collective notion and it already has
people like Steven pinker would argue
that that it's becoming easier to
identify with other people's suffering
because we identify with a lot of
aspects of how they live their lives to
begin with.
It's no longer like who are those
strange people with dark skin nowadays.
You know,
people are dressing the same no matter
where you go,
you know,
and I kind of recognized on the plane
from a woman from Bombay,
from Mumbai because she watches how I
met your mother and telling me all her
friends love how I met your mother and
she was flipping out that the guy from
how I met your mother was sitting next
to her and she had a heavy accent.
She was talking like I couldn't.
I can't believe I'm watching all my
friends.
I could.
I take a big step.
She was so excited and she had this
heavy Indian accent and I thought that
is,
that never would have happened.
No,
you never would have happened.
And so we are sharing artistic
experience was sharing experience in
high relief usually in movies and TV.
And that's in a lot of ways that's going
to go a lot farther than being able to
download a language because I think
that's always going to take more time.
Well,
if we all just spoke the same language,
it will be really fucking boring.
That's true.
But it would be really cool if we
understood what the fuck everybody was
saying all the time.
You know,
I think it would smooth out a lot of
shit between people.
I really got to think that like if we
could have like real time conversations
with like Kim Jong,
uhm,
you know,
if you could have a real time
conversation with that dude and sit down
and go,
what is your life like?
Like explained to me like what was,
what was childhood like for you?
What's the environment around you all
the time.
He's a real,
he's a real life king and he's like,
he's a monarch.
One of the few remaining is not that he
lives like a king and it was raised like
a prince and Dennis Rodman's,
his homeboy that problems,
a great,
great spokesman for him,
wasn't he?
Dennis Rodman comes down things with
that dude and plays basketball and shit
and then leaves like what kind of
fucking bizarro reality TV world are we
living in,
or Dennis Rodman just hops on private
jets and hangs out with the king of
North Korea.
Be the greatest reality show I ever
made.
I mean him and Kim Jong Un,
me and me and me and the Canada.
It's like rocky Marciano hanging you and
Mussolini.
What do they talk about?
Look at them.
They're together.
Having a good old time.
Do you think he's freaked out at all
about the middle amount of metal that's
in Rodman's face?
I know.
Freaks them out.
God,
look at that.
That is such a strange thing.
Yeah.
Look at him.
He's a king.
I mean,
didn't he have his own uncle eaten wild
dogs or something?
Why?
Yeah.
Oh,
that's right.
Yeah.
He assassinated him.
That says,
I was thinking about a Rodman.
Rodman did that had his uncle killed.
His uncle apparently was trying to
organize a coup,
so he killed,
I believe he killed everyone in the
family.
Everyone in the family except the wife,
and he gave the wife like a raise really
promoted her to a better position.
Real true.
Killed her husband.
Yeah.
Interesting.
You know,
something along those lines.
I'm going to be making that up.
It's real game of thrones shit.
Yeah,
it is.
I mean,
he really did kill his uncle and then
his uncle's sons,
so his uncle's sons couldn't take
revenge on him.
Yeah.
The Russians were good at that.
She used to do that and Stalin,
you get rid of.
Everybody needs to do that.
So I'm saying,
who was it?
It was talking about that.
I was at helmet shoulder.
One of the ex German premiers went to
meet.
He said,
I want it.
Whereas the,
I want to say hi to the ambassador,
these different D German ambassador who
I've known for 10 years,
and they said he was.
He was,
unfortunately,
he was,
he was executed for,
um,
for treason and he was like,
he'd known him for a long time and it
was really kind of taken aback and I was
like,
oh,
that's,
that really makes me upset.
And he goes,
well,
can I see the family?
I got to know the family,
I'd like to give them my condolences to
the family is no longer around either.
And uh,
he told that story.
I think it was on that.
Oh,
Charlie rose or something where.
they killed his whole family.
That's real.
I mean.
And,
and again,
like you were saying,
we have no idea what it's like.
We're so lucky.
We're so lucky we can walk away from
things we don't like because most of the
world has to live with something they
don't like.
Concluding a government that tells them
what to do and tells them where to live
until some where they're going.
I don't know if this is propaganda or
not.
I don't know if it's bullshit or not,
but I'm just telling you what I read,
that they were putting people in jail if
they didn't cry hard enough.
When Kim Jong Il died,
they.
Some of them were getting six months of
hard labor from what?
I'm not crying hard because they were
not grieving hard enough.
So you see these pictures that I'm
beating their chest and crying party
members crying for know nobody wanted to
be.
The first person has stopped crying,
so they're crying for hours.
Oh my God.
This is madness.
That's like group madness.
Whether that's what North Korea is.
Group madness.
Yeah.
It's like you're watching what happens
when you allow these really ancient,
horrific methods of dictatorship and
they do even worse.
Hey,
if you really fucked up,
they'll put you in the coal mines and
you never leave.
You never come out of the coal mine so
you don't get any sunlight,
so your skin starts to fall off,
but you don't leave.
You're not getting up.
You're,
you're living in the coal mine.
Oh my God.
It's so bad for not crying.
Thousands of North Koreans face labor
can't response in Labor yet.
Oh my God.
Upset enough about the death of Kim Jong
Il.
That is insane.
It's amazing.
Like I guess that's the only way to run
a cultural.
Like if you're going to run it that way
as a dictator,
you have to have everybody absolutely
terrified all the time.
So no one takes a chance.
Wow.
How can you maintain that?
Uh,
fuck.
Are they maintaining that?
If your family might get put in jail or
kill you,
you'll do it.
I know,
but I mean,
it's amazing.
I mean,
it has to be at like a boiling point.
Could you imagine?
Look at that.
These poor people,
even the kids,
they move you and they move.
They move.
You like your designated.
Where do you live in North Korea?
The neighborhood you live in,
if your family was against or for the
original founder of North Korea,
Kim Jong,
UN's father,
if he was,
if they were in opposition to him,
you live in a very shitty neighborhood.
If they were allowed to have your three
generations later,
you live in a good neighborhood.
Oh my gosh.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
Good stuff.
They're nice guy.
He apparently was mad during the famine
and the nineties that people were
eating.
The dogs were eating Korean dogs.
He's like,
there are national,
you know,
the,
the agenda has like one of our national
treasures and these people are eating
the dogs.
He was all irritated.
It's a good guy.
Yeah.
That's the worst country in the world
and it's always read into that that way.
It's just so crazy to think that
someone's able to pull that off in this
day and age.
Well,
he's got nuclear weapons.
Thank you.
Pakistan.
It's just,
uh,
I just have a hard time believing that
that can be maintained.
But yet here it is.
It the fact that it's still here in
2015.
It's pretty nuts.
This is like really late in the terms of
civilization to have a full on dictator
like that where we look,
look at those pills.
People crying again.
Could you imagine any sort of a scene
like that in America?
If a guy died who was the king?
Can look at that,
look at all that.
So these poor people are just faking
crying.
Everybody's terrified to not.
They all have handkerchiefs to stop
crying too soon.
God.
Oh my God.
It is.
It's it's madness.
It's probably what a lot of history was
about when you had a king and he was
absolute ruler and if he was a
sociopath.
Luckily if you.
If you're lucky,
you got a good king.
Somebody who wasn't crazy,
God damn dude.
That is the nuttiest shit of all nutty
shit.
The fact that there's a still a country
of millions of people that live like
that.
Yeah,
I know God damn.
That's terrifying.
And whenever people talk about
privilege,
white privilege,
black privilege,
whatever kind of privilege you might
have,
heterosexual privilege.
Here's the biggest privilege not having
to live like those folks.
Exactly.
That's number
one.
Above all else that isn't that,
isn't that the reason?
One of the big reasons to at least read
the newspaper or a little history or
know what's going on in the world.
Have some perspective anyway.
You can get it.
Yeah.
You know?
That mean that the term white privilege,
like people don't like that term.
People get mad,
which usually means there's some
validity to it,
but everybody's.
Everybody says like white privilege and
you see a white dude role in his eyes.
You might have a little racist.
Anybody?
I might have a weird conversation with
you and have to go,
wait,
what?
No.
Is Not a Muslim.
No,
no,
no.
I had a conversation with a friend like
that.
He's in the middle of the conversation
goes,
I'm on Obama's biggest Muslim in the
country.
I go,
no,
he's not.
What are you talking about?
Why you saying Shit like that?
Man?
There's no evidence that he's a Muslim
at all.
No,
none.
Zero.
By the way,
his dad was a Kenyan and Muslim,
but he didn't know his dad very well.
He grew up in Hawaii,
right,
but the two is not living like some
secret life where he's ready to blow up
America from the inside that says these
dumb ass thing,
callus on the middle of his head where
he prays every day,
which is to really get.
You're supposed to that if you're very
pious in Islam,
you get a.
You get a dark darker.
The skin in that area where you touch
your head to the floor is darker than
the rest of your skin.
That's when you know somebody really,
really religious.
So it's like the cauliflower ear of the
Islam world.
Wow.
It's a badge of courage,
right?
What happens if you're a pussy and want
like a little little pillow,
a little soft pillow or they get mad at
John.
Don't the orthodox Jews were something
like that when they pray.
Um,
I don't know.
I do not know what their practices.
Well,
but they want to get showing these guys
with dark spots on their forehead.
Oh my God.
Well,
I just pulled up all these photos of
these guys,
these super dark spots in there for.
That's when you know that you got to
just,
just know that he's very religious.
He'll be that old dude with the glasses
down there.
He's got like a hole in his head.
Well that is.
Yes.
A scroll down a little bit.
Some of bin Laden's righthand man,
that guy,
he's got his head.
It was our hearing.
That's the Egyptian Dr who is a Osama
bin Laden's right hand man.
And he's still at large and you make
that photo larger.
Is that possible?
Fill at large by Jesus Christ.
Access forbidden.
Yeah.
He's a doctor to Jesus Christ.
Look at his forehead,
dude.
That that.
Man.
I never heard of this before.
This is insane.
Brian,
can you teach me something new?
Every time we talk.
Smart Bitch.
Come on.
Look at that forehead,
man.
That's crazy.
That dude has worn a hole in his head
that's like,
it looks.
I mean it's hard to tell because it's
fairly low resolution,
but whatever.
That is not a good guy by the way.
He's,
he's.
He,
he and assignment were good buddies.
He's still alive.
He's still out there.
They don't know where he is.
Whoa.
Egyptian doctor.
That's what we're using.
Very religious and very violent.
We live in a movie.
We really do.
We really live in a movie.
We live in a
movie and it's a weird one.
You mean?
You mean just the fact that we're
Americans are in general.
The whole world is theater and it really
is.
I mean,
obviously it's real,
but what I'm saying is the way it's
playing out,
it's so goofy.
It seems like a work of fiction.
The North Korea thing seems like a work
of fiction.
The Uber pious gentleman dressed like a
genie who's worn a hole in his head from
praying.
That guy is a character in a fucking
movie.
Oh,
and by the way,
they can't find them phase out there and
make is out there.
He's a doctor.
He's evil.
He's probably got millions of dollars
and they can't find.
Yeah.
When his Batman coming in were his
Batman is.
It's true.
Right?
It's also weird,
like people have plans and they pull
them off,
like they just get together and go,
listen,
you guys were gonna hijack planes and
fly them into buildings.
You know,
people do Bengazi.
Yeah.
Anyway,
I mean there's a bunch of different
things,
bitch,
bit different events that have happened
all over the world where people kept
their mouth shut,
plotted them and executed them.
Dan Carlin and says this beautifully,
he talks about,
we always talk about they live in the
age of terrorism.
He said,
well,
the lineage Tara,
Tara was actually since 1914,
and he tells me a fascinating story.
If you don't know the origins of World
War One,
it's very important because the world
war one and World War Two,
our connected World War Two is the
continuation of World War One and about
80 or 90 million people lost their lives
because of those two wars.
And Oh,
and it destroyed all of old Europe.
Oh.
And it changed the entire map of the
world.
Oh.
And all of us live in its wake in a much
deeper and more turbulent way.
Then you can imagine,
uh,
that in fact,
let me keep going.
If you want to know about the Middle
East,
really,
you got to study World War II.
If you don't,
you know,
historian will take you seriously.
And Dan Carlin says something
fascinating.
I don't know if you know the story said
it did.
World War One and the world you live in
was changed by one man and his name was
carvello princess.
And he was a Serbian terrorist.
And he found out that the archduke
ferdinand of the ostrow,
Hungarian Empire doesn't matter,
was coming to town and they had control
of Serbia and Serbia was looking for
their independence.
So they said,
we're going to kill this guy.
And he was in an open car with his wife
and he was in a parade and one of the
Serbian terrorists came running out with
a grenade or a bomb through it at the
car and it went it.
It had a faulty thing and it blew up
under the other car.
And six out of six people were very
badly injured.
I think one person was killed.
But guess what?
Our stoop,
Ferdinand,
he survives.
He goes,
he makes a full account.
They apologize to him.
And it remember,
this was in Serbia,
it was in Syria.
I Sara Aviel,
which was a sort of a colony,
if you will,
of the Servo Hungarian,
of the Austrian Hungarian Empire.
Here was the next in line for the,
the in charge of the Austrian Hungarian
Empire.
Now check this out.
This crazy.
That's another story.
I've sat and listened to the podcast.
Maybe go ahead and keep saying it if you
want.
So it's just awesome.
Because so,
so now they say,
well,
we missed our assassination attempt.
This Guy Carvello Prinsep who was part
of this whole group,
goes in for a sandwich and as the arts
duke for advanced and let's get you out
of here.
Says,
no,
I want to go to the hospital and I want
to check on all the survivors of this
bombing.
They said,
okay.
So they go down a road and the guy
misses his turn and he misses his turn
and now he decides to back up and as
he's backing up the car stalls and they
got to kind of figure it out.
And as the car stalls,
because he missed a turn,
a guy named Carvello Prinsep,
part of this Serbian thing comes walking
out with a sandwich and he goes,
oh fuck.
There's the archduke Ferdinand.
He just right in front of me.
And he shoots him and he shoots his
wife.
And that was because the driver missed a
turn and was backing up.
And carvello by coincidence,
just sees the archduke and shoots him
and that pin as Dan Collins has that
created the hand grenade that was World
War One and World War Two was because a
driver missed a turn and because one
terrorist,
1:20
year old guy had a gun in his hand and
said,
that guy's a bad guy and shot him.
And our world has changed forever
because of that strange missed turn.
That's part of what's fascinating about
history.
That's an amazing podcast.
Which one is the.
It's called the name,
it's called.
Yes.
It's called countdown to Armageddon.
And it is awesome and I'm glad we got a
chance to blueprint for getting
blueprint farmer.
Good.
I'm so glad I had a chance to drive in a
car with you.
We had a long trip and we could listen
to Dan Carlin's,
the Mongoltauge.
You opened a whole can of worms for me.
I've been telling you how crazy that
was.
Like forever.
I'm like,
you just got to listen to this podcast.
When people say that to me though,
it's hard to take them seriously while I
just got to listen to another podcast,
but if you listened to wrath of the
cons,
you will be a changed human being,
100 percent.
You will understand what it was like to
live in that time as best as anybody
could ever describe it in a way that is
so ultimately paralyzingly,
terrifying,
900 years old or whatever the fuck it
is.
You mean because you're in your.
You're huddled in your church with your
family and they're at the direct,
the gates in there.
They're bashing your gates down.
You know they're going to come in and
kill everybody.
That was like,
what?
Eight hundred years ago,
700 years ago,
Jesus fucking Christ.
We're going to get your head cut off.
You're going to die by by stabbing or
cutting.
It's going to suck,
and they were launching bodies.
They would light bodies on fire and
launched them with catapults and that
human fat burns better.
Apparently when you really light it on
fire,
it can catch things on fire better.
They were so fucking ruthless.
While I was thinking about how they
live,
like you know,
you and I,
we'd go hunting,
so we live outside and for four days or
three days sometimes and it's miserable
and we wake up and we're freezing and
we're wet and we're like,
this pillows can wait to get back to
civilization,
but we do it because we love it.
It brings us a close to objective
reality where like I feel a little
tougher,
a little more manly,
you know,
the Mongols I was thinking about how
they,
I was kind of trying to picture it there
on a horse by the time they're three.
They live in the.
Yeah.
To stop and think about that.
Let's just start there.
Three,
throw the kid on a horse and I have a
four year old.
She's not running any fucking horse.
Looks no fuck.
Especially wild horse in the tar tars.
Fairly broken and these still have like
20 of them per Pi Whistle.
They'd be like,
no idea their horses show up.
I,
no,
I never had heard that.
I didn't know how the.
That was one of the most terrifying
things is like how well organized they
were.
Well,
because that's how they would hunt,
so they would hunt on horseback.
They were such trick riders.
Have you been on a horse since you were
three?
You can do anything on a horse,
right?
You can shoot an Arrow on her horse.
You're just much faster,
but he was.
What was the were the clinical reality
came in?
I thought to myself,
their lives were so violent to begin
with.
First of all,
they lived.
The staple was mayor milk and blood from
their horse,
which they would mix.
They had mixed the milk and the blood
and they would drink it and I wonder
what that does to chemically what that
tastes good.
Probably knocking Christ.
How many parasites did they have in
their body?
By the time they were like 10 years,
God knows or none,
and they would chase because they would
ferment the milk and they would.
They would.
The way they would hunt animals,
if they would do the same with humans,
they would.
They would sort of push them all into
one area.
Then create an opening for them to run
through and then they'd been waiting
with a party there.
They were so just daily existence was so
physical and violent and they had
ultimate disdain for people that live
behind walls.
They lived in felt tense and that was
like their whole thing.
It's like the actual description of what
they were calling Genghis Khan,
something about ruler of all who dwell
in the tents.
It's nothing crazy that they would show
up in town and they would say,
look,
I guess you guys weren't aware that you
owe gingiss con money.
Yeah.
So or jingles.
They like to say genius.
It was gang is when John Wayne did it.
I grew up with gangs.
I swear to got to go hang with Dan
Carlin.
I was like,
dude,
this holiday Gangas Ching is gone.
His real name is [inaudible],
but Dan Carlin,
what he does so good is make it utterly
fascinating.
He's such an expert narrator
storyteller.
He's an expert.
I mean like a real master at it.
So when he's telling you these stories,
it's not just.
It's not just really cool information,
which most absolutely is,
but it's the ways written it all and put
it together and worded it.
It's just fucking.
He lives in Portland.
Don't give him his fucking address with
the Mongols.
Come here.
Right.
Shit,
man.
I'm just going to be important that a
little bit.
I want to try to him man,
getting.
We're Dan,
if you're listening to this,
come to my show in Portland.
He's a great guy.
You'll love tweeting with them.
Super Cool Guy.
Real fun.
I've had him on the podcast a few times.
Yeah,
I'd love to meet.
He's doing a goddamn national service
with that 100 percent of world's
service,
I should say.
I shouldn't say interpersonal.
It's on the Internet.
Could not agree more.
It's so much more entertaining than any
other history thing I've ever witnessed
and watched.
Listened to.
I mean I've spent enough time over the
past 20 years at least listening to
different kinds of like the turning
points in European history and you know
from the teaching company,
really good professors and nothing
compares to that guy.
Nothing.
Well,
there's so many good podcasts right now.
It's just like there's a,
you know,
I was talking with someone yesterday
about how many good tv shows there are
today as opposed to like when we were
kids,
like we were kids.
Like what was a really good show on TV?
I Mash,
I guess mash was a really good.
What was it like a really good drama was
running.
Oh,
Hill street blues.
Hill street blues was great,
but that's the only one I can think of
off the hill street blues is later.
That was like,
wasn't that.
It was 85.
What does it really?
Actually it was 80,
81.
Why do I have that all fucked up in my
head?
Oh,
I think I haven't fucked up with NYP ed
blue.
That's what it is.
Yeah.
What else?
What's that?
A good drama.
I can't think of a good drama right now.
Compare that to what's available today.
Compare that to game of thrones.
Walking dead mad men breaking bad.
Better.
Call Saul.
Yeah.
House of cards.
Homeland.
Jesus Christ.
It's not.
I can't even keep up.
Salt of wizard shows they're so goddamn
good and you got to be good because they
have those hbo shows.
Now,
those hbo shows took everything to a
totally different level.
When they put out the soprano's,
the whole game changed.
All of a sudden you're like,
Jesus,
this is better than a movie.
This is a movie that's forever because
they made a character.
It used to be.
The rule was that character has to be
somebody you like,
who you want to bring in your living
room every week.
That was the rule and when you went to
pitch a show and your character wasn't
quote unquote likable,
people were like,
Nah,
it's not going to work.
Along comes Tony Soprano,
huge adulterer,
murderer,
kill his friend,
his friend and tells his son to do his
homework.
In the same breath,
talk about a dichotomy and and of course
as human beings,
we're like,
well,
that's real life.
That's how I feel sometimes.
He was the courageous mob character in
the history of mob characters over the
top,
down the hill,
through the valley,
up the mountain,
through the ocean.
Everyone else can suck his dick.
All of them,
they all can suck his dead.
We were talking about the greatest of
all time.
I think me and shop and a couple other
people were talking about the best
overall character on TV ever.
Yeah,
I think it's got to be Tony Soprano.
I vet or Walter White.
The felons or why?
It's a good bet.
Yeah,
I was.
I was torn between the two and I think I
ultimately went with Walter,
but I might say now because of peer
pressure.
Tony Soprano.
Yeah.
You know,
there's,
there's been some goddamn good ones.
There's like,
but that his character had.
We had so much time to get to know him.
Yeah.
You know,
and that's just so different was that it
was,
wasn't like television style,
like show making.
It was movie making,
but it was a new thing because it was
really complex and you could do it over
a long time.
You could have a season and you're
going,
you know,
you're telling a story over months and
months and you're getting people
addicted.
It's a completely different experience.
And you realized like at a certain
level,
like they,
that show changed everything.
That changed everything.
It was just so next level.
It was.
I never gave a fuck about mob shows.
Yeah,
it was one before that.
In a way.
It wasn't even a mach show in a way.
It was a guy running two families,
a crime family and his own family.
That was.
That was the idea.
So you were looking at a human being and
what I think they did an amazing job was
as evil as he was,
they were putting them in impossible
situations.
You couldn't run that fucking crime
family without being a complete
motherfucker.
Yet he had to run his own family,
make marriage work.
That's it.
I didn't know a lot of people identified
with the impossible life is that way.
Yeah.
It's an extreme example,
but you know,
it's,
it is really.
It's like we could almost,
if you were born that guy and that guy's
family and that guy's life and that
guy's neighborhood with that guys
experiences,
you would be in the exact same situation
as he is right now at chain of events.
From the time you were shot out of your
mother's,
Vijay,
Jj has led you to where you're at.
It's just like looking at those North
Korean people.
Man,
should they pull themselves up by their
bootstraps?
Like what should they do to anyone to
say,
hey,
you know what?
Hey,
where everybody's got to hug.
My friend Mike,
he was born in Africa,
but he said I want to be American.
So he got in the car.
He drove to the airport,
you know,
you know those guys.
If they wanted to,
they could do it.
Like,
do you know what the fuck you said?
You anecdotal asshole.
He told one shitty story about some
supposed friend that probably doesn't
even exist.
It was born in the step.
I remember the argument with them.
It's like if you make.
If you make the sanction strong enough,
his people will get so miserable that
Delta overthrow the go.
You try overthrown that guy when he
kills your whole family.
Yeah.
They're the ruthlessness that these
people operate under.
Like if you live in American,
you haven't experienced war and you
start talking about stuff like that.
Like start talking crazy,
but do you remember there was a time
during the debates that John Mccain,
I think,
I think anytime you've got Sarah Pailin
as your fucking running mate,
you're hamstrung,
right?
I mean you're basically over because no
one,
no one rational is going to say yes to
that.
Like you've got someone have really
clearly marginal marginable
intelligence.
Yeah.
It's a very marginal right.
If you look at the way she communicates,
she's.
She's obviously not very bright.
She's certainly very myopic in her
experience and her perspective.
She's got that down home,
folksy thing going on,
but it's.
It seems,
which is very poorly thought out.
Like there are people that are down home
and folks when you talk to them their
way of communicating,
you can.
You can,
you can still get through that to that
like,
well,
this
is an intelligent nuanced person with a
lot of depth to what they're saying.
This is just the way they they talk to
maybe from Wisconsin.
Maybe it's like Doug Durant,
our friend Doug.
Yeah.
From Wisconsin.
Very,
very smart guy and brilliant.
Yeah.
Brilliant guy.
If you underestimate him because he's a
farmer in Wisconsin,
we'd be in for a surprise.
Yeah,
exactly.
Like the idea that some someone has to
fit into any particular style of
communication just to Napa and we were
talking about what was the wine,
it was canvas,
which is a high end wine,
like $200 a bottle and she was saying
that the guy who makes the wine,
I mean when you buy a winery and a
restaurant,
please be ready to spend if it's
special,
select 325 bucks and you'd think this is
a genius winemaker,
and she was like,
he's a farmer at parties,
piece of farmer.
He grows good grapes and then kind of
does the thing that he was told,
but at the end of the day,
Wagner is a farmer and and you had
underestimated him.
You saw him in his overalls and you'd be
like,
well that guy's one of the best
winemakers in the world.
Will those folks that we were talking to
up in Napa,
the Rainelle is friends.
Friends.
Yeah.
They were all farmers are grape farmers.
The noises people.
They were.
How about that was so cool.
The food was delicious.
As soon as I saw that guy and I saw that
he was cooking,
tried tips.
I'm like,
this motherfucker.
I guarantee you could cook the shit out
of a tri tip.
However you said old California dudes,
old rancher,
California.
Do they know how to cook those tri tips?
Because it tried.
Tip is a very peculiar type of meat.
It's very lean.
You can't overcook it.
You got to cook it the right amount.
It's not a lot of fat on it,
but if you know how to nail it and for
whatever reason,
California ranchers,
dude,
special ed,
they had like a special grill for it.
I think it's called Santa Maria Grill
and it cranks and as you're cranking,
you're like raise or lower it above,
above the heat and you want to make it
you.
It's like you have to.
This is back.
They learned how to do this shit before
they have thermometers was just how the
fork would go into it.
They could figure out like how done it
was just by how the fork felt,
how it slid into it.
So I saw that dude and I saw he was
cooking tips.
I'm like,
Oh,
where we were eating here dude,
because we were thinking about going to
a restaurant.
I was like,
restaurants in the world.
We actually forego or went down because
it was so god damn boy,
that guy was cool as fuck.
And we started talking to him.
Damn it.
Do you remember his name?
And now I want to say Mike,
I know his son is a model for rick or
Mike.
His son who was a nice guy was there is
a model,
I forgot to give him shit for it.
But if someone's a model for a romance
novel Vampire Romance on a lot of
vampire was ah,
you know,
you've made it when you're a model for
vampire romance novels.
And I forgot his name too,
but he was cool.
Very friendly guy,
but he's just some guy.
I interrupted you with my,
my tangential story about that because
you reminded me of it and you were,
you were making a larger point.
What was I saying?
Fuck me.
Whatever it was,
it couldn't be that unfortunately.
Exactly.
Keep it rolling.
Keep it rolling here.
I don't even remember at all.
Hey Man.
We went.
We went Turkey hunting.
You guys look at this quote from the
Denver police,
the Denver police.
They put out a tweet.
I'm.
No,
that's not what it was,
Jamie.
There was one.
It was more hilarious.
Scroll down a little bit.
It was the four slash 20 tweet.
Does it like there is.
No.
They had like a,
like Roland,
Roland,
Roland put it.
It's on my twitter.
Dude.
Just go to my twitter and you'll find
it,
but it's.
It's actually kind of hilarious.
I retweeted it.
I think it's a good patient.
I their there.
Fuck,
look at that in Denver said,
I said even the police or high end for
20.
Look at this.
This is the police.
We see you Roland,
but we ain't hate and ha ha.
Seriously though.
Hashtag Denver.
Please remember to Hashtag consume
responsibly this for 20 weekend.
Good fats and the police department,
like the police department in Denver,
they have little music things there.
What are those?
Emojis?
A little music kimojis for them.
Good for them.
I love it was not the nicest police
department of all time.
They might be.
See,
ladies and gentlemen,
this is what happens when you let a
state gets stoned.
This is what happens.
This is exactly what I've been telling
you forever and it's an action right
now.
This is the police are nicer first
cylinder and nobody was getting
cavities.
Now it's we'd.
Where'd it go?
Colorado is Colorado.
Is Florida in the water.
Good Dude.
Is that,
is that real?
Well,
that's what I think in the fifties,
what they found with certain communities
in Colorado that we're not getting
cavities thing.
It's in Colorado and they couldn't
figure out why.
Why aren't the kids getting cavities?
And they found there's a high level of
Florida and the water naturally.
Yeah.
That does happen,
right?
Like if you have a.
there's some waters that have higher
levels of fluoride,
like natural fluoride.
Yeah.
And apparently there's.
That's one of the things it's supposed
to be not good.
When you drink distilled water,
they say don't know because you want all
those minerals and all that other jazz.
It's in water.
Very much so.
I think,
and I believe you used distilled water
on a plant,
a lot of times the plant dies.
That's what I was told from a farmer,
but some people think that fluoride
ultimately is not good for your body.
Is there any science that goes with
that?
Because people love to quote.
They always say this one thing,
hey man,
calcifies your pineal gland,
and I'm like,
have you done any lab biopsies?
If we have a pretty good big control
group,
like,
like the entire population of the United
States over the past 50 years,
I don't see a lot of people with
calcified pineal gland,
pineal gland.
I don't know if that's even a real thing
for Sarah.
I don't know.
Is it possible guy isn't the pineal
gland?
Yeah,
that's what they're saying is that it
always feels a little stiff.
I can't see out of it.
I'll tell you that much.
And then there's this other one that
they say that maybe snopes this Jamie.
They said you do that fluoride in the
water was pioneered by the Nazis for
mind control,
Dude.
Well get you knew that man.
So with think about that.
Think about that man.
I drink green water wilting in that
because you haven't thought about it.
Big Dude.
You don't even know fucking I'm online.
It was the last time you read about,
besides twilight decides to Info wars
manual of life infowars.com
book.
Besides twilight.
If you're a guy and you're reading
twilight number clauses,
I come out of the closet.
You can be like what you like.
It's all right.
Like what you'd like man,
I was at the Chateau Marmont and that
guy sat and sat at the table with me and
my buddy Frank Grillo or at the guy the
main vampire that throw the fucking guy
from twilight.
Robert Pattinson.
Yes.
And he sat at my table and I stared at
him.
I didn't say hi.
He was very nice and he got up and it's
like nice to meet everybody and I was
like,
see you later.
That's my story about him.
That's an amazing story.
Thank you buddy.
Dude,
you should.
You should write that down.
I met him.
Um,
there's a guy named John Stewart that I
used to work with a on fear factor.
The greatest hilarious dude,
just a guy who had been in show business
forever and he was a straight total pro.
All Right Ladies and gentlemen,
it can't get any better than.
This is just one of those guys.
He would move the contestants through.
Everybody was smiling when they talked
to them.
Just one of those motherfuckers.
He's Kristen Stewart's dad.
Oh Wow.
Makes Sense.
Of course she was raised by a wild man.
He's a cool motherfucker.
He's the coolest long hair,
scraggly hair.
His daughter's school dude,
man has been around forever.
Just a super sweet guy.
I grew up around sets acting.
Yeah,
probably,
but back then like she did a couple
movies and I was like,
dude,
why are you letting your daughter do
that?
Isn't it freak you out?
And she's like,
can I get famous at a young age?
And she wasn't worried about it and then
obviously she became this giant fucking
movie store.
So I'm like,
dude,
lucky he didn't listen to me.
Yeah,
get her out of Alistair.
I was telling you to pull your daughter
selling insurance right now,
the gigantic fucking movie star.
So don't listen to me ever,
or how about that if I give you advice,
but who knows,
man,
truth about fluoride doesn't include the
Nazi myth.
Okay.
So the Nazis a minute.
If history shows,
I actually didn't Nazi Germany and one
of the first things they did was add
fluoride to the water and the ghettos
were the Jews stayed.
Matt Leffler of Cleveland told the
county commissioner Tuesday before.
Well,
what does it say here?
if he's saying,
okay,
what is this is not saying whether it's
real or not real or who knows.
It's just a story on it.
We should figure out like what is the
actual truth?
Where's the story come from?
Here it goes.
What is the story?
Cause no teeth to this claim.
Yeah.
I can almost guarantee you that it is
indeed in the urban myth said,
and the whole injury.
Who handles the media relations with the
US Holocaust memorial museum.
Well,
okay.
Hmm.
Okay.
It seems like it's not real done right.
Or could be.
Wasn't about Nazis,
Florida in water.
It was communist,
but okay.
So it seems like more than likely it was
an urban myth.
Well,
now what about,
this is the thing,
Jamie Google this fluoride calcifies the
pineal gland,
because I just want to get to the bottom
of this.
Get to the bottom of this.
Studies have been done on the pineal
gland.
What happens if,
what's floor?
I do it in there.
When are they going to clone hair?
That's what I want to know.
Ladies and gentlemen,
you can get hairier fluoride,
deposition age,
human pineal gland.
Ooh.
So is it saying to pot?
The purpose was discover.
That purpose was to discover whether
fluoride accumulates in the aged human
pineal gland.
The aims were to determine a f
concentrations of the pineal gland,
wet,
whatever that means.
Corresponding muscle,
wet and bone ash be counseling.
Calcium,
concentration of the pineal,
pineal,
muscle and bone were dissected from 11
aged cadavers.
Okay.
What does it say to or too much reading?
I'll take A.
I'll take a calcium pineal gland then
hold her teeth.
My teeth suck.
Here it goes right here.
Fluoride does not accumulate in the
brain who.
Wait a minute.
Okay,
so it's not,
so you would really do that though.
You would take of calcium and your
pineal gland.
It means saying it's not real,
but what if it was real?
Yeah.
You knew t.
that's right.
Well,
I don't want holes in my teeth.
Go with dentists.
Dentists,
pineal gland.
I do makes Melatonin Shit.
They believe now that it makes
dimethyltryptamine that really heavy
duty psychedelic.
They uh,
it makes a bunch of different things.
Shit,
take Melatonin pills and have good
teeth.
You know what it looks like.
The weird thing about the pineal gland,
have you ever seen the look,
look up a Egyptian image,
pineal gland.
The actual like side,
um,
view of the pineal gland.
I didn't even know it was actually a
real.
I always thought it was like the third
item is,
yeah,
it's a real.
That's what's really fucked up.
Look what it looks like.
It looks like that thing a lot,
that Egyptian solo a lot.
And if you look at the actual structure
of the pineal gland and that I,
what does that,
I suppose to represent?
Probably someone super smart is watching
you bitch too.
It looks like to me,
I mean it's super,
super similar in appearance with the
pineal gland looks like and what that
thing looks like.
If it's dissected and cut.
I'm sure that the Egyptians did their
sheriff cutting brains up and being.
You look at that thing nest.
That's where the pineal gland is way in
the side of the brain.
I thought it was right to write in your
forehead.
No,
it's like,
it's like look where your eyeballs are,
right?
Yeah.
And then it's like literally like right
here and back like right where your
brainstem right in there.
Apparently they think that this
uncertain,
like lower animals like snakes I think
or reptiles.
That thing actually has a retina and a
lens.
I don't see where it says pineal gland
on this thing.
I think that's a backup there,
Jamie.
That's what the gland is and that's
where it is.
Let's see.
You know,
see where.
Where does it show it?
Does it have a buddy?
That's the thalamus buddy was acquitted
of that
pineal gland part one right there.
See pineal gland on the right and there
they are.
Okay.
That's what they're saying here.
Neither of us know what the fucking
pineal gland looks like.
There is a pineal gland is looks like I
said at the base.
How freaky is that?
I don't know.
It's all this.
There's just the.
The knowledge that your brain is making
all these weird chemicals all the time
and keeping them in balance is super
important and you can do it with
exercise and you can do it with like
having positive thinking and getting
outside and the sun and it's also what
is the brain?
That's what sort of what really is it
really is it,
you know,
what kind of some sort of blows my mind.
Some sort of a.
As it's functioning as it's all lit up,
right?
It's some sort of a portal to everything
in the universe and that's really what
the brain is and eventually that,
that thing will get to a point where
it's capable of communicating with
anybody within any reasonable distance
instantaneously.
So as this brain continues to get
stronger,
accumulate more information,
accumulate more technological
breakthroughs that allow it to do more
things and manipulate matter more.
As long as it stays alive,
as long as the human organism stays
alive,
you've thought of it as a giant super
thing.
Yeah.
It's something that if you're looking at
the in terms of the creation of the
earth,
the earth is billions of years old.
It took a long fucking time to go from
the first version of the earth.
All the rocks and the lava and the water
and shit to what we have today.
It takes a long ass time.
Well,
I think the human organism takes a long
ass time to become what it really is and
what it really is,
is the universe figured out how to build
something that can make a universe.
While I was going to say that the human
brand is going to get to a point where
it's able to replicate itself and then
improve on itself and you'll be able to
download other people's brains and
you'll be able to send your download to
other people's brands and you'll have an
experience of what it's like to be that
person and there's some people that
resist this because they say,
look,
we already right now don't know nearly
enough about the biological functions of
human body.
We already right now don't know.
I absolutely understand that and I agree
that they're right.
I,
you know,
I'm not disputing that at all.
What I am saying though is it might not
even matter.
They might be able to come up with
technology that completely circumvents
all the biological bullshit that we have
to deal with as far as like processing
proteins and vital nutrients and all
that horseshit.
We could possibly
bypass that one day by meshing with
machines.
I think it's going to happen.
I really do.
I know you had to.
Aubrey de Grey on your podcast.
I had in my mind,
I'm having them on again,
I had him on my show,
but I'm having them on the podcast real
soon.
Yeah,
because I was talking to him.
He was talking about there are seven
different,
I guess a cell.
There are seven different ways of self
degenerates and they're working on
figuring out ways to stop that
degeneration.
It's a mechanical issue at this point
that they're.
They're isolating how cell breaks down,
why it does and they're going to try to
figure out a way to stop it,
but you know,
I said nanotechnology and stuff.
Wow.
There's a chance that all your work
could be circled circumnavigated by just
that,
that inexorable rise toward,
you know,
just kind of pushing us way beyond our
biology with machines.
And he was like,
yeah,
maybe.
You know,
I just,
I think if you look at it in terms of
the long haul,
well let's just assume that people are
able to stay alive and not below each
other up or not get hit by a meteor for
the long haul.
Let's give us a 100 years to have any
idea how goddamn crazy technology is
going to be in a hundred years.
So anybody looks at it's pooling is we
don't have the capabilities.
Don't you think that that's what they
said back when they lived in caves?
How would we got to block that hole?
We can't do it.
We don't know how they had to figure out
how to make a fucking door.
Okay,
so when you had to figure out how to
make a door to a cave,
somebody had to figure out fire.
Somebody had to figure out stone tools
and then we learned from them.
It all keep steam rolling and apparently
the brain is evolving as well.
The brain is evolving in the way that it
interfaces with computers.
The way we process information,
it's all directly with our way of the
allocation of resources mentally is very
different now than it was before.
You could just ask Google a question is
this is some weird.
Shit's going to happen to the brain
itself.
If we start adding things to it,
if we start putting in little
transmitters or little things,
little little way,
ways to wireless interface with each
other,
you know,
you and I've talked about this,
that experiment that they did where they
sent a word,
they sent a couple of words from one
person to the other person through the
Internet and they received the word.
They were blindfolded.
They,
they,
they put take all these steps to make
sure that the way they're receiving it
was only brain to brain.
Like,
dude,
we're,
we're getting like,
these are the baby steps of some really
crazy shit.
If we could just stay alive.
If you can stay alive for like a hundred
years,
the world will be unrecognizable.
Well,
they say that's the case in 40 or 50.
Ray Kurzweil says in 40 or 50 years it's
going to be.
He might be right.
Yeah.
Because it's moving so exponentially and
the minute machine start replicating
themselves are building better machines.
Yeah.
Comes with a very dark side,
but also comes from a very promising
sign.
Just reject it.
Biologist reject it.
That makes a lot of them do.
But a lot of them do because they think
that they don't.
We don't know enough about the human
mind to even come close to saying that
we could replicate it or download
consciousness into a computer and that
seems to be the truth.
And what I think is it's,
it's going to be the case of technology
reaching a level of capability that we
can't even fathom.
We can't fathom it.
It's.
It's too far away from our little pea
brains right now.
So there could be kind of an interface
that we can't even imagine.
I think that they have to,
if you can imagine it,
I think that human,
the human imagination exists because
that is a window into what is actually
possible.
In other words,
you know,
I think that if you can imagine it,
it's going to be a matter of time before
it actually becomes something you can
measure and see with your eye,
your ear,
or an instrument.
I think it's going to be something that
you can actually touch.
I think anything that like where you're
talking about downloading the human
brain,
communicating the way we communicate
with radio waves,
the way we text texting each other with
our brains.
I don't think that's magic.
I don't think it's far fetched.
I think if you look at the way science
seems to be developing,
it's a matter of when,
not if it's so weird.
If you think about what a human being
is,
if you think about like I've been
watching nature documentaries lately,
man had gone through this one of these
weird stages while I just started
watching documentaries on,
you know,
various animals and the just the cruelty
of the environment that they live in,
the cannibalism and the attacking each
other and life eats life.
Oh,
it's fucking chaos,
man.
We watched this documentary on baboons.
These baboons fucking each other up and
you're like,
Jesus Christ,
trying to protect their babies in the
baboons should the show should have been
called dead baby babble because they
showed us like 10 fucking dead baby
baboons.
This scientist on Ted,
the Ted talk was talking about how
humans are not the only animals that
just kill each other because you know,
because you know the animals kill out of
dominance or our food and stuff,
and he said,
let me tell you something.
This baboons showed up.
He studies baboons babbling shows up in
this whole group and he's kind of an
asshole.
He's just loud.
He's just not being respectful to the
other males.
He just running around because I kind of
tried to fuck the the women without
going through the necessary baboons
steps you got to and he's just loud and
being a pain in the ass.
Well,
the next morning he said,
he said,
he goes,
I knew this bat boom was going to get
it.
I just didn't know how.
Next morning he shows the picture.
All they find is the baboon's face,
the baboon's face basically torn asunder
through whatever,
every direction and just his perfect
face going like that.
Just a silent scream was left on the
ground.
Whoa.
That's what they do.
Cut His face off his face off with what?
Their teeth?
Yeah,
they just bit his head off.
They've been as head away from his face.
Basically.
You've got some big deals.
They do.
They have ferocious looking teeth,
man.
They're.
They're like a dog fucked a monkey.
Yeah,
that's exactly.
It's really what it's
like.
It doesn't look like any other animal.
It's such a weird dog monkey
combination.
Shake pet.
They,
if they,
if the baboons was in a movie,
like if they didn't exist,
but they were in like Lord of the rings,
it would be a terrifying animal.
Like an animal that lived in the forest
that was thinking about like stealing
your babies.
You know,
they eat human babies,
man.
Well my soul champs too,
by the way.
We throw a birthday party for my,
my,
one of my kids and they brought a
baboons.
Oh No.
And I was like,
Oh yeah,
we'll just make it a pattern.
She tends.
She was,
she was a very submissive.
She would fall to the ground and let you
pick bugs from her back.
That's how they show submissive
submission,
but nervous.
She was nervous.
She had big teeth and she was large.
That's all.
Let's,
let's keep about 10,
10 yards back.
Fuck that.
Yeah.
Well that's not fair.
That animals shouldn't be there.
Software,
the animal you're putting the animal
without even understanding its language.
You putting it in this incredible
stressful situation where it's around
kids look at the fucking teeth on that.
That's a male.
Oh my God.
The monsters.
Just monsters.
Look at the teeth.
It's like a werewolf.
It is that what it insanely crazy
looking animal.
Like if that was in a movie and they
always chasing after Bilbo Baggins,
you would totally buy it.
You'd be like,
oh my God,
that's a werewolf.
How is that not a werewolf?
I mean,
look at the fucking teat on that thing.
Those are stills are giant teeth,
man.
Those fangs are so disproportionately
large.
Yeah.
Do the females have teeth like that?
Probably.
Damn.
Look at that thing.
Jesus Christ color.
Oh my God.
Dude.
Below that picture up.
Look at the fucking face on that thing.
Yeah.
But look at the,
uh,
female genitalia and the other picture.
And that's what I'm looking at.
Look at that.
That's just retarded.
But with a face to like,
this is real,
like,
okay,
if human beings didn't exist,
if we just didn't exist at all on earth,
this fucking thing would be out there
just like it is now if we never would
never existed.
Yeah.
If we just.
We never figured out houses.
We never,
we just.
We died off a long fucking time ago.
That thing would be out there just like
that.
That thing would be out there a million
years from now.
Just like that.
Look at that fucking monster.
I mean we made it to 2015 with cell
phones and jet airplanes and microwave
ovens and tvs and laptops and that
fucking primate that came up with us.
This fucker didn't make it out of the
neighborhood.
That's what they always say is the
fundamental difference between human
beings and animals.
Even though we're an animal,
we're the only animal with potential,
with the only animal that continues to
evolve.
We evolve within our own lives.
Yeah.
We,
we can see in the future,
you're really observant of yourself and
correcting of yourself.
You'll continually evolve.
Yeah.
You're going to be smarter and 10
generations and that baboons,
they're all going to be the same way
they will have.
That's interesting that you said that
because I want to keep hate,
keep saying radiolab,
but there was another podcast they did
about instincts and how you could change
the entire behavior of a tribe of
baboons.
If they got rid of this one alpha male.
That was like fucking everybody up.
Really?
Yeah.
They got rid of twitter.
They got rid of one alpha male that was
fucking everybody up and then something
happened.
I forget what the actual event was that
caused them to be submissive to each
other and grooming each other and then
they just kind of kept up with it and
then they came back years later
expecting to see the same sort of
violent behavior that they've witnessed
before,
but no,
they had this.
They had developed this like peaceful
baboons tribe,
which is.
There is no.
There was no threat.
What was it?
A way?
Lesser Threat.
They're still fucking baboons,
but apparently the way they dealt with
each other was way more relaxed like and
they.
That was really confusing to these
biologists who observed it.
It was very unexpected,
I should say.
Shouldn't say confusing.
I mean it was a welcomed discovery.
I'm sure he realizing like,
wow,
how much of behavior,
okay.
Like we're talking about North Korea and
we're talking about America in 2015.
Look at the difference between the way
that cultures are allowed to communicate
and express themselves.
Just by this podcast.
You could see the difference between
someone who lives in a crazy,
crazy dictatorship that they're living
in is happening in the same timeline.
Yeah,
it's happening right now.
Well,
it goes back to also when you first
started this podcast about talking about
most people that are great and there's a
couple of assholes.
It takes only a couple of assholes in
charge to change the character of an
entire society to and make people behave
in a very crazy way.
Those baboons changed when you took away
the alpha.
I wonder if North Koreans would be
crying for three hours straight if they
didn't have a fucking alpha male running
their tribe.
Who is that much of a fucking monster?
Obviously not.
I wish I could remember the exact
specifics of what caused them to chill
out.
Didn't remember too much information in
my head.
I'm having a real problem with that
lately.
I got to regulate the amount of
information that's going in my head and
then go over it with a fine tooth comb.
I think I feel like I'm taking in all
day way too much data.
I feel that way too.
Like I forgot.
I can't really remember names and
specifics.
I have to start talking in general terms
because I'm afraid I'll make a mistake.
I'm talking really about individual
stories and individual subjects of news
especially because I feel like if you
got online every day and start scouring
the news and looking for interesting
things and seeing the latest video to
see the silver back gorilla that slammed
into the cage at the zoo.
No.
Oh,
ready?
Tight.
Tighten up your belt.
My favorite day.
There's a little kid that starts doing
some chest thumps.
No.
Yes she does.
And the silverback ain't hearing it.
Watch this.
This is fucking crazy dude.
So you see the little kid.
You could see her in the corner.
She's pounding are her hands on her
chest and this why we never fixed that.
The shitty video quality thing.
Those little things we bought didn't fix
it.
Okay.
Coco the gorilla with Robin Williams.
We still have that really super shaky
video for some reason.
Yeah.
Coco the gorilla.
I can't believe he let that thing touch
them.
They're a lot less dangerous than a.
They say gorillas have their own
personality,
so some can be really mean.
It's not going to be really sweet.
She was super sweet,
but if she wanted to just pull your dick
off stuff at through your eyeball.
She could anytime she wanted to.
It might be a guy,
isn't it?
Is it?
I think it's a girl.
How thick.
Oh Wow.
So he just pulls him down to look at
that.
Oh my God.
Can you go full screen on that or is
that when screws up.
Oh,
good God.
Well that's like an alien dude.
You know?
Look at that.
Wow kisses his hand.
Oh Shit.
This is an amazing time.
This is a bizarre video.
I guess I wouldn't be so nervous that
things really peaceful.
Look at him.
Wow.
It took his glasses and put his glasses
on.
Whoa.
See that's when it gets really weird.
Nigo what?
What do you mean?
What are we dealing with here?
This is like a life form that speaks a
some sort of a sign language with human
beings so it understands what you're
saying.
It just can't vocalize the noises that
we wanted to in order to communicate,
but man,
that is a crazy animal right there.
If that thing didn't exist,
fuck big foot.
I'll just say it right now.
Fuck.
Big Foot and his dirty crusty ass.
Big flips.
Not nearly as cool as a Goddamn St.
tickle me.
You're going to take all the girl isn't
a Nazi signs.
Tickle guys want to see stronger.
That thing is to me.
Oh,
what are you talking about?
You can't even fathom it at a different
level.
It's not even the same.
It's just not fair.
It's like how much stronger you then a
flower.
Well,
how about just Brennan?
Who grabbed me around the waist the
other day and he was like yesterday.
I was trying to get out.
First of all,
I try to shoot a single leg on him.
Look at that.
No,
keep it.
Give it to look at this.
This is so crazy.
It's just looking at that body.
Get them laughing.
It's so.
It's nuts that each other with great
pet.
You're hilarious.
Stupid gorilla in your house until he
decides that he wants to eat your food.
Right now they actually are a strict
vegetarians.
Which people find a shocking.
Yeah,
there and people are like,
hey man,
this is totally evidence that you can
eat in all plant diet and you can be
immensely massive muscular or it's
evidenced that gorillas are different
than people.
They always say,
well,
both are so strong and their total
vegetarians.
Go eat grass and then run a mile.
See how you feel.
Yeah.
Good luck with that.
You have four stomachs.
Whatever the fuck it is.
Yeah.
We're different men.
That's a gorilla to different than a
person doesn't.
It needs only Broccoli.
Coco checks his ID.
That is hilarious.
Science tickles.
I went to the Santa Barbara Zoo like
maybe six months ago or so,
and they have gorillas there and uh,
you just get right up next to him in the
glass and you look in and you see them
walking around and they're,
you know,
they're essentially just a few yards
from you just right there walking
around.
It's kind of fucked up in San Diego.
Santa Barbara.
Yeah.
It's kind of fucked up because you
really shouldn't be able to just look at
a gorilla because if you just look at
them in real life,
they run at you,
they'd make them.
You ever seen that bluff charge they
make that is pull a video of that
terrorism.
Makes Silver.
Black silverback.
Makes Bluff charge.
Do we figure out why this is so crammed
the shape?
D glass after?
Yeah.
Here he goes.
Look at this boom day.
Do you have any idea how fucking strong
he must be a south.
And that was just because she was on her
chest and then nuts,
man gets charged by Ma.
What does that say?
Gorilla those second one down?
Is that the one that.
I think one of the largest silver back
500 pounds.
Try that one.
Bluff,
charge 500 pounds silver,
but we'll get the belly to belly.
That's parasites,
Bro.
Is that what that is?
I don't know,
but that's a crazy belly.
I'm disgusted and ashamed.
Do you think that gorilla cares about
his gut?
I don't freak them out.
Is that a girl you think or a guy?
Um,
I think it's a guy that looked very
girl,
like for some reason,
like maybe she was pregnant.
Oh,
maybe she was.
Yeah.
I feel like that's probably the silver
back.
That's probably why the silver box going
to bum rush the show.
That is the silver.
You imagine these assholes are actually,
I say assholes with all due affection
and admiration,
but these dudes are in the middle of the
fucking jungle.
Just walking around with cameras in
front of wild gorillas.
Not to mention there a bunch of really
bad people in the Rwandan juggles.
I think Joseph Kony hangs out there
sometimes.
Yeah.
And his Hutu militia is what?
A freaking animal.
A gorilla is super intelligent thing.
It's enormous.
Possibly strong.
Just strong eats vegetation and is so
strong,
it could just rip you apart with the
hands and that's how it gets by.
It gets by,
not by killing everything around it gets
by,
by being able to kill so many things
that everybody just goes fuck that.
That's why they nest on the ground.
It's unbelievable gorillas.
They could,
if a gorilla wanted to pull himself up a
tree,
it would be pretty fucking easy.
But they don't nest in trees and proud
of it.
I'm sure that's a great.
That's a pregnant girl.
Is pregnant part of it.
Um,
because she looks like a female looks.
She's because I'm a biologist.
I don't know if you know,
she just looks less horrifically strong
than the male is.
She's more like soft and fuzzy.
I didn't.
They find out originally they used
tools.
They definitely like will dig with
sticks to dig,
to get roots and shit.
No,
they're all,
they all vegetation.
That's what they,
they're all about vegetation.
I'm sure that they have probably figured
out some sort of tool to do something
and we just make sense man.
I mean,
it's not like they're building the
wheel,
constructing houses.
I think it's still food to a bear.
Look at the size of grizzly bears,
size of that thing.
I don't know about all that.
Five hundred pounds.
How much do they weigh?
A lot more.
A lot more,
but it's a different kind of weight,
is it?
Yeah.
I mean,
no grizzly bears are ridiculous.
Strong animal,
but a fucking big five slash 600 pound
gorilla.
He might fuck a grizzly bear up.
He might smack a grizzly bear and his
head,
grizzly bear might be stupid to tangle
with this thing.
Hard to hurt.
He looks like his head was well.
The grizzly bears are impossible to her.
He ever seen them fight each other.
It's insane.
So what's the bear going to do it?
Unless he knows the Jujitsu,
he's kind of.
I mean the girls got to get behind them
and choke them with the grill.
Going to do the grills.
Going to just smack them in the head.
Just pound them,
bite and throw them.
Maybe freak the fucking bear out into
thinking that this thing is way scarier
though a bear.
Yeah,
but as far as if they went to the death,
depends on how big the barriers and how
big the gorillas.
Oh,
guess what?
Those are so fucking smart though.
I would think that they would figure out
a way.
What would you fuck a.
either where they are,
because they're wild too.
I mean the reason why they have those
giant canines,
that's the fight they fight other
gorillas.
Yeah.
It's just a matter of does he have like,
like a grizzly bear.
You know what's interesting about the
way grizzly bears kill?
So we were.
It was really kind of creepy.
It seems that animals that kill a
variety of things or animals that eat a
variety of things,
I should say a real omnivores which
bears are real.
I'm no worse.
They don't necessarily kill things
before they start eating them.
Right.
They just hold them down.
I know there've been a lot of like in
grizzly man,
I think the guys start getting his legs
eaten first.
Yeah,
and for like seven minutes the video
goes on lens caps on what you just
hearing the sound of him screaming.
Oh,
and her screaming and this is going on
for seven fucking eating him alive in
Christ and that's how they kill you.
They eat you alive.
Fuck.
That's not at all they want to do is
hold you because there is so much
bigger.
There is so much bigger than you.
So the thing has pawned my chest and
he's just wilson down on my quads.
Mostly your gut or your asshole,
they'll.
They'll go asshole first.
Yeah.
Apparently that's how coyotes kill the
kill asshole.
First.
A deer like they've found deer that were
locked up together.
I mean it's like sometimes when deer
for.
I know you know this,
they will.
They're the men are fighting and the men
their horns because they slam heads
together.
Sometimes they wedged their horns
together in a way that they literally
can't get out and there's a video of
these.
You find this video of these two bucks
that are connected together and one of
them dead because it was eaten alive by
these coyotes in the coyotes ate it,
asshole first.
So the whole back legs and the haunches
and the assholes all torn out like they
ate all of that and,
and this other deer is still connected
to him.
Well then he must have been like,
eat a little more please.
No,
it's,
it's like that.
But the,
the,
it's a video and they're,
the actual carcass is still attached to
the other one.
Like it's not like that.
It looks awful.
It doesn't look like a full deer.
It looks like the bottom half is
halfway.
No,
that's not it.
No.
I guess you start to see if you could
find it.
Um,
I forget the exact way it was phrased in
the title.
Something about a hunter's rescue.
Buck.
One Dead,
one alive.
I don't know.
It might be it.
That's weird.
It might be it so weird.
It's hard to tell God that video looks
like Shit.
It was wobbly.
Okay.
It's just pictures.
That's why I was like,
that's ridiculous video ever.
Uh,
that's not it.
The actual one was these two.
Doesn't matter.
You can find it folks if you've got more
time than us,
but they,
um,
they lock horns,
they get stuck in the coyotes.
Just eat them,
asshole first.
That's how they do it.
I don't want,
I don't want it to turn me over and eat
my,
but how about you going to stare and
your buddy's eyes while you're connected
together by the head while he's getting
his asshole eaten?
You got to wear a fucking stuck because
coyotes never.
They mean they catch Fonz.
They never catch a full grown buck like
that.
A full grown buck,
a big 150 pound animal with giant Horn
licious.
Coyotes are like,
that's too much work.
Yeah,
for the most part,
I bet you a diet already.
And then came in here because the other
one was kicking them away.
They were like,
let's eat this.
End of wonder doesn't move.
But they're connected together by the
head.
I don't know.
Who knows?
Interesting point being.
This is my whole point at the beginning
of all this nonsense.
I think that the need for separateness,
like the need to defend yourself,
the need to attack the need for
aggression was all instilled and
whatever animal to human being
ultimately became all instilled to allow
it to stay alive through the darkest
times,
the most primal times.
Because without that aggression,
guess what?
Fuck face.
You're not going to make it to 2015.
If you remove aggression from human
history were bare food.
We're coyote food.
We're mountain lion.
Food were,
fill in the blank.
If you remove the need to figure out a
way to stop the world around you from
swallowing you up,
you need to have a certain amount of
personal sovereignty and a certain
amount of aggression.
You have to fight off anything that is
predatory.
Anything that has to threaten the
survival of your very species until you
figure out how to get it together.
So go from the beginning when people
made the first houses to figuring out
how to make it gates to keep other
people out,
to figuring out how to,
how to keep themselves safe from
predatory animals and all those steps
were like super necessary to get to
today,
but at a certain point in time,
when do we outgrow that expression that
were so dominant over all the other
animals?
We don't have to worry about that
anymore and the only problem we have
with each other,
it seems to be like allocation of
resources.
I was about to say that's the big one.
You Watch how fast people devolve.
As soon as there's a.
there's a limited source of water and
you're going in their car or whatever,
may not have enough water for the day.
That's when things get really
interesting.
It's all a question of this.
What I mean,
most of most tribes that fought there
was always that situation.
It was a fight over resources or water
rights or whatever it might.
You know that they're pioneering a new,
a desalination plant in San Diego.
They're going to spend some untold
buckets,
a load of cash.
Yeah,
and they're going to make this
desalination plant.
If that's true.
What you want to do is buy real estate
on Catalina island because it's going to
be a road that leads out to the
[inaudible].
We're going to dry out the ocean.
People are creeps desalinization.
Once they figured out desalinization,
we're just going to be sucking the ocean
off every day.
We're just going to be pulling billions
of gallons.
People are like,
if we don't stop drinking out of the
ocean,
it will be dry by 20,
75 by 20,
75.
All the water will be in like golf
courses and bottled water facilities.
There'll be no water in the whole ocean.
Just big dry hole.
Well,
they did that.
Went to the LLC.
The LLC was the the ecological disaster.
That was the llc and then it dried up in
Russia and they dried up because people
pulled the water out of it.
It just.
It would be a logical disaster for a lot
of reasons and apparently the algae grew
so much and there's too much hydrogen in
the water and then it is a thousand
things and they were siphoning the water
off with dams and rivers and it became a
disaster.
Dried up articles,
see eco disaster and saying,
hey,
go arrow,
arrow,
Arrow,
look out there and you can just see
boats that are just on dry land.
Huge Ocean liners.
Now these things like how quick does do
these things happen?
Like when,
when,
uh,
see dries up,
do they get a 10 year window?
Do like,
well,
I think the LLC took about 40 years to
dry out,
but look at the boats out there that you
still see that was all,
see all of it.
And,
and because of mismanagement and,
and,
and using the water irresponsibly for
agriculture.
And so damming up parts of it,
running off parts of it,
they literally got rid of the C and
that's,
that's the eco disaster.
So this was all because of human
engineering?
Yes.
Oh my God.
So that was a natural sea and human
engineering lead it to dry up.
That's.
That's insane.
Yeah.
It's also very common,
that kind of shortsighted thinking.
But it is also fascinating because
you're looking at the underlying
mechanisms of the very thing we were
talking about that this human animal is
like figuring out all kinds of shit all
the time and it has the power to reshape
land now.
Make areas uninhabitable with an error,
you know,
or bring them to life with an error.
Right.
The salt and sea,
the salt and sea for like a long time,
like a couple of decades was this
amazing spot where people would go on
vacation.
They called it like California's
Riviera.
There was a seed that they created by
opening up the Colorado River.
It was an accident.
The whole thing was an accident.
Well,
you know,
so now it's an eco disaster to it is.
Oh yeah,
now it's horrifically salty and filled
with runoff from all the agriculture all
across the state and all that shit
that's trickling down from up north and
all the water systems.
It's going into there a lot of you
getting runoff from farms and getting
all sorts of fish.
That's,
that's where it is,
man.
They have millions of fish die off the
salt and sea.
That's millions.
The Salton Sea has so many dead bones on
its beaches that its beaches are
actually dried fish bones.
Wow is beaches.
There's entire beaches that are
completely covered with white dead fish
bones and you're walking in it and you
don't realize until you look down on
that gray.
That is all that is.
Fish bones to see that that person's
walking,
taking footsteps in fish bones that are
so plentiful that they looked like sand
and this is still efficient.
It.
Saddam Hussein was empower in Iraq.
There was an area,
um,
I think in the south of Iraq.
It was in their lives.
People called.
They called the Marsh Arabs who had been
there for Millennia.
And when he did,
he found out that a lot of Iranian,
you know,
a lot of the Iranian forces were using
it as sort of a hotbed of insurgency and
also using it for our strategic stuff
for the Iran,
Iraq war.
He in one of the greatest ecological
disasters ever committed by one man
drained the entire marsh and go,
if you go to pictures,
good pictures of the Marsh Arabs in Iraq
in the seventies and you'll see what it
looked like.
They,
they'd been living there for thousands
of years.
Thousands.
It goes all the way back to Alexander
the Great and he drained it in the
course of less than a year and burned.
It gets back to what we were talking
about when we were,
um,
in the car.
We're talking about hardcore history in
the Mongols at that,
the way they used to live.
Some people just take things that's a
painting though.
Some people just take things to a
completely different level when it comes
to like aggression and psychotic
behavior and it becomes a total game
changer.
It just like no one knows what to do,
takes hundreds of years to recover from
what this person does.
Say that the Middle East never really
recovered from what the Mongols did in
2012,
2012 slash six or 12 slash 20 or
something,
whatever it was,
somewhere in the 1200 they were saying
about Iraq.
That was one of the big ones at Baghdad
at one point in time was like one of the
cultural centers of the world filled
with intellectuals,
but after the Mongols came to
description was that the river ran red
with blood and black with ink,
so all of these scholars who at the time
like people have this idea of Islam,
especially when it comes to history like
the history of the world as being just
like barbaric or very violent group
that's willing to kill you because they
draw their.
Their cartoon character guy was
obviously.
There are people like that out there
that are because of that that believe in
that.
But if you go back to the history of the
religion,
like at one point in time they were at
the front of the line when it came to
science and philosophy.
They were at the front of the line and a
lot of people argue that what the
Mongols did literally changed the age of
the enlightenment for them,
right,
because what it does,
but it allowed what they did,
the Chinese and the end,
the Middle East,
the allowed the Europeans who are
nowhere close to as technologically
advanced as philosophically or even as,
as,
um,
culturally advanced as say the Middle
East.
It allowed them to gain ground on both
China and the Middle East because of
what the Mongols did to them because
they destroyed in the course of,
you know,
over the years just destroyed that.
The centers of their civilization,
their infrastructure,
their,
their canals for,
uh,
agriculture,
all of their.
Essentially their culture killed their
best and their brightest.
Yeah,
it's really amazing how many people were
killed.
When you look at the,
the,
the number that Dan Carlin site to
somewhere around $50 million.
They believe God the died within his
lifetime as a result of the decisions
that he made and the orders that he had
carried out somewhere on 50 million
people.
He believed,
you know,
one of the things he ends up,
he ends the thing with saying,
I'm say we will,
his,
his for the force of his nature,
the strength of his nature.
He truly believed he was this divine
spirit who had a mission
to remake the world in his,
in his mind's eye,
like he was the center of the universe
and everything belonged to him and his
legacy.
So what a,
what a,
what a crazy way to think to begin with.
And the fact that it worked and he did
it all on horseback.
Yeah.
Did it all on horseback and he had an
amazing ability,
which one of the.
One of the things I found most unique
about this,
a narration by Dan Carlin was when he
was talking about how the guy would win,
he would find people that were really
talented,
that were the enemy.
He would recruit them like a guy shot
him off of his fucking horse,
shot his horse from under him,
and then he made him one of his generals
and he named him the Arrow call this Guy
Chubby,
chubby.
The Arrow.
Like the idea that you would take a guy
who tried to fucking kill you and shot
your horse out from under you and then
say,
dude,
you're a pretty fucking good shot.
You give him some knuckles and you want
to fucking kill everybody in the world
together.
Like our item in these guys know I had
an orgy together or something.
Did some opium and had a good old time.
Yeah.
He felt that he could spot talent.
Well,
he would take people that were.
You would capture people and he would
find out.
Does anybody do anything?
Any you motherfuckers have any skills
because if you don't have any skills I'm
going to kill you.
But if you've got some skills,
let me know what you do.
Right.
You know,
and people would say I'm a surgeon or
hey I don't whether even surgeons back
then probably I could have been a.
and how with that you would have been
like,
I'm a black belt in Jujitsu.
What's that?
Come roll with me.
I'll show you some shit.
C'Mon.
Survive.
Oh,
I would have to.
That's what I would have to do.
Blood.
Come on when you bitches with Russell,
just get them to see a team.
Real quick bar.
I bet they knew some shit actually need
to think about it like in wrestling,
but do you think it went back as far as
$1,200?
It had to have.
It had to have been the.
I don't know if much of they talked
about it because they were so busy
killing each other with arrows and
swords and shit and spears and
catapults.
I don't think the wrestling was
paramount.
You're talking about a group of people
though that that fought with their hands
up close,
eyeball to eyeball.
Did it and I'm all the guys that we're
talking about who are coming into your
village or your town had had plenty of
experience with that in that space.
When you're fighting for your life,
when you're really killing somebody,
I'd imagine it it.
It's a very different muscle.
If you're using very different muscles,
you're using a very different mindset.
So I would imagine they had a lot of
Marshall Sense.
They probably were pretty,
pretty good with hand to hand combat.
Yeah,
they probably knew like.
I mean,
you think about like the,
the early days of martial arts,
there was most certainly a lot of faulty
technique and faulty ideas that they had
not taken the most,
the most effortless path or the most
technical path.
They hadn't figured it out yet.
Like there's,
there's certainly some evidence that
indicates that because by the time we
got like the highest versions of martial
arts in like the fifties and the sixties
and seventies,
if you really compare some of the top
guys to like what's,
what's possible today.
It seems like it's evolved like many,
many,
many times.
You know,
like.
So I think Hector Lombard me down on any
fucking Mongols,
every one that ever walked there
punching through your fucking stupid
Mongols.
But those Ruslan providing the cough
type dudes does like the same type of
dude.
It's like that guy's an animal.
Do you see those pictures of him and the
post fight where he pissed black?
No.
Yes,
he put it on his instagram.
He's doing his urine sample and he
pissed black.
God.
Yeah,
him and Lucas.
But I haven't even seen the fight yet.
I got it saved on my dvr on the road.
They went to war apparently is fucking
unbelievable fight apparently.
I haven't seen it.
Is this,
was this use Hbo Boxing?
Oh,
I'm sorry.
Black urine shows.
Real brutality of boxing.
Like look at his instagram.
He's this total is instagram.
Look at that.
Look at that picture,
man.
That's it.
That's on a diet coke.
That's his piss.
What?
Yup.
That's what his urine came out like.
Oh No.
After 12 arounds of.
Whoa.
God Damn it.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
He's,
he took.
How about that fight with Bradley?
It was the craziest one I've ever seen
him.
Amazing fight and I think that uh,
that the genetics that come from that
area from Siberia and from the step and
Mongols and the genetics of survivors of
hundreds of years,
thousands of years of oppression and war
and he's like almost a distillation of
like the strongest,
strongest survive just to be born and
lived to maturity.
People don't like that because it seems
to like to indicate some sort of cruelty
of nature,
but I think to really not be objective
about it is real cruelty because then
you're.
If you're not,
if you're not expressing it for what it
really is,
you're not.
You're not seeing it for what it really
is and expressing it in an honest way.
If you're expressing it through an
ideology,
you doing everybody a massive disservice
because it's pretty obvious that
aggression was necessary and beneficial
to get us to here.
I think everybody recognizing that would
help the idea of like,
okay,
so if we really did need to do certain
military actions in order to stop
certain psychos from,
from growing and marching forward and
taking over giant chunks of land just
like they have throughout the Mongol
days and this person and Filipinos and
the grain,
there's always been someone that does
that.
Right?
So you need some sort of defense to hold
that off or we agreed and then anybody
who doesn't agree,
then you've got a real Koombaya problem
because he got to go,
listen,
dude,
have you ever seen really crazy people?
Have you ever been around someone who's
willing to kill you for money,
for fame,
for women,
and for your water?
Water rights.
There's.
There's people out there that aren't
playing by the rules.
You're playing.
Where did you grow up?
Pasadena.
That's a great place.
Pasadena is a great plant.
The Tar tar steps.
It's not Istanbul.
You fuck.
It's not in the middle of.
It's on the middle of Baghdad in a place
that doesn't even have a roof anymore
because the soldiers blew it off with
their robot flying thing.
No changes you.
Yeah,
of course it does.
Of course it does.
So anybody that doesn't think you need
some sort of military force until that
is all eradicated.
So that becomes the real question.
You've got to figure out how do you
eradicate all the shitty pockets of life
on earth.
And I don't mean like eradicate the
peep.
I mean eradicate the problems that make
those people shitty and that seems to be
by the way,
because you,
you have to eradicate the problems and
the way a country,
the institutions that that give rise to
evil people.
If you have a society that's structured,
if you have institutions that are
structured so that the only way to get
ahead is if you're a bad.
If you're.
If you're an amoral motherfucker that
then you're going to have people like
gang gangs con at all.
Rise to the top.
You can't.
It's the way society is structured,
you know,
they always talk about we have to cure
poverty or whatever.
The United States is powerful because of
its strength of institution.
It's powerful because we have courts
that mean something because we have
property rights where you own a house
and you actually are secure as an
American that somebody's not going to
come in and take your house.
Very few countries share that luxury
today in 2015 and courts that are
objective that just because you have a
lot of money,
and I know this is there exceptions to
this,
but just because you have a lot of
money,
you're getting off for sure.
No,
we have courts where if you have a lot
of money and you kill somebody and you
get caught,
you have big problems.
If you're a cop and you're caught on
video shooting,
somebody you have big problem with.
Cops don't have a lot of money,
but rich people have been able to really
finagle systems,
good lawyers.
That is a problem and it certainly is a
problem,
but not to the extent that it is in so
many other countries.
The corruption is not as blatant as it
is in so many other countries.
I think there's no denying that.
I think the real question becomes,
um,
of,
of one of the customary actions that
we've taken.
Because W,
what I mean by that is if you look at
people from where we are right now at
the 21st century,
2015,
and you consider what people were like
just maybe a 100 years ago,
200 years ago,
like there's never really been a time
where people have had this method of
communicating with each other.
So when we used to,
we didn't,
not only do we not know what was going
on in Japan,
we had no connection to it.
You would read some stuff on paper.
There's a guy from Japan and what's a
fuck us up?
This is crazy and you would have no
connection to those people and you just
knew there's a people over there just
just like Lord of the rings,
just like,
you know,
fill in the blank.
Any war movie from the,
you know,
the mon goals to whatever the Romans,
the,
this idea that you would have this group
of people that was waiting to come over
and fuck you up.
That
doesn't really work anymore.
It does.
Because there's satellites everywhere.
We see everything.
We send information,
everybody.
But this has all happened inside of our
lifetime,
so there's been a change that's taken
place that I don't think we're really
fully aware of yet.
There's this weird connection thing that
we have to literally,
everybody on the world will also
remember that when you had an enemy,
even as far as even in World War II with
the first thing you did was you got your
soldiers to believe that,
that that enemy they were.
They were subhuman,
they weren't human,
they were subhuman and you see it over
and over again.
Again,
that's becoming harder and harder to do.
Dan Carlin not to bring it back to him,
was also talking about how when you
fought them enemy in world war one and
you,
you encountered your first line of
Germans or whatever.
You didn't know how far back that line
went.
You didn't know if there are a million
of them or if there were 100,000
or 2000.
So you just fought sort of not knowing
to not only the effect you're having on
their,
on their forward momentum,
but also on their general population to
begin with.
Like you were fighting and when they
stopped fighting it,
then you find out,
Holy Shit,
there were a million of them.
We just fought these guys,
so just think about that.
Now we know where their regiments are.
We know how far back they go.
We know exactly how many people there
are.
We can plan accordingly and not only
that we can talk to each other.
That's what was missing was missing was
the only people that are talking to each
other with generals.
The generals and presidents were like
the only people talking to each other.
Listen Bitch,
we're gonna fuck you up.
Nope,
we're going to fuck you up for God,
Bitch.
God's on our side.
And wars would start because of these
alliances and they would just,
they would just be like,
well,
we're going to fight and break this
alliance and then you'd find out about
it as a,
as a citizen,
you'd be like,
but I'm farming my land.
No,
no.
How the fuck that Japanese got together
with the Germans and the Italians.
How the fuck did that happen?
Which war?
World War II.
Like would it be.
I mean,
I know how it happened,
but how the fuck if you look at the
personalities of the different groups of
people and the languages they speak
three completely different fucking
languages,
three complete,
completely different types of people and
all their dictated had a lot of trade
and a lot of connection.
I mean,
but,
but one of the things that the Germans,
I mean,
Hitler wanted to create an access,
sort of an access to a sort of a new
world order and he had a great deal of
respect for the Japanese.
He considered the Japanese,
the Ariens of the east,
and he had enormous respect for the
British really areas of the.
He loved their yellow fever,
Szeto,
which was the idea that way of the
warrior.
Japan had been in a low grade war for a
civil war for really a thousand years.
I mean,
it was just constant battles between
Laura feudal shoguns like these,
these,
these fiefdoms shogun would run
fiefdoms.
He'd hire mercenaries and they would
just fight for land.
And that went on for a really 310 years,
about a thousand.
That's why the swordsman and their
ability,
they're there,
they were legendary archers and they
were just legendary and ferocious.
I mean,
when the Portuguese were trading with
them,
they came back and the first thing they
said to their European rulers is they
said,
hey,
couple things you don't want them doing,
learning how to sail long distances and
learning about a little something we
call gunpowder.
Don't give them gunpowder.
They are straight up the most ferocious
group of motherfuckers on the planet.
If they're late for something,
they immediately request to kill
themselves because they've dishonored
their,
their fanatical to authority.
And you know,
that,
that Plu,
this tiny island took up,
took over a great deal of the world.
Um,
they,
there,
they were insanely warlike and
impossibly disciplined
and their version of martial arts.
So this day is being taught.
I mean,
once you understand all the,
like Leo Machida who lost this weekend,
but still,
you know,
a great all time fighter and he's an
amazing martial artist and his styles
showed,
oh,
con based.
It's based on that style is another two
dozen Japanese mentioned.
So really Jujitsu is as well,
I mean Brazilian Jujitsu was modified by
the gracies,
modified by Helio and,
and Carlos Carlos,
they modified it in turned Jujitsu into
what it would ultimately become.
They spent much more time on the ground
fighting then the judoka cause.
But a lot of the judo cause even like a
lot of their techniques came from,
there was an infusion of techniques
where there's some sort of a blurry
crossroads between catch wrestling and
judo and some catch wrestlers.
I'm also taught in Japan,
like Karl gotch and Billy Robinson,
those guys taught a lot of people in
Japan,
like Sakharova was a student of catch
wrestling.
And so he imparted that like sort of,
uh,
a lot of catch wrestling,
submission holds that style of
attacking.
He incorporated that in a lot of MMA
fights and started a lot of people,
not just in Japan but all over the world
fighting that style.
So I think there's like,
there's many different versions of what
Japan has brought out to the rest of the
world.
There's many different versions.
But as far as like martial arts,
it's one of the biggest contributors.
Like ever,
they just figured out I quito,
they figured out judo that figured out
Jujitsu and figured out submissions in a
way that you really can't find parallel
at the time.
I definitely think that the Jujitsu is
better now than ever before and I think
I credit that to the Brazilians.
I credit that to the gracies in Brazil
to this day still has a huge number of
super high level Jujitsu guys worldwide.
It's evening out way more than it ever
has before,
but I mean just the overall output and
the origins of it in the fact that it's
still called Brazilian Jujitsu.
Everybody calls a Bjj for a reason.
Yep.
You know,
they,
they deserve all the credit.
And then there's still guys like Jocko
ray with jock already did this weekend
and Chris Kamozi that armbar setup that
transition,
like it's such a hero magician,
artistic,
artistic.
It was one of the most spectacular forms
of,
of like a submission of applying a
submission in a scramble that I've ever
seen.
Me Too.
I was just,
I didn't even know that he's doing.
And what,
um,
how do you defend against that?
You can't defend against that.
He's an artist.
I was going to put it on my twitter
feed.
I'll re a retweet it earlier today,
but I think grappling world on twitter,
I think that's the ones who put it up.
It's uh,
they,
they put up a little 15 second gif.
I guess it is.
Whatever it is on instagram and you get
to watch it.
It's,
it's insane.
He's so good.
He's so God damn good.
It makes you wonder though,
like with the Japanese going back to
them how good they were at as swordsmen,
like what they could've done.
The Samurai.
So that's again,
I think what we were talking about,
what the Mongols like,
they spent so much time on weapons
because that's how you fought most of
the time.
Like how much time are they really
spending on learning how to kick people
in the face?
Yeah.
It's probably like a lot of what we
think about the way people used to kick
and punch and it's based on movie
depictions of it and in movies like
enter the dragon or in these kind of
crazy movies there.
They're trying to do the most impressive
stuff so they're throwing.
We'll kicks and jumping,
roundhouse kicks and jumping side kicks
butt in real combat.
Like Bruce Lee wrote very extensively
about real combat situations.
Like he was always like completely
fascinated by the concept of utilizing
minimum effort,
incorporating all the best techniques
from all different martial arts and only
doing what's effective in discarding
what's useless.
And He,
you know,
the Tao of Jeet Kune Doe he wrote like
extensively,
but all sorts of different martial arts
even like lifted whole packages like
paragraphs from other martial arts books
and put them in there and people will
say like,
oh,
he's plagiarizing.
Well,
no,
no.
This is what he was doing was collecting
all the information.
Now whether he attributed it to this
book or it should have or I don't know.
Yeah,
I agree intellectually probably it's not
the most honest thing to do.
To not credit,
maybe he did credit,
but my point is what his art was,
was absorbing everything.
He didn't invent any new techniques,
but what he did was he took the best
stuff out of everywhere and he
incorporated a system based on his
knowledge at the time who took in judo
from Jean lift arm bars and I don't like
the way you're talking about him in the
past tense.
He suggested there's dead person's dead
brother.
I guess you haven't read the secret
history of a lot of these.
Yeah,
but my point was that like that guy,
what he had done is really kind of,
um,
not just unprecedented,
but he was like the first big blip of
this new concept,
this new concept of just do what you
want,
what was possible and do what's useful.
Everybody else before was in a tribe.
I was in the shadow con karate tribe.
You're in the,
you know,
Gung Fu tribe.
This guy's in the judo tribe and there
was very little exchanging of
information.
You know,
I,
I only started exchanging information
when I got started getting involved in
kickboxing because I didn't have good
boxing technique,
so I started working at a boxing gym and
then I started hanging out with a dude
who's doing some Moitai as well,
and then I started learning about like
leg kicks and all these different things
and I remember thinking,
God damn,
I was so wrong.
Like the camp of taekwondo was good for
a bunch of things,
but it wasn't good for any of these
things these guys were doing to me.
I'm like,
dammit,
there's some holes in this motherfucker
and that's the only way you would find
out.
The only way you would find out is by
exploring these other martial arts.
But until Bruce Lee came along,
that was taboo.
You were a trader.
If you went to a different gym to train,
you are a fucking trader.
I know.
I remember having been a wrestler and
then I went to Iowa,
Dan Gables camp for,
I think it was two weeks.
It was a nightmare and three weeks and
you know,
and I got to wrestle with some of that.
Those Ncaa like Jim's Alaska,
those,
those hawkeyes as like as a 17 year old
and having wrestled I,
I kind of,
I knew I had a real appreciation for
what are really good [inaudible] college
wrestler was about,
you know,
and not because not because I ever.
I rolled around with those guys but not
because I was just hit,
they were teaching us,
but I knew,
I knew what tough high school wrestlers
were like and then to think about don
wrestlers and then I started taking
taekwondo when I went to Washington dc
and I say someone of my friends,
I'd be like,
just know that if you're in a bar and
you see a dude with closed up here and
he looks like he wrestled in college,
that's the guy to be afraid of it.
I'm a beer.
Buy Him a beer man.
Buy Him a beer because even if you punch
him,
punch them.
Right.
I may have gone.
I love knowing.
I was like,
I don't know if my kicks are going to
work.
He has to do with it.
In a way,
it's kind of what we're talking about.
We were talking about the Mongols were
the mongols lived this life of constant
strain and effort and they were so
strong and the strong survive anyway,
like as far as like how many people
lived in tents?
Man,
these motherfuckers were constantly at
war.
I'm sure their genes that with what they
had was warrior genetics and those
people when they encountered regular
soft people that lived inside these
cities like they were,
they were like predators to them.
I mean they,
they,
they had disdain for these people,
like they were sheep,
like they were cattle because they were
so fucking strong.
I mean,
when you're dealing with a guy who's
goddamn amateur wrestler,
a serious competitive amateur wrestler,
you're dealing with acute has probably
been wrestling since he was a bay.
It's all reaction for him.
Everything's reaction.
Not only that his body has developed by
throwing bodies around dented and much
like you can't understand what it's like
to lock up with that gorilla you.
You can understand how much stronger a
division one wrestler is the new.
You really don't know.
No.
Like you really probably have no.
Unless you ever wrestled with one of
those dudes and it has them grab,
grab them,
grab a hold your wrists and pin you down
and,
and get out of submissions like it's
nothing.
Or you feel their posture power there
like several times stronger than times.
That's right.
If you get a guy who's like,
look,
here's a perfect example,
Habib Neuroma gamete off.
Okay.
That motherfucker's a world samba
champion.
It's a different kind of wrestling,
but the point is he uses all wrestling.
If you watch him fight,
he's a relentless grappler and when he
gets a hold of dudes,
they were shocked at how fucking strong
I rewatched that does Tanya's fight and
the way he was,
the science is a monster monster and he
was just.
He was like a,
like an octopus,
just like a fucking,
just wouldn't get off his back.
He's a motherfucker to it.
Any motherfuckers,
everybody like that.
He motherfuckers,
everybody liked.
I'm so excited about this fight with
cowboy because I really want to see what
cowboy does to stop him and I really
want to see how he does with cowboy
fighting.
Cowboy on top because cowboys guard is
fucking nasty.
No,
I don't.
I don't think we've ever seen anybody
threatened Habib with any sort of
submission attempts before and I wonder
what would happen in Dos Anjos didn't
get a chance man,
but dos Anjos has never been like a
guard player.
You know,
he's not a big time guard player is more
of a top smash you guys.
Yeah,
he's really good man.
He's so God damn good.
Like what he did to pettis was like,
yeah,
that mother strong too.
He's strong.
Aggressive.
But with Donald and cubby.
But I wonder if.
First of all,
I think Donald has better hands and
feet.
Well,
he definitely does.
Yeah.
He definitely is a better striker,
but Habib is just so much stronger when
it comes to grappling.
But Donald,
unlike the other guys is dangerous off
his back.
Donald has a nasty triangle.
Sounds throws down.
Yes he is.
He's a long.
He's got an awesome check.
Need.
The body throws that check knee with the
left side.
He fucks guys up and he,
he mirrors it a lot of times or hides it
behind punches.
Like Donald,
you'll see,
we'll throw punches where he's not even
intended to hit you.
He just getting you look at these and if
you think of moving in and then boom,
that need comes to the body.
He fucks guys up with that.
He's putting on a show for you.
Manage dancing like a cobra.
Know he hides,
kicks behind punches like he did that
when he fought.
Um,
Jim Miller,
he showed him the right hand and boom,
the net kick was right behind it.
You know,
you're looking at that right hand and
his fucking neck kit comes along,
Bang,
and your legs go out.
He's a cubby and this is going to be
crazy.
He's a motherfucker.
Motherfuckers Donald's a motherfucker
and Habib's a motherfucker that isn't a
mate that could be easily a world
championship fight.
That's easily world championship caliber
fighter.
They asked him about conor mcgregor and
caboose is a very good fighter,
but if he wants to come to one of the
55,
his welcome.
I make him welcome,
swell job keeping that guy off you.
If you're supposed to be fighting 10
pounds lighter,
look,
especially if you don't.
If you're not arrested first.
Yeah,
well you listen man,
I'm not.
I don't.
I wouldn't say that connor can't fight
at 1:55.
What I would say that if he's competing
successfully at the top,
at 1:55,
45,
like he is right now,
the transition time,
unless he's some Mexicans supplements,
there's gonna be a long transition time
to put on the,
the right amount of weight to compete at
that level.
World of difference,
right?
Yeah.
Because he's pretty elite at 1:45
in his movement,
in his endurance,
like he's not having any problems and he
hasn't.
Granted he hasn't been in a real war and
that's what everybody really wants to
see.
Everybody really wants to see him
against a wrestler because everybody
we've seen is tried to stand up with him
and he's got nasty hands man,
nasty power,
nasty accuracy,
super,
super aggressive with his striking
disdainful almost with his stance and
his movement towards you.
It's shocking his confidence.
I think that fucks with a lot of
people's heads,
man.
A lot of people when he comes at you and
he's been talking shit about you for
months already made you feel like an
asshole,
you can't give you the courage,
you know,
everybody's thinking like,
and then by the time you get in there
like you've suffered a mental beating
already,
whether you know it or not,
like you're,
you're at a deficit.
I said,
I asked him where his confidence comes
from.
So why,
how did you like,
uh,
you know,
he said,
Tj,
he's how it has two belts.
He was a European national champion in
boxing,
has got another belt for something else.
But I said,
where does this come from?
This is my work ethic.
I said,
I know,
but a lot of guys were crying because
they tanked.
They work hard,
but they don't.
I my eye,
if it does not involve the fight game,
it does not involve me.
And that was it.
He goes,
other guys have extracurricular
activities.
I don't.
I count my money and I fight.
And those are the two things I like to
do.
He's a game changer,
game changer.
He's like shale times to best thing that
ever happened to Jose.
Aldo is career profile.
It'll,
unless it goes down the way connor
thinks it's going to go down,
then it's probably the worst thing to
have some guy come along and humiliate
and then fuck you up and you leave with
a check.
You were one of the best pound for pound
fighters in the world,
but if connor could do to him what he
did,
the Dustin Poirier,
that would be the most shocking thing
we've ever seen inside the.
It'll be crazy.
Do you compare a dozen poirier as a
fighter to Jose?
Aldo is not.
No,
and that's no disrespect to dustin
because I think Dustin was doing himself
a disservice by cutting down at 1:45.
I thought you look fucking sensational.
His last fight,
he looked amazing at 55.
He looked,
look comfortable.
They look thick,
was moving while he still fast as shit.
I think Dustin's a big boy and I think
those guys had cut down to 45 like that
or fuck,
it's your body's getting tortured and
you can kind of bounce back from it.
And when you're younger,
it's easier than when you get older,
when you've been in the game a long time
and your body has been taken kicks and
punches and you know you're dehydrating
and every few months and then
rehydrating it,
like after a while that's shit is going
to pay.
You're going to pay a price,
it's going to pay its toll.
And um,
you,
I think that a guy who is a really good
fighter that cuts less weight and has a
less great advantage but has a full
healthy body and all of the endurance
that comes with that and all the peace
of mind knowing that you slept well and
ate well and your body feels really
rested and you probably are better off
somewhere on the comfortable side of
that than in the comfortable side of too
dehydrated because those are the people
that wind up looking almost like there's
points where they're almost like
helpless because their body has
dehydrated so much.
And the grueling newness of the fight.
There's some guys you never see do it.
Some guys pull it off like Benson
Henderson.
He pulls it off,
man.
He pulls it off like you never see that
guy tired,
you never see that guy worn out and he
loses a lot of weight.
But then when you saw him fight against
brandon batch,
what you saw is one guy who was enormous
batch who's a huge for one seven.
He cuts a lot of weight so big and
Benson wasn't cotton,
hardly any weight at all,
if any,
to fight at one 70 because usually
fights it time especially and great and
part of it you have to consider is that
Benson is a guy with way more
experience,
way more ways to win and a way better
ground game.
I mean Benson has a legitimate blackbelt
ground game and his,
his,
his manager and trainer,
John Crouch,
he's legit as they come.
Like Benson is super good on the ground.
He's very good on the ground despite the
fact that pet is condom in that arm bar.
That was just so God damn quick and
perfect.
Yeah.
But when you look at his real ground
game,
like when he fucked that,
she realized like,
you know what man?
It'd be like,
it might be better if he fought bigger
guys and he was healthy.
It might be better because he's so
technical,
like it's not a big,
it's like the guys who rely on slugging
it out and smashing and hulk smashing
dudes.
Those guys have to be really big for
their way class.
But the guys who fight like Benson or
like Frankie,
super technical,
super endurance constantly on you,
you know,
always cutting angles,
always making you work,
always pushing.
You.
Always putting pressure on you.
I think Benson Henderson is,
is,
you know,
can keep me with anybody in 70.
Certainly Robbie lawler and,
and uh,
any of those guys and Johnny Hendricks,
he's kind of very similar.
He's just as tall,
might be a little shorter.
But for the most part I think that
there's nobody in the 70 pound weight
class that I think gives him a beating,
including Carlos.
Well,
you know,
he mean he could be a champion at one
seven and everybody says that's
ridiculous because it's so.
But look,
man,
that fucking weight classes,
nuts,
right?
Anybody in any given night in that
weight class could be a champion.
Same with 55.
Rory Macdonald can be a champion.
Robbie lawler is the champion.
I mean,
either one of those guys could be
champion,
you know,
I mean condit could still.
He champion Woodley could be championed,
hugged her lumbar,
could be champion.
I forgot.
I keep forgetting about it.
Guys like hector,
he's out for a year.
Yeah.
Steroids for the juice is my friend had
the juices study said that anybody who
does steroids should be banned for life.
And he says my.
Someone gave him a drink.
My friend rubbed oil on his body.
I think it was looking a.
This is some translation issues between
Spanish and English or the pharmacy man.
Fucking nose gave him something.
We talk about the 85 pound weight class.
Seventy pounds.
I forget about him and I forgot about
guys like Yoel Romero and.
Well he's 70 now.
He went down to 17 hectors at one 70.
Um,
but you'll all Romero,
he's another one.
That was a bummer that he didn't get to
Rey this weekend.
What happened to him is he got hurt,
he hurt his knee,
dammit.
Fuck.
That was an insane fight.
And then became an insane demonstration.
See if you could find that.
That Jeff of Jacques Rey Armbar and
Chris Kamozi I think.
I think if I had to put money on the
Yoel Romero shocker,
a fight I go with,
with A.
Because I,
I still think your morale or if he's
fighting five rounds,
if it's four and five,
he starts to gas because he's just,
there's so much muscle to feet.
So the top one is the guard pass,
which was equally ridiculously
impressive.
And the bottom one is the actual arm
bar.
Jamie.
Yeah,
that's the guard pass.
We just look all the weight he put on
them with a one shoulder.
Whereas whole bodies up priest turn off
ad block.
Fuck you man.
Bitches running scripts on your ships,
find it on another,
go to another website.
Um,
but anyway,
point being this,
uh,
this,
this era that we're living in right now
was like greatest ever for martial arts
I think.
I don't think there's ever been a time
ever in my life where I've seen this
level of execution on a scale like this.
It just didn't exist before.
It didn't exist.
When you combine the skill level of the
kickboxers,
like the glory kickboxers skill level of
the guys that are coming out of
Thailand,
you know,
it's just all right.
Everybody sharing their own techniques,
we will call.
Well,
you can watch them online now too.
That helps a lot.
And there's.
I just think that overall Jujitsu,
Muay Thai,
kickboxing and mma,
I don't think there's ever been a time
that has been even close to be
represented the way martial arts to
represent it today.
But that's just part of it.
The real impressive thing was the,
uh,
the transition to that.
They were going a scramble.
That's just the end of it.
They were in a scramble and jock array,
a dove on his arm and threw a leg over
and then hooked him under his leg to
keep them from rolling out of it and
then scoot his hips to the left and I
was watching.
I was like,
that is art.
That's ballet.
He's a master.
I think something else was happening
right away,
right?
Yeah.
I knew it was going for the arm.
As soon as I saw him,
I think I probably yelled at how he's
diving for an arm,
but I could tell that he,
he does that all the time.
Some guys don't like to do that because
it's a tricky transition between like
sometimes from the back.
Some guys will say,
you know what?
This guy is defending the choke to good.
I'm going to set up the arm bar.
Like,
um,
who smart Paul Horez did that to Ivan
salivary.
He went from the back to an arm bar.
There's a video of him doing that same
exact transition to a gym to.
I'm Jason Miller.
I think that,
uh,
he's got a lot of techniques like that
where he can transition from the back to
something else.
Jaggery does like,
he's got like levels of transitions that
other people just don't know.
Like I was watching combos and OSC
Kamozi trying to figure out what Rey was
doing while he was doing it and it was
just,
it was so high level.
Dude.
It was so high level,
like if you're a guy who does Jujitsu
and you watch how,
how this transitioned flows.
This is not it.
You got to go through.
It's before that.
Yeah.
But it's before that.
It's not,
it's they missed the whole thing.
So this is just an arm bar.
This is an bar and it's impressive,
but that's not what's impressive.
What was impressive was the full
transition go to that grappling world,
uh,
instagram grappling world on instagram.
That's where I said it was a,
you could see the whole thing,
but the way he does it,
it's like you have to have this insane
knowledge of where to put your legs in
the transition where he's going to
likely wind up where his legs going to
kick and there's so much data that he's
calculating and it's all based on
technique.
Just like very minimal effort,
like none of that that he did with
strength.
And that's like the most pure expression
of martial arts.
I mean certainly strong as fuck
strengths certainly aided him and
pulling off the moon.
Don't get me wrong,
but what I'm saying is that move was
pulled off because of his perfect
technique.
I mean,
you have to be physically strong person
to do anything to a Jujitsu person,
but there was no resistance there.
If you look,
there was defense,
but the way he moved into that position,
he was never resisted because he was so
far ahead of Kamozi.
Technically like in the dive
commodities,
like,
Oh shit.
He's diving going,
oh fuck.
He was already set.
He was adamant.
He was way ahead of.
Yeah,
he's way ahead of when you roll with
really good guys,
they.
They are ahead of you.
They've been there before.
They've seen what you're going to do.
They can predict what you're going to do
and sometimes if they're really good,
they can get you to think you're going
to do something you do that.
They already know you're going to do
that,
and then they capitalize.
That's what makes shocker a truly
special.
No,
there's two.
There's two running right now for the
number one contender after this,
Chris Weidman,
Vito Belfort fight.
There's shock array and who won on the
quote and then Luke rockhold.
Yeah,
and I think Luke rockhold made a giant
statement by beating Machida and
smashing them with a choke hold.
Beat.
Shocker,
right?
Yes.
Yes,
he did.
He did your take on that,
but there's a very good fight.
Look,
I think rockhold against anybody is a
very good fight.
Rockhold is a mother fucker,
dude.
There's no denying it now after what?
He did a good looking guy either.
The only reason why anybody gets laid is
because rockhold didn't get their first
got there.
First do.
It'd be no pussy for anybody else.
That's the bottom line is hansel
bastard,
but more importantly what it does inside
the octagon is super unusual.
Man.
He's a long guy is like Javier Mendez
explained it to me in the cage after the
fight and I was congratulating him and
Bob Cook.
Javier said he's long and he's strong
and usually don't get those two
together.
Oh,
because he's a long dude,
but he's also yoked as fuck.
He's not like a long,
skinny Roger Gracie type grappler.
He's long and he's yoked and he trains
on a daily basis with Kane motherfucking
full last name.
Oh,
that's right.
It's in Daniel motherfucking.
Call me every everyday.
These guys going to war with the biggest
killer the heavyweight division has ever
known outside of Baltimore.
This is just two guys that you would
never consider to be the greatest
heavyweight cyber.
There's one who's in the UFC.
He came to Alaska as in one from pride,
fader politics.
Both of them are.
Don't have.
If I saw them on the beach,
I would be like,
that guy used to work out perfect.
Say perfect way of describing fader.
Yeah.
He used to work out well in the day.
The earlier days of his career,
he was a little thicker.
Like there's been this picture of him
standing in front of the Kettlebell is.
Yeah.
What a great picture to jerk off to.
I've dropped the number of loads,
straightened loads,
but still I'm like,
are you rushing?
Rushing,
bear size of your tendons are bigger,
right?
Your trash.
Oh Gosh.
Dog Legs Stud all time greats insertion
cabs.
I mean,
uh,
it's,
it's hard to say.
He doesn't shave his chest,
he does,
he does he fuck.
It's hard to say like who would have won
in a fight in his prime versus cane in
his prime because they came in in two
totally different errors and if you want
to look at accomplishments,
boy,
it's really hard to discount cro,
cop beat and or fate or being cro,
cop fate or beaten pretty much everybody
they put in front of them and in pride,
I mean he really beat some of the best
in the world and the heavyweight
division in pride back then was probably
outside of Tim Silvia and Frank Mir,
who in their prime could give anybody a
hard time.
That was probably the strongest
heavyweight division the world has ever
known because everybody,
first of all,
I was allowed to do all sorts of
Mexicans.
She can do whatever the fuck you wanted
and you were dealing with guys who were
fighting for a lot of fucking money.
I mean there was a.
You got.
Think about it.
You Got Alexander Million Inco,
you've got cro,
cop,
you got cro cop in his prime when he was
head kick and ventilate asleep,
you know.
Oh my cookie mooglie.
You've got Minataro who was fighting off
his back and triangling Mark Cole,
but off his back,
like call in in his prime crazy.
Coleman was strong as fuck.
It was nothing to triangle.
Just a head and shoulders.
Minataro when he was off his back was
special dude.
He,
he was.
He represented a thing that no one had
ever seen before.
A real legit Brazilian Jiu Jitsu black
belt.
Who's a fucking bonafide heavyweight who
strangles guys off his back because he
was the mentor.
He.
You,
you got lost in the maze of his Jujitsu
or what was it?
That's a good question.
I don't know.
I'm going to guess that's what it is
because you don't want to get lost in
minute.
Charles Mayes,
maybe it's just like he's half bull.
So fucking strong.
Yes,
it's tough.
She was tough.
Shit.
Just started another lap.
Just another level of toughness.
So you think about minotauro.
Okay.
Fate or beat him in his prime and fader
beat cro cop in his prime.
They never.
Josh Barnett and him never fought.
When he was in Josh.
Josh was in his prime.
Kevin Randleman.
Remember that he beat Kevin Randleman
flex.
No,
Kevin,
right.
Got an arm bar just moments later.
So it's not good enough.
I'll break this.
Okay.
Top.
That was the craziest transition dude.
He was a motherfucker.
Fader was a motherfucker,
but if I like it,
it's timing with those shots.
Fantastic.
And his ability to knock guys out and
he's saying uh,
and Andre Arlovski knocked him out in
the air,
but that was by the way a fight where
our last,
he was picking them apart and that was a
fight where a lot of people looked at
what?
This guy's got some holes and it was
also a fight where he was criticized by
his old trainers.
Trainer was saying,
you know,
he's up to his old tricks.
He won with a trick like,
but they didn't prepare for this
properly.
His trainer was vocal about that.
That training with Freddie Roach,
I think.
I think you're right.
Yeah,
well Arloski got crazy and went with
that flying knee and if he didn't go
with the flying knee,
who knows what would happen if you
continue to pick them apart like that.
It could have been crazy.
It could have been crazy to watch fate
or get kick boxed,
you know,
but Arlovski,
at least on paper was a,
you know,
very formidable kickbox and threatened.
He had like one punch knockout power
lasers straight right hand me through a
right hand that when he knocked out Paul
blend like early in the first round,
he threw a right hand.
It was like a bolt.
So to really comes off his shoulder hits
you in your genuine.
You know what the fuck happened?
He's so fast.
When Arlovski was in his prime dude,
people were terrified of him.
Remember the first time he came in
there,
they get this 240 pound guy moved like a
small man.
Would that pony tail?
Well,
when fader or gone to him,
he had lost a few and he'd been out of
the UFC in fighting for affliction,
you know,
but I'm still still was pretty
formidable five rounds.
Who knows,
that's the problem.
It's like you'd have to have a time
machine.
You'd have to coordinate like you know
when,
what version of cane before the first
fight with junior dos Santos before the
second fight with junior dos Santos,
you know,
I mean junior dos Santos knocked him out
in the first fight and then they went to
fucking war for two fights in a row.
And those fights,
you got to think like,
man,
you fade or obviously lost a step
somewhere along the way and you have to
attribute it if you don't attribute it
to his focus.
I don't know what his focus wasn't
training his coaches saying something
like that.
It could be that he was kind of getting
tired of fighting or it could be the god
wars he went through.
I mean,
nobody rides for free when it comes to
those crazy fucking 10 minute rounds of
sparring sessions that he would go
through,
you know,
meet me.
We were talking to Tony Jeffries about
this and he was calculating and he was.
He had 106 fights,
26 of which were pro I think.
And he said if you look at all the
rounds I fought to prepare for those 106
fights and this is when I became an
amateur is not when I was a kid.
He calculated it.
He takes about.
He took over 55,000
shots that God to him,
$5,000
and so crazy and call for a lot of
boxers because you've got to take into
account the,
the,
the five
jabs.
Just the five jobs you'd take around.
Even if they're light when you're
sparring.
It's so crazy,
so crazy when you know,
when you just think about all the
different micro injuries and different
times that Brian's rattling against the
skull.
Different little things that have the
connective tissue that's separating or
twisting or popping or I know,
but don't you need some of that in life?
Like I was going to ask you,
you know trauma?
No,
I.
well somebody didn't call his pockets.
This French general I think are a
British general said we have to have war
because if a man doesn't have war will
will,
will dissolve into materialism.
I thought all right,
whatever that sounds like a general but.
But there is something to be said about
a conflict free world as we were talking
about and I was wondering like,
and I was just trying to like draw a
through line to the people.
I really connect with my really good
friends,
the friends that I have and it's not
that there will be on their list,
but you are,
but it's not that they're all fighters
and unnecessarily,
but they definitely have and continue to
sort of live in a world that is not,
of course like the Mongols,
but they keep themselves a little
uncomfortable.
They are always in touch with kind of
coming up with their own,
with a sense of reality.
Well,
that's what I told you that before.
You're the only dude that I'd ever asked
to go to Montana to sleep when it's 90
degrees outside in a little cloth house
was horrible that nobody,
none of nobody other.
None of the other comics we know are
really good at are going to hack that.
I don't think Duncan and I love him.
And,
and,
and Tony Hinchcliffe are gonna Kinda
like hiking up those mountains in that
cold.
Tony might get down with it.
I'm telling you,
Tony Micah done with it.
That little fucker is.
He's,
he's a little weasel.
Really shouldn't say weasel.
It should say uh,
I meant to say he's a golden pony.
I meant badger and he's a determined
little.
He's like,
weasels are tough little fucking animals
by the way.
That's a weird thing.
Like weasel became somehow or another
toughest shame.
An asshole like weasels killed cobras,
don't they?
Well,
I think family,
they're,
they're tough little fuckers.
You say weasley like all the dudes
Weasley,
right?
I mean,
he's,
he's not to be fucked with.
Tony will rise up.
He will figure it out with a pack on his
back and that cult.
You know what man?
Physically,
not exactly designed for it.
He's not designed for it,
but he's a tough little fucker.
Look at that.
This photo of a baby weezer flying.
That's at Photoshop.
Oh,
come on.
Someone caught this.
A baby weasel.
How did he get on his bird?
I don't believe it.
Well,
why don't you believe it?
It can happen.
Really?
Yeah.
The world's crazy.
Why is that so weird?
Hats.
Amazed.
Some baby weasel figured out how to jump
on this fucking birds back.
Tell me right now.
I think it's completely photoshop.
Listen,
we know weasels exist.
We know birds can fly.
Why would it be so hard to imagine
perhaps the weasel jump on his back and
they went home with venture.
All the fucking variables in the luck in
the world when it comes to wildlife that
couldn't take place.
Watch this.
I don't think that bird would be able to
have the,
uh,
to be able to.
Hang on.
Let's look at this little,
but also that weasel doesn't have any
strength.
That's a baby at parts.
Not letting that reason a him.
Jamie,
please snopes this and get back to us
with the final results.
It's actually real.
Wow.
Come on.
Jimmy says,
it's actually real.
Still crying.
I'm still calling bullshit.
Don't call bullshit.
Wow.
There's another picture of it.
Weasel catches a ride on a woodpecker
was that guy.
That guy's a liar.
That's fucked up.
That's the guy who caught it on camera.
Wow.
Better not be lying dude.
Phase lines.
Those hacks.
Sores.
Dudes are gonna.
Find you.
They'll find you can't lie to them.
Yeah.
They have elite skills with the
photoshop layers.
Remember that like these photoshop guys
were going over the fucking image that
Obama's birth certificate.
It's clearly been Dr.
and photoshop.
Photoshop the.
Do you know anything about that Jamie?
The layers of the photoshop argument
when it comes to Obama's.
Obama's birth certificate was doctored
in Photoshop.
I'll show you doctor,
if you watch,
if you.
If you take it apart,
the image is several files.
Some of them fucking Kenya.
Several from several.
Five.
How about this?
How about he's from Hawaii,
which is not America anyway.
How about that?
You know,
buys from a fucking.
He's from a country we stole from a
tropical island.
Really Nice Group of people.
Yeah,
they were sweet.
We say it's an island.
It's just a small country.
That's what it is.
I agree.
Hawaiians are Hawaiians.
They're not Americans.
They are American and since they will
take the meal and protect them with the
constitution in the military of the
United States of America,
never forget the nr there in our
protectorate.
Look at Brock,
but what I'm saying is Hawaii.
Oh Shit.
There's two different pictures and they
photo shopped him in there maybe.
Hm.
Huh?
Where's the hand?
Where's that left hand?
He's got an upper ass in that second
picture.
Just this is not real.
Oh,
these are hilarious.
These are hilarious.
Chunk of your edge missing.
Oh Jesus Christ.
It's not even a high resolution photo.
You fucking Weirdos till they understand
the difference between looking at
something with a white background and
looking at something with a black
background.
Go up to that ear.
I'll just prove this right now.
You fucking dummy.
They see the difference.
See where the transition is.
The transition is right where the white
meats,
the black,
you know why it happened because the
camera picks it up again to bring it
back.
This is becoming the Dan Carlin
podcasts,
but he said something really cool about
how people like conspiracy theories
because it's really hard to believe that
the random just happens where that one
man like Lee Harvey Oswald can change
the course of history with a bullet and
that's a lot harder to believe than you
know,
a group of people who were very
organized ended up doing what they did
and it's human.
We all want.
We want to a logical explanation,
not a random one,
not the fact that we're fragile enough
that one man can fuck everything up with
with a good bullet or a good bomb.
It's just,
it's that time where that was possible.
I wonder if that's possible today and
it's certainly to a lesser extent,
like there's certainly there's a weirder
connection that people share today than
they've ever done before and I wonder
how much we realize about how that's
shaping society's shaping.
Just human civilization as a human,
you know,
we were talking about before as a
gigantic super organism,
super organism that relied on aggression
to get to a certain point of innovation
and then once it got to that certain
point of innovation,
what,
when does it no longer need aggression
and when does it need like a realization
of what it actually is instead of
aggression.
When does it need a real realization
like,
listen,
the only way that's going gonna work out
for everybody as we got to act for
everybody.
That's the only way.
If the human race just treats everybody
that way,
like you have to find where the weak
spots are.
Prop them up,
figure out why they're fucked up,
engineered correctly.
You know,
as far as social engineering,
education,
counseling are you saying that we should
do unto others as you'd have them do
unto us as rabbi hello and a guy named
Jesus Christ said,
and once you get to a point where you
have something called the Internet and
people can exchange these ideas and
exchange these,
these points of view and these
expressions like,
this is how I feel about you,
is how you feel about me.
When you communication like this,
you can communicate like this in real
time in a way that's never happened
before.
So they're not like these weird people
in Germany that you don't know that.
Or they have this guy standing on top of
a podium and he's screaming shit out and
you're like,
what's going on over there?
Why are they all marching?
Why they all goose step in like that?
What are they doing with the Jews?
Like,
what the fuck is going on over there?
And you're reading things about it in
the paper and you're trying to take
these little printed words and piece
them into a narrative that makes sense
in your head.
You're reading the New York Times every
morning to find out what's the news,
what the with Europe,
what's going on over there without boys
and you want to look into the paper
trying to find out how the score is the
war and you're listening to the radio at
night,
the fucking radio.
You're listening to the radio to
Kranich's blaming.
You would go to the movies and they
would show a clip,
a highlight war,
real clip of the news while you're
waiting for your movie to start.
I know what the fuck.
I'm very controlled to the.
Your information was controlled.
War was actually was actually kind of
presented in a very sanitized way as
well and in many ways still is like the
idea that when you get hit with heavy
artillery,
you come apart.
There are not holes in your body.
We don't show a lot of that stuff.
Probably shouldn't lonely,
shouldn't.
We?
Wouldn't.
Wouldn't be.
It'd be good for people to know what the
fuck they're signing.
I know.
I know that the.
I know that the logic was always that
you censored media during war time and
didn't let them show the really horrific
stuff because it was bad for morale
among troops and at home.
Now,
does that make sense to you?
I don't know enough about what it's like
to motivate young men to go to battle.
to be a general or a person in power
when I'm in a war time situation.
I don't know what it's like to be.
To have the very existence of my country
under threat the way we were in world
war two,
when that,
when those kinds of policies were made,
so I don't know,
man.
I think I'd have think I'd have a very
different point of view if I was.
That's all and I think we'd all have
very different points of view and would
do very,
very different things and behave maybe a
lot like the leaders we criticized if we
were under the kinds of responsibilities
and pressures that the leaders we talk
about we're under.
I think that if I were the emir,
the caliphate of Baghdad,
and I knew that the Mongols were doing
what they were doing to people and they
were on the way to see me,
I'd be pretty ruthless with any kind of
dissent,
any kind of a Mongol sympathy,
and I would be pretty ruthless with
anybody who wasn't pitching in for the
very survival of my my town because the
consequences are so high have not taken
seriously,
not being aggressively prepared.
Yes.
The question becomes like how if ever is
it possible that because of the fact
that we can communicate with each other
all across the world instantaneously,
how is it possible that we move past the
idea of armed conflicts entirely?
Like isn't it possible?
It is possible and it's already kind of
happening?
How is it?
How can you say that when we're going to
war?
I mean we're.
We're in the middle of like pulling out
of Iraq and Afghanistan while
maintaining thousands of troops.
Yes,
we have bases all over the world.
there's this isis shit that's going on.
There's this overall,
if you look at the number of violent
deaths from 2000 until 2015,
according to Steven pinker in his very
well researched book called the angels
of our better nature essentially said it
proves and and makes the case that fewer
people have died violently in that span
of time.
Even with the Congo,
even with the Middle East,
even with all the things that go on in
comparison to any other time of epoch,
any other time in history,
and it seems that a lot of countries
like China,
for example,
China,
yes,
rattles sort of Taiwan and things,
but China gains a great deal more from
being an economic powerhouse.
Military Power House just isn't,
and I maintain this case with Iran.
Iran wants to Gemini,
Iran wants control over parts of the
Middle East.
Iran has a lot of influence with the
Shia,
the Shia,
Sunni schism in the Middle East,
et cetera.
I think Iran gains a lot more and we
could create incentives for Iran and we
are trying to at least parts of the
government or some people disagree with
this.
I feel like if you created a situation
where Iran saw that there was much more
to be gained from joining the Economic
Community and playing ball in accordance
with its laws is an in getting weapons
of mass destructions.
They're all scared that those chicks are
going to find out they don't have to
wear burkas in America.
Votes cover your come over on boats and
then seek out black dick like a magnet,
like a magnet to steal filings.
Perhaps they're tired of being
suppressed.
They want a torque on some dude in a
club,
maybe no crazy,
funky religious outfit on and they can
escape.
You know why?
Because no one knows to fuck.
They look like they could just blend
right in.
Good luck with your passport photo when
it's looking through a fucking lit of a
garbage can.
Like Oscar the grouch and that's who
you're fucking passport.
It looks like you see your eyeballs.
I mean,
did they have to take this shit out for
their passport?
Right?
Don't they?
Are they allowed to?
It's like stealing their soul or
something.
Right?
Well,
the minute that a lot of Saudi women go
to places like London and quake,
guess what comes off immediately?
Their headrest,
the whole thing,
and I was shopping and they dress in
sexy outfits and they're just like,
yeah,
cause see impression man.
It's just amazing that you've got
countries that in 2015 still make women
dressed like they're in star wars.
This is not a reason for it.
Another reason for it.
There was another very logical reason
for it.
Logical.
Well,
I'm just saying if you're,
if you're,
if you're really,
if you're just saying,
if you're a religious man and if you are
trying to create a productive society,
the logic went.
If you have women walking around looking
all sexy and naked,
which was a lot of the Middle East,
well if you have that,
what happens is we're thinking about
fucking not producing year.
So you've got to cover your chicks up.
Jasmine,
if she wanted to get any work done.
That's not true though.
I kurzweil miracle producers like a
model for that.
How about that?
Hot fruits over.
It's so true.
Freedom.
Is that what she looked like?
Prince,
Princess Leia.
Is that a real body?
Yeah.
Damn.
Should've banging body as she did.
That was real to those pre,
pre sucking.
Tuck.
God bless her.
You know,
she didn't have no light pole,
couldn't look more board.
Um,
she was beautiful at the time.
Very exotic.
Leo steelbrick made older brother
remember that shit.
I love it.
She kissed her brother in Ellipsis tick.
Is that true?
It had to.
He didn't know that it was his sister.
That's rude.
Your sister comes and gives you a real
kiss with a body like that since he got
some unit.
She's even bother telling you that
she's.
Did she know at the time that she knows
she was?
No,
no one knew how to do a love scene when
you were an actor back in the day.
I wasn't an actor.
I was never really an actor.
I did acting work.
I had to.
I had to do some serious love scenes.
Awkward and weird.
I bet man,
because I was awkward and weird as it is
being in a car with you for six hours
trying to Turkey hunt.
How about that?
Huh?
We made time,
dude.
We did have a good time.
We always have.
I will always haunt because it's just
like white going has nothing to do with
killing the animals.
For me it's I get to hang with you get
to be idiots and laugh.
It was like I was saying like,
there's not a whole lot of dudes I'd
asked to sleep in a tent,
you know?
Come on man.
We're going to go.
We're going to go to someplace like I'm
calling my tv star famous comedian
friend going,
come on,
we're going to go.
We're going to sleep under the stars and
Montana,
Napa Valley.
We're going to go shoot deer and then
we're going to eat them over a campfire.
You in Turkey hunting was interesting.
I can't give it away,
but I will say that I killed between
zero and 10 birds.
That's a good number.
You know,
the Turkey hunting is very exciting.
It's fun,
but it.
The only issue that I have,
and I don't really have an issue with
it,
but the only thing that I would save,
it came to like preference of time that
I would spend hunting.
I would spend less time,
Turkey hunting and more time doing other
things because the fact that you can't
get anything more than a Turkey.
Yeah.
You stayed there all day.
You shoot this Turkey,
you've got one Turkey and that's great.
I mean there'll be delicious.
I'm sure I haven't cooked it yet.
I've got it in the open.
I told everybody I killed a Turkey or
did you know this is where now I had a
picture of it.
He put it on his instagram so I'm fine.
Um,
but it,
it's just a Turkey.
We tasted some of it.
We ate some Turkey and tasted like
Turkey.
It was good,
but the breast tasted identical Turkey.
Apparently the legs are like a little
tougher and the one that I got was
apparently a good one to eat because it
was fairly young and those are like more
10 called Jake wasn't a top a jake and
um,
they just don't.
Here's the deal,
you know,
there's not that much food there,
it's like it'll feed a family and then
maybe you might have sandwiches the next
day.
If you shoot a deer,
like if you go out and you shoot a deer
and you spend those those nights
sleeping in the tent in Montana and
you're successful,
you're kind of come back with 50 or 60
pounds of meat credible.
I mean you've got backstraps and loins
and Burger and you're making sausage out
of it and you got just butchering it.
Just portraying it as a bitch.
We did it for her,
we butchered it and we joked around.
We had a great time or that Moose.
See if I shoot one of those that moves,
I'm going to be eating.
That moves forever.
One of the greatest pictures I've ever
seen that picture and the fade or
picture with kettlebells are the two
pictures I use in my fantasy violence.
Well,
this is.
Listen this,
that,
that picture is like what it means to
eat animals.
That is a moose leg.
I don't know how much that way,
but it was heavy as 100 pounds.
Well over 100 pounds.
Well over a hundred pounds.
What was the 900 pound Moose?
Which isn't even that big.
Look at that.
My phoner Ben.
He shot one that was about 1400 pounds.
Was much bigger than mine.
It's huge antlers.
It was ridiculous,
but that moves is going to feed me for a
year to come over here.
Come on.
Okay.
Do you have good cuts?
Yeah.
Well,
I'll let me show you how to cook it
because it's not easy.
It's a different thing.
It's different than dear.
This gladiator animal that you're
eating,
like first of all,
when you eat the meat,
I'm going to have you over come over to
the house and you and I will sit down
and have a meal together,
Cook you a real moose steak.
You're going to eat it and I'll bring
the one.
You're going to be like,
Holy Shit,
because it makes you.
It's almost like a stimulant.
There's so much energy in that meat.
Listen,
I've done that with deer meat.
I ate deer meat every day for 10 days.
I am telling you,
and I'm not hokey.
You get,
you get it.
You get a rush.
Like I had an.
I had an extra kick in my,
in my body.
It only makes sense if you look at their
body.
Their flesh is so healthy,
like their tissue is so rich and red and
dark.
Yeah.
Like you're dealing with an extremely
healthy animal that is surviving against
really hardcore predators.
I mean,
it's running away from mountain lions
and wolves.
Like this is existence for a moose.
It's wolf packs.
If you make it from the time you're a
calf to the time you're a full grown
moves.
Good luck.
We never started that picture that I
had.
We came across one that had been torn
apart by wolves.
No.
Yeah,
well we were up there hunting.
We came across a moose calf.
Wow.
When we're,
we're,
we're actually moose hunting and uh,
this thing had been torn apart Europe
and wolf country.
Oh yeah.
Not only was I opened wolf country,
I was up in a place where they don't
even have a limit on how many wolves you
can kill because they're just so many.
They want you to kill wolves all day
dam.
They want you to set up bait.
You can do whatever you want.
There's such a motherfucker,
there's just such a motherfucker and
there's,
they don't have a handle on them at all.
The guy that I lived up there,
uh,
the state of displays,
brother that lives up there,
he's neighbor lost a cow to a wolf.
Well,
when we were,
when we were in Napa vow,
we were in Napa Valley,
the farmers I was talking to,
they used to keep emos emos like,
which are miniature ostriches and lambs
and said the mountain lions wreak havoc.
The mountain lion would come in and pull
those emails over the fence,
the seven foot fence,
and they just find feathers on the top
of the fence that goes our emo and lambs
to just eat the shit out of land where
the place where you and I were standing
up in.
That's where it was.
Yeah.
The place where you and I were staying,
they they've lost all their sheep to
mountain lions,
this farm that we were at,
I mean they had all these cows and shit
and they think about you have to survive
the winter and a mountain lion and
wolves or you'll start hating mountain
lions and wolves content.
There's a totally different idea that
you and I have about them.
Like you know,
you look at a wolf,
you look at it,
it's like a dog.
They don't.
That's not a dog to them.
That's a danger of starvation thing,
that starvation.
It's a dangerous fucking thing.
I'm trying to find when you're in the
frontier and we'll take care of all your
livestock.
You and your kids couldn't eat.
Yeah,
man.
Well,
it's.
It hasn't been.
Okay.
I found the pictures.
It hasn't been that long ago that human
beings really had to worry about wolves.
That's why those big bad wolf and all
those different,
you know,
those,
those legends go on in Europe.
That's what we're found.
That was probably.
We had gotten there probably the night
after or they still have like lots of
meat on it.
Yeah.
And what you didn't expect.
What I didn't expect was the hair
everywhere.
Oh,
that's stuff that you see on the ground.
And that picture jamie could pull it up.
It's on my instance care.
Find A,
a,
um,
a body of a moose calf.
It's from four or five months ago.
The,
um,
the,
the legs still has,
you know,
there's still,
they would come back,
they're probably going to come back and
finish off the rest or they were just
full and they were going to go somewhere
else and get something else,
but they always know where it is.
They'll come back.
Where was that?
That was NBC.
Like northern British Columbia.
Yeah.
Do when you meet people at the airport?
Just A,
just a random guy at the airport saw
that I had a cammo jacket on and asked
me if I was hunting to talk to me about
how much he likes to kill wolves.
These city people,
they just don't understand.
You know,
the,
they lived down there in Vancouver and
they're making all the laws for up here
and you know,
we're,
we're the ones who have to hear them
howl and you know,
and wonder how many of them there are
out there and they kill your livestock
and they kill your dogs and the
different perspective.
They're wolves.
Like the movies,
like Little Red Riding Hood.
Look out little girl.
Don't go off in the woods alone because
there's wolves out there too.
They're so smart.
They know.
What's our next Honda we're going to on
to know we could pay current.
You know what I was thinking?
I was thinking we should go go caribou
hunting.
Oh cool.
We'll call Alaska us too cold to going
in.
You're going in August.
I'll go then.
Yeah,
they migrate in August.
Right.
What about before that?
I don't know.
We'll figure someone to kill a pig up.
Oh,
you're crazy.
You're violent.
What happened to you?
I want to eat a pig.
Oh,
I need some pig and eat them.
I love.
I still have some from the pig I shot.
You do?
Yeah.
I'll cook some.
At the House I made a ham,
like maybe you still have all my hunting
gear or your house.
Some of you.
I made a ham.
That's us were Turkey hunting.
Look if you look at me,
but I made this ham that I a slow,
a slow cooked on the smoker for like
six,
seven hours.
I brightened it for like four or five
days.
Chase Brian it like he'll take ice,
put it in a cooler.
You take this bronx mostly like salt and
sugar and some spices and you dunk this
ham in there and then surround
everything with ice and put it in like a
Yeti cooler and then look at that.
Wow.
You're getting to be quite the meat
cooker.
I'm getting good at cooking meat like
I've.
I'm no chef.
I don't have skills.
I don't know what I'm doing,
but I do know how to smoke me.
I knew how to grill steaks.
I cooked a written out last night.
Yeah,
he's like a real chef.
Like he could be like a real chef.
I tell people he made me beaver.
I said some of the best meals I've ever
had.
Get out of here.
Those are some.
Those are some ribs that I cooked.
I was.
You're so funny that you post.
I always.
I finally went in instagram.
Obviously posting meat.
That's where cooked last night.
Cowboy cut of goodbye.
That was when his son that's artwork to
me.
Is that boosie?
No,
that's Ribeye steak.
Could,
that's a regular steak.
I got a cowboy cut a big thick.
It was probably like maybe three inches
thick.
At least one to two and a half.
Maybe it was a fat thick one where I had
to use a thermometer to cook it.
So,
uh,
I cook it on the outside.
You see are the outside on these things
called Grill grates.
I gotta I gotTa show you the smoker I
got.
It's a yoder.
It's,
uh,
it,
it uses direct heat as well as indirect
heat.
You ever seen those things?
Those pellet smokers know?
Well,
this one you can sear it on one side.
Then you move it over to the other side
and then you just leave the temperature
of what you want it.
For me it was like 400 degrees,
so I dropped it down to 400 degrees and
I have a thermometer in it.
It's tells me when the temperature,
the internal temperature hits like 1:25
and then I watch it carefully.
Took it to be about 1:30
in there,
pop that bitch out and let it sit for
roasting it.
You're starting off grilling it.
You're starting enough grilling.
It's direct fire like fire literally
below these greats.
Yeah,
and you see are the shit out of it.
I don't mean the shit out of it.
You don't want to burn it,
but you want to sear it for.
Depending upon the thickness of the meat
and the temperature that you're searing
it.
I don't do it for more than like two and
a half minutes aside and I just really
just like cooked the outside,
you know,
you're,
you're burning off any possible bacteria
that's on the outside.
You get a nice crust and a good,
like a delicious,
like top area of it where it's like real
crispy and you got like kosher salt and
black pepper and a little bit of garlic
powder.
I mix on there and I let it sit for like
an hour before I put it on the grill.
It's an art form to.
It magnifies.
It is because like I,
I put post pictures of it because I like
when other people do too,
like,
like looking at people's instagrams and
shit that they're making.
My,
my father in law can cook the greatest
stakes.
He put Hughes's hickory chips and he
smokes it that way on the.
Well he's just a master with a grill.
I try to replicate replicated.
I just can't do it.
There's two different styles of cooking
steaks.
Like some people like the Argentine
style,
which is like a slow grill.
Slow and low.
They'll cook like a steak slowly.
I like my meat to be a little raw
though.
Like rare.
No,
but I mean they don't.
I mean they can certainly still cook it
rare.
They just cook it at a low temperature.
They don't like,
like American style grilling a steak,
you know,
you see that stake hit the thing and you
flip it or you move it a little and then
you flip it and then you push it off to
the side and you always put the lid on
it and you let it rest.
Like you got to let it sit like you
grill the top of it.
But unless it's a really thin steak
that's not going to really get the
center where you want it.
It'll be really rare in the center.
So what you do is you put it like if you
have a,
um,
like either one of those Weber's or I
have a Kamado,
you put a top layer lever to it so that
the heat is not really underneath and
anymore cooking it from the bottom.
It's cooking all around it and then you
put it on the top,
close the lid and it'll drop down like
maybe 350 degrees or somewhere around
there.
And then you cook it slowly for the
next,
like depending upon the thickness of the
steak,
I don't usually like to go more than
five minutes and then I pull it off of
there.
So what I've done is I've seen her the
shit out of the outside with like really
odd flames and a hot grill
grate and it's.
Everything is just like really cooking.
The outside of it would then slow
cooking it after that.
So you get that.
They do it all kinds of stuff.
On the outside.
I had,
I had a big stake in Utah where they,
they put it in a plastic bag and they
boil it.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
That's a new thing that God damn.
It was good.
That's the thing that snake river farms
is really popular right now.
They're,
they're,
they have new ones that they sell that
you put like you put a pot of water,
you know,
and then you stick this heater element
in it and it cooks it for you.
You just sit it on the,
on the,
on the counter,
but it's not the sitter on your stove,
but it's not the stove that took cooking
it.
It's this device that you have in the
water so it'll keep the water steady.
Hundred and 35 degrees,
which is like medium,
medium rare.
So you would just do that and it would
cook it perfectly.
Like you couldn't fuck it up.
It couldn't overcook and then you take
it and they cook the outside of it with
like a torch.
Right.
I could take a butane torch and they
crispy sear or the outside of it and
it's supposed to be amazing.
Yeah,
I've had it.
It's incredible.
I don't like that shit though.
I had a wagon was sent to me from snake
river farms,
which apparently like I went to Mastro's
and God goes,
well,
snake river farms is the best dude.
I don't know what they do there.
I don't know what they do at those cows.
I,
I'm,
I'm just telling you is the best steak.
I.
It's better than Venice spending
anything you might like.
Different things that I like because
I've,
I've tried that Wagyu.
I've given a bunch of tries.
I've had coby fatty tissue,
fatty I liked about this is what I like
about like that,
that I'm what the fuck tri tip that we
had.
I like lean to.
I'm more of a lean guy.
I don't like a lot of fat and this was.
This was an exception.
Maybe they're just the preparation.
The chef just nailed it now because they
sent me my own stakes and I just cooked
it and fucking butter and I was just
still like the best steak I've ever had.
Well,
I'll give it another shot.
I've had it before.
I didn't like it.
I felt like I was eating.
I'll call them the guy.
I think I know the guy.
I'll have him send you some steaks.
I felt like I was eating a bedridden
patient.
If you took a cow stuff,
froot loops,
duck fat face and getting drunk every
night and then killed it.
I'm curious what you think of this snake
rivers.
Well,
I'll try and have it to a size.
Apparently there are these day are like,
there's,
there's other places that do Wagyu and
then the snake river farms.
Like everybody,
everybody who's in the,
they all say,
well that's,
that's the Cadillac.
That's the Mercedes Ferrari of snakes.
Again,
another Japanese invention,
those slick bastards.
Robin with peer,
don't they?
And they do all kinds of weird shit with
the cow.
They don't let it move.
Nice.
The whole culture,
when you think about one small island,
just thinking about what they did to
revolutionize the car industry,
they made cars reliable with insane,
with insane,
um,
cooperation.
And I'll give you an example with fully
contemplated a plant.
This is back in the day.
This was 20 years ago in twitter
company.
They could start from,
from when they started with the one
piece that was,
they were going to put the car together
on the assembly line.
It took five minutes to assemble an
entire Toyota dollars.
You take 10 guys,
just make sure the bolts are tightened
down.
What the fuck man,
don't rush my car.
No bolts on five minutes.
That seems like a little quick.
Maybe.
Slow down.
I think so,
but they have it down to a science.
They always say that Japan was so
heavily influenced by one factor,
a lot of people in a very small area and
it required a great deal of cooperation,
but even more importantly because of
typhoons,
their,
their architecture was made from rice
because you didn't want a wind to blow
stone on you and die.
So the reason that the origami,
like,
you know,
they have like sliding glass doors and I
mean paper,
a lot of their,
their houses were made if the inside was
made of paper.
Well the problem with that is when you
have walls that separate you,
that are made of paper,
you can hear what goes on in the room
next to you and if you have a couple
that's fucking or whatever,
or crying or arguing,
now you're privy to their business.
And what that did was they said,
how are we going to run a society like
this?
This is weird.
I mean,
I,
I know he's listening to me and then I'm
listening to him and what a lot of
social scientists talk about is this
idea that the Japanese got super good at
actively not hearing things they're not
supposed to and it was like this sort of
social contract where,
first of all,
you never mentioned that you heard
anything.
Second of all,
you didn't even gossip because you
didn't hear it.
Hi.
Not Listening.
I'm not listening.
I am jacking off.
What a bizarre culture that they
exhibited so many unique traits and
characteristics and at so many unique
strengths.
You know,
I mean if you,
if you think about their contributions
just to martial arts alone for one
island like that,
it's unprecedented.
I mean,
the other island,
I mean Brazil is obviously an enormous
country and there they had a massive
influence on as well.
Holland is a small country.
They had a massive influence on
kickboxing and Muay Thai and on the
economy of the world.
I mean a lot of,
a lot of,
a lot of that day they're an economic
powerhouse responsible for setting up
shop in Africa and and I believe in a
place called New York and that's right.
If the kit there,
I was just there.
I was confused.
Denmark.
Holly Hallmark.
The Netherlands is the same as
volunteer.
Yeah.
All of that area.
You can fuck up.
You're a Dane.
You're from Denmark.
What does that mean now you.
Okay.
Are You Dutch?
English,
history from the Netherlands.
You're Dutch.
You're here from how I.
it's always confusing,
but they also figured out we'd and
hookers a long time ago.
They're great.
They figured out a lot of shit.
They're like,
let's just like how about you just get
tested and do whatever you want to do
and the only issue with the Japanese is
their challenge has always been
innovation.
Like they're really good at mimicry and
making things better,
but as far as.
And the reason for that is because of
the way their society is structured so
that if you are someone who comes up
with a better way to do something,
then your boss,
your boss would lose face.
And so that's why a lot of things stayed
rather stagnant.
Even though they were good.
It was very hard for them to sort of
keep up with the in.
So not as much innovation comes out of
Japan.
They don't really have a silicon valley
the way we do.
Uh,
and that's,
uh,
that's an interesting way of describing
it.
If you have a boss and you go out to
drink the boss strings,
a higher higher caliber whiskey than you
do really,
cutty Sark and you'll drink something
shithead,
give up the good booze son.
This man,
come on Bro,
you make more money.
He's up.
Come on,
we work together.
Let's be friends here.
And also very chauvinistic.
But they did some amazing improvements
on existing things.
Like that's what their unique
characteristic,
their unique traits,
especially when it comes to automobiles,
automobile electronics,
phonics,
like the NSX forced Ferrari and Porsche
to change the way they were making cars.
Like they came out with this fucking
Nsx,
I want to say like 91 or 92 was the
first NSX and it was basically like a
super evolved sports car for the time it
like had these ridiculous things that
they'd built into it like baffles in the
fuel lines to make sure that the weight
always stayed completely central.
Like they wanted to have like a pure 50
slash 50 weight balance.
So it's a mid engine car so the engine
is behind the passenger seat.
All these unique innovations to the
suspension geometry and the way it
handled was just like,
like it was on rails man.
And it was not even a high horsepower
car.
It was like 275.
I think initially maybe two to 90
towards the end of its production line.
It wasn't like that speed.
It was just bulletproof.
Who's all aluminum?
No one had ever done that before.
No one had ever made an all aluminum
sports car.
I remember getting in that car with you
when you first got it.
So amazing and you were just like you
were telling me about it.
The engineering is unprecedented and
they lost money on every one they sold.
They didn't make money on that car.
Why?
That makes a flagship car just to show
you,
look,
not only are we going to make something
that's better than any of your shit.
It's not going to break down ever.
It looks awesome and we're going to lose
money selling it.
Fuck you.
Shut.
You shut your mouth.
Damn,
and they kind of do that with the Nissan
does that now with this thing called the
GTR.
They have this car,
that GTR.
It's actually more expensive now than it
used to be for awhile.
It's like they were barely breaking even
on it,
but I think now they realize that has
such a demand that it's.
You can kind of charge more money and
they've continued to innovate it.
They continue to.
It's like a Samurai sword.
They built the Samurai sword and I want
to say the NSX came out like 2007 or
something like that.
I might be off,
but that time they've just made a better
version every year.
Every year,
every year.
Every year.
That's what it looks like now.
Two thousand and 15 cost.
That's a hundred and something thousand,
but it is a fucking spaceship.
Really.
I rented one of those when I was in
Austin at budget know Hertz.
Hertz rent a car will let you run a
fucking NSX.
Hilarious.
So I rented an Nsx and me and the
Hinchcliffe machine,
we're fucking tooling around.
That thing is the fastest fucking thing
I've ever done look like.
That's what I like about it.
It's such a,
you know,
it's kind of an understated sports car
that's not a GTR.
What is that?
That's got different tale laws.
Unless it's got.
No,
I think it's just unique tail lights.
Is that a real one?
Maybe the real tail lights or go back to
the previous image that you had.
That's the real tail lights.
They're really cool looking.
It's a spaceship man.
The way it handles,
it's all like the thing that people
don't like about it.
The people that don't like it,
most people love it,
but the thing that people are a little
perturbed about it.
Look at that.
That's the answer.
That's the Nissan.
I kept thinking we were looking at an
Acura.
I know there's a new ACURA NSX is coming
out as well,
but it probably won't be,
but go back to that image,
that rear end image that you just show
him.
Look at that fucking thing.
I mean that might as well be in star
wars.
Look at the fucking the way it's built
and all of that is aerodynamics.
Like all that shit you see around the
back end,
all that shit around the pipes.
That's all designed for downforce.
Extreme amounts of downtown Florence is
super important to me.
Well,
that's why it has that.
Tailoring it in the back of it.
That's all about keeping the ass end
down because this thing has such fucking
insane power that sometimes they can
catch a flight.
Like there's one of the nerves have that
Goddamn,
uh,
the wing,
yes,
yes.
But still,
because of that,
sometimes they get back end heavy,
which means the front end comes off the
ground and they go flying through the
air.
Yeah,
it happened recently at the nurburgring.
So Nurburgring look up this gtr crash at
nurburgring.
It's a crazy thing to watch because you
realize this is not just a crash.
This is a guy that has no control of his
car because the cars wheels aren't
touching the ground.
It's flying.
It's crash.
Not Grad.
Okay,
let go to videos.
That's it right there.
Bam.
Watch this shit.
Oh,
you motherfucker.
Watch this shit.
This hurts my,
like,
my anticipation hurts my adrenal glands.
Oh whoa.
Whoa,
whoa.
Yep.
Look washed out again.
He's going around the corner.
That's what it kills.
So many died man.
So he died in this.
Yes,
they did not hit.
Was hit by the car.
Look at this shit.
He's coming over the hill and it just
catches flight.
Like he's,
he's scraping along the back bumper.
Like just skipping through the air.
Fucking crazy.
The front end came so far off the ground
that the car literally was bumper to the
ground.
Like look at that,
the bumpers on the ground to the wind
upside down.
How fast is he?
The wheel actually caught it from going
upside down.
It goes back forward again and it flips.
Oh,
he's going ridiculously fast,
but that's not what the problem was.
The problem was he lost control.
I mean it's not about going fast.
It's about when do you go fast and when
do you slow down and you got to know,
look,
I'm a circuit.
Like the Nurburgring,
the Nuremberg ring is the most famous of
all circuits when it comes to testing a
car's lap time.
Like if you can get a really fast lap
times the nurburgring,
it's worth millions of dollars because
that car will be the new king of the
Nuremberg ring.
The GCR was like,
I think one of the best production cars
in terms of lap times the fastest for
the longest time was a corvette Zr one
this fucking insane 650 horsepower
corvette.
But now the new corvette,
z o six is even faster than that.
And every year everyone's trying to get
a faster lap time on that track.
But here's the problem with that track,
that track sort of mimics the real world
and a sense that it's not like a flat
line.
It's not like a flat circle,
like a nascar thing,
but there's ups and downs and twists and
turns.
When you.
You're changing levels,
you're going down.
It's what you get from a real.
It's a real test,
the real test of the car's ability in
the real world.
So that is particularly disturbing
because that guy's coming off that hill
like that with the kind of power that a
real gtr that you could buy in a store
has and he's going flying through the
air.
So you have to stop and think,
look how beautiful that is.
God,
is that where the crash took place?
That's the nerve again.
Oh my God,
look how beautiful it is around it.
It's amazing.
I've never seen when people stand too
close to car races like that with no
protection.
Other guys who are golf watching golf,
when the guy tees off and what are they?
Right in the line of fire.
You as a good point this,
especially though,
right?
Look how beautiful that is,
man.
You're flying around next to this
unbelievable countryside,
so gorgeous parts of Germany and parts
of Switzerland and parts of France that
are just like that,
that blow your mind.
Then you go into these little towns and
they'd been there for a thousand years.
The issue with this racetrack though
apparently is that a lot of inclement
weather,
like you'll watch a bunch of labs,
they'll do what's raining out and shit
like in the UK,
you know,
like top gear.
One of the hilarious things about top
gear,
um,
is that so often they're testing cars
and it's raining.
Like Chris Harris I've had on the
podcast before is like one of my
favorite automotive journalists.
So many times he's driving a car and
it's raining out really.
And these tests.
Yeah,
she's in the UK.
It rains all the fucking time.
Think and maybe this is maybe not so,
but it's raised card racecar driving
more popular in Europe than it is in the
United States.
That I would say so,
yeah.
Formula One,
they're just like dumb racing nascar.
He's got swag man.
And swapping bank is why does he have a
southern accent is most of the people
that will listen to.
What if I did it like a contradicting
yourself?
What if I would accidentally be
sophisticated?
It looks like the swabbing paint that
moment
they're going left.
I'm Lin love with this.
Chevron is gaining ground on him.
I tell you,
man,
it's unbelievable the way he continues
to turn left baffles the mind of razor.
He's doing a reparable damage to his
reputation and to his chassis.
How can he do it with such accuracy?
The art form outrageous.
Now they're fighting.
They're.
There's a weird culture.
The English man,
they they.
They're also the regal illness and their
their way.
They have like set up all these
different sorts of patterns that they
follow.
All the rest and behavior of control.
Do you play snooker?
A madden play snooker of a hooligan will
be playing eight ball at the ball,
but a gentleman prefers Nuka.
Knowing your place,
knowing your place,
discipline.
The British were always very disciplined
about protocol.
What's to be done,
what's not to be done made good soldiers
or home until they've figured out
Americans figured out.
Just shoot it.
That white stripe that they're keeping
the middle of their chest.
That was a long time ago.
Domino's was a shit.
It ain't gonna work,
but it's all the same thing.
Yeah.
People from their folly,
they need to learn what they were
wearing wigs and they had wool coats on
in the.
In the heat.
It sucked.
Was that about like what was the wig
thing and protocol.
Powdered wigs.
Like why did they have powdered wigs?
There was always a form of even the
French up until World War One war,
you know,
lots of like very like feathers and very
brightly colored clothing.
Peacocks,
yeah.
As a.
As a soldier,
you are.
You,
first of all,
you had a uniform and our uniform is
going to be much more grandiose.
We have more money than you people do.
We're.
We're a higher birth so our soldiers are
decorated with the honor that that is,
that is bestowed on the greatest army.
There is where a sparkling jewel.
All of that.
Our sabers are are polished,
shiny,
and bright colors.
Think about how birds.
It's the same thing until Vietnam.
Those motherfuckers started heightened
and holes in the ground shooting at us
and the Brits always just wear khaki.
The breads would just fucking down home.
Khaki motherfuckers.
They were just like,
yeah,
you guys were all your stuff.
We're going to look.
Had to wear Khakis.
I wonder who figured out hunting like
Cammo for hunting.
Like who's the first person to invent?
He goes back to millennials I think,
think so.
Fuck leaves and shit.
Right?
As they were covering themselves and
leaves waiting in the cold for dinner.
Fuck yeah,
they made it.
You didn't.
You didn't get to this point.
Trust me,
trust me.
You with your fucking ironic glasses on
that don't even have a real lens.
Like people were like clear glass.
Fashion has always been another thing
that we.
Fashion has always been there fast,
but people's appearance.
I mean,
you know,
if you look at indigenous cultures that
have had very little contact,
they're still putting bones there.
Knows I'm wearing feathers and
peacocking men and women,
but the eyeglass one is one of the
weirdest ones.
Well,
because it's a friend of mine's mother.
He couldn't get a job.
It wasn't a friend of mine.
It's a friend of mine told me this story
about this kid.
He's Puerto Rican and he couldn't get a
job and his mother said he'd been on.
He was a great student.
He's a great guy.
Just couldn't get a job.
I was trying to work on Wall Street.
His mother went out and bought him a
pair of glasses,
just clear glasses and he got us.
I got every job we went in for.
He had glasses on.
They went,
this guy must read and he got every
fucking job.
His mother was genius.
He said,
I'm going to put some glasses on your
watch this.
It's also the only a candy cap that is
sexually arousing 100 percent.
Like men,
like a secretary looking chick with
glasses on.
Women like with classes really do
though.
Yeah.
Tell me about it.
When you do put glass on style,
I have to use my reading glasses
sometimes.
We resist all the time and my wife went,
that's really sexy,
just looks old.
She likes gray in my beard.
Guys,
they're dying.
Loves old guy.
She loves the old men.
She loves him.
Wrinkly.
Dude.
Rankles.
We're almost out of time.
I understand that you're going to be in
Sacramento doing your standup comedy
this weekend.
Brian tells them about it and they're
actually expect that the punch line.
I'm glad you asked Joe.
I'm going to be at the Sacramento
punchline tearing it up this Thursday,
Friday,
Saturday,
and I am under the impression I've been
talking to Tj dillashaw and your
favorite.
There's a chance they might come out and
see me because they're friends of mine
and I couldn't be more excited about
that.
Yes.
Thursday,
Friday,
Saturday.
Joe,
and I want to say one more thing I,
you know,
I've got a podcast called the fighter
and the kid heard that it gets one point
$5,
million downloads a month.
That's,
that's the rumor and it just to end in
the rumors.
True.
Wow.
More importantly,
I'm going to be having A.
There's a.
There was a documentary called Lady
Valor and I'm going to be having the
navy seal who became a woman,
uh,
Kristen Beck on our podcast and I am
very excited.
That is.
We're going to keep the camera on him.
Jamie.
This is a surprise.
That's right.
Gentlemen,
we're going to record it soon.
She's just taking the shirt off and
you've got,
you've got a body looked like a naked
silverback is a surprise dude.
Oh,
sorry buddy.
I love it.
Oh,
okay.
Here we got the surprise coming.
You guys.
Christmas comes early.
Those gentlemen are biggest promoter.
Looking at not just the shirt but a
cultural phenomenon.
This shirt,
this master,
Ken's 1984 taekwondo national champions
shirt from the fighter and the kid,
they sold 800 of them in about six
minutes,
right?
They flew off the shelves.
Just keep them in stock.
They bought new ones.
They were gone by the end of the day.
They're twice restocked shirt.
This motherfucker right here.
A cultural phenomenon that is the
fighter and the kid.
Now,
what does that feel?
We're running out of time,
but that's kind of trippy like to know
that you guys like yours or like pet
show is taken off.
It really is.
It really is a good fucking podcast.
I appreciate it.
And a lot of it has to do with your
support and we just try to keep it
inspiring and funny and uh,
and I,
you know,
it's,
it's one of those things,
I think it's chemistry,
I'm just doing it and showing up and
it's just a,
you never expect it to be.
You don't,
you're not managing success.
I just show up and do it.
But I think Brendan and I have a great
chemistry.
It's very unusual.
Hilarious.
You guys were together too.
Yeah,
it's,
it's a very,
very funny chemistry.
We crack each other up and try to stay
as authentic as we can.
That's,
that's rare and both really good dudes
that comes through in the show.
Like I know a lot of people that like on
the underground,
especially like that guy won me over
fucker.
Like they listen to a fighter and the
kid can't used to them.
I'm telling you,
like I was telling,
I've been telling Dana white this
forever.
I'm like,
the guy,
he's a great guy.
Like I gotta get to take himself
seriously.
He's very aware of his faults and he's
always working on that to rose.
He's so silly.
Hilarious Shit.
Did you see the instagram?
I posted of him wearing that hat.
I was like,
I can't be friends with him.
He kept going all hands on deck,
all hands on deck.
Everybody like,
we don't know that people were playing
volleyball with these.
He's got his hands on his knees,
this giant UFC fighter all hands on
deck.
That's always fun for everybody else who
falls outside trying to figure out
what's happening on making.
His motto was cauliflower ear.
He's so silly.
Yeah.
He's a funny dude,
a fighter and the kid.
It's available on itunes.
It's hilarious.
Podcast.
It really is fun and you guys get some
great guests and lady valor.
That's going to be very interesting.
I want to talk to her.
I want to have her on.
That's a.
that's an insane story and I'll ask
better questions to you.
So what I'll do is I'll just watch you
guys fuck it up first.
I'll come in.
I've been trying to think what to ask
her.
I'm so excited.
Oh yeah.
We went Turkey hunting.
This podcast is supposed to be about
that.
We missed it.
We also did a podcast last week.
Folks,
if you want to get it,
it's available on itunes.
It's just in the car with an iphone.
Just Brian and I drive and having fun
for like two hours or something.
Talking about the fighter and the kid
podcast.
Uh,
the punchline in Sacramento this
weekend,
Friday,
Saturday,
Sunday or Friday,
Thursday,
Friday,
Saturday.
I'll fucking phenomenal club.
If you live up there and you haven't
been there,
it's an iconic club.
It's one of the best.
Love it set up clubs in the country.
And this weekend,
Brian,
mother fucking Cowen.
count with a Y,
B R,
y a n on twitter,
much loved Sacramento.
Sacramento fuckers.
See you soon.
Punchlines punchlines Sacramento.
All right,
that's it.
I'm at the cod theater.
May Twenty second with Tom Segura and
Tony Hinchcliffe,
the court theater at the mgm in Vegas.
That's all I got coming up.
See?
Oh,
this weekend in Montreal,
but it sold out.
All right.
Much love you fuckers.
See you soon.