Okay,
boom.
That's it alive.
We're on now.
Fuck you,
Joe Rogan.
My man.
Thanks so much for having me back.
Thanks for coming back.
There's a lot of pee everywhere.
I F this is the fucking tonight show,
man.
Where I go.
My and her.
John,
Joe Rogan heard you on Joe Rogan's.
Been the last year of my life so
I can stop at.
Stop fucking answering them when I'm
going to be back back right now.
You are back right now?
Yeah,
it feels weird.
It feels like it feels like it was here
like two days ago.
That's a problem.
Maybe you're drinking too much on the
road.
I definitely was drinking too much.
Um,
I,
uh,
I went to my,
the last tour I ended up in a,
I don't want to make,
it's not too bad.
Ended up in the emergency room in the
last tour with,
uh,
with the Ivs,
but the fucking real shit.
Yeah.
I went a little too.
I don't know,
I don't.
They said it was kind of just exhaustion
and you know,
whatever.
And you know,
the,
the normal.
I think that people at the emergency
room wouldn't believe me that it wasn't,
you know,
on hardcore drugs because they come in
and I'm just,
I'm fucking out of it.
And I am
like,
where you been?
I've been,
I've been out on tour.
Then I go,
shit,
we know what's up and they torched it on
my blood work and there was no shit in
there.
And then nothing at all.
No,
I think,
I think it was honestly kind of just
meet at what they did,
find some kind of like vibe,
like a bug or whatever,
just bug that I had been on.
That probably was more of it than I
thought,
but I really do think it was just
kind of nonstop every night rocking out
and you know,
pushing it a little too hard.
So you really did wind up in the
emergency room?
Yeah.
Yeah,
it was that.
I mean the official diagnosis was just
exhaustion.
What were you worried about?
Like what did you think?
You didn't think you could just go to
sleep?
Like how does one go to the emergency
room?
What happened?
What happened was I,
um,
I was off the tour and had a meeting
with some managers and shit and in the
meeting I fucking barfed like in a,
in a,
in a nice building.
We're in a nice building talking about
shit rush.
You're talking about the shit that rick
is over here doing it with like guys in
suits and I fucking threw up on myself.
Whoa.
And they go,
are you okay?
And I go,
I think I am in,
they hand me a banana to get some food
in me and I couldn't peel the banana.
So then I just,
I drove myself to the emergency room,
couldn't peel the banana,
didn't have the strength to open a
banana.
Really?
Yeah.
But I do now.
Um,
and then I,
um,
I drove myself to the emergency room and
they hooked me up to ivs,
like put me on fluids and everything.
Just to give you an example,
I,
so when they finally said I was good to
go,
I went back out and I couldn't fucking
find my car
and I just checked my parking ticket.
I was like,
where's this lot?
And I called the guy on the lot,
he's like,
yeah,
your cars in here.
It's the windows are down and it's,
I guess apparently I just drove myself
to the emergency room and fucking close
the doors and walked into the emergency
room and said help me.
Wow.
So yeah.
And I actually,
you know,
while he was,
we talked about last time a guy who was
a big help to me.
Then I was just like,
I reached out to starch,
I'll just like,
you know,
do you ever get like,
just because at the time I just,
I didn't know I had a bug.
I thought it was just pure exhaustion,
which again,
doesn't that sound like the old rock,
the rock star,
like heroin excuse,
like he's exhausted,
he has to cancel a tour.
And I reached out to Sturgis and he's
just like,
yeah man,
you gotTa,
you know,
take care of yourself out there.
Just,
you know,
it's mental,
physical,
everything.
Fatiguing,
you know,
I think I need to figure out a way.
It's funny,
I was,
I forget who you were talking to a few
weeks ago talking about um,
talking spirits,
shit about suicide and stuff and about
how exercise is such an important part
of that and I've been on a pretty
vigorous.
I've been,
you can't tell,
but I've been running a ton which you've
been running to and um,
I was talking to a doctor recently and
he was like,
um,
uh,
he told me about a study they did with
um,
with like $200.
He told me he was like a couple,
the 200 depressed people and the study
was half of them.
They gave Prozac the other half they put
on a strict like running regimen.
They said there was no difference
between the two.
It's like they both,
they were both helped a ton and the,
the running,
I don't want to give out,
you know,
medical information,
but that's,
you know.
Yeah.
The woman I had on Kelly Brogan,
she's a psychiatrist.
She said that it's more effective.
That exercise is actually more effective
than psych meds.
I'm wondering
just the fact that a doctor told me that
makes me think that he was airing on,
you know,
he still wants to sell the drugs,
but I'm just wondering if like um,
because I started when I fucking run,
I feel fucking great.
I mean I can't do it in cowboy boots and
shit,
but you know,
it's hard to do.
It's hard to wake when you're on,
when you do the tours.
Tours just hard to wake up before
showing.
Yeah,
it's very hard.
But you gotta do it.
You've got to do it.
Like it's brushing your teeth.
Like it's,
you know,
it's just something that is.
If you give yourself the possibility
that you won't do it,
then you won't do it.
Exactly.
And I think in my back,
my head,
I'm like,
well this is a tour,
this is a little vacation,
a little break and that's just,
that's why I need it the most.
I got to start.
When you think about it as a tour,
is that what you think about?
I think about it as work.
I think about his work,
but I think about it as like,
that's my excuse for not.
Oh yeah.
It's definitely.
It's definitely more work than anything.
Yeah.
The human brain seeks comfort,
man.
We like to fuck ourselves up.
I try to take those little nap so you
don't really need and blow things off
that you really should do.
So.
Weird Shit.
We just got back from New York City and
I,
I fell asleep on the couch for what?
You know,
I just woke up from.
I just slept for 12 hours.
Wow.
I feel.
I feel great now,
but
I bet it would help you with this torn.
I bet if you like really got hardcore
into shape and start eating right.
I brought it would definitely help.
Totally.
Yeah.
Well I'm not going to work.
We got a tour lined up for I think mid
July and I'm not.
I'm not going if I don't do it,
like if I don't get up and fight,
don't make sure there's someone there
making me do all that shit.
I ain't going to do the tour because
I've been looking at your tour online
and.
But looking at some of the photos and
videos from your shows,
they're insane.
Yeah.
It's been pretty crazy.
You know,
you're doing giant places.
I'm a giant,
but you know,
uh,
hoping that it gets bigger.
But it's been,
it's been fun.
It's,
it's a um,
it's been a fucking blast.
You know,
one,
to me,
one thing,
I hate to change the subject,
but it's just like I'm going get the new
record out here,
boy out and I'm still making records.
Yeah.
This,
I think this one's better.
But Jamie,
what are that sound?
I mean,
I mean like actual physical copy.
I know it's the only thing I could
bring.
I can't like bring it out like to
spotify.
I should have just.
Yeah.
Um,
it's almost like,
these are kind of silly now because I
gave it to one guy.
He's like,
my man,
you give it to somebody that their
desktop,
their laptop doesn't even have a CD
player and you're like,
thanks for the CD.
I'll throw it in the back of the car and
load it up and listened to it in the
car.
Most cars still have a CD player.
Bet they'll stop pretty soon.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
I used to have a,
an Acura NSX and had a cassette player
and is still the cell phone holders.
That's where they're putting the thing
to hold them.
Now instead of put it in your error,
dear air filter thing or the AC comes
out to clip on that.
There's like a little thing that spreads
out to this fits in the CD slot.
Ah,
taking up space.
I don't know about you,
but what my new thing is everywhere I
go,
you know,
I ran,
I ran a car.
I'll get to the airport and rent a car.
Right in the first 20 minutes is mason
in that fucking car trying to figure out
the Bluetooth and it.
Every time you find that it just like
every fucking one.
They make it so fucking impaler
yeah.
I love cadillacs,
but God damn that escalate.
Infotainment system is a piece of shit.
It's so bad.
It's so hard to work.
Apparently they switched it.
Now they're going to do apple car play,
which is infinitely better.
You might.
Uber driver had that the other day I
asked him,
finally had something to talk about with
my uber driver.
He was telling me,
explain it to me.
It looked like the whole interface was
just.
Yeah,
it's like a phone.
It's not the whole interface because you
know,
you can't get most of your apps,
but you get things like messages,
podcasts,
things on the science.
Yeah,
I mean the good.
I mean,
what I was kind of getting to before is,
you know,
we're talking about the crowds and shit,
which was when I first put out these
crazy records of mine,
um,
you know,
the,
the assumption was,
um,
you know,
there's nowhere,
there's nowhere to go,
right to terrestrial radio won't play
me.
I ain't doing all that shit,
but I don't want to kiss your ass too
much.
You know,
you know that.
But it was kind of finding this kind of
like,
this is all,
everything's fucking equal now.
It's like I was.
That was kind of the big breakthrough
for me was like,
and I did a few weeks ago,
did Joey Coco Diaz who's my new favorite
fucking dude,
this is the best time I'm now in the
Rogan world.
I did that and Bert Kreischer.
It's like,
it's like,
it's like doing the tonight show.
Then like Colby and I'm telling you
these things and I've got numbers to
prove it.
It's,
there is no mainstream media.
It's like if you go to the backdoor and
do all this shit,
it's,
it's bigger than that fucking shit.
What mainstream media if you.
No,
the actual numbers that they get,
it's not even close.
Like a good show on CNN,
you know,
might get a million,
a million and a half views.
If we got a million and a half
downloads,
we've pretty bummed out.
Yeah,
it's crazy because the week I came in
here,
I never even told you this.
So that week I came in here another,
someone told someone has access to these
numbers.
I don't have them,
but they said
I sold more albums from being on here.
Then the artists that we did on snl,
so this is,
that makes sense.
Like what is snl get what kind of uses
this?
And I'll get
on a good episode.
We'll get 10 million downloads.
Great.
I mean also too,
you know,
here it's,
it's me talking to you on snl.
It's like,
do they make it to the music?
Probably not.
They're just there now.
Some funny.
Well not only that,
they don't watch the whole thing because
snl,
I love snl sometimes.
SNL is one of those things though.
They fuck you like 70 percent of the
time.
Yeah.
I got really pissed about it.
And point 7 million views,
uh,
with the rock.
That's a one.
Oh,
the finale.
Okay.
So that's their big one of the year.
So the other big one is smaller than
yours and normal one.
Okay.
Melissa Mccarthy was 10 million of the
top two.
Okay.
So our top one for the year was Alex
Jones at 15 million.
And then number two be Neil.
I think
Alex Jones got put out of country
record.
You should probably should.
Reptilians and black helicopters and he
could do it too from Texas.
That shit would sell.
Yeah.
Fucking would Alex Jones to just wanting
to country music,
country,
new world order music.
I'll fucking.
I'll produce that shit.
You should come on a show.
You should go on a show and just start
talking crazy shit about storage will
again.
Yeah.
Oh by the way,
and this is not for lawyer reasons,
but I'm sturgill Simpson is not
affiliated with the CIA,
nor is he a trained CIA assassin.
I want to get that on the record last
time.
It's possible.
I may have mentioned that.
I think you did.
I think you said he worked for James
Comey and he was a.
yeah,
he has no affiliation with the CIA.
He's doing some weird fucking gigs in
Europe this year that look a little
fishy to me and I don't get it,
but I think it might be over there doing
some hits on the site.
The lawyer part of me says no,
but the sensible part of me,
he's doing some dates in Europe with
John Prine.
I think John Prine kind of talks to
them.
Sales them down and then starts.
We'll fucking take.
Who's that guy?
Who's John?
John.
John Prine.
Great.
Fucking a folk kind country singer.
He's great.
He's just getting into the country
world.
He's the last slide.
Almost call them like more like folk.
He's more in that kind of.
Isabel struck him in spiritual Sharon
office in Nashville.
Yeah.
It's bells in a weird category,
right?
He's kind of country,
but he's also kind of folk at this days.
We don't know nowadays what the fuck his
country who the funder is.
I complain about all the time,
but you know,
Jason Isbell is a bad motherfucker
though.
Oh dear.
He damaged as I heard a few songs from
his new record.
Sounds killer.
Yeah.
I think he's going to ruffle some
feathers too because it sounds like a
little political,
which is a no,
no in that world,
you know,
so
um,
it's kind of a crazy day.
Did you watching that shit,
that shit this morning.
Call me stuff.
I didn't watch it.
Did you watch it?
I watched some of it,
but it was,
I felt like it was a waste.
It's just like shit we knew before.
It's just like politicians lie a Komi.
It was like I felt like we knew well,
I didn't see.
I didn't see anything fucking knew.
It seems like it's way too easy to fire
him.
Like you could just decide you don't
like what he's doing at firearm.
They didn't seem to be any like real
clear definitive reason why he was
fired.
He,
I mean like the,
like the main news is like I said,
politicians lie,
you know,
news flash and the other one was like,
they can make the point that like trump
is a different.
It's different than.
Most presidents were like he used to
host a reality show.
No Shit.
We knew that.
That was their big takeaway.
It's like two hours of fucking.
I just used the time to fucking tweet
about my new record saying how I kept
tweeting that James Comey was.
It was all code for my new record that
he wanted people to buy it.
I know I saw some instagram posts that
had a Colombian endorsing your album.
Yeah.
He's a big fan.
He,
he,
he said he wanted to talk about it
during the hearings because that's a big
audience,
but the,
apparently they wouldn't let them go.
Yeah,
collusion between me and comey would
have fucked things up.
Is that what it's called?
Yeah.
Uh,
well I actually,
it's funny because this guy,
because there's,
they say there's a chance which looking
less like there's this guy,
luke combs who like my arch nemesis even
though he's a good dude.
I just,
he was up against me this week on the
country charts because my album comes
out.
My new album came out this week and I'm
trying to beat him and I sit on twitter
that Russians have colluded with Sony
records to like have him out sell me and
he kind of played along.
So we'll see.
I think,
I think they are,
I mean Nashville's definitely trying to
keep me down,
but are they really,
are they fucking with you?
Like how,
how are they receiving you now?
Now that you've become a mainstream
success?
Because I hear about you all the time.
Donald Cowboy Cerrone,
I think you know that he listens to your
music before he goes out and fights.
Ronnie reached out to me thanks to you,
he called,
he called me up and he was on the set of
a movie with Michael Madsen and uh,
they got,
I don't know how it seems like last
second,
but they'd go,
hey capital,
you've got a scene tomorrow where you
sing Karaoke with Michael Madsen.
And he saw you on saying and he's like,
fucking eating pussy kicking ass.
The producers like,
fuck you talking about.
He's like,
I want to say eating pussy kicking ass.
do you have the rights to this song?
He's like,
I'll have it in like five minutes.
He just fucking calls me.
I call my peoples,
like now I'm in a movie with cowboy
cerrone and Michael Madsen singing eaton
pussy kicking ass.
He said he was in the trailer,
you know,
like,
rehearsing with Michael Madsen gets to
the sucking Dick Park.
And I think he was just like,
what the fuck we sing in here man.
He's been,
he's been awesome.
And um,
yeah,
kind of like I to,
I'm now in your world,
you know,
doing,
I just did.
I was telling you before I did joey,
Coco Diaz,
Bert Kreischer,
like all these dudes.
It's like,
it's cool to have.
It's cool because I went into the second
album,
I was like,
I gotta make my fucking money back.
You know,
it wasn't about the money.
I'm just saying it's like,
what am I going to,
it's going to be the same shit again.
But like no one I have these other
places to go now is so fucking great.
Yeah,
well that's,
there's a transition happening and I
think for the longest time they always
felt like the whole idea of mainstream
media like that was just going to be
locked up.
That was going to be the case forever.
It's CBS,
NBC,
the Cable News Networks.
They were gonna be there forever.
That's not really the case anymore.
No.
And like I said,
I've got the numbers to prove it,
but you know,
I came,
everyone was telling me,
you know,
you can't get on fucking good morning
America.
You can't be on fucking terrestrial
radio.
And I just kind of lucked into finding
this and you guys been being supportive
and shit.
It's just like these things are.
It's,
it's all.
I think I saw Mark Marin,
some guy was tweeting to him like how
your podcasts fucking,
it ain't the tonight show or something.
And he,
he said something back to the guy,
you know,
it's just all media now.
And that's kind of how I look at it.
It's all fucking even where.
I mean,
I mean you guys are probably bigger
than,
you know what they quote unquote
mainstream media.
But it's to me it's just all,
it's all part of the same fucking thing.
Like,
yeah,
what's up
bigger and what's more popular as all
kinds of silly thing that's different is
that if you go to mainstream media,
if you go to television shows for the
most part,
you're not going to get 100 percent
dedicated audience.
You get.
People are just flipping through the
channels.
So some people might fall upon them
because they were looking for it.
But a whole lot of people I just going
to be flipping channels.
Like what's on
exactly.
And the people who listen to you,
like that's why the first pod,
I don't want this whole podcast to be a
review of the last one,
although I wouldn't mind because I had a
blast.
But
the whole,
when they tune into you,
they're like,
it's like it's your buddy,
if you say by the new Wheeler Walker Jr
record,
they fucking buy it by the new Wheeler
Walker Jr.
Record there that I said it.
They'Re going to buy it now.
can you?
Um,
it's called old.
Always lived by the way.
I just found out something that you guys
either you guys know about this.
I became a hit yesterday on some I never
heard of on black twitter.
You became a hit on black twitter.
Black twitter is a big fan of black
twitter.
So they,
he alerted me to black twItter.
I wasn't even aware of.
I didn't know.
BuT the more black people I can bring
any country music,
the happier I'm going to fucking be.
Terrence rutgers not bringing in a ton.
No,
no.
It's all white people.
Yeah.
Is it most of white girls to write?
Probably.
Yeah.
But no,
I'm the king,
I'm the king of black country and I'll
say that loud.
Really?
Yeah.
So they took a clip from a um,
fuck you bitch from the first record and
some one of the big black twitter guys
put like a,
a clip of it.
And just at the top it's like,
I didn't know Country music went this
hard and so then it like got it got
millions and millions of views and all
of a sudden my.
Because now my new album,
oh wheeler,
but now is out.
And the first one's going back up the
fucking charts too because of black
twitter.
So we got white white people buying the
new one in black people buying the old
one.
Interesting.
Yeah.
Well who's this guy,
if you know blackboard,
you know,
day kwan tae,
do you know de quan?
Really big instagram accoUnt.
I'll pull it up for it.
And who is this fellow?
Is he fell.
It's a group of people like the fuck
jerry accounter.
Oh I have no idea.
But,
and then like a business definitely.
And then erica,
bad new fucking tweeted about it and she
said she's a big.
She's a singer.
She used to bake steering.
Rnb singer.
Yeah.
The biggest thing.
Or in the nineties,
a big singer.
The nineties.
Oh,
tyrone.
Tyrone tarlant.
I feel like I'm calling in from another
planet.
I had no idea what this fucking black
show today.
Yeah,
the black twitter
is fascinating to me.
I thought it was like a hashtag,
but it's not even a de quan.
9 million followers.
Wow.
Yeah,
go down.
You'll see it.
You'll see it down there somewhere.
And they posted a letter right there on
the right.
Yeah.
I never,
I never heard of a country district till
now.
a
2 million,
700,000 views.
That was in a few hours after being on
the road for a fucking year.
I should just talk to dave clark.
Well,
there's so mAny guys that have a youtube
accounts now to that.
They'll put up a video just talking
about something that just happened in
the news and they'll get 7 million
views.
That's crazy you say that because I am.
One of the guys I work with,
call me up and go,
who's jehovah?
They go see somebody in your video keeps
talking about jehovah.
And so I,
of course I look it up.
There's a guy playing wii.
He just fucking plays video games in his
parents basement and while he was
playing the video in the millions of
people watch while he's playing the
fucking video games,
he was singing my songs just along to
it.
And lIke the album started cell went
back up the charts and it's like,
that's the world we live in now is a
dude in his mom's basement singing,
sorry if you don't live in your mom's
basement jehovah.
But he probably doesn't.
He's probably making millions of dollars
playing video games.
It's crazy.
And then he calls me and then he,
he tweets me,
he goes,
um,
I always thought about doing a podcast.
He goes,
you mind if I just skype in and just do
one,
just try it out with you.
And I'm like,
that's where other artists would just be
like,
fuck that.
I go,
I'm home.
Just,
yeah,
let's do it.
So I went on his,
he posted an interview with me on his
youtube page and it just,
I don't know that it was huge,
but it was just like,
why am I not saying well?
I say no.
Just like,
yeah,
it's all.
It's like you said,
it's all fucking.
Even though,
yeah,
it's
might not even be.
Even guys like that pooty pie guy.
I don't know how much he's dropped off
since the nazi controversy,
but that guy was,
he has millions and millions of
downloads for every single thing he
does.
Like he might be above mainstream media.
I give you that.
I think that's one of the reasons why he
felt like they were going after and like
the wall street journal went after him,
was at the Washington post,
the wall street journal,
wall street journal.
Because both of them,
eventually they went after him and they
kinda made it seem like he was a nazi
sympathizer.
He was making a few inappropriate jokes.
what'd he say?
What'd he say?
He just joked around and did like a sieg
heil salute or something like that.
but he was apparently making fun of
people that were nazis making fun of the
idea of being nazis.
that's great.
That's been all been distorted and
twisted.
I agree with you.
I mean like I was like this new record.
I feel like there's people out there way
after you that are coming after me and
try to make sure I don't chart high,
which by the way I'm banned from all the
chains.
Are you really?
Yeah.
Best buy,
best buy.
Walmart.
Target.
Exactly.
Put.
The weird thing is country music fans
do.
And that really pissed me off.
Yeah.
And it was this other site,
pledge,
pledge music where you can preorder
albums.
I was the first album they ever dropped.
So they're buying cds.
Still has led.
one of the few genres is still bought
cds,
genres of buy cds.
And so I can't compete wIth on the
charts as well because they're making
sure I don't go.
And I think honestly it's not just the
language that's bothering him,
it's the fact that I'm doing it outside
of this.
So thank you.
Can't go on rogan and joey diaz and you
know,
like we have a way that we do it,
we do it on the radio.
We'd go on fucking tonight show like
you're messing up.
Like it's all these guys in suits,
walking down music row in nashville.
Like you don't tell anyone that don't
tell anyone that nobody needs us or
you're going to fuck up our fucking
jobs.
But I think also they don't like that
you're,
I mean you're opening up the door for
people doing pretty much anything in
country music now with the crazy fucking
lyrics and the fact that it's been so
successful and you got people,
you got a whole goddamn theater filled.
thousands of people singing along to eat
and pussy and kick it as my favorite.
MY favorite one is when I go out and
tour and I see a sea of just like,
like do you know bros backwards,
baseball hats and all singing along
which one you queers going to suck my
dick and a singing every fucking word.
And for all I know I was going to call
them to make America gay too.
Or just because I think they're all
going home.
I think they.
I think they because they listen to
everything.
I think they're just going home and
blown each other.
Do you think that you have that kind of
power with a really good song?
Get a guy to go home?
I'll.
I mean if anyone can.
It's me because my songs are that
fucking good,
but I mean,
but there's.
But there's no way these dudes have ever
in their life screen.
Which one are you?
Queer is going to suck my dick and I
would imagine of fucking open
area.
So.
But along with a bunch of other people
doing it,
that's the thing.
Gives them freedom.
Yeah.
I think it's weird.
It's probably weird for their wives when
they go,
yeah,
what'd you do tonight?
We went out with 800 dudes and screamed
about blowing each other.
She'd go,
did you actually blow each other?
Like girls will find a loophole or.
no,
we didn't actually do it.
Okay.
Yeah.
I think I'm kind of hoping to get some
of the women back with this,
with this.
Do you think you lost a lot of them with
fuck you bitch?
No,
the women women's favorite song because
they,
I think they could sing it too.
They can see it from all three
perspectives way that they had that much
that they had that much.
Like for example,
the woman who made me write,
fuck you bitch had that much power over
me to make me write that.
DoeS she know who she is?
Um,
I think she does now unfortunately.
But um,
she laughs and I think she's honestly
upset and I've,
and I've had,
that's happened a couple times.
I've been,
I've been on some,
a po po.
Do you know this is new.
This is podcast I fucking love called.
I think you've talked about before.
two guys we fucked pod,
which is basically women talking about
women,
talking about dudes.
The way that guys talk about women and I
fucking love it.
And,
and it's,
it's the way women talk about men when
we're not around.
So it's like an eye opener for dudes,
but for some reason there's been no,
no one's really done that before.
And I was in New York to impress and
they'd reached out before they wanted to
use one of my songs and I was like,
well,
I'm out there.
I like,
can I stop by?
And of course I just start telling a
bunch of fucking stories than my phone
starts blowing up.
Like,
don't fucking know.
Don't tell him,
don't talk that shit.
And I got in a lot of trouble for that
one because you can't really go tell him
those kinds of stories on.
Because my thing was,
I didn't know that the podcast was that
fucking popular is.
Yeah,
they're very popular to a lot of.
A good example of what I use is like,
people always try to say that,
ah,
you can't start a new podcast and have
been successful today.
I'm like,
that's not true.
Those girls started that podcast just a
couple of years ago and fucking
gigantic.
Yes.
I mean,
I got a lot of fucking people talk.
I've gotten a lot.
I lost some pussy over,
but I've gotten a lot of trouble.
That's.
Well,
don't forget I got a podcast to do.
Yeah.
When did you start doing that?
Uh,
like a month ago.
It's actually what's weird as it's
doing.
It was the number one music podcasts for
like a month.
And I,
and I,
and I'll even admit like the problem
with doing a podcast now,
and I kind of want your notes on this,
but the problem is with someone like me
who sells records is I didn't,
I don't get the months of
testing and you know,
it's like they hear it from everyone
listened to the first,
you know,
there's no way there's,
I can't experiment as much and I can't,
you know,
obviously what you're saying.
Yeah.
That's the case with us to our first
ones are terriBle.
But that was to him but.
But yeah,
but,
but it was probably before but it was at
least before he got huge.
Yeah,
yeah,
for sure.
But they're still available.
Like if people who I'm going to start
from the beginning,
they might get to episode three and go
fuck this dude.
Yeah.
I mean you were in the early days you
were doing just like straight to video,
right?
With like video effects and shit.
Like,
yeah,
sometimes,
we had snow flakes in the background and
we'd do it right to a webcam.
I love it.
Yeah,
I mean it's been fun.
It's a cool way to just talk directly to
your people,
but
It's not my natural.
What happens is you had,
you had,
you talked to a good example about the
other day which is you just have
conversations like
I've been doing them all over the phone
because all the musicians I want to talk
to you on the road and when you do it
over the phone it becomes like an
interview and I don't want to interview.
I just want to talk to my friends,
um,
over the phone and over skype.
They're both weird.
I mean,
it's better than nothing.
Some people do well,
like sam harris does a good podcast over
skype,
but I think that it's,
uh,
it's just the lose something.
you want to be in the room with
somebody.
Burt was the one who told me that and
said like,
you know,
don't do it over the fucking phone.
And then I did one in person with a
singer.
I really liked it.
It was so much fucking bed.
We were just hanging out.
That's what,
that's what I like to listen to when I
was in a podcast,
his buddies hanging out,
you know?
So when you started touring from your
last album,
and it was this just out of the gate,
surprised,
smash hit took the whole country music
industry by storm.
What was that like?
Did you,
did it feel surreal because it seemed
surreal on the outside it felt it felt
surreal was because of my.
That's why it's this one so much
different and I kind of hate it.
There's expectations because what I left
the studio on the first album with the.
I just paid cash for.
I think I told you I didn't have a
label.
I didn't have any way to release It and
I was just like,
this is a great fucking record,
but it's a bummer.
No one's gonna hear it.
And I finally started getting it out
there and so then I really thought it
was going to just be like a cult record
and like I was gonna run into some do 10
years from now down the street.
Go,
you know,
I did the record,
but then when you know,
the guys who do the tours for me were
calling up like,
you're not going to fucking believe this
man.
We sold ouT,
you know,
you know la,
like the whole west with twitter for me
is because it's so country to me.
It's like we did a west coast tour and
I'm like,
what the fuck we do in a west coast tour
for the whole west coast sold out.
It's like,
well how the fuck did I sell tickets and
seattle and portland.
That makes no fucking sense to me.
Like do they even know what country
music is there?
I think,
I think it's almost like they're looking
at me like in a glass cage,
like look at the,
look at the redneck in his natural
habitat kind of thing.
So I think they're just having fun,
man.
Well I think they're having fun.
I think it's that too.
I think they're also,
if there are a lot of people out there
who do love country music and if you
love it,
there's not much of it left anyway.
Not to mention.
Not much the price goes to seattle or
portland isn't there seemingly is some
sort of a resurgence though and like
really good country music seems like
there is.
It seems like there is a little bit,
you know,
know there's sturgill is,
the guy,
the guys who still aren't chris
stapleton stapleton.
Yeah.
I mean I definitely feel it too.
But then again,
you know,
there's,
there was an award show and there's like
a country music award show on like every
fucking week now.
Either really.
Well there's a lot.
There was one last night like for the
cmt awards,
like why are they even have
entrepreneurial,
just show fucking redneck reality shows.
What would the,
what would the cmt still country music
television because I think they're like
changing or something right onto
changing.
Like they're,
I think they're,
yeah.
They reached out to me about something
and I said,
I told them I wanted to host the top 20
countdown.
I got a hard pass on that.
I think they're like,
would you make fun of the artists?
I'm like,
if they're shitty.
Alright,
see You later.
Um,
he,
I feel like I'm real countries coming
back,
but I also feel like the shitty stuff is
getting bigger,
like they're at going at the same,
like it's not that pop bro country shit,
which I talked a lot about last time,
like the Georgia law.
Well there's a new,
there's a new song by thIs guy chris
janson called fix a drink that just came
out because now I'm looking at
everything that's coming out the same
week as mine.
The song fix a drink was,
it was the worst fucking thing I've ever
fucking heard of my fucking life.
It's this white guy just kinda wrapping
about like fox news and he sings about,
I can't fix the world,
but I can fix you a drink.
I'm like,
jesus fucking christ.
I mean it was doing well.
It's doing better than me.
There's a lot of mutants out there.
Yeah,
I mean there's a lot of.
I mean,
who the fuck would.
even if you're not an expert music fan,
who would want to listen to a song about
fucking dude,
fix it.
A fucking drink.
A dude who wants to fix a drink,
a dude with limited use of his brain.
Exactly.
It's just like,
that's like his main.
That's like his main.
Um,
but to think about it there's,
we know there's a lot of fucking idiots,
right?
Think about how many People would just
double minded folks and then think about
how few people are talking directly to
them.
And then finally someone comes along and
does like finally,
finally.
Yeah.
Finally enough about life and you know,
enough sturgeon but life and like what
it's about.
Finally someone I can relate to,
just how much,
how much whiskey,
how much sour,
you know,
that's what I want to fucking hear it.
But some people just want life simple
down.
It isn't that sort of alwaYs been the
knock on country music in the beginning
because the country music would,
it does,
it sort of reinforces these stereotypes
of this simple step.
They tried to get me on that shit
Before.
I was just saying also I think they were
just like,
you know,
you're doIng like a,
you're like mocking redneck,
you know,
using a mocking like redneck shit.
And,
and all the crazy shit like fucking your
cat and like,
you know,
kIlling your dog and all that shit.
But I didn't think they got that.
I was just kind of making fun of my
buddies back,
you know,
like what the cliche of being a redneck
was.
You know,
and I still see it.
It's weird because we were talking about
the political shit,
like an snl.
There was a,
there was a sketch on snl near the end
of the season on,
you saw it,
but it was alec baldwin doing trump and
he was in a small town called union
kentucky's,
what they said,
which is actually not far from me.
And the whole
idea of the sketch was that this,
that um,
which I've been hearing a lot with,
these were these southern people who
were so dumb that they voted against
trump against their own interest.
Which I'm so sick of that fucking
narrative,
you know,
against their own interest.
How can they say that?
Well,
they're just saying that like,
there's a lot of,
there's been a lot of shit in the press
about how,
you know,
these old quote unquote southerners and
rednecks voted for trump,
but It's like they're the ones who work
there.
They're the ones who are going to lose
their health.
Aren't you even hear that a lot?
I don't know,
maybe it's just from my point of view,
but I found it very condescending to,
uh,
to,
and just,
you know,
I don't like the sketches.
It seems like,
you know,
like 50,
like in the foRties,
you know,
like some characterize Mr. Trump.
I got to,
you know,
that kind of shit.
You know,
I think people are nervous because the
same thing that you're saying when
you're talking about that there's no
mainstream media anymore and there's
just media.
When a guy like Donald Trump gets in
office,
it's,
it's changed what being a politician is
because now it seems like anybody can be
a politician.
Now we had a reality star that became
the president of United States law.
What?
You know,
what is this?
There's no real precedent.
Yeah.
There'S just a guy we have no control,
like we can't,
there's nothing we can control and we
can't stop non-politicians from being
president anymore and it seems like they
will be able.
They were able to do that for the
longest time.
Obviously.
There's a lot of other factors.
He's very rich.
He's very famous.
He handled a bunch of politicians for
many,
many years and paid them off and
understood and understood from behind
the scenes that going to be the next 20
presidents.
Are they all meet president?
kanye coming up.
Mark.
Mark cuban is the one they're talking
about,
but that is a good one.
He's.
He's rich.
He's on.
He's nice guy.
Smart.
Yeah.
I mean why not?
He'd be superior.
It's entirely possible.
He might do it.
Yeah.
I mean that's the one I keep hearing,
but yeah,
it could just be from now on.
You just buy the presidency.
Well,
it could be.
I mean,
until we figure out that that's a dumb
idea,
that being a president is a dumb idea.
It's a dumb idea to have one person
running shit that just the fact that
trump has the ability to fire that call
me guys,
ridiculous that he could just say,
yeah,
I don't like what you're doing.
You're fired.
Like doesn't even have to have some like
rocks.
Like if you get fired from walmart,
they have to have a reason like you,
you can get fired from the fucking head
of the fbi and you just.
He doesn't like the fact that you're not
willing to drop it.
Investigation.
That seems like that seems insane.
The whole.
Yeah.
The whole thing is fucking like.
I mean,
there's nothing more you can say other
than that.
This guy was hosted a reality show.
Now he's president and I think that's
another thing that fucking scares people
about.
Oh,
we'll walker jr is country stars aren't
allowed to fucking talk about that shit.
You know,
you can't talk politics.
You gotta you gotta fucking right man.
When the dixie chicks talked about joy
still killbuck go back.
Yeah,
they're done.
What happened with that?
They were essentially blackballed from
country music for years for saying that
they were against the war,
which by the way,
pr,
which,
which trump basically got elected,
you know,
he was,
he kept saying he was against that war
too.
So they like,
you know.
Well I think they said that he's an
embarrassment,
that they're embarrassed that George
Bush was the president.
I think it had more to do it.
They set it at a club in england,
so doing it out.
It's like you can't leave the country
and talk shit about american lawyers,
but if that was pop music,
that'd be super standard.
Like no big deal.
The weird thing,
I mean,
we grew up on like dylan and the beatles
and whatever,
hendrick people,
all they did was talk about that shit.
You know,
neil young,
it's like he,
his whole album
is just,
you know,
fuck this politician,
fuck this guy and you just can't do it
in country.
I don't know why that is.
Well,
it's the same thing.
We're talking about that simplified
narrative that these stereotypes of this
world where,
you know,
you go to bed and you get up in the
morning,
the birds chirping and you work hard all
day and you know,
and everybody loves god and it's,
it's just this simple version of the
world that's boiled down to like,
there's,
there's things that are allowed inside
the simple version of the world and
there's things that are expected and
then there's things that are just not
discussed and you don't discuss sucking
dick and kicking ass.
Yeah.
I mean,
you're supposed to keep that to
yourself.
A sucking dick and kicking ass.
That's supposed to in any way moch the
president.
Well,
that's,
that's.
Yeah.
I mean that's the other thing too,
is uh,
you know,
my first single pussy king,
the first song is I put that out and I
got everyone got so pissed,
you know,
you can't be totally go and I send the
interviews.
I'm like,
I heard worse.
Talk about this on meet the press.
You know,
they show us all that.
Grab the pussy talk.
Yeah.
I'm not grabbing the pussy.
I'm just talking about how I'm going to
stick my dick in it if with with
consent,
you know,
I don't think I used to work consenting
the song,
but I think even grab them by the pussy
was implied consent because he was
saying they let you let you grab.
ThAt whole thing was so fucking weird
because it's like,
I hate to still be talking about it,
but it's like
I just found it funny.
I like it.
It didn't change my opinion of the guy
at all.
he knew was a scumbag.
I mean,
you knew him in whatever ways.
This is who he is.
I think part of it too is about you
guys.
But like,
I'd never heard that phrase before.
Grabbing by the,
you know,
it's like,
no.
Yeah,
that's somethIng i'd heard.
So it was new here.
I have a question for you guys.
I have a question for you.
What do you think?
Here's a theory I have,
which is,
do you think someone that trump
organization.
I've been wondering this for like a year
now,
secretly after that happened because he
smiled.
No doubt he's a smart businessman.
Copyrighted that phrase,
because you know for spring break from
now on,
there's going to be grabbing by the
pussy shirts for a little while.
You could sell it,
but I think that's kind of died off.
Those things have like a short shelf
life,
like those fidget spinners,
anybody making those fidget spinners.
Salesman as you can now because a year
from now no one's going to.
I don't even know.
Yeah.
Part of black twitter.
No,
no,
no.
It's a kids.
They have these little things and they
spit them and they hold them up on their
finger and they spin around in circles
and people really weird.
I'm like,
crazy.
Yeah.
I was looking at on the other day,
I was like,
how the fuck did this become a popular
item?
But it won't be for very long tonight.
You it?
Yeah.
I know.
I've seen those online.
Online.
Just these things spin or.
Yeah,
they're nuts.
I have done.
We've become just like watching shit
been around.
Yup.
Well,
there's another thing to do in this
anti-stress device that you hold onto
and it's got like switches on it and
buttons that don't do anything.
You just hit the switches and press
buttons and supposedly like if you hold
onto this thing were you stressed out
and start hitting switches and pressing
buttons.
You feel better.
Yeah.
I'm sure that works like a fucking
child.
Um,
I think go back to let's just run
instead of either what we haven't even
mentioned,
but I think rick,
you're cut.
Uh,
I'm so fucking big now.
They're doing a fucking tv specials.
We have a guy here from showtime because
showtime special and they're doing the
recording my life and work and uh,
and uh,
you know,
it's weird for me to,
going to that they're making a tv
special about me,
but they let me do it on sensor not
telling the real story.
And I was like,
fuck it.
Just shoot it.
All right man.
But um,
they follow me around like that and I'll
do an interview in five minutes and I'll
just go get the fuck out of here.
Wow.
Said fucks up.
But he,
does he bring it up afterwards and go,
hey man,
the way he told me to fuck off,
that guy is really cool because uh,
the um,
the guys doing it,
um,
I don't know if I'm allowed to say his
name.
What's the piece part of the jackass
crew.
So he's,
he's,
um,
literally jet,
the show jack.
So like the fact that he,
there's no fucking goat ges and shit.
I'm sure he's just happy.
Yeah,
he's excited.
There's no explosions and also don't
forget he's working.
So anytime someone says,
fuck off,
he's off the clock.
So.
Oh,
there you go.
That's right.
So he gets to relax.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
this showtime thing,
is it a,
are they doing a showtime special?
Like you're going to play music on?
Yeah.
How much music is going to.
They've Been following me around forever
and they're going to do like,
I don't know what the title be because
like I said,
this is literally the first time I've
ever mentioned on any sort of jesus.
It's a scoop.
Yeah.
You got that rogan exclusive
button.
You can press wish we had one
follow me around for years and I'm not
years,
but for a couple of years now and we've
got obviously I've been,
we've got footage from the old days,
they're going to tell my whole life
story and we'll get some songs in there
and you know,
I was just psyched to be able to
hopefully took until it my way and not
sick at all.
These fucking,
all these lies and rumors,
lies and rumors.
Yeah,
I mean,
yeah,
it was.
It was weird too because that was
another thing too about combing today,
which is komi.
He admitted,
he's like,
they kept bringing up these New York
times articles.
He's like,
no,
that's not true.
It's almost like backing up truck,
you know,
these,
these stories.
If the head of the fbi under oath saying
that these story,
he said it's got a bunch of his trees.
It's like none hAd the fbi saying that
in New York times articles completely
untrue.
I got to believe,
you know?
Yeah.
There's definitely people that are
printing things they hope are true with
limited mount of references that can
verify it.
Yeah.
It's like,
and there's also two,
there's the stories that will sell
newspapers.
It's not just that.
It's also the bias of the people that
are writing the stores who are heavily
left wing.
You're really freaking me out with that
bottle.
You keep opening and closing.
Yeah.
This is still from.
This is from the airport.
I'll be tweaking from.
Seems like you've got something going on
with that opening and closing that
bottle.
It's like I'm going to stop a fidget
thing.
I got one of them fidget spinners.
Yeah.
That's what it is.
A water bottles to get the stress
relievers.
Wheeler walker water bottles.
um,
what were we just talking about?
A stress.
You're talking about New York times know
the bias of the people who are writing
it.
They want to get at trump.
So if they have any sort of an article
that even might be true.
They kind of think might be true.
It seems like it would be exciting if it
was true.
They just run with it.
I thought that was interesting what he
said actually,
which is like because it's highly
classified information,
he's not allowed.
He's not allowed to go out there and say
it's not true because that would,
that would,
you know,
sure would put them in a weird place of
the then you know,
what top secret information isn't true,
so he has to keep quiet about it.
So,
so when he's doing these interviews,
uh,
and there,
there are a rather,
um,
when there is under investigation,
there's given these statements,
how do they,
uh,
justified then how does he say it's not
true because isn't that still top
secret?
Because this is,
you know,
he's under oath and they're asking him I
guess is the only reason.
But there are definitely some questions
where he said,
I'm not allowed to,
you know,
I can't say that in an open hearing.
Yeah,
that's what I figured was one of the
reasons why trump could fire him because
he wouldn't be able to talk about the
investigation until they hired a special
prosecutor and all this stuff that
you're seeing now.
I would assume that people will like
call comedy's going to talk.
I'm like,
well,
he can't really talk.
That'S one of the reasons why trump
could fire him because that guy is under
oath and rather all the stuff that he's
talking about,
what's he allowed to talk about now that
he's gone to st?
That same rule.
it's top secret.
Everything's top secret.
I bet he's not allowed to talk about his
job at all.
I bet they could fire up not firing
rather,
but they could arrest him if he.
Because he admitted today that he.
He did.
He admitted the leaks and stuff.
Yeah,
but he leaks stuff that was
unclassified.
He just leaked is memos.
They weren't classified and people were
freaking out about it like no,
he,
he did it because it was real simple.
He didn't want to be the one who was
making the statement and the way he
described that he had a funny
description.
He said it would be like feeding
seagulls at the beach.
They would just follow them around and
look for more.
And he was like,
I just wanted to get the information out
there.
So I had someone put it out there,
but he was honest about it and you know,
it lets you understand that that's how
these people do business and this is one
of the ways that information does get.
I think it's just.
I think a lot of it is guys like a.
Wasn't a movie all the president's men.
I think it's a lot of guys who think
that they're gonna.
If they get the scoop,
they're going to have a hit book and
then they're like,
you know,
brad pitt's going to play them in the
fucking movie.
If they get this fucking scoop.
Well there's also that.
but then there's just,
if you're an investigative journalist
and you're covering the president,
United States and this unprecedented
event where reality stars become the
fucking president and he's a liar and he
just keeps lying about shit and getting
caught lying about shit.
And there's a bunch of people that don't
care that he's a lIar.
He's like everybody loves and they just
jump on in with it and you don't expect
a higher standard of behavior from the
number one most influential person in
the free world.
You know,
he's still tweeting about like,
people that suck in people who get
terrible ratings.
CrazY shit.
I mean like,
uh,
I mean,
I'll never forget it.
I remember Watching the republican,
one of them was public in debates and
he,
he talked about how fat rosie o'donnell
was.
I was like,
can we do all the debates like this?
I fucking love this,
you know,
like a roast debate.
Like how the fuck even rosie o'donnell
is gonna be sitting there like,
why are they talking about my weight on
rosie o'donnell's decided to dedicate
most of our twitter feed to shitting on
trump.
Now she's losing her marbles.
Man.
What about kathy griffin to that scene?
That was fucking.
What did you think about that when you
saw her?
Kathy griffin holding up that fake head
of Donald Trump covered in blood.
What did you think?
Well,
maybe my all I think is how fucking,
how fucking badly do you need fucking
attention?
You know,
it was like,
I mean,
exactly.
What did you think?
best case scenario like,
right.
I think if,
if,
if that's your.
If your viewpoint,
is that what you want to presidents,
I mean just to twist it,
imagine ted nugent holding up obama's
head like it's overdue.
Well,
ted nugent did at one point in time say
he wanted obama to suck on his machine
gun.
He did say that words or less powerful
in that image.
I guess I heard a picture's worth a
thousand words.
That's what they're saying.
No,
that's what they're saying.
Oh shit.
Well,
I didn't know.
Is that.
I didn't know he's gotten that big.
Yeah.
Maybe more than a thousand.
If it's a picture of what was it for?
I don't.
I never found out.
She's just doing it to get attention.
That's what it was.
Sticking around the house and just like,
I'm going to hold up.
He had a photographer come over and the
photographer setup thing and you know,
they covered this mask with blood and
she held it up like she was isis.
I mean,
this is not,
you're not talKing about teens and that
medieval France.
That's.
I mean,
that's just a sign of a fucking idiot.
You know?
It's like,
not only if that's your viewpoinT,
you gotta be smart enough to know that
that's only going to hurt your,
your where you're coming from.
Not only that,
she did this press conference in paint
herself out to be a victim.
She's seen he's a bully and he's trying
to ruin her career.
And then she was like celebrating the
kind of comedy she does.
She was like,
you know,
I've always pusheD the boundaries and
um,
uh,
you know,
my comedy is,
it's not for everybody,
but it's,
she was like,
like relishing the moment to express how
she feels about her comedy or two to
sort of describe comedy.
And it's not a free speech thing.
I mean,
no one's saying she didn't have the
right to do it.
We're just all saying it's fucking,
it's fucking lame.
You know,
it's an attention thing.
It's all,
it's purely an attention thing to the
point where there's no,
there's no entertainment value to it.
Like it's one thing if you have some
ridiculous idea in your head that is
funny or is entertaining.
That's what I'm saying.
What was the best case scenario?
There's no,
there was nothing,
no thought.
It was just like,
let's do this.
People are gonna.
See it.
Well,
the only funny part for me was that like
mike,
who does all the photoshopping for joey
diaz,
I don't know if you know him.
He's been
helping me with some photoshop and the
second I saw that picture I go do me a
favor,
put my head on kathy griffin's head and
change trump to sam hunt and he fucking
didn't five minutes and it looks pretty
good and I put it up.
So then I loved how some of the people
thought I was like,
actually once I was like,
no,
no.
It's a comment on the fucking kathy
griffin.
I didn't hear about the kathy griffin
thing until I saw her apology.
That's how I found out about it.
I found out about it through her apology
on instagram and so I was clicking on
this video and it was her apology and
she looked like hell.
So literally she hadn't slept and she
was freaking out as opposed to when she
looked awesome as opposed to when she
looks hot as fuck.
Yeah,
that's good.
Photoshop right there,
it's perfect.
Your,
your head sits perfectly on her neck.
It's weird.
Yeah,
I pairs perfectly.
My,
my beard and her beard look exactly the
same.
I don't think she has a beard dude.
But um,
I saw the apology and just,
I was like,
what did she do?
Like she was like,
I went too far.
I went too far,
you know,
I'm sorry,
I've,
I've seen the comments.
I went too far.
I apologize.
I'm a comedian and sometimes we go too
far.
I was like,
what the fuck did she do?
And then I went and saw what she did and
I was like,
oh,
I wonder.
I'm trying to think.
Have you,
have you heard anybody even in the
comment,
if you heard anybody defending her?
Yes.
Who you have to say,
I don't remember their names,
but it was a,
it was a defense of the intent behind
it,
which I agree with.
The intent behind it,
meaning,
which she was trying to do is be funny.
She was trying to get some attention.
She was trying to.
It's like a joke that you do that fall
short,
like here's a perfect example.
Bill maher's joke.
Did you hear what he said?
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
So if people haven't heard the senator
from Nebraska was a senator.
Got damn.
That's fucking voice upon the senator
from Nebraska I believe.
Said you should come visit.
We can have you work in the fields.
And bill threw his hands up and go,
not me.
I'm a house nigger.
That's what he said.
And everybody was like,
what the fuck?
Like what makes you think you could say
that?
And when he did a hbo released a
statement,
they were pissed off and there was a
fire bill maher,
twitter hashtag thing going on.
That one,
don't you think?
To me is it is a little more least.
I understand the intent of his joke.
Yeah.
He was trying to be naughty.
He made a mistake.
Look,
pete,
here's,
here's the thing.
He's working on a show.
Okay.
He's working on a very important show
for hbo.
That is a very high profile show.
This is extreme amount of pressure,
extreme amount of demands.
There's a lot going on behind the
scenes.
He's probably working very hard.
He's probably tired and he's in the
middle of this interview and he's trying
to make something entertainment.
The guy gives him an opportunity,
right?
The guy says you could work in the
fields and he's thinking work in the
fields for him to work with.
I know who works in the fields,
slaves working the fields.
Who's the guy that's in the house?
I'm going to say this,
and he just goes with it to try to be
shocking because he's,
you know,
he tries to be that naughty,
edgy guy and it just was.
It was lame and it wasn't funny.
Yeah.
I get more pissed when I watched.
When I see his shows,
it seems like he's.
When he makes a joke and they don't,
he gets mad when they don't want to
fucking left.
That's the part that bothers.
He's a silly boy.
But when,
when he,
when he made a joke and it was lame,
he was just trying to be funny.
Like he was trying to entertain people.
It's important to him.
His show's important to him.
It's a very good show.
He works hard at it and most of the
jokes are really funny and there's a lot
of edgy,
controversial jokes on the bill maher
show that are really funny and he.
That's the line he pushes in.
Sometimes you cross that line and he
crossed that line.
Is he racist?
Fuck no.
Is he a bad guy?
No,
no.
He was a fucking mistake.
He's a human being.
It wasn't like the n word slipped out
talking derogatory about,
you know,
he was trying to exact point about
slavery.
It was just trying to be silly.
He was trying to be funny.
He was like,
he's not like being.
Remember when dog,
the bounty hunter got caught dropping a
bunch of bombs about people.
There's,
there's a way.
Look,
there's no words that are forbidden and
the idea that the.
That's that word exists in countless rap
songs,
but you can't sing along to those rap
songs and yet ransom,
walmart.
It's ridiculous.
I think those rap songs are banned from
walmart too though.
You and I found out recently,
which is those.
There's walmart versions of all those
jobs.
I didn't know that.
Oh,
where they take out the cuss words.
Yes.
I mean I know that I fucking ordered a,
an itunes once,
a copy of a,
one of the dead,
not dead presidents.
Who the fuck was.
It was one of those hardcore rap bands
and as I was listening to it,
it was all this backwards fit.
Yeah.
No,
like bleeped out or like it was like
empty spots where there was the,
I,
I downloaded a m and m album.
I heard all these backwards sounds.
I thought it was like,
you know,
the old sergeant pepper shit.
I guess they took it out the bad words
and just played them backyard even
worse.
I listened to one from gangstarr and
they had alternative words,
alternative words,
and I was like,
oh no,
you can't have alternate world star hip
hop guys like jay z or some big I go
fuck this way and doing this anymore.
I think they're not doing it anymore,
but the reason why they do this for
money,
there's so much money out there.
I mean,
if they can get their shit played on
radio and get the more.
It's all about exposure.
I mean,
you know,
it's all about the most amount of people
that you could reach with your stuff.
Yeah.
Well they asked me to do a clean
version.
I said no,
good for you.
But my,
my,
um,
my morals definitely cost is going to
cost me a lot of fucking can.
I don't think so.
I think in the long run it'll save you
money because it'll,
it'll elongate your career because if
someone's a fan of yours and they're at
a barbecue and someone pulls out the
lame version,
like,
oh,
you gotta hear
this guy,
he's fucking hilarious.
This guy's crazy.
And then it's like,
f you bitch,
f you b,
you broke my heart.
Screw you girl.
Or well remember when cee lo green had
that?
Forget you.
No,
no,
no.
Forget you.
It's fuck you.
And why the song again?
Why can't he say fuck you on the radio?
Doesn't mean nice.
I mean,
I know why,
but yeah,
it's like,
it's stupid because a long time ago
people were dumb and they thought that
the son was 17 miles away and they
thought there was an old man living in
the clouds,
had friends that used harps and that,
uh,
you gotta be careful with words are
clinging onto the,
I mean the same thing.
And like tv and radio,
they're like,
they're still like.
But like,
it's like there's,
there's youtube,
like,
you know,
we did it.
We,
we,
we premiered another video from this
record again.
We did the pornhub premier,
you know,
like,
fuck this,
let's reach the people fuck up.
Yeah.
You premiered on pornhub,
which is hilarious.
How did that come about?
I reached,
I,
uh,
what happened was people were just kind
of like,
you know,
like let's find a place to premier,
they always do this thing where like,
you can premiere a video on like,
I don't know,
will it be an example like a v club or
some shit,
you know,
and,
and we're rolling stone or something
like that.
Give me those numbers.
You know,
it's like so and so gets 50,000.
We're like,
well,
what about lookup pornhub's numbers?
It was like 200 something million.
I think one of the,
I think we're rolling stone with
something like the $8,000 or something.
Biggest website and I go check out what
pornhub is in porn.
I was like,
number 19 in the world,
and I go,
well I go,
I go,
let's just reach out to them and see if
they'll premiere.
It will be the first guy to premier
country music video on pornhub.
The problem is when people go to
pornhub,
they're sweaty and nervous and they're
just thinking about beating off.
Well to get in the wrong mindset.
Well I think,
I think after you beat off,
you ready to fucking chill out and
listen to some good country.
Yeah.
But you're also really ready to hide
what website you were watching on your
browser and erasing your history.
It fucking worked,
man.
I mean,
I've seen,
I saw a lot of people,
you know,
like uh,
I don't know how many people I could
tell you that came up to me like a first
heard about you because they don't want
to admit it,
you know,
but the numbers show that people
fucking,
it was crazy because we,
we premiered it on pornhub and they're
like,
it was almost like,
you know,
if you guys do this for me,
I'll show that,
you know,
it worked in a cell.
You can sell things besides fucking
boner pills,
you know?
Right.
Well,
it's also,
it's one of the things that if you did
it just knowing that you did it,
people would go there to check it out.
Like he's,
he's premier to shit on pornhub.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Go there to check it out.
And it's funny because we put it up at
like noon or something and I was like,
I thought it was like hundreds of
millions of views aren't that high and
someone there was like,
wait till 5:00 when people get off work
and stop beating off.
Yeah.
It was like 5:00.
The numbers fucking just shot through
the roof.
It's like once that fucking work,
bell rang.
It's like they were fucking.
Yeah.
People get in trouble for beating off at
work.
Right.
You can get fired.
Yeah.
It's a bummer.
I wish there was like a section.
There is no country music section of
pornhub you think there would be due to
just be the wheeler walker section down
is I,
I got to figure out how to because I set
up my own channel to um,
to printer that video and I got to
figure how to turn it off.
I get alerts on my phone every two
minutes so and so clicked like on your
pornhub video or so and so like from
like left a comment on your porno
videos.
Like I gotta get that shit off.
It's all day.
It's like I wake up until the night to
and it's just.
And it's like,
um,
you know,
trump jazz,
44 gigs.
Your,
your,
uh,
your new,
your new song.
Did you ever look at some of the
comments on,
on porn website videos when they start
rating videos and describing.
I know that's how I know what to fucking
watch.
Yeah.
Well the star system is pretty good.
When you get to the actual words,
you start feeling real uncomfortable.
What were you expecting?
Yeah,
I didn't like kosher wind.
Wind,
wind rows.
Huh?
Jesus.
Yeah.
Like sometimes you'll go on there and
you'll see the first thing.
She was like,
don't watch this one fucking finished.
He finished insider.
You can't see shit,
man.
Thanks for the heads up.
You know jesus christ.
People get mad.
They think it's fake.
It's fake calming.
Like,
wow.
That's weird.
Yeah.
The,
I believe in fake news.
I don't believe in fate come.
There's definitely fake come.
I've seen it.
Seemed fake dicks should seen one.
He always has sex with his pants on
because he's got a big fake rubber dick
and uh,
it has a button in it where he could
just.
Eddie presses the button and it comes
out.
It looks like,
um,
what's that set of?
Filled at the face lotion that people
use.
What's that?
No,
no,
no.
That's for zits set of like that face
soap.
It's kinda like.
Yeah,
I was looking.
I saw one of those two and then right
before he just,
it was like a hard cut.
Like if you'd like,
you can tell that they filled up the
fake dick machine to pump it up.
Don't book book book.
Get it to the,
to the top.
I wish I could sit here honestly sat in
jack off to that one.
Wow.
Now,
um,
do you think you're going to have more
songs that come out on pornhub or is
that a one time thing?
Um,
what about you?
Does he ever thought about going to one
of the other competitors websites?
Deal?
Some company called perth city gave me
a,
a free membership per vociti.
He had never even heard of him,
but it did look in to get through your
webcam.
That's what they're looking to do.
I think they were looking for me to
mention on your show and I just felt
like,
oh fuck,
I didn't mean to.
Sorry god it.
Um,
but they got their money's worth I
guess.
But yeah,
I think if I could do only point,
I mean,
cmt ain't gonna fucking play it.
So now they won't even play one of your
songs.
How many songs do you have?
Like with no swearing?
Zero.
I'm just rounding off there.
But would you,
uh,
you know,
what's weird too is um,
so I got one of my new tunes,
it sorts of definitely an american thing
because I just have the cmt of
Australia,
whatever it is.
My out,
my,
one of my new songs from the new record
is like in heavy rotation there and this
thing about,
you know,
a stretched out pussy and shit in it.
And they play in regular rotation.
I guess they're just Australia.
They don't give a fuck.
They don't give a fuck in Australia.
They're savages.
Those people that are descendants of
prisoners and they're just freer over
there and that they,
I didn't even send them the video.
I think they took,
took it off youtube and just put it on
fucking tv now they're,
they're pretty bad ass.
And Australia legalized prostitution.
Really?
Oh yeah.
They wanted me to come over and do some
shows and I'm like,
that's a long fucking long trip.
But you would sell out over there.
But here's the thing that weeds illegal.
They're really so backwards.
You can sing about a stretched out
posting on tv and weeds.
Illegal,
crazy legalized prostitution.
No,
we'd soon do you think because I keep
looking at,
I think weed's going to change big
Kentucky,
you know,
my home state is the place where I think
it will be the most because I know a lot
tobacco farmer friends of mine whose
families are in the tobacco farm
business,
which is like they need this.
They need that shit right now.
They would make,
they could get their business back and I
don't know why it's not legal there.
It's renewable.
It's very easy.
It doesn't reQuire much in terms of like
resources so less pervious and I seeing.
I'm seeing the tide change.
Every time you go home you see more and
more
legalized from like more and more
businessmen and shit in town,
you know?
Yeah.
Because it would Really help the
economy.
Well it's also people realize it's
stupid.
It's stupid.
Just like making whiskey,
illegals stupid.
It was dumb.
They figured that out in the 19 twenties
and the fact that here we are in 2017,
then they haven't completely embraced
it.
That's one of the things that pissed me
off about this jeff sessions guy.
Like what a giant step backwards that
asshole is coming back with wanting to
bring back.
Just say no and say these aren't good
people.
It's basically what's the.
What's that crazy movie?
It was basically idiocracy now what's
the crazy we'd movie from.
Oh yeah,
I'll reformat.
Reefer madness was.
He was like acting like that.
It's like he's just a guy who doesn't
smoke pot and probably never has and
doesn't even know what it does.
HIs idea of it is like people doing math
or sniffing glue or something.
He doesn't know what he's talking about.
Yeah.
It's fucking pisses me off too.
It's just like,
well,
it's also,
there's a lot of money involved.
I mean these guys are all whores.
You gotta,
you gotta pay attention to like who's
buttering their bread and there's a lot
of people that have very strict agenda
and if you go out there and start
talking about,
look,
that's one of the things that piss me
off about hillary clinton more than
anything.
She gAve some sort of a speech and in
that speech she said that she was
absolutely in every sense of the word
against marijuana legalization will fuck
you.
Old lady.
She also said she also said she was
against.
She wanted flag burning to be illegal.
Right.
She was also against gay marriage until
2007 or 2013.
Yeah.
They just want to forget things about
what they used to think.
When you just say the word democrat,
that you're like,
we believe in these things.
Their,
their opinions aren't real.
They're opinions.
Are there strategic sort of a
conglomeration of ideas that they think
are going to serve them?
Well when they go out In public,
that's wHat their opinion.
They forget that it's 2017 and
everything.
There's a record of fucking everything.
Yeah.
I mean,
I was getting pissed because there were
a couple of weak companies who wanted to
sponsor some of my tour,
but it's too complicated right now
because how different states,
like it could be like I could get
arrested in certain states just for just
for advertising advertising,
which is crazy.
LIke,
so I couldn't put it on a tour bus or
anything.
So there's no way to really do it right
now.
Yeah.
And you also become a target in the
states where it's very illegal where
cops have been arresting people for a
long time.
You've got them trained to arrest
people.
Then all of a sudden you tell them they
can't.
I'm like,
what?
Well,
it's legal now.
Like what?
Fuck that.
Like there's guys that still want to
arrest people out here,
out here.
I mean there's,
there's still arrested or taken place,
uh,
in,
in other states,
but it's so fucking dc for,
for instance,
Washington dc.
Marijuana is legal.
People are still getting arrested for it
and they don't.
They don't spread that around.
How?
Because I didn't even know that black
people.
It's not white people getting arrested
For it.
It's black people,
black twitter.
Yeah.
Well they,
you know,
it's a reason that they can arrest you.
They could find a reason to arrest you
and look,
there's a lot of gross shit that goes
along with law enforcement,
but one of the grossest ones of these
fucking people have requirements for how
many people they're supposed to arrest.
They have quotas are supposed to be
making or how many people they pull off,
pull over how many tickets they write.
You know,
there's been a long time.
Yeah.
You're the wrong guy.
The wrong time or you know,
the cop Just decides he's going to
arrest you for it because it's federally
illegal and you just make a call.
I know it's not good.
Yeah.
Me,
if it's fucked up that you couldn't,
you know,
I can have a tour bus with like,
bourbon on the side and go across the
country and back and that's fine.
But which yOu can advertise on the
fuckIng road.
Work and kill people.
Yeah.
My friend ron white,
he runs around a giant truck that has,
is um,
number one tequila on it.
He's got a huge bus,
huge ass tour bus,
which says number one,
tequila on the side of the bus.
Yeah,
they probably pay them good money and I
was like,
this is his company.
Okay.
Yeah.
I was fucking excited about some fucking
marijuana money.
Like let's help me out.
Get a nice bus.
Yeah.
People have asked me to partner up with
them or to get involved and I'm like an
eight at the time yet.
Yeah,
you're.
I agree you'd Be.
You'd be target number one.
It's just,
it's worth it financially,
but it's not worth in terms of like the
mental mortgage that you have to pay to
be involved with something that's
illegal.
I've always wondered about that.
Like I always wondered like,
you know,
like snoop dogg's on tour,
if you see,
see snoop dogg's bus,
why wouldn't the cut?
They do.
They do all the time.
Oh,
he's been pulled over before.
He's been arrested before.
it's weird to just be that adamant about
it.
You know what?
After Willie Nelson,
you don't have to fucking really?
No.
Here's the thing though,
like if you're,
if you're A stoner and known stoner,
all you have to do is just know somEbody
in a town like you don't have to travel
with it,
like traveling with it as stupid,
like people that get busted with weed,
like don't,
you know there's a weed where you're
going.
But yeah,
I don't think I've gotten off stage once
and there hasn't been a joint ready for
me,
for somebody that I've never even met.
Yeah,
there's always something.
But the thing is,
do you smoke that weed?
Um,
I usually do,
but I would say don't do it every
couple.
Every once in a while I'll smoke it and
then later that night I'm like,
something don't feel right.
You know,
people are going hardcore,
people are going hardcore.
Some dude was telling me about this
spray that he invented.
That's an acid spray.
It's lsd in spray form and he goes,
just as many pumps as you take off of
this spray is how deep you go into
alice's rabbit hole.
What jesus christ.
Did you see that?
There's a new documentary that's
execucare just talking to him.
His documentary out,
that's pretty good.
I don't actually.
I'm not a big grateful dead fan,
but there's a documentary out now about
them that feels like it's pretty crazy
watching them in the old fucking days.
I lacked the grateful dead dead jean.
I'm with you like I don't get it.
I watched this to try to get into it,
but it was.
The acid tests they were doing back then
were fucking crazy.
they would.
They would dose the fucking record
company dudes.
Yeah.
Well people just dose people back then,
which is one of the things I think is
we're seeing a dick move.
Well,
I think one of the things we're seeing
with his bill cosby thing,
I think people had a different opinion
about dosing people.
I think bill cosby was amongst a group
of many people that we're dosing people.
Back then,
I think it was super common thing.
I think it was super common because they
joked around about it.
You know,
bill cosby had a whole routine about
giving people spanish fly and he's joked
around about dosing people.
What the tv Show he did.
He did a routine on someone's late night
talk show.
Oh,
I saw that was Larry King too,
and it's dark and he talks about
spanish.
He talks about spanish finance and larry
king's or laughing as I would've because
I would've thought he was dicking
around.
You would've thought he waS joking
around and then when you find out,
I just think all those old dudes,
he used to go to the playboy mansion and
hook up and you know,
meet all these young ladies that were
very happy to see them.
And I think they were dosing actually
actually sixties and the second you say
that to girls when I take them out and
if the,
if I go to the bar and get a drink and
we'll come back with two drinks is like,
how do you usually do this?
Because I'm cool.
But like how do you,
how do you know?
Oh yeah.
I don't know.
You should go,
you know,
actually you shouldn't be dRiNking this,
you know?
Yeah.
I,
well I won't take a drink if I don't
know who it is and someone just hands it
to my you where that happens a lot too.
They'll put shots on the stage and then
they'll call me a pussy for not
drinking.
I didn't drink.
I don't know you,
But I know people.
I know people perSonally that had been
drugged.
I know.
I know several people that had been
drugged.
It's not uncommon at all.
Hunt for tattooed woman who drugged and
robbed too wealthy men of $200,000 worth
the cash of watches after them at
exclusive
hollywood nightclub.
Wow.
The woman twentY met two men at a
hollywood nightclub on March 5th.
She wenT with them to an apartment in
studio city,
made them drinks.
Men say they passed out,
woke up hours later,
but she had gone.
They claimed $200,000 where the watches
jewelry.
Awesome semester.
First of all,
these guys are fucking assholes.
they have $200,000 worth of cash and
watches and they're living in an
apartment at studio city.
Shut up.
YOu guys were doing.
You were pimping on a budget,
right?
I know what you're doing and you just
dragged in the wrong cat.
You fucked up.
it fucked up.
You got lucky.
You lucky you're alive.
You're lucky he didn't wake up in a
bathtub filled with ice or the big
fucking incision mark where your liver
used to be
and you're lucky that you made at that
fucking long and it happen the fucking
first week he tried to dumb asses.
You got tricked by a 20 year old.
You fucking rookies.
I am.
I want to.
It's almost like,
it's almost like you almost want to like
even me,
it's a cool,
but like you totally see where she's
coming from.
It's just like fuck these fucking dope.
Well they might've been shitheads too.
They might have been like real gross to
her and she's have been like,
I'm offended.
Paid rob These dummies 200
sound.
Like it was too tough for some about
drug and people man.
Like it's a very dark,
dark thing to do though.
Honestly.
All jOkes aside,
it's pretty fucking evil.
Yeah.
Put something in their drink and watch
it affect them.
Like a lab rat,
like,
you know,
they don't even know what you did and
the people that's happened to like,
I want to maybe not even high school or
even junior high and they still are,
still aren't over it,
you know?
Oh yeah,
for sure.
For me up for life rape.
Yeah.
You geT raped.
But I'm saying even like if you were in
ninth grade and someone dosed you and
you had like the worst fucking day of
your,
of your fucking life.
One,
here's something crazy.
My,
um,
my uncle,
uh,
in nashville was a med student,
back in the fifties and he,
um,
they came.
Professor comes Into class one day and
he goes,
uh,
so here's the assignment for today.
There's this new thing that government
says,
the alcohol lysergic acid.
We don't really know what it does.
So It go.
So here's your assignment.
We're going to split you up into groups
of two.
One of you takes this and the other one
has to do a report on how he reacts to
it once.
Want some weed.
And I'm good.
I got show night,
man.
You do your show sober.
I do my show,
I drink a little bit,
but I can't do if I get stoned.
I forgot all the lyrics.
Really.
I forget who's fucking who and who's
working who off,
you know,
it's like a specific,
it's very critical.
Yeah.
It's like I need to know that rita is
blowing this dude and I get it.
It's all the names.
You don't have to explain to me.
You've been there.
But yeah.
And they actually led to the lawsuit
about what,
how,
when you weren't allowed that you
weren't allowed to a
test drugs on students?
Oh yeah.
But he didn't know they did that to um,
the ins,
the unabomber,
the unabomber.
Ted kaczynski was a part of the harvard
ellis
experiments.
No way.
I didn't know that.
Yeah.
I'm doing what to dosing him up.
They toast the shIt out of that because
then they originally think of some kind
of truth serum.
Maybe they didn't know what it was.
So they were trying to figure out,
well I will Albert Hoffman and figured
it out.
Right.
He,
he accidentally discovered it.
I think he was coming up with a drug to
induce labor.
I think that was the original premise
behind creating lsd and he got some of
it in his hands and then on his drive
home through absorption through the
skin,
he was tripping as fucking balls off
riding his bike.
That's the whole story behind the
understanding of lsd as a psychoactive
substance and human beings.
So they started doing all sorts of
studies.
There's some videos from the,
I believe it was the british army.
They dose their their soldiers up and
they filmed them and they're running
around laughing and giggling and they
can't do anything.
It's like a black and white footage
from,
I want to say like the fifties.
Yeah.
There was a lot of that crazy footage in
that because I don't think,
I mean it's hard to say because it's
obviously influenced a lot of great
fucking music,
but also they were like,
they were so taken so much acid.
There was a part in the movie where the
drummer for the grateful dead was
telling the record company guy.
He goes,
I alwaYs love these kind of drugged out
hippie stories.
This guy goes,
he goes,
we want to take a microphone and we want
to record the small,
you know,
like we wouldn't go out to the desert
where there's clean air and record clean
air and put the two sounds together.
That's our,
that'll be a rhythm track that's a lot
of acid and to take.
And they wanted that to be the drum
track and some guy at warner brothers
records into suits.
Like,
what the fuck are you talking dead jean?
I don't have that gene.
I feel like if you could play the dead
to like a young fan of rap music that
like never,
never heard the dead like a young black
dude just like sit him down like,
tell me what you think about this.
They'd be like,
what the fuck is this?
That's how I feel.
Yeah,
just don't get it.
It just sounds to me like,
again,
like a bunch of drugged out hippies just
noodling around when you're on acid at
the show.
it's amazing.
I've heard people say that I was never a
fan of the grateful dead until I saw
them when,
um,
when I was on acid,
I'm more than willing to agree to that
because there's some songs that I've
heard when I was tripping that like you
go,
oh,
now I understand.
I remember the first time I got stone
her and black sabbath and I remember
saying to my friend like,
other people who listen to this without
being stoned,
like,
what does it sound like if you're like,
what's the point?
What's the point of fucking black
sabbath?
if you're not stone,
it doesn't even make sense to me,
but you have a black sabbatH to me.
I can still listen to even not stolen.
They've got some bright jams.
I just,
there's something about the sort of
hippie nature of the grateful dead
people too.
I was always like,
well,
you just running away from life.
Go get a job.
You stinky fucks fucking dirty here.
But then my own cousin became a dead
head for awhile.
She's cool.
She traveled with the dead for years and
she was like,
one of those people that lived out of
the back of a vw band,
they would,
they would go to a store and buy bacon
and
eggs and cook them up for the people
that were in the,
in the concert,
and then they would sell them and shit.
And that's how they got by that sell
bracelets and shit.
Like she lived like that for man.
I want to say it was more than a year
she traveled around with the dead.
Yeah.
I mean it was kind of because they,
they,
they had a big kind of country
influenced what they did according to
the documentary.
I'm like,
well,
I don't fucking hear it.
You know,
it's like,
I love the idea that they were making
kind of trippy kind of country,
but it's like,
that's not what I'm hearing in my ear.
Yeah,
I get it.
I get it if you're into that music,
but I feel like that's like food,
you know,
there's certain people that I just know,
like my friend tom,
I have a friend,
not to girl tommy.
Hey tommy,
shout out child to tommy.
He's a buddy of mine that I've always
been a fan of spicy food.
I can eat some fucking spicy food.
I go deep,
but not nearly as deep as this
motherfucker.
There's some dudes that I think that
they,
their taste buds are just wired
different.
They can just take in a different level
of spice than I can.
Like I,
it must be affecting their body
differently and I know for me like I
have friends that don't like anything
spicy.
I don't always say shit just doesn't get
to them.
To me,
I love it man.
I eat jalapenos pretty much every day of
the week.
I'm always,
I put hot sauce on everything.
I'm putting a habanero sauce on
everything,
but some people it just doesn't
work with only thing I can say.
I tried these shots of like super.
It was like there's some little shot you
can take.
I thought it was coming down with
something on the road once and they gave
me this super is something like filled
with vitamins and had some kind of
pepper.
It was supposed to help me.
Oh,
okay.
Tie in and it hurt.
It hurt,
but it fucking helps.
That definitely helps.
Yeah.
I wonder what the real sciences behind
cayenne pepper,
but they always like to add it to those
wellness shots to make you feel like
it's doing something.
It gives you a little woo.
It opens up.
You're not studying the way they market
it.
Yeah,
I mean you feel great right after you
get the shot done because you're just.
You're just kind of like,
can't believe you got it down.
There was this place that we went to.
The doesn't exist anymore.
There was an encino is called chili my
soul and it was a chilly place that had
levels of chili like from mild all the
way up to like.
I think I forget what their system was.
It was the x system or a number system.
I think it was a number system and I
think the top was like 10 and one day I
tried an eight and they would give you a
sample and it was like the size of
those.
You know those little paper cups that
you get like at a hamburger joint.
These are supposed to fill up a catch up
like it was that small,
a tiny little thimble full of.
I was like,
this is so little.
Just try it,
just try for a sample and I put that
fucking tiny spoon in like an ice cream
spoon,
like a sample spoon.
I put it on my tongue and I just started
sneezing and hiccuping out of control.
Snot was pouring down my nose.
I couldn't believe how fucking hot it
was.
And that was just an eight.
I remember thinking I had one of those.
No,
not probably not that hard.
I remember thinking like I'm never going
to recover like my mouth was burning and
I remember sitting on the toilet just
like,
I was like,
I was like apologizing to my asshole for
what I'd done to it.
It's like,
you know,
it was like,
it was just a [inaudible] attack,
man.
That's why I worried about,
especially on the road,
like,
you know,
I could see how like,
like a big bank and go eat the wrong
thing,
get up there and fucking shit your
pants.
Oh,
for sure.
There's also something about really
spicy food that makes your shit just
want to get out of your body
immediately.
Oh no.
Yeah,
it was.
It was like if,
if someone had been in that stall at
that restaurant that in this particular
case I'm talking about,
it would have.
I would've fucking toward through my
fucking shit.
I was going to shit,
no matter what.
That's that shit in the sink or the
garbage can.
Which way would you go?
Honestly,
I think at that point I would have just
probably those shit.
Your pants.
No,
I would have taken.
I didn't.
I probably wouldn't want to ruin,
ruin my pants.
I probably would have just pulled them
down.
Just shit like on the fucking bathroom
floor.
I'll bet you think it's hard to.
It's hard to know.
I mean,
what's the move though was if you want
to be like,
I bet there'd be a lot of arguments.
I probably would have gone to the
urinal.
Really?
Shit in the urinal.
That's rough.
Well,
if a guys got to clean that,
yeah,
we'll do offer to clean it.
Fuck no,
but I wouldn't.
I wouldn't.
I don't think I would have,
um,
you know,
we wouldn't have been too nice to do it
on the fucking floor.
Yeah.
That's one of the rare things about
going to a public place,
like a restaurant or something like
that.
You're not,
you shit all over the place.
You don't go,
hey man,
you've got to clean that.
And you're like,
no,
I don't.
It's funny.
Before I ever hit the road,
I was talking to some other weird.
Yeah,
some,
some other musicians.
They were just like,
the main thing about the road is,
and you may be,
you know,
is like finding a good place to.
It's all about finding good places and
I'm like,
I put my heart and soul into these
records.
Like it's just gotta be more to it than
that,
you know,
what support people they've already
given up,
but they've just given up on their
dreams.
Play drums on the road.
Yeah,
exactly what they're just talking about,
how like,
you know,
taking will.
If you're in this town,
there's this one restaurant that
doesn't,
that doesn't check you make sure you're
eating.
They're like,
there's like a,
you know,
they give me the fucking toilet tour of
America.
I'm like,
you know,
if that's my biggest problem,
it'll be fine.
There's something about shitting and a
past the bathroom at a gas station
that's actually kind of satisfying.
It's like,
yeah,
it's disgusting,
but you're not going to ruin it.
You took a terrible dumping.
That bathroom.
We just liked this one.
I'm here for.
Or a park when you go to a park and they
have those stainless steel toilets that
don't even have a lid and you just sit
down on it.
You gotta wipe all the piss off at first
before you sit down.
Yeah.
Those risks,
those rest stop bathrooms are pretty
nice.
Some of those up myself.
Yeah,
you can mess them up.
It's a weird thing that that's where
dudes chose to go to get together when
they were gay and in hiding like
throughout the fifties in the sixties
and seventies.
That was like the thing,
you know,
they'd go to get rest stops.
That was like a who's a hacky joke in
the early days of standup comedy and
I've got a new song.
Yeah guys meeting.
I should sell my album that wrist and
you'd probably sell some for sure.
Truckers are one of the few people that
definitely still have cd players.
Oh yeah.
They probably have vhs still.
I've got a lot.
I definitely have a lot of truck or
faint,
you know jeff,
like meet people after the show was
like,
you know,
I drove fucking 36 hours or whatever,
can we do to shout out to the truckers?
Yeah.
There's a lot of people out there just.
I mean,
you're stuck in a truck for fucking 12
hours.
You need some god damn content.
Totally.
I mean,
I don't know how you do without like.
I think some of those guys don't know
technology that well,
but without having access to podcasts or
fucking spotify that shit.
Well,
how would you feel?
You'd be amazed.
I think truck drivers are more in tune
with that kind of technology,
like entertainment technology that they
can't take in while they're driving than
anybody.
What does that jamie still luxury
sleeper cab for a long haul truck.
Oh wow.
It's a god damn apartment.
That's what I see.
That's what I need to get that big.
That's like a camper.
Holy shit.
Well that's cool for him man.
So he just goes back there when he's
done.
Oh,
there's the thing.
He goes,
everybody's got a coffee machine there
and shit.
I can live in there.
Yeah.
One of my buddy's got one of those with
a shower in it too.
You ain't got a magazine thing,
but you know,
still the rule.
You can't shit in it no matter what.
You're not supposed to shit in those
things,
however.
Nice it is.
Well,
people do it though.
They wreck those things.
Yeah.
There's um,
there's,
I mean it's still,
it's a sucky job for those poor
bastards.
And they get off.
They all get fucked up backs.
You're sitting in a chair all day.
They need to get these ergonomic chairs
for driving a car.
That's what they need.
Right?
And hemorrhoids.
Hey ergo depot,
I got fucking task for you.
How about you guys figured out
replacement car seats?
Does that make sense?
Yeah,
it does.
You could sit in this,
this and driving cars that keep you
straight up.
There's tons of like cushions and weird
shit you can buy for them.
Yeah,
there are.
They say the lumbar things,
the big one because it makes you,
it forces your body to say straight
instead of that like hump thing.
He was going to say there's probably
uncomfortable shit that's probably good
for you.
That makes your back.
Yeah.
Well you're supposed to sit like this.
It's supposed to sit straight up.
That's why they say like those balance
balls are really good.
Like sitting on balance.
Paul's are good because you kind of have
to sit up straight.
Yeah.
A lot of guitars have a lot of back
problems because you know,
you put it on it and it's.
And it's not really that heavy,
but just a little bit of weight every
night of your fucking life,
you know,
after 30 years we'll start to get to you
a little bit.
That makes sense.
I feel that same place.
I feel like people that wear backpacks
probably the same thing.
Right?
It's pulling on you to slowly but surely
a women with purses.
They say women with big tits.
You wouldn't think that tits would fuck
your backup.
Oh yeah.
It happens a lot.
I know people who have had a breast
reductions because it's helped their
bed.
I new girl had one in.
That's another thing too.
Like when you're a funeral,
what's that sort of funeral for her old
tits.
Did you know,
because I was definitely bummed.
But um,
but for her she's like,
probably like,
god damn it.
It was,
it was,
it was always.
She was always like a pain in the ass.
Like I get these fucking giant things.
Giant jugs.
Yeah.
It's probably annoying as hell.
I got it.
Imagine if your dick was so heavy.
Dark curtain.
What do you mean?
Imagine?
I mean imagine your dick that have no
fucking way.
No,
I was good.
Try it.
Like the surgical thing.
I was like the whole what?
I'm going to try to start a rumor here
that my dick's too heavy.
I and I got to.
We rolled around in the wheelchair to my
shows that,
well,
who's the guy that they sent out the
giant hog dolton.
Burl would say,
milton berle just whip his hog out just
to settle everybody the fuck down,
talking to a bunch of shit.
And milton milton berle,
go,
listen,
let me show you something here.
Shut the fuck up.
Just.
Yeah,
it's got the biggest fucking pulled his
hog out.
Like how big?
How big we you mean?
What are we talking?
Ten inch limp.
Jesus christ,
monster hog fat.
Can you even get erect if your 10 inch?
Yes,
he could know them.
Could you just guess like elephant?
Yeah.
Milton berle on the rumors of his
endowment.
Let's hear this
dawn by word of mouth.
You never know how much truth there is
to any of them.
So just once
say becoming for the record.
Is it true?
Are you talking about my endowment
endowment's?
Is it true?
All I can say is that I'm still working
on it.
What does that mean?
No,
that's been thrown at me so many times.
That Question.
I don't know what's so thrilling about.
Is it true?
I really doN't know,
you know,
I'm not the only man in the world.
There are better men than me.
Of course you would have to show them to
me.
Now.
I've had a little success with it
even recently at ada,
so it seems quite true
online.
Know
that when I get an erection
I black out.
I,
I really do hope that he was getting
laid at 88.
They say that I had a friend and I'm one
of her friends worked at a nursing home
and she was saying that they just fuck
like cats and dogs in that place.
I believe dudes get ahold of viagra and
they don't give a fuck and there it's
like a dormitory.
So like they don't have any
responsibilities because look changed
their whole fucking.
Oh yeah,
it changed the game.
But here's the thing,
when you think about people in nursing
homes,
right?
Essentially,
no one can take in,
right?
You have to be in a nursing home because
your family can handle you anymore or
it's just you need assistance.
So as soon as you start getting
assistance,
right,
you get assisted living.
It's not good.
But it's also you have less
responsibility,
less things to think about,
less things to Worry about.
You're in this assisted living place and
you're with a bunch of other checks that
are just like you
in the same boat and like come on girls
and it's not like you get to a certain
age,
you just get tired of dick.
Right.
TheY probably still want some dick and
they probably remember when only 30
years ago when they were young and hot
and the guys can kind of remember it
too.
And they're like,
let's just do this.
What else are they going to do?
Play bingo.
But also the other nephews come by with
fucking love chocolates and you much
rather have a dick.
Then probablY someone's coming by trying
to change the will.
Get on the science of shit's probably
gross.
Imagine talking to your relatives,
you know,
they're trying to weasel you out of
money.
We'll just wait.
Yeah.
We got an aunt like that nashville right
now where it just feels like everyone's
stopping by just to hope to get into,
you know,
can I have your fucking apartment when
you're going,
dude,
it happens.
I know a familY where the son tried to
get the mom to change the will and the
other son found out about it and they
start suing each other and fucking
christ over your mom's money like really
fits.
But it's real common.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
Everybody thinks they're right.
You know,
so I helped her.
I have the right to this and everybody
gets real weird.
But mick said that
I always liked it when they had those
wills where the gut,
you know,
if it was really rich guys and they'll
be like a mystery,
like 5 million to some girl who they
never knew.
You know?
There's some secretAry who used to work
for like 20 years ago that he stuck it
in there.
Yeah.
He's thrown decatur for years.
Nobody knew.
That would be the best relationship.
Feel like a secretary to keep her mouth
shut.
You guys just both smashed it and you
can say,
I'll leave you something in the will.
You ain't got to pair then.
Yeah.
Was that what it is?
Pain or maybe she liked the deck as a
gift.
Yeah.
Saying like it'd be a nice thing that
I'm going to start telling women that
leaves them.
Somebody in the will you get my last
album broke even you can have half,
but with your reckless lifestyle,
don't you think that they would be
worried that you would die penniless
because you're so impulsive and law
gonna be penniless soon if these,
if these things don't turn around.
But Yeah.
DId you record really just break even as
many as you sold?
Yeah.
Well I say that as a joke but not really
a joke because what I did was I took all
the money and put it into the new
record.
Right.
So in a weird way I've seen no money
from it,
but I have the touring money though,
but I have but I have,
you know,
like I'm putting everything I have into
the new band,
into the new.
Do you mind saying how many albums you
sold?
I forget what it was.
I mean it's.
It was a crazy number for physical.
It was like over 50,000 physical copies,
which is,
which seems rare,
which to me it didn't seem like very
much,
but someone brought me in a cd just a
few days ago and I was like,
look at this thing.
Who was it?
Oh,
it's everlast.
He brought me in war porn,
but you could see.
Here's another thing.
Can you read that?
You think you could read that bottom?
The white part
was that say
infestation.
Yeah,
exactly.
What is war porn?
Yeah,
man,
you got to fix the font.
This shit.
Yeah,
that's what I've
been saying it.
He was like,
no,
it's art.
It's art.
And I was like,
okay,
well art that people aren't getting
what?
It's an here with me.
I've been having a lot of issues too.
I'm fucking pissed at spotify right now.
What are they doing?
Here's my issue with spotify is,
which is,
I don't know if you guys use spotify,
but almost everybody does and people
don't know this.
I'm going to get the truth out,
which is those big giAnt numbers you see
on the thing that people do.
People not like me and you,
but there's these playlists that are
fucking huge,
like some people just go on spotify to
listen to like country hits,
you know,
or country wild country.
I don't know why the fuck they refused
to fucking playlist me.
So everyone else's has these inflated
numbers.
But when I did your.
Did your show the first time eating
pussy kicking ass became the number one.
I don't know if you knew that.
I probably sent to send you that info
became the.
Had the viral charts of what's going.
The actual with the actual listens,
the viral charts.
eatin pussy kicking ass was the number
one most viral song in the on the
planet.
After I did your show,
I said,
well now can you put me on some of your
like country play?
Listen shit.
And the guy who's the guy who runs the
country playlist,
it's expect to the meet the new boss.
Same as the old boss shit.
There's a guy from country,
the guy they hired a guy from,
from terrestrial country radio who,
who designed those playlists and he
won't put me on the fucking playlist
because I say fucking dirty words.
Uh,
so I'm losing tons of listeners and I
can't
get on the,
you know,
like when you see Florida Georgia line
with 100 million listens.
A lot of those are just from automatic
listens just from those fucking playlist
and people don't know that shit.
We had an offer to do one of those was a
spotify or the other one.
Pandora or spotify.
Yeah.
They do podcasts and,
but,
but I was like,
well what do you,
what you guys have an app?
Do you guys have money?
Like what's going on with this?
Like what is this?
You guys are just distributing content
so you must be making some money.
I didn'T want to pay you,
but it's very,
very,
very little.
It's just doesn't make any sense that
you would actually.
I actually make when they,
when it gets played,
actually make decent money from the
combine because I didn't want to say how
much online but I would,
but um,
because I own my own label,
most of those artists have to,
the label takes all their spotify money.
what's confusing to me is like what's
the benefit other than like being
introduced to stuff that you never would
have heard of before.
Like the benefit of spotify is the same
benefit you would get from radio except,
but streaming,
except it's in real time,
right?
Yeah.
Me then better to.
The benefit to me is to listen to what.
Oh,
I'm on the road.
I haven't listened to this zeplin
element a long time.
Then you have it,
but so like you can make a spotify
playlist and people can listen to your
playlist.
Is that the,
is that the case?
Correct.
You could make one and everyone could
listen to like the updated one you
share.
Diplo is a popular producer and he has
an updated hip hop list.
He makes.
He updates it every few days,
but there's no official spotify one
that's separate from las.
Bought a fire official playlist.
It's just when you searched for him and
follow an influencer you like.
So I started a
playlist.
I could put your song on my playlist
and then it would be on.
Yeah.
But the people for some reason they go
in,
they own the interface so they make it.
So there were offIcial ones are the big
ones on the page.
So you just went over here.
The country hits like this.
This album's going to be in the top 10.
They won't fucking play it.
So I'm in,
I'm not saying I'm banned but you know,
if they ain't gonna put me on the
playlist and I'm,
I'm at a disadvantage.
Like who the fuck cares about?
I mean is it that big a deal?
Say hey you.
So they do pay you when it goes on.
You actually make like get check when,
when,
when my,
when people listen,
I get,
I get paid.
Yeah.
See this?
Um,
I don't,
I just don't think when I.
There's a band of like a year,
you can't do this now,
but they gameD the system and they made
it an album that was silence and told
their fans to stream at all night long
and so they made a bunch of money just
off of the streams being played of
silence for like eight hours a day.
How could you do that?
But there was no way.
They didn't have any writing to stop
someone from doing that,
from uploaded.
They stop it now.
You Can't do that now.
Yeah,
that's the limit.
There is someone up.
I saw the other day,
you couldn't someone up like eight hours
of rain so.
Well that's someone's going to get paid
for that.
That rain track someone owns.
Is that recording here?
You got to make sure that you didn't
steal it from youtube or something.
Also someone had to actually be up for
eight hours recording.
You deserve a little bit of money and
there's a lot of people you got to do
that until their fans,
you know,
listen to this song.
I just put it on repeat or with that
seems ridiculous.
That's a silly request and you,
you,
it's,
it's unfair.
You like,
like,
hey,
make me some money.
They used to do back in the day,
call your radio station and request my
song on the radio.
It makes you different though.
Oh,
and requesting a song and you want to
hear it.
That's saying you want to hear it saying
stream my rain 24 hours a day.
But yeah,
these playlists,
you know,
it's almost,
it's payola again.
It's like there's one guy who's
controlling basically all the radio.
Yeah.
It's like this one dude is just doing
it.
Just like if you're his buddy,
you know what?
Any of those things.
It's like whether it's pandora or
whether it's spotify or what you're
doing is you're selling or distributing
other people's work.
So you're basically just a distribution
center.
I mean that's all it is.
Other than like the unique features of
the distribution.
Oh,
but you can make playlists or oh,
you can do this and people can recommend
things to,
oh,
there's algorithms and if they could
find out what you like and then you go
seek out those things.
But at the end of the day,
if there's no things to seek out,
you don't really sell anything like the
youtube people suing them.
Like youtube isn't anything right?
It's just a player.
But youtube has bandwidth and that
bandwidth is extremely expensive.
It's a different animal because you're
talking about they,
they're not just streaming something,
they're streaming video.
Video is,
you know,
god,
what would kind of fucking.
And they have to be able to store it
when they upload it.
I mean,
what kind of storage?
Fucking youtube
and where is it all fucking stored?
Your mom's house.
Fucking my upper,
upper fucking cunt.
Is it different than like a museum,
like a,
maybe like youtube where our museum is a
building and they store a bunch of stuff
that people come to look at and they
have to make some sort of money to keep
it running and to keep people there.
I Tried to make this argument the other
day.
I was talking to someone about it.
Is it the same or is it completely
different?
Um,
this is an argument that it's in the
ballpark.
Well,
the argument with like when youtube
originally sold for like billions right
at the time,
it was mainly just clips of other
people's shows back in the old.
Now they have original content.
Now they have people that they pay
people to that.
But back when it was sold,
people make people made.
There were dudes who made hundreds of
millions of dollars basically stealing,
selling off,
you know,
clips of fucking was content.
Other music videos.
Yeah.
That is an issue or was a giant issue
with youtube,
but they seem to have ironed out a lot
of that.
Like if we put up someone's content,
like if someone has an like.
It happens a lot with me with animal
attack videos.
Like anytime in animals attacking
another animal or some nature of video.
If you try to put that up on youtube,
you will get flagged and pulled off and
illegally.
Remember last time we got pulled
because for putting on my song and I was
like,
I told the,
the distributor like I give you
permission.
You it kept getting
tagged or something,
right?
Yeah.
When we had everlast on when we're
planning is war porn songs,
we had to make sure that we have
permission to release the flags and all
these things for us before we ever did
it.
We had to like coordinate.
Well not my.
I get flagged uploading my own fucking
videos,
which is really.
I just,
they say.
Do you own this?
I own it.
You own all your style?
Yeah.
I own your videos.
Everything.
I owned my master's.
Yeah.
Even eating pussy and kicking ass.
The one that was on comedy central.
I own the song.
I don't own that video.
Okay.
So within that video gets uploaded
though.
Like I say,
if you took that video and uploaded it
onto your channel,
would they flag it with comedy central?
Flag it
maybe,
but they,
they would,
they would that one.
Other than that,
they would.
That one,
they would have a right to I think,
but everything else like you know,
like,
like when the guys we fucked podcast
people call,
they wanted to play a song from the new
record on my,
on the podcast I was like,
this is like an intro music.
I'm like,
I give you permission,
I own it.
Even if they come at you,
there's no suit lawsuit [inaudible],
so you don't have something like that
where someone's looking for people that
are uploading your stuff to youtube or
things along those lines.
Like I was talking about those like,
like I,
I have had like youtube gamers who like
want to like up.
Can we cap load your video to my
channel?
I'll always be like,
yeah,
sure.
Right.
But that's the one I'm talking about.
I'm talking about like somebody just
creates a channel,
just starts uploading your content,
which happens all the time.
Oh yeah.
I've seen it around a lot,
but you know,
um,
but you don't have anybody that flags
out for you?
I think it's a good question.
I think that there's a,
there's a um,
algorithm on youtube that catches it
that because,
you know,
my,
my d distribution goes through this
distribution company.
Right.
And I think they have someone on their
team who does like to fly,
you know,
like,
I don't know how they know it,
but there's definitely,
there's some kind of algorithm,
you know,
like you said when you put it in it,
here's that everlast songs,
you know,
and I think there's someone that does
flag it for me.
But again,
I don't know.
I think we're finding out too,
I don't know where the fuck my money's
going.
You should do some sort of an online
video series like where you're giving
people access to you getting on the tour
bus,
traveling and going different places
because you know,
you're doing this podcast now.
I Think that would add,
that would sort of compliment that.
Well that'd be good too.
We'll hopefully the,
you know,
the,
the thing rick was shooting that'll,
if that's around enough will show enough
behind this,
you know,
that be a,
a bigger,
a version of something like that.
Yeah,
they'll definitely.
And yeah,
if you start doing it from showtime and
then take it to youtube or wherever and
start streaming it on the road,
I think that's a great idea for you.
Yeah,
it's been cool though.
It's weird too because you get back into
the whole like,
you know,
that,
giving.
I'm giving my music,
you know,
the,
the tv thing is going to be for myself.
So how much do I sell myself?
The music,
you know,
it's like,
do I do I do,
I try to rip them off on the fucking
price of the music?
No,
because I want the thing to,
it's easy.
It's very weird areas where people are
like,
try to talk you out of just like,
oh,
just give me the fucking music.
You know,
like if you do a standup special,
I'm sure there's,
they've had negotiations.
I'm not speaking for you,
but there's probably times where there's
like,
listen,
this suspicious is going to help you,
so take fucking less money here.
Don't do that.
It's like,
it's almost like they're doing you a
favor,
kind of a general.
They can do stuff like that.
They can say,
you know,
if they're right,
they're right.
If they're not,
they're not,
you know,
I mean if you're chris rock,
they're not right.
They have to pay chris rock like it's
good for them more than it's good for
him.
Well,
I'm saying like if you ever had any
issues with like I'm telling.
Well guess what,
your last couple of in netflix,
right?
My last one was netflix.
My one before that was comedy central
and like you want them to like market it
more of your head issues and they're
just let you know.
No,
unfortunately no.
Comedy central was great.
That was going to say the other thing
too is you've got a bigger marketing
outlet than any of them,
so now I do.
Yeah.
And netflix doesn't really market.
They put up a few billboards and just
leave it alone.
They like let people word of mouth,
but that's the thing,
like if someone puts out a comedy,
special
fears comedy special coming out July
18th,
he was just on here,
right?
Yeah.
Was yesterday.
If he puts something out,
comedy fans are just going to get the
word out.
Word of mouth.
You've got to go check it out.
You got to listen to it.
I mean,
I found out about a lot of people
specials because the main
thing with my records,
which was it,
it was a lot of which I really loved,
was that it was,
it was old school.
It was literally word of mouth.
It wasn't like.
I mean there wasn't means until it
wasn't.
Memes are fucking youtube ads and all
that shit.
It was just,
you got to hear this shit.
It was found out about it.
I found out about it from people send
them,
sending it to me.
You already knew you were doing
something,
but then people just started.
Just started sending me shit just
randomly.
That didn't even know I knew you.
Well I th,
I think that it was.
Yeah.
I think what happened is just,
you know,
it's like
they'd never heard country music used
with this.
It's like,
dude,
you gotta hear this motherfucker.
He's talking,
you know,
like,
like hip hop guys and fucking country
and it's fucking crazy,
you know,
and they get up.
You gotta make nowadays.
You just got to be so loud,
I guess is maybe what it is.
It's hard to believe that you were the
first guy that figured out sort of the
andrew dice clay approach to send no
comedy.
You know,
I say comedy,
I'm sorry to country music comedy,
sort of shock comedy.
Like,
yeah,
I was just like I say when people tell
me that I'm just like,
all I did was not censor myself and have
fun and I,
we the new album,
I think you can hear us having even more
fun than the last one.
The last One I felt it feels a little
stiff almost like I was trying to figure
out this one.
You can hear us having a fucking blast.
It was like,
because country musIc is so serious and
the people are so serious,
it's just like,
you know,
just fucking let loose and have some
fucking fun.
Yeah.
It's kind of be so bizarre to see a room
full of guys singing along to some of
your lines.
Then I sucked his dick and I kicked his
ass.
Suck day.
Yeah.
well that new song called puss in boots
and one of the line is a
line about,
you know,
she,
her tongue,
her tongue knows where my butthole is
that is in the chorus,
you know.
Um,
and I'm seeing watching people screamed
that out.
You know,
it's like I was dicking around man,
you know,
like don't do that,
I want a girl on a cowboy hat or tongue
knows.
And my butthole is that,
um,
that's a weird thing to hear back at you
just as well.
It's weird when you were thinking like,
should I even put this in the song was
we were just like,
this is a crazy thought.
What if I just go with it instead of
trying to hold myself back,
which is all the best shit,
you know.
But obviously the impact has been
tremendous.
I mean the results are amazing.
I mean,
just the idea that we're playing the
troubadour tonight and it's sold out a
month ago.
It was fucking crazy.
Yeah.
You're selling out way in advance and
that's a big place.
Well,
the troubadours like a famous,
you know?
Yeah.
You know,
a lot of horrible fucking music that's
got their start there,
you know,
and Just to,
for,
for me to go up there and singing about
puss in boots,
you know,
it was like to conquest.
Yeah.
Like concord.
Fuck you.
I'll do it.
I'll put it to the flag.
I'll put up.
I'll do this shit the way I fucking want
to do it.
Fuck you guys.
Well it's another era.
It's or another,
a rather a representation of our era
that this world is not what it used to
be.
We're in a different place.
Totally.
Well that's why I kept bringing it back
to this,
which is just like you can make whatever
you fucking want.
You have to censor yourself.
Find the people who,
you know,
find the rogan's,
whoever in your world that you know,
get the,
can get the word out bigger.
You know,
there's ways to make it wasted,
to distribute it in ways to promote it
without fucking suck in some networks.
Dick,
you know.
And on that note,
ladies and gentlemen,
this shit's available right now.
Go get you some
all wheeler wheeler walker tour.
The tour is available.
You can check it out on instagram.
He's got a full picture of all the tour.
Seven 12 starts out in atlanta,
Georgia.
Woo.
Charlotte,
North Carolina,
Virginia Beach.
He's traveling wheeler walker jr.
Ladies and gents,
thanks as always,
guys.
Love it here.
My pledge brother.
Always good talking to you.
We'll be back in just a few moments with
Megan Phelps from the westboro baptist
church.
Wow.
Wheeler walker jr.
Ladies and gentlemen.