Three
why Cheeto Santee.
Know why that,
I'll tell you.
When I first moved to Los Angeles,
um,
I was playing this basketball league
with these kids from east La.
There was like the only connection I had
in la with,
he's like a couple of kids that I knew
from Long Beach and uh,
we would go play ball on this league and
then afterwards we'd go to a bar and
just get shit faced,
like just blacked out out of our mind.
22,
like every dime we had was going to
booze and partying.
So we were partying and I'm wearing
basketball shorts like white people do
when you play basketball.
And all my Mexican friends,
you know,
they were like,
whatever they had on the floor that
morning,
it was like jeans and you know what?
There was no never basketball shoes for
them.
And we're sitting there drinking and
this Dude Paavo his buddy of mine,
he looks down at my legs and he goes,
dog,
I got to fucking seo question player
like,
did you have fucking orange leg hairs
dog?
I was like,
Dude,
I've known you for years.
You've never seen that.
He's like,
no,
dog is so gross dog.
He's nasty to look at row.
It's kind of like if you ate a bag of
cheetos and you'll wipe the finger dust
all over your fucking legs.
And she got cheeto legs.
So the she don't think so.
Then all these dudes,
all these fucking,
all these homies were always like Chito.
It was just,
it just stuck so hard that when I got
twitter and Instagram,
I was like,
I have to have Cido as my shit.
Like I have to embrace the chain.
Crazy.
They embrace the cheeto man.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's a good time for orange haired
Comedians to the greatest of all time
have orange hair.
It's,
it's wild because,
uh,
I've always been such a massive fan of
bur.
I mean,
I can't preach them enough.
I think I,
I think I do it.
I did ride them so hard.
I think many people I talk to her like,
all right,
do it enough.
Like I get it.
You like him.
But I do,
man.
I,
I've always loved him and Louise changed
the game in a totally different way.
Um,
they're both those two days of all time.
Shocking bur right
now is he's doing something real special
and he's also a man's man and
unapologetic man who,
thank God there's so few.
Yeah.
It's such a hard time to be
guy.
Yeah.
You're not allowed to.
And shame on you say that.
If you say that people like booth and
Ooh,
it's so hard to be a man with all your
male privilege.
Oh,
cisgendered males complaining.
But how hard it is,
I was being judged folks from all judged
harshly white,
straight male and the literal enemy,
public enemy number one.
Right now I walk around,
you are the enemy.
You're automatically a rapist and a
massage therapist and an ego.
Maniacal money,
hungry,
driven,
bad human being.
It's so fucked up.
This is how ridiculous it's gotten.
There was an article,
oh,
they're still complaining about being a
man.
He was an article that I just read that
was advocating that women should never
go to prison.
It was like,
let's stop putting women in prison.
Yeah.
See if he could find that would fund.
It was,
the idea was that women are suppressed
and they already represents such a
significantly small portion of the u s
population that really needs no for
heinous crimes,
don't then they don't deserve
the same punishment as other people that
have heinous crimes.
The number of women hit men would just
go through the fucking roof.
Right?
My God,
if they couldn't be arrested.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
So much.
So much domestic.
Well that's like saying,
okay,
so if you're saying,
if that's what that,
if that's the article is trying to say
then then say any other repress group in
society,
then then minorities can't go to prison
anymore.
That's the same logic day represent a
much larger percentage though.
So the thing there she saying about
women is there so few women in prison
already and women are like a lot of
their behaviors due to the fact they've
been suppressed by men.
Okay,
sure.
Oh my gosh.
Well it's just the idea of us being on
two teams is so crazy.
The penis team and the vagina team,
it's that simple.
Shirts and skins,
it's that simple,
right?
You're all,
all people on your side are good.
All people in our side of the bed.
Do you know how fucking crazy that is
insane that,
well that's what I said like um,
not to sound like I'm plugging my
special,
but in my special,
I talk about,
I was shot in Chicago where I'm from and
at the time there was a lot going on in
Chicago as there always is a lot of cop
shootings and I think there's a big,
there's an immediate uproar of like fuck
cops.
And I hate that because I've cops in my
family and you can't just blanket
statement an entire thing.
Just like you can't blanket an entire
race of people,
sex class of people and say you're all
the same.
That's the same thing as saying like
every cop is a bad person.
Like are you out of your fucking mind?
Green was millions of police officers
that are great people.
You happen to hear stories about bad
humans that happens in any industry,
right.
And honestly,
if you look at it statistically like the
number of bad cops versus the number of
cops,
and then you have to break down the
number of interactions cops have with
people,
it's stunning.
Have you been,
have you met people?
They're awful.
People are fucking awful.
Can you imagine every day who,
but imagine how awful they are.
If you are a professional enemy,
they know that you're just a person just
like them.
So you're pulling this guy over,
this guy's done a crime,
you know he's going to lie to you and
you're the enemy and you don't even know
this fucking guy.
You don't even know him.
You don't even have a real beef with
them.
But now his whole life is on the line
right now in this altercation.
You never know if he's going to shoot
you.
You never,
you never know.
There's so many videos online there,
the most,
one of the most terrifying videos of
this cop,
Poland,
this guy over and the guy was some
Vietnam veteran who is a a real fucking
killer.
And he wind up killing the cop and they
show him killing the cop on the security
camera.
The guy's trying to give this guy all
the,
all the room in the world like,
sir,
please get back in your car,
please get back at star,
Sir.
Put your hands down sir,
sir,
put the gun down sir.
And then it gets to the,
I mean he's,
he's trying so hard not to be at con and
this guy shoots him and kills him and
you're telling me that other cops
haven't seen that video.
You don't think that they're terrified
that they're going to be the next guy
that's on some fucking youtube clip that
to comics are talking about on a podcast
because it could happen easy.
Every time you pull the guy over,
your life's on the line and the stress
of that is ungodly and we expect them to
manage it like robots.
We expect them to be like no person
we've ever met,
right.
Where just no problem.
No stress.
If you're a fucking accountant,
what is the worst shit that can happen
to you once you're in the office?
Printer breaks almost nothing is life
threatening.
No,
Microsoft Excel crashed this morning.
Everyone's going crazy in fucking
accounting,
beat cop,
Jesus Christ.
It's the same way with,
uh,
you know,
I know this is,
this is all this has been said,
but the way we treat veterans and shit,
it's like,
you know,
I grew up with a kid who was a really
close friend of mine.
They killed himself a couple of years
ago.
It was a veteran,
and I think the expectation of the
return to normalcy is not only it
ridiculous and insane request,
but it's just so illogical that that's
a,
that's not approach.
It's like,
dude,
these people can't come back from any
sort of combat and,
and just be pushed back into the real
world.
Like,
well,
you're good.
Right?
You're good.
Did we,
did you turn off the switch when you
landed back in the United States?
Yeah.
And it was just a little toggle in my
head and then I'm good now I should go
get a regular job.
I guess John,
the just the lack of responsibility that
we have for like taking care of those
people.
It's crazy.
The lack of a emphasis on psychological
recovery on a giving them coping skills,
mental health,
man,
that's a biggest issue in the United
States.
I say that all the time.
It's like there's so much lack of help
for mental health dude.
You see it so constantly in so many
different facets now.
I think it's coming out more because of
the Internet because you see,
you know,
violent crimes and,
and,
and you see where mental health has kind
of led our country now.
There should be a bigger focus on it.
Did I had a psychiatrist in the podcast
yesterday,
Kelly Brogan who uh,
she wrote a book called,
what is it called?
The mind of your own mind,
of your own is the name of rubella.
We talked all about these psychiatric
drugs and when they prescribed them and
why they prescribed and what are the
side effects and how easily they
prescribed them.
Right.
And how so many of these same exact
symptoms can be cured by exercise and
diet and they don't even advocate that.
And she's talking about like how
incredible it is like her coming from a
background of psychiatry being an md,
going through the whole training thing,
writing a book about it and you realize
like Oh my God,
they're just doping people up.
Yup.
Cause it's easy fix man.
They want short term,
short term solution as fast as you can
working out and exercise sounds like
such a,
it sounds like a marathon and they just,
they're like give me the theme of the 40
Yard Dash.
Like what can we do to get them in the
40 yard dash and they're like here,
take this pill and that that changes
everything.
Just the disassociative quality of these
pills are so dangerous and we just hand
them out.
Not we obviously you and I aren't
involved,
but someone's not as far as their
audience knows.
We don't do it.
Imagine if you're a guy right now,
work at first pharmaceutical company and
every day you read the news,
you see some fucking mass killing.
Please don't let it be on our shit.
Please don't let them be Pfizer every
day.
It's like rolling the dice online.
Hope hoping.
It wasn't some guy on one of their
drugs,
she was talking about how the numbers of
people that commit these mass killings
that are on drugs,
they're on psych,
psychoactive,
some sort of cycle,
pharmaceutical drugs.
She's like,
it's crazy.
It's like a hundred percent yeah.
Well let me get,
let me get,
let me give you something.
This is how powerful
that world is.
I probably shouldn't say this,
but I'm with you,
so I don't really give a shit,
but on the only one thing I wasn't
allowed to talk about,
we're not talking about,
but specifically say on my showtime
special was about accutane.
I want an accutane when I was a kid.
Do you know this drug?
Do you know what?
Like you said,
sit dry.
Yeah,
it is,
but it's unbelievably unstable.
Okay.
It's caused a lot of suicide.
People got real fucked up from it.
So it caused a lot of chemical and
mental reaction that they didn't
anticipate for youth.
Youthful,
you know,
kids under 18 with underdeveloped
brains,
you used to have sign a form to say I
can die from this medication.
There's a risk of death.
That was a real thing for pimple
medication.
But on the special showtimes lawyers
called us and said,
I can mention the company,
but I can't say the joke.
Uh,
I said,
if you don't know what accutane was,
it was developed in the eighties and the
nineties to kill acne.
And then people and they,
they were like,
we can't say that.
I was like,
why can't I say that's a,
that's a fact.
And the guys,
you know,
lawyers were like,
there are massive sponsor,
Jesus Christ.
That was the crooked,
that was the control.
They were like the first of our
thoughts.
Showtime didn't have any sponsors.
CBS,
CBS is their mothership.
It's Viacom.
Right.
That's also a spite thing.
Yeah.
That was the only thing that they were
like,
we just can't say that,
which has a respectively removed.
Cause I was like,
I didn't need that piece anyway.
But I was like,
that's so weird that they are that
meticulous about this one small thing
because they wanted to cover up the fact
that people,
people used to die from it.
People want it.
Kids who are,
who are the most insecure point of your
life.
You've got shit all over your face and
you just want to fix it with a pill.
Cause you want to feel better about your
life.
You're already so vulnerable and ugly
and weird and they're willing to risk
their life for it.
But this company won't recognize that
that was a thing.
What,
what numbers of people died off?
I mean there was at one point I,
I remember when I was in high school,
there was like three kids.
It,
it made national news cause there's like
three kids in a row committed suicide.
It was a consecutive like three young
kids,
puppet boom that committed suicide.
And of course you can't just attribute
it to one thing.
I'm not saying you can point a finger
and say that's what it was,
but there's enough evidence surrounding
things like that that made the company
put more legal action behind,
uh,
release forms from when you take the
drug.
Uh,
nowadays I think it's,
I think there's different levels of it
you can't give to people under,
under 16 or a certain age because of the
strength of the medication.
Jesus.
Yeah.
Because all I wanted to do was not be
ugly anymore.
So what did it do to you?
You know what's funny,
man?
It cleared my skin up and I never had to
take it over again.
I know people that did it two or three
times and uh,
it,
it gave me a lot of joy because I felt
fine again.
I had,
so I had such bad acne.
I say I had such bad acne when I was a
kid that it made me not believe in God.
I was like,
nope,
nothing exists.
I'm alone on this earth.
And I was,
I felt like I was the ugliest person to
ever walk the planet because you felt
so.
So this thing [inaudible] it fixed me so
to speak.
It made me feel like everything was good
again,
which is gross.
But that's how
like shallow we are kids.
Cause you're just like so vulnerable
around your peers.
You're like,
I just want to be,
I just want to be normal.
When you're like 16 years old,
if you have a horrible acne attack,
it fucks your head.
It fucks you up.
You feel so weak.
Yeah.
He's like,
you're so at the mercy of this.
I mean obviously,
Ooh,
poor white,
cisgendered man worried about Zika.
Now you know what?
I understand there's worse problems.
Look at that.
That is this.
This is a list of the side effects of
this nice carriages,
carriages,
birthday fracks,
increased internal skull pressure,
bone mineral density,
depression,
psychosis,
suicide,
aggressive or violent behaviors,
a acute pancreatitis,
unknown in quotes,
cardiovascular consequences,
deafness,
hepatitis,
bowel disease,
excessive bone growth,
night blindness,
sight loss.
You can just lose your vision.
Well then you know,
you lose your vision.
You can't see your acne anymore.
So I guess that's kind of the caviar
list of birth defects.
Scroll back down again.
Please look at this part where it says
the list of birth defects.
No.
Up Up,
a little up,
a little up a little.
There you go.
Genetic name,
facial and nerve system deformities.
Mental retardations patients must be on
birth control when using it.
Yup.
Cause you get miscarriages.
Are you out of your fucking mind?
Net crazy patients must be on birth
control.
If you want to use this medication,
she can't get pregnant.
Your baby will come out of Mutant at
Jersey.
Man With 25 million verdict after you
alleged that Roche Acne drug gang,
Dan came,
inflammatory bowel disorder that
required the removal of his colon.
He had to rip out his fucking Kollel.
My God,
Jesus Christ,
you only get 25 million if they take out
your colon.
That's it dude.
You lose your,
but you get 25 one payday from the rock.
Like one of his big movies.
Maybe they take your colon,
he might get more than that.
It might get more than that for like
Baywatch and to,
they write in the,
in the memo of the check for colon,
fuck for colon,
for anus.
So,
um,
I worked at a hamburger place,
a place called Newport creamery when I
was in high school.
And uh,
I got graduated from dishwasher to work
in at the grill.
That's a big deal.
It was a big deal with the problem was
working at the grill.
You get fucking crazy zits dude.
Oh yes.
This is grease in your face all day.
Like literally you get out of there,
your face is covered in grease.
What will hold were you 15?
I guess I was 16 when I started working
there.
15 or 16,
some of my first job was McDonald's.
So of course I was really aiding in the
shit face of my life.
I was like,
let me eat shit food.
Uh,
be around Greece all day,
all day,
all day.
Last Friday.
Leaders like that shit's in the air.
What's gross?
Like you have a thin film of it on your
face coded.
Yeah.
And My zits got out of control and I
remember when there was this girl's
really cute girl that worked there and
she grabbed my face once.
Like she just has been nice to me.
She goes,
you're so cute.
She grabbed my face and all I could
think of was,
oh my God,
she just touched my zits.
I'm so disgusting.
I think about it to this day.
It's crazy.
It sticks with you dude.
Dude was so devastating at the time.
I just like,
I'm like,
cause I was attracted to her.
She's very cupid.
I always felt like she was out of my
league and then she's all of a sudden
she's touching my face.
I'm like God Zits,
I remember we were going to like a a a
family function of some kind and I had
obviously just picked at something on my
stupid face and my little bread sister
was like,
you're bleeding.
Oh,
it was like out of my face.
I was like,
I'm a mutant.
You feel like you're like blanket me and
hide me in the back of the car.
The only thing what,
what changed it for me was exercise.
Yeah.
Once I started,
um,
I started like really heavily working
out,
it kind of went away like towards like
17 and 18 by the time I was 18 and it
stopped.
But man for for that 15 and 16 it was
bad.
Well I played sports all through high
school so that was an issue cause it was
always sweating and it was making him to
exacerbate it made it worse.
And then in college all I did was work
out and didn't play a lot active sports.
So,
but that time it was all cleared up and
I was fine.
But in high school was just like,
I did everything to make it worse.
Like everything possible.
Everybody would get a sunburn to kill
their zits.
Remember that we'll look at me.
I can sit in the sun.
I just would get,
I would get cancer and get worse skin.
That's like in the summertime,
I remember that was like,
Oh,
like,
oh boy,
it's going to be sunny out.
This is great.
I can cook off some of these.
Get a sign off these zits.
Yeah man.
I had a buddy of mine growing up.
I mean I cannot complain because my
buddy,
um,
had it real bad.
He was one of those guys that was like,
he's his,
everything.
His neck was covered in pock marks.
His face was covering apart Mars and the
poor kid was like barely hanging on.
Right.
He's like 1516 years old,
you know,
it wasn't like genetically gifted to
begin with and then all of a sudden he
gets hit with this hail storm on his
face.
I mean,
his whole,
all of his skin was just fucked and
there's nothing they can do about it.
And once that happens,
no,
unless you want to lose your colon,
if you want to take a pill than even
that,
it doesn't smooth your face out.
No,
no,
no.
They can smooth your face.
I,
once you have those scars all over the
places,
they have to fucking sandblast you
surgery.
Yeah.
It's crazy and it doesn't look good.
No,
no.
You can tell it's fucked.
I,
yeah,
no,
I feel like I'm lucky that that I that
had worked because I had friends who
worked in work and it was like,
Oh God,
that's just if you were my friend who
just got hit with the hail storm,
like you would think like maybe for that
guy be worth taking a chance at suicide.
Yeah.
Why not?
If you're going to do it,
do it.
Cool.
You know,
you never know.
You never know,
right?
You just rolling the dice.
You might be that one or that one out of
a thousand people.
That goes completely fucking insane.
Once that stuff hits your system,
it goes blind.
Insane.
Shit's yourself.
Sculpt pressure was the craziest thing.
Bone growth.
Weird bones are going to start to grow
horns.
You see Mike's Second Chin.
You just have another chin start
to grow below.
You ever.
We'll go to this lady.
Um,
uh,
Dr Pimple popper on instagram.
No pop zits dictated to this lady's
instagram page.
The point where it almost seems like
she's sponsoring this show.
Tell everybody about her.
You go to her page and every day she's
cutting open cysts,
popping zits.
And there's,
you can,
she's got millions of look at,
she's got 2.4 million.
Okay.
2.4 million humans watch this all the
time.
Constantly.
Dude,
I watch it.
But uh,
all of her stuff is um,
these giant Zit go to that will lower
right hand corner one
click on that.
This,
she's just cutting open these cysts and
it's so oddly addictive man.
When you,
she's got like this little circular
razor blade tool.
It takes a chunk of meat out of your
neck so that she can now push all the
boss.
God.
Isn't this insane like people's bodies
and these errors,
these like skin errors that we have.
Like how many of those do we have inside
of ourselves?
You know,
like when people hear about people
having cysts and liver cysts and shit
like that inside of you like this dude,
I have,
I have a cyst when I was in,
when Jesus,
when I was in college,
I can't look away.
It's fucking insane.
No,
that's what I'm saying.
I'm in the sunken place,
Dude.
I can't fucking look away at the shout.
It's very interesting.
When I was in college,
Dude,
I thought I had nut cancer.
I thought I had testicle cancer and I
went into a doctor.
This is insane.
I want to do a campus doctor and he
feels around in my nuts and he feels the
bump and I'm sorry dude.
I tried for like two days.
He,
I started sucking my cock and he was
like,
I'm going to get that nut.
I'm going to get that.
There's only one way to get it out.
He said to me,
this is no shit.
He goes,
it's a buildup of seaman.
A fucking doctor said that and I was
like,
really?
He goes,
do you have a hot tub?
I was like,
there's one in my complex hook your
come.
He goes,
go in there and jerk off in the hot tub.
He told you to jerk off and swear to God
and tell me what time,
like 10 oh one and I don't want you to
look up.
He said,
well,
he's a military time actually.
Yeah.
He said,
he said at 2022 I want you to come close
your eyes.
If you're talking about a guy jerking
off and you're telling them how to do it
during military tiny 22 I want to watch
no dude.
This guy said it was a fucking,
I'm not kidding.
He said it was a build up of semen.
My Dad flew into town because he was
concerned cause I was like,
dude,
it freaked me out.
I was like,
I have this thing on my nut.
We went to the best doctor we could find
and the guy was like,
I should fucking have this other dude.
Like get his medical license removed.
He's like,
this is spilled up of semen is
completely incorrect.
This is a cyst on your testicle is not.
He's like,
it's benign.
It's you're fine.
But the fact that that's someone on
campus,
like a campus doctor told you that
that's a real medical professional.
He was probably high out of his mind.
Eight out of his fucking,
I went to Arizona state so he was
fucking lost.
Yeah.
It was just a dude.
They
found that morning at the bus stop.
That doesn't even make sense to me.
And um,
I don't have no medical training.
He said it.
I was like,
there's no chance send in video.
That's what it was.
He's like,
take a video of it.
That's what I want you to do.
I want you to take your nuts and hold
them over a lamp so I could see through
your nuts and then take as many pictures
as you can.
No filter.
I'm going to bring in a couple other
boys in here.
Young boys don't use filters.
Have you seen that?
Have you seen that movie tickled?
Have you seen that documentary tickled?
I have not,
but it keeps getting recommended some.
We're all going to have to watch it.
It's unreal.
If blows your fucking mind how these
guys were tricked into this.
It's as simple as young actors being
like,
you gotta,
you gotta just make a living.
Can,
can you let another guy tickle you on
the Internet for five minutes for a $100
and these young kids were like,
dude,
I've had friends get hit on by guys
during casting sessions.
Like just all,
just straight forward.
Like if you want to fuck.
Yeah,
like I've had friends,
like literally get propositioned.
I've had a few friends get propositioned
by some very,
very famous,
very famous people that are like,
you come to so's house.
No one will know.
No one will say anything.
But as a in the public eye,
people think they're straight.
There's such a leap man.
When you're a dude and you're straight
and you're like,
all right,
how much money is that really?
That is,
that is the crazy leap.
Like I honestly absolutely firmly
believe that prostitution should be
legal when you're 100% it doesn't make
any sense that you can decide to fuck
someone for free.
And we all agree that nobody got hurt.
But if some,
for some reason there's something wrong
with like someone paying you to jerk
them off,
well why?
What?
What's the hires?
Can you imagine?
Do you imagine if fucking tiger woods,
if tiger woods could have had
prostitutes,
this would have never gotten exposed.
Do you think if that,
if prostitution was legal and it was
kind of not a full pot thing in society,
do you think he would have never had
this moment of collapse in his career?
He would change the way we look at sex.
If prostitution was legal like right.
Like it's,
it's so illegal and it's been illegal
for so long that if someone,
male or female has someone pay them for
sex,
you're a whore.
Right?
It's a label right away.
But we know for a fact that there's gold
diggers,
like gold diggers are real,
but they're not,
but,
and there are even hidden their blatant,
blatant,
yeah.
They just say Internet that you've seen
that if you ever seen that instagram
post where the,
there's these really hot like instagram
models and then it shows a picture in
the next box of a bunch of guys that are
like in their sixties with giant guts,
with hair on their guts is like those
instagram models in Dubai.
This is who's paying for those precise.
Yeah,
of course you,
we know those people exist and there's
nothing.
We don't care.
It's like,
look at her.
She got it good for her.
That like that Dan Bilzerian guy.
You know him?
Yeah.
That's like his,
that's his ammo.
Well,
sorta.
He's a good looking guy too.
Yeah,
but these women that are around,
they,
he knows what,
they're around four and she,
they know what they were around for it.
It's a,
it's a fucking mutual d.
It's a deal.
I think the best example of it was j
Howard Marshall and Anna Nicole Smith.
It totally,
and Anna Nicole Smith married that 90
year old dude.
It was in a wheelchair and she was just,
she was just giant titties and a big ass
and just out there.
Brilliant.
It was amazing.
It was amazing because it was so
blatant.
I had a whole bit about it.
In my act.
There is,
right.
She set the tone that's setting the
fucking town.
That's the gold standard of gold
diggers,
right?
Well,
yeah.
Come on.
And he's mourning.
Are there,
how is that not prostitution?
That's one of the funniest things
anybody said.
Go back to that photo.
Zoom in on his face.
Look at how unhappy he looks.
It's remarkable.
This guy is so fucking old.
He can't formulate a smile when he's
marrying a woman his age.
And I think at the time she was a
lesbian,
so she was just eating pussy and hanging
out with him and she had to do like
marital relations with them.
And when she would do the marital
relations with them,
you know,
she would just like tell them to go to
work.
What does she,
what does she got to do?
He can't fuck.
What does she got to do?
Just that
tug.
Suck his dick.
I suck them exclusive.
Maybe.
Did they have Viagara back then?
No,
I don't think so.
I think they did.
I think we came up with the timeline for
Viagara.
Maybe they came up with it for him
is all his research money,
not that close to Mary and Anna Nicole
Smith.
You piece of shit.
Make something.
Keep my tick hard for an hour and a
half.
I've got $10 billion and not a lot of
time and watch or listen to me.
You son of a bitch.
That's so crazy.
I love it.
Good for him.
Go out with a bang or at least attempt
and attempted a bang.
Is he dead?
Yeah,
he's dead as fuck.
What'd he say?
Of Happiness data.
Being a boy.
He died in joy.
The world blessed him in his final
years,
but that's legal.
It's totally legal.
Totally marry someone and have sex with
them for money as long as you marry them
and then get to steal all their money.
And it's like a small transaction.
Like if he could just pay her like for j
Howard Marshall,
a multibillionaire type character up a
hundred grand's not out of the question.
It's nothing.
One,
one evening for a hundred grand.
It seems like a worthy proposition.
Here's this,
this,
this.
If he's a b,
this is,
someone told me this recently,
we were talking about this.
This is amazing.
The different between a million and a
billion because I think in America we
just kind of like,
we don't even think about it.
You know,
you just hear it.
You're like billion.
Oh,
he must be a billionaire.
You know,
I'm sure someone,
Joe Rogan,
who's,
who's got to be a fucking billionaire
dude,
here's the difference that people don't
realize a million seconds is,
is how many days would you guess?
A million seconds.
I've done this before and I always
forget it.
Do you know a million second million?
Second 30 days.
That's a great guess.
Okay,
is it?
It's 11 days.
That's good.
Most people are fucking way off.
So it's 11 days chance.
Yeah,
that's good.
A million seconds is 11 days.
How many days is a billion seconds?
How many 31 years.
Jesus.
11 days to 31 fucking years.
Jesus,
look at that.
So when
trillion seconds is 31,000 years,
when tries to fucking say like they
understand what a billion is.
You're like,
you have no fucking idea what a billion
is.
Up to billion is so beyond far away.
Now,
as far as it's been explained to me,
and I've never researched this at all,
so I wonder if you could find this out.
Someone said to me that when you look at
the richest man in the world,
like they look at like Warren Buffet and
Bill Gates and all those George Soros,
all or characters that they're not
really the richest men in the world,
that the real richest man in the world
are these Saudi guys.
Yep.
And a lot of these oil guys,
but they're their monarchs and they
don't have to disclose their wealth.
They never do.
It's not like they're the CEO of a
corporation there.
Their head of a royal family that they,
oh no government,
any indication of what their earnings
are.
So this dude who knows one of those cats
was telling me that he's probably a
trillionaire fuck me.
And I was like,
what?
I go,
that's real.
And he goes,
yeah,
I go to,
I didn't know there was trillionaires.
He goes,
it's very likely this guy might have
access to $1 trillion.
Because the only thing that we know is
our famous billionaires were infatuated
with our billionaires that we kind of
have as these social icons.
You know,
like Zuckerberg and these guys that are
like,
they did something that we can recognize
these Saudi families that have had that
money,
have had that money for a fucking long
time.
It's not new money.
No,
this is old bit.
They had,
they had hundreds of millions 50 years
ago.
Right.
So now it's only accumulated into
billions of,
I mean they own,
well the what the um,
that guy that the Chinese billionaire
that,
um,
what was his name?
He just bought the Basquiat.
Oh,
we had this Japanese.
Japanese,
yeah,
$100 million that we just were talking
about that which shows as bill burr.
Yeah.
Dude,
on 110 I think it was.
I mean,
and he owns another one that he got for
like 57 but that 50 sevens nothing to
him that's like,
it's a flick guy's insane.
Who's this cat?
One point 4 trillion fucking dollars.
Oh my God.
See?
Oh my God,
the royal family is worth a staggering
one point 4 trillion Solomon bin.
Abdulaziz he sowed pictured is the
current king too.
That's balling on a whole new level.
So that's just new shit.
One point 4 trillion.
Oh my God.
Who is this guy?
The Rothschild Rothschild's.
Yeah,
for sure.
There's probably a bunch of those little
scoundrels running around taking a piece
of that pie,
but that's a,
so a billion is a thousand million
thousand 700 trillion.
The rothschilds estimated between 1
billion and 700 trillion.
Hey,
how about you do a better job?
I could do as good a job of estimating.
Is that no shit.
That's so far.
Probably a kazillion.
It's like when you ask a kid how much a
car is and they're like eight $8 and
you're like,
yeah,
it's like $8.
That's how much cars are.
$8 hundred dollars yes,
exactly.
It is a Mercedes.
So
how the fuck could they have such
terrible like gap in there?
They're guesstimate.
Well,
that's gotta be key that see those kind
of old families that have been around
for that long,
you know that they hide money.
They don't like when they say x amount
of dollars,
it's because that's what they've been
told this for so many sources.
I used to know that.
You know the guy,
this Guy George Soros,
do you know who that is?
They got to bring them back in
Manhattan,
the name,
because everyone brings it up when they
talk about like anyone on the rights.
I like Alex Jones and said that George
Soros was making the marijuana stronger
from mind control.
I take it once a year.
I smoked marijuana to test the
efficiency.
I like how he's the gauge.
I'm going to do it for America.
Yeah,
I will smoke.
He says he's functioning once a year.
He said that during his custody trial
once,
that's it.
Just once a year to test its potency.
That's George Soros.
So I party with his kid one time,
25.2 billion.
I party with this kid
time with one of these Hollywood things
and I've never seen someone so,
and I'm not gonna say anything negative
about him and I just never seen that
kind of money firsthand.
I've never,
I'd never known a billionaire I've ever
been friends with a billionaire and this
kid was so lucid.
It was almost as if he's not living now
at all.
He's just kind of go,
it's just flow.
He's so floating.
It's like whatever happens,
happens.
I said,
where are you staying while you're here?
He's like,
with these guys,
I guess.
I was like,
what do you do?
You have suitcases and shit.
You're in town from New York,
like,
are you not?
He's like,
Nah,
I just fucking,
I don't know.
I'm going to figure it out.
I guess bounce around a little bit.
I think it's just like there is no,
there's no groundedness.
When you're that rich,
it's almost like,
I don't know,
I can do anything all the time forever.
There's no source of
repetitiveness.
Yeah.
I don't think it's a good thing.
It's so bad.
It's,
it doesn't seem to work out.
I mean,
I would think the only way you would get
a kid through that is you got to take
them to sports or something.
You got to get them involved in some
adversity.
He's got to lose at something.
Yeah,
a lot.
If you lose,
if you lose it,
right?
Shit.
And you start to understand how human
you are when you're like,
oh my God,
there's so many people better than me at
so many fucking things,
dude.
Because when you're given everything,
you never lose.
You never,
you never heard no.
There's no negative in your life.
It's just kind of like,
how do you get any sense of fucking,
you know,
any normalcy or anything grounded in
your hands when you're like,
yeah,
we need feedback.
Yeah.
You need to know that that's not good
and that's okay and that's terrible and
that's good.
You need to know where you land on the
spectrum of in the social world.
That's why so many rich kids are
socially so fucking awkward because they
never had to,
they never got beat up at school.
They never got made fun of whose it was
all like fucking flat
flats.
All flat.
Yeah,
you can't have all flat.
You don't want to have too many crazy
dips cause then you're fucking,
but you definitely don't want flat.
Like the worst drive ever is not the
longest drive.
The worst drive ever is like when you
drive in and those,
those roads,
the people we stopped take album cover
pictures in.
Yeah.
Well you just see just flat and nothing
forever.
There's nothing just flat.
Like if you go the same distance but
you're driving on like the the Pacific
coast and you're headed up to San
Francisco,
it's fucking beautiful.
Barely recognize you.
First of all,
he's like the cliffs right there.
Fucking clips.
Right.
What if I just fucking,
you could just do that and people do do
that for sure.
They just go off that cliff and you just
want to make sure the guy on the other
side is not thinking,
I'm just going to head on this guy and
we're both going to go off this cliff,
do this shit together.
Let's do this shit.
I'm going to drag somebody with me.
Fuck him.
Ah,
the last moments of your life flying off
a cliff because some pilled up asshole
decided just slam into you and one
afternoon it can happen.
Have you seen those birds that jumped
off the cliff right after they're born?
Have you seen these [inaudible]?
This video?
Yeah.
Yes.
Look up.
Look up bird jumps off cliff after
birth.
So the moment they hatched,
the mother and the father go to the
bottom of this like 500 foot cliff and
the birds jump and he's,
and they hit them.
They hit rocks all the way down and
whoever survives survives with the
parents.
Oh my God.
Dude,
it's fucking amazing.
I just saw it on,
it's on,
I think it's on,
um,
on planet earth.
Planet Earth.
I can't really show this thought.
It's the people.
I'll,
I'll link to Katie or something.
But what is a video called?
So people getting chicks jump off
cliffs,
chicks jump off cliff,
which is another one that they do here
in la,
sometimes in Hollywood.
But
I think that different,
look at God,
this is insane.
They don't even have wings yet.
Nope.
Nothing.
Just fucking bold.
Oh my God,
this is insane.
This is insane.
So this poor little thing is,
it's kind of like a flying squirrel
looking situation.
This is insane,
dude.
The first time I watched it,
I was so baked.
I was like,
is this a loop?
Because it looks like it's never going
to end.
It's so far.
I think he says it 500 or 600 feet or
something so insane that this is how
life gets born.
Oh my God.
And he hits the rocks and you've got to
assume he's dead.
Nope.
Oh my God.
He's going to hit more rocks.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
So many fucking rocks thing.
It's flipping head over heels.
It hits more rocks.
Oh,
he a little grass.
Derek got caught a break.
Break,
break,
break.
Look at this thing.
It's going down the side of the cliff.
Head over heels,
headfirst,
asshole.
Head head to a rock for a second.
Assault to a rock.
Got a minute.
We've got to break.
Nope.
Gotta let her mind break again.
And then more,
more bouncing.
Boom.
Head for others.
Your face.
There's your Dick Hole.
Here's a rock up your asshole.
Here's one of the side of your face.
She's one of your eyes.
Here's one year,
oh,
another hundred feet to go again.
There's mom and dad and mom's like,
cause this mother fucker gonna make it.
Look it.
There's another one behind it.
No,
look at this.
Boom.
How's he doing?
So then the insane,
they stop and wait to see which ones,
which ones live.
Jesus Christ nature.
So harsh.
See,
I knew you would love this because I
thought about you the first time I saw
this and I was like,
this is so fucking proof about
surviving,
dude.
It's so survival.
This,
this is the most basic.
You have to leap and almost died
the moment you enter the world.
God chick is tough as fuck survival.
Do five rounds of Giorgio Petrosian and
just shake it off as rgo versus dead
one.
Yeah,
there's one that didn't make it.
I'm sure there's a ton of dead ones.
Oh Jesus.
Fucking Christ.
Yeah.
You could actually hit one of those
corners and it could gut you.
You know for sure.
Yep.
I mean this is all shale.
That stuff is so dangerous.
That's all that one's dying.
Oh,
Jamie,
don't show us this.
This is so sad.
I had a bird come on my house the other
day and this poor little fuckers.
He flew right into the wind delt dunk.
I'm sorry to laugh.
Every time I see that he was going to go
out and then woke up and then flew into
another window full speed dunk out cold.
So I thought he was,
I thought he's probably dead.
And My,
my daughter's going,
oh no.
Is he going to die?
I go,
we don't know honey.
Let's,
let's put him outside and hopefully
he'll wake up.
Fucker woke up.
He did.
Yeah.
He woke up like five minutes later.
He like shook it off and facility away.
Like imagine that was a person that
thing's going like 30 miles an hour
right into a window.
Dunk that tiny bird to just,
he got k code,
but then got up and flew away.
Came back for another round rock came in
the house.
That was weird.
Uh,
buddies.
I was at a buddy's house,
uh,
at this like party in a fucking
hummingbird flew right into the house
like right through the double doors.
Oh Geez.
Stuck in a skylights and it was
panicking because he didn't know what to
it.
Like it wasn't willing to come down.
So I was just fucked up enough that I
was like,
I have this idea.
Give me a fucking huge pan,
the biggest pan from the kitchen and
pour a sugar and water and heat up the
sugar a little bit so and put it and I
put the Pan Up to it.
I got an a ladder,
put it up.
It started getting in there to drink the
sugar water and I slowly took it down
and walked outside some wizard shit
wizardry dude.
I was fucking magic hands.
That's very smart.
You ever seen them in slow mo?
Man,
they're so bizarre.
They're fucking,
their wings are moving so fast.
Unbelievable.
It's insane.
Like it's beautiful to watch,
man.
Oh Man.
I was in Costa Rica and we went to this
place that had a,
a,
it had some sort of a sanctuary for
them.
The humming bird sanctuary.
Yeah.
Do you know what it is?
I went down to Costa Rica just last
year.
So they have,
you know,
you can,
they have these feeders to see,
just hang out by them and take slow mo
on your iphone and you see the thing
floating around your head.
There it is right there.
I mean they could just hover.
It's so crazy.
Like how did they evolve like this?
It's so strange.
Like no other bird makes that,
that weird sound when it goes by you.
It's like they have little wings but
they move stupid fast.
How many,
how many?
How many per cause?
It'd say like how many,
uh,
I knew their heartbeat is insane.
The heartbeat is like there's a hundred
times ours or something like that.
They're so cute.
They don't seem like killers at all.
No.
Right.
They're just out there eating pollen and
shit.
Right.
Look at that.
It's incredible.
Did they eat bugs?
Like what do they eat?
They got that little tongue sticking
out.
Like going for like nectar and steps for
nectar.
Yeah.
This is going to have some facts for us.
How many birdly one to three egg several
times per year.
Eggs are about the size of a jelly bean.
Oh,
that's not good facts.
I want to know what they eat.
I want to know that kind of shit will
get ahead knows there's the craziest
beaks too.
Like if that was a giant bird,
you'd be like,
what the fuck?
That's pretty sick.
Did you see what that just said?
You had an extra set of eyelids and they
can see ultraviolet.
Oh,
that's fucking amazing.
Whoa.
That beak is crazy.
That beats like a Narwhal Horn.
Like it's so tiny.
We don't notice how crazy long their
beaks are too.
That's the other thing I haven't seen
that they can,
there is no consistency of color between
all the birds.
Do you know what I mean?
Like usually most species have a similar
color pattern or the,
is there a bunch of different kinds of
hummingbirds?
Oh,
they do.
Insects powers,
saps out tree,
sap pollen and insects.
So they're omnivores.
Interesting that birds are a trip,
dude.
They,
there are some of the most unique
animals on our planet.
I've I really 15 or them.
I really ignored birds until I saw my
first eagle and person in the wild.
It's crazy,
right?
Yeah.
If I saw it,
I was with a Ari.
We were in,
um,
uh,
Alaska.
We were in anchorage.
We're going fishing for salmon fishing.
We're like,
dude,
that's a fucking Wild Eagle Eagles.
You stand there on this branch.
Just looking down on us.
I was like,
what?
Like you started realizing what they
really are like,
well,
that's how I got murdering dinosaur bird
that flies around and snatches fish out
of the water was wearing a star fish.
It's chilling.
We were catching these fish do do.
They were like this big,
this salmon,
these,
these powerful fish and this eagle comes
down and grabs it out of the water with
his talents and flies with it.
It's fucking awesome,
dude.
I started tripping out on birds after
that.
Just be in DM.
Being near them in,
in the,
in the wild and seeing them move around.
It just seems so different than seeing
them in the zoo.
They're so fucking hardcore.
They're wingspans are so amazing to me
when they opened up how fucking huge
there.
Whenever you see one in person you're
like,
that is way bigger than I thought
whatsoever.
It's a view back to a much more ancient
style of living thing,
you know?
I mean it's a view back to dinosaurs and
they're starting to realize more and
more dinosaurs fossils are being found
with feathers.
Let me fucking birds is,
have you ever seen a moose in real life?
Oh yeah.
I've shot a Moose Moose right there.
Whenever I go,
whenever I go up to Canada like have you
ever been a Bam?
You know where that is?
An Alberta?
Yeah,
I know that it is dude that at that has
the biggest Moose I've ever seen in my,
like I've seen,
I've seen Moose when I was kid,
but nothing like up in northern Canada.
Dude.
I mean beaut,
the size of a fucking school bus.
I mean it's so big.
I think people think they think they
know what a Moose is cause you're like,
yeah,
I think it's like a cow or something.
You know what I mean?
Dude,
they're massive,
massive pelvis.
They're so big.
Shocking.
It was twice the size of our car.
I was like,
get the fuck Outta here.
That's a moose there.
They're so big.
It's insane.
And if you run into him like you hit him
with your car,
you're fucked.
You're fucked.
They would read.
They'll requeue.
That was a grown up in the midwest,
dude.
I'd hear people getting bad car
accidents with deer all the time.
These guys in Canada,
there is no stories about it.
You Die.
You hit a fucking,
it's not like,
dude.
You hear about Mikey fucking hit a deer.
It's like you hit a moose.
It's like Mike's car exploded.
Mike is,
Mike is dead.
Dear will fuck you up though.
There's plenty of mine who lives in
Oregon of guy on the highway in his
neighborhood.
Hit a deer.
The deer flipped over his car and hit
the car behind him.
Fuck and went through the windshield and
killed the guy.
Really Nice guy was fine.
The first guy was fine.
The car,
the deer flipped over his car,
like as he hit it,
it went flying through the air and then
it landed like right,
right on his fucking into this guy's car
and killed them.
The craziest Shit I ever saw.
I was like eight years old.
My Dad drive it on the fucking Dan Ryan
in Chicago and a car.
Uh,
the middle of the lane was,
the fastening was under construction.
A car went over the fucking median on to
oncoming traffic and hit another car.
Oh Geez.
Like a hundred yards in front of us.
I watched it fucking happened.
It was the craziest Shit I've ever seen
in my life.
And he was like,
the afternoon,
I don't know if he was fucked up or what
booth,
right over the median shred into another
car.
She,
and you saw the whole thing I watched.
I watch it happen.
I mean,
it felt so fake when I was a kid.
I remember thinking,
I remember getting older and asking my
dad if it happened because I thought,
you know,
in,
in your childhood sometimes you're like,
did I see that in a fucking thing?
And that it wasn't real.
You know,
and you formulate these different
stories in your brain as a kid cause
you're,
you know that line of what's real and
fake when you're so young.
But dude,
I w I can't forget that happened.
It was Cray Z.
Dot.
Is Craig perfectly hit another car.
It was almost as if like magnetic
fucking head,
right head on.
Wow.
Yeah.
It was wild.
I think those fast and the furious
movies at fuck people up when it comes
to like what you can and can't do in a
car.
Yeah.
Did they jump a car from like a building
and shit to another building and live,
it's fucking insane.
I mean there's a lot of
dumb kids out there that watch those
movies.
They gotta be like,
Yo man,
I got to give that a shot.
Has to be someone cause it thinks that
that's what's going to happen when they
get behind the wheel.
Bro,
I'm going to be the best ever.
I never even drove yet,
but once I drive,
I'm going to be the best fucking over
overdog.
I watched that movie all the time.
He would just want to be cool.
They want to be
the aunt ship,
spin that wheel.
Did you ever watch those fail videos
online of people showing off like
showboating and nice cars.
That's my fear.
That's one of my favorite stream.
Yeah.
They were always like some guys like
some guys like spinning the wheels dude,
some guy like a fucking gtr.
I was like
just right into the fucking wall next to
him.
Just spin out,
crash right away.
It's just dude,
it's great.
I love to see that shit.
I love to see people showing off and
then right away they're fucked.
I love that shit.
Nothing funnier.
How many
videos of that now too?
I mean there's so,
it's almost like if you have a camera
and you're pointing it out,
the guy who Kinda hexing him cause he's
saying,
man,
I hope I don't fuck this up because it's
going to be on every site.
Everyone's twitter account,
instagram page.
It's like you're kind of like putting
too much pressure on them.
Your accident is now sharable.
Yeah.
Your mistakes are now.
Everyone's a joy.
That's the world we're in now.
Your fuck ups could be of somebody great
Monday,
you know,
come to the new world is brilliant.
It's a crazy new world.
Man didn't exist.
It was never like this.
Yeah.
You didn't have to worry about someone
seeing your fuck up.
How old are you?
33 I'm 49 when I was a kid.
We didn't even have,
like when I was born,
back in the day you heard stories,
somebody fucked up somewhere over there.
This guy did that,
you know,
that's all.
That's all.
There was one guy in our town killed
someone in a car and dragged this guy
around.
Like he,
he got the guy stuck under his car and
he just kept driving.
Fuck.
Did he not know he was under there or he
was like,
fuck it.
I don't care.
I'm going to prison.
I know,
I know.
They don't know if he was drunk.
I don't,
I don't know.
I don't know when he got caught either,
but it was a story.
It was in the news and I remember it was
in like,
uh,
I was delivering newspapers at the time
so I saw it like in the newspapers that
I was delivering.
It's so weird to have known someone and
then know that they ran over somebody in
a car and then dragged it around.
Yeah,
I didn't know him well,
but he was like one of those guys in the
town.
I think he was a little older than me,
but he was one of those guys that was
always kind of hanging out with a nice
car.
He has had like a,
a nice trans-am IROC Z was about the,
yeah,
his family had money and uh,
he ran over someone and dragged them
around.
There was always this thing about people
whose families had money,
like the rich kids get away with it.
Well it was,
it was a weird thing too.
It's like we knew that there were like a
little off.
Like you always knew that the rich kids
were never like a complete human right.
They were always like,
like there was just a few of them that
were just a little like if you knew
their rich,
there's probably a lot of kids that we
did know they were rich and they are
rich,
but it was,
they weren't fucked up so it didn't come
through.
But the ones that wanted everybody to
know they were rich.
Like I always had designer clothes on
and they always had the nicest shit and
they always had like brand new cars.
Like when they were 17,
this guy had a brand new car there.
It's almost like there are,
uh,
a little bit,
animatronic like,
or something robotic about really rich
kids where it's just kind of like a
super,
super high functioning in a very like,
disconnected level because they're so
unaware of what it's like to not have.
Yeah.
Well I'm watching these shows.
My kid,
we went to see this,
a diary of a wimpy kid.
Yay.
Thankfully a funny movie,
man.
This is a funny shit in there.
I laughed hard a couple of times.
That movie.
Yeah,
I just went because they wanted to go.
But in this movie,
one of the things that's like,
it really strikes home is like everyone
is struggling.
It's fuck kids.
Like everything has fallen apart always
constantly.
Right.
And because of that,
he's kind of got a fun personality.
Like he gets checked all the time.
As soon as he gets cocky,
he gets crushed again.
Right.
It just keeps happening through and
there's a whole series of these movies,
but I like,
that's not happening to that.
The rich kid that I grew up with,
no fuss.
That's why probably when he hit the guy
in his car and had the guy stuck under
his car,
he didn't,
what the fuck to do?
I mean,
he just thought he was gonna get away
with whatever he figured.
He figured,
I just gotta get,
I gotta get away.
Just cleaned the car.
There was a kid I went to high school
with that,
uh,
had a hit and run and didn't,
and they got,
he got away with it.
I mean,
obviously I didn't know it was this kid.
I went to high school,
but he got away with it for a long
fucking time.
It was such a public story that f a
famous nascar driver at the time painted
her name on his car,
like find so-and-so's killer because it
was such a fucking big deal.
This girl that was hit and run and he
came out years later,
this is crazy.
He was pilled pilled the fuck up.
And he showed up to her sister's house
and admitted the whole thing to her
sister and was saying he was gonna like
run away,
kill himself,
whatever.
And she cleverly,
she spoke Polish,
she told her husband to fucking call the
cops and was trying to call him this kid
down in the meanwhile,
telling him to call the cops and they
finally caught this kid before he could
fucking off himself or something.
But he killed this girl on a hit and run
and thought he and God,
for what it's worth,
got away with it for a long time,
man.
But he was probably not a bad person.
He just was weak at the time.
And it haunted for,
yeah,
he had it had to come out fuck crazy.
Right.
That's a mistake that if you make it,
God damn it.
She liked that happened like,
like from from your area of where you
grew up.
Like do you read stuff now years later
that you hear about fucked up shit from
back then but like said gotten exposed
now like these teachers,
like these teachers I knew ran a fucking
prostitution ring
came out in the paper.
The teachers did.
Teachers did the shop.
The old shop teacher,
his daughter,
the shop.
The shop teacher has pivot.
Dude,
that's insane.
Who the girls,
the girls were high school students?
No,
not high school students.
They were fucking just like girls in the
community probably grows.
I went to high school and graduated,
but all the girls said they were pimping
out from the school.
They were pimping from school.
What school was this?
This is out in the suburbs of Chicago.
Wow.
Here's the question.
If they did make prostitution legal,
it's set up just like you go get a
massage,
you can go off sex with somebody.
Yeah.
How much would that change?
Like the notion of marriage
relationship.
Nobody's getting married.
It's over.
It's all only a law that's keeping like
what percentage of people married,
I mean you,
you said it before when we were,
when we,
when we touched on this prior,
the reason that we make it okays cause
the church gets involved,
right?
So if the church says it's okay,
it's like my dad was a drug addict grown
up,
my dad was,
was in and out of prison my whole life
when I was a kid and my mother divorced
my father when I was one.
So I don't really have any recollection
of any of that.
So I don't have that like damage that
people,
like my dad got divorced when we were 16
I didn't see it.
I didn't know it.
But my mom came from such a hardcore
Irish Catholic world that my family,
the older generation didn't approve and
was like,
you can't divorce this man that's
against our religion.
And my mom was like,
he's a fucking terrible person to me.
I have to get out of this relationship.
And now she was just,
they were both young,
you know,
she just wanted to make the right move
for,
for a baby.
But the
church has so much influence on certain
parts of society that my grandmother was
like almost disowning,
like,
eh,
but that's such a reality for that
generation that it was like,
how could you,
what do you mean divorce?
I mean that's like you're,
you're,
you're going to hell.
Like that's it.
You're done.
So my mom had that kind of fuck up in
her brain of like that.
And that's how much influence the church
has over marriage and coupling.
And it's crazy.
It's fucking crazy.
It's unbelievably ridiculous that people
succumb to that.
It's so crazy.
It's controlling man.
Well,
the,
the Catholic church in particular is one
of the weirdest ones ever.
I'll show strangest,
this insanely high percentage of people
that are involved in child abuse.
I mean,
what other religion has that connected
to it like that there's none.
What a Muslim is the biggest in the
world,
right?
The biggest religion in the world,
I think it is.
It's not Christianity.
Yeah.
Start there.
Probably Toto.
Either way.
You don't hear about that.
So are they covering up shit?
It's not the same thing.
The thing about the priests and the
priests being forced to be celibate and
then spending time with boys like that
shit has always gone bad.
Yeah.
Forcing guys to be celibate,
bad forcing guys to hang out with boys
back.
Awful.
Someone.
Something is weird.
Weird Shit's going to happen if there's
no parents in the room,
dude,
when it,
when as soon as you deprive someone of
something,
they are going to have it.
They want it immediately.
Then you attach to it.
The ultimate power that comes from being
a representative of God.
Yeah.
Like you're wearing a priest outfit to a
little kid.
Like that kid will suck your Dick.
He'll do anything you say.
Does he know what's going on?
He's a baby.
Oh,
it's freezing.
So dark,
deep,
dark,
dark control.
And when you find out how many of them,
yeah,
that's the thing is it's not just one.
It's not just 10 I could,
the more you hear,
the more you're like to,
this is not a fucking accident.
These are coincidences.
This isn't like a,
a conspiracy that this is a fact that
this is rampant and it's crazy.
It's crazy because it's still happening
now.
They don't talk about,
yeah,
it's no.
It's like it's,
you know.
Well,
how about that benedict guy?
The pope that had to resign,
they found out that he had been involved
in the moving of these child molesters
from one place to another place,
keeping them clean,
clothes the story down,
shut everybody up and then move that guy
to another place.
And one of the guys went on to Molesta
hundred deaf kids.
Yeah.
He get molested,
a hundred deaf kids.
And he was put into that position by
this guy who wound up being the pope.
A hundred deaf hundred deaf kids.
Yeah,
it was.
It's horrible.
Fucking awful.
It's hard.
There's so much involved in it.
There's so many people that covered shit
up.
There's so many different versions of
these stories.
So many stories.
Thousands and thousands of stories that
people are molested by priests.
Yeah.
I mean,
it's crazy.
And if you bring it up immediately,
you get people defending it now.
Now,
now look,
you're exaggerate.
I Blah,
blah,
blah.
Like I've said this before.
It can imaginative nascar drivers.
Fuck that many kids.
It'd be shut down.
You shut the fuck down.
But because it's the church,
we're like,
well let's,
uh,
you know,
but there's good things to their working
for God.
Okay?
It's crazy that any organization can
have a history of fucking kids were
working for God.
It's God's side job,
fucking children,
because that's not whatever it is.
It's not working.
But we forgive them.
We will.
It's not all bad.
We don't want to break the whole thing
up.
Definitely don't want to do that.
No,
stealing is not that fucking a kid is
the same as like some minor bullshit
infraction and society and thousands,
thousands of cases,
maybe even millions of cases.
It's and then still do you have these
world leaders like trump met with the
pope.
The pope was all bummed out.
Trump should be like,
I'm bummed out to be next to you,
motherfucker.
You represent you mad at me cause I'm
pulling out of the climate accord.
What about all the kid fucking,
Bro,
you should bring up the kid fucking,
he's been fucking kids.
That's it.
Oh,
that's right.
You do a good trump.
Have you seen the pictures of trump with
the pope?
The pope's totally disenchanted rail
bumped to pope should relax.
He should slow as fucking role.
You're a part of a giant kid fucking
ring.
Yeah.
Who Do you think you are?
Right?
You're getting cocky because the
billionaire guy who tricked American
devoting forum is uncomfortable.
Do you know what the best,
you know what the Ma,
the thing that bothers me the most is
the church is all about fucking to
community and the people and they don't
pay taxes on all this great real estate.
They own tons of it.
How come they can't house homeless
people or sick people in those churches
all day long while they're there?
That's free property.
Yeah.
I don't understand.
There it is.
Yeah,
it's fucking believe I got this trumps
like my hair looks good.
Good hair day or good hair day.
Puppy like my hair.
Touch it.
Thrill.
I got a gun that the guy that I used
went to Tony and guy the hairstylist
school.
The color of his hair is like the color
of every retired Florida Golfer in his
70 [inaudible] so gross.
He's got this weird blonde,
grey thing going on.
It's like he moves it around a little,
like some days it's like a darker Brown
Sundays.
It's like a blog on gray.
It looks,
it's just like sand.
He's getting it worked on.
It's what I'm saying like this is not
the color of the hair.
Now what you do one or two things.
Let me be clear about this.
Either you work on your hair or you
don't work on your hair.
Okay,
so either you die your fucking hair or
you don't dye your hair.
It's one of those two things.
How fucking when you dye your hair be
consistent.
You can't go gray and then be blonde
again and it'd be dark haired.
It's too confusing to me.
I need to know what kind of a person to
you,
like how much you working on your hair,
what's your level of haircare,
how much time you spending putting that
together every day?
It does.
Did Donald Trump changes?
Eric?
Of course.
It was just fucking obvious and of
course he did.
He's changed his hair color.
It goes.
He's moving it around as his hair is
probably very great at this point.
He's in his seventies there's nothing
wrong with that.
What did you think about all this,
Kathy Griffin?
Shit.
She's ridiculous.
It's fucking insane.
She needs friends.
Why are you doing that?
It's just,
it's a hundred percent attention.
Attention,
man.
What a bullshit call for attaching edgy.
She thought she was being edgy and she
probably was talking with the wrong
people and got the wrong in her head and
went with it and had no one like you
around and go,
what the fuck are you talking about?
If that's the president.
Right,
and it's a person.
Yeah,
to human.
Yeah.
You can't,
you can't pretend you want to murder
him.
Isis style on the hold his head up to
the camera like a hostage video.
That's fucking crazy.
I think it's just,
it's,
it's one of those things where both both
parties,
both extreme left and extreme right,
are at such a heightened version of
what's happening that people are
becoming blind to like logic.
Yes.
I 100% right.
Logic is like it's gone.
Yeah.
You would fucking never,
if somebody did that with Obama,
a holy shit.
Oh my God.
I mean the fucking world would stop
spinning.
There'd be so much chaos from that.
It would be fucking,
it w it would be an insane thing to see
that happen.
Well,
look,
it's just,
that's not any one solution.
Like that's not a real sort of like
holding up that head is not a real
solution like killing anybody like that.
Okay.
And not only that,
even if it's like the worst person in
the world cutting their head off and
holding it up like that,
it's fucking barbaric.
We wouldn't even want that from Osama
bin Ladin.
If we found the,
the video of Osama bin Ladin and one of
the seals held him down and cut his head
off and then held it up to the camera,
we'd be fucking extremely like,
what are we doing?
Why don't you just kill him,
kill him.
Like we're not them.
We're not torturing them.
We're not trying to terrorize all these
other people.
We are not going to become what we're
afraid of.
Right.
And B,
that's what she's doing.
By holding that head up,
you are becoming what you were afraid
of.
Your becoming a monster.
You're yours,
your tread face.
You're not even emotionally attached.
The fact that you're holding up this
bloody head.
No.
Like what kind of nonsense?
False imagery is this?
Like you don't really think that.
You don't really feel that.
Is it art?
Like what is it?
That's what the,
I'm sure that's what the argument from
from Bruce Sake was.
It's an artistic piece where the with
the,
with a photographer who's,
but it's about a real person that's not
Medusa.
You decide like a dragon's head you're
holding up if it's just crazy.
Right?
Is he here?
If it's your own head,
it's your own head.
You can make a funny statement trying to
make a statement.
Sure.
But it's like what are you doing?
You're terrorizing that person if you're
that you have,
I know everybody thinks that the
president has to assume a certain amount
of mockery and I agree that he does.
Sure.
I agree.
Everybody in any position of power like
that is going to,
you're going to have people coming at
you of course.
But there's a difference between that
and advocating a brutal assassination
and terror video that's head removal.
That's just,
yeah,
it's not,
that's not,
no one's going to be sympathetic towards
your idea and in fact you're going to
empower the people that are opposed to
you cause they're gonna Think,
oh,
these people are these crazy ideologues
who want to like literally promote the
murderer and torture of someone cutting
their head off.
The whole thing is crazy,
but it's just,
it's still something that people do
where they're trying to get attention
and they're trying to entertain or
trying to be shocking that just,
it's [inaudible].
It's a continuation of,
of uh,
trying to be in people's,
uh,
frontal lobe.
You know,
it's like people in Hollywood at some
point just want to stay in Hollywood and
I feel like that's what she,
she does a lot.
I want to stay,
I want to do something controversial on
the fucking New Year's eve hosts that
she does or whatever so she can stay in
Hollywood.
It's such this great,
this great director once told me that
the sat is never that.
Imagine if this is a,
if this is an actor and and uh,
as if we're the sun and the sun and the
earth and moving,
moving around one another.
Just like an actor in a spotlight.
It says if the spotlight has is on the
actor at some point,
but when it moves away,
if he actually tried to move towards it
is when it becomes sad.
When,
when it shifted out of your line of
sight,
when,
when your work and your progress has
shifted as if your time perhaps maybe
coming to a close as far as it's worth
when you are continuing to search for
it,
there's nothing more desperate and more
obvious.
He's like,
you can always see when someone's
hunting for it again,
it looks sad.
It looks,
it looks desperate.
It's also contrary to the very reason
people like you in the first place.
Like people like you because you're
doing things they enjoy exact,
doing good work.
You're doing good comedy,
you make it a good movie.
Whatever the fuck you do,
making a good song.
That's why they like you.
They don't want to like you because
you're trying to get attention or that
you're trying to get people to,
to just,
well,
I mean,
what is that?
what,
what do you get out of holding ahead?
Like what kind of attention do you get?
Like what did she say?
Go girl.
Like,
yeah,
we're with you fucking him.
Kill him.
Like you're,
there's people that do things like that
and they could have easily been right
there,
might be left.
They could have easily been,
right.
It's a,
it's a way of thinking and you get that
way of thinking and then you program
yourself,
you get locked into this predetermined
pattern of behavior.
Like all right wing people,
like a giant percentage of them have
like an established series of,
uh,
of,
of opinions about certain things that we
count on because they're the right,
right.
Like,
like abortion or even it used to be gay
marriage was one of them.
There's always a bunch of them that are
just climate change is one of them.
Like it's like halfway there,
like maybe 25% of them hardcore on the
right.
Where's the left?
Climate change is almost 100% accepted
without it.
Without question.
It's weird.
I counted these,
these ideas become right or left ideas
who logged them into the database of
which side do they belong on?
It's talking points.
People on Fox News started talking about
it.
People agree with it.
They liked convenient things.
That's,
it's a cycle.
It comes,
goes,
don't worry about it,
but we need is jobs.
And then they run with that and it's a
tall,
it's this,
this predetermined pattern that people
just love to fall into.
Man.
It's weird.
It's creepy.
That should no longer be separation of
just permanent party.
It shouldn't be.
You're always left an always right.
That's so fucked up.
Too Vulnerable.
I feel it myself.
I feel myself.
The urge to be a part of groups.
I do it all the time.
We all do.
Right?
It,
that's uh,
that's,
that is nature and habit,
right?
You,
everyone wants to belong to a community.
That's why fraternities exist.
That's why when you join a gym,
you start to eat in the moment you join
a gym.
You start to see people repetitively
that you know,
and you,
it starts off with a,
Hey,
what's that?
That guy you see all the time.
Then it's,
hey man,
I've out it.
Oh yeah.
And then it becomes a relationship you
create because it's communal because,
oh,
we both do this thing.
We both enjoy ICU.
Often we do this thing,
we create tribes.
We Love Haciendas.
We like to be a part of our little
tribe.
And when it gets infiltrated it you,
you become vulnerable.
You feel like you're,
the walls are weakening.
It's almost like when the word
gentrification,
gentrification really just means a tr,
uh,
tribes area has been compromised.
You know,
it's like this has been this for so
long.
When white people or people of privilege
or money move into anywhere,
they're trying to overtake that tribe.
That's why there's so much backlash.
That's why people fucking get so angry
about neighborhoods turning over quote
unquote,
cause they're like,
what can be ours?
That's,
it's such a fucking delicate thing
because you're like,
you can't stop that.
You're never going to stop that.
Well not only that,
it's there's a game being played in your
part of it because you're paying rent.
Yup.
And there's a game being played.
Your part of it,
when you're working,
you're getting paid for your time during
the,
I know you have to decide what you're
going to do with that time and you might
feel very stuck in this game that you're
at right now where you paying this guy
for rent and you're working for that guy
and he's giving you a certain amount of
money and it all kind of evens out at
the end.
There's nothing leftover,
but you're still playing a game.
This guy's playing the game too,
but he's been playing it for 35 years
and his games,
I buy houses,
right?
And I sell them to white people and a,
I'm going to keep playing that fucking
game cause this is all legal and this is
why you pay me rent.
Stupid.
It's a fucking,
we know the game,
but the game is,
I'm 30 years ahead of the game than you
and you know,
I'm a 70 year old guy with a fucking
pocket protector filled with pens and
I've got a bunch of apartment buildings
all over the place and I flipped those
fuckers.
There's a lot of those guys out there
like why this gentrification thing?
I know it's uncomfortable with people.
They like,
we're losing the old neighborhood.
Like let's go back to the fucking tps.
Let's go back to the cave.
We lost the old caves,
man.
We're,
we're not saying what she moved to other
case.
It's going to happen.
They just shift.
Things change.
You can't hold them back.
You can't decide.
No,
we want this neighborhood to stay
shitty.
You know?
Or we want this neighborhood to be all
Puerto Rican.
Well listen,
sometimes it doesn't work that way.
Some people die and New People move in.
Do you really care of Swedish people
move in your neighborhood?
You know,
we're losing chinatown.
What do we do?
I you going to be okay.
Is it okay if they live here or people
that there's going to be changed,
it's going to come and go.
You can't control it and you can't
control it based on this stall.
Gia,
this is always been East Harlem's fat
finest show.
Slovaki place.
We have to keep it like,
no we don't.
No,
no one has to do anything.
I do love East Harlem Harlem's famous
Lavaca place.
I will say to know what that is not even
a thing.
I'm searching for a word,
but it was like that.
And that happens like when,
when restaurants and people get furious.
Yeah.
So it doesn't have to fucking keep the
restaurant open.
Stupid.
I was just up in the change up in
Seattle and these guys,
a,
these Costa Rican guys I started talking
to at the,
at the Fremont brewery were telling me
about this great Caribbean food place up
the street.
And I said,
uh,
what makes it so great?
And he's like,
you know,
it's just the recipe because a,
the guy that used to own it was this
great,
this Cuban guy,
he's just brilliant chef and he key,
uh,
got sued for illegal wage wage
garnishing these illegal employees that
couldn't speak English.
She had sued to the city,
shut them the fuck down.
Some other fucking white rich guy came
in,
bought the recipes from the guy,
took to help him out with his lawsuit,
still runs just as good.
I like it can be done if someone does it
correctly.
He bought the recipes.
He was like,
Eh,
the mistake,
I think when people buy a bar or buy a
place,
they think they're buying the place.
Now.
There's more,
there's more than just the brick and
mortar.
There's more to it than that.
So he knew the food success was because
of this guy,
the way he did it,
but you can't just like,
it's not just a Cuban restaurant or a
Caribbean restaurant.
He was like,
I want to do it exactly how you did it.
So he paid for him to give him those
recipes so he could just the recipe just
to show him how he was cooking and she
would cook that.
He paid him for the recipes,
not to know the rest of the details,
but that is to get it back to where it
was and this dude from Costa Rica was
like still the same.
I fucking love it.
Wow.
He was just a couple of white guys that
are back there now.
He's the same food.
It doesn't,
doesn't mean that I don't appreciate
people that live in these neighborhoods
that are being forced out and you'd have
to get a new place to live and you can't
afford it.
You can't afford to live in the
neighborhood anymore because people are
buying it up.
I get it.
I understand that it sucks,
but ultimately it's probably good for
everybody.
It's definitely good for the
neighborhood.
The neighborhood's going to get like
these nice houses now and people are
going to move in.
They're going to have that.
It's going to be more value.
If you did buy a place,
if you did take the risk and bought a
place,
that place can be worth more money.
Now I know maybe you couldn't buy a
place.
I go,
well,
it's hard to buy a place when I get
paid.
I get it,
but you don't have to do that,
right.
I know.
You feel like you have to do that and
they can come up with a bunch of excuses
and everybody would argue all day long
about white privilege and you're lucky
and this and that,
but the bottom line is you're not in a
cage.
All right?
If you're not in a cage and you're out
there doing something,
you could figure out a way.
Maybe it's a month from now,
maybe it's six months from now to
transition into something else.
Figure your way through the maze.
Right.
We don't all start at the same spot in
the maze.
Nope.
Agreed.
Could it,
but don't ever complain about your spot
in the maze.
Just figure,
figure your way through that thing.
Right?
You're in the mace.
Yeah.
It sucks.
Definitely hard.
Not Easy.
Keep moving.
Don't jam.
This up with your tears.
You Fuck,
keep moving.
You don't understand capitalism and
that's why I'm a socialist and okay,
just keep moving though.
You don't,
you know,
just talking too much and not move in
and I'll do it.
Yeah.
There's not enough happening here that's
complaining about other things
happening.
I get it.
It's not good.
The climate change agreement is a
terrible thing to leave.
It's a bad thing to leave.
His own daughter told them not to leave,
but I never liked [inaudible] so we got
to get out of Paris.
She did it.
She has owned his own daughter was like,
this is a bad idea.
This guy's crazy.
He didn't want he and science.
He is perfectly out of his fucking mind.
He's going against science.
The scientists are saying,
Hey,
we've got to reduce emissions 100% we're
polluting the air.
We breathe.
We're ruining the very air that we need
to exist on.
Yup.
Now that true,
don't agree.
We bike.
We bought new air.
There's show by Jay.
Have you ever seen a chair?
There is.
Maybe he's doing this because he's about
to move.
Move into position to use one of those
gigantic building sized air filter
things.
Maybe it's going to have a trump air
filter filters.
Set them up in every city.
You could all go back and buy diesel
trucks and no one's going to care
anymore.
We're going to clean that air.
Nice.
It's kind of like idiocracy do you ever
see that movie I ever saw that movie,
Dude.
It was that kind of thing where the
future is like,
they don't drink water anymore.
They be convinced by this,
this like gatorade type drink where it's
like,
this is better than water and people
like it's gotta be so everyone fucking
drinks it.
The big sense.
I feel like it's better than water.
If you can convince enough people what
it is,
people will get on board.
Regard blind faith.
I'm trying to talk about that on stage
right now about blind.
We have so much blind faith.
Like I had a fucking,
I would at the gas station to get this
thing.
I had a Brownie.
It was like,
uh,
pow,
you know,
protein packed Brownie or whatever.
I just trusted it.
That's all real.
I don't fucking know what the next is.
Probably just a bullshit ass Brownie,
but it's packed with protein.
Yeah.
If you actually got the real statistics
on it,
it's probably,
gosh,
yeah,
there it is.
Craved.
It's got electrolytes.
It's who's brilliant and it's crazy.
What was the name of the stuff?
What was it called?
Does it say what it was called?
The g the juice.
It was like,
but it looked like gatorade.
oh,
they were watering their plants with it
and shit.
Nothing was alive anymore.
But out of the sink would come this
fucking gatorade type looking drink.
[inaudible] that's right.
Bronto thirst.
Muda lunar.
That's hilarious.
I need to watch that movie.
Click on that picture,
uh,
to the up just all the way over down at
the left.
That one.
Yeah.
Look at that.
That's what the world has become.
That makes sense.
You see the size of that Costco.
That's hilarious.
That could happen.
Totally.
That's all totally possible.
Have you been watching this handmaid's
tale?
No.
What does that,
no,
have you know about this,
it on Hulu man was a book written.
Um,
I want to say 20 years ago,
uh,
it's Elizabeth Moss is the star of it.
It's essentially about,
um,
if world war three broke out and we
became like an ultimate police state and
there was like a sub government that
took over and we went back to
essentially biblical times when women
who were fertile were used for the rich
as handmaids for making babies.
Whoa,
dude.
It's fucking trippiest shit.
Whoa.
You got to watch it,
bro.
You will.
It's based on modern time.
Yes.
It takes place in modern time as if
world war three broke out.
I don't want to give you too many
details,
but then two,
we're under a police state.
So these handmaids,
these fertile women who are of
lower socioeconomic status,
they must wear these things and abide by
their masters,
which are the wealthy one percenters of
the world who own these fertile women
because their wives are infertile.
So they must repopulate this new
community.
Whoa,
dude.
It's fucking right up your alley.
It's insanely good.
But it was a book that was written.
That's a total possibility.
Well,
that's what I do.
It's getting so much love.
In fact,
some of the parallels in the show of
what's going on in society now and some
of the commentary cause this was shot
prior to the election.
It's so specific.
I mean that's why people are falling in
love with it because they're like this
is creepily real.
Like it's almost,
you know,
I think with what,
especially from a for,
for what I've heard from women's
perspective,
you know like taking the fear of women's
rights being removed as far as things
like planned parenthood or,
or what have you,
the choices of your own fucking body.
I think there's so much echoed in the
show that it feels creepily real where
it's like you could one day just go like
they do in one of the scenes without
giving anything away.
It's like all the women are fired today.
Well you know that I ran of today is
nothing like I ran of like the 1960s no.
Have you ever seen like the difference
between I ran then and now?
No they became when I think when it was,
when the shop took no,
when the ayatollah took over.
Cause the ayatollah was a religious
figure and he took over and the change
of the country,
I'm,
I'm terrible with Iranian history.
So if you listen to this and you're
upset that I'm getting it wrong,
Iranians would fucking piss essentially.
They used to dress like much more free.
Yeah,
look at it is like much more
Westernized.
It's like the seventies in the seventies
yeah.
Looked like seventies the United States.
I mean,
and then shit changed.
And now if you go there today,
I mean look,
the Middle East is with a shiny example
of what is possible in 2017 as far as
like suppression.
Her shirt is there.
Ah,
you're dead if you'd wear that.
No big old titties.
It's chocolate.
Chocolate.
Yeah,
but you ended up yet,
right.
She'd be fucking slain for now.
They have to cover their head.
I mean they have like religious scarf
laws and you know what's really crazy is
there better than like Saudi Arabia.
I mean,
Saudi Arabia's what you can and can't do
today.
I mean,
you're essentially like a second class
citizen if you're a woman below.
I don't think there's they allowed to
drive now.
They changed that.
I mean there's,
I know there's some people that are
trying to change that.
There's some people that are progressive
over there that are trying to change
that.
They're straight property man.
That's what that they view him as a
straight numbers.
The idea that you have to keep your head
covered,
you have to wear the those,
those robes and the garb and and then
this women that are trying to say that
that's a source of empowerment.
There's a bunch of crazy people out
there just like there was always uncle
Tom's like during the civil rights
movement and just like people are just,
there's always going to be like black
guys for trump.
Zoe's contrary is always there's going
to be women that said that the wearing
the,
how do you say it?
His job,
he jogged by three job.
That's a,
it's for women to fuck it is you have to
wear it.
It's a religious symbol of
depression.
How could you,
how could you,
I understand being born into something
and not knowing any other way.
I do understand that.
Like I get it too,
right?
But at the same time,
or born into and being convinced that
this is the way that it should be.
But when you see freedom of the world,
when you see the freedom of the world
that we're all born fucking naked and
free to be these things.
I don't know why there isn't a little
bit more of a click that goes,
why did these women and other places
have more freedom?
Because w because the goal of any sort
of religious fucking constriction is
questioning,
right?
So if you question it,
you're automatically fucked.
But if you question it enough where you
research and you look and you find out
and you learn,
I would assume you would become
enchanted with the idea of being free,
of just wanting to not have someone
fucking tell you where you can walk,
what you can do.
That makes sense.
But when you connect an ideology with,
with God and with the idea of the divine
right,
that's the ultimate,
that's the reason to stick around.
Like the end of the day,
it's clothes.
Clothes are made by people.
If you're telling me that God is saying
that you have to wear some kind of
clothes and not other kinds of clothes.
I'm calling bullshit.
Yeah.
Who's the people?
You're not talking to God.
He's never talked to you and told you to
wear that.
This is crazy.
And when you have an ideology where
you're trapped into dressing a certain
way or wearing certain clothes or
wearing a certain emblem or some sort of
assemble your trapped by the mind of a
human being,
that is the mine of a human being.
They've created a pattern that they want
you to not deviate from whatsoever.
I want you to walk around like this.
We're going to cover this and you're
gonna wear these and maybe have one of
those on your neck and maybe a certain
amount of beads that symbolizes your,
you're single.
You're not bullshit.
This is somebody,
this is by a person.
This is some cult shit to guy and 100%
has nothing to do with God like you.
You would be serving God more to be free
and naked like that.
God created you.
If God is real,
he didn't make clothes.
God doesn't have any stock and Levi's.
God's not making burgers.
God,
we'd like you to be naked if they're,
if that's real,
if God just lets or wear whatever the
fuck you want because it's all there for
humans to where like if people are
making clothes,
they're making clothes for people,
they should be able to wear whatever the
fuck they want.
If I was God,
I would say,
yeah,
that makes sense.
Where would we like stay warm?
You know,
don't,
don't die I guess.
Yeah.
I think the only reason I'm just going
to cover your hair,
why this is nonsense.
This is people talk and someone said
that a person said it.
We believe in it.
Well the priest must trust like a
wizard.
Why?
Why does he have to dress like that?
No one dresses like the pope anymore.
Why is the pope dress like the pope?
Shit.
The fucking get the suit off.
Someone loved wizardry so much.
They were like,
I gotta we gotta fucking keep that and
we got to keep somebody in that.
I always think that when I was a kid and
I'd have to go to church,
I'm like,
why does he have to wear that stupid
fucking collar?
So selvans so silly to me?
What does that collar,
he has to wear that collar,
so I know that he's real.
And the one,
oh,
he's got the thing on.
He's got the preschooler.
Look at that.
Ooh,
that pope,
he's got wings like,
look,
he's in a a window,
an MTV video in the 80s what does that,
that once,
but that one sponsored by red bull.
Is that blowing in the wind?
Is that what it is?
That's the answer.
My friend,
that's his wing and the wind is blowing
in the wind.
Catholicism was one of the,
and this is what I was raised in,
sort of a wizard wizard hat show.
Just for you look above my,
my favorite.
That is so funny.
And why is that any more outrageous than
that fucking thing?
Yeah.
That's even more weird.
Look at that giant crucifix.
Look at this fucking hat.
Oh my God,
they're so silly.
They're the silliest people.
The fact that anybody says,
yeah,
that guy.
Keep that picture up there.
Don't change the that clothes.
Go full screen with that.
What in the fuck are we looking at here?
This guy's got a three foot tall hat on.
It's all gold and studied in ornate like
wouldn't you think that God want you to
be humble?
If you're a servant of God,
he really supposed to be covered in
gold.
Gold is gold.
Fucking pimp rang.
Guy Represent God with my nugget ring
because that nugget,
kiss it.
This is a Persian rug draped around his
shoulders,
his fucking this elaborate work on that
robe thing that he's got on.
It's so preposterous.
The idea that God would want you to
dress like that.
You know what I always think of when I
see like big elaborate things like this
is at the end of the day he's got to
like take that off to take a shit and
it's like so sad to like take that off
and drape it on the ground.
You know what I mean?
When he's sitting there,
backs it on his lower back,
like wipe,
did a terrible job of cleaning up.
So the,
the bottom of it has a little shit stain
on it,
but he's still the pope,
so he's bringing it up to the sink and
he's trying to wash it in the sink and
it's just sort of walk wet.
Brown is trying to get that little shit
streak out of the bottom of this thing.
We call him the pope,
but don't say that.
Respectful to my beliefs.
Your disrespect.
Yes.
If this is what you believe,
I believe this guy is the fucking guy
who's talking for God.
Come on,
man.
I'm not saying there's no god.
What I'm saying,
we have to be very wary of people.
They're just people and cults and people
and the patterns of thinking and
behaving that they want you to engage
in.
This is what we're looking at here.
This,
there's two people holding this guy's
fucking coat.
These two guys who are dressed like gay
matadors,
like giant Golden crusted gay matadors
and they're holding on to his cape.
They're fighting the devil and they're
walking with him as he walks around with
his giant staff of magic.
He's got a wizard's wand.
It's a Goddamn Gandalf wand.
He's dressed like a wizard and he's got
a staff like,
why isn't that glowing?
Why isn't there a lightening bolt going
from that up until the storm cloud that
it looks like the level of Cape bitches
way above the other guys.
Like that's a graduation for them to be
Cape Pitch is real big.
That's a big deal.
Cape Bitch is a huge position in these
guys is to Cape pitches the guy and the
left's probably that annoying.
It's fuck.
I bet he tells a lot of long stories.
Probably guessed the pope alone.
He's like,
you know,
just wanted to tell you about my cousin.
And uh,
his,
uh,
that is a safe in the Lord and you know,
I think right now he's not getting to
Guba.
Is this the first pope that's okay with
gay marriage?
Isn't that what he said?
Yeah,
he's got to say this is the first one
that was like whatever he tossed out to
thrown too.
He's got a normal chair.
Does he?
Yes.
That's kind of cool.
It is kind of cool,
but I think that was probably a joint
effort.
They like look as a pc move,
it was a politically fucking car.
Doors behind me.
There's a thousand kids back there
waiting to suck your Dick.
Okay,
we've got to make this right though.
We've got damage.
We're still gonna do plenty of kid
fucking,
one of you saw the pope,
a throughway of chair and got one of
those like uh,
the medicine balls to sit on.
You know what I mean?
Like he started,
he started really getting,
he had standing desks and shit.
He started getting like corporate
America.
What is the,
what do you show me here,
Jamie?
Is it the pope won't be all the new one.
The popemobile,
the new one doesn't have bulletproof
glass anymore.
The last pope was like,
I know they want to kill me.
I'm hiding liquor.
They don't even need glasses all the way
up because his back arches silver so
much.
He doesn't sit up straight so they don't
need high glass.
It's like a child window.
I wonder if that is different colors of
glass because I would imagine you want
to keep the head shots from coming down
from the roof.
Totally.
I mean,
if someone's going to shoot that dude,
but this guy doesn't even thinking he
was going to shoot him and he's like,
if someone wants to shoot me,
they'll fucking shoot.
Man.
It's done.
Yeah,
he's,
he's exposed.
Is it a Benz?
It's a Benz.
Oha.
God.
Oh,
he said he left Mercedes more baby.
Jesus loves the G Wagon Kid.
Like the other old one's a Benz to
little light proof one.
I bequeath my son a Mercedes Benz boy.
There's nothing that says faith like
driving around in a bulletproof fish
tank.
Right?
I mean that just shows you,
you really have a belief that God has a
plan,
can run flat,
half inch thick steel plate,
lightweight Kevlar Armor,
God,
three inch composite plastic glass that
was spoke with an explosive Jesus
Christ.
It's five tons.
That's 10,000 pound truck.
That's crazy.
15 miles a gallon.
That's very efficient.
And that is really here to 66 seconds.
What sets quick,
dude,
wait a minute.
How's that even possible?
That's bullshit.
And get that fucking thing on top gear.
Run a stop sign of Stopwatch with that.
That's no way that gets zero to 60 in
six seconds.
Going to rice.
The pope mobile first is the king of
Saudi Arabia is mobile.
That's hilarious.
Dude.
You sound like the guy from,
I'm not top gear.
It's like fifth gear or something like
that.
Yeah,
yeah.
Got It.
Yeah.
What's the other one?
That's who I thought you sound just like
that's creepy.
The Pope Mobile.
It's something I like about British car.
Uh,
analysts.
Oh dude meet so much once they take the
piss out of everything.
I like how self deprecating there when
they shit on cars.
It's my favorite.
Jeremy Clarkson's the best cause it's
hilarious the way he shits on things.
There's so much fun and I just like to
see fucking friends dump on each other.
On TV.
Yeah.
It's fun to watch people dump on each
other.
Well,
especially in this day and age.
So that would be considered bullying.
Bullying their friend.
That's really rude to pick on him like
that.
Yeah.
They just go after each other constant.
It's fun show.
I probably,
they have a beer afterwards.
It's fine.
It's fucking fine to stay playing
characters like James May would be
captain slow.
Yeah.
I love that shit.
They fucked up when they canceled that
show.
Jeremy Clarkson punched some producer
and they cancel the show and fired them
if they knocked out a tooth or
assumption like that.
Well,
he's drunk.
It's what happens.
You want to hang out in a big crazy
drunk dude.
You want to talk shit,
Talk Shit,
Talk Shit.
Get hit that you guys are all drinking.
That's how it goes down.
You guys at a bar fight,
six of the most normal thing happened
and he apologized afterwards and the
other guy accepted it.
It was just they fucked up and then why
can't that be the end of it?
I don't know man.
They have a new one they're doing now
and Matt Leblanc from friends is on it
now.
You see a big car guy?
Yes.
Oh Wow.
He's a giant car guy and he's a knight.
He's a nice guy and I don't know
anything about him,
but I didn't know that it comes off like
a good car guy.
It's not that he's bad,
it's just that God Damn Jeremy,
Jeremy Clarkson is a fucking icon.
He's a maniac icon,
but Matt Leblanc is a,
is he a car collector?
Does he have is he loves cars.
I don't know to what extent,
but he definitely loves cars.
He knows how to drive to,
he drives on the show like he's driving
a porsche nine 11 are he can rip it.
He knows what he's doing.
That's good.
Yeah,
he can drive.
It's so,
so he must have some experience,
some real track time experience,
but the Guy Chris Harris who's on it,
he's been on the podcast for that guys,
he's my favorite.
He's all the guys out there that are
reviewing cars now and he knows so much
about them.
Like he really understands like the,
the geometry and the physics behind it.
Like with the suspension,
they can tell you what they've changed,
what they've improved,
would it feels like and what's being
lost in this.
That's always impressive to me.
To have a bevy of knowledge like that.
My Dad's worked in the automotive
aftermarket industry for,
so my Stepdad,
he was my dad.
But what does he do dude?
For years and years,
he worked for,
uh,
the ever famous turtle wax carwash.
He was the president of sales for turtle
wax to sell,
towed away.
And then now he the standard,
the gold standard and now he works.
Uh,
but the turtle fired him.
The shell fired him.
Fuck,
fuck them.
And then he works for this company
called Haynes,
who's out of la out of Britain.
And they,
they are one of the last remaining
companies that makes zero,
uh,
a to z manuals on hand building
vehicles.
Wow.
So if you want to hand build kit cars or
you want to literally build a car from
fucking scratch,
most of their sales go to like
mechanics,
auto body shops,
but they're also,
they own the rights to fictional,
how do I say this?
The only rights of fictional mechanics,
uh,
fictional mechanisms that in our film
world or real like the fucking
Millennium Falcon,
they own the rights to how to build a
Millennium Falcon from scratch.
Whoa.
And they sell that manual.
That's a real fucking manual.
You can buy net fucking crazy.
That is crazy.
They had that for a bunch of cars.
Kit cars are pretty wild to kick arse.
I was always fascinated with my buddy's
dad used to build mgs all the time and
let us fuck around.
And um,
and I was fascinated with mgs cause he,
he loved him.
I mean he was just dope English kit car
that was for sale really recently.
And you would do it,
buy it
and then once you got it over here,
then you had to put an engine in it.
Yeah.
Dude,
sell it to you with no engine.
Right.
You've got to bite you.
Will you build a first and they drop it
in there.
Jumped into,
but it wasn't that,
it was different.
It was,
it wasn't a total kit car.
Like you start from scratch,
you attach the suspension.
You're right.
It wasn't that.
It was like they would sell it to you as
a,
as a car with no engine and then you
would have to put the engine in.
It's a dope.
That's a current,
the name.
It's like it's right there,
but there's so many,
so many blocks I could,
there's only so many blocks I could fit
in that framework.
Right?
Yeah.
You would get like a parameter and you
know like a v eight ls one or something
like that and try to put it in there.
God Damn it.
Noble,
Noble.
That's what it's called.
It's called the noble.
It's a dope look and Carmen and guys,
I think they're just,
you know,
you don't want to have a certain amount
of horsepower could take,
but I didn't think,
I don't think he'd have the drive train
either.
I think he had to have the ad,
the drive train as well.
I think essentially it was just a frame
and the doors and all that shit.
It must've just been parts from other
third party car manufacturers and they,
they got whatever parts they could it
put them together.
You built that and then the engine is
what from anywhere at all?
I think you'd have to just know how to
do it.
I mean there's a whole market now or
they buy engines and then they put him
in older cars so they'll buy like,
uh,
one of the big companies that does it as
a company called icon.
And um,
uh,
what they do is they take,
like,
uh,
69 bronco and they strip it down.
They put the car back together again
with a modern suspension and then they
take a 2017 Ford Mustang engine and
enshrine the Bronco.
Yeah.
So they put totally modern brakes,
totally modern suspension,
bronco engine.
What?
But the Bronco Engines,
uh,
19,
you know,
a 2017,
uh,
for,
for tea,
it's called the coyote motor.
It's a really high end,
high tech motor.
It's a really nice motor.
So you have like this old school costs.
So they have like kits,
like they do that with ls one for
[inaudible].
And maybe you and I talked about that
someone was saying that they were taking
classic methe Ford might have been doing
this themselves where they take classic
mustangs and put New Mustang engines in
old classic Mustang bodies.
No,
we were talking about that.
You and I were talking about that.
There's a guy who's got a page on
instagram where he did it and it's,
I think it's a,
I think it's called gt 500 super swap.
So he's got a somewhat,
Ma had a shelby shelby gt 500 yeah,
from 2012 and he put that body of a 1969
car over the 2012 car.
Fuck.
So it's the best of both worlds.
That's it right there.
It is so beautiful.
It's so beautiful.
Wow.
So this guy nailed it and,
but he's only done one car.
What does,
he was like doing it.
I thought there was a company that was
doing it,
but apparently it's just this one dude
who's done this.
What does that run for?
Did it say what he's selling those for?
I don't think he's selling it.
No,
he just wants to fucking shit.
He just did his shit.
He sell the fuck out of that thing.
You should sell the fuck out of that
look.
That'd be what?
I had a 2012 gt 500 [inaudible] who was
a great car.
That's another one though.
That's a different color.
Oh,
it's different car for helping a
friend's house.
Six eight Mustang.
Three three K.
Ooh,
that's a beautiful car.
33,000 miles is nothing.
That is nothing.
That's a beautiful card.
God,
those things were classic.
Those 1960s mustangs are some of the
most beautiful shapes ever.
And to take that and put a uh,
I think 2012 the GT 500 packed 550
horsepower.
Yeah.
Almost 600 isn't that crazy that this
won't be in the future,
that like in the future,
like no one's going to have a lot of
these current cars now we're just going
to go by the wayside.
Like there's only so many cars that will
stick around as classics from the,
you know,
early two thousands era.
Yeah.
There's not going to be any like driving
yourself in a hundred years.
No,
it's over like that.
That idea is fucking dead.
So we'll have that's a noble.
Yeah.
Well that's it right there and not a
dope car cut out.
It has a Ferrari body a little bit of
sort of like,
like an old,
um,
more like what is the car I'm thinking
of the [inaudible] used to look like
that.
Yeah,
the load as fast.
That's why like the loaded,
the cool lotus is of like,
wow,
look at that.
Oh that's a newer one,
Huh?
Wow.
That's tight.
That's a,
that's a digital image.
We can't hear you.
You know our website is pretty cool.
Where's it said Italy,
right?
Is that where they're out of British?
I think they don't have airbags or they
didn't have airbags.
Yeah.
Cause if you go on one 80,
fuck that doesn't live there.
Get an airbag to me and just looks like
a steering wheel.
You Die.
You Die,
I guess.
Yeah,
because think it's too complicated.
Yeah.
Fuck it.
Fuck that airbag thing.
I wouldn't,
I would want to find out like now that
looks like it might have one.
Actually I never an airbag nuts horn.
That's a horn.
Yeah.
Fuck it.
I think that was the problem.
I think they hadn't gone through all of
the fcs.
What is it?
What would be the,
what is that,
the name of that now?
I can't think.
The FAA not at the uh,
Ihsa safety mode.
Yeah.
Ihsa yeah,
that's fucking really sexy looking.
They're looking at all the carbon fiber
in there.
God,
those seats look amazing.
That he break is up,
but it doesn't look like it stick.
That's just what you put your app in
your asshole.
Oh,
that's where you get fucked.
when you,
is there one of the front two,
can you suck one way?
You fuck.
You can't be greedy.
That wouldn't be noble.
Look at the inside of that thing cause
he'd go back to that coffee.
So he does know that that's all push
button.
There is no fucking sticking on manual.
No manual transmission.
That's what they're all using now.
When those exotic Italian cars and
everything,
everything is paddle shifts.
Now.
We'll look at this.
Did you ever,
do you see this?
I,
I had this,
uh,
this was for a thing.
Hold on,
let me show you.
I'm really bummed out the new NSX.
Look at that fun thing.
Huh?
I rented that for the shoot that we were
doing all that's as the old magnum Pi
Ferrari man.
No,
that's a,
a couple years later it was three 55 Gt.
Right.
It's a similar design though.
Jon Lovitz had one of those.
I drove that once.
Dude.
John Level let me drive his car that
year of Ferrari.
Uh,
or,
well,
not just that year,
but I mean that was when Ferrari's,
uh,
one was down,
you know,
for our,
he's one is down instead of up reverses
up,
but one is down two,
three,
four,
five.
But that thing was so much fucking fun.
Look at that.
Oh,
that's right.
I forgot that they had it backwards.
It goes backwards.
1995 was,
I think the year that Ferrari,
somebody wrote Pontiac Fiero,
dope,
Pontiac,
fiero.
But do you remember when they used to
have those kid cards go pontiac,
fiero and put like Ferrari bodies on the
outside,
like a fake Ferrari body?
Yeah,
it's pretty great.
So much work.
Somebody just showed me,
uh,
I forgot about Lamborghini coon tosh and
it was like there something gear
anniversary.
And they just are rereleasing the coon
Tashas.
Do you remember those cars too?
That was when I remember thinking that
that was the only car that I ever
thought was worthy of any amount of
money that it was worth.
That was like,
that's the fun.
Any dime that thing is fucking worth.
I went by that fucking thing.
Do you remember he was such a low bar.
Rocky drove that car rocky for what he's
done.
And so he had like,
there's a crazy scene.
Handsome basket was boxing shoes.
My boxing shoes.
A hilarious,
that's the coon tosh baby is beautiful
man back then.
Um,
but there's a,
uh,
like it's literally a music video where
they play,
where he's in the car and the music
starts playing when he's cruel.
He's driving.
It's so corny.
So cheesy.
Yeah.
Can we no easy way out and give you some
volume on this.
People at home can hear this or no south
Paulino trouble plate was
so he's,
he's driving around and he's thinking of
Dolph lundgren kicking his ass while
he's driving a
Lamborghini.
So Manchin,
uh,
it's so silly.
Oh Dude.
He's the fucking man.
No smiles at all.
Not Happy.
Not excited about it.
Yeah,
it took a deep breath.
I'll just call them.
I'll just go to think about what my life
was going.
The best part about it is to do this
movie or to do this fight.
He had to go to old school methods and
move to the fucking woods and was
carrying logs around and running this
chopping down fucking trees.
Dude.
That's how you get in shape.
Fucking name,
man.
Shit,
Shit Woods.
Go out here chopped wood.
I got to Chubb would then I'm going to
fuck you and then
I'm gonna go whoop.
Carry a log to this.
No.
Shut this off for a die shit.
I can't do it anymore.
Those movies are great though,
Dude.
So fucking great.
Window into time.
I know a return when it was okay to be
ridiculous.
And Helmet.
Yeah man.
Now it's,
everything gets checked and balanced so
much that everything is like has to be
proven by the studio.
Back then that was an idea.
He,
I'm sure he was like would a foam drug
when around thinking about the fight and
make a music video and they're like
great,
we got an extra hundred grand at burn
this week.
Let's fucking do it.
Dig.
We have a time lapse of all the shitty
moments of my life.
All the things that worked didn't work
out.
Can you go show a first time a family
member died?
We'd go back to the first time I have
the Kista Adrian.
Okay.
Yeah.
Rock.
We have some of our own scenes planned.
[inaudible] that fuck.
I know my people
he does though.
I mean he sneaked out action movies.
He's kicking people's asses and he's in
his seventies duty.
Can I tell you the one I did a fucking
benefit.
Uh,
I did like the standup at a better
benefit for Tom Arnold for this thing.
This charity he runs and sly was there.
Cause there,
they've known each other for years.
And uh,
as I got off stage,
I walked past him and I didn't want to
like,
you know,
I didn't want to be like hey and fucking
call attention.
But as I walked by he goes very,
very good and I was like,
that's fucking awesome.
I was like,
that's enough for me.
He did very,
very good.
I interviewed him once for the UFC.
There was some thing was going on.
He was,
some movie was coming out,
I forget what movie it was,
but he wanted,
he was fun.
He was easy.
Does it take expendable is,
I don't remember.
I don't think it was,
he's the thing.
It was another movie.
I forget what movie it was,
but uh,
he was super like self deprecating and
easy to get along with.
That's how you stay fucking on earth.
Man said something about his mom that
someone yelled something out.
Like someone like cackled them yelled,
somebody goes,
oh there's my mom.
She's up there
like he's quick.
But he was like a genuinely nice guy.
Like just friendly,
easy going.
Like one of the biggest movie stars in
the world in the world,
but like was like,
Hey,
what's up?
What's up?
How are you doing?
It was pretty cool.
I liked it.
It was nice.
Well that's what we were saying before
we jumped on at the level of,
of what fame means to be an
international movie star now has changed
so much that like while I was in Japan
and I'm in Japan,
I bring up my instagram cause these
young Japanese kids are wanting to like
see my social media and he sees the blue
check mark of the verified shit and he's
like famous,
famous and I'm like,
no,
no dude,
no.
I was like,
and they give that to any fucking
asshole now.
And they're all like laughing cause
they're like,
well what,
what do you do?
And I'm like,
ah,
comedian,
comedian.
And their faces were kind of like
comedian and one guy goes,
will smith?
And I go,
yeah,
will smith.
That's exactly,
that's exactly,
that's exactly right.
But then you realize
level of when you say what's famous
around the world,
you're like slight when you say like who
was a famous,
I don't know if we have like I don't,
I don't know if the rest of the world
knows as many of our stars as they used
to.
It used to be you are an international
star and that's what made you a mega
star.
Now it's Kinda like you can be famous
here in film and not really be known at
all over there.
I mean you could then,
but there was,
so I feel like we were pumping out
international stars at one point.
They were like,
uh,
just a bevy of international action
stars.
You know what I mean?
That just became in that era of sorts
and egg sly,
even like we were talking about John
Claude van Damme before this Seagal,
like all these like Willis,
like all these mega international
superstars because the action movies
were so big.
Now we've put that into fantasy film.
So now it's guardians of the galaxy.
Now it's any superhero movie that's
become it.
But I,
I miss the world of like,
why can't we have an action movie that
has isn't a comic book?
Where does that go?
Yeah,
we would need,
it would have to be like someone you
bill,
you'd have to be the rock.
But that's not me.
Like he could do it.
They can do it.
But the why,
why doesn't it exist?
Maybe people don't want those movies
anymore.
Fuck,
why not?
You have to have some sort of a metric
there.
They're judging this from right?
Like when they're making these movies.
I think it's because they made a couple
of seconds
near a movies.
I mean they made it a couple of comic
comic book films and they did so fucking
well that now we have a bevy of them
cause they know that there's such a big
market for it.
So I can't imagine you wouldn't want to
see another
diehard type dudes.
Yeah.
Why the fuck not?
Why haven't they done redone diehard?
They did see they go,
yeah,
but don't read it.
They redo diehard.
When did they didn't Redo it.
They just kept,
they're still doing it though.
It's,
Oh,
it's being done right now.
We're making another one,
right.
Who's,
who's the die hard?
Bruce Willis.
Get the fuck out.
Bruce Willis is not kept himself up.
It looks like you throw a punch and
shoulder would blow out.
Fucking owl.
They're really hurt.
I mean,
unless he's been working out since I
last checked in 2013 and then it says
future here.
Let's see.
It's all,
they started it in 2013.
That was the last one came out with,
did they try to do a TV show?
Is that what it was making another one
who was a die hard in 2013 with the
Justin Long I think was in it and his
daughter and
I'd fucking net doesn't sound at all
familiar,
but if you had to tell me too,
and I'm a Bruce Willis Fan.
I think Bruce Willis is awesome.
Shit.
I load,
if you had to tell me like,
when was his last movie?
I'd be like,
um,
I assume he's just popping by agron
shoot loads all over the place.
I don't know what,
what is his last fucking movie?
Die Hard.
Good Day to die hard.
Wow.
And who's The guy?
Two sides that Kevin Hart?
No.
Who is that dude?
Never seen that guy in my life.
It was just a guy that was on set.
Did anybody go to see that?
Wouldn't get an amd be 45% on rotten
tomatoes.
Wow.
Wait,
we can you go to box office Mojo and
look that up?
Will you look it up on box office Mojo,
Office Mojo?
There was go back.
Sorry.
Go back to the previous page.
What is box office Mojo?
It'll tell you like budget and I'll tell
you what it made here in international.
Look at that down there.
It says,
I know all the 92 million
box office.
It made 304 million.
Is that what it says?
So it fucking killed.
It did great.
Good.
Probably all all overseas.
How foreign sales?
Yeah,
go to box office Mojo.
It'll show you.
So maybe he's like one of the few guys
left that can still do that.
Yeah.
You know like Steven Seagal still sells
a ton of movies overseas.
Fuckload they do those,
uh,
straight to,
you know,
straight to video,
straight to DVD.
Cds did.
He makes tons of money.
He,
they've internationally sell the movie
before he even makes it.
Do you know that?
You know,
he's a Russian citizen.
I know.
I love,
I gave her a pass.
It's hilarious.
He's sticking around.
There you go.
Rushing passport.
There's a look at that as the proof.
It made 62 million here and a 237
overseas.
Wow.
International superstar did get that
paper Bros pay bruce.
That's amazing.
What do you think he walked away with?
Oh,
he took 10 upfront to make it.
He probably got a ton of money.
I don't know how it works.
Points.
He's probably got 30 30 million out of
that.
Maybe balling out of control.
Bruce hit us up,
dude.
Yeah,
he's good friends with dom.
Irrera yeah,
those too.
That's so funny.
I would love to see it.
Uh,
just a dem too in a diner having a
conversation.
I know,
right?
It's this Bruce Dama rare.
Tom Are rarer still doing the day.
Dude,
I fucking love him.
He did a bunch of episodes on the
showtime show.
I did.
He?
Yeah.
Dude,
it's fucking so awesome that they got
like real comics,
man.
The showtime show looks great,
I love how authentic everybody looks and
the hairstyles and killed it.
Real comics.
Y'all magical you neuron Erik Griffin.
Jaren uh,
um,
fucking dumb.
Earl Skakel does a few poppins on it.
Um,
oh my God.
Oh,
I'm sure I'm drawing such a blank.
There's so many other guys that like
came in and left.
She would get fucking gold.
Yeah.
That's that man.
That's crazy.
And Melissa,
Melissa,
you guys feel like an extreme amount of
responsibility while you were doing this
because you're doing a movie that's
based on the most important comedy club
in my opinion.
Ever.
Yeah.
TV show,
but yeah,
yeah.
No,
yeah,
yeah.
You're doing a show.
The pressure was fucking,
yeah,
man.
I felt the pressure,
the responsibility was fucking huge.
Wow.
We premiered last night and it will air
this Sunday.
And uh,
Jim Carey said some amazing things,
man.
Yeah.
That's our cast photo.
That one that you clicked that one.
Yeah.
Did it feel weird to be on that?
I mean it must have been like I can tell
you from the bottom of my honest heart,
it was the most important thing I've
done so far.
Wow,
dude.
I mean we're paying homage to the world
that,
that we love and respect so much and it
was a big effort on Jim's part and his
producing partner,
Michael Aguilar to like tell real
stories.
A lot of the stories that people will
see if you watch the show,
and I hope you do come from Jim's real
life to do term Boston move.
They live in a fucking dude's closet in
West Hollywood and they used to be a guy
that would jerk off and watched him
change and Jim,
Jim put that story in the show,
man.
He wanted all these little great tidbit.
There's a great moment about jokes
stealing in there and a fucking huge
fist fight that breaks out.
That was real from gyms,
personal life about guys who used to
come in from the fucking radio,
from talk radio in the,
you know,
in the morning they come to the club at
night,
come to the store,
steal shit.
The next morning comics would fucking
hear it.
Yeah.
That's a real common thing.
And that was always going on.
You know what else was going on?
A big one was,
uh,
writers for sitcoms would come same shit
and they would watch people do sets and
then they would wind up putting their,
their bits and like,
even in fucking Seinfeld kept wanting
Kevin James Signature bits got used on
Seinfeld after he had a bunch of
meetings and then they came to see him
perform a bunch of like top writers came
to see him performing an NBC showcase.
This is like when Kevin was a getting a
development deal and they came down and
watched him and then like the next
season,
his muffin bit was on a Seinfeld episode
and he was like,
what the fuck man?
Well nowadays they fucking,
they're blatant.
They tell you like I,
I tested for Saturday night live and you
sign a form that says these characters
can be used after the audition.
Whoa.
And this is crazy.
I'm not calling out anybody you're
saying anything.
But they did.
There was a character ended up on the
show that Vanessa Bayer did fucking
hilariously,
that I did something similar in my
addiction.
I was like,
damn,
that was really good.
It's winning me.
You so you,
you audition,
you have a character you audition with.
Yeah,
I did this character.
It is fake or skills that they own that
now when you audition,
you surrender the character.
Fuck you,
man.
Yeah.
You sign a piece of paper that's crazy
than not even giving you money and
they're stealing your idea when you get
there.
That that's the respect that,
uh,
the SNL has earned in the,
in that community who,
you know,
you don't have that respect.
It's crazy.
That's stealing.
You're stealing.
Well,
I signed the form,
man.
Oh my God.
Dude,
that's so awful.
I signed that sheet because you can
almost taste it.
You know,
they're making you sign something
saying,
we're gonna steal from you.
Totally.
That's insane.
We're going to steal from you.
We're not going to pay you anything.
We're going to use this thing.
It might be a fucking Mike Meyers movie
someday,
and you'd have to say,
yes,
sir.
May I have another take it and take
acid.
Can I dig it?
It's so crazy.
I took it,
man.
I took it.
It was a wild process.
Let the fact that some she usually
successful business wouldn't want to
compensate people for creating those
ideas to fly you out to,
to show yourself off in a few.
I mean even if you just don't hire them
but you liked that character,
you there should be like an established
rate that you have to pay for things.
But I mean not,
you know,
and my whole thing is like,
I'm not saying what they did was what I
did,
but it was,
there was some similarities in,
in the nuances of the character that I
thought were either just,
you know,
a confluence of great ideas,
but um,
it is hard.
You think about that stuff you're like,
is that close to what I did?
Because you know,
like we said back in the day,
like our show shows,
people were blatantly steep.
People have been blatantly stealing in
comedy for fucking ever.
It's been like the beginning of time and
especially in the 70s which I think is
what we tried to show was like they
would steal these radio guys and fucking
show up again and be like,
hey,
like it was like it.
I can tell you how,
come on buddy.
Hold on that that was one of your shit
jokes from last night.
We always,
we always promote you.
You ever,
you're in.
Yeah,
like I'm really,
I'm really lucky that I didn't grow up
in a generation where you didn't get
paid in the sense of like when I
remember hearing stories of guys that
would go on the road and then get fucked
out of a check.
You can get fuck still really get
fucked.
Yeah.
I've heard of people getting fucked.
Joey.
Joey Diaz had a,
an experience about a year ago.
Well,
Joey's got to fuck with too.
Yeah.
He called this guy up and started
screaming at him and said,
listen,
you know you don't fucking pay me.
He goes,
I'm going to tell the whole world.
I'm going to have all my friends tell
the whole world and no one's going to
fucking work here anymore.
That's it.
Yeah.
And he wound up getting paid but it took
him a while to get paid.
There's a lot of club owners are still
doing coke.
Isn't that fucking insane?
I know a guy,
I know a guy still getting placed on him
every time I'm around him.
He's coked up.
No,
he's just limited like the old days.
But here's the thing,
they never saw.
It has been a part of it from the
beginning of time,
like from the beginning of when I
started doing standup,
there was a lot of club owners that were
on coke and they just normal.
Yeah,
they partied Nick's comedy stop in
Boston.
It didn't never happened to me cause I
was never a coke guy.
But they would offer you if you wanted
to get paid in money or coke.
I'm not kidding.
Any other industry.
They would pay the comics and cocaine.
Like Lenny Clarke has told me about it
in great detail and said I'll just take
the coke.
I guess some guys took the coke,
can you do a half a half?
Can you do like an eight ball?
And these guys were selling coke and
running comedy clubs and it's kind of
brilliant.
I mean there was,
it was total on organized crime shit.
It was all organized crime.
It was just like at a level where it was
acceptable.
It wasn't like they were killing people
but they were selling coke.
But coke was still okay that it was
like,
man,
that's fucking dude.
No one's totally captured the crazy days
of Boston.
I was a kid back then so I got to see it
really from the outside.
And it all started before I even
started,
about four years before I started.
It was at its peak and like 84 yeah.
Those guys were maniacs out of their
minds.
Maniacs hammered every night on.
So like Mario joinder was talking about
it last night at the store.
Yeah,
cause he was hosting the show that we
were doing and Mario joined.
It was like they would just go up there
and just get hammered and just be
killing.
It's crushing,
blacked out,
crushing,
drunk,
hammered.
It was a different,
it was a whole different groove,
man.
Now you have to be on your p's and q's,
man,
now everyone's got to be real tight.
I feel like the majority of people in
comedy,
the,
the longer I've stayed in comedy,
the more I see people sober now.
I think a lot of people,
it's just not,
people are,
I feel like there's a lot of,
there's a lot more clean people working
now than people who party.
I think there's a lot of people that
realize the consequences of partying.
You can only stay on that fucking train
for so long because you look at the
great ones that got derailed,
whether it's cat williams,
whether it's Kinison,
the great ones that have been derailed
by cocaine.
There's Liz,
a ton of them that we know of.
The cocaine one gets you ends in a bad
way.
If you go back,
your creativity goes away.
You get paranoid,
you get tired.
Your act diminishes greatly like
Kennison him and my opinions with a best
example.
He's the best example of a guy who at
one point in time was just arguably the
best ever for like two years and then
stop.
Good.
Just a monster,
a Ma and a thing like no one had seen
before.
Like there wasn't a Sam Kennison like an
archetype.
Yeah,
it didn't exist.
He was,
this fat guy been fucked over.
I've been married twice and he just
would come out this giant fucking big
energy.
There's this thing,
I got fucking human storm of comedy,
but then it dropped off so radically.
Like Ari was talking about the other
night.
Like if you go and watch his stuff after
the second special,
it's like it's just to eat.
The second special is a big dropoff.
The real shit is his cd or it wasn't
even a CD.
Warner brothers wouldn't even make it a
CD cause it was so homophobic.
They kept it a cassette for real.
His cassette louder than hell and then
his hbo special and don't watch anything
else.
The HBO specials.
What I remember fucking seeing as like
one of the things where I was like,
this is insane.
This is like a fucking mad man who's
hitting all the marks.
You know,
it's like,
uh,
smart madman.
Yes,
at Gigi a genius.
But he,
but he didn't,
but he's not,
but he didn't miss it was weird.
It was like,
yeah,
it's like watching something that
someone do something brilliantly in
sports where you're like,
everything worked perfectly.
It was like all the stars were aligning
for him to just chugging on this train
of crushing.
That was crazy shit to see,
man.
And it was like during the Reagan era
where people started to get a little
buttoned down.
Like that was like,
we went from Carter to Reagan,
right?
So we go from this hippie peanut farmer
from Georgia.
The couldn't get the hostages back from,
I ran to this movie star with a slick
back hair and oh,
this is like,
there was,
he was a part of that.
I mean there was a part of the whole
country was fucking crazy at the time.
And kinison came along and he sort of
embodied the frustrations that a lot of
people fell.
The timing was perfect.
Perfect.
But cocaine got him like he wasn't the
same guy after,
after that special,
there's the just this giant dropoff in
the amount of focus he put on his work.
Yeah.
Well,
because you become complacent and you
also like,
I think the more money and fame you get,
I think unless you have sense,
sense,
sense of groundedness and humility
around you,
like friends to be like,
dude,
you got to fucking change your game.
You're fucking up.
You're slipping,
you're not producing,
you're not producing any more.
You're not writing.
You're not developing.
You're not changing who you are as a
comic.
And if you don't have that around you,
if everyone around you is like more
fucking coke.
Fuck Dude.
More bitches.
That's overages.
That's it.
No,
I agree.
Um,
the train crashes.
I don't know Kat Williams,
but uh,
I'll tell you what to this day,
like pimping chronicles,
the pimp chronicles him,
whatever that special is that he did,
that is a god damn genius.
It's amazing.
And apparently he looks to local.
Whew.
I don't know,
but I just wish he would clean up.
He's one of those guys.
I look forward when he puts out shit
cause it's so fucking different.
Crazy.
Just wild.
Wild.
He's real.
I mean it's just,
he's a maniac.
It's fucking hair's all slicked back
sweating like a pig.
He paused especial to change his clothes
because he sweat so much genius.
That's how you know you're putting in
work,
sweat through his clothes.
You're getting your money.
When did it change?
It came back out and kept crushing.
That's how you know you're,
it's fucking near where he put in work.
Yeah.
And that was like after he had gone
through all those cancel shows and all
the craziness and like got on stage and
yelled at a heckler for five minutes and
then laughed and everybody wanted their
money back and they booed him and shit
still came back and crushed.
Yeah.
He's fucking good.
It's that goddamn cocaine though.
Get some,
gets everybody.
Everybody that we know that never made
it.
I mean,
how many guys do you know that were
funny?
That never made it,
they started doing coke.
A shitload of dudes.
A shitload.
Not just coke too,
but just anything,
anything,
anything.
I mean,
as soon as they got into the party
world,
the hard party world of like,
yeah,
coke,
it's got to be cold.
It's coke one was bad.
It just,
it just,
it just snacks people.
God damn pin an ae disappear man.
Who Love Coke must hate my podcast.
Like you always shitting on coke.
You don't even never even done coke,
bro.
That's about rogen dude.
I like him,
but he's like a pitch about coke dog.
Let it go bro.
A do little coke.
I do little coke every day.
Apparently.
That is the best way to get girls to
have sex with you though.
Like if you've got some cocaine,
it's did you gotta be in the right place
for people need cocaine?
Not Allowed to say no.
They just say yes.
They just get crazy and they do coke.
I guess it's like a super inhibition
lowering thing.
You know?
I think the idea is so fun that they're
like,
he can get coke,
like anybody can get weed,
but it's like he couldn't get coke.
You're waiting at the house for the guy
to show up.
The guy shows up in a Lamborghini with
that fucking music playing in the
background.
There's no easy way out of his car.
Puts the break on Yo man,
I got your package.
You give him the money you hug like a
little bit too violently,
like a little slap hug.
You know that slap the back hug cause
you know that you're dealing in some
seriously illegal things.
That guy knows where you live too.
How's your sister man?
She's good bro.
Thanks for asking.
No Shit.
No shit for the coke man.
No doubt.
Good Shit.
Oh Yo the best yo,
next time I got some non,
some really clean shit's not stepped
down dog.
So fucking hit me to fuck up right next
week.
Next week I got a new shipment coming
in.
And you gotta be careful though.
Don't Odi cause it should that strong
don't odd dude.
I don't want that on my conscious but
just be dropping their panties for this
shit bro.
You gotta be bitches in the house?
No.
All right man,
I gotta get out here.
Did you see that?
That Mary Latino Lady that uh,
fuck that kid in school and went to jail
and then had a kid with all broke up
after 21 years together.
Can you believe it?
This kid finally woke up.
I was like,
this bitch is crazy.
21 years later,
still took two 21
years.
This kid has been banging her.
I got to get the fuck Outta here.
Oh,
you're not to fuck me when I was 12.
What am I doing here?
Shit,
I didn't realize this was super
unhealthy.
All right.
Yeah.
Thanks.
I gotta go.
I think they have a kid together.
Do they?
10 year old daughter.
18 year old dog.
Well,
she's going to be,
she's going to fucking have everything
in order.
I'm sure it's going to be the leader of
a punk band.
Yeah,
she'll be,
she'll have her head shaved.
She'll be fucking wearing doc martens
stomping around.
Mary Kayla turns husband.
We only split so I could sell pot.
I love it.
I love life.
Life's beautiful setting.
It's still happily together and he
merely filed for legal separation from
May 9th because he believes it will make
it easier for him to get a license to
distribute marijuana cigarettes.
She,
she's a registered sex offender.
Oh
yes.
She has to be right because he was
underage.
That's hilarious.
I've met,
she's still Afrique.
Totally dude.
I bet she puts like alligator masks on.
So He's 55.
She's 55.
They're fine.
That just got legally divorced or they
could,
uh,
seven years in prison for,
I'm happy for that.
Did she really?
Seven years is fucking wild.
That's so stupid.
He was,
he was in sixth grade.
What's six grades that 1212 or 13?
Jesus.
That was a DJ in Washington.
Would you go see your shows?
I was up in Seattle.
I should've gotten up there.
Yeah,
it's probably awesome.
Really,
really good.
Show.
A fire bomb goes off.
Fucking glitter in the air.
It's crazy,
bro.
Shit is the shit.
He knows that a party.
What do you spin man?
Bam,
Bam.
Whenever I'm feeling dog
amp.
Amp,
Amp.
Kids loved that music when they're on
the drugs though too.
When you're on net,
molly,
you can't escape the beat.
How many times have you done ecstasy?
Ecstasy.
I've,
I've done
two or three times.
Two or three and dma cause two different
things,
right?
I think Mtma is ecstasy.
The old ecstasy that we did in high
school was definitely not what it is
now.
It was like whatever pill they crushed
together of shit from the sink.
They lied to you.
Fuck yeah,
that was bad.
Shit.
You get lied to in Chicago.
MTMA was
Mtma the first time I ever did it was in
London and about 10 years ago,
that was the first time ever even heard
of it because he wasn't molly,
didn't they?
No one's had molly,
but the guy was like,
Andrew,
this guy who lived next door was that do
I've got these fucking a dude.
You've got to try it.
And I was like,
all right,
whatever the fuck his big like Jamaican
British dude.
I was like,
all right dude,
I'll try this shit.
We went down by the beach and watch his
concert and I was like,
Dude,
how do I get this all the time?
And he was like,
it's limited supply,
but I've got more for you.
We did that shit for like four days
straight.
I was like,
this is the most fun I've ever had.
And then I just stopped doing it for
years and years and years and I tried it
again one more time.
And that was it.
Never again.
I only did it once,
but it was spectacular.
It's amazing.
The,
the,
the calm down,
those who strong the comedown was
devastating.
I was like this.
Do you get hard crashes when you do
shrimps or no?
No.
You don't crash at all?
I mean I feel weird sometimes I fit.
I'm always so bill belittled,
not belittled,
so obliterated by the experience.
It's always like I'm trying to process
it.
They're like,
I'm barely aware of my physical state.
Um,
almost like eating just to like,
just cause I have to,
I know I have to get calories excess and
it should be in my body.
I mean,
let me just figure out what the fuck
just happened.
You know,
it's always like,
oh yeah,
I knew,
but I did know like I Kinda,
I needed to see it but my crack at my
crashes were for some reason they used
to be fucking terrible.
I used to come down off of mushrooms and
I would feel fucking miserable.
Is it always every time he did it almost
man.
Did you ever think that like maybe the
one thing that does happen apparently is
that sometimes people grow mushrooms and
oddly enough the mushrooms have fungus
that develops on them.
I didn't get sick from the fungus and
then sometimes people say they have like
these,
they have these almost like hangover,
like feelings.
Because of that.
I have read that I've never had a
hangover.
I mean I just,
I just remembered a lot of the crashes
being like a fucking bummer.
Like I was like,
this is for some reason acid was the
first time I ever did.
Acid was had like,
I felt like even when I was off of it,
it was great.
I didn't really didn't fuck with me.
Yeah.
I,
I did acid for the first time last year.
Like was it last year?
Six months ago?
Something like that.
Yeah.
But it didn't,
um,
it didn't,
it didn't crash me.
If that felt weird when it was over.
I was just didn't want it.
I just,
I did it and I didn't want to do it
again.
I remember doing it and being like,
Eh,
I just didn't want to do it again.
They say the thing about ecstasy,
those if you take five htp,
you've got to take that shit.
Like while you're on it cause it helps
rebuild your serotonin so it balances it
out.
Yeah.
Cause it's the building blocks for
Serotonin.
Take that and it'll uh,
it'll help you a boost yourself back up
when you come through.
That's because once you come through,
cause it gives you this giant burst of
Serotonin.
You feel so wonderful.
But then it depletes train while before
it spools back up.
The five htp apparently can help
mitigate that and sounds like printer
ink.
Yeah,
it does.
The five htp,
I guess.
It's so funny.
There's like a science enough staying
fucking healthy while you're on drugs.
I know when I first started doing drugs
it was like figure it out.
Did met you,
your lip off.
Uh,
you get a Jig applesauce
home remedies like that.
You were having a new Udo [inaudible]
minuto is the Mexican.
I'm like,
I'm like not what I thought it's a drug
now I'm a noodle.
Yeah.
New though is a,
the Mexican hangover cure.
It's fucking great.
You can get it.
This is a legit Mexican joint down the
street,
right?
It's pork basis and it's a bunch of shit
in there.
They have tried Chari soul and shit.
There's,
there's like stomach like you like
pieces of like stomach in there.
That's it's,
it's like this brown suit.
It's chick peas in it or not brown.
It's like a reddish stew stew.
It's God damn delicious.
I love it.
If you not get any real place,
like a real Mexican joint that has real
menino,
whoa.
What's the fucking spot up the should I
go to?
I'll show you.
Yeah.
You guys should get a,
I got a room.
I don't,
I know exactly where it is,
but I don't know the name of it.
Something Tacoria oh,
it's so good,
dude.
Everyone's watching Mexican tv.
You go in there,
everyone's speaking Spanish.
They look at you like,
what the fuck you,
how'd you find his blade?
Yeah.
And you're like,
hey fellas,
they barely speak English.
Barely.
When you're ordering food that's the
barely,
and they have to ask you like two or
three times and you have to explain to
them and then,
you know,
you could try,
try to like,
you'll be embarrassed.
Try to say it with,
uh,
the Spanish flair,
but it's so good,
man.
Whore.
Chada there's big those bigger chat of
vats.
I love the vats.
Yeah,
that's,
yeah,
that's it.
You're going to be a rich Mexican.
You want an Horchata Vat at your house.
You don't think Gabriel Iglesias as
hundred dollar.
He's got a giant one,
like an oral barrel and he wears the
helmet with tubes every morning when he
walks around with it.
Oh.
Horchata helmet.
It's going to be,
what am I hope she had a helmet.
The fluff,
the fluff,
the fluff.
Scott it,
he's like taking time off that guy.
I mean he's fucking,
he's a machine.
He's been doing it for so long.
I think he probably needs a little bit
of a break.
Right.
I think he said he just wants to do a
bunch of shit now.
It's just going to have some fun just
party,
just doing some money.
Fuck off by a boat.
Made so much money.
He's got all of it.
People don't even realize how much money
that dude made.
That's why he's so good at what he does.
Cause he keeps it on the low.
He doesn't end up like he has money.
He doesn't seem,
he doesn't come off that way.
Yeah.
He's a real low to the ground with that
stuff.
He was doing so many shows.
He has the record number of shows that
were sold out at the ice house.
He did like some crazy run.
We was doing three,
four shows a day.
It was something on the Wa.
How many was it?
Would you say?
Jamie?
He's back on the roof.
Fucking so we took the time off and jump
back in.
Fluffy is fucking back.
Oh,
he's got a new special.
Oh Shit.
Look at all those dates.
Huh?
He's hot.
Look at all those dates every day.
I'm hustling,
dude.
Dude.
Fluffy family is connected,
Bro.
I'm sorry for what I said.
When I was hungry I was going to Norway
and Sweden,
Estonia,
the United Kingdom.
Germany,
Belgium,
Netherlands.
Holy Shit.
Finland.
Vegas.
Wow.
She's got a whole European leg of his
tour.
Holy Shit.
Renee Park,
California.
Where's renee part?
Rohnert Park.
Good question.
It's a place where white people
shouldn't go pro.
I'm going to say that Sioux falls back
on the road,
baby.
When is your showtime special?
It's coming out very soon,
right tomorrow.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
June 2nd we released tomorrow baby.
What's it called?
Home field advantage.
Oh,
Jesus.
You do it in Chicago.
Did it back home at the vic theater
where I used to go watch a band play
when I was in high school.
It was so fucking surreal dude.
Wow.
Van and she'll see you cancel.
You're looking cute man and wrong beard.
Strong beard.
And it was,
I was this when I was shooting the
shell.
Oh look at that.
Do you know what that is?
He'll go back to pictures.
You know what that's suddenly mean.
Paying
tribute to somebody.
Do you recognize that picture?
No.
Or what I'm doing?
Carol Burnett.
Ah,
fuck.
Yet in Carol Burnett used to fucking
touch your ear for her.
For Grant.
For a family.
Wow.
This is a trip without her family.
She used to touch your ear.
Grandmother was like touchy for me while
her grandma's,
I say I say hi to Nana on TV and she's
like,
I can't do that.
She's like,
the fucking fire me.
And she's like,
I promise I'll show.
I'll do something.
I'll think of something that you know,
like as a shout out to you.
And she told her like,
you know,
for short time later she was like,
I'm going to touch my year.
You'll know him thinking of you.
So she used to do TV outside to appease
some annoying family members.
Yeah man.
You gotta I bet you realize Nana.
I got shit I'm doing up there.
Okay.
I'm working.
I'm God damn.
Carol Burnett.
I'm wishing her a restaurant recently.
A couple of years ago I was at a
restaurant.
She was there.
It's weird.
It's like she was just hanging out this
restaurant really and there with some
guys kicking it.
Oh yeah.
She's,
I think she's fucking,
she was genius.
That show.
Carol Burnett show was a great fucking
show.
She's brilliant.
Everything about her was like so
inventive of that fucking time period.
I can,
I appreciate that kind of Shit so much.
Well you don't have to also have to
realize how crazy it was that someone
was willing to invest in a woman running
a show like Yup.
It was unheard of.
Carol Burnett shown as a sketch comedy
show.
Unheard of.
Yeah.
I mean fuck man,
look at her.
She's the only tugging on her ear.
Yeah.
It's Kinda crazy man.
Like at the time,
so powerful man.
How few women were like that at the time
that had that kind of poll.
I mean Lucy,
lucy was the only one of,
of that prior era that had fucking
massive influence in Hollywood.
Yeah.
Who could say anything and be like,
this is how it is.
In studios were like,
Huh,
we're show was called,
I love Lucy happening.
Jesus.
It couldn't have been any other way.
You know what I mean?
For her,
it was like,
she's like,
I am a star.
I'm going to be the star of the show.
I'm on the fucking intro to be my face
and then show Ricky Ricardo.
I don't even know Ricky Ricardo his
name.
How about that?
Who's that?
Ricky Ricardo Guy.
What was his name is.
Ah,
it's not clean.
That's what I'm saying.
It's so embarrassing.
I do know who it is,
but everybody knows who Lucille ball is.
What's that dude's name?
I honestly thought it was ricky Ricardo
name,
Bro.
That's the TV name.
Desi Arnaz.
Oh,
okay.
I kind of had,
I must do,
but I knew that,
I knew that.
I just forgot it.
You're allowed to forget shit like that.
I wouldn't forget Lucille Ball.
Fuck No.
Hmm.
Can't good goddamn show back then.
And that was back when the white girl
was a lot of data.
Cuban Cubans were,
were very white back then.
Well.
That was the only kind of cute,
but yeah,
it was the only minority she could date
on TV.
Yeah,
like if it's like if she had a show
called I love Mexicans and she was a
date dating a Mexican guy and not a
Cuban guy.
Little humans are like from Spain.
It's like a Spaniard.
It was,
it was thought of as a different thing.
Desi,
Desi Arnaz a handsome bastard back then.
He was think he ever bank lucy.
No disrespect.
They were married.
I'm saying,
do you think you banged her though?
No,
no charity in real life.
And then they worked together on TV.
They were.
Wow.
Look at that.
The heyday,
back in the day,
man,
you ever watch old TV shows just to,
just to get a glimpse of what it was
like to be back in that era.
My fucking old man loved Andy Griffith
is their favorite fucking show in the
history of television.
My parents watch Andy Griffith every
day.
Oh God.
They're assessed.
They love that shit.
My Dad loves that Shit.
They long for nostalgia heath.
He just thinks that like that's such an
iconic period of time when like comedy
was pure and clean and the jokes were
about life situations that were,
yeah,
there was a town drunk and as a town
hall,
you know what I mean?
It's kind of like everything was such a
setup,
but me,
mom,
behind the scenes,
they were just as freaky back then,
if not don knotts used to use to stick.
Uh,
the cop aton up his own ass right before
they shot every day.
Are you sure?
Nope.
Look at that picture.
That's the baton going in his ass.
That's why Andy,
he's laughing.
Did you ever,
um,
hear the fatty arbuckle story?
Fatty arbuckle was the big comedian from
like the 1930 [inaudible] 1940
[inaudible] and they had some girl that
they were doing something with and
someone put a bottle inside of her,
like in a,
in a vagina and it broke and she died.
Fuck yeah,
she died.
Yeah.
There was something along those lines.
There was a bit where it was like,
we're going to put a bottle in your
pussy.
I think so.
I think they were partying.
I think they were going too hard and a
fatty arbuckle was a huge star at the
time.
Yeah.
And when that woman died,
I don't know if he was,
I don't know if he was a convicted,
he got charged with me whether or not he
was convicted.
I don't know if he was convicted,
but his,
his career was over and then it all
dried up for him.
I don't even know if he did it,
you know what I mean?
Um,
I'm not really sure.
He was probably around for the party
most likely.
Yeah.
Hotel Room.
She sneezed in the bottle.
Broke.
Arbuckle was charged with manslaughter
and endured,
not one,
not two,
but three trials for the alleged crime.
Not going to go into the nitty gritty of
what went on in each trial,
but try to imagine the mismanagement and
publicity akin to the Oj Simpson trial
and you'll be getting close.
Well then he should have got into it.
I mean,
who knows.
I Dunno.
Court TV,
there was no court TV coverage,
but there was a thriving tabloid press
and no shortage of bombastic rhetoric.
The assistant prosecutor for one of the
trials Minton Milton,
you wren.
Hmm.
Became known for his flora.
Damning description of our buckles
lifestyle to wit a Babylonian feast was
in process in progress there.
The defendant had sumptuous quarters
with his friends.
Food was spread.
Wine and liquor were served and this
modern bells Johar.
I don't know what that means.
Bell Shahar.
That czar
our sat upon his throne surrounded by
his lords and there ladies,
there was music feasting,
singing and dancing.
How do you know?
Were you there?
The,
yeah,
he's,
he just said above.
He didn't want to fucking get into
details and then he explained a bunch of
Shit.
A modern Belshazzar,
however,
the last king of Babylonia sundered
[inaudible] his decadence.
This is some game of thrones s dooms day
stuff right there.
That's a,
that is an interesting thing that a
prosecutor could do back then.
They could make that sort of like
ridiculous description of the events
that took place.
Like you weren't there.
Yeah.
You just say what you actually do not
know.
You'd actually do not know that this was
what happened.
It's a bit of big fish story.
And so did he wind up going to jail.
You know how many people have stuck
bottles up people's pussies and they
didn't die and they went,
they read that story and I did it this
morning.
Have you got like one of those Mexican
coke bottles was real thick ones.
Those are hard to bless or heartbreak.
You'd have to fucking throw her against
the wall or something.
If she had a pussy that was so strong,
it could break one of those bottles.
They could probably endure the cuts to
oh yeah.
It's all good.
Dense.
It killed his career.
He third trial,
he uh,
just pretty much lost left Hollywood or
he's shunned by Hollywood and could no
longer find work.
Isn't that crazy that he was acquitted
right?
He got off.
He was acquitted and uh,
it's still,
yeah.
I guess back then that was it.
It was,
it's on and there was only one machine,
you know,
there was no internet back then.
Nope.
He couldn't have had a youtube page.
Could have made his on youtube based
Fatty arbuckle put out a special on
Seeso.
Man.
It's pretty good.
It's on epix that they're going to sell
to Netflix and five years.
How's the working for showtime?
It was good too.
They've got good shows,
man.
They did me right.
I will say doing this special this
Friday and then the show comes out on
Sunday,
so it's like this weekend they're gonna.
They're pairing it together and I
fucking,
they were great.
They did great by me,
man.
I can't fucking say anything negative
about that.
The network is the shit right now.
Billions is good for them.
They still kicking out shameless people.
Fucking love.
Shameless still bloodline.
I mean there's a bunch of fucking really
good shows.
Yeah.
Showtimes resurfaced as a of the premium
cable network that it's w wanted to be
for a long time.
Yeah.
I did a a Netflix special in two oh five
and in 2006 showtime eared it.
They,
they've put together some good comedy
specials.
Well,
they have the Netflix and showtime have
to have some kind of deal because a lot
of the times you're showtime shit ends
up on Netflix.
They,
they buy out the rights of that.
That would be smart.
You know,
if they did that,
that would be smart.
Well a good move.
It's good move for everybody.
You know what I mean?
And I hope they also have it available.
Like we,
it's easy to watch online know where the
mega with very few hurdles to be able to
watch it online because you've got to
give it to people.
Men At some point.
Well not only that,
more people find out how good it is.
More people watch it,
you know,
whether it's your show or whether it's
just stand up,
you know,
the more,
more,
more stuff that gets out there,
the better it is.
Right.
Absolutely.
Who getting these crazy day and age,
I hope you've come along in the golden
age of the comedy store.
You know that right?
It's fucking wild man.
Yeah,
the boom,
this is the boom right now we're gonna
throw it.
Is the bubble going to pop?
I don't think so cause there's so much,
there's so many funny comedians.
That's the guys like yourself guys.
There's a lot of guys out there that are
really good and that are coming up that
are really good.
There's real good comedy going on.
I know.
It's crazy.
I think it's breeding really good
comedy.
I think because there's so much great
competition,
there's so many fucking good people.
I think it's breeding to people to be
stronger and stronger.
Sometimes I see fucking guys and I'm
like,
God damn are getting so
strong.
Well it's like you see really good stuff
around you.
You know,
you show up one night in Chappelle goes
up and then Chris rock goes on after him
and like you're seeing this stuff on a
regular basis and they'll like the
quality of the comedy that you say.
It's very high and that guy's coming up.
You know?
When I first started the store in 94 it
was a dead zone.
It was just a terrible time.
It was like right after the Kennison
boom,
it ended Kennison left.
They're like 86 and then by the time I
came around,
it was an eight years later.
Kinison was dead and the place was
weird.
Nobody wanted to be there.
It was weird.
It was weird there for a long time man.
Especially in terms of like talent
coming up,
you know the talent coming up.
Back then it was just like it was really
poor.
This is the best you've ever seen it
since you started at percent?
For me it's not even close for some guys
say was even better early on.
Dell's does.
They say it was even better.
Like I'm in the 80s they say like before
like the kittens and error,
like um,
dommo rare especially he says that like
there was a time when they were doing
three shows in the main room,
two shows in the or and they were just
rotating.
Just fuck.
Yeah.
But we're pretty close to that and I was
just going to say that's where we're
knocking on that door to close two shows
in the main room all the time.
On the weekends we do two shows in the
or all the time on the weekends and
sometimes I've done four sets in a night
there where I did two shows in the main
room,
one show in the belly room in one show.
In the or.
That's fucking crazy.
Belly has developed itself and deal like
a real fucking great,
oh,
there's just so much creativity and fun
going on there.
That's what it is,
but you know I'm in the Improv is not
bad right now to the Improv has been
really good too.
It's like comedy is just like
experiencing it in a cool little bump.
Yeah,
it's wild.
I think people don't know how lucky they
are in la.
It's wild,
man.
People people live in La and they're
like,
yeah,
how many guys are on tonight?
It's like,
well,
they're all going to be fucking amazing,
so stick around because everyone you're
going to see is going to be fucking good
comment.
I in a couple of that sock.
Sure,
sure.
It's a few.
Sure.
There's going to be a few.
There's a lot of a comedy tourism to
people coming here from Ireland,
Scotland and that's why it's strange
like we've,
we flew over to watch the store.
Like what weird.
I hope that,
I hope our show helps that too,
because again,
it'll help push the idea of the store
being just another fucking iconic piece
that people don't know about.
You know,
for people that don't give a shit about
standup when they see this,
I think it'll be more like,
oh fuck,
that's kind of cool.
I'd like to go see more of that shit.
No.
Are you touring?
Are you going around the world?
What are you doing right now?
Because we're kind of waiting to hear
what showtime size.
If we're going to do this again,
that I have to fucking cancel a bunch of
dates,
but next week I go to Austin cap city,
then I go Chicago,
Denver,
just for laughs in Montreal.
Raleigh,
some torn a little bit here into the
summer,
but if we have to shoot again,
I have to cancel a bunch of different
dates.
No kidding.
Huh?
Showtime wastes of the first episode
airs to release any official
announcements to when is the first
episode Air Sunday baby.
So if it does well on Sunday,
they make a choice.
Right?
Then in there it takes about,
you know,
it takes a,
whatever,
a little bit of fucking manipulation
time of them deciding what they want to
do.
But yeah,
usually shortly after the first episode
they talk about what's going to happen.
So did you get a chance to watch it?
We did.
We saw it last night.
Last night was a premiere for like
internal for critics and shit.
Now it's fucking happy.
Jim Carey said some fucking amazing
stuff.
He's an executive producer of the show
for,
I didn't,
I don't know if I said that earlier,
but he said some fucking really dope
shit man.
He said how much this meant to him and
how,
how people don't really fucking know
some of the,
the true history of what that world was
like to perform for,
for no money.
And that,
that where there was one,
there was one way in was Johnny Carson.
It was like you get on Carson,
it was like,
you are fucking on the moon dude.
Wow.
And he talked about how
a lot of critics,
I guess,
Scott,
you know,
they got episodes a couple of weeks ago
and he said,
a lot of you guys have been saying the
word dark.
It's not a comedy.
He's like,
we never sold it as a comedy.
Never once did we promoted as a comedy.
It's a fucking dramatic show about the
world of comedy.
Is that funny?
Sometimes yet there's some really funny
fucking moments on our show,
but it's about the world that exists.
It's about what it's like to be fucking
23 and hungry and poor as fuck.
And trying to get pussy and trying to
get stage time and trying to figure out
what you're,
what you're doing,
who's beating you.
And it's just about fucking life.
The life of a standup,
the life of a hustling,
hungry,
angry,
angsty,
jealous,
fucking stand up.
Cause we all go through that shit dude.
I'm excited.
I want to watch it right now.
It's fucking,
dude.
I really hope people enjoy it.
And I think the first episode is
powerful is shit.
We have some do the at the pilot is
insane.
We have,
um,
Robert Forester,
Cathy Moriarty from raging bull.
Melissa Leo is the
matriarch of the show.
She,
she plays Goldie who runs our comedy
club,
um,
who is a variation of Mitzi,
but she wouldn't say that we,
we're on our own space.
Um,
Ari Grainer,
Michael Lang Carano there's some fucking
just bangers on the show.
People that are,
they act their mind out that are just
fucking really good man.
And I'm jealous you,
I've sit along with those people and I'm
like,
fuck me.
These people are really good actors.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
Melissa was,
Melissa was the best worker that she
want to fucking academy where mentioned
won an Oscar for the fighter.
So it's like being around a fucking
human that won an Oscar is crazy.
Wow.
It's wow.
Because I never be,
moriarty was enraging pool man.
Yeah.
Man was also in the dice clay's show.
That,
uh,
what is it?
What was the name of the show?
Bless this house.
Lester's house.
Yeah,
that's right.
She was nice.
His wife Alfred fucking Molina.
You know him.
Alfred Molina,
he's the shit.
He's in it too.
I mean we have dave,
they pulled out a few big names and you
always want to act or did you want to do
stand up or did you want to do both?
When I went to school,
I went to school to,
to write to do journalism and English
and I knew I wanted to write and
perform,
but I was a pussy about performing in
school.
So I did a fall,
a few plays cause I really want it to be
on stage,
but I didn't like the idea of place.
I just wanted to get on stage to like
get my comfort level up and the w and
the training wheels he had do it.
And one of the fucking,
one of the teachers pulled me aside one
day and she was like,
you know,
you could actually be a good actor if
you didn't just fuck around when you got
onstage.
And I was like,
well I,
I really want to fuck around on stage.
She's like,
well then why don't you go do that for a
living and no shit.
I was like,
I'm gonna try.
And I knew I wanted to do standup so
bad.
And I moved.
When I moved to La,
I started in La and I was like,
I'm either going to sink or swim and I
just start,
what year?
2000.
I moved here 2000 at the end of 2006 I
lived on a guy's fucking lazy boy in
Long Beach and I used to drive up my
buddy's truck every single fucking
night.
I drop him off at the casino.
He was a professional gambler.
I drop him off the casino,
take his truck,
cause I didn't have car money.
Do fucking Mike's,
go to the store and get intimidated,
uh,
learn some lessons and then fucking
drive back home,
pick him up and we fell asleep,
you know,
could get a burrito and do it all over
again.
That's wild man.
So you started really coming to the
store when I was gone.
Yeah.
It was like 2007 as you weren't around,
put your legacy was there.
You know what I mean?
Like it was like we all knew those that
came before us and we,
those that we talked about.
But it was like I was right there when
you were,
when you had kind of left that left that
world a little bit,
but it's wild because it was like I
hated the store when I first started to
two thousand six thousand seven it was
fucking awful.
The people above us,
I didn't,
none of the older comics where that
fucking nice divide was negative as
shit.
There wasn't a lot of crowds.
Delvin Mike's,
we're fucking brutal.
They were miserable.
They barely got watched.
You know?
It's just so many negative things about
that place at the time that I was,
we were going through it and then it
slowly kind of turned into this,
you know what we've seen now,
which is just fucking amazing.
We see now it's crazy.
You pull into the parking lot is jam.
The haulers are jammed with people and
it makes me smile from fucking year that
year.
Heared right.
Isn't it weird?
It's weird.
I've been there since 94 minutes.
Never been like this.
This is a totally different thing.
It's just,
you know what?
It still does to me.
This is the truth.
You kind of get desensitized to shit,
but seeing my name up on the fucking up
on the board when it's a pack night,
it still gets me like,
I still get excited.
I'm like,
that's fucking cool.
I'm a part of this moment in time and
comedy at that fucking club,
in my opinion,
the club,
it's just something else,
man.
There's something powerful as shit.
That's sometimes I walk to the club
because I live in the neighborhood and,
and I like to walk instead of drive
because it helps me get out of my brain
and uh,
time I fucking walk
up that,
you know,
and I see my name up there.
There's like a fucking overwhelming
feeling.
The moment I see it,
it's like this is,
you know,
soak it in a little bit cause it's
fucking doesn't last forever.
It's nice to have a place that's like
that too.
Like to just have one place that stands
out as something that means more than
just a comedy club.
It's like,
it's,
it's an iconic thing.
Yeah.
There's,
there's something about that place.
Like we're at the store.
It's bigger than comedy,
man.
It's,
it's,
it's like,
uh,
it's something,
it's something big.
It's something fucking special,
man.
Well,
pauline and I were talking about this
and I told him that your moms,
one of the most important people ever in
comedy period,
like ever one of the most influential
humans in the,
in the comedy world,
in the world of what we know today.
A standup comedy.
Yes.
Mitzi.
Sure.
Like without her,
like stop and think about what other
comedy club owner has had the kind of
influence even remotely similar to what
she's had.
I would know none of the above.
I mean,
I guess the only person that you could
bring into that namesake,
maybe budd Friedman from the emperor,
maybe because he did evening at the
Improv,
any of the Monaco and everything like
that.
But I don't think in the hardcore sense
it's not a clothes won't be the same.
No,
but but,
but yeah,
what she did was shape and revolutionize
the business that you know today.
She knew how to do it,
to leave it up to the Comedians,
leave him alone,
and then also give them hard spots
making going to come work for them,
work for it.
That was the,
that's the best part about that club.
You think someone's funny,
good.
Put them on after dice or put them on
after you know,
whoever the fuck it was at the time that
was killing.
See how funny they are after Richard
Pryor.
Exactly.
Yeah.
See how funny they are after someone
just destroys.
He just got to go up to this wasteland
of the audience.
That's such a testament about that club
too.
It's what they've always done.
You'd I feel it.
Plates of Shit in that place.
There's just no way around it following
everybody,
following anybody's I filed prior for
five weeks.
Fuck when?
When prior was in a wheelchair so they
would have to carry him to the stage.
It was,
it was dark.
You know,
it'd be really funny for if you had to
go on and you had to carry him off and
then do your set,
like just start it,
start it from the crowd carried out.
Yeah.
It was a,
but that,
that philosophy that she had that make
you work for it make you sink or swim.
So important.
Because if people that we know to this
day that are scared to have tough spots
and we know those people totally,
they will,
they see somebody like Joey Diaz in the
lineup and they're like,
oh,
I'm going to go for a drive.
I'll be back in a little bit.
They'll let somebody else take their
spot and they come in and they check.
Oh,
oh,
is he up?
Oh,
I miss my spot.
Am I on next?
I thought you were just here.
What'd you go?
Yeah.
You hid from Joey Diaz.
Motherfucker.
The only way to go up after Joey Diaz is
to fucking,
is to just ride that line.
You got to ride the wave.
You gotta.
You have to enjoy him.
You have to have fun.
I fucking love watching him.
Yeah.
But that's what I'm saying,
like the problem with comics when it
comes to those sorts of situations is
you see someone killing and for some
reason you think that's taking away from
your ability to be funny.
It's a weird,
the opposite.
Yes.
They want you to win with someone.
Let them know that you're there to win
again instead of,
Oh,
I can't fucking follow that.
Not going to talk about what joy is
going to be disappointing.
Don't get your hopes up.
Yeah.
Oh,
well good.
I'm glad you set yourself up.
Yeah,
it's fucking,
you also should be going up laughing
like it should be fun that something
happens to some comedians along the line
where they stopped being fans of comedy.
Like why did you get into this in the
first place?
Didn't you like watching it?
Right.
It wasn't going to stop watching it.
Now that you're a pro,
that's crazy.
It wasn't because of all the billions of
dollars that you thought you were going
to make.
You know what I mean?
Nobody got in was like,
dude,
I can't wait to make so much fucking
bank on this shit.
Yeah,
no one's getting into comedy for that.
Although it can be done.
You Know Kevin Hart,
it can be done,
but that's not why you get into it.
But it's like what we're talking about
earlier,
it's like people that are trying to get
the limelight.
It's that weird depressing thing versus
someone who's just like,
I'm just trying to do my best shit.
Just tone it.
Trying to put out my best,
my best stand up product.
I just want to pump out what I'm proud
of.
Just hammer that bitch.
Just one.
I'll fucking punch him enough fucking
head.
Does the,
uh,
does the showtime special have your,
your rock bit,
the bit on the rock?
It's on.
It's on showtime right now on the south
by southwest to tour that.
I did.
They do the fucking behind the scenes of
south by southwest and I did a bit at
the showcase for south by southwest and
I put it up on there.
Is it in your showtime specialist?
Not Dude,
it's just on that.
How is that possible?
Because I did that first and showtime
put that up and I,
so what?
I know I should have done it again.
I know.
It's so good.
I should have done it again,
mother fucker.
I thought of you actually.
That's right.
I thought he,
I was like,
God,
I should have done that Joe.
I bet you fucking Joe.
Joe would have said,
I should have told against so many
people about that bit.
That's a funny bit.
But the beauty is it links to it.
So it's on showtime so they can watch my
other set and all that stuff.
That's another 15 minutes that I didn't
put in my special that I did at south
by.
Oh really?
Let's get that shit on youtube.
Somebody.
Somebody won't rank wink,
wink knows at a strip things down.
I know that underground,
uh,
no.
What does that say no more?
Is that under my first album?
That's my old album.
When did you put on an album?
What year was this?
It was two years ago.
That was my first album that I put out.
Say No more,
Andrew Santina saying no more.
All right.
That's not it.
Let's,
let's bring this bitch home.
So a baby.
So the show starts Sunday.
That's my first air.
I'm dying up here.
Starts Sunday on showtime and a,
if you're a fan of comedy,
we definitely want that to keep going.
So let's,
let's try a sport.
That thing and Andrew Santina was comedy
special called home field advantage
comes out this Friday tomorrow baby.
You're one of my favorite up and coming
guys.
I think you're a fucking hilariously
talented guy.
Thank you.
So it means a lot coming from you.
That means a ton to thank you brother.
My man.
All right folks.
We'll be back tomorrow with Bret
Weinstein and Bret Weinstein is that
college professor is being kicked out of
school
because he's been forced out of school
because they actually closed evergreen
college down today because of threats
the students have taken over the college
and that he was forced out because he
wasn't willing to participate in a white
stay home day.
They want it all white people,
all people of white privilege to stay
home and he's like,
that's ridiculous.
I'm not going to not teach because I'm
white.
And this guy's like a super progressive
guy too,
which is really crazy.
They're attacking him.
There's screaming in the hallways,
hey,
hey Ho Ho this racist teacher has got to
go.
They're calling them racist.
We are.
We are almost at the breaking point of
political correctness to Bret Weinstein
tomorrow about that.
And he's also brilliant professor with a
lot of other important stuff to talk
about.
So we'll see you soon.
Bye.
That was awesome.
Hmm.