Four,
three,
two,
one.
Boom.
And we're live.
Candice Owens.
How are you doing?
I'm good.
How are you?
I'm very good.
Thank you.
Thank you for asking.
A lot of controversy these days.
Candice,
I guess a little bit in the twitter
verse the world.
Yeah.
Just everybody's excited about being
outraged.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's exactly right.
This controversy every five seconds.
You know,
I had a guy on before,
the guy that you just met,
a Dr Robert Schoch.
He's a geologist from Boston University
and he is a part of this,
uh,
backdating of the ancient,
the history of Egypt and they're talking
about,
you know,
all these different structures that
might be thousands and thousands of
years older than people think they are.
And one of the things that he's working
on is that there was coronal mass
ejections from the sun somewhere around
10,000 years ago that basically killed
off a giant percentage of the population
on the planet.
Lightening storms millions of times
greater than anything we've ever
experienced before.
That literally,
which like lightning coming down,
like rain,
barbecuing the ground,
killing people,
people forst indicates civilization
resets.
It's almost like we need something like
that to really be upset about because
instead of being upset about Roseanne or
Samantha Bee or Samantha Bee,
use the c word today,
that Nadia
chest outrage culture.
I say everyone should just wait like 48
hours if everybody hates you and then
there'll be onto the next person that
they have.
Yeah.
Well that's one of the cool things about
the Internet is the cycle.
Boy,
it hits you hard,
but then it goes back
really fast.
Yeah.
It's never that serious
sound like the old days when someone got
in trouble with something.
Boy,
that trouble stuck.
No,
I don't know that time.
I,
I genuinely don't know that time.
How old are you?
Twenty nine.
I just turned 29.
So you're very,
very young in the shit stirring culture.
Yeah,
exactly.
This is all new stuff to you.
It's new.
Yeah,
and I think the thing that sucks for me
is that I'm really conscious of it.
Like I wish I thought all of this was
normal.
It would be easier,
but like even when I do things like just
before this I was like,
oh,
let me do an instagram story that I'm
about to go on.
Joe Rogan.
I'm like,
hey guys,
like we under Grogan.
I'm like,
how weird.
I'm like holding my phone in the middle
of talking to this device you're aware
of.
It's that kind of sucks that I'm aware
of it.
Like I.
It would be so much more natural if I
wasn't aware of it,
you know,
girls that just hey guys,
and they all day and it feels normal.
So being conscious of it is kind of not
that fun.
That's probably the best way to approach
it though,
to be conscious of our goofy it is
because if you just swept away in the
Zeitgeists,
I don't know.
I think it's basically ignorance is
bliss,
I think.
Yeah.
I think there are people that think it's
the most normal thing in the world to
just put your entire life on social
media and I actually don't think it's
the most normal thing in the world,
but my entire life is on social media.
Well,
I've just met you,
but you seem like a very bright woman
and that's probably part of the problem
is you're not stupid.
You're stupid.
You'd be like putting everything on
instagram and you'd be.
Do you do the Selfie face?
This is my favorite.
This thing,
when
they do that weird thing with their neck
angle,
I'm really bad at selfies.
My cousin always has to take them if
we're in the same picture,
but I'm getting good at my like
instagram angle and the things that I
say like,
Oh,
do you guys like this eyeshadow?
Like it's like it's,
it's that ridiculous.
My friend Cameron hanes loves you.
He saw you on Fox News.
He's like,
who's this girl?
She's making so much sense.
He's like super hardcore conservative.
So he likes when anyone is like young
and conservative,
like loves Ben Shapiro.
He loves all that Shit.
So you got excited about you.
People have been really excited.
I think it's just because I,
I'm,
I'm really unapologetically myself and
today that's like,
it's like seeing an alien.
It's hard to pull off,
right?
Because people get mad at you.
People trying this,
this one thing that is absolutely
happening,
whether people like it or not or believe
it or not it people are trying to
silence other people's opinions.
If you say something that doesn't jive
with them,
instead of saying,
wow,
this lady's kind of out there,
or she's saying some shit that I'm not
sure I agree with.
Instead of that,
they're like,
fire her.
Get her off here.
You know what?
Boycott boycott.
Which was insane.
It's like,
do you really want someone to lose their
job if you didn't like a tweet?
Like how weird or some of these
situations I'll make you really want
this person not to able to feed their
family because you don't like a tweet.
People are crazy.
Just they find targets and they want to
go after him.
There was a bunch of people that were
writing,
writing boycott.
Joe Rogan because I was talking about
having Roseanne Barr on the show
tomorrow.
It's insane.
I know and it's like she just.
She doesn't have a right to speak.
Genuine.
Can't even talk.
She can't even talk.
Even though I'm sure you don't agree
with.
I don't agree with what she said,
right,
but the idea that she can't like have a
conversation after that to me is like
the most bizarre thing in the entire
world,
but that is what outrage culture is.
It's like they need you off the island.
He doesn't even agree with what she said
and she apologized and nobody cares.
She's taken all kinds of
antidepressants.
She's drinking.
She's fucked out of her head and like my
mom took ambien.
She just told me about this today.
I forgot I forgot about the store
because I was telling her the story
about another friend of mine on the
podcast yesterday.
I talked about how a friend of mine got
on Ambien,
made a full meal,
cooked it,
ate it,
went to sleep,
got up in the morning and had zero
recollection of it was in total denial
of it.
It happens.
My mom told me that she went to bed,
got up in the morning and she had got up
and put red lipstick and I'm a and nail
Polish all over the white bathroom.
Carpet was a little.
She's painted on it like a child now and
she had zero recollection of it.
She's like,
this is scary shit.
Like she's painted like a little kid
would like a two year old would get
ahold of your lipstick and start drawing
on the walls.
She did that on this shag carpet.
Ambien is just like sleep look like.
It instantly brings you into sleep walk
and you can do anything you want.
Ambien.
I,
I had a bunch of college friends who
used to do ambien and bizarre stories
would just come out.
I'm like very anti pills.
I don't take anything.
Nothing,
nothing at all.
No drink.
I don't drink.
I don't do any toddler.
I,
I mean I wasn't always.
I just,
I kinda got,
I guess you could say it's like a little
bit of paranoia,
but once I started down this journey of
realizing that like,
Whoa,
oh my God,
I lived for 26 years in my mind wasn't
my own.
Like I thought like being a liberal was
okay and like everything that was said
on tv it was okay.
Then it's like very easy to sort of get
a little paranoid and go,
okay,
well what else did I do?
I accept normally that is actually
retrospect to look a little weird and I
started thinking about drinking.
I'm like,
how can drinking possibly be the cure to
everything?
Like it's like you're getting married,
drink happy,
you're sad,
drink a little embarrassed,
have some drink,
right?
You want to come out of your shell drink
like no matter what emotion you have,
there's like a liquor designed for it.
So I was like,
this is a little shady.
Like I don't know,
I just feel like.
And I did like a little bit of math and
I calculated that since I had started
drinking when I was 14 years old and I
look,
I would say like fair,
like I drank every weekend,
probably more in college,
maybe five days a week in college.
Right.
Then I was like,
wow,
I've technically drank for like three
years of my life and that feels weird,
so I'm just not going to drink any.
So you put in your time.
Yeah,
take a little break,
take a little break.
Yeah,
which is weird because now I go places
and I'm like,
oh,
I don't drink and everyone gets really
uncomfortable and they're like,
oh,
okay,
I'll have a glass of water.
I'm like,
I'm an alcoholic.
You can have a beer and no,
but um,
it's a weird way,
like if other people were drinking,
you don't do like,
Huh?
No,
I'm the weird one.
Yeah.
Yeah,
they don't,
they don't trust you.
Almost like,
it's either just like,
I can't trust this one.
I'm like,
water's going to be like,
man,
we were fucked up.
And then whoever did weird shit.
It's like it's okay,
we're all hammered.
Right?
But if one person,
every person right and shit down
the atrial,
all my friends are getting married and
like the first thing they say,
when I say I don't drink,
it's like you're not going to drink at
my wedding.
And I'm like,
well yeah,
is that okay?
Like,
can I still come and like,
they feel like you're ruining their
wedding because you're not going to
drink it.
It's like a very strange thing,
the culture of drinking as a nondrinker
you really realize how bizarre it is
socially.
Take off.
How long has it been?
I stopped drinking last November,
so it hasn't been like super long,
but long enough for people to really
have some weird feelings about it and
just some shit.
I'm just sober man.
I Dunno.
It's not a bad thing.
I took a month off.
I took a.
We did sober October.
No Pot,
no booze,
and then we had to do 15.
Yeah,
15 hot yoga classes,
90 minute hot yoga classes in a month.
It was this a bad between me and my four
friends was.
It was a stupid bet because it wasn't
even a stakes.
Right.
Like if one of us didn't do it,
we had to throw a party but we all did
it so it was pointless but.
But we learned a lot.
You learn a lot about just,
you learn a lot about that even if you
don't think you use alcohol or pot as an
escape,
you do,
you lean on it a little bit?
Yeah,
and I always talk like people were like,
what are the differences
you've noticed and there've been so many
differences,
but I think like the number one thing is
just like the amount of confidence that
I have.
Like I,
I have this theory now that alcohol
gives you anxiety.
Like I used to be stressed out.
Like I realized that I was self
diagnosing myself.
I'd be like,
Eh,
I'm on a morning person.
I was probably just like perpetually
hung over and never like now,
like I,
I jumped up now in the morning I have so
much energy,
so I'm like wow,
I wonder how many things I've been like
self-diagnosing.
I'm like,
Oh yeah,
my skin just got bad.
Once I turned 26,
like skinny immediately clears up.
So I'm like,
wow,
maybe I,
I just had so much alcohol in my system
that I like developed random things like
it just kind of making excuses.
It's definitely not good for you.
It's certainly not good for you.
Five,
six nights a week?
No.
And the best way to like stop drinking
is to read an article that freaks you
out about like what drinking does,
like this is what I do because it's like
how I trained myself to do things.
I'll look read some really extreme thing
on the internet and then be like,
okay,
like
no,
like this guy had this theory that like
alcohol and people call alcoholic
spirits or whatever that like when you
drink,
like it allows like evil spirits to come
into your body.
Like the most bizarre thing.
And I was just like,
yeah,
I can't drink anymore.
Got To keep away from evil spirits.
And that's what you used?
Yeah,
yeah.
I just like read weird articles and then
I'm like,
I'm not gonna drink anymore.
I'm done.
I'm over it.
And then I realized like who else
doesn't drink?
Like the most successful,
like Donald Trump has never drank
alcohol,
which is just fascinating because I'm
like,
I don't know,
he's got so much energy,
right?
Like he's just like going at it.
And I'm like,
maybe that's the secret.
Charlie Kirk doesn't drink.
He's like 24 years old.
And taking over the world.
So I don't know.
Um,
who else?
Don trump junior doesn't drink.
Doesn't.
I mean he did like,
I used to drink.
I don't mean to but he doesn't drink.
Um,
yeah.
I don't know.
I guess the people that I'm around now
don't drink so it makes it easier,
but they're just like highly productive
individuals and I'm now like highly
productive.
Kim Kardashian doesn't drink and whether
you like to
be highly productive,
but it's also good to have fun.
And I don't think there's anything wrong
with the little.
No,
I think there's nothing wrong with that.
People can drink around me all the time.
I don't care.
Oh actually I will say like when people
get like completely sloshed,
it's a weird thing to observe when
you're sober.
It's a strange place.
It's like being on another planet where
like everyone's acting like a toddler.
It's like watching a preschool class and
going to the bathroom like,
you know,
I'm like,
why are you screaming close to my face
and talk to you and explain and they
want to get wrong.
Really close,
like drinking makes you a really close
talker.
There's something where you need to feel
like the heat emanating off of someone's
space.
You know,
people grabbed people do weird shit.
To him.
It's a weird thing to watch sober.
There's a certain number of drinks where
it's fun and then there's a certain
number of drinks were like,
wow,
human beings are weird.
You know,
you're going to go back.
I mean,
look,
I'm sure I'm not going to like never
drink again,
but like I'm not even,
I don't even think about it.
Like it's just like this is the new
candice I'm sure like when I get
married,
right?
Like I'm not going to not have like
gossip champagne,
but like right now,
like especially with like the stuff that
I'm doing,
I'm like I just don't have the energy to
be like tired.
Right.
Which is kind of a weird
sentence.
How did you become this?
You're a very popular,
what I would call conservative thinker,
but you're very young.
Like how did this all happen?
How did you become this Fox News
personality?
Conservative thinker?
Yeah.
I mean I just launched a youtube channel
and fucking Youtube Youtube where magic,
but you teach a strange place.
Strange,
strange place.
Yeah.
The Internet and the Internet of things
happen on the Internet.
But yeah,
I just kind of,
I was really passionate.
Um,
I understood I had studied for like,
it sounds strange,
but like I spent a year underground,
like studying politics once I had my red
pill moment,
if that's what you want to explain that
because you used to be a liberal,
right?
And then you became a conservative.
That's correct.
So what was it?
So the story really starts with like
high school I guess,
like you know,
how things can happen you in life and
they don't make sense when they happen.
You're like why God me?
And then when you get a little older and
you're like,
this makes perfect sense.
Right?
So I was the quote unquote victim of a
hate crime when I was in high school.
When you say quote unquote victims
victim know I hate the word victim and
it's,
I'm like an again early.
I can see why early on I've sort of
developed this mentality that like being
a,
there's no value in being a victim and
people rush to call people a victim.
They rushed to call somebody the
aggressor.
So how do you describe it that you
experienced a hate crime against
something that was labeled as a hate
crime?
I W I wouldn't even call it a hate
crime.
I think we live in a label obsessed
culture and before we seek to understand
what happened,
we seek to like put it in a box like so
what?
Someone has to be a demon and someone
has to be an angel.
Right?
So what happened was I received some
voice mail messages from about four kids
and then like,
you know,
the language was,
it was pretty strong.
It was like run a tar and feather your
family.
Um,
we're going to put a bowl in the back of
your head that we did the Martin Luther
King.
Like,
you know,
Edward,
Edward Edward.
And you received these on your phone?
On my cell phone?
Yeah.
How'd they get your phone number?
Well,
there was a prank phone call,
so I didn't know.
I was like four male voices and I was
like in high school at the time and I
was like,
okay,
I cannot think of for human beings that
want me dead,
that would say like been up,
put a bullet in the back of your head
like we did to Martin Luther King and
Rosa Parks.
Like naming a school.
Where were you?
What part of the country?
Stanford High School in Connecticut.
That's a shithole.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's a total shit hole.
Connecticut Connecticut's on a Shithole.
It's a running joke.
I'm sorry.
I have my buddy Tommy Junior.
He lives in Connecticut and I'm always
telling him,
dude,
you got to move out of Connecticut.
And it became this terrible running joke
where I talk about the Connecticut's the
worst.
Have you actually been a bunch of times?
I used to work there all the time.
Well,
I used to work in all over Connecticut.
When I was doing standup,
I would drive from Boston into
Connecticut.
I did like a lot of gigs in Hartford.
I did gigs
and shit.
It's a shit hole.
Bridgeport is a shithole.
Shout out tomorrow and starling junior
though
he was a boxer that came out of
Hartford,
big time boxer,
Marlin,
Marlin starling.
But when you were in high school,
somebody started doing this prank call
and shit on you and was,
this is all in one night.
It was all in one that was like four
voices tied to like a boyfriend or a
friend's house when I got the calls and
I just like put aside like it was a
blocked number.
So I was like,
I think anything of it.
And then like what I listened to it like
it was like some pretty horrific stuff.
Like I definitely cried,
you know,
I was 17 years old.
Um,
and then the next day at school I took
this philosophy class and like,
I don't know what the topic was.
I don't know what prompted me to raise
my hand and like introduce what happened
last night as like,
you know,
a segway,
maybe I just needed to get off my chest.
But like the teacher like spazzed out
and was like,
get up,
we're going to the principal's office,
like,
you know,
you have to report this.
He brings me into the office,
the principal like,
freaked out.
Like she just like the language was
like,
you know,
it was shocking,
you know.
Um,
and then she called like the resource
officer and then like the next period of
my life was like a blackout because it
turned out that three of the kids I had
never even met.
Like this was like maybe some kids that
had their first beer,
one of the kids I was like friends with,
but we were arguing because he was upset
that I was spending so much time with my
boyfriend,
but I didn't know he's gay.
Like he wasn't,
like,
he just was like Jelly,
you know,
like,
just like I,
you saying album every day started
hanging off my boyfriend was a stupid
thing.
He wasn't 100 percent.
Yeah,
no I 100 percent from what I'm told.
But um,
yeah.
So,
uh,
then petty.
And then it was like,
here are my three friends and they were
all going to get drunk and call these,
call this black girl and you know,
it's easy to say awful things until like
this,
if you don't have to look at a human
being like,
it's easy to say awful things.
But unfortunately for me,
one of the people in the car happened to
be the current governor of Connecticut
Sun.
Oh.
So this turned from like some kids prank
called to like said some awful things to
like front page of the newspaper
throughout the entire state of
Connecticut,
a little bit in New York Naacp outside
of my school.
I have to.
It was like this situation that was
talking about outrage culture.
My first like introduction to outrage
culture and the things that sort of
formed my thoughts like this was a very
formative experience in my life.
Um,
which to me it wasn't,
it was nonpolitical.
But it was like my life wasn't mine.
Like I went from like sitting down
watching.
I was watching Talladega nights with my
boyfriend to being the most discussed
person in the state of Connecticut.
And what was interesting about it was
just that,
because it was the governor of
Connecticut sign that was in this car,
they had to get the FBI involved to
determine the authenticity of the,
like maybe she called herself instead of
just saying like,
yes it was my son,
he actually left the FBI,
investigated for six weeks and waited
and to get arrested six weeks.
Like,
you know what I mean,
like his son denying this one,
see if they can get away with it.
But this is politics,
you know what I mean?
Like,
can we get away with it?
Is it plausible for us to get away with
it?
You know,
so six weeks of the entire state.
I didn't,
I left school.
People were like fighting on my behalf.
Fighting.
Yeah,
it was,
it was just like,
yeah,
yeah.
This was just like,
it was like a monstrosity of a situation
and it was one of those things where
like literally like letters to the
editor and be like,
mom's like,
talk about,
you know,
outrage culture,
right.
I don't believe candice,
this happened,
this girl,
I believe she called herself like,
like I'm just looking for attention one
night and I just decided to say I was
going to hang by family from a tree.
Isn't it funny that someone would even
have an opinion on that?
It's,
it's bizarre.
Writes letters to the editor.
Like I.
The whole thing is weird
retrospectively,
right?
Like,
I don't believe her,
but that is what life is about,
right?
You have to go to youtube.
I still don't believe.
Exactly.
So it was the situation that was just
completely out of my control.
And then as quick as it had,
these kids got arrested and then as
quick as it happened,
it was over,
um,
for like everyone but not for me.
Are these kids,
right?
Like,
so I never wanted these kids to get
arrested.
Like if no one look at this whole
situation was taken out of my hands.
People thought I didn't go to the
police.
Like my teacher went to the police.
It turned into the zoo.
These kids were labeled publicly
racists,
right?
The youngest kid in the car,
it was 14.
I'm not comfortable with every labeling,
a 14 year old racist,
right,
or any of these kids racist.
These are kids and in my opinion,
adults that failed to act like adults
and adults that fail to take a step back
and say,
okay,
why would,
what would prompt these kids do this?
Why is it so easy to be mean?
Right.
Why is it so easy nowadays for children
to be mean?
And no one to me,
like when I really thought about that,
I went through like five years of like
anorexia because of the situation
and I was the victim.
Yeah.
And Yeah,
you went through Lexia,
which is so weird now because like
people that know me now,
like there's no way you never didn't
eat.
But I did.
I did like did not eat for like five
years.
I had issues with Anorexia because I
actually has a disease that genuinely is
about control.
It's about a certain control of your
life.
And I felt that I had my,
like my life was fine and then like
people took the narrative,
um,
and I could decide to determine what the
narrative was.
You're in,
you're,
you're a victim or maybe you're a liar,
you know,
these kids are racists,
these kids are this,
and just nobody really thought that,
like you actually ruined all of our
lives.
Right?
Like for a little bit like these kids
went on to have duis and get arrested
and got into drugs and it was because it
was outraged of everything that happened
and I was like,
would have been totally cool with an
apology.
Like,
you know what I mean?
sorry.
Good for you for looking at it that way.
That's hard to do because everybody
loves when they are allowed to get
outraged.
Everybody loves,
get outraged.
Obviously what they did do was horrible,
but I think a lot of kids,
especially if they're drinking,
they don't even understand how stupid
and gross it is what they do and they
just know they can do it and they get a
thrill out of it.
And then there's that mob mentality when
there's like a bunch of people together
doing the same thing,
wrap it up and start saying crazy shit.
Understandable.
When you think about it as a human being
and not as somebody who to ab opinion,
like ear,
like,
hey,
we're going to call this black girl,
right?
You've got a bunch of kids were going to
say mean things to her on the phone and
you don't have to look her in the face.
Right.
It's like if I hold up this pen and
unlike just say mean stuff like
someone's going to get,
you could say anything to this pen.
So it's,
it's sort of um,
it,
it was a formative experience that in
retrospect I understand has so much to
do with why I am who I am because I
hated that,
that label obsessed culture and the
outrage machine and then like,
oh,
okay,
we're done.
But like,
you know,
forget the people that,
whose lives we just like.
No.
Do you know those people anymore?
I don't.
I,
I know like the siblings of them because
I was friends.
Like that's the thing,
like one of the people that was
involved,
I was very good friends with his brother
and it's like,
you're just going to tell me this kid,
like a racist.
Like I actually knew the kid's mother,
you know,
like nobody cared.
It was just hot story necessarily
racist.
They were just stupid,
stupid,
did something stupid and they do that.
That was a way that they could scare
you.
Right.
That they could and they might fit,
you know,
like drunk.
Maybe it was their first beer.
Right.
But people can do well.
The youngest was 14,
the youngest and this person was labeled
a racist.
Like that's to me is like,
that's harsh on people say,
Oh,
you're too forgiving,
but not labeled them a racist because
what they said was most certainly
racist.
Yes.
The words are racist.
Right?
Can somebody,
the.
I guess the question is can somebody say
something,
say a word that is racist and not be a
racist human being?
Yes.
I think now I'm going to tell you why.
Okay.
If somebody stand up,
I was watching,
I actually don't remember who it was.
Like maybe it was Louis Ck,
I don't know,
but he was saying how he like instantly
turns into a racist,
like if somebody cuts him off and it's
like a Chinese person,
like,
like instantly the first thing he has
something to do with him being Chinese.
Right.
And there's a little bit of that in all
of us.
Like I was walking through New York City
the other day and I'm like a huge bus
just happen to like stop in front of me.
And like literally 45 agents got up and
suddenly I was just like,
I couldn't walk around.
I'm like,
oh,
I was like,
why do Asians always travel in packs?
Right?
Like the most bizarre thing,
like I don't have an issue with them or
taking a bus and traveling.
And then afterwards I giggled.
I was like,
what a stupid thing.
Oh,
stupid thoughts even had to have because
I'm frustrated in the moment that I
can't like get my bearings in New York
City.
Um,
so yes,
I think that people in a moment of
frustration of anger,
if you add alcohol,
if you add Ambien,
right?
Um,
and are,
are coming from a place of upset and
they can just do something that's stupid
without holding this like whole word for
the rest of their,
your 14 year racist and forever you are
raised.
That's march.
Yeah.
So especially today.
Today,
nobody wants
anybody to recover from anything.
That's right.
They want to know that you're,
you're dead.
It's over.
Your career is done.
Your life is over.
You said the wrong thing.
Done the wrong thing.
I mean obviously there's some reasons
for some people to be like Harvey
Weinstein's.
Perfect example of that guy should be in
jail.
Of course,
for sure this is a rapist.
Yeah.
This is great.
Police alleged rapist.
What for sure.
He's done a lot of horrible shit.
Correct.
But then there's people that like,
like,
what did Samantha Bee say today?
She called up Ivanka con.
Exactly.
What happens there.
Thinks he gets in trouble.
I bet she doesn't.
She's not going to get into,
but she doesn't because she left wing.
She's left wing overmanned space to say
sorry.
I'm assuming some of this shit that
Keith Olbermann job at espn.
It's,
they don't care.
There are fucking so many tweets that he
put out that are crazy called trump a
Nazi and fuck you and think about what
people say
about like Ben Carson and black
conservatives.
We get.
Ben Carson was literally called a porch
monkey.
Eat it and that's totally fine.
He's black.
It doesn't matter.
They like,
who created this system?
Who is it that did it though?
It wasn't like a famous person,
a famous person.
Absolutely called monkey black person.
Black Person.
That's like if I call a Guy Guinea but
it's porch monkey is not.
I don't care who it's coming from,
right?
Like,
yeah,
but black people are allowed to say
racist shit to other black people.
Which racist.
It's not.
Okay.
None of it's okay if the uncle toms and
we go weird stuff that we have laws or
rules culturally and I don't like those
laws and rules,
so I pushed back.
I hear you.
Yeah,
I agree.
It's definitely hypocritical.
Like someone was saying that there was a
tweet that I retweeted today,
that smallville girl,
that smallville show is still on the air
and that girl is apparently she,
she's admitted to sex trafficking and
that some of it was her idea.
I read the smallville still on the air
and they're pulling Roseanne from Hulu.
Right?
Roseanne swear she did not know that
lady was black.
She swears she.
I mean she doesn't,
she doesn't look,
if you don't allison mack's as branding
the sex slaves was her idea branding
them.
Allison.
That's means like burning a logo into
their bodies.
Right.
What is wrong with that?
I don't know enough about that story.
Put that bitch must be off the charts,
which is crazy.
Yeah,
but it's,
it's only accepted.
Like if you have any ties whatsoever to
conservative thought like if you have
even liked,
liked a tweet that trump sent out,
like forget about it,
forget about it.
Like I'm not even conservative,
but I have conservative people or talk
to and people call me all right and all
this crazy shit.
They're just looking to silence and
labor.
Right.
They're obsessed with labels and I hate
that.
I hate the idea that you can't say
something like they were literally,
I mean everyone piled in every celebrity
on the sun piled in.
When I tweeted a couple of weeks ago
that I was having a conversation,
I don't know if you saw this,
I was like,
I was having a at lunch
because I've just been observing Chelsea
handler.
I just think she's weird person.
Like I don't know what happened because
I used to really like her.
Like you know,
10 years ago when you were liberal.
Yeah,
I.
But like when she was,
had her show,
like she was not politically correct.
I mean I don't know if anybody remembers
the show Chelsea lately,
but she was making fun of everybody and
now with the era of trump,
she's like,
something's weird.
She's getting older and I think she
wants to be an activist now and I think
she's looking for more meaning and
importance because she doesn't have a
family or children and I tweaked that.
Oh,
you tweeted this,
tweet it.
But it's true.
I'm like,
I'm talking to like a friend at lunch.
I was and we were talking about like,
why some of these like older woman I
have just gone bonkers and you know,
my friend made a comment.
She's like,
if you don't like use your eggs,
they scramble.
Like just saying
that.
My friend said,
well I didn't even tweet that.
I didn't tweet that.
You're French.
Put that shit on TV show.
It's really funny if we don't use your
eggs scrambled.
So I was like cracking up.
I know it's a but there's something
there.
There's something there.
It's not politically correct,
but I observed the pattern of Kathy
Griffin.
I observe the pattern of Chelsea handler
and Sarah Silverman on the fence.
Not as bad but in that neighborhood.
So I tweet out,
do you think there's something
associated like between like woman who
don't have children and they need
something to nurture and foster and try
to raise and in this sense it's society.
Like they are just trying to parent the
hell out of society.
And I think Sarah does.
Sarah goes back and forth.
She's like,
she's like,
she's a kind person,
but there's something like once in a
wash,
I'm just like,
what?
Like I did actually go back when I said,
you know what,
Sarah,
I shouldn't put you in the same category
as Kathy and Chelsea,
but it's like this.
They're like obsessed with like
everything and they're completely wrong
and educated about everything and yet
they think they can say whatever they
want.
So I tweet this and I mean everyone was
like,
you'd like to believe that you like l,
like Ellen.
I'm the ellen shows producers.
Like,
I mean jake tapper,
like delete the tweet.
I was like,
I'm not deleting jake.
Jake tapper jumps,
chunked up or delete the three now.
He said,
he said like,
this is literally,
so I tweet,
this has nothing to do with trump.
Anybody.
He's like,
this is the girl who supports trump and
works for turning point USA,
which loves trump.
I'm like,
what were the weirdest,
like logical jump ever.
So yeah.
And I just like,
I'm like,
Jake,
stop yourself.
Like,
come on.
So in the end everyone was just like,
delete the two.
And I was just like,
how about,
what was the actual wording of the
tweet?
I think my exact words were at lunch
with a friend talking about like how
bizarre Chelsea Handler Kathy Griffin
and Sarah Silverman.
So Sarah something.
I just tweeted something like pro
[inaudible] and it was like the whole
Israel.
It was bizarre,
you know,
and how crazy they've gotten.
And then I just said like,
do you think that something really
happened?
Swimming if they don't have children.
And that was,
it's just a question question.
Such a hot spots or you're going after a
soft spot on.
Yeah,
that's it.
Right?
And I'm like,
Sarah Huckabee,
sanders
going to lose her job.
Right?
She can say anything.
We want to say anything that's Sarah.
There's anything to anybody to me,
right?
Anybody that supports trump,
it doesn't matter.
But then like these women who literally
go after these people,
like the amount of vitriol that Chelsea
handler has thrown to Ivanka to every
single woman in the world.
Chrissy teagan's also like a net.
Like she just like angry,
like,
you know,
just like hate,
hate,
hate.
And then like you say,
one thing about them and like they were
like,
how could you even question,
how could you even ask a question if
it's because they don't have kids?
And I'm like,
the fact that you guys are so outraged
makes me sort of think that,
you know,
yeah,
a little bit.
And I didn't delete the tweet.
If you didn't have any point at all,
it wouldn't work in that way.
Just like a stupid
person.
She doesn't know what the fuck she's
talking.
And I tweeted that.
I was like,
there's gotta be something here because
you guys are all losing your minds.
You know,
it's so Sarah Silverman responded.
Kathy Griffin was like,
they went nuts.
This was like a full on,
like Kathy Griffin is so happy someone's
talking about her,
but she's busy and they'd gotten
bizarre.
And at one point these people to me were
funny and something sort of just
happened.
And like trump is the means like they,
whatever they're going through in life,
the outlet is trump.
And anybody that likes trump will people
think there's a cultural war going on
there.
Most certainly is areas for sure,
so they feel like they're on a side and
they have to,
you know,
they're going to lob grenades during the
war and it gives people,
it also gives people a sense of purpose
like that engaging in these twitter
fights somehow or another is like
reinforcing good behavior and shutting
down the bad behavior and don't
necessarily believe that I,
even if I don't agree with someone
online,
I very rarely tweet about them.
I'm not,
I just,
I feel like I try at this stage in my
life to avoid conflict as much as
possible unless it comes to writing
jokes.
Sometimes.
Some people gotta get you gotta take the
hit.
I know.
And usually when I go after someone
like,
I mean I'm not at that phase in my life
where it's all peace.
Like I'm definitely a person that'll
just say something,
but usually it's just in like,
that's what I thought,
you know,
it's not as thoughtful like,
and people were like back down or you
can't,
like this morning or yesterday,
like Ben Shapiro and I got into a little
spat and we actually like each other.
But like I genuinely annoyed by his
behavior online,
like it's genuinely,
yeah,
I just find them to be like,
like,
and by.
I like him.
Like that's the thing that's bizarre.
It's like I think people think there's
much more like hate between us and there
is,
it's like not,
it's just like genuinely like I read a
sweet sound like dude,
shut up when I say,
what did he say?
Just little petty things that he throws
that trump's sometime that are so
unnecessary.
It's not even trump.
It's like he,
like Kim Kardashian goes to,
you know,
get Alice Marie Johnson.
She's been fighting for this for years.
She put all of her money into a legal
team to do this and that's not the only
case she's been working on,
like actually trying to help these
people get clemency and she takes a
picture and he's like,
he says something just very Ben Shapiro.
He was like,
we should not be worshiping.
Slept like that.
Hopefully he's worshiping as we're
taking a meeting
with convention,
not worshiping a celebrity.
These are,
that's a little extreme of an analysis
for a meeting.
And the picture is taken,
like,
you know,
I've visited the president,
there is a full time photographer and
every person that to the president,
you've got a picture of the,
in the Oval Office.
It's like a part of the system.
Um,
and yeah,
so I was just like,
dude,
shut up.
Like,
you know,
like I didn't say shut up.
I said like,
she's got a good point in a way we
really shouldn't be worshiping celebrity
for the sake of celebrity.
And especially reality show celebrity.
I mean,
it doesn't mean that she couldn't have a
very valid point about prison reform.
Yeah,
that's what I'm saying.
That's what I'm saying.
She wasn't he,
I think he said something like,
we shouldn't allow celebrities to shape
policy.
She wouldn't go there shape policy.
She literally had a case that she's been
trying to get.
Pardon me?
The only person that can do that happens
to be President Donald Trump.
It's actually,
you know,
what she's trying to do is actually very
honored.
That's what I said.
I said,
listen,
she.
And she's been working on it for you.
Like,
she's actually into this now.
Like she's into this prison reform and
I'm passionate about it.
Like I grew up seeing my uncle's in
prison.
So like for me,
the only time that I like snap back at
anyone is if it's something that I care
about.
Obviously.
Like I'm,
I really am passionate about black
America.
I'm really passionate about the changes
that can happen for black America and
prison reform or something I'm really
passionate about.
So I've been observing like how hard
yard at and working on this.
I hardly,
Blanca has been working on this and have
really understood what they're trying to
do.
Like,
you know,
I went to the prison reform summit a
couple like a month ago and,
and Kim in this,
she doesn't even like agree with trump
on a lot of stuff.
She's thrown some shade at him,
but this is something is Alison Marie
Johnson case she was doing before trump
got into office.
What I love about the picture of her and
him,
she's like,
where the fuck over here?
I was taking a picture with Donald.
I'd be hugging.
I'd be like,
ha ha.
But she,
she cares about the case.
But look how far away she is from them.
Look at it.
I will say two of them
I will say is awkward though because his
desk is a lot lower than you than you
realize.
That's actually a little closer to like
stand up straight like she's standing or
like Ben,
I bent when I was in there,
which is also kind of weird too.
So it's like you see people who either
like this or they're like this and
there's no in between.
We could do like 19 fifties,
moviestar picture like this.
What do you mean exactly?
I should.
That's what I should've done.
But she's closer than I thought she was.
I felt like maybe I put it in my own
head.
It's actually pretty.
God damn good right there.
She's gorgeous,
but it doesn't look anything like she
used to look.
But yeah,
whoever did that,
nobody does.
Nowadays Mr. Surgeon,
you did some awesome work.
She's plump.
It looks good.
But I guess the question is kind of
celebrity.
Do a good act,
you know,
and.
Sure.
Of course the answer is yes.
I mean that's,
that's what Chelsea handler's trying to
do.
I mean,
that's like she's donating,
but she really is.
She donated a million dollars to Puerto
Rico.
Oh,
right.
Which is good.
Yeah,
that's good.
That should be celebrated.
That's what she's trying to do with all
of her money now.
She doesn't even give a fuck about like,
which is,
which is good.
Good.
All of that stuff.
Like when they do stuff like that,
it's great and it's honorable,
but like the stuff that I hate that
celebrities do and what I wish I
differentiate
from,
and I guess this confuses people is when
they just give their opinion like we,
you know,
at like the emmys and they're onstage
just like teaching all of us about how
wrong our opinions are.
It's like I don't need the celebrity
grandstanding.
Like you know,
if there's an issue you care about other
than the fact that people disagree with
you,
then sure do.
That.
If you care about like Ashton Kutcher
going after sex trafficking,
celebrate that.
That's cool.
Like Kim Kardashian going over after a
crime justice reform.
Celebrate that.
That's cool.
But when you get these celebrities that
just get up there and try to deliver a
tier two,
it's like shut up.
Literally nobody cares what you think
like this.
Well the care enough that that person's
got that platform and they feel like
this is their opportunity to say
something significant.
I'm looking at this girl also like
thinking they're for sure 100 percent
virtue signaling,
letting everybody know how moral and
ethical they are.
Even if they are,
I mean this is just those fucking award
shows or weird as shit.
They're weird.
It's weird.
You should go up there and you should
say thank you God.
Thank you.
Thank you to the man upstairs.
Owed and you for number of the days when
they used to do that.
Yeah.
They used to say a couple of names of
producers come up with a little piece of
paper and then they used to always think
the man upstairs and they used to go
down.
Now they have like,
like the face and the emotion,
you know,
started off.
Started this.
Marlin motherfucking Brando.
Really?
In between having sex with everyone.
Marlon Brando apparently fucked Richard
Pryor.
Who knows what the fuck.
He's fucked a bunch of different people.
I've,
I brought you.
This guy was one Marvin Gaye.
Am I making that up completely?
I think one was like,
it was sad.
It was Marvin Gaye,
but it's,
you know,
it's Pryor's wife admitted it,
which to me is a huge prior fans.
Uh,
there was a spike through the heart.
Quincy said he would fuck anything in
quotes.
Yeah,
I bet it would be fucked.
Richard Pryor.
I mean,
what the hell?
He's still.
He started this.
So he started this because when he won
the academy award for I wanna say it was
apocalypse now.
He had a native American guy go on stage
and take it to this place to highlight
the plight of native Americans.
Maybe it was a different movie,
but it was,
it became as big political.
Marlon Brando was crazy for the
godfather.
The Godfather.
Thank you.
So we had this guy go up and accept the
award in his place and give some speech
is woman.
Oh,
okay.
So then just became like a culture of
like trying to one up each other.
So that was going on really was him.
I just know that that was a miracle.
It's unbearable.
You know,
it's just a little odd.
I can't stand it.
It drives me insane.
But that's a huge difference.
That doesn't mean that I think that
celebrities can't do good in the world.
It's just that like the celebrity
grandstanding can use volume on this job
bearable.
Roger Moret looking all good.
Oh,
so this won't hold on.
Go back to
modern Glendo the godfather.
And so now
my name's a little feather.
Holy Shit.
I look at,
look at them.
They're like,
we can't say shit.
Even back then nobody knew what to do.
Like a
little feather.
I'm the president of the national native
American affirmative image committee.
She's hot as fuck.
She's really pretty
and he has asked me to tell you in a
very long speech,
which I cannot share with you presently
because of time,
but I will be glad to share with the
press afterwards.
CanNot accept this very generous award
and the reasons for this being are the
treatment of American Indians today by
the film industry.
Excuse me,
and on television and movie reruns,
and also with recent happenings at
wounded knee.
I beg at this time that I have not
intruded upon this evening and that we
will in the future our hearts and our
understandings will meet with love.
Pause for a second.
Isn't that what was going on?
Just a second.
This isn't it?
The same place where a couple years ago.
Well,
no,
that wasn't wounded knee.
What was that?
Standing rock
standing rock.
Know that this is heavy head.
Wow.
This is where it all began.
It's where I've
been trying to one up each other.
Maybe I might've made that up.
Like she like one.
She came in around the perfect time.
Yes.
NBC wrote,
this is our president tweeted it.
It's insane.
It's like the not even pretending,
which I appreciate now.
They're not pretending to be the news
anymore.
Like they're just like,
we hate trump and we are the propaganda
machine that will tell you like twitter.
It was just the NBC twitter,
it said something like,
I was just like,
wow,
wow.
And then everyone was out.
There was like the opposite of outrage
culture,
which I don't even know what it is.
It's like run,
run,
run.
You have to run because like speech
secret and Dr Oz.
It's just like I can't take anything
seriously anymore.
So there's things to be taken seriously.
But celebrities probably on that list.
It's hard bureaus,
right?
Yeah.
Dot,
well he's right about this.
But he was trying to correlate like what
Kim did like with Alisha Marie Johnson
with like that.
And I'm like,
come on man.
That's like totally different.
And just in general,
like sometimes she just gets a little
like hall monitor for me.
Like you know,
like it's just like,
you know,
you can't help themselves.
Was very snarky.
I liked him a lot.
I like him too.
That's the thing.
It's like people we actually really get
along,
but like the hall monitor,
I know these types of school,
like I was in their classes,
you know,
like they're just like,
like late
to school or the last person you want to
see is like a hall monitor.
Like you know,
like the idea that she would be late
writing you a pink slip.
It's like Ben just gave me the pink
slip.
Do that.
Just give it to me,
Ben.
All right.
Like right.
This is a gateway to Saturday school.
Like it's just like,
it's so bad
he saying sometimes.
Yeah,
I do that.
A lot of you do that.
How do you do that?
Can't do that.
And he's doing it sober.
He's not like some dudes who do that.
They're all adderall dot.
Yeah,
he does that.
But I liked that.
I liked these kids in school.
I'd just be like,
you know,
I was just the kid that was just like
Kinda like more chill and like I don't
need to like and sometimes new just
schools over stupid stuff.
It's like.
But I do wonder like if he's learning
anymore,
that's the one thing,
like I like,
yeah,
because he doesn't like to have like
it's like once he has an opinion,
like I liked to be,
like to have conversations and I like to
be wrong and about the conversation
because I don't know everything.
I think that's kind of like white people
love this podcast so much because you're
open to learning anything.
Like it will have people on this
podcast.
You're like,
what was he having,
you know?
Because there's some,
there's always something that you can
learn.
There's always something that you don't
understand that you don't know if you
have an open mind.
Right.
And I think that in in many ways and
that like sometimes he's just not open
to learning about certain things and
somebody might know something about a
culture beyond what he knows and it's
just like,
nope,
that's the idea,
right?
Like it's just drives me crazy,
but I like is really fucking smart.
And that's the problem.
That's the problem.
Exactly stupid.
He thinks everyone is stupid.
Know,
like I hate it.
Like I got so annoyed with like the
Kanye West for second to the greatest
article saying Kanye West is just crazy.
I'm like,
yeah,
and I wrote him an email.
I was just like,
dude,
like I understand that to you and the
way that you've done your life.
This doesn't make sense.
Right?
But this is actually really important
for black people to see that he was the
most important thing.
Which thing was it him like,
you know,
him tweeting out.
I love the way cancer was saying,
but beyond that saying that he openly
supported the president so I can see why
ben chips something like that down
initially because to him like culture is
not the way you talk about politics.
Right?
Like because he's by the book,
but he has to understand that by the
book is not the way people in the hood
or being raised by the book.
It's not the way people in the projects
are being raised.
These people have had their families
destroyed and decimated by,
by the welfare system.
Right.
The fathers aren't even at the homes,
you know,
the single motherhood rate jumped seven
from 25 percent in 1965 to 74 percent
today,
and so these kids turn to culture to
father them.
They turned to Jay z and beyonce and hip
hop and Kanye and to tell them what's
right and what's wrong.
So for so long because the left has had
a stranglehold on culture,
they've had a strangle hold on black
America.
So the most significant thing that
opened up this dialogue beyond the work
that I was doing was this simple tweet
and the simple show of support from
Kanye West.
And I was so frustrated that he had,
he had to like in that moment just like
dismiss them as crazy.
It's just like dude,
like just be willing to learn,
like,
you know,
just be willing to say like,
I don't understand why the hell this is
the way that this is why people want to
talk about politics.
Right?
But maybe there's something here.
And I always understood that culture was
the most important vertical.
When Charlie and I first met and we sat
down,
I defined three very minimal.
Charlie is Charlie,
Charlie,
Charlie Kirk is like this 18 year old.
We started turning point USA who I work
for when he was 18 and he is like a
savant.
They call him like trump's boy wonder,
like,
he's a brilliant.
If you want to talk about like smart and
beyond,
like the smartest person I know is
Charlie Kirk,
hands down and he's only 24.
Um,
he didn't,
he didn't go to college,
just like,
I don't know,
just like just reading weird stuff when
he was seven.
I don't know,
like,
just like things that everyone's like,
oh yeah,
I just read that Thomas Soul.
He's like,
yes,
I read it when I was six,
you know,
what am I trying?
Did you not say that?
Could you be cool?
But.
So,
um,
when,
when Charlie and I met and I,
like I told him like my plan to sort of
help black America and wake them up
because I understood how we had fallen
victim to this brainwash.
There was brainwashed,
the leftist dogma.
There's this idea that because we're
black,
we have to vote Democrat anyway.
That is not a Democrat is racist and
against helping us.
That is like what so many black
Americans believe.
I believed it.
You know what I mean?
So,
and I'm a,
I'm a pretty smart girl,
you know,
I've always been a very smart girl.
I've always,
I've always been,
you know,
I've excelled in,
in academics,
right?
So how did I fall victim to it?
The exact same system,
right?
These three verticals,
the first being the family,
that breakdown of the family.
The second one I'm being culture,
which then to me like growing up it was
like Jay z,
like Jay z was God to me.
Like I would throw on like I was,
you know,
I went through a lot of stuff when I was
a kid.
I didn't have a great family,
um,
you know,
but I would throw on a Jay z album and
like whatever he said was like,
it was like going to church,
you know?
And then,
and I can't stand them now,
but the third vertical,
no,
because he knows exactly what he's doing
and he's a trader,
but the third vertical being education,
which was casual side trader,
yeah,
it's like beyonce and Jay z because he
knows what's happening to black America
and he's somebody that built his entire
career off the backs of black America,
you know,
of being the guy who started in the
honing in in Queens and worked at,
you know,
as a drug dealer and worked his way up
and it became the ideal for so many
people in Black America.
And then he stands on stage and endorses
Hillary Clinton.
He stands on stage and tell us,
black America to put the same people in
the White House that locked up more
black men than any present history of
United States.
Bill Clinton,
right?
The person that stands on the crime bill
of 94 is Bill Clinton.
But because Jay Z is now focused on
getting a piece of the pie,
the globalist piece of the Pie,
he doesn't care about black America.
Um,
that's,
that's my opinion.
Um,
so what,
what it was or do you think that maybe
he thought that Donald Trump represented
a lot of racist white people?
No.
Oh God,
no.
Not even.
Kind of,
not,
not for a single second,
Jay,
because Jay z is very smart now.
I didn't speak to him.
I just,
I know like there's a certain thing
where like I just,
I know that Jay z and beyonce betrayed
the black community.
Like there they are.
I think they did it purposely for
financial gain.
Yeah,
I think,
yeah,
I think that they,
they,
they were interested in having,
they want to be
the people that control the world and
they felt that Hillary Clinton,
you know,
they were working with Obama very
closely and very cluey.
Now we know that the Obama
administration worked very hard to get
Hillary Clinton to office and they
wanted to stay in that group.
And so they supported Hillary Clinton
who was selected behind closed doors,
forget the American people to the next
president.
United States selected certainly by the
DNC.
Yeah,
no 100 percent.
But beyond that,
it was an embed with Obama,
you know,
she was our secretary of state and she,
she was doing deals behind closed doors
and Jay Z and beyonce,
we're a part of that click,
right?
So they were a part of the celebrated
celebrities that were allowed to go to
the White House and they'd wear the ties
and everybody will be taken photo.
But it was a cool thing to be friends
with Obama,
right?
Nobody wants to go to the White House
and like celebrities.
It's hard to get celebrities to go with
trump.
There's so much controversy attached to
attach your career.
Can you get attacked and attacked by
quarter left and right?
Part of what's happening with Rosanna is
not just that you made a racist tweet,
she didn't know it was racist.
She supports trump and then she,
her character supports trump and people
were looking for something to hate her
over and she handed it to them.
You know,
you,
you stick your neck out in that way and
you're just people on the left for sure.
Look at anyone who's a trump supporter
as an open target.
Even if they're a reasonable person,
even if they're a person who is kind and
measured and very even keeled,
he's like the nicest person I've ever
met about the trump,
you know,
and she's like never responds,
never punches back.
And,
and look what they,
how they treat her.
Well,
this house,
Samantha Bee did it.
But yeah,
other people have gone after all the
time.
They go after Ivanka.
She's such a kind person,
but it's just because her father is
Donald Trump.
So it's open season and that's why jake
tapper jumps into a tweet about Chelsea
handler and tries to correlate trump.
It's like they're obsessed with people
that I'm like,
trump.
I like trump.
I don't know what to say.
I liked the guy.
I think it's really funny to have jake
tapper on the news the day of the
election.
We did a comedy.
We did a podcast from the comedy store.
Uh,
we,
we call it the end of the world podcast,
have a bunch of people because whoever
the fuck when's the end of the world,
this live podcast.
And uh,
I went into the green room afterwards to
the comedians bar and jake tapper was on
TV and he was so bummed out and I took a
photo of him like him on the screen.
You just see the sadness.
I remember his face.
He was really sad.
He was sad to find that,
oh my God,
it's
the best likes,
like a splice together,
like all of the clips of just like it
was exceptional.
The news anchors and the emotion that
was coming out of them.
And he did some crazy thing is all of
them that said he'll never win.
You'll never win.
It's forever.
They laughed,
they laughed.
I remember there's a moment where like
Ann Coulter,
they said,
so who do you have winning?
And she says,
Donald Trump.
And they broke into laughter,
like the cool kids,
the cool kids at the,
um,
at the lunch table.
And that's really how they've been
acting like they're not interested.
They think that they're the cool kids at
the lunch table and they get to define
what's cool and they're just having a
rude awakening right now.
And it's beautiful to watch.
I love it,
I love it.
He loves an upset to.
Yeah,
people love enough.
And then they also wants their team gets
in.
Then they want to support their team so
they fucked up.
I'm making it tribal.
Tribal right.
Versus left.
People go,
well,
fuck these guys.
Fuck Jake tapper.
I'm going on this side.
That's my team now.
It's like team sports fanatics right
now.
It doesn't even matter.
There's little sense anymore.
It's just like this is the team that
I've plugged my life too.
And part of that is ego.
Like you just spent how many months
calling everybody racist,
sexist,
deplorable.
Are you really going to go,
man,
you know what?
I was wrong.
They have to hold on to something.
Right?
And,
and I see that because like when I went
to this prison reform summit,
I'm Van Jones was there and,
and Donald trump is speaking and it was
like love between them.
It was.
But this is the guy that said White
Lash,
you know,
right after the election.
And He,
you know,
but how,
how can he go back from that?
It's very hard to,
you know,
peddle backwards from that.
So half of them are fake in my opinion.
I find them to be fake because I've seen
them behind closed doors.
They don't feel that animosity for the
president cause it's hard to.
He's really likable.
I mean like his presence when you meet
him,
he's very aware of himself.
He's aware of the jokes that are being
made about him.
He'll make the jokes about himself and
yeah,
he's,
he's likable,
he's got the.
He just has something about him when he
makes a tweet,
a memorial day saying that the dead
soldiers would be really happy to know
how the economy is doing and how black
unemployment.
It's the slowest.
Never been like,
that shit was ridiculous.
I actually missed that to you.
I'm just laughing as I.
every time someone says a trunk to be,
I just like,
I laugh.
I just think it's funny that he put the
me in memorial.
There was an article,
I'm telling you,
I'm telling you we're in going in
different directions.
Like I predict in 20 slash 20,
like he's not going to go on seat and
he's going to be like,
be here.
Like it's like he just wants to talk and
it's really hard.
It's really hard for these people to
speak because what happens is they go
onto a stage and the room,
they love him.
They great.
Everyone loves him because he's really
likable.
You can't be in room with trump and not
laugh and like him.
But then they take out his fingers right
now I know they take away the,
the clips and they spliced up and they
make it,
like he said something bad,
but what they're doing is it's a
terrible game to play because you're not
just lying on trump.
You're lying on the 50,000 people,
you know,
the thousands of people that are there
to hear him speak,
right?
Like so they're playing a game where
then those people get pissed off with
me.
You think they're playing a game where
they're,
they're misinterpreting the things that
he's said plenty of shit.
The way they spliced it up.
Like for example,
when that,
that,
that moment when he says,
Oh,
if this was the old days,
we take you,
we take you out to the back,
like,
you know,
do you remember that moment when he said
while he was running and somebody was,
you know,
causing a circus in the
crowd and like he was like,
get him out of here.
And then the way they ran it,
right?
Like,
oh,
like when in the old days when they used
to like hang black people from trees.
Like what?
Why?
I think he literally meant that you used
to be able to get your ass kicked.
That's how they spin it.
And then same thing,
like when he said you,
what do you have to lose?
Prior to that,
he had listed every stat.
We're quietly,
you got tentative and you're like,
oh,
you know what I mean,
the loser,
you know?
But then they get that clip in there
like,
oh,
trump is insulting black America.
He's saying that they all live in.
No,
he's saying this.
Typically speaking,
if you look at the people that live in
the projects are going to be letter in
poverty.
It is black America,
so he's asking the current,
the past administrations have not been
serving you.
What do you have to lose?
So it frustrates me because it's like
you see that,
um,
that they mix it up and they try to
divide the country,
but at the end of the day,
unfortunately for them,
he's actually really likable and same
for don trump,
junior like,
I mean they're,
they're really funny.
They're really likable and they're aware
of themselves.
Like they're in on the joke guys like,
well,
Jamie was telling me the other day that
they made some video.
What was the video that they made to see
if you can find that video was really
funny with her all mocking themselves
about that.
What was it about that Laurel and um,
yeah,
the two words.
I actually haven't even heard the words
that everyone was.
I haven't either.
I'm like,
fuck you.
I'm not paying attention to that stupid
shit.
I will not listen to the board.
Yeah,
just to woods in my life.
I don't care.
I literally don't care.
I didn't even listen to the word,
but yeah,
they made fun of themselves.
Yeah.
Let's see.
It will play it.
Kellyanne Conway.
Was it?
Give it to us from the beginning.
John Young.
Jamie.
This is a different.
It's a different one.
The news put it up so I've got to get
the real one.
They put.
Okay.
It's,
it's hilarious that they have.
I mean this is,
this is actually a very clever thing to
do
because they.
But they're all like that.
Like Ivanka,
like they're all aware of the joke,
like they're in on it
here for sure.
Do you have an ad blocker on?
Yeah.
You clever bastard.
So clean.
It's Laurel.
It's Laurel,
but I could deflect and divert to Yanni
if you need me to do that.
Definitely.
I don't know.
It's
sorry.
Laura.
Sara,
it's been reported that you hear more or
how do you respond?
Clearly you're getting your information
from CNN because that's fake news.
Uh,
all I hear is yawning.
Oh Man.
That's Laurel.
Laurel.
To stop this.
What is,
what is wrong here?
Something going on today.
The things messing up.
What is messing up the tri caster?
Yeah.
We to do that thing we were talking
about and fix up.
Anyway.
It's just the idea is that these people
had the sense of humor and then with the
trump at the end he's doing.
What is he saying?
Was He at
a year?
Yeah.
That's funny.
Yeah,
and that's the thing is they're like,
like they were in on the joke and I
think that people don't realize like how
in on the joke they are like,
they're like,
he's aware that you say all this stuff
about the fact that he tweets out and
says all of this stuff.
Right?
Like,
like don trump junior is aware that he's
a billionaire son and that's what people
say,
Oh,
you're a billionaire.
So and like they're so funny and that
it's sad that people don't get to see
that side.
So I actually do hope that they all come
on the show because it's.
People should actually see how hilarious
they are and how aware of themselves
they're like the most to me,
in my opinion,
the most likable,
relatable first family of my lifetime.
Like,
you know,
I can't speak to anyone but there.
So you didn't think that Obama and
Michelle were likable.
My God.
Oh my God.
Are you going to like Obama?
Like he was a likable guy.
Just,
you know what's funny,
I was at a dinner last night with people
that came over from Cuba and this woman
said that when she first heard Obama
speak and she was,
she was way older.
She broke down crying because it
reminded her of the first time shared
Fidel Castro street,
which is a bizarre thing to say,
right?
I was just like,
well,
I don't know anything.
I've never been to Cuba.
And they got scared that America was
going to turn into a communist country.
It was with a bunch of Cubans.
Yeah.
Crazy.
Right?
Like they literally came out of their
mouths but have ptsd but what they know,
but what they say could be.
It could be,
but what they were saying was like the
veneer of it all.
Like,
like,
you know the.
It was like exactly what you wanted to
hear.
Obama said,
and the perfect and the perfect home.
The perfect hand mannerism with,
um,
with the,
I don't know,
the perfect inflection in his voice and
there's something about that to me,
like,
especially the person that I am,
that just was super inauthentic and not
saying,
by the way,
when Obama won in 2008,
I cried like the let's,
let's,
let's let me not be fake here.
Like I was like,
like he's black,
I'm black,
everything was going to be great,
you know?
Um,
but,
uh,
you know,
as things went on and I was watching
him,
it just,
everything seemed so fake and he wasn't
really doing anything.
So I just don't respond to that sort of
a personality.
I liked that authentic and I think
that's why trump coming in behind him,
um,
was so relatable as a precedent.
Like there's this theory and it's a good
one.
Bye.
Tumor,
Koran,
that,
why do you like revolution?
Revolutions take place unexpectedly.
You could argue that right now America
is having a revolution.
It's,
we're not out there shooting each other,
but there's an ideological revolution,
a cultural war,
if you want to call it,
that's taken place.
And too many people just seems
unexpected,
right?
Obama was in office and then like,
Whoa,
went to Donald Trump.
You know,
and the theory is that when you're,
when the public and the private of an
individual,
our personas get too far apart,
a natural evolution takes place.
And Society really has just been so
fake.
It.
I mean,
like everything offends you.
Everywhere you go.
People get offended by people's hair.
Like literally Kardashians will put
their hair in braids and the whole
Internet will explode.
Saying that they need to pay tribute to
Africa.
Like the crazy.
I'm like,
I have never in my life looked at
someone's hair and felt emotional.
I'm just like,
whatever you're doing,
your hair is fine with me.
Like if you took the time to do it,
it's fine with me.
But the idea is,
is that as a culture we've become so
fake.
I'm just looking to get angry at things.
I think it's fake thing.
It's fake.
It's 100.
There's no person that can tell me that.
Like the first time they saw Braden,
someone tear and upset them.
But then somebody told them that they
should be upset,
but like privately when they're at home,
do you think they get upset when they're
watching TV?
I think they do.
I think there's some people to get upset
at a lot of stupid shit.
I don't think.
I don't think they're inauthentic with
their being upset.
I just think their focus in their anger
is just misguided and dumb.
Yeah.
Maybe.
Maybe it's the dumb part.
Maybe it's just when it gets to dumb
with hoop earrings,
shit,
it's like crazy.
Like Bantu Braids,
you need to pay tribute to the island of
Jamaica.
I'm like horse off.
Like you've got to be a really inspired
person to even look up why you're
offended.
Like that takes a lot of research.
Like who is researching?
Like who started the Bantu knots,
like who's who started the corn row.
I'm like,
you've got a lot of time on your hands.
For me personally,
like if I could just not have to
research why I'm offended,
have a little more time.
Ejections boom,
power grid goes down.
Lightening storms million times greater
than anything and we wouldn't be worried
about braids anymore.
I know.
It's insane.
Too easy.
It's too easy.
It's too easy to live.
There's no wolves in the street.
There's no humor either.
That's another thing is like,
especially like you a former standup
comedian,
right?
Current.
You still buy,
but do you tore in and do you do comedy
or
comedy or do you.
Okay,
so to speak.
I don't speak ever do I speaking right
now?
Places you do that shit.
I don't do that shit.
Get you on the road.
Could just be having conversations with
the crowd.
People love to talk to you.
That's tiresome.
So the thing is like how is it difficult
when you're standing?
You can't say anything anymore because
like five seconds in your whole life can
be over.
Can you just have to legitimately not
give a fuck and have a bunch of good
friends that you really love and you
know,
you surround yourself with loving people
and you all support each other and then
when people get mad at you,
that's what I do.
People don't realize.
I think they don't realize how little I
care about their outreach.
I've always say to myself,
I wonder if they knew how little I
cared.
If they actually write the article,
like if they actually knew how little I
care a little.
You still talking about jake tapper and
fascinated by it and fascinated.
Just look at Jake tapper was like a day
where they all were just like,
ah,
and then like the next day,
his fist right now.
Yeah.
Then the next day it was over like,
you know,
like just now with like Ben Shapiro.
It's like no one cares.
Like I don't care.
I know Ben doesn't care like that.
I don't like it.
We're going to teach other in one week,
like in two weeks I'm in Texas,
we're doing an event together.
Like I see them all the time and I like
them,
but like to everyone else they're
weighing in.
It's like,
it's like,
so this is your business though.
This is your,
you're in the business of politics now.
Now this is what I want to get to.
How do you go from being a liberal who
cried when Obama was elected?
He's black on black.
Yay.
How do you go from that to being miss
conservative poster girl in 2018?
Because that's what you are 10 years
later.
No,
you are like a lot of people that are
conservative.
They love the fact that you're
attractive,
you're smart,
you're articulate,
you're black and you,
you're fucking forceful with your
thoughts and ideas and you them through
quick and
you're not scared of pissing people off.
And this is very exciting to
conservative people that are on the
sidelines.
It's like we got fucking great running
back,
you know,
we're going to win the superbowl this
year.
Like that's how they look at you like
you're,
you're like a great soldier in the
field.
That's how people look at it.
That's fine.
You know,
I appreciate that.
So how do you go from that?
What happened to reconcile?
What happened to me in high school?
We got to that and then we got off track
two things that I wanted to correct the
world.
I guess I wanted to correct what had
happened to me,
so the first thing was I launched a
website,
like a blog for young girls that were
going through things I had gotten out of
the eating disorder and I wanted to just
give girls that may be going through
something a way to.
Right,
right.
So I do I build this blog,
would you go and eat?
I tell them they can write whatever they
want.
That was the first thing.
The second thing I wanted to do was to
combat like I felt and I still feel in
my soul that children today are growing
up in a time that people can't,
don't even stop to think about,
we have 10 year olds that are killing
themselves over snapchat.
Like if someone posts a picture on
snapchat and they killed themselves,
you know,
and no one has really thought about how
much technology has negatively impacted
the ability for a child to grow up.
Right?
But they're concerned about the way they
look.
Like I used to Babysit name to put
myself through some years of college and
I'm a nanny for these kids.
So they care about how they look when I
was 10.
Like I didn't care how I looked,
I didn't even know how I looked at it.
I definitely didn't have seen the
pictures.
Right.
So,
so,
and now we have kids color.
Just so the second thing I wanted to do,
I said I have this great idea that I'm
going to build this project.
Um,
and this is,
this is the,
the,
the social autopsy bit that the
youtubers were freaking out about and
they thought that it was a political
machine and it was going to be to help
children.
I found that
it never launched.
It was an idea that I had to build
something that would be like screenshots
of what people said online and like to
put them in like a timeout.
So I literally,
we were going around,
we were meeting with high school,
like high schools and saying like,
we're thinking about building something
for children that.
So instead of going to prison,
because you send a mean tweet or a snap,
like what if you just couldn't like trap
for the football team,
you know what I mean?
Like what if like your teachers to check
the database to see like how you're
behaving online.
Was it like naive going back like sure,
like it.
But the idea that the feedback that we
were getting from principals was like
first try it on adults because like if
this goes awry,
like to do this for children is not
going to be a great idea.
So I started kickstart her saying that
I'm raising money for this project to
help combat online bullying.
Like it was like a project that was so
from the heart,
it was just like trying to rectify the
wrongs that I felt were done for these
kids that aggressed me,
you know,
in high school.
And instead I ended up in the middle of
a firestorm again.
It's unbelievable.
I was like,
God really?
I'm a Gamer Gate scandal like that.
Do you know about this?
Um,
you've spoken to my leg.
So I knew nothing about it.
It wasn't a Gamer,
I wasn't lying,
I wasn't politics,
nothing about it,
um,
but I put this kickstarter up saying
like,
what we're doing is figuratively lifting
the masks off of trolls and the Internet
lost its mind.
It lost its mind.
And a girl named Zoe Quinn who was
patient,
one of the Gamer Gate scandal calls me
and at this point she was working for
twitter as the official anti harassment
or twitter and she basically threatens
me and tells me to kill the project.
And I had no idea at the bread and
butter of the Gamer Gate scandal called
me on the phone.
She contacted me via twitter.
My numbers were threatened first she
started off with like,
I'm the girl that was the victim of
Gamergate.
And instantly to me it was all people
don't wear a victim like a badge.
Like I knew this because I had gone
through this in high school and she was
like,
I'm telling you why you need to kill
your project immediately.
Um,
because there are people,
you know,
there are that harassed me and they will
harass you if they find out about it.
I'm trying to save you,
like,
you know,
and I was Kinda like,
I appreciate that and I'd be like,
no thank you.
And then she got like,
you know,
increasingly like you have to kill this
project.
And then she started crying.
It was like very bizarre phone call.
I'm super confused.
So your project was to take the masks
off trolls.
Figuratively.
We'd never had built a technology.
We never like what we were saying,
like what we were going to literally do
was archive facebook messages because
kids on the Internet will being
ruthless.
Yeah,
fine.
Their messages and archive it.
So why don't you have an issue with
this?
I don't understand.
My kickstarter said,
I guess I said a word that made them
think that we were going to be able to
unmask twitter trolls,
like a tow something that we had never
even thought of that like literally like
that we were gonna be able to like build
the technology name is going to be like
that's Joe Rogan.
No,
we did not build this.
This is like crazy.
Like we literally had an idea to a
better place.
If I know I actually not opposed to
that,
but we weren't building it,
you know,
that was she opposed to it.
That's why I'm so,
you know,
the bread and butter of the Gamer Gate
scandal is that people say she harassed
herself.
Okay.
I didn't know this.
I just hung up the phone with her.
Yeah.
I hung up the phone with her and she was
like,
if you go through with this project her,
these were her last words,
you're going to ruin everything.
Crying and hangs up the phone.
I was like,
what?
Oh.
So you're saying that people think this
is the Gamer Gate scandal.
She harassed herself in order to get the
left media helped her and launched like
a thousand charities.
Like all of these girls harassed
themselves.
So this is like literally why Milo's
some people have definitely harassed
themselves.
Yes.
And the whole,
she was the first person that this
started with and everyone of these
gamers like,
mind you,
I'm a Gamer.
I'm just telling you the two sides that
I walked into,
I didn't know.
So I hang up the phone with her and nice
and a tweet that was like,
don't know who zoe Quinn is and I can
tell you this girl has never been
harassed and the world breaks what I was
going to say.
My,
the finished resends.
I know some people have harassed
themselves.
They faked it,
but way more people have actually been
harassed.
I'm sure I agree.
I'm just saying that her in particular
and you say by talking to her,
she's never been around 100.
I,
dude,
I know like I'm telling you,
victims don't like,
you would never like be like I'm the
victim of it.
It's something that you know,
here,
here that's the story.
So I hang up the phone with her.
I tweet this within one hour we start
getting inundated.
Just like she said,
she said,
if you don't kill the project,
I mean trump supporters are going to
come after you and start harassing you.
Like literally,
like we're getting inundated with emails
that say like Bob@trumpfortyfive.com and
they're like die and were die.
Like if you go through it like we're
going kill it,
just like the most,
like I was like,
well this is kind of perfect,
right?
Like you warn me and then it happens.
Like within an hour we had had no
messages,
nothing,
and then all of a sudden I was full on
like,
and I was like,
no,
no sweetheart,
you did this like you aren't restricted
this.
And she had been accused of doing this
like five times.
Like it wasn't like Milo and Breitbart.
We're just covering all of the instances
that people have accused her of like she
calls them and then they get harassed.
She calls them and then they get
harassed and I didn't give up.
I had no horse in the race.
I don't care about,
you know,
gamers respectfully.
I don't game right.
I didn't care about politics,
you know,
respectfully.
At that time it wasn't politicking.
I just had a phone call with the girl.
It was a little weird phone call and
then I suddenly,
I was getting inundated with emails and
just making youtube videos at the time.
No,
I was literally like fully doing this
degree with anything and I was going to
really try to build this high school,
like this thing to help kids that
everyone says you docs minors like
literally like we were building this
platform is that children will never
have to be like get in serious trouble
for doing stupid stuff.
Like via technology ever.
How did she get your contact?
She messaged me.
I gave it to her.
She messaged me on twitter,
like she was burnt,
which are something that you and I,
I like it literally her Hannah was burnt
rich and like at that time I wasn't even
like on twitter,
like I had just made a twitter profile
and I see someone that has a check mark
and it says like official whatever
handle of twitter.
So what seems more official than like a
check mark?
And so I was like here's my number,
call me.
We'd love to talk.
Like,
you know,
you're going to have a conversation with
that maybe wants to partner with me
because I'm like oh this girl's been
harassed on the Internet.
Like maybe she'll like want to help
kids,
like,
you know,
like Alice in Wonderland,
like totally like insane alice in
wonderland and then like all of a sudden
there's like a Cheshire cat who's like
smoking.
So you think that someone orchestrated
this attack at 100 percent fake trump
supporters that we're going after that.
That was my,
like I was like,
oh,
how can we,
we've been on kickstarter for three days
and no one has harassed us.
You call me and tell me killed a project
or I'm going to get harassed.
I hang up the phone with you and now or
later we're getting inundated with
harassment people.
She was saying that you were going to
get harassed by trump supporters.
She said she,
she didn't say trump supporters.
They all have their addresses happened
to be like,
you know,
like trump 45 at ge,
whatever it was like they would,
they would actually have like weird porn
handles.
Like,
I don't know,
like weird handles,
you know?
I still have them.
I would have to pull it up.
Why did she think that someone was going
to harass you?
That's,
I'm still confused.
She was saying she was trolls.
Yeah,
and that's what she said when the
Gamergate people like these,
these anonymous men who were harassed
people,
the people that harassed me,
when they see what you're working on,
they're gonna,
they're gonna Freak out,
you can't do it.
They've ruined my life.
You know,
she's.
And then she started saying,
you're going to get doxed.
They're going to find out what your
parent lives.
And like literally after that someone
sent me like a map and they had dogs to
my family,
like my grandmother,
like where she lives,
my grandfather.
Like it was just like,
was what she said was going to happen to
you contacting her.
So you think that she did.
She did it like I've said this a
thousand times.
I said,
and then the second I said it,
all of a sudden the New York magazine in
the Washington Post tried to smear me
instantly.
Instantly.
At that time I thought,
no,
it's not implausible with the timeframe
of getting no.
Nobody messaging me right.
To her calling me all of this flooding
in.
And then the New York magazine,
I was a girl on kickstarter,
why the hell is the Washington Post
calling me after I tweet this girl
harassed yourself,
the Washington Post New York magazine,
the usual suspects right now,
the usual.
So at that time I was like,
oh great.
The Washington Post,
I was like,
totally an idiot.
Um,
you know,
we're rushing to say like,
oh,
candice got confused.
Like it's,
it's,
it's been a long time internet
conspiracy.
So we Quinn's harassed herself and
Canada's got sucked in and like,
I don't even know what Gamergate is.
I don't know,
like,
I don't even know this article is about,
had no idea that there was accusations
that she had arrived.
Zero,
none.
The hall been harassed.
It's an instinct.
One instinct.
And I got in the middle of a cultural
war and people were like,
get in touch with Nero.
I'm like,
fuck,
is nero was Milo Yiannopoulos or the
tucker again,
just like,
even though like you just like landed.
And then people that I thought were
white nationalists,
which was like,
Breitbart was the only publication that
was like just telling the truth about
what's happening.
Like just saying like,
this girl jumped on kickstarter this
like,
she's no pulling no leg in this race to
nonpolitical.
I'm not end like,
this is what she says happened.
So it was just a,
it was a very bizarre situation.
But it changed my life because the
people that I would have thought in that
moment would have like come after me and
said awful things about me or said like,
we're the people that were very kind,
like,
you know,
at that time I would've said I was a
liberal,
you know,
I would have said like,
I supported Bernie Sanders or Hillary
Clinton,
you know,
whatever it was.
He probably wasn't politically active.
And people that were like reaching down
and just being kind were like Mike
Cernovich,
who if I googled his name,
said it was,
he was like a white supremacist.
So it just was like a weird thing.
Like my whole life just went like,
I was like,
well,
okay.
So one interaction,
that's all it took.
It's a subsequent firestorm.
Is there ever been any proof at all
who's done what you think she did?
Just a bunch of people saying the same
thing that had nothing to do with one
another in different situations and the
media refusing to,
to um,
so like one of those blamed the victim
things nobody wants,
unless there's just overwhelming and she
never responds like I've said it,
a thousand things.
Like she harassed her,
like she never responds and I stick by
that.
I'll never veer from that.
And it was.
But I always say that was,
that was my moment,
like this project that I had never even
built out.
Um,
that changed everything.
I like,
I stopped the project and I subsequently
just wanted to learn.
Like I just like,
is it possible that I got to 26 years
old and have everything wrong about
people that I thought,
you know,
I was just believing in the background.
You know,
that anybody that CNN said this one
interaction with one person that may or
not be deceptive,
why would that make you switch political
affiliation?
It was even switching.
I wasn't politically active.
I just like if you had asked me,
I would've said I wasn't.
You know what I'm saying?
Like I was never,
I was never a girl wearing a pussy hat
outside.
Like people don't understand if if
chest,
no,
God,
if press now that I think of like where
I'm at now and talking about how I hate
labels,
I was probably already a conservative
but I didn't give a shit about politics.
I had $100,000 in student loan debt and
I was just trying to pay back.
That's it.
That was my whole life.
There was nothing about politics,
but at that moment it made me,
it was forced to me to consider my
political affiliations because I had me
saying this.
I'm saying like,
you know,
the New York magazine like tried to
smear me.
I say the Washington Post I just made me
at the exact same time Donald Trump is
getting on a stage and he's saying
they're fake news.
It was just this divine moment trying to
smear you.
So they called me and pretended to be my
friend.
I'm like,
we just wanna know what happened.
Like I told him the story,
I gave him messages of like Zoe,
the timestamps that the hate vibe and
receiving and then the articles that
they wrote were like the.
I'm like,
dude,
I just have a conversation with you on
the phone.
Like insane stuff.
Like,
I mean I'm like,
you know,
the Washington Post actually,
because I caught them in a lie.
I recorded the conversation and the
email of what she wrote didn't match.
They pulled the article.
I said,
if you run this article,
I will sue you guys for libel.
And the manager pulled the article and
he was like,
you're not even relevant or even
important.
Really.
We don't have to run this article I'm
writing.
I still have it.
They were ready to lie.
They were trying to make it.
They were trying to make it seem that I
had like they were trying to figure out
who was funding.
So like social autopsy was what that was
the like what the journalists were
trying to figure out for whatever
reason,
like who's helping you.
So when I refused to say any names,
I just got that weird gut feeling on the
phone.
Like I'm like,
why are you like,
I'm telling you like,
this girl has been harassing her.
So why are you trying to figure out
where I'm getting money from?
You know?
Um,
and when I refuse to answer the,
the girl was going to like,
lied and tried to say that I had said
certain names that she was just trying
to get like other anti bullying,
like organizations to come out and say I
was a liar.
Like say I was working with them but I
had never said any names throughout the
phone and somebody gave me a tip.
Like one of the antique,
I'm not gonna say the name of the.
They gave me a tip and said that,
you know,
they called and you know,
did you tell them this?
And I was like,
no.
I was like,
I literally have the recording.
And they were like,
you need to lawyer up like the
Washington Post is trying to smear you
if.
Because he just wasn't that they said
that you hadn't said they were trying to
say that they were basically going to
try to get a really reputable
anti-bullying company to issue a strong
statement against me calling me a liar,
but this company,
because I had been in touch with them
because I had been on the phone with
them,
had a sense that it just wasn't like
they didn't feel good out the reporter
either,
so they gave me a heads up.
I had actually recorded the conversation
with the Washington Post was in the
conversation that they didn't want to
prove they were going to print.
That like I said,
that this company was supporting me and
they reached out to that company and
that company denied it,
but I had never said that they was just
the way to say that I was a liar.
I never said it.
You get what I'm saying?
The conversation.
Oh,
my instinct was just like,
record the conversation.
So imagine like you go through that and
then Donald Trump gets on the stage and
he was like,
Washington Post is fake news.
Jeff Bezos is like,
it was just like this,
like order things from Amazon.
I.
It's awful.
I know that one click.
I know.
It's just amazing.
I know I shouldn't.
I shouldn't,
but what do you need?
Crazy glue,
Bab.
I hear there's another company coming
out and
he's got us all.
I know I lot shit off Amazon.
I know.
I do too.
I can't even deny it.
I know.
It just shows it's there.
It's just when you get home,
it's there.
It's home to you know.
Do you think he has anything to do with
the Washington Post?
Because he bought it.
It's his personal diary.
Now of course,
if you have you seen the stuff that they
were their publishing show subscribe to
it online,
meaning I pay to get it online,
pay for propaganda.
Well occasionally I have a good story.
Yeah,
it's all it's propaganda.
I,
I can't take any other article series
this up.
They've run and that they've said it's
just like it just everything.
I mean like the stuff that you read like
the Washington Post lately.
Do you like what was the last good
article?
Let me ask you,
what was the last that you thought this
was a fair and balanced reporting job by
Washington Post?
They don't hate trump.
They just went to report the news.
Difficult question,
because I read too many articles.
I'd have to go back and see which one.
What's the number one?
What's the number one article on the top
of today?
Right now?
That would be an interesting question.
Let's get.
Let's get a trump.
I'm going to go ahead with it out there.
Will.
It could be saying because it correlates
to trump.
Maybe it's,
uh,
what's her face be?
They're going to burn me that story.
Okay.
Lynn manual.
Miranda metal.
Tariffs trigger retaliation from Mexico.
I will trade war that Samantha Bee,
apologize.
After White House.
Couldn't condemnation calling Ivanka
trump a vulgar word I went to.
They're forgiving her.
Forgiving her in that.
Just thinking of the headlines.
Yeah.
She apologized and she looks nice in
that picture.
Will be forgiving her.
She apologizes after combination.
Ivanka trump a word.
Why don't they just can come on camera
for airing the word.
Oh,
they did it on TV.
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute was on her TV show.
Cut The fuck was on TV.
It's insane.
That's tbs had to apologize to tbs said
Gunt.
No,
it was on her shows on tbs say cunt.
Like the word they just apologize for.
No,
no,
no.
I'm saying did they air the actual word
or did they beat.
I don't know.
That's a good question.
Yes.
You remember when Steven Colbert,
when he,
uh,
he said he,
that trump uses a Putin uses trump's
mouth for his cock holster.
That shit's crazy.
That's what I'm,
that's what I'm saying.
They would lose their mind.
Just imagine.
Imagine people that get it the worst are
black conservatives like that.
Like we get the things that people say
to us.
And what's bizarre now is white
liberals,
like,
they just feel comfortable.
So I'm like,
why to like this?
It's like so weird.
They'll,
they'll write and they'll say anything
to me.
TBS networks.
It's taking the right action,
the right action,
and apologizing for the vial and
inappropriate language used about Ivanka
trump last night.
Those words should not have been aired.
It was our mistake too.
And we regretted,
what is this?
I do not like the way they worded that
she's taken the right action.
So they,
they,
they have a positive action attributed
to her before that negative.
When you read,
when you read what,
how they're going to interpret it while
she was there.
It's always going to be going to be
positive,
but it's just not going to get fired.
That's oddly positive.
They're not going to know because
there's a double standard is double
standard.
And this is what I heard Roseanne when
she had the number one show in the
country,
they just threw away a lot of money with
that one.
Yeah.
And also,
you know,
and did a lot of jobs for people to hook
it up.
I think she doesn't want to do it
anymore.
Talking to Roseanne.
Yeah.
Personally I think she was so worn out
from doing that show.
She's 66 years old,
you know,
and she's not in the best of health.
And she told me she got bronchitis doing
the show and she almost died.
She was like,
I'm too fucking old for this shit.
I can't do this anyway.
And they were wearing me out.
I just wish that there was just a little
more humanity like,
and I'm not saying that it's just like I
really fundamentally,
strongly dislike something about the
outrage culture and the willingness to
forego the fact that she's a human being
and human.
Like there's something about people that
they believe that human beings are
perfectible and tractable.
I think that this is something that left
has sold the idea that it's predictable,
that you can defeat racism with the
right person in office.
That you can like,
you know,
defeat sexism.
Yeah,
you can defeat massage and this is not
possible.
You can't defeat these things.
Bad things happen because human beings
are constantly learning.
We're flawed,
but,
but don't you think that ultimately the
direction that we're all moving in as
human beings,
if you looked at human beings from 3000
years ago to human beings have today
we're moving in a general direction of a
much more positive culture
does to me,
but to me it does.
Do is negative.
Could both agree,
right?
Can't be depleted,
but don't you think it can be shunned
out of society?
Slowly but surely.
If people realize there's repercussions
for racism,
then you're operating from a fear.
That doesn't mean that you're not racist
because you're afraid to say it.
No,
but people realize that,
you know,
it hurts people's feelings and it causes
all sorts of issues and no,
maybe no human beings,
especially when they're in.
And I've learned this all the time when
they were in a spot where they're
fundamentally unhappy.
It's very easy for them to,
to,
you know,
lash out.
So if you find someone who's just
miserable,
right,
but it doesn't,
you know,
have,
I dunno the career,
the girl,
whatever it is,
that
person is much more likely to say
something that's vitriolic and that's
just,
that's the human condition.
Like you're not happy.
So you lash out at someone else.
I agree with you,
but don't you think that human beings in
general are less racist today?
Certainly less racist publicly in
America than 1950.
Oh my gosh,
yes.
No questions past eight years ago.
Yeah.
If we go back 68 years ago,
the world has changed for the better.
Like what love 100 percent in terms of
the social progress progress that we've
made,
especially in America.
Sixty,
eight years from now,
we could at least come very close to
eradicating racism.
Um,
that's a very good question.
Uh,
so if you're talking about just America,
yes.
Well let's just go with America because
it's was just it up because I don't know
what the fuck's going on.
China or wherever.
There's some places where racism is just
deep and they accept it.
That's why I say like racism never go
away,
but they change it up because then
they'll say Americans are racist towards
Muslims,
right?
When you say that you're going to do the
Muslim,
the Muslim ban from certain countries.
And that's also considered like racism
and not just like,
you know,
national security,
right?
So everything sort of becomes racism.
So the problem with racism is nobody
knows it means anymore.
Everything is racist.
You can use,
you could the starbucks situation,
which to me was not racist,
was racist.
That racism,
the starbucks.
We have to define racism.
You don't think that was racist?
No,
I don't think that was racist.
I live in.
So you think if those were white dudes
hanging out in starbucks,
not buying anything,
just sitting down mind their own
business that they would have got fucked
with the same exact picture.
So first off,
I live in Philadelphia.
I'm not kidding.
I wonder if sometimes when I'm there I'm
like,
I wonder if any white people live here
like Philadelphia is like,
it's 44 percent black,
not excluding Hispanic,
44 percent black.
It's unbelievable.
Everyone who works in my build,
everyone's black.
It's like the weirdest thing.
I'm like,
this is a very black city,
right?
So bizarre city to be racist.
Outright racist in like you're dealing
with black people all day.
So you remove that and then you think to
me,
and I've seen this happened tons of
times,
is it possible that this guy was just on
like a power,
like power trips happen?
I've seen it happen at the most bizarre
places and I'm like,
all right,
like at the airport the other day,
like this woman gave me absolute hell at
Tsa.
I mean it was like I came recap,
it was just absolute hell.
I could've walked away and said she was
racist and she randomly selected my bag
22 times to go through and made me go
through and miss my flight.
Right.
Or she was having a bad day and she was
power tripping,
you know?
And then people have these little
positions.
It's like that movie where they go door
man,
you know,
and like,
and they have these little positions
like the manager of starbucks and you're
having an off day and these two kids
that could have easily said,
okay,
I'll buy a cookie.
Right.
Like common decency by the way.
Even for me,
if I go use the bathroom at starbucks,
I'll just fricking buy a cookie or a
little juice box or water.
Just something that makes me feel all
right.
It's a little more civilized if I just
buy something even though I'm just here
to use
the bathroom like so on both ends,
pee real bad and there's a line you go
and then I,
I,
I'll probably spend to the bathroom and
then buy something afterwards.
I do that.
It was like a natural thing that like,
it's a little more because of these guys
you could just be a shower and the
toilet because of outrage culture rich
culture and say like my cousin who is
half Mexican and black had to go through
this training and she works for
starbucks.
It's like,
it's to me,
it's just insane.
It's like,
is it possible that this guy was power
tripping?
These kids were being like,
you know,
that could've just bought something and
it could have been resolved,
but you had two people that are being
stubborn and,
and taking it to as far as possible,
you know,
talk about like hall monitor,
like you know,
these are the rules and it just got too
far.
That could be a perspective that is
possible.
But it's also possible that they were
racially selected.
Yeah.
That's racist.
And looked at them and they said these
guys are black,
we don't want them sitting around here
and not buying anything for.
Could you remind.
Weren't they just waiting for their
friend to the whole thing didn't make.
How long were they sitting there for 45
minutes.
But that's like until the cops got
there,
they probably weren't.
I mean,
how long does it take to get the cops to
come and fill it?
Just like if you were sitting there,
I fill it.
No,
I don't know.
I've never called the cops and feel it,
but I do know that like Philly is,
it's just a very,
it's a very black city.
It's a very black city.
You know,
I was there with uh,
Dave Rubin and
Jordan Peterson.
Peterson opened for them and it's just
stand up,
stand up.
I'd be good at it.
Come out tonight.
I'll get,
I'll get you up.
I'll do it.
Oh wait,
no I can't because I have A.
I'm going to Wyoming right after this.
You have any ideas of what you were
talking about if you went on stage?
I don't know.
I would be really funny though,
I'm like randomly really funny random
noises that when people pay.
No,
I would be really good,
like really good voices.
Like really good,
like I'm finding to believe that most
people think they would do really good
at standing up,
but it's hard because they get nervous.
Yeah,
I could see that.
It could be just like I'm not funny
anymore.
I probably would if I was on stage,
I feel like I would be like that like
stereotypical comedian that just gets
completely sloshed and goes out.
It's interesting to try to loosen up the
labs.
I think it's a really hard thing to try
to be funny in front of a sold out room.
I think it's important to be objective
and I think it's important to look at
something for what it really is and I
think it's highly possible that that
starbucks thing was racist.
I see.
I think it's.
I think it's just as.
Yeah,
like I said,
it's just as of outweighed culture.
It's here we are.
It's got.
It's got to be racist.
It's like,
yes,
the chances.
I'm just telling you like a lot of black
people that come in.
I work from the starbucks and reading a
book.
I work from starbucks all over
Philadelphia.
That's like what I do.
Right,
and it's just there's.
I don't know if there's any white people
in Philadelphia.
I'm constantly trying to find where,
what area of town where you met?
Tower theater.
That's where we.
But they probably commuted.
Oh,
the fuck drive.
Yeah.
It's all black people,
so it's a bizarre place.
Thank you.
Yeah,
it's rough.
It's really rough and people don't
understand.
I'm like,
dude,
like it's a weird place to come to if
you're racist.
It's like really hard to be racist and
filled up because everyone's black.
Like it's like
we went to the movies once and we saw
planet of the apes actually,
ironically in a really black
neighborhood and then we were.
It was.
I was there for the UFC and it was me
and my again,
my friend Tommy from Connecticut and we
were looking for somewhere to go and we
went to this uber black neighborhood and
it was a fucking blast.
It was hilarious because I never,
I never go to an all black movie
theaters,
but they were yelling shit at the
screen.
I mean,
they became like it was,
there was the audience that was
entertaining and those,
a movie and Talese.
There's one scene in the movie where
the,
you know,
the planet of the apes kept.
What was the guy's name?
Caesar got mad.
He's like,
ah,
you
barbecued.
We were high out of our mind.
So the whole thing was like extra
hilarious
black hole.
This is a thing.
It's in.
So funding is so much of what I do is
inspired by this.
It's just like people like this,
I guess presentation of black people in
the media.
It actually gets me mad because to me,
and I could be biased.
I think black people are like the most
like funny.
Like we're so funny,
so endearing.
Like when I'm around my cousins like I
do,
there's not a better time that I can
have when I'm around.
My family were not easily offended.
Right?
We're constantly being funny.
We tried to making fun of other people.
Like there's no one meaner.
People are portrayed like victims,
like everything upsets us.
Like we're just,
we feel so oppressed and I'm like,
this is not like the black community
that I grew up in,
in my family and it's also not the,
the black community,
just like who we celebrate.
Like I was watching.
Was it Chris rock stand up bigger and
blacker.
I watched that like from 1994 classic,
like it is like the stuff that he said
he could never say today,
just like that is black culture.
He went there on every single race.
Every single culture made fun of
everybody and it was beautiful.
It was perfection.
It was a sold out Apollo theater.
He comes out in.
The first thing he says is like ratio
was like,
Oh,
white people in the back today.
You know what I mean?
And everyone gets up and starts cheering
and they started making fun of black
people about things that we need to fix.
Right?
He's using like,
it's,
he's being funny,
but he's also saying stuff that's real.
Talking about that baby mama culture and
the difference between like the white
community starts,
she's talking about school shootings.
It had just like,
maybe it was columbine that just
happened and he starts talking about
that and nobody was sensitive.
Nobody.
Nobody in the audience was going the
way.
You know what I mean?
It was a different time.
I missed that time inundated with school
shootings.
There's so many of them now that people
are just twisted.
They don't know what to do.
Right.
So I don't know.
I don't agree with this is the problem
with when you blame the NRA.
No one in the NRA has ever committed.
I know it's,
it's insane.
It's,
it's,
it's bizarre that people blame them but.
But
there's an argument that there should be
tighter regulations on people with
mental illness.
People with the slope.
Incredibly slippery for that.
It is slippery and it's like it's
something you can't define.
Like it's,
it's,
it's too slow mental illness,
right?
Yeah.
It's too slippery.
So what does that mean?
Does that mean if you go to one therapy
session,
like it is so slippery?
I don't like it.
I,
it's a dangerous way to go down to
having to be 21 to be able to buy a gun.
I'm against it because you shouldn't be
able to go get your limbs blown off
overseas.
If you can't come back and defend your
home totally against it.
That's a good argument that you
shouldn't be able to go to war if you're
not 21 either,
right?
The frontal cortex isn't developed until
you're 25 years old,
so who knows?
Who knows when you can make real good
rational decisions for yourself and the
idea is that if you take a 17 year old
kid fresh out of high school and send
them overseas and put a gun in his hand,
like he doesn't really know exactly what
he's doing in the first place because
you're not making informed choices.
You're just following the lead of the
people that are in command.
You're hoping that they're telling you
the right thing to do.
You can get so bizarre to me is that
we're sitting here and we're talking
about the age,
like as if guns were just created like
you know when something's wrong,
but what's wrong?
What do you think is wrong?
Mental Health,
right?
So I say I,
I agree with you,
but I think it should the aeration of
culture altogether.
Like they used to be taught the Bible in
school.
Like you know,
people,
people make fun of that now.
Now we've got this culture where you're
making fun of kids.
Like religion is like,
we're so far away from religion.
Like that's like weird to us.
Like you know like teaching religion is
like it's got like a scarlet letter if
you come in as like a crow holy
Christian kid and like a normal public
public education thing.
You've got the family structure where
it's like these kids are running the
houses these days.
Like I look on facebook and it's like
supposed to be funny when like a four
year old is acting like Cardi b.
I'm like okay.
Yes.
It's funny because she's four,
but it's also like not funny because
she's four right?
Like,
how do you feel about little tay?
Who's a little tay?
Tay Is this all of out of the news now
because they found that it's a hustle.
She's a nine year old Asian girl from
what?
Vancouver is that what's wrong?
And she talks mad shit,
throws money around calls everybody
bitches and haters.
That's my point.
Like this is considered like funny.
It's entertaining.
Like the fact that and,
and we're okay with that.
And so parents are pushing their kids to
be more outrageous because there's a way
that they can make it.
So to me it's like hanging out with Rick
Rubin,
Rubin.
Oh,
she looks like she's.
She like,
how old is she?
She looks like she's fingers.
Oh,
those are hooks.
You should get the horns up and she's
got a g wagon in front of us.
It's just like the cash me outside girl.
Right?
So we don't talk about any of that.
We don't talk about the fact that we no
longer focus on family.
We know it's no longer focused on
religion.
Doesn't need to be,
doesn't mean to be that everyone needs
to be religious about their structure in
religion,
right there.
Structure in,
in me when I grew up in and my grandpa
used to make us read the Bible around
the table,
there was some structure to that and
lessons and prayers that.
And then there's this mass,
the facebook,
the snap,
the snapping,
the instagram,
the twitter.
It's like we've changed the world and
expected children to say stay the same
of it and nobody talks about it.
So is that they say it's the gun's
fault.
We need to be stricter
gun gun legislation,
but the entire world has shifted.
We're not talking about those changes.
The dynamic of the world that has
shifted.
So I,
I just hold the different position.
I,
you know,
I think it starts with family.
It starts with structure.
I think we need,
we need religion back.
I think that that needs to stop being
such a dirty word and into stopping
mocked roundly by the media.
Like it shouldn't be funny,
you know,
when joy Behar,
um,
you know,
says something about Jesus and the whole
audience giggles.
That's weird.
She said something about Mike Pence
being mentally ill.
Yeah,
because he talks to Jesus.
Think about how weird that is,
right?
Like how weird that the stuff that we
used to be normal,
like you know,
praying,
talking to you.
Just like when I grew up,
that was like my grandparents'
generation.
That was everyone was religious and now
we're so far away from that.
Right?
That,
that,
that seems like,
like it's okay to mock and we roundly
market all the time.
So these,
the structure in the home is,
in my opinion,
the most important thing that needs to
change.
The fact that some people are growing up
without fathers in the home is something
that needs to change.
Letting your kid have a facebook account
when they're seven.
Right?
Like just,
there's just too much.
It's the information age,
but what information are they
downloading?
Well,
I definitely think that people need
structure.
family and community and all those good
things,
but when it comes to religion it's like,
which one is right?
All of them.
It's not about being right about.
Yeah,
it doesn't sound like there's not.
I know I'm going to be honest.
I know nothing about scientology,
so I'm not.
I know that people hate scientology.
That's all that all I know about it
created by a science fiction writer and
it's all nonsense right there.
That's all you needed to know,
so that's one of the dumbest religions
of all time.
If you read like what they are,
what they stand for,
Leah Remini,
who was in it for years,
I didn't watch her series,
she been on my podcast and she explained
her journey into it and what happened
with it and when she started to question
it and there's a whole thing.
There is a,
what is the fucking Hbo Documentary?
It's also the book,
the HBO on Scientology.
The Lawrence Wright going clear.
Going clear.
Yeah.
I read the book and I watched the
documentary so crazy.
I know nothing about it besides like Tom
Cruise,
I'm going to be like,
I'm going to be honest with totally
ignorant.
It's,
you know,
for some people.
Here's the thing,
for some people its structure and it's
helpful,
right?
Ideologies are helpful sometimes because
they give you like a,
like a format to live your life by or
scaffolding to keep your,
your,
your moral beliefs inside of these
boundaries and it helps you get ahead
and you have purpose in decision making,
but at the end of the day it's a cult
and there's a lot of them,
so a lot of different ones.
So it's how do you decide?
It's just
that there's something that comes from.
I think just learning certain lessons.
It doesn't need to be.
I'm not saying like we all need to like
structure structure,
like a,
like the Bible used to be taught in
school objectives will be taught by
people that were not practicing
Christians.
Right?
I'm used to be taught in school
objectively because there are still
lessons that are timeless in these
stories.
Isn't going
to do with whether or not your.
You don't need to then say,
oh,
and then we go to church and then we
pray in school and all that stuff.
You can almost extract that and try to
teach these lessons objective,
Lee,
but what kids are learning now is like
how to be an anarchistic,
like,
you know,
feminism 100,
one and every issue.
You're like actually fostering an angry
culture by telling them in every term if
they should be outraged.
We are in outrage culture.
And then your,
you're surprised when somebody does
something outrageous.
It,
it's,
it's a little bizarre to me.
It's like,
no,
everything should piss you off.
Everything should make you angry.
Everything should make you upset.
Everything is as unjust.
Everything as oppressed.
And I don't know why this kid to shut up
at school.
I was so angry.
Like,
it's weird.
It's like we're weirdly fake.
Uh,
no one wants to have the conversation in
shooting happens and everyone's to talk
about the NRA.
And then David Hogg is back on the news.
Jordan Peterson has some interesting
ideas about religion and the fundamental
beliefs and the lessons that are learned
from things like the Bible and how they
apply to human life and that are our own
belief systems.
Without them,
without these sort of structures and
belief systems is one of the things that
leads civilization astray and that it's
done that before and things go awry.
Well,
I actually had this debate with Charlie
and I did a panel.
I'm down in DC and we were talking about
whether the reintroduction of God and
teaching them to school and I said like
at some point there seems to be the
struggle.
I have this idea that like human beings
in a certain way,
we're doomed to just keep repeating
history.
I'm obsessed with Greek mythology,
obsessed with like Egyptian history,
hieroglyphic,
like anything that like or where they
tell stories,
especially Greek mythology because the
lessons are there and we just keep doing
it.
Right?
Greed,
lust,
like the things that human beings fall
for.
Right?
So I had this idea when we were talking
because Charlie is,
is an evangelical Christian.
I'm not right.
I believe in I,
I super smart guys.
And Evangelical Christians believe Jesus
came back to life.
Yes,
yes.
He's an avid dog.
Believes that someone died three years,
three days later they came back to life
and that they walked on water and
yeah,
I mean I haven't really gotten into a
thing because I'm not like,
I'm not the person that should ever be
like debating or talking about religion.
It's not my shtick I guess.
But.
So what I,
what I said to him [inaudible],
me and him both believed that in many
ways the reason that the government has
a,
the media has started roundly dissing
God,
right?
Like in dissing,
he says Christ is because the government
wants to be God.
Right?
So if people don't,
the media is responding to the
government's suggestion.
Is that what you think the reason why
religion is because the media is
responding to some sort of orders from
the government.
That's wrong.
So directive.
No,
no,
but you know,
Andrew,
Andrew Breitbart said that politics is
downstream from culture,
right?
So,
and you can argue that they feed into
each other,
whatever it is,
but there's definitely something between
culture and politics that is linked,
inextricably linked.
Um,
so when,
you know,
when it,
when everyone's on the same page,
like,
so if the government wants to get
bigger,
which it has been doing right,
and wants people to look to them for
answers,
which it has been doing,
you have to understand they have to sort
of destroy everything else that they
would potentially be looking to for
answers,
right?
So instead of when you're down and out
and people would just go to church and
pray,
right?
Or believing in your family or the
family structure,
they need to know that no matter what
you think the government is the answer
and that is what a leftist at the end of
the day,
the left believes the government can fix
all of their problems.
And uh,
and I find especially when I realized
that as they do not believe in religion,
like there's just a thing.
It's a trend.
I've noticed that,
you know,
I'm not religious,
I'm not saying that,
you know,
there's something wrong with it,
but leftists tend to be,
you know,
really apart from religion.
So you could make the argument could
definitely be made that the destruction
of believing in the Bible have stopped
teaching the Bible is because you want
to make it so that every time you have a
problem then because you're still going
to our soul,
we need to believe in something.
We're naturally beings that we need to
believe that something can fix
something.
I really believe that that is the reason
why we go get our palms read,
right?
Like we just like there's something
else.
Somebody has the answer and people are
starting to believe it's government in
America and it freaks me out.
I agree with you that people like
structure and I agree with you that
people without religion try to find that
structure and those rules and other
things.
But I don't believe that,
that this is like some calculated by the
government.
I think it's human nature thing.
It's human nature.
It's.
It could be a daddy.
We want someone to tell us what to do
and if that daddy is the government or
if that get daddy is aliens,
whatever the fuck it is,
people need something smarter than
Charlie
because then he said,
you know,
we got rid of the guard right now.
We have to go back to religion,
and then I said,
okay,
but Charlie,
but then we could actually recreate all
the terrible stuff that happened with
religion when religion became daddy.
So we might just be going government,
religion,
government,
you know what I mean?
Just swinging the pendulum corruption in
both.
Exactly.
And that's my.
And that's what I believe.
Yeah.
So I think that we could say that yeah,
we need to start reading using these
things,
but then we could just end up with the
extreme again where there's massive
corruption in the church.
Not everyone's pleased about the
emphasis in the church.
So then I just said,
wow,
we're just doomed.
I think we're doomed.
Mark Twain had a great line.
History doesn't repeat itself,
but it rhymes.
Interesting.
Go on.
It's great.
Fucker.
Duncan told me that yesterday.
Yeah,
it often rhymes.
That's the quote.
I think it repeats itself fully.
Like we like all of the signs there.
I'm like,
we could literally just read this all in
a Bible.
We can read this on Greek mythology and
we know what happens.
Like it's like it's our humanity and but
there's.
Is it fixable?
No,
that's why people think that as a
society perspective,
of course it's not perfect.
There's going to be great,
there's going to be less,
there's going to be,
but now we're in this culture where it's
like he cheated on his wife like,
oh,
like this.
Humans
are different than we used to be and if
we keep moving in this direction,
we're going to improve.
We're going to continue to improve.
I think the problems,
thank queen cynical.
It's not cynical,
it's just,
it's.
There's just always
lifetime perhaps,
but the idea is that we're moving to a
greater good.
We're moving towards a greater good that
some day our children will enjoy and
that we are in a better situation than
our grandparents were.
Our grandchildren will be in a better
situation than us and we're constantly
moving towards improvement and this is
the reason why we're so dissatisfied
with racism and sexism and homophobia
and hate and all the bullshit that we
see in the world that can be prevented.
We think that if we can shun that and
shame that and push it out of our
culture that some day in the future
we'll have gotten past this and evolve
to the point where we as a culture and
we as a civilization will be something
that we are proud of and we're not proud
of what we are now with school shootings
and people dependent on Oxycontin's and
seven year olds on facebook and we'll
take flashing cash in front of a g
wagon.
There's a.
that's nothing new.
I want to talk about overmedicating
children,
like when I was a kid is sick shows
bouncing off the walls.
We just said you were hyper today.
It's like give him adderall is.
I literally like ice babysit a kid and
like the mom would give them adderall.
He was six years old.
He's like,
oh no.
What's wrong with him?
Like he might be a kid,
you know,
and,
and that's another commerce,
he's got energy,
don't want to have kids when,
when,
when kids are going crazy and you're
tired,
it's fucking hard.
Yeah.
But you don't medicate them and it's.
And it's bizarre.
And,
and then they say,
oh,
well,
you know,
something's wrong with him.
He's in school and he and he's not
performing his while he's not paying
attention.
Maybe he's just not interested.
Maybe he'd rather be out.
Oh,
I remember that very well.
And I remember thinking when I was in
school,
I am never going to tell my kids that
they have to pay attention to some
fucking boring shit.
Right?
Or assume that maybe you want them to
pay attention,
but I assume that there's something
wrong with them if they don't is what's
crazy to me.
They assume there's something wrong with
their child and that they need medicine
because they're not paying attention to
math problems on the board for an hour.
That's what scary.
I mean it's like parents are out of
touch down.
It's the whole thing is unnatural.
I,
I totally agree with you.
Like I am like so anti and you see that
like there's this famous kanye quote
where he says like,
when you see a five year old,
they have so much energy,
but there's,
they have so much confidence and so much
passion in everything that they do,
like they think they can be anything or
they can be a dancer or a singer,
they'll try to do flips and then go find
like an 11 year old after they've been
socialized in school.
They're like the,
the,
that,
that spark just dies in them and it's
because they're literally being put
through a system that tells them that
they can't.
Well,
this girl got a 90 on a test and you got
an 80,
so something must be,
you know,
you're not getting this right.
Well maybe math is just not her thing.
Right?
Maybe she does.
She does.
And she's not as good at math as
somebody else.
I think everybody has their own pieces
of brilliant and that the current
education system does not foster to
those individually to individualism.
They're actually trying to create a
collectivist society by being able to
measure.
You know,
I'm a kids brilliance by standardized
testing something.
Charlie and I very much agree.
Yeah.
I don't think they're necessarily doing
that,
but what they are is uninspired and
underpaid and they're boring and kids go
to their classes and their board or
their mind,
they have to get
this stupid grade so they can keep
going.
Me,
I was so bored.
I was those personality to your.
You got a lot of energy.
I would imagine you sitting.
What am I just always felt like they
were stupid.
Like,
you know,
I'm like,
is this teacher even like smarter than
that?
Can we take a test?
Like a just like a quick Iq test to see
if I should even have to take a class
from someone who's actually dumber than
me and we're having those thoughts like
in high school just being like just
aren't even smart sometimes,
like they're not alone.
Good news is that from that you get this
dissatisfaction,
this feeling of just not not wanting to
be a part of this anymore and then you
start seeking other ways to make a
living.
Other ways to get mean.
Let me see.
I got on Youtube and I started talking
about stuff and people responded to it.
And so how did you go?
Full blown conservative?
I'm a human.
The White House.
Yes,
I have.
Oh fuck.
Have you been in the White House?
You're a conservative for two years.
Two years ago.
This is why some concern talking shit
online.
I'm telling you,
it's because you're like a conservative,
wet dream.
A little bit of jealousy.
But I'm like,
I'm like,
this is.
But this is like,
I believe in this so much that I wish we
could stop that because like,
I'm like,
no,
let's change the paradigm.
Like let's get trump to do the,
like the Joe Rogan show as opposed to
saying,
you know what I mean,
like there's.
But people don't see things that way.
It's all about me,
me,
the ego comes out,
you know?
So.
But anyways,
um,
so I,
I met Charlie,
that was a huge thing that happened.
Um,
I was speaking at the David Horowitz
Freedom Center.
Charlie's 24.
You could ask why he's flying around
with the first family too,
but when you meet them,
you understand he's just absolutely
brilliant.
Um,
and uh,
we just wanted to do this together.
I met him and I said,
look,
I think that there needs to be a black
revolution against the Democratic Party.
I think I'm the person to lead it.
Like I'm your girl.
And I was speaking on a panel with Dave
Rubin about why I left the left and what
I understood about the left and he hired
me on the spot and the rest is sort of
history,
you know?
I mean,
that's really it.
I worked,
I worked my ass off.
The one who hired you,
who?
Charlie Kirk.
He actually runs turning point USA.
I know.
He's like so young.
It's insane.
And you should look him up and figuring
out who he is because he's,
in my opinion,
he's going to be a future present.
United States.
And everyone says that everyone who
every show is bound and Fox as like very
rarely do you meet,
like rush limbaugh just said,
very rarely do you meet someone and
think that's going to be a president of
United States.
Try the is probably on like 18 different
kinds of pills.
And I know he said it's,
it's so many times.
Yeah.
But yeah,
he's
clean now.
I didn't even know that he was not
clean.
Took 100 pills a day.
That's scary to me.
And from taking pills,
you understand this.
I won't even take tylenol.
I don't even like.
I'm just like told me that by the way.
Very Fair.
Fair warning.
Alex Jones,
he explained to me,
he explained to me the mechanism of rush
limbaugh going deaf and taking pills.
So rush,
if I'm wrong,
I'm sorry.
I,
I have no idea if that's true.
It's true.
As long as we can from taking pills.
Gone almost never lies.
Look up mine.
Exactly.
Me and Brian Cowen or we're brothers and
sisters something.
But yeah.
So I just,
I,
I just,
I've worked incredibly hard.
I feel like I haven't slept since last
year.
I'm traveling.
I mean I flew like a politician,
but not all policies.
People ask me,
they're like,
candice,
what do you like?
What are you going to do?
I'm like,
I'm not a.
I'm just a girl who talks about stuff
that I believe in and people view me as
a politician.
I don't.
I don't understand pills though.
You pull that article.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to interrupt you.
The article on the screen.
Why?
What about me?
Seems like a Paul.
This is what I don't get a little bit
polished.
You've got a little bit of a sort of a
plant.
You said these things before.
A lot of the things you're saying,
you're very good at it.
You've got a well oiled path.
There's a nice groove in your brain.
Well,
you know how to say these things and
then occasionally pop out of it and you
just play in Kansas,
but you know when you're like,
I'm going to leave black America.
I'm going to go against the Democrats.
I believe.
I believe you believe,
believe you said it many,
many times,
but I just said to you,
I told you,
I told this in November.
It was my plan,
so I'm just a person that's going after
my goal and then as I started
accomplishing it,
people are just like throwing shade and
he,
and I'm like,
dude,
like now it's turned into like,
what has been the shade and the hate
that you think is unwarranted?
One?
Well,
first off,
let's not pretend like we can talk about
social justice warriors on the left.
We have them on the right to,
let's not pretend we don't have the
people that like they can't.
Like as soon as I got to a 100,000
youtube followers every youtube or
suddenly it was like,
who is this deep dive?
And then they came with the like she
was,
she,
uh,
she created because she wanted to doc
smile.
The most bizarre I have youtube or
looking up like,
has she ever dated a black guy?
Like the most absurd.
I'm like,
what are you guys doing?
Like can we just all like just
peacefully coexist like this?
What would it be conservative that I'm
not asking you.
I'm just saying like what would it be?
The issue will be the article.
I know.
I'm like,
what is the article going to be here?
The same boyfriend from high school and
he happened to be white,
but that'd be problem.
It wouldn't be a big part would be an
article that's for sure 100 percent,
but they just started digging in and I'm
just like,
guys,
I'm just working hard and if you want to
know what my strategy is,
I don't make videos about you guys.
I,
I make these not what I care about.
I have a brand and define my brand.
Your brand is just going after people
and that's not,
that's not a brand at all.
That's a weird thing on youtube where
you have these little communities,
they attack each other in the
communities.
Have you ever seen the Vegan hate videos
where they go after it,
but I got,
it was like banana.
What's it?
Banana girl
freely or something?
Yeah,
I've heard about.
I've heard about it,
but I didn't say call youtube like
youtube high,
like it's like I and I was like the new
girl who showed up,
but there are like 40.
Yeah,
I mean I know that's what's weird,
but like I was like the new girl who
showed up and like,
like
cheerleader.
Yeah.
I like the captain of the cheerleading
team.
All of a sudden
they were like,
no,
hate me.
They hate me.
Was like,
I don't want to be a youtuber.
I just plugged my
content on youtube and then I really
hate me.
That's bizarre.
That's just like totally weird.
But it's fine because I never ran into
them because they don't have like,
there's no brand here.
I really don't think they go outside,
but there's no brand if you don't see,
they run,
run back inside and make another huge.
That's bizarre.
Youtube,
there's youtube high.
Then you have what I call game of
conservatives.
Just like didn't,
didn't,
didn't it?
Did it like they're all like racing for
the throne and I thought,
I'm like guys like there's like white
walkers at the wall.
Like,
you know,
the glove is trying to like turn this
into comedy so America can we not
compete for the egos.
That's like it's helping to save
America.
I genuinely believe that,
like right now is the only time that we
have to save this country.
I genuinely believe that.
Like we're at the.
I think if Donald Trump did not win the
election,
we would've lost America.
I genuinely like Hillary,
the global initiative.
Just this like the.
I like,
they were like communist to me.
I'm,
I really believe that this is an
opportunity to sort of like,
we're like the last stand for Western
civilization.
Look what's going on in Europe.
It's like insane and people don't
understand that.
I'm like,
what is going on in Europe right now?
It's like Europe's done.
Like she want you to watch the video.
Like Europe has committed suicide or
whatever it was called Douglas Murray on
the podcast.
He was trying to explain to me his book
a strange death of Europe.
Oh,
I,
I think he did a prayer.
You video on that too.
It's,
it's real.
Like they've lost Europe and the last
stand for resin civilization is America
and then you have people that are
competing for Egos.
I'm like guys,
no.
Like there's white walkers at the point.
I don't understand how you think that we
were almost losing America and there's a
battle for America.
I really feel that like just in in every
regard in terms of just just the people
that were running like Hillary Clinton,
like this woman was a globalist.
Like just think about who we were,
who we were in bed with like Saudi
Arabia selling all of our uranium to
Russia.
Like trump came in and was like,
no,
like America people.
We weren't the gap.
Like we lost them.
We're losing the middle class.
That gap between the rich and the poor
was like literally causing that.
A policy's shipping all of our jobs
overseas.
The regulation,
the government getting bigger and
better.
You can't do anything as an entrepreneur
entrepreneur in America without a piece
of paper from the government,
discouraging people with this piece of
paper,
like sending,
like shutting down the factories from
getting that.
There's something,
there's a little land between New York
and La,
believe it or not,
like,
you know,
and this is what trump understood.
We were losing that and,
and trump appealed to that.
Those people.
I'm still floored,
like as I'm traveling the world and
seeing different pieces of the country,
I'm learning how ignorant I was like,
and that's the best thing in the entire
world.
Just I fell victim to the idea that like
it was progress,
it was progress.
We have to care about the environment.
It was progress and it's like no,
like we've been losing.
America has been losing and Donald Trump
understood that in a way that I didn't
end.
I thought we have to care about the
environment.
Not even a little bit,
not even a little bit,
no.
Okay.
Let me,
let me clarify this.
I don't throw trash on the ground.
Like I'm not saying like we need to
like,
you know,
trash the environment like,
but do I believe in climate change?
No.
Don't believe in climate change.
I think the climate always changes,
I guess is what I should do.
I believe that this is like,
you know,
an issue that,
um,
is being that is fatal global warming,
which they've changed conveniently.
They got rid of the word one.
Scientists started disproving it.
Now they only say client climate change.
Um,
no,
I,
I think that that was just a way to
extract dollars from Americans.
I don't at all believe they had no
actionable plan.
It was great for trump to gather that
deal.
It was terrible.
Okay.
But this is an incredibly complicated
subject,
right?
You would have to talk to a bunch of
different scientists and see how they
gathered data and see what they
understand about co two levels and
what's the danger of that and what can
combat it and what could not.
Have you done all this flipping opinion?
This is not.
This wouldn't be the hill I died on.
Right.
But it's not about part.
I just genuinely,
I've read a ton about it,
but I would not be able to.
I would not be able to come to you and
say like,
this is my strong opinion,
but here's like the easiest way to say
this,
right?
The fact that there is a disparity in
the science committee about whether or
not it's real,
it's enough to very little,
very little disparity.
Most,
most,
most scientists,
most the vast majority agree that human
beings are negatively affecting climate
change.
The vast majority.
Yeah.
I don't,
I just,
I just don't think so.
So you think that the very few
scientists that disagree with the
consensus or the ones that are correct?
Well,
I think if something is it,
it's either subjective or objective and
their objective truths.
Right?
But it's subjective.
If you're saying that there are some.
I don't think there's very little.
There are some that don't get paid to go
on tv then some of their are not bill
Nye who are not funded scientists.
Um,
and,
and that has been a whole world not
assigned.
It's just not my heart when science
piece,
but that's the,
that's the point.
Now that's not a good word to
scientists,
but bill Nye is like a science
influencer or a science entertainer.
He's like,
he doesn't have a background in actual
science.
He's not a scientist,
doesn't have a phd in science.
How to do with he promotes science.
Science is not bad,
but the real problem is with climate
change is that would for sure there has
been ups and downs throughout the
history of this planet.
They're observable.
They've.
They followed them in.
We was one of the subjects that I had
earlier today with a Dr Robert Schoch in
2014.
The vast majority,
87 percent of scientists said that human
activity is driving global warming.
Yet only half the American public public
ascribe to that view.
So what website?
80 seven percent.
And this is scientific American though,
like that means it's making money.
I don't trust that.
If it was a.org,
I would probably take that,
but that this is just a random website
and scientific American is not
necessarily a random website.
I don't.
I don't believe this like at all.
Just so you know,
you don't believe it.
Like I genuinely.
I genuinely don't believe I know you do,
but I genuinely don't believe it.
I believe first time the consensus of
scientists that are studying the data
and so what they're doing is studying
all of the stories that came out about
the scientist that said that when they
tried to present their evidence to show
like they were basically just getting
shut down at every corner,
you can pull that up to like scientists
who look up,
I guess look up the opposite.
Right?
So instead of instead of looking for,
you're searching for,
looking for what you're not looking for.
I didn't search for it.
That's what I found when I searched it.
Sorry.
But yeah,
look up is my question.
Why are you so sure.
This is a
complicated subject and it is,
and I said I am not so sure that I would
die on the hill for it.
My opinion right now,
and it's just that it was a means,
because forget the fact of whether you
believe global warming is real.
Let's say it's 100 percent real estate.
We know for fact that trail.
Is there a way clear global warming,
global climate change is definitely
real.
It's happening.
It's happened,
yes.
It has always had what?
What are we?
What is the climate change?
Yes.
The climate changes.
It was different weather yesterday than
it was today.
The climate is forever changing like
that.
That's the problem is that people are
making it seem like that's something
weird.
It's not unique.
You're misrepresenting the issue.
The issue is people think that human
beings are exacerbating climate change
to the point where there's a.
there's a tipping point.
We cross over that tipping point.
We're going to deal with huge problems
that could be corrected if we act now
and put a lot of funding into climate
control and this is what Howard bloom
was on talking about a few days ago.
He was talking about that the real
future involves the technology of
climate control and that will we have to
be really careful of is letting it get
too far where you can't ever stop it and
pull it back.
This is what scientists are reporting
about.
This is why they want emission
standards.
This is why they want to figure out how
to get people to be aware of the fact
that this is a real issue.
Now,
it regardless,
human beings,
if they never existed,
the earth has constantly gone through
cycles.
The question is not whether or not the
earth has gone through cycles of cooling
and warming.
The question is,
are we exacerbating that?
The vast majority of scientists say we
are now.
This could.
This could negatively impact all sorts
of coastal cities.
This can be a gigantic problem.
This is not like the propaganda that's
drummed up by some sort of big business
that seeks to make money off of this or
some sort of a organization.
Al Gore might've made some money off of
it,
but who's making money on that?
We were in
the amount of money that America was
losing,
but here's what I was gonna ask you.
So let's say amount of money.
America was losing who was the Paris
agreement because this is the reason why
we wanted to get out of the Paris
agreement is,
but that's why I wanted to get to say we
all agree that global warming is real.
I don't believe it's real.
Okay.
So I can't see the question,
but why have a belief?
What do you mean?
Why have a belief as to whether or not
global warming is real or not real?
Because I just found in it you don't
understand the science,
but why have a belief in it?
So it's high believe it's not a belief
in.
I don't believe in it,
but that's what I'm saying.
But you have a belief that it doesn't
exist.
I,
I know,
I personally think that this was just
the next.
The fact that it was presented to us by
Al Gore and it's just,
it was,
yeah.
Not presented to us by just by Al Gore.
Al Gore made a vr film and he's been
called like the first green billionaire
who's made a shitload of
the offer that he flies in his private
plane because he's so worried about the
emissions.
That is hilarious.
This is something hilarious about that.
But the people that are telling us a
fucking politician,
there's gross and all that stuff.
Right.
And that's what worries me.
So my question is,
let's say that it's real.
Let's just assume like,
if that's the best way to have,
let's say it's 100 percent.
Yeah.
Do you feel that you have found in your
research that there is something that
human beings can do that would change
this all around?
That's possible?
Yes.
One of the things that they're figuring
out how to pull carbon out of the
atmosphere and even even possibly reuse
it.
There's,
there's all sorts of things that people
were trying to do.
I mean,
we had,
um,
what was the young man who made that
device on slot?
He figured out a way to make this device
that pulls plastic out of the oceans.
They're figuring out a way.
Yeah.
I mean there's,
yeah,
there's a lot of plastic,
just can't like a overtime,
but that's what I mean like,
so when I say that I'm like,
like I,
I believe in recycling.
I'm not like a person that's like this,
but the idea that the government is just
going to take trillions of dollars
because we're in some agreement where
we're all agreeing that we should do
something is useless and,
and look from the stuff.
Like there's obviously a lot of debate
here and as I said,
I'm not so at the one thing you always
find with me is I'll never pretend to be
so educated on something like I'm not
going onto college campuses talking
about global warming.
I don't do that.
Right.
But why are you saying that you don't
think?
I just don't,
I just,
I don't know.
Maybe because it got so close maybe
because it got so politicized.
Studies into scientific agreement on
human caused global warming.
And look at all the studies.
It's between 100 percent and 91 percent
at the lowest.
Ninety one percent of one of the studies
from 2014.
Since the Union of concerned scientists
work,
they almost,
it's,
it's a pretty broad consensus.
Who did?
Who are they?
I'm pulling.
Is it the people that are a part of
this?
It's a good question.
That's what I'm asking.
Numbers can 300,
six scientists to confirm over 97
percent of climate scientists agree and
over 97 percent of the scientific
articles find that global warming is
real and largely caused by humans.
So my question to you is if you want to
step outside of the scientific
consensus,
which is vast and involves 10,000,
306 scientists and just say,
I don't believe in it.
Even if you're right,
even if you're right,
you don't have enough information to say
that
right?
You might be.
Why I said this
was the thing you don't believe.
I don't know.
Yeah.
I would have to have someone sit down
and convinced me that it was real.
I personally don't believe it.
That's okay.
It's good to start at a place of not
believing something.
No,
it's not.
You think you should start with
believing everything he did not believe
either or not believe?
Yes.
Not believe no,
but don't say you don't believe I learn
about it,
learn about it and then have an opinion,
but you're stating this opinion without
having any real understanding of what
climate science.
But that's.
That's exactly what an opinion is.
I'm not going,
like I said,
if,
if you said that Kenneth,
she went onto 10,000 college campuses
and you said that global warming isn't
real,
then we'd have a problem and I just
having a conversation.
Why have an opinion on something that
you don't have data about?
This is my question.
Like I don't necessarily have an opinion
on climate science.
I really don't know much about it,
but what I know is that what I've read
is that the vast majority of people who
study it or an agreement that human
beings are effect.
So I just my recall on a lot of things
that I read,
and this was a while ago,
so this is why I.
When I first formed my opinion,
not believing this,
I read it a shit ton of articles,
can't recall the data because like I
said,
this wasn't something I was super
passionate about.
It was like somebody posted something
and then I went on a tear or reading
about it.
Um,
but it was essentially just noting that
in a lot of these studies,
like when you go and you,
if we had time to sit down and really
pulled this up,
they're pulling,
you know,
10,000 scientists that are within a
community that is like these,
that works,
do you believe?
And everything that media matter,
media matters,
dot org puts out for statistics,
right?
That's a political,
that's a political arm of the Democratic
Party.
Politics versus science.
This has been politicized.
It has global warming in particular has
been politicized 100 percent.
It has been politicized,
right?
That's the whole reason that I fell down
this dark hole one night reading about
it and I didn't.
I was like,
you know what?
The day care it has been politicized.
And I think that's also maybe why you're
saying you don't agree with it so
quickly because it's an ideological
right wing point,
right?
Is that global warming isn't real if
you're one of those people that thinks
global warming isn't real,
you're almost always on the right and
that's fine,
but I'm telling you that like,
again,
I didn't do a deep dive on all of this
because I read about it because it was
at a forefront of discussion and so I
read about it all night and my
conclusion was that they started pulling
up all of these studies and the person
that did this,
I did a deep dive on and they started
showing how like these community of
scientists were in fact,
somewhere behind that.org as someone
that was being funded.
So to me,
the issue got to politicize for me to to
to believe that global warming was
something that was going to wipe out the
world.
Now that is a fact,
but that doesn't mean that the funding
affects the scientific research and the
data which they all agree on.
And this is universally across the
entire plant.
Thousands and thousands of scientists
would not stake their reputation on
false data,
but what they're saying is not that the
only reason why the world is getting
warm is because human beings that the
only reason why the climate isn't
totally static for the rest of eternity
because of human beings.
What they're saying is we are negatively
impacting our own environment and we're
doing it because we have technology and
we use coal and fossil fuels and
emissions and we're raising our CEO two
levels and this is based on data and
this is.
This is something that you can look at.
You could look at the data and follow
where they're getting this information
from and follow how they're making these
conclusions and follow.
The vast majority of these brilliant
people study that shit their whole line.
Exactly,
and if I look,
if I was a person that was putting forth
policy on climate change or if I was a
person that put out by opinion publicly
on Paul on on climate change,
I would do all of that.
I'm just not.
I understand what you're saying,
but what I'm saying is that you are a
very smart person.
Yeah,
and people listened to you and they're
going to listen to for a long time,
I believe,
but hold on.
Let me finish what I'm saying.
To have a formal opinion on if you don't
have to have a formal opinion on
everything.
What you do have to have is the ability
to know when you don't know what the
fuck you're talking about.
You said you don't believe it.
Don't believe.
He asked me and I said this wouldn't be
the hill I chose to die on because I
don't say you don't believe in because I
personally do not have a belief until
you really prefer if my language as
opposed to admitting that I do not know
this.
I went diamond,
so I've never made a B.
I've never made a public statement.
You would have preferred if I had just
started by saying I have no.
I have no opinion.
No,
I don't know.
That's what I'm saying.
But you.
You say no.
You say I don't believe in it.
I don't believe it.
You.
You're saying really clearly that you
don't think it's real.
I mean,
I think it would be the same if I said
to you like,
you know,
do,
do you believe in God right now?
I would say I don't know if he would
say,
I feel like this is sort of like
linguistics though.
I would say.
I don't know.
I always say I'm agnostic.
I believe I believe it or I don't.
Right.
So it's like if you say a lot of people
say they don't know.
I think believers is definitely worth
associated with God,
but
don't say I don't believe in God.
And then somebody starts saying,
oh,
you need to form.
It did.
It's like,
no,
you don't.
Because God is not scientific data.
Right.
There's a big difference between
measuring the CEO two levels in the
atmosphere and deciding whether or not
there's an afterlife.
I,
I'm sorry that I just don't believe.
I don't believe in global warming.
I'm happy to try
to influence her.
You're a very bright person.
If somebody had asked me like at a place
for influencing on a college campus,
what's your opinion?
I would say I have nothing.
I bet you would say I don't believe in
it like you just did.
That is absolutely not what you,
we.
There are so many instances where you
could watch.
It's just like,
and you can ask Dave route,
but when he asks me a question I say I
don't have any opinion about a different
subject for you and I are having a
conversation one on one.
I'm not,
I'm not sitting here to try to.
I don't go on campus talking about
global warming because I don't,
I don't have an opinion on it,
but if you press me and asked if I
believe in it,
no,
I don't really believe in it,
but it could I go deep dive in and learn
that perhaps I'm wrong.
Sure.
I personally am inclined to believe that
a lot of those studies are manipulated.
Um,
as I said,
generally the one night that did deep
dive on it and when they showed like all
the pieces of evidence,
whatever,
it just seemed a little shady,
but I felt that it was politicized.
But I think I have a right to say that.
I don't believe in something,
but I also don't know and that's what I
said to you.
I don't believe in it,
but I wouldn't die on this hill.
I don't know enough about it.
I don't
when dinosaurs.
But you also said you don't believe in
it and you stated the reason why.
Because you think it's a scam.
Yeah,
that's true.
What do want me to.
You want me to lie to you?
It's okay,
but I just.
I'm not sitting here saying like heated
issue.
It's a very complicated.
That's fine,
but I,
I.
What do you want me to lie to you and
say I'm not a politician.
You want me to say you should the
correct term like the.
I feel like this is like the editing of
people do like when they're like,
oh,
a bond.
If they ask a question you don't know.
I'm not running for office.
I'm answering.
I'm talking to you.
I don't believe in it that I appreciate
you.
I can't be fake.
I die.
This is my number one problem in life is
I can't be fake and I know that you're
oppressing me or that you want me to
adjust and to say like,
I don't.
I do not have an opinion or the EPA.
I'm not a politician.
I'm telling you I don't believe in it.
Could I?
Could I changed my perspective of
leaving in a year after I read that?
If you were just a regular person,
you said,
I don't believe in that.
I'd probably go all right.
The problem is you're not.
You're,
you're,
you're a very.
When I'm aware,
I'm aware when I'm on stage,
when I'm on my youtube channel,
there's no videos of can.
If someone's talking about global
warming,
I'm aware of that.
There is now a.
yeah,
exactly.
Now it's going to be broken.
It can go either way.
I just.
Yeah,
exactly.
They were going to be mad at me because
you
know what's funny though is that like
this feels so like we're not on the
Internet right now,
but it's like I still don't feel like
we're on the Internet.
This is the problem.
Yeah,
but like if we were,
if you and I are on a college campus,
I'd be like,
Eh,
I'm not really sure.
I don't have an informed discussion on
it.
Jack Shit about global warming.
I really don't.
Yeah,
I think with the real fear is not even
global warming.
The real fear is global cooling.
The Ice Age is the most terrifying thing
that can happen to human beings that
should happen is everybody dies global
warming,
you just move inland.
I think that the real thing that people
are concerned about is like,
just beyond any of that stuff.
I don't know.
I think that there's more concerns in
society.
Like I,
I personally think that some scientists
are talking about global warming and it
got politicized.
They figured it was another way to
extract human beings money because of
fear.
That's my opinion.
I think there's probably some truth to
that.
There's definitely going to find our
core scientists that agree with
everything we say.
If it's improvement.
Harvard studies have been in incorrect
because they were being funded by
certain political interest group,
so I'm not inclined to pull up something
on and um,
I'm blanking.
It'll come back to me in a second.
But there were Harvard papers that had
been funded by certain researchers that
are trying to get a certain political
position out and it causes mass fear.
People are willing to spend their money
a certain way possible.
It is.
It's real.
That's very real.
People are flawed.
So I'm not inclined.
When someone pulls up an article and
says,
look,
a 10,000 scientists,
I err on the side of,
okay,
I don't know those scientists are.
I don't know what the organization is
by,
so I'm going
to stick by my guns and say,
I don't really believe in it yet.
Now if I decide that I'm going to run
for office and I've got to make a
decision on,
on the atmosphere and,
and,
and what we're going to do about global
warming into two missions,
you better believe I will be fully ready
to discuss it.
I'm not gonna.
Make a youtube video and just know the
outskirts of it.
I don't do that.
Right.
But if you and I having a discussion,
sorry,
I don't believe it.
Like I would almost say
open,
open to learning,
open to learn.
I'm always open to learning.
I've,
I've been wrong before.
I was a liberal two years ago,
you know,
um,
or three years ago.
So that's,
that's not a problem.
I'm open to learning,
but I'm not going to like for like say
something that feels inauthentic and
what I wanted to say there was,
I don't believe in it.
It's one of those things that it's
become,
it's a real right wing talking points.
It's like there's very few,
like pro life is a very right wing
talking points.
Very few I would imagine.
I'm just guessing,
but very few liberals who are also
prolife well no.
So when I first went on Dave Rubin show,
he asked me about that and I said,
I don't really know.
I'm forming my opinion on it like just
like you and I just said about global
warming.
I said to Dave Rubin about a pro life
and pro choice,
um,
and he was like,
this is the first time someone has just
said that,
like just said that I'm forming an
opinion on it and didn't feel like they
needed to get an answer.
And I said,
I'm not a politician.
Same thing I'm saying to you like I can
answer how I feel and,
and,
and I'm happy to learn,
but that's a different kind of subjects.
But then I wanted to get really educated
on it and I became prolife but not
because I think people that are pro
choice or awful human beings,
um,
you know,
who needed to burn in hell.
But just because the history of it is
really shady.
I'm with Margaret Sanger and because I
do recognize that it does seem a little
off putting.
I don't say like,
you know,
I'm,
I'm prolife,
but I just say to people that like,
the idea that the left is so pro choice
at the same time that they are running
around reporting to know black lives
matter.
It doesn't make any sense.
When you look at the numbers of black
babies never even get a chance to live
and when you look at the numbers and
just understanding that 17 million black
babies had been exterminated since 1973.
So what kind of black lives do you care
about?
I don't believe that baby's life starts
after three months.
I think that that's crap.
That's scientific crap.
Anybody.
We could probably pull up some articles
that say for sure the baby's life does
not begin until the three months.
We wonder the best indication that the
baby's life begins before it because you
have to rip it out of the stomach in
order to kill it.
It if,
if,
if you,
if left alone,
it would grow into a baby.
Right?
So I've thought about that issue and now
I have a stance on it.
Like,
and that would be my stance.
You know,
if I was president,
I'd say it's,
I don't want to be the president.
I'd states,
you know,
I.
let me say what trump said,
if I,
if I stepped up,
if my country needed me,
like I said,
10 years ago,
I would step up and I would do the job.
Right.
Do you have aspirations?
I.
I promise you I get this question all
the time on the road.
Kenneth,
do you want to be in the White House?
Do you want to be the White House?
I would love if Charlie Kirk was a
president of dates.
I would have fun being the press
secretary.
I'd be like,
just let him in,
let the dogs in.
Like I would choose.
It just looks like a fun job because
they're so crazy fun job does because
they're just so crazy and I.
I would just have fun at that too.
I feel like that's what I'm saying.
It would be a fun job.
They're so serious and like,
I'm like,
you take yourself seriously like Jim
Acosta.
Just be running the government of the
greatest empire the world has ever
known.
You think that would be fun?
That doesn't even seem remotely funny.
I know I'm being,
I'm being a little facetious,
but it insanely stressful.
Who's the press secretary?
Sarah Huckabee.
Sanders.
She looks stressed out.
I think she's just trying to have a game
face you just like a stupid question.
I'm like,
Jesus Christ.
It's one of those things.
It's like,
how far can you swim?
Some people could swim for sandy hours.
Nobody can swim forever and that's what
that job looks like to me forever.
Nobody can swim forever.
Yeah.
I didn't like,
I didn't start this because I wanted to
get into politics.
I started this because I saw a dial that
needed to be moved.
And what?
You're obviously a very ambitious
person.
You seem very ambitious.
It.
Listen,
I'm good no matter what space I'm in
weather,
like when I was in private equity,
I'm always good at my job.
When I put my mind to something,
I can do something and people will be
blown away.
That's always in my character.
Um,
and,
and I will do it despite people saying,
I can't look at that.
To me,
my whole to do list is people telling me
I can't,
you know,
like I don't like when people try to put
me in a box.
Like,
I really don't like the whole idea that
because you were this,
you can't be that.
It's like,
it's like I'm always going to decide
what's best for me and you to be
Republican in the first place.
I'm not Republican,
right wing Republican.
I'm independent.
I know I would say.
I say I leaned right.
I definitely right.
Because that to me is just,
if you believe that people are allowed
to have different opinions,
you lean right?
Like literally,
that's where we're at right now.
Like it's like you're not even allowed
to have a dissenting opinion.
Second Amendment.
I just think the slippery slope,
pro life
anti global warming,
the anti global warming thing is like,
this is something that I've looked at.
Your organ has forced on me.
I genuinely like we're getting along
great,
right?
Like this is,
I just,
I have no reason to believe that because
some scientists that could very well be
funded as we constantly,
things are constantly being funded to
create a public perception.
I very much believe that.
I see that.
Um,
and we see this in the case of Donald
trump there.
If you go pull people in California,
they're going to say he's a racist
sentiment.
It's just whatever is put on the
Internet.
People believe as the truth.
I like to do a deeper dive.
I have not done deeper dive on global
warming.
Save that one night when I went down to
our coal or what other like right wing
talking points.
Is there anything that you don't agree
with?
Um,
yes.
Uh,
I don't know if this is still a thing,
but I like,
I fully support gay marriage and,
and,
and the reason is simple,
like regardless how people feel about
gay marriage,
the government has stepped in and is now
doing marriage and the idea that two
individuals that are in love to should
get tax cuts while the others shouldn't,
is nonsensical just because,
you know,
that doesn't make it.
So forget the.
I personally don't think the government
should have gotten involved in marriages
in the first place,
but they have you.
You can't sit here and decide that to
gay men don't get tax cuts.
And Amanda Woman Do.
That's wrong from a,
from a governing perspective.
So if you're 100 percent.
Yeah,
that's a good one.
that's a good one because that's one
that gets slippery.
Even Caitlyn Jenner,
it isn't in a gay marriage,
which is fucking.
I know that one is.
Yeah,
this can't get anywhere.
I have cousins that are gay like it's
even though despite the fact that
Internet,
I found them anti lgbt,
which is insane.
But I just think that since the
government has,
has stepped up and decide it's going to
be in it,
if it's the governing body,
everyone should have a right to the same
tax customer.
They shouldn't be.
That's the real problem.
But nobody talks about that.
They are.
Well,
everything you,
you have to get married through the
government.
You got to be saved from the government.
It gets recognized by the government,
your tax cut,
you know,
you get,
you can check certain boxes when you do
your taxes because you're married.
So since the government is doing that,
there's no reason why if,
if two guys live in the same house,
that they should not be allowed to get
tax cuts.
So the difference,
it's the separation of the church in the
state,
right?
Well,
the state has taken on something that
traditionally was in the church and
because they'd has,
you have to be looking at it
objectively.
Um,
despite your personal feelings.
it looked at objectively and every,
every person has a right to,
to get a tax cut because they married
the person that they love
100 percent with you on the gay marriage
thing.
So what other ones don't you agree with?
I don't know what the right way.
I don't even think about like,
right wing talking points.
So.
Okay.
So first off,
a chance just hilarious.
So it's funny,
you just jump in it,
you know.
Um,
but.
So the number one thing.
So my whole shtick,
the only time I snapped back or get
upset,
it's because I'm really focusing on
community dude.
And the,
the committee that has been affected the
most by illegal immigration is a black
community.
It's just a fact.
I mean,
you talk about low wage workers,
the people that are the most
unimportant,
this company or our young black men
between the ages of 18 and 21,
right?
So they have been negatively impacted by
the influx of people running over the
border because they'll come here and
they'll say,
okay,
well you were going to pay this guy $7,
you know,
whatever the minimum wages will do it
for less.
And that directly impacts the black
labor force.
So I,
you know,
I recognize that we very much have an
immigration problem.
I think that the immigration,
you know,
they talk about diversity.
It's not diverse whatsoever.
Half of the immigrants that we take in
from Mexico,
that's not,
that's making America,
Mexico,
that's a problem.
If you want to take in some more from
from Africa,
that'd be great.
Only only three percent come from Africa
or I think four percent last year came
from Africa.
Tougher Commute.
It's,
it's,
it's tougher commute.
Right?
But the truth is that the argument that
is behind people that are like so pro
immigration and against the wall is that
it's about diversity.
It's not about diversity,
Let's go look around the country and
actually make a diverse.
There are tons of people that live in
Africa that worked their ass off.
I would love the opportunity to be in
America and we need to work that system
out just because they have a Geo Geo
advantage here.
Doesn't make it fair.
So,
um,
I'm,
I,
I'm not,
I'm pro coming up with a solution for
immigration because it's negatively
impacting running for president candice.
That's what I'm hearing.
I'm not running for president.
I'm here and people going crazy and
shit.
A
logo.
Let's just do it.
Looks like what would be my slogan?
Make America great again.
Is already taken.
He needed another one.
Keep making America better.
Even better.
Even more better.
You've been more better.
No,
but these speeds of the things that.
So anything like in every situation,
and you'll see this if you watch like
trial and I live on campus.
Let me do this.
Every situation when I'm asked my
opinion,
my answer is tailored towards the black
community because I just think that we
have really gotten the shit end of the
stick.
Did you write a lot of this stuff,
a lot of these thoughts out of these
locked in your head?
My had I read,
um,
I,
I make cards like to just remember
certain numbers and to watch.
Yeah.
And I just do that.
Kind of weird.
You out that a couple years ago you were
liberal and now you're not just a
conservative,
but you're on all these fucking cable
network shows and you're constantly
talking about it and you're the in a lot
of people look at you as like the hope
for the future.
You get a good looking 28 year old woman
who's super articulate and smart and you
could rattle off facts and Statistics
and talk real good on camera.
We got one,
we got a good one.
You know,
that's what they look mean.
Anyone young and vibrant.
That's what every political party looks
towards.
Like,
you know,
whether it's on the left or on the
remaining constant looking for somebody
on the left.
They're looking right now.
We need someone to go against trump.
We need someone good bleak
Charlie Booker.
We need someone.
We need someone like Charlie.
He's like an actor.
He's just an actor is.
It just doesn't come across as authentic
to me,
but whatever.
Yeah,
I am.
I do not like cory booker.
I know him whatsoever.
Great Guy.
Yeah.
He could be personally,
but he's a publicly.
He's representing himself fictitiously
in my opinion.
That's just my opinion is to.
It almost sounds like no,
stop that attack knows how to go on the
attack.
No,
I just,
I've just.
It's the language I really don't like
when people sit on a stage and go
racism,
racism.
It's just,
it's to me,
it's insulting to people's intelligence.
Talks about to me about what's going on
black minute.
You don't need to scare them.
Like it's the fear.
Politics pisses me off and that's what
they do every four years.
It's fear politics.
Well guy bought for us because racism,
racism,
racism.
It's not.
That's manipulating.
That's using fear to control what we do.
Okay.
We have a right to just be presented
with the facts and being allowed to make
a decision on our own.
That's.
That's my really perspective.
That's the big thing that's been so
controversial.
Candice Owens thinks that the black
community should be spoken to about
what's going on in their communities.
It shouldn't be thrown Jay Z and beyonce
concerts,
all law Hillary Clinton.
Right.
But like that.
Is that really that controversial a
thought?
It's,
it's broken the Internet.
I go out and I say,
Hey,
I think that there might be a little
more to the story that everybody's
racist and they go,
oh my God.
Like she can't say that I'm not the
first black conservative views.
I don't know why I'm the most like
controversial at this has turned into
like
we already highlighted it young and
you're good looking and you're all
looking conservative.
Articulate person farm.
Me and other young one.
Yeah.
How many have you got?
I don't know.
Young whip.
Smart.
Fast with the tongue,
and I do want to say this.
I think that people like the.
Unless they say,
oh,
it's just because like she,
she's a black girl,
scream with them.
It's like,
no,
it's because for the first time someone
has the audacity and it's not the first
time.
You know,
I met with Secretary Ben Carson last
week.
Lovely man,
lovely managed time money or sometimes
he is brilliant.
Love all that shit.
When people were hating on him and angry
at him,
he never lost his cool.
He's so calm.
So imagine he and I are meeting and I'm
like,
they'll like knock them down,
let me out.
Yeah.
He's like,
hello candice.
I was just like,
that's what you want for a dude is
operating on brains called.
Yeah.
And I'm like here's what we're going to
do.
We're going to have something to do.
And we just like love each other.
Like,
I mean like it was just a love affair.
Like I,
he,
it was,
I didn't realize that I was so
intellectually uninspired my whole life
because I was in a room of people that
didn't understand me and I never
realized how,
how misunderstood I felt until I got
into a room with like Secretary Ben
Carson and he just like got me and Andy
Armstrong Williams who was a close
friend of his and he just like got me
and Kanye West,
right?
Like,
who?
They just,
they get me and,
and it's,
it's been so inspiring and I'm so happy
and I don't think I've ever been this
happy in my entire life.
That's why it's hard for me to ever take
a negative perspective on anything
really except for global warming.
It's not real
because I'm,
I'm,
I'm like,
I feel so alive.
I feel by vicious and I,
I see the change happening in the black
community,
unlike all you have to do is be an
individual.
I do not tell.
I don't go on campus and say vote for
trump.
I don't say you need to be a Republican.
I actually have tons of palm with the
public and people just want ask me,
you know,
and they assume I'm a Republican.
They assume I'm a registered Republican.
That's just not true.
Um,
I and I fully support the president.
I love the guy.
I don't know what to say.
I love president trump.
I love his song.
I love don trump jr.
I love eric.
I love ivanka and that's controvErsial.
I love them.
They're great.
They're great people.
I want you to meet them because they're,
when you can't,
not like them,
like,
think about like,
like terribly wrong.
ThIs could go bad,
but think about like boundary.
Like,
this is a guy who is out hunting.
Moose friends of mine.
He's supposed to come in here,
we're supposed to play techno hunt
archery game.
And he helped me.
He's like,
you know,
really like a grizzly bear out in the
wilderness and nature and it's just like
they've gotten a really lIke unfair
shake in the media spokesperson.
I,
I love them.
I mean,
I,
it's authentic.
It's not.
No,
I'm not.
no,
no.
I've actually explicitly say it.
I don't want to work on the
administration.
If someone came along and said,
we've got a sweet deal for you.
I've already been offered people just so
everybody knows who thinks,
oh,
she's pining for.
I've been offered shows.
Everything that you think that I've been
off,
I'm going to towards.
I've already been offered.
I've actually believe in what I'm doing
and I'm building my own company.
I believe in it,
super ambitious.
I don't want to work for anybody because
then you have confines.
Like let's say I went in,
for example,
worked for cnn or fox news,
right?
Then I can't say David Hall kind of
sucks,
but like at that tweet I would have had
to remove about chelsea handler outrage,
right machine,
and the
best thing ever is when jake sites lead.
I'm like,
ha ha,
no.
I'm going to retweet it.
You can get away with it.
Like samantha,
she did the right thing by apologizing.
She made the right action.
Take the correct action.
Yeah,
she did.
She took.
She'd made the correct action,
but what's so beautiful for me is I'm
free.
I say whatever I want,
and then they say deleted and I retweet
it.
Okay.
By the way,
that's.
That's to me,
that's freedom like that.
You can'T be like,
that's the best part of this is that I'm
truly free.
I can say whatever I want.
I don't have advertisers that you can
boycott.
Like it's just.
I can say my whole,
my twitter feed is just me.
That is a very powerful thing.
Yeah.
I feel so empowered.
It's a very good thing.
You know,
and I'm sure your ideas,
I mean you,
There's no better way to have your ideas
expressed than to have no one that you
are beholden to.
No boss.
I love that and that's why I was like,
you know,
I start working with charlie in there,
so I build my own company and now he's a
part of my company now we work for each
other and it's just like we're,
we're mission or mission driven and I do
support the president,
but I don't.
I don't want to go work administration.
That seems like a really the worst job
in America.
That's what I'm saying.
We need to be the secretary or press or
no,
nope.
I'm particularly.
This administration has got it because
they have.
They're so angry and bItter about
losing.
Like I by that time 20,
24 comes around,
you know,
it'll be a little different,
but they've just been like,
oh.
Like they're just like,
if you can sense it,
they're angry.
Like definitely an ideological war going
on that it clouds a lot of thinking in
terms of winning.
I don't know.
You tell me who's winning.
We were winning.
We were republican now.
I didn't say it properly.
Can you just insert their code was we
know we're winning the independent
thinkers.
The people that think,
yes.
See,
see,
just check in.
See exactly your republican.
Now I know people that have this
mentality that people that are are,
are,
are freedom driven,
that just want to be able to have
different ideas and that's why I snapped
back at,
you know,
conservatives to.
I'm like,
I'm not a product of the right.
Don't think like,
I don't want people to go,
oh,
candace is just joining the lap.
Then she wants to create a model.
If on the right,
no wrong,
all I want walk you would do is
understand you have a right to like
certain ideas on both sides,
but you don't like what you should never
allow us.
For someone to use your identity to
define how you have to think.
You should always be the person to
finding how you think.
That's the message that I say on college
campuses.
That's a very good message.
Qantas,
we could probably talk for hours,
but I've got to get the fuck out of
here.
I got out of Wyoming.
Now you're going to Wyoming.
Yeah,
right now you're going to hang out with
kanye on the ranch.
Maybe.
Maybe that's what she's doing.
She's going to go ride horses and shit.
Piss off somewhere.
Liberals.
You're firecracker and good luck to you.
I really enjoyed talking to you.
We'll do this again sometime.