One of the few things I get nervous
about,
not nervous,
but like,
oh,
what do I do here?
The start of every podcast.
It's like,
all right,
once we get off to the races,
we're all good.
Turn off your volume.
I think that would be the second thing
that you think.
Have you said it and right when you said
it,
the volume came on.
I'm pathetic.
It's not even funny anymore.
It's just sadness.
This podcast brought to you by hover.
If you go to hover.com
forward slash rogen,
you can get 10 percent off your domain
name registrations plus a lot of stuff.
Hover provides for free,
like a who is privacy,
what hover is a company that's owned by
the same folks that own ting and with
the same sort of ethics behind them,
they just want to put together a cool
website where you can buy a domain name
fairly easily and do it all like
ethically and have it set up now.
Real simple,
easy,
intuitive.
I just used it the other day to register
some websites.
I'm just going to go on the porn
business on.
Are you really?
Yeah,
not really,
no.
What am I doing?
Claymation porn skin.
I'm going to make like little fake
things.
Fuck No.
Uh,
that's not what the website's for.
I just had an idea,
but anyway,
it was easy to do,
super easy to go and register it.
And uh,
as I said,
if you go to hover.com
forward slash rogen,
you can save yourself 10 percent off.
Sweet Baby Jesus.
Look at this.
I looked@Dunkinlovesbabies.com
which is available and Duncan does love
babies.
I love those little sweetie.
But then like it gives you,
like the other available domains that
you can buy through hover and it just
goes from Dunkins loves babies.net
to Chicago babies.
But Chicago babies is $488.
Just don't try it.
Don't connect the dots here.
Let's just move on.
Do you have a baby in Chicago?
Yeah,
I forget it.
Just move on.
Dr [inaudible] been having babies.
What?
I love him,
just because you love them doesn't mean
you have to have them.
That's it.
Go to a go to hover.com.
Forward Slash Joe.
As I said,
is that what it said is that you want,
I said what was the exact wording of it?
Hover.com.
Forward Slash rogen.
Sorry.
And you get 10 percent off your domain
name registration.
So that's hover.com
forward slash rogen.
Uh,
we are also brought to you by
[inaudible] dot com.
That's an n I t a done this commercial
fucking billion times.
Um,
this,
uh,
what an honor it is,
a company that sells supplements to
increase your performance,
whether it's cognitively,
whether it's physically.
There's a shroom tech sport,
which is an amazing,
amazing supplement that we put together.
It's from the quarter seps mushroom and
the idea behind it is there certain
plants like cordyceps,
mushroom being an excellent law,
but it's not really a plant because
cordyceps mushroom is a crazy kind of
fungus.
It's like a weird sort of a living
thing.
It's closer to funguses or I believe I
don't want to speak out of school,
but I believe they're closer to humans
and plants is right.
True.
Yeah.
Well,
this quarter,
eps mushroom stuff,
uh,
the,
the first experimented it apparently
when in high altitude hurting
communities,
they found that the cows are more active
after the ate these mushrooms and so
they kind of put it together and the way
it's grown,
it's grown like on caterpillars or some
shit.
It's like this really freaky fucking
process to create.
But what it is,
is a,
it's an amazing endurance supplement.
It's a fantastic stuff.
It's like really obvious effect if you
have like a brutal workout,
if you're going to go a do a spin class
Duncan and get ferocious to some
eighties music,
you know,
some fucking Pat Benatar and you're
like,
yeah,
right.
Um,
it's just an excellent supplement for,
um,
for endurance.
Anybody's doing Jujitsu.
If you're doing kettlebells,
anything along those lines.
It's got a lot of [inaudible] in it as
well.
Real noticeable effect.
Um,
Alpha brain is,
uh,
another supplement that we have that,
I swear by it,
I've been taking this shit forever,
but I've been taking nootropics forever
too.
I just think it only makes sense to me
that if it's possible,
as long as I'm not starving as long as I
have money to buy supplements and if you
don't spend your money on healthy food,
but if you have the money,
I would always think that what,
what,
what is like really important?
Speed,
speed.
What is really important when one of the
things that's really important to me is
the way my brain functions,
you know,
because I know it's variable.
I know there's a big difference between
the way I am when I'm hung over.
There's a big difference between the way
I am when I'm jet lagged and when I'm in
the groove,
when I feel great and my words are
flowing and conversations are going
smoothly and you're in the middle of.
I don't know what the fuck causes that.
Okay.
I think it's a bunch of things.
I think it's rest,
but I also think it's health and I also
think it's nutrition.
And my experience with,
uh,
started off with Bill Roman [inaudible]
stuff.
It's called neuro one and he created
that because he,
he got a bunch of concussions from
playing football,
famous football player and um,
you know,
he was fighting against it and one of
the things he did is try to improve the
quality of his brain and improve the
quality of the functioning of his mind.
So he started experimenting with various
nutrients that do that and uh,
and that's sorta where Alpha brain took
it.
From there we just tried to put together
the best combination of what we know so
far about these things.
And if you're not interested in it,
that's cool.
I understand.
If you are interested in it,
you can go and use the coordinate Rogan.
You can save 10 percent of any of the
supplements.
This is all fairly controversial stuff
with some people and that's one of the
reasons why on it has a money back
guarantee.
One hundred percent the first order of
30 pills within the first 90 days you
have 100 percent money back guarantee.
You don't even have to return the
product to stay.
The sucks.
Give me my money back.
Its because no one's trying to rip you
off,
but just trying to sell you the best
shit.
It's not a massive difference.
It's a subtle difference,
but I believe it's a real difference,
I think.
I think it improves,
it improves the quality of my thinking.
It sounds crazy,
but if you,
if you just google nootropic and o,
o t r o,
p,
I see you will see,
uh,
all the different studies and tests that
had been done on it and it's shown
increases in memory and it's really
fascinating stuff.
Um,
and very controversial as I sent.
So it's a fake,
but that's a real,
that's a fake really?
Oh yeah,
that's real.
Wow.
Yeah,
she's in shape.
She's,
she's on it.
Oh forgive me.
You know,
I've talked about this,
uh,
this supplement company so many times
with so many podcasts that almost seems
ridiculous,
but that's just something I believe in.
I believe in the ethics of the company.
I believe in the message.
I believe in trying to give people shit
that makes your body work better.
I'm huge on that.
I think it's super important.
So I'm psyched to be working with them.
And again,
used code name Rogan save 10 percent of
any of the supplement.
Is this Dr Lazar.
Who's this guy?
I don't know.
That's interesting.
That's A.
Oh,
that's heath haring.
Oh really?
Yeah.
He is a former UFC fighter,
former pride fighter legend MMA legend.
I think he's a pro poker player now.
Crazy,
crazy dude.
Wild Man.
Look,
there's an asteroid so it doesn't matter
because everyone's going to die from
this aspect.
I think on it.
It's just saying listen to the hill
pitch.
I don't know what the dream.
That's dope.
That's an Alpha brain induced serious.
Fuck.
Yeah,
it doesn't make sense.
Well look,
it's the whole company is like,
it's very cool.
It's a very cool company and you know,
one of the cool things about it is
they're like,
Aubrey is a young dude.
He's a very enthusiastic guy and
occasionally they would
do things that are like just a little
bit silly,
you know,
but it's not bad intentions,
he's,
he's just all about going after it and
getting it.
Um,
when you talk about going after it and
get it,
getting it though,
there's,
there's a certain douchey genus that
just sort of like comes off when you
talk about like,
you know,
uh,
anything that pumps up your masculinity,
you know,
anything that like makes you more a
vibrant as a man.
It's like border line,
really Douchey,
you know,
and one of the things that was in my
message board picked up was it said in
the,
uh,
this new supplement t plus at
testosterone,
but it says something about it
increasing your swagger.
I saw it,
first of all,
I it and I went,
no.
I was just like,
no,
please.
They didn't really write swagger,
but it was just for a lot of young
dudes.
That's a cool thing to say.
Like,
yeah,
you know,
it's just my fucking swagger.
Everything.
I mean,
are you being honest?
What is swagger?
Isn't that important?
It's important to have like a sense of
invigoration.
It just such a Douchey word
unfortunately is it's not bad to have a
swagger.
It's definitely bad to use the word.
Yeah.
If it's a like a genuine name,
that should not be said.
Do you know what I mean?
What is that?
When you feel great when your.
When your life is fucking rolling
around,
perfect sound,
the perfect frequency and you have that
feeling like you just walk up like is
that that it's not swagger.
Okay.
Let's.
It is kind of a swagger but swaggers too
gross or word,
so we have to have another word for it.
What is that feeling?
That feeling like when you're at your
past like,
wow,
I'm about as happy as I think I've ever
been a being in the zone,
but what is that harm?
Whatever.
Whatever it is.
You can't call it swagger now and the
audit it so thank you.
Rogan board know that the people that
makes axe body spray probably have a
good answer with that question.
I don't think they would even be
perplexed the other.
The other thing that the rather rugged
boy put out was the t plus supplement
has an ad where it's a dude super power
lifter guy.
He's like one of the world champion
power lifter guy.
He was a huge,
enormous guy and I'm the end of the ad
was him at a bar with two different
girls and they're like,
this guy look at,
he's stretching,
kissing,
kissing.
No,
he did not go back and look at this
video.
Every time we an arm,
he's stretching.
What is this thing?
You guys don't understand what you're
talking about?
He's about to lift $8,000.
Fucking million pounds.
Some guys enormous.
But the commercial is,
uh,
you know,
I mean,
the dude's legit power lifter.
The idea is that supplement to increase
your body's production of testosterone,
but at the end of it,
it was a little hotties at a bar and it
was like no grinding cocaine for brain
powder on it.
That's an enormous person.
That swag.
Do you think he's got swag?
What'd you just say?
Would you not even tell you?
That's why we just say swag?
No,
I'd run from that date.
Honestly.
If I saw that.
Cue The music man.
Usually code named Brogan and go fuck
yourself Joe Rogan.
We love you.
Powerful dog.
So your back man.
I'm back back.
Back from the precipice.
Back from the precipice,
well none of us are ever like from the
precedence,
but I saw a big sign today.
It was something about surviving cancer
and the lady was a smile and laugh and
then she was like holding a baby or
something like that and it says
something about surviving cancer,
and I thought about it.
I was like,
we don't really survive shit.
Do it.
Nope.
There's no surviving.
Yeah.
Something we do for a little.
We put it off for the amount of time
that you're.
You're sentient.
You extended the amount of time that you
have consciousness.
It's a very funny thing.
It's like our age starts.
The moment that matter were composed of
wakes up to an awareness of itself and
stops the moment.
It's not aware of itself anymore,
but what we are.
That's not really our age.
It's much longer than that and surviving
means you've extended the amount of self
awareness by some number of years,
but it doesn't really surviving.
Don't.
This is something I've been entirely on
stage.
The whole surviving cancer thing is a.
it's an annoying term to like now I'm a
cancer survivor.
That's what I am now.
I don't want to be that.
That's it's so many other things I'd
like to be represented by then.
Then that,
that's not there.
Anyone out there who's fighting cancer
right now,
by the way,
keep up the good fight.
There's a whole brotherhood that you
find out there if people and and
sisterhood of people who are dealing
with this shit and it's beautiful.
So I don't mean to denigrate your
struggle that you're going through.
It's just,
I wish there was another word for it.
And then then,
then,
then survivor such a dire term.
It's such a dire term.
It's like you just climbed out of a
dragon's mouth.
There's are smoldering car.
I think
there's a real problem whenever you
label anything,
call people,
uh,
you know,
a cancer victim,
a cancer survivor,
a cancer,
a success in the war on cancer,
you know,
whatever,
whenever you,
you,
you automatically categorize it,
falls into this sort of package.
They want to classify everything man.
And even not just fucking,
you know,
the,
by the way,
can't find.
I'm a cancer survivor.
I had and I don't that.
It's not a term I I care for,
but fine,
but what's weird is when people really
that's becomes their new identity,
like what they were before,
they didn't die from a disease or a
thing becomes insignificant to this one
little moment of overcoming something.
And I think that's where it's weird to
me.
It's like,
well,
no,
you're the sum total of everything
you've done,
not just some inevitable Blewett that
emerged that you climbed out of or
temporarily managed to,
uh,
stop.
Why are you wearing a pink ribbon?
Then?
How do you know?
How do you know what's tied around my
cock cock ring?
Who's the first sick fuck that figured
out a cock ring?
I got to figure out how to get more
blood in my dick.
Hm?
How do I do this?
Let me just come down.
It might be a good idea.
I've done the finger cock rang though
when you're like a little too drunk and
he can't quite get it.
Hard to like squeeze the base of it to
keep us on track.
I didn't know that.
How do you know Jesus?
You don't know.
But yeah,
you never know.
So one of my bits,
oh way back in the day and I'm like,
you have to or something like that.
Clamping the base of your cock.
I forget if it was a.
yeah,
it was like he was A.
Hugh Hefner had said in this magazine,
like they were asking him like,
hey you date like these 20 year old
girls,
what did they feel?
How do they feel about dating you?
And he said,
well they feel very lucky.
This has always been a dream for them.
And then,
you know,
I had this whole lucky,
lucky living in a dream,
squeezed the base of it.
This guy's got a semi going lucky girl,
sweet quota,
Cock.
Lucky the squeeze,
the base of it to keep it semi going as
old as time.
So some dude figured out how to deal
with like a rope
girl that hangs out at the comedy store.
And her mom was a famous playboy,
a person that dated Hugh hefner.
And,
and she was saying that one time she had
those balls inside of her,
the banging balls or whatever they're
calling it.
And then he went down on her and one
came out and choked him and he,
he,
uh,
she had to save his life.
Oh my God.
You fucking freaks.
That's the universe trying to kill you.
He fucking balls that shoot chick snatch
giant lead shot.
That's a funny way to dive.
Yeah.
What is that about?
The carry the weights in your pussy.
So it makes you like clamp down and that
that's what keeps your pussy tightens up
the move.
Yeah.
It's like you're constantly tightening
your pussy up to you.
They control these balls that are inside
of you when you walk.
So it's kind of like a,
we fit for your vagina.
That's fucking bananas.
How crazy is that?
Chicks had been lifting weights with
their pussies.
It works too.
Yeah.
There was a woman in Russia,
I think it was a Russian woman who could
stick something in her pussy,
like,
and clamp it down and like pick up
weight,
like,
like actually like a jaw.
It would clamp down on this shoot,
stick like a ball on a rope and they're
posting and then clamp down and lift
weights.
That's crazy.
Have you seen these anal trainer tales?
They're like,
what?
Girls who'd like anal?
They keep them inside of them and they
have like a tail,
like a hair tail
and chick who can lift weights with
their pussies has got a be just an
unstoppable freak.
Like there's no way you're going to
satisfy her.
She's lifting weights with her pussy.
She is like all.
She's all about milking cock.
That's all she is all about.
That's her number one thing online that
says she's so good at it.
She can't wait to get a cock in there to
shock the guy.
It's probably,
and it probably mostly new Cox.
You know these guys like.
And then what's the big.
Oh Shit.
It's like a fucking grabbing a hold of
her.
I mean she could pick up weights with
her pussy.
It's probably way stronger than her hand
because she's developed it and like some
crazy way.
It's hilarious the way people spend time
on this planet.
It's amazing that some people are just
like,
I'm gonna.
Make my pussy strong in this
incarnation.
Well,
but doing it with.
What is it?
What if it was amazing though?
What if it made a huge difference?
Oh,
I don't think there's like,
you know,
like grossly key.
I'm not saying there's better worse.
I'm just saying it's a funny thing like
if you came out of a spaceship on some
alien planet and you're like,
all right,
while I'm on this planet,
I'm going to make it so my badge final
muscles are fucking strong.
Well,
if you enjoy sex though,
you enjoy pleasure.
Can we tell them it is possible that you
can make the,
the vaginal muscles strong?
You can then.
But why wouldn't you do that?
I would do that if I was a chick.
Why wouldn't you want to a Super Pussy
Dick Pills?
You do those,
you know,
we all deal with it.
I am not leveling judgment on these
wonderful women who are making their
vaginas strong and I encourage it.
I think you should do it if you're drawn
towards that.
I just think it's a curious thing.
The way people spend their time.
That's certainly of the ways people
spend their time.
That is a fascinating way.
It's also fascinating the idea of like,
um,
like a Viagra or something along those
lines,
like a pill that makes your dick hard.
And what if,
what if there was a wooded flood was
like exercise you could do that could
make your dick bigger and harder.
You like you could grow your dick the
way a dude grows his chest muscles.
You know,
just steady workout gyms would be
disgusting.
Did you see the video I posted about the
Indian guy that wraps his cock up in a
stick and stretches it out?
Oh,
it's on my twitter.
Find that on my twitter and pull it up.
I think we can even show it on new
stream because you don't really see it
sort of.
He's sort of tucked away.
It's a very strange.
Please use stream.
Don't take us down please.
Youtube.
Don't take us down.
Oh yeah.
Ustream won't let you show this.
This,
this,
this.
This is amazing what we got.
Yeah.
If there's nudity in it,
we can't show it.
Show it.
It's,
it's like tribal nudity.
Sunday Bible nudity.
That's like National Geographic News.
We can do it in.
What will happen?
I don't even want to say what he was
doing when I was in jail.
Let me turn off my twice.
Okay.
Hold on.
It happened to me already a few times.
Why don't you just describe it in a very
picture,
esquire.
Hmm.
I just had it happened.
Damn.
Is there a way you can stick a little
bouncing ball over his cock and balls?
Maybe take a look at this page.
Take a look.
Yeah.
Okay.
Just go to my twitter page,
but if I tweet it,
I'm a chatty bitch.
I tweeted it up.
You're going to lose a lot.
I mean if you do like the Dick Pills and
use the Zma like I've been doing,
I do not do those.
Create.
If I was going to do a pill,
I would get the real chemical.
I think you're,
you're,
you're taking a crazy gamble.
What these fucking 7:11
store.
I know.
I'm revealing.
Um,
I've gotten to the point where like I
realized 7:11
takes the safe route.
Like their products are little bit
weaker and not say,
but you go to some of these like
miscellaneous gas stations that they
don't give a shit.
There's these things called like ml two,
like good for two weeks and you're like,
how is that even possible?
And then take it and like,
I'm like,
I'm cover.
It's just like a skull in a boob or
something.
The way they're getting away with it,
as Aubrey told us was that they're
taking,
they're taking,
they're taking giant amounts of generic
cialis and generic Viagra and those
chemicals are not that expensive and you
can get those chemicals and if you sell
it in like little single serving forms
at a gas station,
it's actually profitable.
So these crazy flux,
they're just selling Viagara.
It's,
I mean it's Cialis,
Viagra.
I should go grab the one that's in my
car and just show you how ridiculous is
that?
You also should really listen to what
Tim Ferriss said.
Oh,
I know Tim Ferriss,
who's a brilliant guy,
has a great quote.
And the quote is he doesn't believe that
there is a biological free lunch.
He's like,
anything that's doing hasn't has that
positive and impact in one direction
will have most likely and equal equally
positive reaction in another direction.
It's very possible that it could cause
real issues.
You're talking about something super
potent.
Yeah.
Isn't that weird?
Why is that?
That's a fascinating thing.
That one thing.
There's always a weird trade off,
but I mean,
what could it be that your Dick doesn't
work without that stuff?
Is that possible?
I think with Dick Pills,
it's better to burn out than to fade
away.
Did you just went deaf?
Leopard Leppard us.
That's right.
That's hilarious.
Yeah.
Well you might have a good point.
It depends on,
you know,
would you rather have.
I don't do it every 10 years of life
left with boners or 30 years of life
with basically start you start off with
three quarter Chubby this year.
I only do it half a Chubby next year,
but you'll know it shuts off and within
five or six years and then basically the
rest of your life you just,
you know,
walk around.
I only do it when I go to strip clubs
for the most part,
unless I know that there's a guaranteed
good lineup of sex that night.
Oh yeah.
Well,
as long as you're not abusing it,
Brian.
Yeah.
I just don't know if that stuff's safe.
I mean,
what is a.
I don't know.
What's the studies on,
on taking that,
Brian,
those boner pills,
those things are magic.
Not supposed to post to
take with her on nitrates.
Is that correct?
Like men who have real serious heart
issues,
I believe.
Yeah.
Now you have a very serious heart issue.
You also shouldn't be fucking like a 12
year old and these things.
Make sure you should.
Well,
it depends on what,
what,
what would it go?
That's the way to go.
It's a great,
great way to go.
But those pills you gave me.
Hot Rods,
$50,000.
Those fucking things.
Those give you like,
like first time you see porn when you're
a terminal boaters criminal like insane.
Hiroshima,
boner.
You know why?
Also why it's sold,
where it's sold,
because it's soda for gay people to go
clubbing.
Oh Geez.
I mean a straight guys going take
advantage of that.
All that Boehner in the and the and the
fucking thing.
Man.
It says on it.
I researched this stuff,
it says,
and this made me think that our breeze,
cialis theory was totally dead on
because on the website it says that the
ingredient is crushed up and I know amp
owners,
but that's something someone lying says.
She's like saying anything.
Nobody fucking cares.
They have great boners.
Don't care when you could say
that's hilarious.
That's exactly what it saved.
They're totally bullshitting.
You know,
what is it?
Odds bugs crushed up and give a fuck
what it is to make sure the questions
I'm trying to sell some illegal shit.
Yeah,
I mean there's the food and drug
administration ever shake loose a tablet
and there's on an ad in this bucket,
do they shake loose tablets
and then by the way,
it might be possible that there's a
toxin in certain answers that could give
you a hard on because they know that
spider has it.
Sure does.
That that spider in Brazil,
the walking spider,
it apparently it just wanders around the
ground and if it stings you,
it gives you the most in possibly
painful Boehner where you dick splits
open like a ballpark frank.
Yeah,
you're done.
It's super good.
Do Bird toxic.
Okay.
It doesn't just give you this ridiculous
boner it most.
Most of the time it kills people,
but if it doesn't kill you,
your Dick is done.
Your Dick's broken forever.
Why do we allow that to exist?
That spider,
it's a red lining.
Dick bug it just red lines or dick.
It's like taking it
like engine deep into the fucking piston
starts smoking ganja.
I don't know why we allow that,
but Jesus Christ,
that's a scary fucking animal insect.
Rather you dilute it down enough.
You know,
you mix it with enough stuff.
It's perfect.
Yeah.
That's wonderful.
Well,
that's what they're thinking now.
Spider.
But they're trying to.
They're trying to figure out a way to do
it and apparently that's connected to
nitric oxide and nitric oxide.
I believe I'm saying it right is what is
in a lot those like not to explode,
like all these different sort of
supplements.
He's like workout supplements and get
people pumped up because apparently
Viagra,
cialis,
all those things,
their,
their performance enhancing its far as
like your,
your body's ability to pump blood like
through itself and makes you more
efficient and it gives you an endurance
benefit.
So I do.
Yeah.
So they're,
they're making it.
I believe it's illegal in the Olympics.
I think he can't be on.
I know you can't be on that pro provigil
that provigil is illegal in the
Olympics.
They test for that shit now and I
believe they test for this as well.
Yeah man,
that provigils pretty awesome too.
I,
you know,
I just found this,
I started looking up like my favorite
authors to see if they were on speed
because I read and like the majority of
my favorite authors are on speed and,
and that.
And that really got me thinking,
man,
that really got me thinking.
It's like [inaudible] pro vigil,
adderall.
These are modern speed.
It's speed.
And forgive me for saying this man,
but my experience with speed and Alpha
brain outbrain is speed.
Like you can call it an.
I'm sure it has like thought enhancing
things,
but it's speed.
When you take that drug,
you feel that
he feels like Alpha remix.
You feel speed.
Low level adderall.
Wow.
I've never done adderall,
but what Alpha brain does for me,
it never makes me feel it's accelerated.
We feel like smoother.
I.
Yeah.
It gives me a,
it gives me a mild speed
bump.
Wow.
That's interesting.
When did you,
what do you do are you're doing the old
formula or the newer forming?
The new formula is more conservative
because some people were having
headaches.
It was the old formula.
And what made me feel weird and it did
give me weird dreams.
Oh yeah.
The dreams if you take them like right
before bed.
I mean it's.
Dreams are weird.
It's like I don't know how to guarantee
a dream.
You know,
people go to carroll for and fucking no
dreams.
You might have.
You just don't remember him.
Okay.
And I don't know why you remember some
of them.
Why you don't,
I'll go like days and not remember a
fucking dream and then I'll do some
Alpha brand or something and somehow or
another I'll catch a dream.
I'll catch a good one that I remember
and I'm like,
well then I'll start remembering a bunch
of them.
Dude.
I mean you dream every night.
A fucking Alpha brain dream where I was
in a garden.
I was standing in this primordial garden
and there was like fucking all these
weird like silvery golden apples
floating up in the trees.
And I held this like weird silver mirror
underneath it and it.
And it made the,
what the fuck are the front?
What are you giving me this for?
Why are you going to need.
That's my,
that's my emergency pack.
That's actually what they sell.
Now they sold like a condom with a guy
pill and a girl pill together.
So you give the girl the pill and then
you take your pill.
You wait like an hour.
And it's like raging boners and
vibrating vaginas.
Yeah.
And there's the girl pilled do it.
Just like the girl I was with said that
just made her vagina feels like really
tingly.
Huh.
And uh,
the other day I didn't even know there
was a girl pill.
Well that's a fee.
That's my emergency packs that I keep in
my car.
But uh,
the other one,
the other one's for five days.
This was the one that is,
uh,
achieved a cheap one.
Dick's going to blow up.
It's made entirely of wandering spiders
going to explode.
Yeah.
Mega night.
And some magnum condom,
of course.
Yeah,
Because you got a big giant dip,
right?
No,
it's because this pill makes you have a
big giant it,
but you have a big giant Dick Anyway.
No I don't.
It's pretty decent.
It's a little bit of average.
The girth is what's really good about
it.
The chick say that's very important.
You have like a shorter dick,
but it was just stretch out a little bit
more.
What's the hook also like?
I've always put my boner like underneath
my belt,
like my whole life.
Like,
so it's like facing my head,
like straight up you smash it.
Been smashing it and like bending it
towards my face.
The whole child.
I'll never have a boner.
I just put them behind my belt and then
sometimes I forget about it too long and
it hurts.
So you like stretching your dick out the
way those African ladies do with their
neck and the rings pointed towards your
own face.
It makes it ben and grow towards your
own face thing.
So that's what urban myths on.
That's just the shape shape at Dick's
board with some people are born with
Kirby as Dick's.
The only thing that would really do it
was trauma.
You can get a broken dick.
There's a dude named Ray lb who uh,
is an MMA fighter who posted a picture
of like a bunch of bloods shit and told
his story on the underground girl got on
top and she planned and less dick had
broke his deck and it started bleeding.
It can happen apparently,
but in that can,
that can give your Dick Funky,
funky,
right?
Right Hook.
Have you sprained your Dick from having
like I sprayed my dick recently where it
hurt for like three days a week.
Don't let crazy bitches get on top.
You've got to control the situation,
son.
Anybody breaking your Dick because were
on ecstasy and they fucking think this
is an awesome song.
Yeah,
a girl can do it.
A lot of damage.
If she slips on it wrong,
she taints you.
She takes you right on the crowd.
It was bumped Boeing,
right?
The bone.
Your Dick especially,
she's got some good fucking thigh
muscles and maybe she plays volleyball
or something.
Did it good at jumping
a duncan?
I was listening to your podcast the
other day and you see that you've only
had sex on the road once,
like you don't take advantage of the,
the,
like I've seen it
club,
I've seen it.
I saw a beautiful,
crazy girl trying to get,
talking to sleep with her.
Do you,
do you not?
Are you not a horny sex maniac or no?
No,
no man,
I,
you know,
I'm really,
I get really fucking horny.
But um,
like I,
I,
um,
well there's two,
two things.
One,
I tend to
have a girlfriend and I don't.
I'm monogamous,
so I,
I,
that's one thing.
But when that's not happening,
then generally there's this,
it's like I get,
I really get up in my head about it and
so I think about,
I overthink it like I'm way in my head
about everything.
Like I'm,
I live in my head most of the time and,
and when you live in,
there's good things about living in your
head and what,
but when it comes to fucking and jumping
into this primal,
animalistic state that creates the best
sexual experience where you just let go
and,
and it's,
it's more difficult to meet,
especially out on the fucking road
because,
uh,
I consider the lead up to it and I
consider the follow follow like after
you fuck,
you know what I mean?
And it's like because porn is the
ultimate,
because with porn you jerk off to porn
and that's it.
You don't have to like walk porn to the
door.
You don't have to like have a like porn.
It's done.
It's not going to call you up like porn
that you've looked at is not going to
call you up and be like,
I'm fucking pregnant.
You know what I mean?
It's just done and so you just get this
middle thing when you watch porn,
you don't see the beginning,
you don't see what happens right before
the porn shoot or God forbid,
10 years,
the,
you know,
the girl like walking in on her dad
fucking a dog or something or getting
fingered by her uncle.
You just see this incredible,
beautiful primal moment of fucking and
you don't see afterwards,
after the porn shoot.
You know what I mean?
That weird moment in the car,
driving back from a porn shoot,
you know,
you wipe a little jazz out of your hair,
you don't use that whole thing.
You just get that one burst.
Right.
So on the road it's like fucking on the
road.
It seems like there's a lot of pitfalls
there and a lot of weird dangers.
It's a lot more than just like,
you know,
what a seven,
what would be in his seventies movie,
but like I said,
I think too much.
You know what I mean?
I think clearly overthinking it.
Satanists are all about doing that
stuff.
You know,
I had a friend who was a satanist and he
said that,
uh,
in life,
and I remember it was really,
it's really rough when it Satan says
something that seems like absolutely
true,
but he's like,
because you know,
this is coming from a guy with lucifer
tattooed on his chest,
but he said,
you know,
in life he said,
hell,
hell is not someplace where you burn
forever.
Hell is that moment that you're dying.
That moment when you're at your death
bed or you're in the car,
you're sitting at the car,
wherever the fuck you are,
you're dying and your mind goes back and
thinks about all those opportunities you
had to experience life to the fullest.
All those chances you had to dive into
life and suck the marrow out of life.
And you did not have fear.
That's hell now.
That was coming from no hills way worse
than that,
that you can just jerk off and ticketing
them if that's what your life is.
That's not that bad.
What do you mean pink?
Disappointed in life is not as bad as
being tortured by Mongols.
Well,
I mean he was saying how he doesn't
exist,
you know,
the whole Christian idea now is
nonsense.
That the only real house since there is
no how.
Absolutely.
If there was obviously if there was a
real Christian,
how are demons fly down and put their
balls in your mouth and like slice you
into bits every five years.
Wouldn't you be surprised if there
actually was a.
How fucked up would that be?
If there was a hell of hell was real.
I mean think about how fucking stupid
you would feel if you were actually like
being confronted by demons.
They were flipping your eternal soul.
They'd be like,
motherfucker,
I can't believe it.
They warned me.
Yeah,
yeah.
If you imagine,
how crazy would it be if you got down
there and there was a devil,
some dude.
He's got goat horns.
Like,
yeah,
they just start ripping you apart piece
by piece over and over again,
and they put you back together again for
eternity.
Well,
see,
this is the funny thing about hell,
man,
when you want to really get into the
hell talk or the hell trip.
I know people who've had held trips
you've ever,
you've probably never had the hell
trick,
the bad trips and felt like they were in
hell.
Where are you start thinking like,
oh,
I mean,
because look,
when you were talking about how we're
talking about a torture chamber created
by the general,
obviously I did not believe this,
but if we're talking about how it's a
torture chamber created by the creator
of the known universe,
so it is the most advanced torture
chamber that could possibly exist.
It's created by the most advanced being
psychotic in this case,
but the most advanced being so when our
real torture chamber the year means of
torture,
not going to be so obvious is like
burning fire and it burns your skin.
The first thing you'd want people to
think is that they're not in a torture
chamber.
You'd want them to think that there's
some hope,
some hope for peace as long as they were
hoping for peace and thinking that there
was going to be some moment of
tranquility.
It would like increase their levels of
disappointment to the maximum.
So that's the health trip.
The trip is where you start thinking
like,
oh shit,
this is it.
This is how we've been.
This is,
this is the ultimate torture device
device by some maniacal insane God that
everyone's popped into and instead of
like remembering where they're at,
they're just like,
oh no,
this is totally normal.
And gotta go through traffic in the
morning,
got to go through three hour commute.
You know what I mean?
That's how you don't even know you're
there.
You don't even know you're there.
Maybe slowly you start with,
I don't think that by the way,
the opposite works too.
You know,
you can also think that this is heaven
and you're just too dumb to see it.
You get to this,
you know,
you can pick where those two a different
mythological constructs
just abandoned those ideas and just deal
with the present because it's the only
thing you really know and we do know
that when you live in hell,
when we use that,
all that guy lives in hell.
It's a series of shitty choices,
a bad circumstance,
bad luck,
combination
of all of the above.
And,
uh,
most,
most of the time when you use that term,
Guy Lives in hell,
you're talking about guys under
someone's thumb,
whether it's a,
whether it works for some crazy company,
you know,
that,
demands him working 16 hours a day and
his weekends.
And you know,
there's a lot of guys that live in how
they're like executives of studios and
stuff like that.
Like those are crazy ass jobs.
You know,
what we're working in,
you know what I mean?
I'm sure like stock market along those
lines,
like anything financial,
there's probably a lot of people that
are forced to wear a crazy fucking
hours.
Right?
That's right.
And if you have like real restrictive
work conditions,
you have to wear a suit and tie.
You have to fucking be very formal
around the office.
Nobody can fuck around,
nobody can relax all day.
Most of your day is just buttoned up in,
locked down.
Yeah.
Yeah,
man,
that's definitely one version of when
you hear people say that they're in,
how it's uh,
um,
but still,
you know,
there's this idea,
Krishna Murti ever heard of Krishna
Murti?
No,
Jay Krishna Murti,
he's this philosopher,
the Indian philosopher who is like this
kid who was discovered by the
theosophists and theosophy were this
strange spiritual group and I don't know
a lot about them,
but they have madam blood tasky and was
the woman's name,
but they spotted this Indian kid,
uh,
at the beach and one of them was like,
his aura is amazing or something,
and they sort of took this kid in and
groom this child.
Any eventually became this brilliant
philosopher and a,
as part of his,
like evolution turned his back on
theosophy and said,
it's not that,
you know,
it's more.
He got really into the idea of being in
the moment.
And I actually,
I wanted my podcast.
I put a awesome sound clip of him
talking about how the past you carry the
past with you.
The past is in you right now.
It doesn't exist.
There is no past.
There's just your encoded memories of
things that have happened.
And the future is something you create
through everything that you do.
But there's no future either in.
It's like you're this packet,
like a d,
like the DNA packet,
the way their DNA for sort of spawns a
specific type of cell.
What you do with what you carry around
with you in every single moment spawns
your reality around you,
which is why people who you know,
you always will run into.
People are like,
I don't know why this always happens to
me.
I always get dumped.
I just don't understand it.
I always get dumped or I always end up
in this predicament or that predicament,
or the reason is you're like a
caterpillar or a silkworm and you're
spinning your reality with every action
that you do because that's all there is.
It's just this,
you know this moment.
So you end up with a shit boss,
you know,
and you've ended up there just because
you've been diluted by that,
by your perception of time,
you know that's the fucking trick
because people listening to this habit
shitbox shit,
white shit,
girlfriend,
shit,
husband,
whatever.
You know what I mean?
And,
and,
and this sound clip J.
Krishna Murti says,
the only thing that you can do is right
now at this moment,
make a radical psychological change in
your apprehension of the universe at
this moment,
at this moment where the ship boss with
whatever it takes this radical like you
have to break free of everything you've
been taught because we've all been
taught to think that there's a future
and we've all been taught to think
there's a past.
There's also an issue that people have.
This narrative has been sort of spelled
out for us by our parents and then as we
get old enough,
when we get into our twenties or
thirties,
we really understand it.
We were like,
oh my God.
They were just clueless.
Folks just like we are like the idea
that anybody had a handle on how to do
this.
Right,
and then you just look at the fact that
these people,
I mean your parents and my parents are
from a generation where they got into
our age before there was an internet.
I mean they're,
they're literally,
they're different human beings.
It's a completely different style of
human being to human being one where
human being to human being three that
are being born right now,
you know that will only know insane
levels of technological proficiency from
the time that they're aware when they're
three or four till till they're dead,
when it's insane.
That's right.
These are.
This is the strangest times of all and
no one knows how to run it now.
No one knows how to figure this out.
No one knows.
The more information keeps coming in,
the weirder things start getting the
fucking meteors landing in Russia.
The fact that no one even saw those
coming and that there was a giant
asteroid that whipped overhead within a
day of that he asked and it was inside
the outer band of satellites.
Like there's.
There's a whole lot of weirdness to this
world that we live in that we're just
not taking into consideration
at.
All.
Right.
Well fuck yeah man.
And it all started me and generally with
people it all like that.
That thing where we like just don't
think about them as a species.
We are living in the same way a modern
individual lives as species as a whole
is living in a state of delusion.
The species as a whole is pretending
that the most important thing is solving
whatever little religious war or a
territory based war or economic problem,
they think that's the most important
thing in the way we're living as a
species is all based on the notion of
there being a of the individual instead
of the totality of the race.
So this,
this way of living is one of denial,
so the human race right now exists on a
planet where we blow each other up every
single day,
fight these ridiculous wars,
fight against each other,
and completely ignore the fact that we
are floating in the void and this on the
regs,
on the regs,
get smashed by fucking media whores.
Now,
why the fuck would we not be doing the
obvious thing which would be in this
situation?
If the first thing you would do is
figure out,
okay,
let's come up with a foolproof way to
control media yours,
then we'll then we'll fight.
They don't fight it,
b one,
and not only that,
a lot of these asteroids that they're
picking up,
they're coming in from amateur amateur
astronomers,
like a good percentage of them.
Oh yeah,
I know,
but that's not that many professionals
watching the sky.
Well,
well this is the whole thing.
Or they say like one month know we
stopped one month of war in Afghanistan.
You know,
you know that that number,
right?
If you stop the war for one month in
Afghanistan,
you could pay for everybody in the
United States to go to college for free.
Some kind of crazy number.
Now that number,
it might be two months.
So in the same way if you consider that,
you know what I mean?
I wasn't saying it as a species are a
priorities are a little weird and as an
individual,
you know people in the same way.
They spend most of their time ignoring
the fact that there is a subjective
media or that's going guaranteed going
to smash into your life at some point,
which is old age disease and death.
There's no way around it,
so people spend their time ignoring that
fact as well.
You know,
it's uh,
it makes sense in a way.
I mean,
thinking about it so fucking intense.
It's a lot easier to worry about your
own personal problems.
The little things,
you know.
Yeah.
I want to,
I want to find this military budget cut
thing.
If that's true,
done one month of the military budget.
If you cut it out,
it wouldn't surprise me.
Find out what the yearly military budget
is and you know,
it's like,
look,
this is this,
this is the fucking thing that Neil
degrasse tyson posts,
which is like the picture of the media
or whatever and this is why we need to
work,
you know,
so I need to work on the space program.
Fuck,
can we.
Do you know what I also think,
I think that schools should be free.
I think we should be paying for,
for whatever it is,
college,
high school,
everything.
I think I,
I think school should be free always.
I think it should be free and it should
be encouraged and we should pay for it
with,
with our taxes,
you know,
I would rather pay for fucking,
like a really high level school that
kids could go to.
Even if there are poor,
I would way rather pay for that then pay
for more military bullshit.
More drones,
drones above.
I mean,
you could do that,
that,
that could be something that can be
done.
Sure.
I mean that's the thing,
but that it can't be done as long as
we're confused as a species into
thinking that there are,
um,
religions that are more important than
religions are countries that are more
important than other countries or people
that are more important than other
people.
As long as we're stuck in that modality,
well then we're never going to fucking
wake up to the fact that we have to
shift.
You know,
and it's saying the staff,
you know,
suddenly sound like you're seeing in
Goddamn a John Lennon song,
but it's fucking hit them motherfucking
problem.
I have a John Lennon is,
he was banging Yoko Ono.
Jesus,
Dude,
you're John Lennon.
I donate,
donate that sweet Asian.
We've shown you the video of John Lennon
with Chuck Berry singing when Yoko Ono
start screaming and
the microphone like,
Bill Bird does this bid on it.
If you haven't heard this,
you have to see it on youtube.
Go find it on Youtube.
Bill Burr,
Chuck Berry,
Yoko Ono.
It's fucking hole.
But,
but,
but back then wasn't Asians more rare?
Like it was almost like dating,
you know?
I mean because like all the war and
stuff like that weren't easy to find.
She's a dangling.
I mean when,
when we were in Florida,
it's not that important that a person's
race.
It's not that important.
It's like who the fuck are they?
That,
that,
that checks alone.
Yep.
That was probably so in back.
Probably like dating men hate.
That's what he loved.
I,
I don't blame them.
It's the only thing that I disagree with
them on.
Everything else.
I think he was brilliant.
He's pretty brilliant man.
I don't think anybody ever gets the
whole package.
Correct?
Well,
no,
not,
not in one run.
How do you know if this is zero?
I'm an old soul,
you know,
everybody always says that,
I think I've been around before.
I think I've had many lives.
No one ever goes.
I think this is,
I just,
I was a rabbit in the last life and a
fucking.
This is my first time as a person.
It's nice to be on board.
Yeah,
no,
everybody is.
Uh,
I'm an old soul.
Well,
yeah,
there are a lot of people.
A lot of Cleopatra is out there of
Cleopatra.
Everybody in their past life was doing
something awesome.
Yeah.
No Shit.
Whenever never finds out
there were just homeless.
Just losers shitting on themselves,
sucking dick for homemade wine.
A man that would be so fucking great to
beg for crumbs,
be able to like remember all those
things.
It'd be so great just to know,
you know,
in the way they can do your DNA tests.
And they're like,
whoa.
You're like,
you know,
partially Scottish and there's some
native American in there.
It'd be so cool to like analyze all your
particles and be like,
Oh yes.
Four percent of you came from the Alpha
Centauri star cluster and the other two,
you know what I mean?
To be super cool to know like just the
various star particulates that are,
that you are comprised of the incredible
or animals like seven years,
seven years
percent cat.
I heard this and I'm not sure if it's
correct.
So there's a disclaimer before,
um,
before I talk about it,
but they were talking about,
oh fuck,
I can't remember this now of trying to.
Uh,
it's too,
it's too weird.
I,
I'll,
I'll get back to it,
I'll get back to it.
It's,
I'm trying to remember how it goes.
I don't want to fuck this up.
I'm going to look it up and make sure
that I get it right.
What about that couldn't terantin of
video,
but before that,
what were we just talking about?
Just before that we're
talking about tracing your weird DNA
back and I don't know,
I can't remember how he got there,
what it was.
Okay.
So this is the,
this is the,
I don't know if this is true,
but they believe that within the next
100 years they will have a computer that
is powerful enough.
You ready for this to take into account
everything that exists today and use it
in a numerical equation that will show
everything that ever existed in every
action and interaction that ever took
place in the past in order to get to
that position.
So they'll basically look at all the
buildings,
they'll look at all the people,
they'll look at literally every
component on earth and that computers
will be so powerful that from seeing
what exists now and knowing the amount
of time the earth has existed,
the computer will be able to paint you
and incredibly accurate samuel absolute
simulation of every single action in its
form,
including whatever words you said to a
girlfriend when you were pissed about
that.
It's all just one gigantic equation.
Every time you hit your horn at a red
light,
every time you said,
fuck yeah,
when highway to hell came on.
All those things,
you can literally know everything that
happened based on everything that
exists.
Well,
this is that.
Yeah.
Why?
Why you say it doesn't seem possible,
but I don't.
Fart theory comes into effect.
How do we know if you've heard it or
not?
Will the but this is the idea,
but you're not really totally paying
attention.
I know what I mean.
He was just kidding you.
Okay.
The idea is that when you can have.
There's.
There's these things that they're,
they're coming up with and they were
like,
they're almost like the size of a large
grain of sand or like smaller than a
grain of rice and they can take
photographs,
video,
they can send images,
Wifi,
wireless,
Lee.
They can also have a gps locator,
tells you exactly where they are.
So essentially you can have a data bank
of cameras with dust.
You can spray dust over a city.
Okay.
These little powder things,
they'd be everywhere.
You never cleaned them all up and you
would essentially have a rough picture
of everything that's going on all the
time.
Yes.
Once you got to that point,
you could get an accurate account of
everything that exists on the earth.
All the water,
all the.
I mean,
it's not outside the realm of
possibility.
If we can measure right now in our crude
technological way,
we're 200 years ago,
we were riding animals and they didn't
have cars.
You couldn't take pictures within 200
years.
We could do that.
We can tell you how many acres something
is.
We can tell you.
We can do a radio frequency tasks or
whatever the fuck they do to find out
what's in the ground with the is made
out of.
We can get a pretty rough account of
what we've got around us.
Well,
if they can get to a point where they
can literally tell you everything that
exists and have it calculated everything
that exists in this form on earth right
now and know how long and know what we
know about human history and put it all
into account and be able to actually see
a recreation of everything that's ever
happened.
But here's the thing that the one little
piece you're missing here.
It's so funny.
You're saying this because I got super
stone and Vancouver and started thinking
about something like this,
but a good.
Here's the thing you're missing.
Yes,
but you know what that is you just
described.
That's a fucking time machine when you
add one more component to it,
which is a neurological interface that
instead of it's like you watching it
places you inside of the recreation,
so now you're able to zoom backwards
through this like simulated past reality
based on like,
well if this happened before this,
we can figure out what happened before
that and there would be a kind of rate
of entropy to based on like the further
back you got,
the less accurate your prediction of
things that happened would be.
It seems like you wouldn't be.
I don't think you'd be able to
perfectly.
You wouldn't be able to do smell because
there's no smell technology that know
all the kinds of smells like apple pie,
like could simulate.
Maybe it could like actually kind of a
good point.
That's what your theory is.
What was talking about?
Well,
what I'm basing it on though is events
and like things that have caused,
like why would you ever go to the big
island you ever been to the big island.
The Big Island is actually the least
popular lated.
It's less populated than a Wahoo or,
or a Maui,
but a big one,
half of a side of it is all lava fields.
It's all just like,
you know that that fucking thing
exploded like recently,
like within the last who knows how many
hundred years,
whatever,
and there's lava rock all over the
place.
If you could,
you could accurately say,
okay,
well this law has been around for 150
years and before that it was pastures
and they actually have photos of it,
you know,
you could,
you could have hugged the locals.
Describe what happened when in the 18,
20,
the lava came over the top and cover the
town.
We can get sort of a pretty decent
picture based on stuff like that.
I don't think it's outside of the realm
of possibility that they can get a
totally accurate picture of history.
Oh wait,
here's the other part.
I forgot this is another piece of
technology that you need based on the
idea that you have this insanely
advanced computer,
right?
Right.
And the idea that they could count,
you know,
what they're doing with the human genome
project.
Somehow they finally pull that off with
the human brain so that you can start
doing brain scans and gather people's
memories together.
That's the other piece of it.
So then what you end up having is
instead of just having these
particulates that scan the geographical
makeup of the planet,
you also have somehow the ability to
absorb the memories and the actual,
the actual,
the memories of human beings.
You imagine though,
if somebody else had to go and access
your memories,
you'd be like,
what the fuck am I looking at it like
it's just like bolary legs and you know,
some girls bought where she shows it to
you and uh,
you know,
a TV show that you barely can remember
the plot.
I mean,
how fucking accurate is your memory?
the idea of tapping into your memories
and then putting it on.
You'd be watching like the most retarded
animated Gif file ever.
That's what it would be really crazy.
It would be like a vine video,
but it'll be a little longer.
It would be blurrier and blurrier.
That's so true,
man.
That's a funny thing you were saying.
That's like an existentialist idea.
That's an existential idea,
which is this idea of like our actual
lives when you consider your pov or so
the opposite of movies and so the
opposite of the construct of like some
beginning and some ending in some middle
place.
It really is just this blur of like
coffee's going into mouth,
turn the radio,
you know,
but it's a significant moments come
afterwards.
You like sort of decide the significant
moments and that's what you were late,
but there's far more moments of just
driving in between those significant
moments or walking or like that.
It's a very.
It is a blur.
Human existence is mostly just a blur.
Memory is a blur.
Memories.
Very sketchy.
That's why people don't like Neil
degrasse Tyson gets out of jury duty,
so as he doesn't trust eye witness
testimony.
Right.
Get out of here.
But he's right,
it's been shown to be wrought,
mean people have gone to jail because of
a false eye witness testimony with the
people who were testifying.
Yeah.
The people were testifying,
were absolutely convinced that they were
right,
but they were wrong and the wrong people
went to jail.
It's been proven.
Sane happens.
You,
especially when you're under stressful
situations.
Who knows what the fuck you're seeing,
what you remember.
You know,
I think a lot of these like bigfoot
sightings and you know,
an animal wild animal sightings.
I bet there's a lot,
a lot to that as well.
I think when you're in a stressful
situation,
you something freaks you out with it's a
bear or something.
All of a sudden that becomes bigfoot.
You know the mayor runs off and you're
like,
yeah,
let's fucking bigfoot,
man.
I swear to God I was big foot,
you know.
Meanwhile it's midnight in the middle of
Columbus,
Ohio Woods.
All right.
You can't see shit out there.
How the fuck do you know if it's
bigfoot?
Yay.
Columbus Columbus weekend.
You know what I'm saying,
Duncan?
Yeah,
I do know what you're saying,
man.
Can't trust eye witness testimony.
You can try it.
Yeah.
If I got a hold of your memories and be
like,
Pataki,
what'd you do to that baby?
And you're like,
no dude.
That was a doll I got.
I got a video in my mind,
a baby
be getting waterboarded.
It would just be.
It wouldn't be so exciting.
I think it just be murky and like
waterboarding only works on babies and
little esther.
That would be incredible.
If you water war babies and they start
coughing up information,
you everything.
They know different languages.
I like poopy carrots.
Would would we be.
Would we support waterboarding if.
If you could interrogate babies and find
out what happened before they were born,
I think it'd be worth a try.
We know Alex Jones believes
at zero.
Dark 30 was a government propaganda film
supporting terrorism.
That's not how they got that
information.
It's a lie.
Yeah,
man,
you can't.
You can't torture babies for
information.
No,
no.
Geneva Convention is going to allow that
shit too.
They even have a Geneva convention
anymore.
It's like a Geneva flea market now.
Oh my God.
That didn't even convention.
That was against the Geneva Convention.
There was a button that was like a big
thing in movies.
Right?
So it was doing something bad.
They're going against the Geneva
Convention.
Oh Jesus.
You.
That's a significant thing.
It's like the constitution.
It's generally the criminal knows the
Geneva Convention.
It's like,
you can't do this because of the Geneva
Convention.
It gets left off the hook.
The Geneva Convention.
We need a.
We need a 2013.
We made it past the mayans convention.
Just get together and go,
listen,
let's look at this.
Realistically when.
That'd be great.
When that bitch be fucking great.
That's what I love fantasizing about,
man.
I love fucking thinking about that
fight.
That thing that finally happens when
everything just.
We finally turn away from these
ridiculous,
uh,
our addiction to leaders.
You know what I mean?
And we turn away from our addiction to
matter and then God damn it,
man.
It'd be so fucking awesome.
We could really.
We could win.
I bet all of humanity just started
working on it right now.
Together we can whip up a spaceship that
would probably traveled.
I thought we could have a light speed
traveling spaceship in 10 years.
I think
one of the reasons why this podcast
resonates so much with people is the
conversations that we have sometimes
where this is not an alien way of
thinking.
This is it.
This is like a really smart way of
thinking.
It makes sense and it seems like it
would be beneficial to all including the
people that are in power,
but if you hear that,
if you hear someone saying something
like that,
you automatically assume that they're a
fucking little.
No.
Yeah,
I know you're not allowed to say these
things.
There's like,
there's just some basic truths though,
and when you espouse,
when you say them,
people definitely get weirded out.
Like when you do say the truth,
the truth is continence weren't named
that for them.
They've already been named that for a
very short time.
You know,
North America was not North America 2000
years ago.
You know what I mean?
That.
So you.
So that's number one.
Number one is the names that we've
given.
These things are not the real names.
Number two is when you say that this is
this country,
well it is right now,
you know,
it's,
you think it's going to be this country
and 500 years,
but for a lot of people it doesn't
matter because it is right now,
you know,
it gives them like a like,
look,
I'm a fucking American bug off almond
butter.
Second Amendment rights are always
weird.
This is what America is about.
Always weird,
but America is in a lot of ways about
those people because those people
represent a large chunk of the
population.
The people who want to keep the guns,
the people that you know,
like Nascar and that's what they like.
As long as they're not criminals,
as long as they pay taxes,
America has to represent that and one of
the ways you got to have some low level
of patriotism type thing going on with
them.
Fuck yeah.
I mean that's legit.
It works.
It gets people pumped up.
They liked rooting for teams like
people,
eight black people like tribal thing,
and those teams are always fucking up
and went back in the day,
think about there was a great team.
It was called the Christians and the
witches and there were incinerating
fucking witches and that was also part
of being an American at one time.
Well,
you know,
burning the witches,
killing the Indians.
That's just like part of being a
Catholic at one time was being an
inquisitor.
You know what I mean?
It's always weird that the team thing is
greatest from a sentimental perspective
and it's like,
I get it.
You want to be an American?
Great.
You want to love the country?
I do love this country.
But guess what,
I love fucking humans.
Do you,
uh,
do you know the story behind what the
latest theory of the witch trials?
Yeah.
Or got.
Yeah,
tripping balls.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's awesome.
The latest theory involves a premature
for frost,
like,
uh,
they were growing wheat apparently.
And uh,
when,
when they have like a frost,
when the plants freeze and then thaw
out,
sometimes they get weird funguses.
And this one,
they did some soil samples and they
found that there was sometime around
that area around whether it was doing
the Salem witch trials was they had
early frost and they had the.
I think they found evidence of this
stuff,
this or God stuff.
It's very common though and on wheat and
what it.
It's like acid.
I mean it's basically very similar to
take in house.
That's awesome.
If that's true.
Well they bought.
They're almost positive.
That means scientifically it all lines
up because they know that it's happened
before that people have gotten.
They've gotten wheat that's been
poisoned by it and they've gotten sick
and they've had hallucinations.
So if you've got a whole country or a
whole city that's eating the wheat for
who knows how long that's filled with
God.
But there's some speculation as to
whether or not it would be still
psychoactive after you baked it.
I've seen people that disagree with it,
but in my opinion,
I mean it.
It seems to be a likely
candidate.
Well,
there's also the thing where there was
like an oppressive religious structure,
confusing people and are thinking that
there was a devil.
Yeah,
he could just be a high level
percolation of crazy.
It could just be let's burn,
which is let's take the ship to the next
level
and then,
you know,
we got to blame it on something because
I mean,
you look at the stuff that,
people are getting burned as witches in
Africa right now and they're not.
There's
no,
there's no ergot.
Usually there's just a bunch of Horny,
angry guys who want to fucking torch a
bitch.
That's what it is,
man.
And it's like also,
it's,
it's the,
uh,
it's the uh,
you know,
it's,
it's the,
it's the bad version of like the,
of the,
of what they call the patriarchy to.
I mean,
the fucking witch burnings.
We're just the same as us,
like killing the Indians in a different
way.
It was like there was a religion that
existed before Catholicism came rolling
through planet earth and that religion
was what we call paganism.
She's country dwellers is what that
means.
Just people who are more in tune with
the earth knew about herbs and stuff,
didn't.
Um,
that's why,
you know,
all of our holidays are fucking weird.
All of our holidays are.
They'll mismatch there.
All mismatched weird shit that we don't
really understand based on Jupiter and
like just strange fucking looper Kalia
is what Valentine's Day is,
is looper Kalia.
You know about that.
You know what looper Kalia was?
What's a park?
Holly is fucking crazy,
man.
You would get like am Valentine's Day
around Valentine's Day is called the
festival looper.
Cali and looper was some kind of Wolf
God that the Romans worshiped.
So what you would do is you would,
um,
as I recall,
I looked it up on wikipedia.
You can look it up guys,
and you'll find a much more detailed,
not spelled ultimate looper.
Kalia,
L U P E R c a l A.
Yeah.
Read that Shit.
That's what Valentine's Day used to be
a.
But St Valentine of course was a saint.
A Catholic saint.
Yeah.
Looper.
Kelly.
That's how you spell it.
Looper.
Cali.
Um.
Wow.
This is amazing.
Yeah,
it's interesting.
It's very interesting.
Ancient.
Possibly pre Roman pastoral festival
observed on February 13th through 15th
to avert evil spirits and purify the
city releasing health and fertility,
but read what they did,
dude.
They whipped,
they like,
or they will,
like there was flogging involved in this
festival is very strange,
but that's what,
you know,
that,
that proceeded.
That was the religion that proceeded,
uh,
the one that is the currently the
dominant religion and,
and that old religion didn't get,
didn't,
they weren't just like,
you know what,
we're not going to worship the wolf.
Got Anymore.
It was that they were getting torched
and I don't think it was based on eating
like fungus.
I think it was because the,
uh,
the,
it's to combating paradigms that,
that didn't.
They don't work together at all.
And uh,
I'm not saying either one isn't
necessarily logical,
but one is more based on the way the
earth works.
And the other one is based on the way
like old dudes try to control people.
That's where that,
that's,
that's the,
I mean,
this whole fucking pope thing.
To me,
it's crazy and hilarious that we even
pay attention to what that clown is
doing.
How is that even making the news?
There's some weird fucking group of
people who do like the most bizarre
ceremonies who I mentioned sanctioned by
governments in mass media.
No one calls it a call to the guy's
wearing a fucking wizard out with a fish
head hat.
It's if you try to do that today and
tried to say,
I am a daughter of God.
He has brought to me this information.
He tried to set up a shop.
They would think you were fucking loon,
but because of the fact that it's been
around for a long time,
this guy has a direct lineage.
We're supposed to take it serious where
he's supposed to take it seriously and
we're supposed to fucking ignore all the
Shit Catholicism did.
Well,
how about this shit
he did.
He released a priest that had molested
200 deaf boys,
200.
He let them go,
Huh?
He let them go into psychiatric.
Instead of bringing in and getting them
prosecuted,
they brought them in for psychiatric
treatment and this guy went on to.
They went to another parish and he
molested more boys.
I mean,
it's fucking craziness.
He did that time and time again.
He took people away from being
prosecuted and sent them to psychiatric
care and and they're free.
They're free to go.
They're free and they're walking around
the street.
Some of them are in these huge religious
retreat places that they have beautiful
grounds and these guys are just
wandering around taking care of for the
rest of their lives and the trauma.
There's a place like that where I live
or.
Yeah,
there.
Yeah.
So.
Right.
So that's happening and they don't pay
taxes.
They don't pay fucking taxes.
That is fucking okay.
Crazy.
All that shit is crazy.
The idea that they should be able to
make golden buildings and not pay taxes.
Bitch,
are you out of your fucking mind?
Can you fucking imagine that's a
business?
It's a business.
It's a fucking business.
You're not.
No.
You don't talk directly directly for
God.
It's 2013.
Stop.
Stop your bullshit.
You're not telling the truth,
you don't know that much.
I don't believe you.
I think you are very charismatic and
there's a lot of people that want to
believe you and they'll go along with
it,
but you're talking crazy.
God's not talking
can new stupid.
No,
you're an asshole.
You're an asshole and you'd taken their
money and we got to make sure that this
stops with our generation.
We got to make sure that future
generations don't.
They don't have a gigantic religious
leader.
Someone who tells them based on some
nutty shit that was written thousands of
years ago by people drew on animal skin,
but also it spreads that the way that
looks with [inaudible] is just one
version of the problem.
The other problem is the guy who calls,
you know there's like an in the way
there's a pope.
There's also a dude who calls himself
the president,
but instead of representing some
phantasmo forest called God,
he says,
I represent the will of the people.
Yet he doesn't really represent the will
of the people.
It doesn't seem like that when he goes
to when,
when,
when they do the polls and that as it
turns out,
you know,
and I'm not just the president,
of course,
the government as a whole,
the president doesn't have to tell
attarian power,
but I don't think that the president
really represents the will of the people
and I don't think Congress represents
the will of the people and I don't think
Senate represents the will of the people
any more than the pope represents the
will of God and I think it's this image,
this imaginary thing that we're supposed
to believe in because it makes us feel
more comfortable as though these people
are really enacting the will of the
people.
I think the will of the people is that
we want peace.
We want to be able to like,
we do want security,
we want education,
but we don't want fucking war war with
Iran.
We don't want fucking war with Iraq,
Iraq,
Iraq.
How the fuck do you say?
And I forgot to say that I got some
start up.
We don't want it.
Nobody wants war.
And if there is,
it's a small faction of people,
sweaty red face cock suckers,
you know,
or like that awful thin fucking
scarecrow con and coulter,
Jesus Christ,
she's like something that Baphomet
fucking coughed up like a hairball.
That Satan or rejected.
Did you see her getting booted?
The Libertarian Convention.
This fucking.
Oh,
she fucking had the audacity,
like in front of the Libertarian
Convention,
she said they were asking her like,
you know,
do you think gay people can get married?
And she's like,
yes,
gay people can get married to members of
the opposite sex.
You Bitch,
you dirty tap dancing.
Scandal is bitch.
She's such a beast,
man.
So anyway,
what I'm saying is there's a small,
there's a small faction of these pigs.
You know what I mean?
That grabbed the spotlight and produced
this illusion.
And,
and,
and certainly the one of the great
illusions is the idea that the pope
represents God.
Governments represent the people.
Television represents reality.
What we have happening on this planet is
a dramatic cases of misrepresentation
coming from a small minority of people
who've managed to grab power.
And this creates an illusion that people
try to live by,
and the reason everything's all fucked
up is because it's not based on what's
really happening.
Yeah,
and I believe that's one of the reasons
why government likes to keep religion in
positions of power and keep them tax
free because it helps when people are in
big groups.
It helps when people are already
indoctrinated to the rules of the group
because then you're more likely to be a
person who listens to rules.
The real issue with absolving all
religion is not the denial of the
existence of God,
but the denial of man's knowledge of
exactly what God is,
who God is,
what God wants,
and instead I could do is base it on the
wisdom of ancient teachings that we know
to be true today.
Lot of that is real.
Being able to treat people the way you
would want to be treated yourself,
in fact,
treat people as if they were you living
another life.
That's how I.
I literally try to do that.
I try to do that.
Gets a little taxing when you're like,
why am I such a fucking loser?
And this other life,
you know,
it gets annoying,
why am I a dickhead and this other life.
But if you,
if you just think about some of the
things that people associate with
religion,
the,
uh,
the ideas,
the good ideas of charity and love and
family and the values of virtue in your
ethics and the way you think of,
of your,
your,
your fellow citizens,
your fellow humans that you're in this
colony with,
that's,
those are all really super positive for
the most part.
It's mixed in with a lot of scare
tactics and fear and nonsense.
And who knows when that was all added.
That's the real problem.
But we know when we feel great,
we know when we feel filled with love,
when we know when our life is at its
best.
And it's real simple.
It's being around people that you also
love.
They love you,
you're unconditional,
you're all friendly,
you're all happy and not having a bunch
of shit that bothers you as far as like,
man,
I should have been a singer or man,
I should've played baseball,
or man,
I should have given it a shot.
Or man,
why didn't I call her that night sale?
Sorry,
but I have to be whatever the fuck it
is.
Whatever it is,
when you have regret,
when you're in that weird state of
regret.
I'm very extreme with that because I
tried to be like,
I'm very harsh on myself as far as like
a monitoring what negativity and
positivity and making sure that I'm in
like a,
a good,
a good track and when you,
when you judge yourself to be like in a
bad place or that can really distract
all of your creativity.
When it can,
it can completely fuck with any new
positive things that are moving forward.
It's instead you've gone onto correction
duty.
Then you have to look at like how did
this sort of behavior manifests itself?
What was the cause?
Is it alcohol induced?
There's an insecurity and Derek's like,
what?
What,
what happened or that were the
combinations of factors that led you to
be a Douche bag,
you know,
and yeah.
Yeah.
What was,
what was,
what was wrong with,
you know,
that made you have a mediocre set.
What was the thing that was bugging you?
Were you sat in front of your computer
for two hours,
you couldn't write chet.
What is that?
Well,
you got to stop whatever that is,
stop whatever that is and make sure that
doesn't happen again and we have to sort
of figure that out along the way.
We.
And that's one of the weirdest things
about being a human is we're all sort of
figuring this out as this thing is in
motion.
And I always equate it to being like we
woke up in the middle of a starship
that's hurling towards the planet and
we're like waking up,
hitting all the instruments going,
okay,
where are we?
We're going $75,
million miles an hour.
How close is that planet?
Okay.
Are we gonna?
Hit that plan.
Does anybody know how to wear the
breaks?
You just think turn.
Okay.
What happened?
How did we get here?
Who built this fucking ship and how long
we've been asleep.
I mean we literally are in the middle of
a,
not just a process,
but like a journey,
a process of constant reevaluation and
ingenuity and innovation where this
technology that we're surrounded by
increasing in its power and ability like
tenfold every couple of years.
So like he's crazy quantum levels where
they're coming up with quantum computing
and they're talking about the ability to
put google glasses on and communicate
with the fucking world all at the same
time.
There's this,
this time that we're at right now is
just,
it's,
it's almost as if we pick the perfect
spot for the most action,
like the perfect spot for like the birth
and emergence of technology into the
forefront of mankind.
Well,
you know that a lot of new age or a say
is that the reason that the earth is so
populated right now is because so many
different beings from infinity,
from the multiverse or wanting to
incarnate right now because it's such an
exciting thing happening to the planet.
That's a great way of looking at why are
there so many entities and currently
right now because there's only,
you only get one thing like this thing
went up.
Planet pops,
you know,
and it like wakes up.
It's like a really beautiful thing to be
a part of.
I love them.
I love that model.
I don't necessarily believe it.
And you have love that.
That's a very empowering Melissa
etheridge style model,
but it's mostly because porn is more
accepted and people are having more
crazy sex and are open about sex.
Right?
What younger people are having sex
younger.
That's why there's so much of a
population boom at this time because.
No,
no,
because fuck exactly the same amount of
porn and Oh,
poor,
poor and actually probably stops them
from fucking as much because they jerk
off.
I don't believe that the early 1900
[inaudible] it's all about family and
stuff.
People aren't having crazy sex or you
know,
your history son.
What do you think the roaring twenties
were those all people fucking like wild
animals.
Doctors were giving abortions?
No,
it wasn't in New York City,
man.
I think your perceptions of the world
are a little off.
The thing that brought people were very
conservative back to being conservative
was the great depression.
So before the Great Depression,
which was in the 19 thirties,
we,
they were fucking going bananas.
People were going crazy and that was the
roaring twenties.
They had speakeasies checks were getting
banged dudes.
We're living in a bachelor or putting
cocaine and coke.
Yeah,
dudes were living a bachelor life to the
point where pool halls were.
There was I think four times more pool
halls in New York City than there are
starbucks today.
There were over a thousand pool halls in
New York City at the turn of the century
because people were.
Kids were gambling.
What do you mean kids like young,
like nowadays that the average person
having sex for the first time,
it was like 14,
15 years old back then was probably 21,
22.
No,
no,
no.
You're wrong.
No wrong.
Yeah,
you're wrong.
no people.
It's.
We always have.
People have always had sex at a young
age.
Boys and girls have gotten together at a
young age forever and fucked.
I don't imagine that there's any more or
less fucking than has ever existed
amongst teenagers.
If you leave them alone,
they fuck you know,
and who fucks more than Catholic school
girls.
You really think religion.
Religion is going to stop you.
Religious is not stopping a crazy bitch
with a,
with a moist pussy.
If you leave almost any animal alone
with it.
Fuck,
I don't buy that.
But the conservatism that we think of
from like the 19 fifties will,
that was in response to the fact that
Hitler had just come along and world war
two came along and our grandparents had
to fight the Nazis.
You know,
my grandfather worked in a plant that
made a part for the atomic bomb.
That was always the big thing that they
were.
What do you brag around the house?
You know,
a grandpa makes a,
a part in his factory that is for the
atomic bomb.
You know?
So the,
the,
the conservatism that I think that came
in the 19 fifties,
the fear,
the McCarthy era,
when everybody's like,
you comment someone's a comment.
So we were worried about Russia doing
the same shit we had just seen the Nazis
do.
So then the sixties come along,
boom.
Everybody finds drugs and free love and
hippy shit.
And the government is like,
what the fuck?
Like stop this,
like we're losing all the government saw
a bunch of soft men running around in
sandals getting raped by Russians.
The Russians just come over here and
just store my beaches and kick us into
the fucking dirt.
Everyone's on acid.
Nobody wants to fight anymore.
We're going to get overtaken by the
Russians.
Not commies are everywhere.
Did you go to the communist manifesto?
Dinner?
I just want to know is all about black
list head.
There was like a wild frenzy to stop the
drugs and to stop,
stop communism and establish the hippy
bullshit and,
and you know,
and put more power back to the
government.
Well that's the,
that's the thing I,
I've been thinking,
dude,
is,
is it.
I think that there's basically two
religions in the world and that one
religion is a religion.
Religions pray that wrong or for when I
got cancer,
my mom's dying.
I've had a weird fucking year and in all
the turbulence man like behind it,
this is what's crazy.
Batch really severe catastrophic things
happening in your life is like,
and why they call it an apocalypse.
Personal apocalypse.
Apocalypse means lifting of the veil.
You know,
it's like you see this fucking thing
behind all the turbulence.
It's really weird after you've like
gotten the initial prognosis or after
you find out the bad news that you know,
you go into shock kind of and then that
faith and you pace around the process
process and in this fades away and this
fucking thing hit me.
You know,
and I felt it when I've been on a lot of
psychedelics.
I think you've kind of talked about it
and you're your dmt trip story,
but God damn it.
It's this fucking thing behind
everything that's saying everything's
gonna.
Be Okay.
Everything's gonna.
Be Oh k.
and you feel it.
It's not bullshit.
You're not delusional.
You really pick up on this thing,
what you feel is that you're caught up
in the idea of this small loop being the
big picture,
that this small loop represents your
reality and it's so important to you
because you have loved ones and because
you have car payments and because you
have a job that you enjoy,
it's so important you this loop,
but then it allows you to see that this
loop is just a and an infinite ball of
yarn that goes on forever and you and
you look at it and just go,
okay,
and it's going,
it's going to be okay.
You're like,
okay.
Because you realize that life in the
universe and everything we find
everywhere we look,
it's fractal and that it all is infinite
big.
All of it is infinitely small and
infinitely big and it exists everywhere
we look.
There's no.
We never found.
Well,
this is the end.
This is the end of matter.
Here it is.
Yeah.
It hits a wall and then there's nothing
behind it.
No,
there's no wall,
man.
It goes down to subatomic particles that
blink in and out of existence.
They're in a super position,
so they're in two different places at
one time.
They're moving and still at the same
time.
It's fucking madness.
They disappear and they come back.
We don't know where the fuck they went
and they can measure it,
but they don't know what it means.
And so I,
I feel like it's probably gotta be that
with just life in general and
everything.
Consciousness in general.
I think we're clinging onto this one
particular consciousness and this one
particular moment in time because I
think the human race is here to do
something.
I think we're a part of a process like
bees making honey or aunts making an ant
hill and that all of our wackiness,
whether it's ego or sexuality or you
know,
the need to conquer whatever these
things are,
they're all a part of this gigantic
calculation to bring us technologically
to the next level.
Whether it's because we're worried about
the other guys doing it first.
Whether it's because you know,
and that's how the,
the,
the movement represents itself
represents itself through the fear of
military conquest by the,
the other.
So we have to hit this technological
superiority first,
like sorta like the moon race.
You know,
what,
whatever the fuck it is.
I,
when I,
when I look at the,
the idea of our inability to grasp what
we're doing and our continued movement
in the same crazy direction like
especially when it comes to war and,
and the lack of respect people have for
poor people and the lower classes and
the lack of resources that are put into
raising the backup.
I almost look at it like it's,
it's natural.
If you look at every other animal's
behavior,
whether it's wolves and the Alpha Beta
representative in the wolf pack and you
know,
the way they have the social world
structured,
even if it's cruel.
We see bears eat their cubs.
We understand that this is nature bears
one of their favorite things to do.
Grizzlies,
they get up earlier before the females
do in the spring and they go and hunt
for baby baby bears.
They're going to go into the dense on
purpose to eat the babies a phase.
Yeah,
motherfuckers.
Right?
But that's natural.
And we know that's natural.
So we see it and we go,
well that's natural.
That's what nature wants.
It's we,
we're the only thing that we,
that can stop nature.
We can stop the equation.
We feel like we are intelligent and
aware and we are capable of stopping the
equation that we find ourselves in and
I'm not so sure if that even makes
sense.
Here's why.
This is the thing.
I thought I was reading this great book
about Ip holders,
so.
Yeah,
sure.
Dr Brian.
He'll tell you about boners.
Brian,
what?
What about that new ps four that you're
not excited about it,
Huh?
No,
I don't care.
I'm mildly excited about it.
I'm excited about the next generation of
these things coming out.
Not as excited about the new xbox,
but I think it was pretty cool.
Have you been playing games at all?
I haven't.
I haven't really been playing games.
Yeah.
I love playing this game called far cry
three.
Oh,
you really?
Yeah.
That's what we're changing the game for
you.
Well,
it's funny because the characters in it
are Douche bags,
like they're like,
they're really a cheesy storyline.
It's like a bunch of actors get
kidnapped by like tribal peppers and
it's very funny that the way that they
communicate with each other,
like we're going to get back to Santa
Monica,
Bro.
It's really weird,
you know,
like they've,
like,
they all were in the film industry or
something,
so it's cheesy.
It's like a chance to.
And also like the main character as he
progresses,
gets a tribal armband that keeps growing
on his arm.
Like it's definitely the game seems to
have been made by somebody who is like
definitely into techno and cocaine,
but it's still a very fun game.
Little Esther's watching us right now
and I've been having a side
conversation.
She wants to get fake boobs for real.
She's just trolling,
you know,
she's,
she really does want to fake boobs.
She has a nice rug.
That girl.
You try to think of him.
Yeah.
I've never seen a little asterisk boobs.
Apologize for that.
I'm usually very professional.
What comes to my urine?
He gotta go,
you gotta go drink a Kombucha.
Before the whole foods started getting
the new Kombucha is in again.
Do you know that a Kombucha tea,
like when you get it like Gts,
Kombucha or synergy?
They.
It was like more than one half of one
percent alcohol.
So you had to be over 21 to buy and you
still have to be over 21 to buy it,
but they just got it back on the
shelves.
They had like a diluted form of it.
We just still healthy.
The kombucha still good,
but it's not as good as the.
The True fermented live culture,
Huh?
Yeah.
It's fucking delicious.
So good.
You get.
If you did get a taste for that.
It's so healthy.
I'll drink a diet coke and feel like a
loser.
I just like,
what am I doing?
What am I doing?
Do I want to fuck my body up?
Like why?
I'd rather drink a coke because I know
it's just fatty.
I don't know.
What the fuck these natural or unnatural
sweeteners do for you?
I don't know.
I don't know what the fuck they do.
I don't know what's dangerous and what's
not,
but know sugar just gets you fat.
I mean,
it might give you diabetes,
have you got a wacky system,
but basically just gets you fat when you
take that.
Aspartame is significant evidence that
point that that stuff causes cancer,
like brain cancer or.
I do.
I eat a lot of that shit.
Yeah.
I don't think you should take a lot of
aspartame.
Linda's six splendid Trenta iced coffee.
I think the only shit that they've shown
that's really safe is Stevia.
Stevia is eventual even taste that good.
No.
Even lately there has been some shit on
Stevia or he'll.
Yeah.
Oh,
I haven't heard that because Stevia is a
plant.
What's that stuff?
This syrup a Gavi.
It's pretty good.
That's what I have is actually not good
for you.
It is so disappointing.
The Gavi is high in like a sugary syrup.
I had no idea.
I thought it was fine.
It's not like honey,
honey is actually good for you.
A Gaba is not good for it.
It's just sugar.
What a mess,
but it's not bad for you.
I mean,
it's like the real problem with sugar is
if you get it without all the other shit
that it's attached to,
like if you get sugar from fruit,
it's not nearly as bad for you is a
spoonful of sugar.
You take a spoonful of sugar in your
body just like jolt like that.
You're not supposed to get that in that
forum and when you drink a coke,
you're drinking like several spoonfuls
just pounded it into your bloodstream.
I wonder how many spoonfuls of aspartame
is in a diet coke?
No one's done that.
I've never seen that.
Even juices.
That's the criticism of fruit juices.
The criticism of fruit,
fruit juices is you're getting far too
much sugar like you,
you're really supposed to do is drink
water and eat oranges.
Like.
Because when you eat,
an orange is attached to fiber,
it's attached to cellulose.
All the different plant,
whatever the fuck the orange to the
fruit is made of.
It's like you're just supposed to get
that.
That's,
that's the,
that's the nutritional package.
It's supposed to get fiber along with
it.
You know?
It's like one of the reasons why Kale
shakes are show so good as opposed to
juicing.
Like this guy,
the whole foods was talking to me about
that.
Like,
do you juice?
I said,
I like juicing too.
I like juicing.
Juicing is great for getting a lot of
chlorophyll,
a lot of like you can get like highly
concentrated like Greens if you juice,
but the fibers really good for you too
and when,
if you can just choke it down,
you know,
and not a lot of people are like,
oh my God,
what are you eating?
Just choke it down.
You mean your Kale shakes?
Yeah,
those are disgusting.
I got to go ahead,
go piss you say they're nasty,
but they're so good for you man.
And I can't tell you how many people
that I've run into at these shows that
like,
this one dude didn't in Anaheim this
weekend.
He said that he lost 200 fucking pounds.
He showed me a picture of him standing
next to Dan Henderson and he was like,
or is it Ben Henderson?
Hm?
Not sure.
Blurry picture.
Um,
I forgot to ask him,
but he was enormous and now he's like
200 pounds.
I was like,
that is insane.
I go,
that's incredible.
He goes,
dude,
it was just listening to the podcast.
He goes,
you guys changed my life.
He,
I started thinking about things positive
and realizing what can I do to affect my
quality of life.
So I started drinking Kale shakes every
day.
I started working out just a little
going on,
walked 200 fucking pounds.
This guy lost.
It's crazy.
Let me check this out.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
This is.
And by the way,
that 200 pound things,
that's just one of them.
I ran into some folks in North Carolina.
They had lost over 100.
One Guy,
the guy lost 100,
the girl last 90.
I mean we run into it all the time.
It's nuts.
It's unexpected with this is what we're
about to play is Quintin Tarantino,
who is one,
talked about this before,
but this is an unconnected.
This video is Quinn Tarantino,
my favorite director of all time.
If you,
if you tell me like if there's a new
Quintin Tarantino movie,
I know I'm going to have a good time.
You guys are nuts,
but I'm like a lot of nuts.
He's,
he's nuts and he's a,
he's a brilliant director but he's a
chameleon socially.
And I noticed it when I was listening to
him on.
I had the Sirius Xm in my other car and
my last car and uh,
listened to him.
He was on stern and he sounded almost a
feminine,
like almost gay or very,
I should say,
very submissive.
Maybe.
I don't know.
What we're looking for is autistic.
Maybe it's that.
Yeah,
he might be that or maybe he's got like,
um,
maybe he's asperger's or something like
that.
But.
So then he goes on,
opie and Anthony.
And then when he was on Opie and
Anthony,
he was one of the guys who like,
you know,
open anthony or like regular guys,
you know.
So you go on that show and Jimmy Norton
stared talking about trannies and you're
like,
I'm one of the guys were,
one of the guys were hanging out here.
Guys.
We're hanging out,
guys,
guys are hanging out.
Then he goes on the Jamie Foxx show and
he's black and it's not really like
sounds black and sounds like an old
white guy trying to talk and he's
talking black to,
you know,
listen,
you want to talk about black dudes who
are bad motherfuckers.
Okay.
Then there's obviously in pop culture or
in athletics and you know,
there's been many,
many African Americans that have pulled
off some staggering shit.
Jamie Foxx is a mother fucker.
Okay.
Jamie Foxx,
one didn't even like her grammy.
He could sing.
It's fucking Dick off.
Okay.
You hear him sing when he did,
when he played Ray Charles.
That motherfucker is talented.
That guy can play.
He can play piano.
He seems like a fucking,
like,
like as good as a professional.
Famous singer could sing.
I mean the dude's ultra super talented.
He also has his own radio station.
Okay.
He's got the foxhole.
It's like.
Yeah,
it was Jamie Foxx.
He asked me.
He has.
Well it's your name is.
Why don't I call it the foxhole?
It's his place there hanging out.
Right?
So quintin Tarantino in the face of
hanging around with this,
you know,
Uber,
man,
you know this,
who accomplished so much.
This is a freak success story in the
history of the African American race
that he liked morphs into a black guy
when he's talking to them.
Let's see this shit and it's really
awkward.
Well then that was,
that was on the radio,
but this is something that I saw on the
Internet the other day where other
people are starting to pick up on this
and this welcome
writer,
director and Academy Award winner
acquaintance.
He knows all these black fellas and
ladies hanging out on this cool set for
the Django and they're asking them
questions here.
Has to be like one of the most quoted
movies in Hollywood with just the lines
and everything.
So you got to give us this.
One of my questions for you is,
what is the most famous like Yo,
your favorite line from pulp fiction?
Uh,
I think probably the most famous line is
I'm going to get married but on your
ass.
Okay.
That's not too bad because he's like
warming up for the
oppression.
But pleasing your fans or pleasing the
critics for you?
That's an interesting question actually.
Um,
um.
Well,
I want to.
I want to please my fans.
I don't want to police to critics that
I'm a fans.
The critics and fans,
I don't give a damn.
He rapped.
He is wrapped into an impromptu rap.
That was one of the most uncomfortable
things.
He's a visionary director.
Division of that girl wants to work for
him.
Ooh,
she's hot too.
I wonder if she would fuck them.
I'm not that computer savvy.
So Athena sent me something that I
plugged into my computer.
I don't know if I would ever heard it
hit download this.
I don't know how to do that.
Alright then Jamie.
My man.
Yeah.
Jamie Foxx.
Fox sitting here going,
man.
Motherfucker.
Rick Ross and the whole plastic.
By the way,
that's the same as Jackson.
Jackson is very uncomfortable.
Look at him.
He's not even taking that fucking
microphone away from his Dick.
Like.
So I can lady and said,
I need 100 black preachers with a black
sir.
Go over to carry with my little tape.
We're going to plant.
Isn't it possible though?
This is some kind of weird conceptual
gag he's doing like he was backstage.
I like,
I'm just going to do this for no reason.
It's isn't it possible at some inside
joke I made,
it does remind me of something that my
ex girlfriend,
the dude just because she likes like
kind of like trolling every single
person she talks.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I got it man.
With someone like Quentin Tarantino who
is clearly a fucking genius.
I've got to think first.
This is some kind of gag.
That's what I think that that guy is so
cool,
man.
Just because you looking for a
conspiracy and everything.
I don't know.
Maybe that's just me.
I go,
oh,
he's a loon.
I think it's brilliant.
I think has aspergers,
man.
I think he just gets uncomfortable or
nervous and he doesn't even realize he's
doing
it,
but I bet you're right of,
look,
we're making fun of the guy.
Okay.
It has to be done.
Doesn't mean I don't love him.
He goes to fucking awesome.
Thanks Jane.
I had an amazing director,
but that Shit's hilarious.
It's hilarious when you're a different
person in three different places,
but you might be right.
It might be that it's gotta be a gag.
Yeah,
let's check this and I'll get took it
home and I played on going.
This is the bomb
before.
My movies are always filled with song,
but it's always stuff that I chose for
me than my own collection or something
like that.
I never had like a music supervisor
hooked me up with stuff.
It's always stuff.
I chose a of the reason.
I know.
Watch this.
I just want to show him to write
something and then they do red nose
reindeer.
A Charlie Brown special.
What was that one with Fred Astaire?
Is the mailman a started.
He's narrating a Santa Claus is coming
to town.
Yeah.
At the end they're like,
what is,
who are you?
I was trying to find that he has speech
he did at the Oscars.
That was a really good one because he
was in front of like a,
you know,
like the highest of Hollywood people
who's being very respectful.
So his voice is.
And how he talked,
it was very accurate.
Like it was way better example than
that.
What we just saw there.
It was super white guy.
What a strange fellow man that is using.
Man.
He's awesome.
I love him.
I love him to love him.
He makes the best movies,
man.
His movies are fun.
They're all fun.
They're all wild chaos also.
You know about the theater he bar right?
They either theater in La that only
shows it.
It's in.
It's not in Santa Monica.
I can't remember the name of the
theater.
The theater he bought like a theater
with it shows like only film.
Yeah,
it only shows shit that was shy.
It doesn't show anything digital.
So like you go there and they show all
these old grind films and stuff and like
it's just bad as in like it's not a
profitable place.
He just does it because he doesn't want
digital to takeover which it is,
which is going to happen.
What's going to happen anyway,
but it's still cool though,
just to have it like that silent
theater.
Is that still open?
Yeah,
it's open.
Yeah.
That's pretty dope.
There's a silent theater in la where you
can go watch a silent movie.
Yeah.
That's where Doug Benson does all his
movies where he watches a movie and then
talks while the movie's going on.
He watches at the Senate families at the
theater.
It's called Santa Fe.
Yeah.
So He.
He watches a silent movie and then talks
over it.
No,
it's not.
It's not in the mood.
Just a regular movie like top gun and
then they just sit there and pretty much
common,
you know,
that was an also an issue.
A quintin Tarantino issue is Roger Avery
apparently was the guy who wrote that
whole top gun gay connection thing.
That was like Roger Avery's baby.
And quintin Tarantino did it in a movie.
Yeah.
He was in a movie and he like
chameleons.
Roger Avery and told the whole top gun
story.
It being sort of a gay love story and
when it really represents,
it's really brilliant,
you know?
Have you ever seen him pull,
pull it up?
Quintin Tarantino explains top gun
because it's a.
it's kind of a trip that Roger Avery was
a really
brilliant guy.
He wrote killing Zoe,
did you ever see killing fucking
fantastic crime movie?
It's a fucking great movie and it's
very,
I don't want to say pulp fiction like,
but exciting in that same way like pulp
fiction is.
I don't want to tell you anymore about
it,
but it's killing is always one of my
favorite movies.
So fucking bad ass.
It's like,
it's just really well done.
And then my cat,
after that I had a cat named Zoey.
Um,
so Roger Avery who created that and also
cowrote pulp fiction with Tarantino and
you can see like when you see like a
killing zoe.
And when you read some of his,
he was the one who got in trouble for
tweeting when he was in jail.
Remember that?
Nope.
Roger Avery was in jail.
I think he drunk drive.
He was uh,
he was uh,
he,
he was driving truck and he killed
somebody.
I think he got in a car accident.
Killed one of his friends.
Oh yeah.
And he had to go to jail for a while and
he was tweeting from jail and there was
like some sort of a,
um,
a controversy with the fact that he was
able to tweet from jail.
So they moved here.
They want them moving.
And I think because of it,
I think it like he really got fucked
over because of it.
I think.
I'm not sure if I'm telling them the
exact true story,
but he,
um,
wrote these really interesting tweets
from jails.
Really fascinating.
Let's talk about the different social
things that are going on and this guy
across the hall.
So the guy owes him money.
This could get ugly.
You know,
it's really fascinating shit.
that he would talk about,
you know,
God is getting bribed and dudes
smuggling heroin up they ass.
This is
what's it really about?
What's your,
what's like it?
It's like a stick.
This is fine.
This one sentence like,
boy meets girl,
I don't give a shit about them.
Fuck boy meets girl.
Fuck motorcycle.
You know what is really being said?
Which really basically that's what you
were trying to about because the whole
idea man is the version you want some
version on a massive level.
You don't want the greatest fucking
scripts ever written in the history of
Hollywood is top gun.
Top Gun is fucking great.
What is top gun?
You think it's a story about a bunch of
fighter pilots.
It's a bunch of guys waving fixer.
It is a story about a man who struggled
with his own homosexual.
That's it.
That is what top gun is about,
man.
You've got maverick,
right?
He's on the edge,
man.
He's right on the line.
All right.
And you got ice man and all his crew.
They're gay.
And they are.
They represent the gay man.
Alright.
And they were saying go,
go.
The gateway.
Go to the game where he could go both
ways.
I'm going to go.
She's,
she's,
she's heterosexuality.
She's saying,
no,
no.
Go the normal way.
Play by the rules.
They're saying no.
Go with the gateway.
The gateway,
the gateway.
That is what's going on throughout that
whole movie.
He goes to her house,
right?
It looks like they're going to have sex,
you know,
they're just kinda sitting back.
He's taking a shower and everything.
They don't have sex and he gets in the
motorcycle,
drives away.
She's like,
the fuck.
What the fuck is going on?
Next scene.
You see her,
she's in the elevator.
She gets dressed like a guy.
She's got the cap on the theater
classes.
Do you want in the same jacket that the
iceman where's?
She goes,
okay,
let's get this guy.
This guy's going towards the gateway,
so I got to bring him back.
I got to bring him back from the
gateway,
so I'm going to do that because I'm
going to dress like a man.
That is how she approaches it.
Right?
Okay.
All right.
But the real.
And they get the movies mix at the end
already gets it.
He has passed over into the gateway.
They are fighting for beating the
Russians.
All right.
And it's over.
And they fucking land and iceman.
Maverick the entire time.
Finally he's got it.
All right.
And what is the last fucking line?
Did they together all hugging and
kissing and happy with each other and
ice comes up the maverick and he says,
man,
you can ride.
You can ride.
That's so great.
Yeah,
that's brilliant.
You are Roger Avery and you wrote that
Quentin Tarantino movie that would suck
a Dick that tax and apparently quintin
claims that co wrote it together.
I don't know.
I don't know what happened,
but that's a fucking brilliant analysis.
Whoever wrote it.
Quintin or Roger?
Every.
Whoever wrote.
That's a brilliant.
What's that from?
That's from killings,
let.
No,
no,
no.
I don't know what that movie.
That's A.
I don't know what the movie was.
That's not killing.
Is that what you know now?
It's from something much more recent.
No,
that's not recent.
That's actually really.
I think I had much more killings.
Oh really?
Yeah,
I've seen that before.
A long time ago.
Okay.
Well now we need to figure that out.
Pull it up.
Find out what,
where,
where it came from.
Um,
but I think killings.
Zoe was in the nineties,
wasn't it?
I don't know.
That was.
Yeah.
I was like,
great fucking movie.
Man.
I love that.
That's what making movies is about as
sleep with that 1994 with me.
Yeah.
So I saw that long ass time ago because
I was addicted to Quintin Tarantino said
to see every single movie that Quintin
Tarantino isn't job.
Have you seen this Microsoft thing that
they announced a four.
It's supposedly for upcoming xbox and
what it does is it takes a picture of
your room.
So like say like your tvs on the wall.
It takes a picture of everything around
your room and adds it to the game and
it's fucking trippy.
Check this out.
Oh.
So imagine like a video game in the
future
scanning room and saying shit on the
wall.
But Watch,
watch,
watch this book show.
Pretty soon it,
it knows the bookshelves there
and so it looks distracting as it looks
better when you see it in hd,
the low raza,
the thing makes it look like shit.
Oh really?
What we're looking at.
Oh Wow.
It does the,
like it really manipulates your
environment.
So it adds it to the game.
Like oh wow.
So it highlights the bookshelf and the.
Yeah.
And so like,
like it showed like it should have
pixels,
pixels were coming at you,
but it knew the floor was there so the
pixels would kind of ride the floor and
stuff like that.
It's cool man.
That well it seems like that's where
it's all going to go right now.
It's going to the fucking oculus rift
dude.
That's where it's going.
Fuck the projectors.
Shit.
Have you seen the OCULUS rift?
What does that have you seen videos of
people with the OCULUS rift off?
It's,
it's this like consumer based virtual
reality helmet that's coming out that is
apparently so insane that when people
wear it and they hear someone talking
near them while the rift is on,
it's confusing.
It'd be like you sitting here right now
and suddenly a disembodied voice starts
talking to you because it like fully
like.
It's like apparently incredible.
There's videos of it out there.
If you've seen those red band got to
show people putting it on the lenses
credit.
Fisheye effect I got to do is give you
the headset.
Yeah,
he's going to where you're standing.
You would have your body,
your brain just naturally just telling
you to start walking,
you know,
it'd be a really good way to put this on
someone's head and they're like,
inside of like a train tunnel and have
them walk towards the light,
come out into the world
right when he puts it on,
walk up to like one of these buildings
basically.
And we can't see what he's saying
though.
We just see a guy with some crazy
good to see for yourself.
That candidate Anthony.
Okay.
So he's going to put it off for the
first time.
Taking the red or the blue pill.
Just adjust a little bit.
Someone that's pretty good.
Looks pretty good to me.
So before you take off running through
the streets of this village,
you know,
I want you to look left,
look right,
look up,
look down shit,
and actually look at 180 degrees of turn
your body and look at me.
Basically Ryan would be phenomenal.
So you do have all three 60 head track.
Wow.
So first just take a look at some of the
snow.
The snow is,
it's all stared at.
So you should see some nice depth to
that snow.
You feel like it's falling on,
you're going to kitchen.
Wow.
So they finally figured it out.
Well they,
yeah,
they've had it for awhile.
They just haven't been consumer based
when you know and they've got to like
the other interesting thing and one of
the other interviews I saw as they're
talking about when there are wasting it
and they say obviously they can't
release it until people designed games
for it and that it's not as simple as
just plugging it into a game because the
size ratios are off in a game and like
the characters running around in the
game are either bigger than a human
would be,
are generally smaller than a human would
be.
So for it to really work,
you've got to design a thing around an
actual human size.
So it's really,
it's a really strange.
They've got to go through and redesign
games based on this fucking thing.
Nobody works harder and longer hours
than game designers.
God Damn drives work some crazy hours.
Do you remember when we were hanging out
with cliff,
he beat and it was getting close to the
release,
one of their games and they said they
would just sleep in the office,
that we just sleep in the office and
worked for weeks at a time and like
loved ones would come and visit them at
work.
They would just be gone.
You've worked forever and just to to to
meet a deadline to get a game out.
Yeah.
It's a crazy world of video game
development.
That's a lot of hours and that's a
difficult
and so weird that like that,
that those guys don't have like an
Oscars that's going to be in the future.
Like now we get these guys.
You like regurgitate wind,
somebody wrote and we're like,
oh great.
What about these people who are God's
creating virtual universities that you
can run around inside of?
Yeah.
That's no joke.
That's no with code,
with code,
with fucking code.
They're not even.
They have to type lines of code to that
invoke virtual reality.
There's so many alternate dimensions
with code.
Yeah.
It's insane,
and then you're going to be able to pop
on and fucking oculus rift and suddenly
be existing inside of world of warcraft.
I call that my last day on earth.
That's going to be that in the hamster
wheel.
That's the one fucking problem and
that's going to be the final thing is
that
I think they'll just create a warehouse.
You know,
they'll just.
All you need is a gigantic warehouse
space,
so you have a warehouse space and you
designed the virtual reality game for
whatever the space is like.
Say It's a airplane hangar,
giant fucking Costco sized building with
no,
no trees,
no nothing.
Where aware we're pole is replace it
with a tree and boom,
you're off to the races and so you stay
inside this building and you live in a
reality totally created for this
building.
Or are you just plug some shit into the
back of your brain stem that makes you
feel like you're moving and gradually
just transformed a big fat wow.
Yeah,
and the other problem was if you had a a
warehouse,
the real problem would be the only
things that you would come in contact
with or things that are touching the
floor couldn't really come in contact
with anything physical and the virtual
reality sense,
unless you're dealing with some sort of
recreated neural impulse.
Right?
Like a,
a fake touch of fake.
Yeah.
It's got to be a fake.
I mean you can't,
you either.
You would either have to have someone
in.
There is a ball of virtual reality ball
thing.
You can roll in.
I've seen it,
but you either have to have something
like that or you would have to simulate.
Well you'd have to have your brain
movement.
Your body convinced this actually
touching the tree.
So it feels a tree.
Yeah.
Maybe if it was so convincing that you
or your fingers responded to it.
Yeah,
he gloved.
It doesn't make sense though because
would be some went to touch a tree and
it wasn't there.
Your fingers would just go right through
it.
Like you would have to.
It would have to stop it.
It have to be a magnetic field that
conform to some kind of shape.
It would have to be some way that
something you're wearing responds to a
magnetic field and it creates the sense
of a shape being there.
You know,
something like that.
Horns can be amazing.
Be Amazing.
Yeah.
It's going to be just insane.
Fucking Asian together.
Be able to.
You're going to be able to dial up a
bunch of people just blowing you all at
once,
like fighting over a spelling.
It's going to be like,
hm,
well would I like today?
Monogamous relationship,
Ronda Rousey's hand job
and it's weird to think that the one
industry that's never going to stop
making money as Kleenex.
It's just always fucking exist.
Get biodegradable man.
They just go with washable towel socks.
Nothing wrong with a little.
Some hemp towels to clean off your
loads.
Yeah,
there's.
There's never,
never going to be an end to that is
always going to be cleaned up.
I always got to wipe your loads.
Tantric and you absorb them all and you
become even stronger is not the idea of
tantric that you like you.
You hold on your lows,
your body reabsorbs you orgasm like
ours.
Ours internally.
Does that shit work?
Have you tried it?
I don't know if that works,
but I know that there's a woman who had
a disease where she constantly orgasms
and she wanted to kill herself.
Yeah,
right.
Bragen bitch.
Far as like,
oh my God,
I'm coming again.
I want to kill him.
You seen that interview?
Stop it.
She's putting on an act so those,
those bitches that can't come don't kill
her.
So it's the only way she can exist in
with her.
Her wealth of Orgasms,
her wealth of coming.
She's like existing amongst the common
poverished women who never come and
she's older ages.
That's what women want to do.
They want to come.
If you could come all day,
he would come all day.
If you can come with the same feeling,
the same like release that you do when
you haven't jerked off for like a week.
You know that when you jerk off with
like bullying comes power and out.
I mean,
it's like there's a lot of force behind
it and get you get some distance.
If you could do that three or four times
a day,
you would do it.
You'd be doing it constantly.
If you have the same room.
This is something I always thought is of
course,
yeah,
like if there's a.
If there was like an orgasm,
are you taking.
You have a nine hour orgasm,
but this woman made me think that maybe
that's not.
Wouldn't that.
No.
They were like,
she was in hell.
Would it be too intense?
Maybe she's one of those chicks just
complains about everything.
Can you mention just,
wouldn't it be cool just to pee though?
Like,
like,
like a minute long p have just come out
really critic crazy.
There's so much more mass to come.
Where were you going to be storing it
all?
It watch your whole body.
Just your.
It would be like a lava lamp tour so it
shrinks down where were were.
You were like 60 percent loads backed
up.
Your toilet's overflowing with lowe's
piled onto the floor.
I joked around about imagine if sperm
just ran like you shot your load out and
they just fucking around around the
house just trying to find a uterus.
They didn't stay put.
They did.
Ran like an
well yeah.
I like based on the.
Maybe somebody out there in the Internet
can help us figure this out,
but based on the size of a individual
sperm,
how big would a giant have to beat as
shoot a load where you could see the
sperm swimming inside of it.
Wow.
There's a boy that died who supposedly
mastered baited 42 times in a day and he
died.
Yeah,
that's in Brazil.
Right?
Who knows if that's true.
Somebody could have just made that up.
How does it kill you?
How does he like jerking off?
That's not what killed them.
Killed him.
He probably didn't eat already.
Starved to death or he fucking fell and
hit his head because he was tired.
The jerking,
jerking off going to kill you.
I don't even understand what you're
saying.
Maybe you had like the abrasions caused
you to bleed out.
I don't know.
I'm.
I'm looking for A.
I wanted to go back to that aspartame
thing because I'm looking at and
aspartame and uh,
when you look on the Wikipedia,
um,
it doesn't seem like it's that
dangerous.
Well,
I mean if it was slightly dangerous,
I doubt would be in coke zero.
You know why?
Yeah.
You gotta wonder like how many fucking
people are taking it?
I think it's just like the science.
Tammy Faye Bakker,
late stage cancer videos.
Is that from diet coke?
He was addicted to diet coke and there's
no correlation.
No connection.
I mean except for the fact that she
drank.
She was one of those people who was
addicted to diet coke and drink
boatloads of.
No,
I'm not saying there's a correlation
that I.
It could have been super,
super unhealthy and all sorts of ways.
Anyway.
Yeah,
there's just something.
It's never been proven.
But there is like,
there is a,
I think there is like a,
some people do think that diet coke,
like you just said causes cancer,
you know,
and she drank a fuck load.
It was like her.
She would have like something,
some ridiculous amount,
like 15 a day or 20 a day.
Like more than you should ever have.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Bitch.
Do you remember?
Rest of soul.
Do you remember when that whole Jim
Bakker,
Tammy Faye Bakker controversy was going
on?
Oh yeah.
That was.
That was brilliant stuff in the 19
eighties.
That was brilliant.
Great.
Saturday night live thing like what was
the thing God was going to kill him if
he didn't get a certain donation level
or something.
Is that what his thing was?
Well,
he his this
thing.
I don't know.
I don't know what happened there,
but it all.
It was basically just an affair.
Right.
So Fair with Jessica Hahn.
I Dunno why it became so popular.
Why did it become so popular?
That was new in the day like nobody
was having an affair.
I like that.
Yeah.
I guess that's what it was.
It's funny you look at it now.
It's so time,
right?
What affairs and well,
in a fair by a preacher with a
secretary,
it would never be something that we
would talk about 30 years from now.
If it happened today,
you know,
it's like we,
it's like finally we got one,
remember what's his face got busted.
Jimmy swaggart got busted with a
prostitute and he was crying about how
he said,
have you ever seen that?
Ever seen him crying?
Yeah,
it's beautiful.
It's so beautiful.
It's like one of the most instancy or
things you could see a person doing
their life and when you watch it,
it sort of inoculates you to insincerity
because he gets a look at it.
Go,
oh,
that's what it looks like.
No connection to reality,
no emotional connection to their words,
no connection to me as the person
receiving these words.
It's almost sociopathic.
Sociopath.
Again,
it's craziness and it's beautiful.
It's beautiful.
It's one of my favorite things to watch.
Let's watch.
I haven't seen.
Pull it up.
Hold up Jimmy swaggart apologizes for
silly bitch.
And then there was the other guy who
said he saw 900 foot Jesus in the middle
of the desert.
That's what I was thinking it was.
No,
no.
One of them was like legit.
Jimmy Swagger is the guy who got busted.
Who saw the 900 foot.
Jesus,
I don't know man.
Your religious coots.
No,
I like them.
they're really are.
They're amazing to watch you.
You liked that dollar guy.
Creflo dollar.
I record his shit.
I.
I know you're talking.
I record his shit because it's so
ridiculous.
I want to address myself as best as I
know how to those that I have wrong that
I have sent against.
He'll go out and get hookers.
First of all,
my wife Frances.
God never gave a better helpmate and
companion with the possible exception of
that sleazy who?
What is this and as far as discussed,
fully playing this one man.
Funny Shit is real and cut.
Yeah,
don't put this fucking parody bullshit
on it.
It's this cool.
Watch them cry.
It may be dark days for the swag,
a church,
but as the Sky Clinton,
English people are talking about you.
There you go,
and I would skip it today.
They knew all the details.
Oh man,
these mother fucking false prophets.
Yeah.
It's an interesting thing that we have
this just deep,
deep,
deep desire to believe that someone has
answers.
Leadership Addiction.
Yeah.
What's a chimpanzee shit,
right?
Yeah.
Leftover Championship.
Well,
it's,
no,
it's the guy.
The thing is,
man,
there is a underneath everything there
is.
I think this is what makes me different
from a lot of people.
I think some people don't believe this.
I think underneath everything,
there's an intelligence that,
uh,
that's filled with love.
It's just love that thing when you were
on Dmt and saying,
I love you,
I love you.
I think that thing is real.
And I think that that thing,
you don't need a leader.
You don't need someone to tell you what
that thing is saying to you.
It's your own relationship with that
thing and how closely you can
approximate what that thing is saying
that defines your level of happiness.
Uh,
in this incarnation.
And there's,
there's people like that who falsely
represent that thing who don't have
never really experienced it.
And that's why it seems like bullshit.
Yeah.
It seems like bullshit to everybody who
hasn't experienced it.
And when you run into extremely angry
people that just have pitfall after
pitfall in their life and the miserable
experience after miserable experience
in,
you know,
you realize that they're just so
separate,
so,
so far separated from the frequency of
happiness,
you know,
and it sounds like some hippie bullshit,
the frequency of happiness really.
Hey man,
some people just live in an economic
downturn where there's a shitty economy
where they live and there's no jobs and,
and they were born ugly.
So they're fucked.
Yeah,
that too.
But there's also people that live like
that,
that are happy as fuck in that same
environment and they have great friends
and wonderful experiences with their
loved ones and they're not constantly
embroiled in bullshit because they
figured out a way to orchestrate their
environment.
And that's one thing that we somehow or
another are sort of responsible for.
Dylan.
Exactly,
man.
I mean that's the important thing that
the point that you're making there,
that's the most important point is that
it's like,
sure,
people are going to have.
You're going to have to task trophies in
life.
Everyone asked catastrophes.
That doesn't mean you're bad,
that doesn't mean you're wrong or that
you've or you're cursed or anything.
All that matters is how you react to
that and all that in the only way that
you're going to react to that in any
kind of way that's not terrified is if,
if you found a way to feel grateful is
something Tom Green set about getting
cancer as this amazing,
uh,
a description of the feeling that comes
when you have cancer.
He said it's a combination of terror and
gratitude,
you know,
and it's like,
because once you get it and you get
passing on a fuck,
I get to live.
It really is this sense of like,
my God,
what a beautiful thing this is exists.
The terror things never going to go
away.
As long as you're living in space,
you're going to be terrified.
We're in a fucking void,
meteorite hit as etc.
Etc.
But thEre is,
once you find that,
that plate,
real gratitude,
not gratitude,
where people shake their finger at you,
that you should be grateful,
but when you really plug into that
fucking thing,
god damn it,
man.
Everything lights up.
It doesn't matter if you're.
You know what the thing is,
it's happening to you lose your joB,
your wife's cheating on and you're
cheating on your whatever the thing is,
if you plug into that underlying thing,
fuck,
it's a beautiful,
beautiful place and it's a very
subversive idea.
The idea that everything is okay and
that behind everything is just this
field of just the happiness frequency
does that stuff
feeling?
That's the hardest thing to overcome in
life when you started out in a certain
direction,
if you'd gotten fairly far in your life,
but you're really miserable and you have
a lot of obligations and you have lots
of expectations and bills and a lot of
issues that keep you in the certain
shitty environment and people don't know
how to manage that,
and I think that's why one of the most
important things to stress is get off on
the right track as quickly as you can
with your life.
I mean by the right track,
I mean,
whatever the right track is for you.
I don't want to say don't listen to your
parents because you might be an idiot
and your parents might be dead,
right,
but you might have an idea that your
parents can't wrap their fucking puny
brains around to you.
You might be talented in one way,
shape,
or form that your father doesn't want to
see his creation go off to be.
And ultimately you are your own person.
You,
you really.
There's so many people that have lived
their life for other people and they're
miserable.
You know,
I've never met an ecstatic son of the
owner of a business who runs the
business with his father.
I always see a man who probably would
rather have carved his own path in life
and it's just caught up in the wake of
another man because that other man
raised him.
You know,
they don't,
but you,
you see a guy who runs his own joint,
you know,
and like they're fucking happy and they
have like zest and whatever they're
doing,
whether they're.
They run a pizza place,
you know,
I mean,
I've met guys.
There's a deli that I go to all the time
and canoga park cabaretta,
the guy who owns a dave,
nicest fucking guy in the world.
He goes,
always smile and laugh,
and the people that are happy says
joint.
You know what I mean?
I mean you.
It could be anything.
It could be a restaurant,
it could be a,
a fucking starbucks that's just hooked
up,
right?
It's your spot.
People like go in there,
you know,
it's like a little spot where people can
have their own little positive,
happy energy as long as that's what you
want to do.
Whatever the f you want to really run a
starbucks or run a coffee shop or run a
fucking jazz studio,
who gives a shit,
whatever the fuck you you're drawn to,
you've got to do that,
man.
That's so fucking important.
And people with their,
their escape clauses and fucking
parachute plans and well,
I can always pull out if this doesn't
work and I got a backup here and then I
got a backup there.
Man,
you better not back up too much,
but you got to travel light.
You got to travel light psychically.
You have to have very,
very few options if you really want to
make whatever the fuck it is happen in a
very few of them.
I love this.
When you remember when we first got to
be friends,
you said something to me when I was
sitting in that fucking desk working as
a talent coordinator.
Stuck is stuck if be dude like really
fucking stuck,
you know,
I like,
I can still remember flash,
you know,
like when people say things to you
sometimes and your brain goes and takes
a picture of freeze frames that because
it's like you listened to that.
I listened to that and I remember
sitting there talking to you at the
shitty fucking desk job and you're like,
you just got to jump man.
You just gotta go for it.
And you just gotta jump in.
And man that,
uh,
I knew you were right.
But god dammit,
what a terrifyinG thing it as they hear
that at first,
you know,
it's,
it's a terrifying fucking thing,
you know?
But,
and you know,
maybe making like if I jumped right when
you said that it might not have been the
greatest time,
you do have to have a little bit of
strategy involved in it,
but yeah,
you,
there is a where you are right now and
there is where you want to be and the
distance between those two things will
create a vertigo.
Well,
you had the most important thing,
which is the thing that you wanted to
do.
You wEre good at.
You want it to be a comedian.
You were funny,
you were creative,
you original.
So that was the most important thing and
the most difficult thing to get.
And I was like,
this other stuff is what's holding you
back.
Well you need to be doing is just
focusing on this thing because you're
awesome at it.
All you have to do is just do it.
Like the ability to do it correctly once
achieved doesn't really go away unless
you lose the fucking plot.
You know,
you lose the frequency in life.
I mean if you're a comic,
I expect to expect to get better.
You know,
I feel like I've had better sets like
these last couple of months than I've
ever had in my life.
I've had better moments I think on my
moments are better.
I think like the like new bits are
coming together in a better way.
Like I'm super super pleased with things
because I'm concentrating on it because
I've worked at it for a couple of
decades and I think that as long as you
recognize that that's what happens,
that as long as you live your life the
way we were talking earlier,
the right way without too much bullshit
and distractions,
too many negative karmic moments that
flood you with regret and fuck with your
creativity.
That's one of the most important things
about being creative.
One of the most important things for me
is being nice when I'm,
when I'm like as nice as manY people as
I can and I'm as,
as easygoing as possible and as
forgiving as possible.
I am the most happy.
I'm my most happiest when I'm dealing
with people and like being forgiving
and,
and being friendly and then I have less
shit on my mind.
And then I can tune into creativity
because I don't understand exactly where
my creativity comes from,
but as in,
you know,
a lifetime of trying to figure out what,
what frequency I tune into when I do my
best,
whether it's drawing or whether writing
or anything creative for me,
I have to have all these ducks in a row.
And the big duck is my own psychic
psychic,
but my own consciousness,
my,
my appraisal of my own consciousness.
How am I,
how am I interacting with this world
that I'm finding myself in?
Am I out of control and my fucking too
much gas on a break.
So my too much breaks down enough gas.
Uh,
what am I,
what am I holding myself back?
Am I limiting myself with my diet?
Am I limiting myself with my actions?
Am I limiting myself with my.
What am I doing in Missouri?
Is everything cool?
Okay.
Now if everything is cool,
then I can go to work.
But if everything's not cool,
I have to figure out what the fuck is
not cool and fix that.
And if I don't fix that,
it'll be bumpy.
It'll be the whole thing will be me
trying to duct tape this fucking ship
together while it reenters orbit and
fucking keep everything from falling
apart,
but as long as you give yourself an
honest assessment of how you're thinking
and how you're interacting with the
world,
that's where it gets fucking hard to do.
It's hard to take that first step and
give yourself an honest look at
yourself,
give yourself an.
And then once you do that,
then it has to sort of become an ethic,
you know,
and you've got a welcome and when other
people do it too.
Even haters when haters like point
something out about you.
That's correct.
You know,
you got to like accept that like,
yeah,
sometimes they get ya.
Sometimes they're right,
you know,
you,
you did something douchey or you were a
little weird there or you could have
reacted a different way and it doesn't
even necessarily mean you're meant to.
Like sometimes you just get picked door
number two and it's like,
what am I even saying this for?
You start saying something,
it's not even doesn't even represent
necessarily how you feel.
it's just a possibility of how to react
and all of a sudden you're off to the
races and then you're like,
nah,
you know.
I mean,
how many times have we said that in the
conversation as well?
Maybe that doesn't make sense.
You know?
It's like you don't even know sometimes
when you're saying things,
but when someone calls you out on that
and they they put it's probably good for
you.
It's not good for them because a lot of
times haters get fucking completely
work.
You figured to hope you sucked full of
million.
Duke's you drone world of semen and aids
and this is the people that get
completely ridiculous with their hate
and almost all of them are losers.
That's a real problem.
When you look at like what a hater is,
there is no successful haters.
There's no like bill clinton,
stop fucking commenting on youtube
videos.
Fucking queer,
you know,
it's like no one who actually
accomplished anything is a hater,
but being a hater is important for
people that are trying to accomplish
things like having critics and hate can
actually help you and fuel you and make
you aware of the broad spectrum of human
behavior,
especially like in a void of love and
absence of the correct.
Like you don't lash out like that unless
you are in an absence.
Let's see you an absence of love and
absence of personal pride and
accomplishment of absence,
of feeling good,
like you don't feel good so you lash out
because if you wanted to,
you could find something everyday that
you hated and just fill your day with
hate all day,
anger and hate.
You could just do that.
You could just do that,
but you only do that if you're an idiot.
Yes.
Yeah.
You're an idiot.
It's not idiot,
idiot.
It's,
it's.
You're stuck in a terrible path.
Yeah.
You're stuck in a pattern.
Terrible pattern.
That is.
It's not.
It doesn't help you in any way,
shape or form,
and in fact it limits you by keeping you
in this sort of,
this,
this negative mindset.
It's hard for me to relate to those
haters.
You know,
the,
the new internet breed of haters,
because I didn't have that when I was
like a lot of douche bags I can relate
to because I can think,
oh yeah,
I was that kind of douche bag.
I know what that kind of douche bag is,
but internet haters is more difficult,
you know,
like a tweet,
tweet haters.
But I've noticed that if you get hate
tweets,
I'll go to their timeline.
Sometimes they're all hate and it's all
hate.
You scan down and it's just one vial
thing.
There's many.
It's like they've got a list of people
and they just are like launching
vileness it as many people as they can.
It's a strange,
not just like one every five.
It's like if you have 40 hate tweets in
a row,
you've gone beyond irony.
Now you're just,
you're crazy.
Like now you're just some weird lunatic
firing missiles into the void for no
reason.
It's very strange,
man,
but other than
you're and you're choosing to do that,
you're choosing to try to reach out and
affect someone in a negative way instead
of concentrating on your own life
like you have made it more important to
do that.
Then anything else you were doing right
then because you chose it,
you chose it as your writing.
Those things.
You chose it above any self improvement.
You were doing any creative work.
You are doing any business work.
You were doing,
any personal emails you've got to get
out.
No,
no,
no.
You chose to call someone you know a
terrible name on twitter like you chose
to say,
I hope this a dumb cunt drowned in a
river of aids.
You decided to put that onto dallas.
Your.
That was your choice at that moment.
Unless it's really funny.
If it's funny,
then it's different.
It's funny.
You're not going to 50.
You know what I mean?
If it's funny,
you want to have 50,
but it's like when you go and look and
like not only is the person just
insulted you,
there is an insult to like,
we're too fucking yet.
Just like anderson cooper,
I've seen these,
these
texts,
the beaver do say they want to kick the
years,
ask idiots.
Mma fighters are constantly dealing with
them.
Yeah.
They,
they'll like and they'll troll you.
They'll,
they'll get you locked in on,
you know,
uh,
an argument and then you go back and
forth.
One of them that I thought was really
hilarious was a,
there's a woman who's a,
a comedy writer,
and she got into online twitter with a
chris brown.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Jenny was her name.
I can't remember if I.
She's a,
she's a very funny but yeah.
And people like,
he viciously attacked her and that's
what I go.
Why would he do that?
So then I read it and he's like,
damn,
I'm looking to old.
And she,
she goes,
uh,
yeah.
Isn't it funny being a complete piece of
shit as a human being tends to age you?
I'm paraphrasing.
I don't know exactly how she said it,
but uh,
and then he went at her and this and
that,
but she started it like he didn't beat
her up.
Okay.
And this is like years later to have
someone sniping at you constantly.
It's got to be annoying and I'm not
sticking up for chris brown in any way,
shape or form or anybody that beats up
the girlfriend.
But she started it.
She,
she decided to tag him in that and,
and,
and tweet him and fuck with him and get
him to react to her.
And everybody's like,
oh,
he viciously attacked her.
Like,
listen,
don't put your finger in the cage if you
don't want to get bit,
you know,
he beats up women.
Okay,
and whaT are you doing?
What do you,
what do you,
what are you doing by stirring it up
with him?
Yeah,
exactly.
She instigated a dummy,
dummy reacted.
She analyzed his psychology.
She knows this is a man who will swing
it.
A lady,
she came out and won some sassy shit.
And it's like,
it's,
it's like throwing salmon in front of a
bear.
Clearly.
But
that's not how they reported it.
It was.
He viciously went after her,
viciously attacked her.
When she started it,
she was dancing.
Enjoy.
The moment that dumbed down were
responded to her.
She must've done a fucking tap dance.
I wonder because I would think that if
there's a guy who's like really violent
and you're a woman,
I would think just the fact that that
guy knows who you are and you can't
defend yourself if you ever ran into
him.
Chris thought,
yes,
absolutely you don't think of crispr.
She said a bunch of mean shit about him
and he,
he saw somewhere he might palm her face
inspire mansion.
I'm saying if no one was around,
no one was around in her mind.
She has to realize that if she ran into
that guy and no one was there to protect
her and there was no security cameras,
there was no witnesses.
He might do something to her.
That's reality.
Okay.
And that feeling is why it's dangerous.
That feeling is what I mean.
That has to be in her head.
You start fucking with a guy like that.
The beat up his girlfriend in her head,
she has to know that if her husband
isn't there or some know maybe her
husband isn't there.
I don't know who her husband is.
Her husband might be kind of a pussy.
You might fold under pressure.
I mean you might run into a situation
where it's chris brown and you and then
what do you do?
What do you do then?
What are you going to.
If I would have to be so stone to like
get to that place now,
it'd be like,
fuck man.
If I ever ran into.
I hope I don't get attacked by chris
brown.
I got you.
You get in an argument with them on
twitter back and forth and saying chris
brown paint while you're not arguing
with them on twitter where you're a
woman and he wants to kick your ass.
I'm not saying he wanted to kick her
ass,
but I'm saying if you know a man is or a
beat up a woman and then she is now
locked in online in this like verbal
insult battle back and forth.
He's saying he's going to fart in her
and he's
saying he's gonna.
Uh,
yeah.
I said he's gonna like jerk off on her
and foreigner mouth and stuff like crazy
shit.
And you know,
to be a chick that's got to be a little
fucking weird.
Right.
What about the black keys drummer and
justin bieber?
Yeah.
Patrick carney did a thing where he said
something like,
justin bieber doesn't deserve an emmy or
something along those lines,
and the bieber fans went after him so he
just starts retweet and all of their
stuff with like hilarious answer's
always the best.
It was really fucking sticking up for
bieber are hilarious.
But he turned himself into bieber.
He made his photo,
bieber and change his name to justin
bieber and then with legs,
right?
And swag and all this different shit to
people.
Like they would insult him and he would
write swag.
Stop trying to pretend to be beaver.
You not be with.
You're a fucking loser.
Swag swag is such a great word to just
say like that.
Swag,
like especially if you're in a battle
with justin bieber's fans,
if you just say swag,
it like seeing that
the bieber army,
they attack a course,
so does the Brittany Spears army.
Neil hamburger a stirs them up every
once in a while where he was getting
attack for a long time by britain.
Brittany
beers.
Remember that video with that guy
screaming.
Leave brittany alone.
Yes.
That was amazing.
That video is one of my all time
favorite youtube videos.
The guy's lying on his bed.
He's gay or than a mansion filled with
dicks and he's just leaving,
just crying with his hair,
flopping behind him on the pillow.
It's just,
it's wonderful.
He's can't even get out of bed when he's
making this.
He's so gay.
He's like drawn to the bed,
like a piece of metal to a giant magnet.
He's just drawn to a bad luck.
It can't even get up.
She's just crying,
looking into his camera.
Cringe city at woman we were talking
about earlier actually killed herself.
Duncan,
the woman's orgasm woman.
Hmm.
Wow.
Betrayed by her body.
She lives in agony.
Not ecstasy.
Warning,
sexual subject matter.
Get your dick out,
boys.
It's just her moaning for bad.
I had not had medical treatment yet or
any kind of medication I had.
I had 50 orgasms in a row in a row.
Nonstop.
This is a saturday night live sketch.
I thought I was going to die.
Oh,
gretchen milan.
And suffers from persistent genital
arousal disorder.
A rare condition that makes her
physically but not psychologically
aroused all the time.
Doctors do not agree on what causes it,
but they do agree on how facilitating
can be.
Gretchen,
who lives in spring hill so she can't
work.
She's tried to get disability and come
twice and failed each time.
Income podcast,
my case had its limited number of
appeals.
Yeah.
She killed herself I guess in a couple
of months ago or something where we were
almost
6:18,
so I'm all right man.
Well we have to tell people that you're
not going to be with us this weekend,
unfortunately.
It's a some really crazy hell shit.
Yeah,
my mom.
Super sick.
I got to go.
Say goodbye to my mom.
Yeah,
you're like literally say goodbye like
your mom's dying this weekend.
Possibly.
Possibly,
yeah,
maybe a few weeks,
but a while.
I want to like,
you know,
you make sure you don't want to catch
her while she's completely aware and
folks in columbus and cincinnati,
sam tripoli's going to take place,
the hilarious tripoli.
So if you want to send duncanson love,
follow him on twitter.
Uh,
it's duncan,
t r u s s e l l and send him some love
buddy.
Listen man,
you're,
um,
your health scare freaked me out,
man.
It really did.
I would hate to live this life without
you.
Thank you.
One of my favorite people and one of my
favorite people to talk to.
And you're just such a unique breadth of
fresh air in this strange world that we
live in,
you know.
And uh,
without you man,
I really think that my conversations
would be less interesting.
you know,
I've had more interesting conversations
with you that I think I've had with
anybody ever in life.
You,
you've made me think about things and I
know we feed off of each other in some
really strange way in these.
We go deeper and weirder when we're
together.
Then when we were apart,
and it's to me,
uh,
you know,
[inaudible] just an awesome dude,
man.
I love you and I'm honored that we're
friends and you,
you're a very important part of my life.
Likewise joe.
Thank you.
Yes,
you've definitely,
I accelerated my evolution and credit
and you have mine.
We have each other.
We all,
we all have for each other.
You know,
it's uh,
that's,
that's the reality of a group of people
hanging out that enjoy each other's
company and then are all sort of like
minded and honest about life and sort of
trying to get through it together.
We help each other.
We've created our own community I can
trust.
So I think part of it,
we're all part of that.
We're all part of it.
So that's it.
You're dirty fucks.
Thank you very much for tuning into the
podcast.
Thanks to [inaudible] dot com,
use the
code name,
rogan and save yourself 10 percent
right?
Is That what it was?
Ten percent of any and all supplements?
Um,
thanks to hover.
Hover is,
um,
I'll use a code name,
rogan,
and you save 10 percent.
A hover is one of our new sponsors.
A hover is a domain name registration
company that has got to find the
fucking.
You pretty much,
you can get your dotcoms there.
You can get your dot nets.
It comes with free privacy protection.
Yeah.
I'm just looking for the hover.com
forward slash rogen.
That's what it is.
However,
dot com forward slash rogen.
You get 10 percent off your domain name
registrations
and uh,
they have such a,
some great things like free who is
privacy and very easy to use.
I used it recently.
It's excellent.
We support them and that they're owned
by the same people that own tank,
uh,
go to a desk,
squad.tv.
Brian has a all new versions of the
kitty cat shirts in.
Um,
so,
uh,
go get them while they're hot before his
new kitty cat gives you nightmares,
you're still working on one day.
You say anything you want at the end of
the month.
I'm going on tour and no matter what,
at the end of the month,
I'm going on tour.
It's on my website@duncantrussell.com.
When you go east coast,
New York,
laughing skull,
atlanta,
Georgia,
boston.
It's 10 days.
I can't remember them all,
but it's at my website.
We got to do some to man.
Anything you're not doing on your own.
Let's.
Let's do it.
More stuff to it.
Get up to toronto.
To the comedy underground.
No,
we gotta do to get to get back to santa
barbara.
Santa barbara was fucking bad ass.
Bad ass.
That's an awesome community.
Yeah,
let's do Hawaii.
We got to do it.
We've got a lot of shit going on.
North carolina.
Thanks a lot.
you guys are the shit.
That was a lot of fun.
Alright,
you fucks.
We will see you tomorrow.
Same bat time.
Same bat channel.
We got a lot of crazy shit coming up,
including this sunday when we get back
from columbus.
We have a special podcast with Dr.
Steven Greer at night.
This is a.
This is the doctor that's fucking
communicating with aliens.
He's the one that's responsible for the
disclosure project.
Yeah.
He's putting together all those high
ranking military officials that smile
come in contact now sunday,
but they've come into contact with alien
life and that we're constantly being
contacted by alien life.
Yeah.
What the fuck?
Okay.
And he's a smart dude.
So this is going to be really
fascinating.
Fascinating shit.
You fucks.
All right.
We love ya.
Love ya.
God is love.
What else?
Knocking holiday.
Krishna.
Hari krishna.
Alright.
Keep it together.
Bitches.