What's wrong with you or you started
already?
You already had started.
We just,
I just,
we just went live.
Hey everybody.
Fuck what's going on?
We understand folks.
We hear your story.
You hear your plight that a ustream has
been fucking up for you.
Uh,
it's been,
um,
what it was called?
Buffering.
It just lost my mic.
You know what I've noticed though,
Joe,
is that browsers,
so if,
if it's fucking with you on one browser,
tried different one because the flash
plugin alone has been just a connie
bitch.
Is that what it is?
Yeah,
like a,
like on Youtube,
Youtube.
I have problems on certain browsers
where it does certain things and I
changed it around and I've been noticing
is a lot of browser issues.
I use chrome for the most part.
What do you use?
I use safari.
I went back to so far.
Why did you go back too far?
Because it seems like it's usually the
best when it comes to working with
everything,
but it's crazy.
It's been fucking with everything.
It didn't use to write.
It didn't use to be the best one.
I don't think so.
No,
but it's always been solid for me.
Crumbs.
Good.
But the problem with chrome is that I
just go crazy with extensions and next
thing I know if he fucks things up like
ad block plus or whatever,
that shit fucks things up and then you
forget that.
That might be the reason why you know
you almost so far,
every type of motherfucker.
This episode,
speaking of the web is brought to you by
squarespace.
You go to squarespace.com,
forward slash rope.
Joe,
what does Joe?
Whereas squarespace.com
forward slash Joe,
if you go and check it out,
you could design your own website.
Joey Diaz.
I know you could pull it off.
It's not deaf.
Stupid.
You say that,
man,
but I'm telling you with something like
squarespace,
you can do it.
I could do it.
It's,
I'm not sure you're that much farther
behind me.
You know Brian does them while the
show's going on.
He's whacking out websites,
you know,
saying dog.
What's interesting about it is you can
try it.
It's not interesting.
It's excellent about it is you can try
it without actually paying for it first.
So you can go,
you sign up,
you don't have to give your credit card
and no,
you don't have to do anything,
just try it out,
start building your website,
and then if you decide to purchase
squarespace,
use the offer code Joe Seven and you
will get 10 percent off your first
purchase.
It's a sweet spot.
You should really check it out because
you can make a very professional looking
website in a tiny amount of time,
including setting up your own online
store.
I have had many sponsors on this podcast
and I can tell you this,
there is one,
one sponsor that I've never had any
negative feedback on that squarespace.
No ever said anything bad about people
say bad about every.
People can fucking find a way to
complain about anything.
There's always,
and not saying that their complaints
aren't necessarily valid,
you know,
I think sometimes,
uh,
people are correct.
They're over judgmental,
but oftentimes they are correct.
But squarespace,
100 percent,
not one person has said anything bad
about it to me yet.
Now Watch.
I'll go on twitter and then they'll
count it up for me anyway.
Go to squarespace.com
forward slash Joe.
Use the offer code Joe Seven and save
yourself 10 percent off.
All right.
God dammit.
We're also brought to you by legal zoom.
Legal Zoom is a website where you can
get a lot of shit done that ordinarily
you would have to go to a lawyer for
like you can get.
You can incorporate or you can form an
llc which is limited legal.
Oh No,
I know what it means.
What is LLC mean exactly?
It's where you make a company so you
could dump all your money into and then
once it fucks up you run and started a
new company.
Yeah.
And you don't owe anybody any money or
something.
Something.
Yeah.
I've had people who have been fucked
over.
Like you could do an llc at legal zoom
for only 100 bucks.
So if you want to start fucking people
off,
it's only 99 bucks and then somehow or
another,
I don't know
what happened to get a will at that
time,
which you could also do at legal zoom.
That's another good idea.
You start fucking people over to get mad
and they want to shoot you so you can
make your own will for just 69 bucks.
You can also get living trusts,
power of attorney and more in the past
12 years or over 2 million Americans
have used legal zoom and they've said
fuckloads of money.
It's a sweet set up and if you use the
code Rogan in the referral box,
you'll save yourself some money.
Remember that legalzoom is not a law
firm.
They just provide self help services at
your specific direction and they can
also connect you with an independent
tourney.
Independent attorney.
No attorney fuckhead.
They can also connect you with an
independent attorney if you need
additional guidance.
So check it out.
Legalzoom.com.
Use the code name,
Rogan boom.
Shock.
A boom.
Um,
what was the other one?
I had to do?
Square stamps.
Legals.
Oh,
stamps.com.
Stamps.com.
Which is appropriate because the new
desk squad shirts are on preorder as of
right now.
If you go to a desk,
[inaudible] dot TV.
My favorite of all the designs that
Brian has created,
I actually love this one.
That's fucking bad ass.
I love the cat.
And the last one,
he was my favorite cat,
but this is a cool shirt.
This is a,
I love the colors too.
And it's um,
it's a very high quality shirt as
opposed to.
It's not that the other ones were low
quality but they're like the standard
way you get a t shirt when you have like
a big design.
Like that desk squad logo is,
they just,
they take like a vinyl,
I don't know,
it's fine or whatever it is,
but some sort of static.
It's like a thick.
It's the process is just a bunch of.
It's like it feels to have a plastic
shield on.
So like when you're working out you feel
like this,
like,
like you almost have armor on and it's
very uncomfortable when you have a lot
of colors when you get sweaty.
Yeah,
yeah.
If you get sweaty it gets weird.
So this,
this process actually bleaches the shirt
and then read the ink in it.
So it's actually the,
the,
just,
just the cotton,
so you can't even feel the design.
So it's an upgrade from the last couple
of shirts I did.
So I wanted to have a little bit better
quality.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
he saw how my higher primates shirts be
rocking it and like damn son.
Why they so sweet.
Oh you know,
because of my man,
Mike Maxwell draw me something funky.
Champs.
That's right.
Um,
so uh,
yeah.
So these would be coming up really soon.
So jump on him now.
Um,
they,
I mean I see a shit load of these old
ones every time I performed,
including this past weekend when Joey
Diaz,
when I wear a rock in the joint and
Vegas.
Goddamn son.
Fuck God.
Damn.
We'll talk about that.
We'll talk about the UFC and more legal
stamp doc.
Um,
and legal squarespace dot zoom.
No,
I'm just kidding.
No I didn't get the stamps.
Dot Com site.
Really real fuck up.
Could you imagine if I was that far?
High stamps.com.
If you go there,
if you click on it,
they have that old school microphone in
the upper right hand corner.
Well,
if you click on that old school
microphone and enter in the code name j
e r e,
which stands for the jail Rogan
experience.
You can save an ass load of money,
including um,
it's $110 thing off.
You get a free scale,
a digital scale which you are not to use
for marijuana.
Sir.
This is for sending packages.
Asshole.
Okay.
You Do,
do not send.
Listened to me.
Do not send marijuana through the post
office use ups because the post office
that's like,
it's against the law.
They'll put you in a fucking cage.
It once,
they'll break your shit and Hollywood
and take the weed themselves.
They're fucking savages.
And you can't blame.
If I was a mailman,
I'd be ripping up a envelope.
Students get sent that.
Yeah,
it's the code.
The codes of sweet code.
You save a lot of money off of what they
normally offer,
but even if he didn't have my code,
it's a great deal.
And you get this sweet digital scale.
And what you do is you print,
like say if you're selling anything like
Brian selling those t shirts,
you just make it yourself,
have it printed up yourself and you just
weigh the packages on a digital scale.
You print up everything off of your
computer or Boehm handed to the
postmaster.
Done.
I used it today actually.
I haven't used the mail in a long time
and I didn't have a stamp.
I'm like fuck,
I got to go to the store and like,
Oh yeah,
I have stamps.com
and I just put the envelope in the
printer.
Bam,
boom it in the mailbox.
It's so easy kid.
You can't go
wrong.
Go to stamps.com
and use the code j r e and save yourself
some money on an excellent service.
And I'm supposed to say something
official to give you shit to sale like
something official,
but
it's $110 value.
Yeah,
it's what it is,
is a really good deal.
That's what I think about stamps.com.
I think it just totally makes sense if
you're.
If you're smart,
like why would you want to go to the
fucking post?
Joe Rogan sell them that I'm talking to.
You don't have that many years left.
I don't have 20 minutes to go down there
and wait for the fucking.
It's a nightmare.
Going to be a lot more than 20 minutes
if you go to the wrong post office.
The wrong time.
I've been there before where it took me
an hour and 10 minutes just to go.
Yes.
Yeah.
There was a gang of people and they all
had shit to way that were all saying it
was around Christmas.
I was an asshole.
I was like,
wow,
this is bad.
I hate going up.
Boy.
I got a box at the Po box.
I go there.
You gotta give it together with online
and I forget to go and I get emails from
people.
They sent my shit back.
Yeah,
and I don't want to burden these fucking
people either.
Who wants to be the 30th person in line
that day with stacks of shit for them to
send out and they're tired of doing your
God damn work for you?
Stamps.com.
Just needs to get a passport thing
because that's the only reason I have to
go to the post office now it's for like
when you have to do things like
passports are showing that just it's
annoying because you're mixing passport.
People in with fucking regular mail
people.
Pat Bluebeam.
Like getting a new passport.
Is that what you mean?
Yeah,
that's where I got my passport recently.
It was a pain in the ass at the post
office today.
And why is that together?
A dozen drugs,
tobacco and firearms and tobacco,
Tobacco,
alcohol and firearms.
They're all together.
Like how?
What the fuck is why those three
together?
That's ridiculous.
Passports and stamps.
So you can send a package or you.
Yeah,
whatever you're sending through the air.
I mean Joe Rogan.
Why would drugs tobacco and show up to a
rescue for tobacco?
Like if you were selling them with
stickers on me.
Well you could sell stolen shit.
It could be that you could be,
yeah,
you could be like not having a tax stamp
or something,
so like you're a company that's trying
to sell it and not pay taxes on it.
People are crazy,
man.
You always hear about people that are
like running businesses for a couple of
years.
Gangster style cash,
only pay no taxes and then they just
vanish and it happens all the time.
You know,
there was a.
We had this lady yesterday from the
Oxycontin Express who was talking about
those pain clinics of Florida and one of
them was cash only.
They were there for two years.
He made $40,000,000
and then they got arrested.
When they hook you up with some oxy?
Yeah,
if you're a.
If you're interested,
go listen to it because she was a.
The whole story was fucking amazing.
We can talk about that on the podcast
because I know.
Oh all day dog.
We just got off oxy and out to get a
little beautiful.
We're also brought to you by [inaudible]
dot com.
As always.
I can't say it in a different way.
I've tried.
I've tried that commercials in a
different way.
I've tried,
if you've never heard this podcast
before on a dessert company and full
disclosure that I have a financial stake
in,
uh,
and essentially we sell really just shit
that I use shit that Aubrey and I use
shit that people use it.
They're trying to get in shape.
It's like we sell a lot of kettlebells
and we have these things called primal
bells or kettlebells with this cool
chimpanzee face we had sculpted into it.
It's pretty bad ass medicine balls.
All those types of things you need for
strength and conditioning workouts.
I'm the type of full body workouts that
are,
think are the most beneficial as far as
like application in sports or in your
everyday life and just picking up shit,
you know,
you don't pick up shit just by curling
things if you're smart,
use your whole body.
And when you do exercises like
kettlebells and steel maces and club
bells,
um,
the,
those are the type of strength and
fitness,
uh,
pieces of equipment that sort of
emphasize those style of workouts,
the style workouts where you use your
whole body as one unit instead of like
really breaking things down to like
isolation exercises,
which,
you know people used to do back in the
day.
And it's okay if you want to look all
sex,
you have some sex,
a biceps.
If that's your only goal,
then go,
go,
you fucking sexy Quito.
You do those curls.
Get your,
the back of your triceps on one of
those,
curling those.
Remember those things,
show ideas,
those preacher curls.
Everybody would do that.
Everybody wanted the big guns to preach
a curl,
one of the least useful positions.
Do you ever find yourself in double arm
barred?
Hanging over a couch?
Doing curls anyway,
go to [inaudible] dot com.
Use the code name Brogan and save
yourself some shackles.
Joey Coco Diaz is here and we're fixing
to get busy.
Okay?
Check yourself before you wreck
yourself.
Big Dixon Yas Day.
Bang son.
We back,
we live,
we would,
Joe Diaz,
Joe,
he gave me a pot candy and I got high
holding in my hand.
Okay.
I held it in my hand.
I got nervous.
That's the people broke it up into
hybrid sativa and Indica and that is
even run as easy was saying.
He likes to cheap but shoes,
but he likes to full boat one.
The white label really goes deep.
Death redness there on long island and
go in and I've had them with coffee in
the morning before a flight and they
fucking picked me up.
I will drink energy drinks because I did
blow.
But these things fucking picked me right
up.
So not bad.
This is the,
I gave you the pain relief on to.
Okay.
These guys are going deep.
If you,
um,
if you do an energy drink,
it makes you want to do blow.
No,
no,
no.
I did blow for all those years so they
don't work.
Oh,
fucking red balloon.
Go to sleep.
I drink coffee and go to sleep to be
honest.
Take you to that too.
I could drink a cup of coffee.
Used to be able to do that when I had
sleep apnea.
I did fucking just hit the crib right
after a cup of coffee.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
Oh my God.
I need to start a drink to start boxing.
Fucking passed out.
Get the fuck out of Cuban coffee.
Fucks up that
uh,
not Persian coffee.
Is that what it is?
Greek coffee.
There's some coffee that's fucking out
there that the cola,
the caffeine is just outrageous Greek or
one of those countries.
Those coffees that people think are like
really strong.
It's like the taste of it.
It's not necessarily the caffeine like,
you know,
I guess out everybody assumes Espresso's
like stronger than a cup of coffee.
Not really.
No.
It's actually weaker.
It as less.
The lighter coffees are the ones with
the more caffeine,
like a dark,
dark coffee.
Apparently a dark coffee doesn't have as
much caffeine as like a lighter coffee.
Oftentimes like when you burn them more,
I guess to make it dark maybe.
Does that make sense?
We roasted it longer.
What am I talking about?
Overhead,
but the first time I ever had Cuban
coffee,
I'm like,
oh,
this is like everything else Cubans do.
It's crazy.
You take coffee,
you put a half a pound of sugar in it
from the start.
They make sweets.
I couldn't believe how Sweden as we were
working in Miami at the Improv and
Joey's like,
you got to try to Cuban coffee dog.
Fuck all that stopped book shit.
That's for girls.
Have you been to Miami International
Airport and see that starbucks is always
empty.
That's fun and compete because it's a
quarter.
It's thirty five cents for a shot.
I know 35,000,
85 at the airport and if they give you
the sugar mixed into it,
you don't even feel guilty for putting
them a cigarette and uh,
you know,
you're like,
hey,
I asked for.
It's like a dessert.
I didn't know it's a desert and there's
a little pick me up,
but people think there's more than.
There is apparently a Venti starbucks.
I mean,
you can get more.
Yeah,
I think no,
I don't think mountain dew that they put
a bunch of caffeine in a while ago.
Maybe they took it off the market by
now.
That's the one that made me go to Cedar
Sinai for having a panic attack.
Yeah,
it was that exact same drink.
Mountain dew made you go to the
hospital.
That was the one where I pulled over on
the side of the road and they,
they,
they like the.
I sat on the curb with my phone out
with.
I had nine slash 11 and had one about to
push enter a just because I felt like I
was having a heart attack.
You feel Brian?
It felt like your heart's going hi to
know I wasn't high or in high school.
I had not eaten that day but I had one
of those to wake me up.
Yeah.
But it was a big ass.
I mean this was like a,
like a humongous,
like,
like a size of a c too.
Like what is that?
Like 18 hours and then it's like 16 to
18.
Yeah.
Yeah,
but.
But they,
they checked me,
the ambulance checked me like,
dude,
your heart's going crazy.
We need to get you inside.
And then they put a whatever that water
in your blood is,
because I said I was dehydrated and
stuff.
They give you like an Ivy tripp and they
gave me an Ivy Tripp,
but it costs me like $3,000
for this fucking mountain dew.
That's incredible.
Isn't it amazing how much it costs for
an ambulance to come and just look at it
was $900.
Don't sign the paperwork at the end,
tell them,
run
out of it.
So when they tried
900 bucks.
Okay.
Is it for their time?
Is it
the surface?
It's like most expensive limo in the
road,
man.
If I was rich I'd be just using
ambulances cause you can go through
lights to say you have a heart attack.
I'm just kidding.
Seriously.
That's brilliant.
Brilliant.
That's like a felony.
No felony calling an ambulance,
an ambulance company and you go through
all the right paperwork and you're like,
you know,
I need to be picked up
dude.
If this wasn't a comedy podcast,
just because when you say you probably
go to jail under the Patriot Act,
it was like a crazy,
brilliant wing.
That is brilliant.
So brilliant guy in Long Island right
now I'm going to open up an ambulance
company.
I'm going to run dog.
That's brilliant.
And they'll do it till they get fucking
pulled over.
What's going on here and the heart.
Oh good.
No,
no.
I told her if I had the lights I could
run through.
Well No,
and if you get pulled over,
you're just in the back seat and go,
all right,
stay that.
You're having a panic attack and we'll
just take it to the hospital.
Well there was a
guy when I lived in Newton,
Massachusetts,
there was a guy who were,
which by the way,
I went back to recently and I couldn't
believe how
mall it was.
It was really weird.
It's weird when you go back home and
then you realize how small everything
was and you don't know what happened.
Especially like Boston area,
like it was all those little towns.
We're separated by these little two lane
roads.
It's really weird.
It's really weird to go back to it.
Um,
I don't forget it.
Oh,
you went back home and you,
uh,
you went to Newton?
I don't fucking know either.
Well,
what would you,
what did you say
before that?
But the ambient ambulance,
that guy,
was that sort of A.
Sorry,
sorry folks.
A Guy,
um,
was using the ambulance,
like it wasn't going to an emergency.
It's just using it because he wanted to
get home or whatever you want to do.
Whatever the fuck you wanted to do.
We wanted to go through the slide and he
slammed in this woman and killed her and
it was,
it was bad,
you know,
I mean they wanted him dead.
I remember this like people were,
were fucking really upset that someone
died because someone abused a public
thing like that,
that,
you know,
people,
people expect that if an ambulance is
coming through it's risking safety
because trying to save a life.
And this deck was just driving around
and thought it was cute to run red
lights.
So I took through.
So you know,
slammed into center.
I always pull over,
I see p play a cop one,
but three cop cars went by me,
me and maybe two other people pulled it
over.
That lady,
they don't [inaudible] pull over.
Pull over.
Yeah.
It's scary.
People are dickish man.
They like to wait for other people to
pull over so they can pull over and
follow the ambulance and like cut a path
through.
I've seen people do that.
They don't
do it at all out here.
I mean Ohio,
everybody,
everybody.
I just saw and I'm like,
this is fucking rude.
California.
Some of the worst driving manners I've
ever,
ever.
It's so rare.
First of all did ever gets out of the
fast
lane.
You know,
it's amazing.
When you watch someone in the fast lane,
then you watched someone pull up behind
them and you see them just sit there and
then the process to go around like they
look and they know and they know they're
going slow,
they're going 60 get out of the lane.
They don't want to get more info in the
east coast.
You dealing with these little two lane
roads,
two lanes on each side,
so everybody who's going slow,
it goes to the fucking right.
You don't want to move to California.
It's like everything else.
It's like such a wealth of lanes out
here.
There's so many fucking lanes on the
highway.
The people that gang and yet the name
man,
u go
check this out.
Have you seen this?
Rethink your drink.
That's just how much sugar is in each.
A different kind of drink?
I think it is.
Oh my God.
Look at red bull.
Holy Fuck.
Is that real or is that caffeine?
Caffeine.
That's sugar.
Oh my God.
Look how much sugar's in red bull.
That's insane.
The same as that small mountain dew
though.
It is,
right?
Oh my God.
I didn't even a regular size mountain
dew it looks like.
And you know what?
Here's the other thing.
It'd be better if it was actually sugar
in there and that was their sugar in
water.
Is that what that is?
This thing.
Fucking water.
Bottled water.
How's that possible now?
True.
Zero,
but show zero.
Red Kool aid.
I think that's just a refresh.
I think that's just a reflection.
Yeah.
Right.
It's trying to get you to drink water,
obviously.
Yeah.
You mean that little packet of Koolaid.
That's ridiculous.
That's the same amount as a little
weight.
Chocolate milk.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
There's a lot of sugar in our lives
folks.
We're kind of hooked on that.
Yeah.
I'm trying not to drink coffee right now
and I've been drinking this Trenta sized
passion fruit ice tea everyday.
It has no caffeine in it,
but I don't get the sweetener in it and
I get splenda and that's just.
Yeah,
but it's got to give you brain cancer,
but the night much splenda that drinking
that much Stevia go with the Stevia,
but starbucks doesn't have Stevia for
someone home.
She got a gang of him here.
Why don't you.
Why don't you think starbucks goes on,
Steve,
too expensive.
I don't know.
Maybe they have a deal with splenda to
keep people from knowing about Steve.
Yeah.
Suppressing knowledge.
Dog suppressing that herbal goodness.
Stevie is delicious.
I.
It took me a little while to get used to
it,
but knowing that it's an herbal
sweetener and then if there's like
literally no strings attached,
it's just your body takes it in.
It doesn't seem to have any.
My talent truth as it seemed to have any
health
very recently.
I heard some stuff in that.
That's why people were telling me to go
to something else.
That other one,
it's like with x or aZ or a Xavier.
Oh,
xylitol salad part.
I've heard that as well.
Like some people like the Xylitol.
There was a reason that people were
saying something recently about Stevia.
Maybe I'm wrong.
Okay,
well let's go.
Go,
go.
What's wrong with Stevia?
What do you do Joe Ago?
Straight stab.
A little Stevie at the House that rob
gave me.
I have the blue packages.
I like it because it's super strong.
I have sugar too,
which I don't use every once in a while
with the new coffee machine.
I'll.
I'll make a Cuban coffee,
but you know what's crazy dog?
The biggest addiction I ever had was to
Coca Cola and with the weight watchers I
stopped drinking soda and it was like
the toughest three months of my fucking
life.
God is like,
I thought it was worse than getting off
the blow,
not having like Chinese food or
something with a coat.
The other day.
I had,
I went to someplace to eat and the guy
goes,
we're out of diet coke.
I said,
you know what,
give me a coat.
It was fucking horrible.
It's too sugary.
Oh my God.
Ridiculous.
Oh my fucking God.
That was terrible
sweat.
This stevie is used as a weight loss
aid.
It's used for treating diabetes,
high blood pressure and heartburn for
lowering uric acid levels and for
preventing pregnancy.
Also for increasing the strength of the
muscle contractions that pump blood from
the heart.
Wow.
Yeah.
That doesn't seem like you could eat
that all day.
It seems like.
It seems like if you ate that all day,
you'd have some fucking issues.
I mean,
maybe we should talk to tate.
He could be our patient zero because
that dude's got stevie and his system
all day.
He just drinks those mugs.
Have bulletproof coffee.
I should give a plug to tate too,
because tate just started his own a
mobile coffee business.
He's doing a butter coffee truck and
they um,
they,
I guess they roll around.
It's called rolling butter.
It's rolling underscore butter on
twitter and he's got like a butter
coffee truck,
all sorts of different flavors and shit
and he shows up at crossfit events.
Those crossfit guys are junkies for that
butter coffee,
like bulletproof coffee with mct oil in
it.
So tate decided to set up a truck and
just roll around and had his first event
this week.
So you need to go to the arnold classic.
Oh yeah.
But the last thing you want to do is
take a fucking truck all the way to
Ohio,
especially in March,
in March in Ohio,
son,
you might get fucked.
That shit my go ugly on you.
It could easily snow like a bitch and
March,
right?
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
It's risky.
In March,
remember that time back when you were
making the videos were that one dude
was.
He took his shirt off and you made a
video about it.
Like he took his shirt off in the
audience,
dancing around.
Remember that guy who was hammered and
then he gave me a big hug and then he
was so ridiculously hammered and then
after the show we found them in the
parking lot,
blood all over his face,
no shirt on,
somebody beat the shit out of him and it
was like zero degrees out or like,
wow,
hey,
take care buddy.
Get in the car.
Like that's a fucking normal Friday
night for that dude would probably
totally
as they're telling you the story,
they pulled the 2000 fucking hit me with
a bat.
Oh fuck,
fuck.
He ain't,
you got any ice on your extra batteries?
Extra jacket.
What the Fuck Guy?
I'll tell you what that show Friday
night that we did was uh,
I was a nice place.
I had never been the joint.
Yeah,
that was great.
To join the audience was amazing.
You know,
the audiences we've been getting lately,
it's just off the charts.
They're so happy.
It's like such a friendly,
happy group.
Like overwhelmingly.
It's amazing.
I don't know how we ever pulled it off,
but it's amazing.
And the joint was probably one of the
best ones yet.
It's one of the best crowds ever.
It was amazing.
It was just.
Everybody's so fine with that bar was
great.
Great time.
Joey and I went to that center bar and
uh,
we held court for like three hours,
three hours just hanging around talking
to people,
you know.
We uh,
Max are.
He got too drunk to see Max drunk Max
everly,
Asians,
Asian Jersey girl.
She was half Asian,
half Irish.
He was torturing her.
Well,
he'll torture your mom.
Foster with Jack.
He's done.
He's a great guy.
That was zooming over.
Yeah.
We had an awesome time.
It was,
it was,
uh,
you know what,
it was like a,
there was a lot of good vibes.
Nice.
I took the limo over to the fucking
South Pole.
You did another show after that 30.
That was j dot Davis was there.
Jason Rouse was there.
And what's the light show,
bro?
It was mind boggling,
like thinking of doing the weekend.
They're like,
oh my calling in August and go give me
the 1230 at 1230.
Wow.
It was good.
It was in a way is what's going on that
all these comics work like bobby columns
is that right?
Becomes 10.
Some other girl did 10.
It was smooth and so there's like a
bunch of real common.
Oh my God,
there had to be 2:50,
one to 50 and what was the locals and
lose what they were telling me,
like people coming back with drinks like
people felt.
Let me tell you something.
I went over there and had to be 150
people from the joint show.
No showed up with tickets for me to
sign,
but we told them you were going to go
going,
listen man,
this is fucking amazing.
I just got for cocktails made $17.
It didn't.
We announced it on stage that you did.
Was drinking something?
Something was going on.
I didn't know.
I didn't know for sure.
People like,
Hey,
you going to be at the south point yet?
Went over that Cj,
Jay Davis.
She got a bunch of comics I hadn't seen
that.
Just hang out and drink it.
Well,
we should do that when we're in town,
like in between every Friday,
every Friday at 1237.
I don't know where it was asking if you
guys are going to go stop by because
they,
I guess they had a show at the other
club at the hard rock the same night.
A vinyl at the other hard rock or
Illinois and diced dyson.
Yeah,
that's hilarious though.
So they were in the same places us and
they seeing if you want it to
before or after.
I think it was before,
but he was apparently his son was
playing.
He wanted us to come watch the son's
band after my show.
But you,
we,
you know,
we got mobbed by people and it was,
we had a,
you know,
Justin was with us so it's friends.
So um,
he's there like every weekend,
right.
I think for awhile or something like
that.
Both Amazing Papa bicycling many comics
with them.
Like a lot of guys came up and say hello
to Joe.
Come on guys.
I recognize I didn't,
I didn't know their names.
Well,
you know what,
if Vegas was was really smoothly run,
there would be a real comedy scene
there.
I mean it doesn't make sense.
It wouldn't be.
You're dealing with all these tourists
that are coming in from out of town on a
regular basis.
It doesn't have to be on the strip.
If you have one good spot,
like think of like that steak joint,
that Brazilian place.
We go to Texas de Brazil with the True
House Korea.
That's nowhere near the strip.
It's way the fuck out there.
It's somewhere in another,
you know,
part of it's not near the casinos but
everybody goes there.
Everybody goes there because it's good
because they know it's there and it's
good.
And you know,
there's people in town in Vegas that are
always looking to do something.
I know the casinos would like to keep
the shows in the casinos and it's great
to do the joint man.
We had a.
That was perfect for us.
But like for like the local comics,
like there should be a few comedy clubs
in Vegas.
It seems like you could have like a real
local scene in vegas.
I can't believe this is embarrassing.
This is.
I hate to say this because people didn't
pick up.
We walked past bread.
It's like we ain't going to break down.
Nobody goes.
We're not going because they don't know.
No,
I shouldn't say that because not Dunkin
does.
And he likes it.
Yeah,
that's why.
But it's like they'll never quite.
I don't wiggle.
It was because we're too dirty.
Is that what it is?
I don't know.
I think that he just likes a certain
style and you know,
I think Adam Hunter did it and he liked
it.
He asked me,
but you know,
when I see it I'm like,
oh,
I never even thinking.
I always assumed that I'm to do.
And then the La Dee la comedy club hit
me up when I was in Vegas and if we
wanted to go over there late at night
and do a spot.
You know the La Comedy Club?
It's at bally's I guess.
So there is a few comments.
A lot of them have like would they have
like Roseanne Barr there every,
every Roseanne bought it.
Okay.
Let me ask you this,
how does that work?
How does someone do like the same town
every night,
like five,
six nights a week?
Vegas for years.
It shows up on Monday we had to have new
people,
new people,
but how do you not go crazy because it's
fucking vegas and has the hottest shit
going on all day.
It's like the best party,
you know?
Yeah.
But let me talk some best food.
Sweetie Pie.
If you lived there,
it's very likely you might lose your
mind.
Vegas has God.
There's A.
There's a void in that town.
You know,
there's a lot of good people that live
in Vegas and there's a lot of fun in
Vegas,
but this is the devil lives in Vegas,
you know,
he does.
We all know he does it.
If you live there,
if you were there,
you lived there.
Woo.
I don't know.
Brian has the baddest bitches.
Listen,
I'm 50 years.
A lot
of fun in Vegas.
She is.
I'm still alive.
I might want to go to Vegas.
You know,
you get older.
You do.
You want to do Monday through Saturday?
First of all,
I wouldn't stay in the casino,
Joel.
Of course I live 45 minutes.
I would not be my life at all,
but like when I heard Roseanne Barr,
she's doing.
Yeah.
She lives in Vegas now.
No,
I guess you commute to stays.
I don't know what to day a week.
She does the whole week.
Virginia Masada,
the whole week Monday crew.
She does the 8:00
show.
Then one clocks on a lineup comes in and
they do it.
So a lot of people like that do just
change it to 10.
You know.
Bobby couldn't make it work.
It takes a certain comment to make it
work.
The hotel has to get behind you.
They just say what it used to be dog.
It's not like I read an article at the
UFC brings how much money per weekend
when there's a vegas and went to a
million dollars.
I wrote a management and it's like,
wow.
Yeah,
I see it.
I see the fucking concessions.
You the cheerleading competition from
Ogallala,
Nebraska and that type of stuff.
This is the new website.
Yeah.
That's one of the reasons why it's so
disgusting that it's illegal in New York
because they would make so much money
from having a UFC there.
It would generate so much revenue for
the city.
It would be fantastic and the fact that
these dirty unions have kept it out for
for that long.
It's really kind of tackle UFC at
Madison Square Garden.
Just close your fucking eyes for five
fucking minutes on my palms.
First we get a steak with lobster on it
or some shit.
A lobster fucking bisque.
How Salad we shoot over.
Are you kidding me?
A wedge from Brooklyn.
We get out of that motherfucking UFC
11:00
because the UFC ends at one and we'd be
walking out of the garden.
That one fucking 30.
It's like walking into your oyster
oyster of life.
You know how everything is open.
You get everything.
You get Chinese cube and you get to
county in the Bronx,
you get fucking school,
Geo Salad.
You can get whatever the fuck you want
at 1:30
in the morning.
We don't have to go get a state.
We'd go to China town.
We've got a really a clam sauce.
How many spots are there in la where you
could pull that off?
There's one in the morning.
It was a few of the standard Dantanna's
Dan.
Dan,
Dan is open till two Dantanna's up until
two.
They serve two to believe they do.
That's a pretty sure I got a stake there
and no one night after the comedy store
it really late and it was God damn
delicious.
Delicious with the side of stuff.
So good googling Dantanna's just like
one of those legit old school
restaurants from the East Coast that
exists in California somehow or another,
and it's just very few places like that.
I'm going to tell you where they're
going to Micah Boulevard.
It's sensational.
Oh my God.
I just was at the spot a couple of weeks
ago.
One of my favorite clubs in the country,
the San Jose Improv,
and it's a lovely place.
It's down the block from the hotel.
Everything's Joe.
You got motherfuckers tell us for lunch
and you go in there.
You get the house salad with the
spaghetti meat.
I can't even eat the meat bones saucers
no more because I get so scared.
I just get the fucking regular rat
Gustavo's now.
No bread,
no butter.
And the house salad,
they took a fucking hell of a steak too.
They got a char grill grill.
Charcoal Grill.
They use real wood charcoal.
They don't fuck around with those
fucking Tuxedos.
Original Joe's is 80 motherfucking five.
And the tablet really when you.
Not that one.
The tenderloin when never been to that
one.
Oh,
this was good.
I just broke down.
They Jewish lightning that something
happened with cap back open.
Something happened.
I don't know.
I did San Francisco last week.
I was in town.
Tremendous.
Tremendous food there.
You loved that one girl.
Every time we go,
you take me to that Hillary Pasta.
Columbia go nuts.
Yeah.
That cal zones.
Columbus shows too.
We filled it.
And that's another,
that's a legit place.
Yeah.
That's a legit place.
There's another place down the street
where it got that video of uh,
uh,
Tommy buttons.
He was dancing.
So was dancing to music and you came in.
It was you,
me mean secure.
Remember that?
What's that Asian place?
So that we go to that?
Yeah,
with denny.
that's a,
well it's Kinda like a sketchy area
where we went outside.
We had some Asian food after the show
and uh,
as we left,
we went outside the door and they had a
aquarium drive by,
filled with strippers.
Let's remember that we got a video of
the truck.
It's on youtube somewhere.
Um,
this,
this truck pulled up.
We were like,
this is the craziest thing I've ever
seen in my life.
And the cops would pull up aside and me
hit the lights,
tell everybody,
sit down,
sit down.
Because they're only allowed to dance
when the,
when the truck's not moving.
So they had seat belts they would have
to wear.
So it's like a pole and just like some
seats and like little tiny seats with
seat belts.
And the fucking cops would pull up and
hit the lights,
go a pseudo this girls dancing on a pole
on the back of a fucking man.
And all I could think of was imagining
life from their eyes.
You're,
you're naked and you're just driving
around like bait,
like you're like,
like they're chumming,
they're chumming the whole city to try
to get them into this club and they're
doing it by putting bait in a box.
Like that's what people had been reduced
to like a woman in the smallest amount
of clothes legally possible with
ridiculous shoes that,
you know,
she can't run good end and she's dancing
around on a poll asking you to come with
her.
It's crazy.
It's ridiculous.
Fucking fish tank full of checks.
Oh yeah.
I went to the playboy mansion and I got
to see all his rare birds and they have
like,
he has,
he's like the largest collector of rare
birds ever.
Really?
Yeah.
And,
and you walk in,
I don't know if it's the number one,
but maybe in California or whatever,
whatever,
but when you walk in,
there's these birds there that don't
even look like real birds.
Like I was saying,
thinking like,
I haven't even seen that before,
like in a book or a magazine or on TV.
So when you saw it in person,
it just seemed like it was fake.
It was so awesome.
He has the coolest animals,
like monkeys,
collections that I've ever seen.
Here's these monkeys that look like old
men that just come up and to go out and
have these beards and like these
mustache and look like,
like,
like Samurais freak you out that they
are locked in a little cage?
No,
because they're humongous cages.
Like,
like it was like having a cage be like
the size of like a football field.
How many acres is that dude have out.
It was a lot because I got like the full
tour.
Like most times you go to the playboy
mansion,
you have like,
look,
they're sectioned off and you're like at
a small piece of it.
I was there with friends with a family.
The girl I was with,
her mom was married to hue in the
seventies and so she's just like,
let me show you around.
So,
so I got to go.
I don't even think I saw it all.
I mean I walk for long periods of times
on these paths where they would have
like these little benches,
like blowjobs stations and then go for
another mile down.
Imagine that place would be expensive as
fuck to keep up.
He had a staff about 100,
200 people there too.
All the time.
I don't know.
One hundred,
200 people.
There's a lot of people.
Imagine you had to pay 100 people and
it's to run your house.
Yeah,
that's amazing.
That's craziness.
Joan rivers of some shit like that.
I don't know.
Joel Rubin,
you know at the end of the day,
that place to calmly store,
they should just pick those places up
and put them together so people could
see that for centuries when the world
ends.
Is it because that's one of the most
interesting places in the world.
Flood Disneyland would fucking rides and
Mickey mouse to mention how many Cox
were really sucked there.
How many dreams were broken there?
How many women left there going,
I'm done.
You know what I'm saying?
Like I just sucked at 11 cops.
I got crabs,
I got chlamydia,
I'm done.
And he didn't put me in the magazine.
I think of what really happened in that
because that's completely different than
being on the east coast.
That's,
that's a fucking of broken dreams,
you know,
it was the coolest thing was how many
older playmates were there?
They were the coolest girls in the road.
Like I was sitting in the game room
smoking weed on the.
I mean,
I don't know if I should say there was a
room that the floor's made out of a,
like a mattress.
So like you walk in and suddenly your
feet feel weird.
Like what are you wearing?
Shoes.
Yeah,
yeah.
Great Staff.
Right?
I know it's fucking to get staff with
the carpets just doesn't,
it looks like carpet,
but it's actually a mattress so,
so you just sit down anyways.
But there was like these ladies that
would come out of nowhere and there were
beautiful,
the most beautiful cougars out,
I would say 45,
48 and they would just come up with
like,
hey guys,
how's it going?
Mind if I join you and you're just like,
that's the coolest shit.
Hot Chick like that part of their uh,
their occupation to sort of mingle and.
Well it was July fourth.
So I think it was more of just like all
the family arguing,
bobby
betting,
all those chips were playmates,
bro.
What's.
She really wasn't the.
But I think.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Is she still doing comedy?
No.
Barbi Benton from the center of the
Brunette when we were kids.
How am I thinking of a Barbie with the
vein of the tech from the comedy store
that used to do that.
We'd room.
I'm fucking Vermont.
That bobby doesn't have the yellow car.
Is that what the yellow mercy she had
taken over.
But they put the vein from a bicep right
in her tit instead of a tattoo.
This bitch had a big Ole yogurt vein
like,
fuck,
getting crunches,
crunches butterflies all after on the
machine.
Whatever the fuck it is.
I kept on thinking I was going to see
Felicia Michael's.
It was like a bunch of Felicia.
Felicia go there.
No,
I don't think she goes.
I think she's been there.
The part like for parties,
like all of us.
How's she doing?
She does.
She's doing whatever.
Don't know.
She was a funny check man.
Yeah,
they were all.
Everybody's doing good.
But that place,
that place is very interesting.
Like I went there with a complete
different,
like I did the comedy for time,
like estate years ago on Fridays and I
go and hang out and some of it I can't
lie to you.
It's not my cup of tea,
you know,
it's not going to suck my dick or you're
not,
you're not gonna walk around naked and
talk to me like that,
you know what I'm saying?
But these,
these savages where you know,
and it was just peep when you're looking
at them and you feel bad,
but they're having a great time and they
have like,
people come up there with the illusion
that they gotta meet playmates,
right?
Like they had guys on this shit.
Polyester suits,
three piece,
the shoes.
It's really,
it was weird.
But when you look at that place,
you go,
what really went on in that?
Well,
what's interesting to me,
it is a,
if I think about it,
the playboy mansion,
is that it's sort of like the last sort
of house like that have a however it's
not going to exist anymore.
I think it's gonna be a museum because
when I was walking through I felt very
like I could see this being a chippy
kinda.
Yeah,
you cannot.
Then that's not disrespectful at all.
I think that no one,
I mean maybe someone could do something
like that in the future where they could
create like a whole destination,
but that's a destination.
It's not just a house,
it's not just the business.
Like it would be like,
oh,
there's the strikeforce fights this
weekend at the playboy mansion.
Like they had fights there.
We went to watch fight there.
You know,
they had a,
they had more than one mixed martial
arts event.
They're having kids though and his sons
and I think they're going to take over.
I mean,
hey look like young versions of him.
Like I could see them just stepping in
and being like,
fucking pimps.
Well they haven't makes sense.
He would groom them.
You know,
why wouldn't you want to keep that
business in the family?
It's a iconic name.
You know?
It's like you can't go wrong with good
management with a whole playboy thing.
The craziest thing,
just licensing those tattoos.
When I lived in boulder,
there was a girl in boulder who was a
limo in boulder at all times.
That's at number one on it and it was a
white stretch limo and a black driver
and the chick was blonde and her claim
to fame was that she was doing it real.
She went to the University of Colorado.
He drove every winter fucking limo.
Wow.
A half one limo,
f one limo and in a bunch of coke.
She did not.
That's what I mean.
How many people I know.
I know.
Like James Caan was associated like I
watched that movie was on about a month
ago.
That stupid movie.
Twenty one.
What was that movie that the girl got
killed?
Eric Roberts played the creepy
boyfriend.
Oh No,
no,
no.
I'm sorry.
Let's see.
Come on.
Come on guys.
What the fuck?
She was the playmate.
Nineteen 81.
Sharon.
I know Eric Roberts.
Killer.
They did 19 what?
Nineteen.
Whether she was the playmate ladies.
Jesus Christ.
Your fucking stupid.
It was a movie with Eric Roberts was
creepy as fuck and he plays a boyfriend.
He discovers her in Canada,
brings it to Marisa.
She's like 15 strange.
When you see a guy like Eric,
Eric Roberts that you see them,
he starts out Poba,
Greenwich Village.
She's in this fucking unbelievable movie
with Mickey Rourke.
I could just still to this day holds up.
Then one day he's on celebrity rehab in
between.
It's like some karate movies and shit
and you know,
for whatever reason,
like he vanishes and then has to come
back.
That's his daughter that's blowing up
right now.
Who just got his daughter.
That's the chicken is an actress.
Yeah.
The daughter was the daughter on a star
rating right there?
Yeah.
Wow.
I don't even believe I've seen this
movie.
He was creepy at the end of the fucking
gets these benches.
He was making weightlifting equipment,
but you also the real business where he
was,
he was making sex equipment and she
takes her over there.
He sits it down.
He fucking ties are you rips her legs
up.
I mean he just destroyed it though.
He was.
He was a creepy mother five,
and he shot himself.
Fuck them.
You know in the movie?
Yeah.
He saw two dudes.
They did two movies that star ready with
this broad and they did a different one
with the guy from the general hospital.
Now the older guy that I married on
June,
do you remember when they cut his thumb
off public?
We're going to take my thumb.
Chocolate Gum,
my dog.
But he's shown the monologue.
What he says to Mickey Rourke when he
goes,
what happened?
Here you go.
She left me.
Go what?
And he goes,
what's wrong with you?
He goes,
you don't have to remember.
He just breaks it down and go.
Sometimes they try to embarrass you and
you've got a backhand them and you look
into the face and tell them,
you don't look at nobody.
You don't say good night to nobody.
That whole little monologue at that
again was excellent.
Excellent.
He was a really,
really good actor.
That's why it's weird when you see him
like one day and that crazy karate
movie.
Remember that Shit I just played in
karate.
Masters backfires too.
As satisfying as you ready for this.
I just saw them motherfucking audition
about eight weeks ago.
Really understand for what additionally
for Costar like me.
All right,
so that's how.
It doesn't make any sense.
I just,
I don't understand.
How does a guy who's that talented and
he was in that Sylvester stallone movie
recently?
Um,
he was in the first one.
What is the one with Randy coture the
expendables?
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
He was in.
That wasn't.
He wasn't.
Yeah,
I'm pretty sure he was the bad guy.
He was fucking excellent guy.
Can Act as Asada and insisted on them.
He says,
I know that when he was,
when they were doing,
you know who his daughter is,
the chicken blow the little girl in
blow.
What's the movie?
Love with that little girl.
And then she went out to be a Disney
star.
She's a Disney store.
Look at Rob Redman.
She's like some Disney check.
But supposedly when they shoot at the
studios they have security that he can't
come on the set.
And she's Julia Roberts.
Nice.
So Julia Roberts really like fucking
with security on him and stuff because
she,
they try to keep her away from him.
I don't know the whole story.
I'm just telling you what I heard second
hand when she shoots movies or TV shows.
There's something going on there.
I don't know exactly what the fuck the
thing is.
She's really cute kid.
She was a cute girl and blow that.
He tells you he's going to meet her at
the end.
The whole thing.
Well when he was on celebrity rehab it
was very strange.
It just didn't make any sense that he
was there.
Like it seemed like he just needed a
break and didn't really enjoy Robert's
Emma Roberts.
I'm Roberts.
She's real cute.
Right?
Young girl has got to be safe.
Whenever someone going to rehab for re
we'd.
They're really almost need like a
behavior or break the need.
Like you know,
you go into Rehab for life,
you're off the rails for everything.
And he said,
you know,
if you really,
if you go into a rehab for weed,
it's like a.
He just need to go somewhere.
Do you think there's certain cases that
you could see going to rehab her way,
like people like,
you know,
like went,
Ralphie may used to be at his prime
where he'd be like,
seriously smoking,
like two pounds of weed a day or
something.
He's a perfect example,
you know,
and no disrespect to Ralphie but look at
them.
Yeah.
And so that's obviously a very impulsive
person and that's where I think that
it's probably,
you're not dealing with just the wheat
itself,
dealing with life in general.
Like there's this look,
we're all impulsive standup comedians
and some most impulsive people to
something about the type of person that
thinks to say the,
some of the shit that we say like the
way your brain works this word.
It's almost like an instinct for us to
just be wacky.
You know,
it's,
uh,
so when you get a guy that like is a
standup comedian and then you find out
he's a gambling addict,
it's never a shock.
It's never a shock when they're,
you know,
you find out they're blowing all their
money,
betting on sports,
like it's normal Mcdonald's or blow all
their money on for years.
But for me,
how about I locked myself in my house
and I played quake for 12 hours a day.
I'm a fucking idiot,
you know,
it's the same thing.
It's like we get impulsive,
we have this like almost uncontrollable
desire.
I wouldn't be sitting around.
I was like,
I would be sitting around doing
something else and all I could think of
was getting back to my computer.
I'm like,
I just want to get online and play some
quake and everything will be okay.
Loaded myself up with caffeine and why?
Because it's crazy.
It's part of being a comedian,
you know?
So I,
I,
I kind of understand comedians being
caught up in almost any like,
nutty impulse like that,
but you know,
marijuana really going to go to rehab
for that.
You're going to rehab for lifestyle.
That's what you do in life itself is
just too slippery right now and need a
break,
which is understandable.
You know,
I need to go to Rehab for Jack Daniels.
I think she really.
How often you've been drinking?
No,
I mean,
I mean not for drinking in general,
but like I,
I try not to drink Jack Daniels now and
it's like I miss it so much.
It's so hard not to do.
I've never drink Jack Daniels my whole
entire life except for like the last,
what?
Seven months.
Coincidentally the last year of your
life,
you've been balling out of control.
You're going out layers,
scared style son.
You'll listen to this sweet home,
Alabama.
You of drives off the cliff.
And what's the number?
Seven meaning the Jack Daniels?
The lucky seven or some shit like that.
It says this is like old number seven.
I don't know.
It's probably like their seventh version
of it that they made.
If I had to guess,
let's find out.
Jack Daniels,
old number seven ingredients gamble for
about four months.
I knew it wasn't me.
Yeah,
I,
I can't.
I can't glorify months.
And I was like,
fuck you.
I don't trust myself.
I'm going to give my money to some
fucking Dinah Thursday at 5:00,
over five fucking dudes shooting a hoop.
That is not happening the rest of my
fucking life or baseball or basketball
or anything that was.
I love going like Santa Anita Park and
Pasadena.
I take $40 with me.
I go and get a hotdog.
I got a powdered beer once.
The $40 is good.
I get in my fucking car and I go home.
You just say a powdered powdered beer.
Really?
So I.
They think they saw you fucking draft
beer.
That's why I got a fucking headache for
three days.
He was a football game where you have
see a vet,
you drink three beers,
went to the fucking headache.
You get the next day.
Yeah.
You know it's pounded fucking bit.
That was real.
How cool would that be?
Having powder beards.
Powdered bit.
I'm telling you,
this is a weird thing.
This Jack Daniels thing,
because apparently the old number seven
is the original recipe.
I don't get it.
Why would they call number seven?
It says old number seven.
Known ingredients.
Also known as black label.
This is the original Jack Daniels.
Oh,
you know what it is because there's a
bunch of different jacks.
One,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
six different tracks.
There's silver select green label,
Tennessee honey,
single barrel gentleman,
Jack.
I like that.
And old number seven.
Six.
Chuck Liddell's.
Everybody.
That's the right one.
Weekly that I don't fuck with none of
those cock suckers.
They'll fuck you up.
And you believed that Bro.
I really have not drank.
Jack Daniels was New Year's Eve.
Nineteen 80.
Well,
it got a big bottle in the other room.
Boy,
I had some of it.
Um,
uh,
this weekend.
Friday night.
Delicious.
Yeah,
I joined.
It was in a can of coke.
You're fucking taking me for a rough
tell you Joey Diaz.
I do some of our best comedy sets when I
have a little Jack Daniels and my
sister.
I'm not bullshitting.
Even smell like Vegas.
Fucking smell it though.
Vegas.
Friday night I had like three,
three shots before I went on stage.
He brought the bottle back there.
I see that there was lightened.
You motherfuckers drinking.
Those are diet cokes.
Listen,
I could smell them in the year.
That crowd though was so fun.
It was fun.
It was so much good stuff in the air at
that,
at that show.
That was such a positive show,
man.
I was a great show and the people that
came,
I listened,
man that you have the expo.
If I wouldn't have fucked up my ankle,
I would have gone and walked around.
You were limping a little bit.
Yeah.
I'm good now.
The next.
That was good.
Something that morning I twisted
something with these fucking adidas
tops.
No more than fucking hurt,
but the next day I was fine,
but I would have gone.
What a great little thing.
It's a great little show.
You get to meet.
You can roll with people.
You pay $10,000.
You could roll with fucking Frank Mir.
They have seminars.
They had all said the same time we're
teaching things.
Yeah,
I've.
I think it's beautiful.
When did you,
when you were a kid,
you didn't get to play football against
everybody.
Yeah,
and you never got to talk to you,
you know,
q and a's with Ronda Rousey Twain's.
It's a great fun.
You after your q and a,
did you hang and talk to the people you
went to eat as much as I could.
They had a,
I was doing this thing for the 20 year
reunion of a or the 20 year anniversary
of the UFC.
There's a documentary they're doing.
So they had rushed me up to this,
a studio that they had set up where they
interviewed me for like an hour before
the weigh ins.
Then we had to rush back to uh,
because I had an mc the way ends and
they did the lands.
The fucking wins were in the arena.
It was insane.
The winds were in the Mandalay bay
convention center and it was fucking Gi
Gan tick.
It was,
uh,
the event center,
Mandalay Bay events center where they
usually do the USA.
So the way ins where I know it was like
10,000
people at the weigh ins and when
Anderson Silva and Weidman gone onstage,
they went not like you could feel this
crazy electricity in the air,
you know.
And there was all these Brazilians that
were bullying when Wyman came out.
And all these people were cheering for
Anderson and you hear all these
accolades,
you know,
you hear everybody call him the
including me,
especially me calling him the greatest
fighter in the history of the sport.
And how long was that kits for it.
And like couple of minutes,
second or two,
you know,
just anderson like walked up to him and
uh,
Weidman walked up closer to Anderson and
Anderson walked closer to him and then
they were face to face and neither one
of them budge.
So they just touched faces.
And then Weidman,
as they backed away,
Wyman goes,
I'm not scared of you,
man.
I'm not scared of you.
And they understand.
Goes tomorrow night,
see you tomorrow night.
He goes,
I'm not scared of you.
He wasn't scared of a man.
He really wasn't.
And that was the difference on Saturday
night.
He really wasn't scared of him.
He knocked him the fuck out.
It's crazy.
It was crazy to watch like Anderson
fucked around like he normally does and
like he eat more so than he normally
does.
He humiliates guys with that.
It's a,
it's a real tactic,
but you got to absolutely know what your
opponent can and can't do.
I mean maybe he could've gotten away
with that with like a lesser guy or a
guy who's like easily be fuddled,
but one of the things they didn't
Weidman's campus,
they had people imitate that.
They had people like taunt him.
They had people spar with him and like
pretend they were falling down and
dropping their hands and poking their
face out and juking them and poc shot
and them and shit and doing all this
stuff that Anderson always does because
he gets you in,
in a,
like a defensive shell.
He gets you frozen up because he moves
really fast and one of his tactics,
his,
he will talk you a little bit and then
blast on you.
He'll blast on you can,
he can,
he could cover distance like deceptively
fast.
So he's really good at closing the
distance and crack and dudes and
sometimes he can knock them out and
sometimes like the Vito Belfort shot or
sometimes he just lights you up like the
first.
A few exchanges with Chris liebing,
you know,
just lit him up,
lift him up,
lift him up again before you eventually
stopped him.
I mean ashland is a fucking tremendous
talent,
but that dropping of the hands,
you'll leave yourself so vulnerable that
even a tremendous talent like him can
get knocked the fuck out,
and that's one of the big lessons of
Saturday night.
The big lesson is everybody's
vulnerable.
Even the best guys are human beings and
a human being as vulnerable.
The whole ideas and not get hit and it
doesn't matter who the human being is.
If their skill levels really high,
it doesn't prevent them from being
damaged by a solid punch.
Everybody gets fucked up by a solid
shot.
Everybody who gets kicked in the head
goes to sleep.
You get,
we'll kicked in the head.
You go night night.
It happens to everybody.
It happens to the best people in the
world and that was like a big lesson.
Saturday night,
the auditory beer really just shut the
fuck up.
Didn't.
It was weird because the room I was in
stopped.
It was weird.
Stopped.
Yeah.
I just stopped and it was a,
you know what,
it's good for everybody now.
Now they start from scratch again.
This is going to be interesting whether
they're trying to set up the rematch.
Um,
for the,
the word is online for um,
the new year's show which is December
28th,
which would be guess Matt Desk Job
Ideas.
Do you know what kind of hype and I
guarantee you in a rematch.
Anderson Silva is gonna dot his i's and
cross his teeth first knockout though
he's never been knocked out his entire
career.
People usually get that after time they
become,
they become vulnerable and they become
human beings.
And not only that,
the reality is if you get knocked out
it's easier to get knocked out again.
And who knows what's happened in
training.
I mean,
who knows,
he's sparring with like really high
level guys and training on a regular
basis.
You know,
he's probably with,
with Machida,
with Fazio,
like there's a lot of those black house
guys that are fucking bad ass beasts,
you know,
like who knows who's tagging him in the
gym,
especially when you're doing long,
hard rounds.
So everyone turns 38 at one point in
their life and Anderson Silva's 38.
So you have to think about that as well,
but you don't want.
When I was growing up it was 35,
35,
but we both discussed this.
Look at our board is 42.
How about.
Yeah,
how about Bernard?
Hopkins is 43.
That's what I was talking about I think.
And this one's got three.
Three more.
Good,
good.
Good.
Battles left.
Oh,
you know what?
They are even more if he fight smart.
Let me tell you something,
man,
before he got knocked out,
he was looking lightning fast.
He was slamming leg kicks in.
He avoided being submitted.
He got back up to his feet.
He got out of a heel hook and got back
up to his feet.
It's not like Anderson looked bad,
but what he did was he does what he
does,
that,
that taunting thing.
I mean,
when he knocks the guy out because of
it,
it's awesome and it looks great,
but when you get knocked out,
man,
it's like that commercial,
you know,
that nos commercial of the guy who does
these flippy kicks and the other guy
just blasted him on a change is called
them and boom,
that's um,
there's,
there's a reason why that's in a
commercial.
That whole scene plays out in the
commercial as sweet justice,
like justice to the guy who taunts.
And that's why the whole crowd was
booing Anderson.
They were booing.
Anderson with Anderson got knocked out.
I mean,
that's,
that's weird.
It's,
but it's a natural reaction that they
had no one told them that they had to
bu.
But there was a lot of people booing.
There was a tremendous amount of people
booing the best fighter in history
because he got caught.
And I think that is fascinating.
They,
like,
they felt,
he let them down because he got knocked
out doing something stupid and they're
like,
yeah,
what did you do man booboo?
Meanwhile,
what happened to him?
Man,
I just lost the title.
I mean,
he made an ass load of money,
but he just lost the title in
devastating fashion and people have no
empathy like big people.
Don't give a fuck.
People don't get the cold realities of
life.
Yeah.
That's whole mother fucking realities of
life.
God wants the envelope sales and the
glamours gun.
The part.
Have you seen that?
Unfortunately though.
That sucks,
man.
That sucks.
But that's a man.
I saw it with my mother.
I start with a thousand.
So you would never do that?
No.
Why would,
I mean you,
if you were there in the audience and
you saw it go down,
you imagine home heartbroken.
I wouldn't have.
Boom.
He's still the fuck I know what
happened.
I,
yeah,
as a fan,
I'm fucked.
You know what the fuck told you to fuck
around?
You know,
I'm the same.
I don't even like fucking around when
I'm walking around.
Brian,
I don't even like fucking around.
When you're walking around pay fucking
attention.
You go to an airport and you put your
shit on line,
the people in front of you and you're
like,
fucking attention.
Yes.
Shit.
But if you fucking do it and you pull it
off,
it's spectacular.
When forrest griffin,
when he fought fucking Damien Maia,
if you live by the sword,
you die by the fucking short.
That's why it's called Karma.
The fight before that I.
that's the first time I watched the
fight.
I didn't want to end.
Even if even if fucking frankie would
have knocked raphael out Olivera,
I would have said,
listen,
let them go again.
Let them go six or seven rounds.
That was a great fight.
The fight before that was a great,
great fight.
It was a great night.
It was a,
it was one of the most exciting nights
of fights ever.
Every Jujitsu guy is lightened the
fucking candles.
Roger Gracie right now.
I don't know what happened.
Oh,
expect that couldn't for whatever
reason.
Getting the uh,
his MMA game is nothing like his Jujitsu
game is off the chain.
He just go back to fighting in Jujitsu
tournament span.
It's like,
it's a great fucking fights.
How about Cub Swanson?
Oh my God.
Damn.
That was insane.
That was the best that kids ever looked.
What was curious?
He was insane.
He tried to cartwheel care.
No,
he did it.
He went to do an upper cut and he went
from where he faked and he came up with
an applicant.
He did something very beautiful.
Yeah,
he was doing a lot of beautiful shit.
He's really crafty,
like he's very,
very creative and unpredictable and he's
like fake slow and kicks high.
He does a lot of weird shit.
You don't 65 brother?
No,
he's 45.
He's 1:45.
Yeah.
That adds a complete different.
Let's just,
let's just put him up against the doodle
wanting to fight Benson Henderson in
Minneapolis.
Let's do it.
That's a hell of a fight,
right?
Would it be a great.
That's a fight right there.
Well,
I would like to see a rematch with him
and Aldo because,
you know,
he fought Aldo and got caught with a
flying knee,
uh,
like a double knee may,
maybe like 10 seconds into the fight was
very quick.
All the although jumped up and nailed
him on the forehead with a flying
economy open and it was nasty,
mean,
you know,
he didn't get a chance to get into the
fight.
He just got caught and I think that he's
a way better fighter now than he was
then.
I think it'll be really interesting
after watching him fight seaver like,
God damn man,
he didn't see her up.
He lifts.
Those combinations are insane because he
was so accurate.
Like the last combination that he
knocked him out with,
he hit him with like three or four
ridiculously accurate shots.
While you know it's a lot of chaos going
on and scrambling and scrambling after
him and he's catching them on the jaw.
That was a great fight.
It was a lot of great fights,
man.
A lot of great fights.
See people didn't give tim credit.
Kennedy enough credit for that fight.
Not even had his back.
He took him down and had his back and
was slamming him in the face.
I was like,
what the fuck is going on?
It's getting punched.
That's what's going on,
man.
Jujitsu is one thing,
but Jujitsu with punches to the face by
a guy who's a black belt in Jujitsu
changes the whole game,
like you might not be.
He might be better than Tim Kennedy at
straight Jujitsu if they had a regular
Jujitsu match,
but Kennedy's got a good enough to just
say that he could hang,
he can defend himself,
like he's not scared to grapple with
really high level guys any strong as
shit,
but Kennedy is also a boxer.
He can hit hard and when he gets it to
the ground,
he's got real mixed martial arts skills
and it gets to the ground health thump.
You with punches and so the guy like
Andre is not really quite a complete mma
fighter yet.
He's just as brilliant Jujitsu guy who's
entering into mma and there's guys like
Kennedy out there.
They'll,
they'll,
as long as they're hitting you in the
face like you're not going to submit
them.
It's just a completely different
ballgame.
You're all dizzy and shit.
Your face is puffy and you can't see it.
You're right.
I mean,
that's the reality of getting punched in
the face.
It's,
I don't like seeing it when guys like
really good at Jujitsu and I see them
come to mma and they're getting fucked
up.
It just,
it kind of bothers me because I feel
like,
you know,
they're not ready yet.
You should have,
if you're going to really enter into
mma,
it has to be a long term proposition and
you should look at it as like,
what are your strength?
Your strength is Jujitsu.
Okay.
What's your weakness?
Your weakness is stand up.
Well,
you got to fix that.
You've got to fix that first.
You can't even think about getting in
there unless you could fight in a
kickboxing match because you're going to
be going right away to some of the
highest level guys.
The world because you're hodrick racing.
They take a guy like that and they don't
like.
They don't move them along slow,
you know,
he's gonna fight high level guys because
of his name pretty quickly and because
of his reputation in Jujitsu.
Whereas the reality of his striking is
he's the one that is striking a few
years.
You know you need many years on the
books before you go and strike with a
guy like the Leo Machida or something
like that.
You just need a lot of years of the
books.
You have to get them because he's going
to light you up.
It's going to hit you with he's going to
pot shot you and he's going to crack you
and you're not going to stop him and
he's going to hit you three or four
times like that and he's gonna knock you
out too.
Sneaky game.
The striking game striking game is a
different game.
Some guys can just adapt real quick.
Like there's some Dan Henderson type
dudes that like almost right away within
a couple of years as dangerous as fuck,
but some who's just never quite get the
hang of it.
Awesome.
Got picked up instantly and you see it.
You see what gets you guys are real.
Jujitsu guy is striking is very slow.
Sometimes it's a new saying,
wow,
is he in the octagon?
But maybe they know something.
I don't remember.
You went so side note something I
thought.
Yeah,
well I think we're dealing with a new
era of mixed martial arts.
I don't think people are ever going to
try.
There's that,
that um,
although jump flying knee,
watch this,
boom.
That's like the first exchange of the
fight.
He double flying knee them in the face.
It was insane.
Cut them,
cut them real bad over his eyebrow.
Look at that.
Yeah,
I mean,
but that's one of those things where
they're send me anybody who gets hit by
that,
that's a reality.
And we,
you know,
a lot of great guys don't get hit like
that,
but if they did,
that's what would happen.
You know,
it's,
you can't avoid that.
That was a big lesson.
It's important lesson,
Saturday night,
important lesson for martial artist
because people like to think that
because the guy is really good that he
can somehow or another magically take
punishment better.
Not really.
So it's a fucking lesson for everybody.
Yeah.
That's a lesson for everything in life.
Karma is a motherfucker.
You see it in April,
you see it in basketball.
Sometimes you'll see a team that's got a
reputation,
the fast break,
and all of a sudden this team that
nobody's talking about,
the fast break through,
they go into finals and the coaches say
fast break breaking and the team that's
been France breaking motherfuckers,
they know how to execute,
but they forget how to defend the fast
break.
They fucking lose.
It happens all the time and the
different types of sports in different
situations.
Man,
the rematch is going to be absolutely
fascinating to see what's going to
happen.
Then to rematch with Weidman.
Anderson Silva will be the greatest
worry match in the history of the UFC.
No doubt about it,
and everybody's going to want to know
why men can do it again and everyone's
going to want to know how Anderson going
to recover.
That's going to be fascinating as,
fuck,
man,
whew.
That's going to be crazy.
I can't write out a guy like Anderson
Silva.
I'm right there with you watching.
Can't 17 fights and the three or two
before that on Youtube,
whatever.
You can't write this guy off.
You cannot write him off.
But then,
however,
however we seen it with a lot of other
fighters,
age takes whatever the money,
the children,
you know,
it's,
it's a new wage.
I can't wait to see today I saw a
picture of this gift to Sin Against Jon
Jones,
the fucking,
uh,
the whatever.
Look at that fight.
Those are two monsters.
Monsters.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
and one of the things about a guy like
Anderson,
we're comparing them to a guy like
Bernard Hopkins,
just 10 years older than him.
Watch out Bernard fights.
Bernard Hopkins is a brilliant defensive
fighter.
Brilliant.
You very rarely see Bernard Hopkins Kit
clipped,
you know,
and when he gets clipped,
his boxing is good enough that he knows
how to go into a shell.
He knows how to move.
He knows how to give you angles and he
gets away with Shit.
He's got a good channel and he gets away
with Shit.
And one of the reasons why it's got a
good chin as he hasn't taken a beating
ever.
He's never taken a beating his entire
career.
You know Bernard Hopkins,
like he kept a skills pass any of the
fighters of his prime.
I think about his fight with Roy Jones,
Jr Acumen.
Roy Jones Jr.
They duked it out once and roy beat him,
but when they do to the second time,
bernard hopkins basically just like box
box box them up because bernard's skills
hadn't deteriorated like roy's reflexes.
Like roy's skills were so reflex based.
He was so speed and reflex based,
in my opinion.
He was The scariest boxer that you would
ever have to compete against.
I mean,
Mike Tyson was ferocious and terrifying,
so I shouldn't say he was man.
It was close cbc,
obviously.
I was actually a line in an a nas song.
This is welcome to the new world.
The new mike tyson's Roy Jones.
That was [inaudible].
Roy jones was just knocking everyone
silly.
He didn't do it the same way that tyson
did.
He did it with just like speed and
ridiculous combinations and insane
accuracy.
He could just move in a way that other
dudes couldn't move.
Like if you go back and watch his
highlight Reels,
god damn,
he was amazing.
But he fought like this weird style with
your hands down and he didn't throw a
lot of jabs.
He threw like a leaping left hook,
but he was so fast with it.
He would just catch guys on a chin and
he would light them up with it.
He threw a lot of lead,
right hands.
He had like a different style and his
style was based on his ability to cover
ground and his accuracy.
And as soon as they started getting
older and starting getting hit and
slowed down,
that style was like and now actually a
detriment.
And so he stopped being offensive.
Like one of the most disheartening
things about watching Roy Jones jr fight
now.
It's not that he's still fighting,
is that he's not hurting anybody.
Like can you watch him fight?
He's,
he's.
He has to be much more defensive.
He's been knocked out a few times now.
So now it's like his boxing is almost
like he's boxing,
she's trying to win,
but he's also trying to knock it knocked
out.
How old is he though?
I believe he's 40 of does.
He owes money.
Yeah.
He wants to get an mma,
that's what the word is.
there was an article about some tax
issues and some,
you know,
I would imagine that he thinks that
there's some good money for them and mma
and even at his age,
all the fights that he's Been in and the
toll that that takes on your body,
his boxing skills are so far and above
tHe average mma fighter that it would be
kind of interesting.
Especially if you give a guy like Roy
Jones jr,
little tiny gloves.
Think how fast he has his regular
gloves.
You know,
I mean imagine give manny pacquiao,
little mma gloves and imagine how quick
he's punching you in the face and could
you even see it coming?
I mean,
how do you stop that?
It was like four ounces on them as
opposed to the,
what is it,
six or eight he's wearing regular basis.
That's a big difference man.
Those little tiny knuckle gloves as a
big difference.
If a guy like manny pacquiao got an mma,
teach them how to teach them some
butterfly guard,
how sprawl,
how to get back to your feet.
It's work with them on that for a couple
of years and set them loose.
Is many though.
It's a good question.
He's in his thirties,
right?
Go do six.
Manny pacquiao.
How old is manolo packy owl?
Yeah.
Don't be a dick.
Right?
Would you like me to search the web for
searching the web for?
How old is he?
Fuck,
fuck.
He was born December 17th.
He's 34,
man.
No,
he's not.
Not in the world of boxing.
The world of boxing is a different
world.
There's only a few.
Bernard hopkins is a matter of fact.
He's the only one that I can even think
of.
There's no one else that's managed to
keep their career going that deep into
their forties.
No one in the world of boxing dirty for
saying is he hasn't taken a lot of.
Yes,
he has.
He's been in some wars and that last
knockout,
that one walmart has knocked out.
That's a career changer.
It's a career change because he ran into
a telephone pole right hand.
I mean literally ran into it,
so it was him moving forward really fast
and mark has catching them on the button
and they had two wars before that where
they dropped each other.
So those guys have had,
he's gone through those fights and then
the fight,
he lost his bradley.
There wasn't a war,
but it was a tough fight,
you know.
But if you go like back to like some of
his,
uh,
his fights before then,
you know,
he,
he'd been in some crazy fights.
I mean,
even though he still winning and looking
spectacular,
you know,
there,
there's some wild exchanges ready for.
Yeah.
And you know,
who knows,
I mean there was also like rampant
speculation of performance enhancing
substances.
I don't know if that's true or not,
you know.
And then there's always the question,
are they,
when,
when fighters do those things,
it's like,
um,
I think going to continue to do them,
how are they going to like regulate it?
How,
how do they.
Like when you hit really high peaks,
like performance enhancing drug peaks,
the real issue is if they are doing
something illegal,
how are they going to maintain that
level and will they maintain that level?
It's an artificial level so it's like
you're going to go ups and downs,
you've got to take time off in between
doing it and you gotta make sure you
catch it right and sometimes they don't
and when they don't,
you know,
you'll see like real ins consistencies
and their performance.
You see them when they looked absolutely
sensational and then you see them when
they're in this like little spot in
between cycles.
Who's not doing drugs?
Can you please tell me it's a good
question.
Who's not doing drugs?
It's a good question.
I think a lot of fighters aren't doing
drugs.
I know bj penn,
I don't say I know,
but I'm pretty sure.
I mean I don't think he would lie about
that.
That's part of his whole honor with the
whole fight game.
And john fitch I think is another one.
I don't think john fitch has ever done
anything.
I personally talked to them about it and
he said he would never be able to live
with himself if you know.
He knew that he got there because he was
doing something.
He was using something that dude got
really far with,
just like fucking grittiness and
toughness and will,
you know,
without any enhancement to his body
artificial.
But there's a lot of folks out there
that do do it.
I don't know how many you wouldn't know
unless you're there with them is all
speculation because some guys just have
sensational genetics.
Some guys are just,
they're just unbelievably robust and the
heel quik and they look great and you
would swear that they're on something.
But then on john shit,
you know,
which is part of the weird arguments
because like not everybody is born.
Like everybody says it's an even playing
field,
but it's not,
you know,
if you're fighting,
you're fighting jon jones,
five foot two.
There's no evil even playing field.
Oh,
you both weighed two.
five.
Yeah,
she'll be fine.
There's not an even playing field.
You're crazy.
He has a super body.
You can't even have a chance.
It's not even,
and there's nothing you can do by the
way,
you can take all the steroids in the
world.
You're never going to beat John Jones.
He said the mechanical advantage of his
frame and his athleticism,
the average guy.
It's never gonna be able to fuck with
that.
Every actor over 50 right now in
hollywood shooting fucking shit.
Musicians on the,
toward doing the 60 and 70.
Well,
most of the guys I think used the cream.
They use,
uh,
the,
you see those,
those cream ads,
testosterone cream a little bit.
This is going to be huge.
There's a spray or an oral spray because
it good.
Yes.
That's going to be the next one.
Apparently the absorption rate is even
better than I'm rubbing it on your skin.
The transdermal method,
it's better when you put it in your
mouth.
He spray like you give yourself a shot
in the morning with cliq.
You know,
you're a mouthwash,
do your mouthwash and then give yourself
a shot of testosterone and you're off on
your way to a cream.
You have to rub all over your whole
entire body or you rub it on your upper
arms and shoulders.
What if you just more your not with it.
You could masturbate with it,
I guess to help anything maybe,
but what if you cleaned up and you
accidentally cleaned up your test cream
because you thought it was just you
would waste some of your tests.
Cream.
I've been last year at dirty bastard.
He's just not all of yourself and then
pull your underwear over it and let it
all cook liberal.
All stu inside your your ball sack area.
I've been masturbating with monistat
once a week now because it keeps your pe
or levels down your levels of what aid.
What is monistat first of all is that
some women use for yeast infections?
Yeah,
absolutely.
What is wrong with you?
Because I found out that you can have
guys have yeast infections and that's
why if you have sex with a girl and she
has a yeast infection,
a lot of times you gave it to her
because you have don't have usually any
symptoms.
So one of the things to get rid of that
is put monistat on your dick and around
your balls and around that shit at least
once a month,
but he's like every 20 minutes.
Here's the weirdest joe rogan 94.
It was an open my comment that was
getting divorced and I moved to New York
and I would work in the city and that
was on the coke and I had this in child
support.
I just couldn't make it all work.
So part of my angle every morning I get
a suit Before I went to work in the
city,
I go to fort lee amp right there by the
George Washington bridge and they just
finished stocking the shelves and I had
a briefcase like a bookcase.
I was a businessman in the city and I'd
put monistat now in the cases and a
monistat and there was something else
they liked,
like a.
Not the little aspects but the big
aspirins.
I like walk over the George Washington
bridge,
take them to a bodega and that's all
they would buy from you is yeast
infection medication.
That's what they tell you when you
brought them.
Shit.
I keep bringing it.
That's the most of them.
One thing up in spanish harlem,
so I would walk over the bridge.
I got like 60,
70 yeaRs.
Any books
in those days?
I was an open mic.
I didn't give a fuck.
I was just going over there just enough
to have money to get a hot dog,
a bag of weed and do whatever.
That's how crazy they were.
The guys would say,
make sure it's the monistat.
Bring the monistat seven.
It says an amazing how much people
identify with their.
Because
there's a thing that women hate more
than not want more than anything is
left.
I mean that's a massive generalization
that has taught myself,
but there's one thing that a lot of
women really do not appreciate and
that's stinky pussy jokes.
You know,
you could talk about your stinky feet,
who can talk about a girl,
stinky feet and talk about a girl's
breath.
You can talk about our girls,
but you can't talk about a girl stinky
pussy to them.
You can lose a lot of people that don't
like when you talk about even onstage
really like,
yes,
yes.
I've seen someone do a stinky pussy joke
and then I've seen women in the audience
going,
oh,
come on.
Just upset that you put that possibility
out there.
I've never smelled a bad fucking pussy.
Like when people did a lot of coke.
No,
no,
he knows that like I'm a fucking gets
that.
If I pick up a chicken barn,
she's great.
I'm thinking I'm going to take,
take a shower.
It's not going to help.
I just,
it it help us.
No,
no,
but I finger banged a girl in Idaho
falls and indian and american indian I
finger.
She had those daisy dukes on triple one
night is and I'm all warmed up.
I got like $32.
I got no blow budweiser.
Fucking furious.
I'm dancing on the edge.
She's letting me touch her joe rogan and
I stick my hand in like this way,
like full finger.
Oh my fucking twat.
And I had that fucking yoga look at the
size of his and I was bringing up this
way.
You know Bruce Lee,
you know I was that.
I stopped and I took it out to call
them.
I could.
I was dancing with it.
I could smell my hand and that was it.
I remember just fucking go do some sad
moments and you can't get it off.
Do you know that the smell of fish is
actually from old come usually.
So if it's a really strong a fish
smelled,
that means there's common inside of her.
That's funny because that's what my is
always smelled like.
If I jerk off and don't wipe up,
smells like fish.
Don't realize I'm bethesda.
I used to take up my own jazz.
I shoot sheet and my pubes and pull my
underwear.
I,
by the way,
I've done that dozens of times in my
life to just.
Once I shoot of,
I jerk off,
I just shoot a load on my pubes.
I don't even bother cleaning it up.
I just pull my underwear up.
I do that.
Especially when I'm in the house.
I'm like,
as long as it's covered,
what do I give a fuck?
If I'm in the hotel room by myself,
I'll get cares who cares.
Bandwidth on the bed and laid on it.
I don't give a fuck all day.
It's like,
oh,
this is my little tropical helmet juice,
but that was the only time I really ever
like.
I dated a chick that one before I
started dating.
The chick was a little proof just when I
was like 19,
20.
I didn't know what to expect to have a
pussy smell.
Oh my goodness.
She took care of it.
What happened?
No,
that you took care of it.
It was good.
I wouLd sniff it and everything.
Never sniffed nothing.
It was delicious.
I,
I knew a giRl when I was young and had a
problem.
Did you say something to him?
No,
I did
not.
I was too.
I couldn't.
I mean it was those back then when you
know,
when you're in your teenage years and
you fooling around,
you know what the hell you're doing.
The last thing I'd do is start bringing
things up.
Did you keep eating it though?
Oh no.
There was none of that.
No,
there's none of that going on.
She didn't want you to do that.
She knew something was wrong,
but it was just like,
it was one of those things where I bet
she was catholic girl.
I better parents and talk to her about
it.
I bet she had no idea and I bet she
thought that's just what they smelled
like,
you know,
and it was,
it was unfortunate.
You know,
she figured it out later though later in
life,
like while you up and told you no,
no,
I,
I hooked up with her later when I was in
like in my twenties,
like once and I was like,
oh,
it's all cleaned up now.
Imagine if it still is a mess.
Like longest running yeast infection
ever.
No one ever talked to her.
It was just like always this thing that
was never discussed.
Some have a pre judge.
If you judge a woman to go chick's
pussy,
stuff.
Like sometimes I look at a woman,
I got a guy with your pussy smell
fucking horrible,
you know,
harassed.
I can look at the chicken guy.
Yeah.
Pete harassed most.
Seeing a girl that took a sloppy drunk
with dirty feet.
You got to imagine that something going
on.
I always go by weight usually because
the bigger girls have a worst smell
because they could be like trying to
clean their pussy for like the last five
years and was like the crack.
Yeah,
but I gave this italian skinny chick
that had a little wine gum monkey when I
was a kid.
I mean it didn't stop me from eating.
She was skinny.
She had to be like 90 pounds,
but a pussy weighed 60.
She was one of those checks and she was
italian so it smelled like fucking.
It was tremendous.
Like melissa,
by the way,
because when you're in the citadel and
salami,
I'm the block from that fucking cuban
joint.
You turned me on tHat domingo's ain't
bad.
Huh?
Is it after then I got the meatball
sandwich.
I could call him red salad.
Where's that?
Is it like a deli?
But yeah,
right up the block from fucking ventura.
The mangoes.
I went there the other day.
Good restaurants on that street.
Not a good restaurant.
Oh.
Somebody was telling me that I haven't
been taught by my house,
like studio sets were invented.
Sushi.
Is that true?
No.
people like bro.
That's where they.
Sushi in Japan?
No,
no.
Right.
Tying all your life.
When did you eat your body of breadth?
A year ago.
You know what I'm saying?
You never eat your bread shit that they
invent now that even the fucking people
going,
the mexicans taco bell and vents more
shit to lupus.
Lupus mexicans.
Like what the fuck are they talking
about?
So you never know anymore.
I don't know.
Van nuys?
Yeah.
What's what?
Taco bell doing?
Commercials where they have chefs
pretending that the flavor has to be
just right.
Like they have a shit.
Don't put anything online.
Don't get us to famous images.
But you know that commercial.
I thought you were
the little lady with a mexican woman who
smelling vegetables.
Really?
I'm going to make sure that you smelled
fucking vegetables.
Fucking radiation shit.
Yeah.
Who does that also as a dominoes?
Like have you had dominant with frozen
pizza crust with shitty sauce?
Is domino's frozen?
Frozen?
I don't think anybody does that,
but yeah,
the garden,
all of our gardens.
Food is frozen.
Is it?
I think so.
I think.
Come on.
I think that what what the story is is
that they get like,
like things like almost like a frozen
food where they just kind of follow it
out on noodles like that.
The whole thing is frozen.
Get the fuck out of here.
Do you can't say that unless you know
for sure we can get tragically xapi or
allegedly you gotta stop doing that.
Dude.
You're gonna.
Get people sued.
Google it.
You can't just say,
the all garden does that.
You're tHe one who's always talking
about the fucking off guard.
Like it's so awesome.
Now you're turning on them.
This is a classic case of a relationship
gone bad.
People get used to each other and then
they turn on them.
At one time you were my love and now I
hate you.
The truth behind their school.
Well you read up on that and get back
later.
Read it up.
Can't be defaming a fine american
institution.
Jesus christ.
I said a legend.
How dare you?
No,
but I know you're in that area.
The whole area is bomb tie.
I loved that place that cuban joined
them.
We go to the fucking says that chicken
with garlic,
the garlic chicken with amazing things
that you like.
Onions,
cuban style.
That chicken is so god damn good.
It's the best chicken in the world.
I love that chicken.
That domingo's is next to a buck law
factory.
Okay.
I know exactly what it is and they
fucking make.
I mean,
I've been hearing it from steve,
so mom,
the aiga stino they bring,
you know,
brought me a half a meatball sandwich
and I was like,
yeah,
there's an episode of anthony bourdain's
show where he goes to this spot in New
York city that's been around since the
18 hundreds with the same family and
they bring him over spaghetti with gravy
and meatballs and so they call it great.
Yeah.
They call it gravy back then.
It's like old style east coast italian
and you look at the spaghetti's yellow
and the sauces ready let ball and you're
like,
oh my god,
it's red led.
That's what kills you,
but you've got to eat that at five and
go for a walk.
Read,
lead,
track realizes.
You know,
what do they put down?
What do real good?
He's put in that sauce.
Let's get down to it.
Nothing else?
No.
Now italians now for the last 10 years
now,
real italians because of their heart.
They Turkey,
Turkey.
That motherfucker faced the same goal.
You're already written off dog.
It tastes the same.
That shIt started 10 years ago.
Yeah.
When you think about what red led is,
they put the beef the fucking sunday
sauce.
Yeah.
There's nothing healthy in there.
They always had a sunday sauce and the
sunday sauce would be just all kinds of
shit.
Sausage meat.
Why didn't you go to sleep after you eat
it?
How many grams do you.
Your body assimilates what?
Thirty grams.
Dirty.
You need 1:50
a day to build muscle.
That shit is 99.
Your body crashes like your body
crashes.
The fat from the poor and the fork and
the fucking brand flavor.
The flavor to flavor the good.
Oh my god.
You've got to have the pork.
The flavor don't put too much,
too Much onion,
onion,
so that fucking scene makes me hungry
every Time.
Paulie's slicing the uh,
the,
the garlic with the razor blade.
A medicare in jail.
Funny guy.
Where they got where they got for.
so you got some bread,
throw it on there.
I got some wine.
That's a rule.
If that was really.
I wonder if that was really how they
live in jail.
It really,
really did.
You could get a.
I'm trying to do a special,
so I'm trying to figure out what they're
doing doing this between houston and
denver,
but if I do it in denver,
I'm going to go close to where I did
time.
I camp George West.
It's a little camp right by golden
Colorado.
The house of course.
Dude,
I think I want to do my next special in
denver.
I think it's,
that's the place that I think I'm going
to do my next special at a comedy club.
Really?
Yeah.
I think I'm going to do my next one at
the comedy works and then ran a bad
idea.
Yeah.
I haven't talked to wendy about it.
Take it back.
Oh,
it's one of my favorIte places to eat.
I like those small things too.
That's the problem.
I want to calm me cup,
but I heard that some comedy because
you've got to give him 20 grand when
you're saying you know when you're
saying you would do it near where you
got arrested.
Like where was that?
I got arrested in boulder so I could do
the fox theater boulders.
Great.
I can do a bunch of stuff to boulder
while school's in session.
Are you fucking kidding me?
We could go there anytime we want.
You tell me you want to book a show in
boulder.
I'll book a show with you tomorrow on
Man,
I love it.
I've been trying to kidnap my wife and
bring her back there for forever.
Boulder is the shit that's the greatest
town on earth.
I mean it's right up there with Alaska
that anchorage Alaska,
but Alaska gets too cold.
Boulder gets tower.
How good was deficient then?
It's incredible.
Did you get with digital you?
No.
Yeah.
I think we had some what would have had
some crab legs out.
Good with it.
Oh,
you get into fresh,
getting fresh alaskan king crab legs,
gelson's with.
Oh shIt.
Eighty $2.
And then it gets here two days later.
What's really bad ass about Alaska is
the people though.
The people are just top notch man.
They were so fucking cool that couldn't
have been cooler.
It was just like one of those plaCes
you're like,
oh,
I get it when you're just there for a
day,
you need to just like,
oh man,
people are there.
They are different up here.
There are different BeCause they got to
deal with an extreme climate and they
all bond together.
You know,
like they were talking.
one of the dudes that was working there
was talking about jewel because jewel is
from Alaska and apparently something
happened once where she had to cancel a
show and uh,
then when she came back after she had
canceled,
it was like really low attendance
because people were disappointed or they
don't forgive you for stuff like that.
Like they think like you,
you like you,
you're a part of a community and if you
cancel something,
especially if you don't have like the
best excuse ever,
they get upset at you.
I don't know.
They said she's normal.
That such as like a normal person.
She's out there just,
you know,
everybody knows where houses no one.
Nobody fucks with her.
Just normal.
Have you watched the liberace movie on
hbo?
I heard you were doing a bit about it on
stage.
I didn't hear it.
I love that.
I love really.
It's so some people.
It's to.
For me,
it's to see what I've seen growing up.
Creepy old fags trying to pick up young
fucking guys and doing it.
and how he did it.
Show how he did it,
how he did it.
He had a lawyer.
He had his manager that would just write
the checks.
You got to give them the jewelry back.
It was brilliant.
That's funny.
I'll tell you what he did.
He,
matt damon's character.
He made them get plastic surgery to look
like him.
WaTch the fucking.
That's hilarious.
watch the fucking movie.
You're gonna die.
You're gonna die when he gets matt damon
in side control with his dick in his
mouth.
Oh my.
Who's up swallows that fucking sword.
Listen to me.
Watch the moon.
Wasn't really that good because watched
the movie though.
That sounds like brokeback nights.
It's not like brokeback mountain,
but it's interesting to see,
you know.
Listen man,
we've heard some fucked up shit living
in hollywood.
We've got a lot of stories.
Yes.
But you never heard of a motherfucker
making another motherfucker do plastic
surgery to look like look like him and
then threw his ass out and gave him 75
grand.
Wow.
So I found ouT the olive garden thing,
I guess it used to be fresher back in
the day.
They used to make noodles out in the
open so everyone could see it and stuff.
But to cut cost they've kind of cut
things.
But.
But it's,
it's a lot of people were saying like,
I always say the sauces are always
frozen.
Supposedly half the shit's frozen.
Half of it's not just like every other
restaurant.
You don't get chicken rice.
Well listen,
if you want low prices,
you've got to deal with that shit.
So this liberace Movie,
it's called behind the candelabra and
when did it come out?
It came out two months ago and I didn't
watch it.
I didn't know what it was and I got
stuck watching him one nighT and I'm
like,
what the fuck?
This is amazing.
He was a veterinarian.
Now this guy and how he got rid of the
veterinarian,
he got rid of the guy before him.
Like he just got rid of him and then he
had a bunch of guys and all.
He would just latch onto young guys and
touch their leg.
It was just really a.
You got to just see the fuck.
Well that's the thing with baltaR gay
dudes,
twinks.
These guys were real old school fags,
bro.
He had a wig.
you suck.
That meant he was sucking without his
wig on the wig off.
I met damon who's this?
And it goes,
oh,
it's the first time you saw me without a
wig.
And it's fucking Michael Douglas.
Oh my god.
You Just 20,
30 minutes.
I'm watching that tonight.
That's my favorite new movie and I
haven't even seen it.
That might be my favorite movie and I
haven't even seen know when I first got
here,
nine slash eight.
The big thing was that book.
You'll never work in this town again.
Remember that hooker wrote a book and
she had don henley and the book and
charlie sheen,
don henley would get five hookers.
Tell him to bend over.
They weren't even allowed to pop the
head open.
They will all in downward dog for hours.
Nobody in that group of hookers had
carpal tunnel syndrome.
Do you understand me?
He would make five hookers.
Come over,
put them in that way and I'm not trying
to be cute.
He'd do coke and walk around with a rope
and put his dick in them twice.
Take it up,
walk over to the hookup,
pump it twice and look at them and go
put on hotel California.
Sit down,
do two more lines of code for viagara
tip.
This is before viagra and this is,
but now it was,
but he asked him.
He asked him liberace.
He's like,
how do you do it?
How do you.
How do you fucking do it?
How do you,
uh,
how did you fuck me four times today.
And so there's shit in there too.
You can see liberace does the poppers
and matt damon wants to sniff the
poppers.
So.
Wow,
this sounds like the best one we ever.
Now,
how does poppers make you get your dick?
Hard as hell,
bro.
I don't know.
The poppers was like a relaxed mother,
papa type of guy.
But in the gay community,
I guess when you're fucking another guy
in the muffler,
you hit them with a papa and it keeps
his dick hard.
I don't know.
I don't quote me on top.
I was never into pop.
What do they call it?
What's a little fucking thing?
Nitrates.
But one of the.
What's the brand locker room?
Whether it's the brand,
the brand.
The popper.
Yeah.
No,
I've never taken it.
I didn't know what a proper guy.
One of his.
But he's got him in his fucking house.
That's his middle name of columbus.
Fuck.
This motherfucker was making sixth
graders sniff that shit.
Its proper speed.
No,
it's this joint.
It's this drink.
And what happened was,
what time of the miami improv had a,
had a condo across the street from it,
the old miami and probably belong to one
of the owners.
It was where he put his mistresses issue
this bit.
But I think he bought the club,
the club and I had the bed in the wall.
I must've fucked 80 women that I used to
tie him up there.
I would tie them up and put coke rocks
in their pussy and shit and they will
all wake up tied up like jesus and you
get that bed,
you can still see like eight rope.
I always had to get new rope to tie him
up.
But one time I wasn't there and they
called me like,
where are you?
I'm like,
I'm in la.
What's going on?
They're like,
well you have to condo two weeks ago.
And I'm like,
no.
And they're like,
because weber was there,
left a mess and they left a thousand
poppers.
The type of mother I snort,
coke dog.
Don't confuse me with doing fucking
poppers.
And it was a little thing like this and
you opened it and had locker in it.
It's,
it was a locker room or something.
That's what it was called,
which sniff it.
And they get you high,
like 60 seconds.
Get the fuck that shit supposed to give
you an instant brain average to give you
age.
I think.
No,
that was
what duesberg was claiming that that was
a part of,
uh,
you know,
I shouldn't even that,
that was the most controversial podcast
we ever do.
The age podcast that we had.
This guy peter duesberg and duesberg is
a,
he's a professor at the university of
California berkeley.
He's a biologist and he was the one that
said that hiv doesn't cause aids.
So we had this guy on and tried to have
them explain to us.
Of course we're idiots.
So we didn't,
we don't know if what he's saying is
right or wrong.
He might be completely full of shit.
He might be making shit up.
We,
we,
you know,
brian and I have no idea.
And so I said,
well,
let me get matt stags to see if he can
get someone to debate them.
Nobody would debate the dude.
Everybody was telling me I was an
asshole for having them on because,
okay,
I don't know,
but are you sure that he's not right?
He's got damn biologist at the
university of California,
berkeley published biologist who has
read all this like peer reviewed
research on cancer that everybody
respects.
And he's saying crazy shit like hiv
doesn't cause aids.
The problem is I'm an idiot.
Okay.
So when I go online and I try to read
the arguments,
like whether or not it does or doesn't,
it seems to me that if more people are
saying it does,
then I would go with them because
they're scientists,
right?
There's a few of these row guys like him
that say it's just they're taking aim on
nitrate and they taking crystal meth and
they're just crushing their immune
system and that's why these guys were
all getting sick and that it's not hiv
killing them.
It's partying,
it's killed.
But then people say,
oh,
you're a homophobe for saying this.
And it's a terrible thing he's doing and
it's an justin's and blood is on his
hands and people are still dying of aids
and hiv because they don't take care of
themselves.
Exactly.
Copper bottle looks like this is so
ironic.
If anybody hears this and you know,
I'm sorry.
Well that's legal.
I rent the horse.
Yeah,
you can just buy them in the stores for
what?
What's the use for?
What are you supposed to use it for?
Oh my god.
Wholesale gay poppers.
That's legal.
Hold on son.
And go back.
Listen,
I'm dropping knowledge on homes today.
Don't promote these because these are
probably killing people.
But uh,
if anybody knows anybody that's a
biologist who wants a date,
a date,
peter duesberg,
show them some aids.
No debate.
My apologies.
Mr duisburg sir.
It was just a joke.
I'm a comedian.
If there was any other show,
I probably,
you probably really be mad at me right
now.
But those jokes happen often.
Um,
I wanted someone to debate them,
but nobody wanted to have any pieces to
intelligent or because.
No,
I think it's like a holocaust denier.
Like if you debate a holocaust denier,
you actually giving them some form of
credit.
You're like,
by even debating them,
especially if they're like a legit
historian sits down with a holocaust
denier,
like it's such a preposterous idea that
even to be connected with it is somehow
another pro promoting it.
And so it's so distasteful that nobody
wants to talk to a holocaust denier.
It's uh,
you know,
it's,
you don't even give them the time of day
holocaust denier.
Yes.
A deny or someone who says the holocaust
didn't happen.
There's a lot of people like that out
there.
By the way.
There's
a lot of crazy fucks that think that the
concentration camps,
and then I'm going to get some tweets.
Now what would you need to know?
Is it the exaggerated numbers?
And what I need to know is why are you
concentrating on that?
Why are you even trying to doubt that
aspect of history?
I mean,
have you ever watched those videos where
you see those poor fucking people being
led to the concentration camps is no
doubt horrific shit went on.
You know,
you trying to reduce the numbers.
It's actually 4 million,
not shit.
It's horrible time in history,
disgusting.
And you know,
what's really fucked up about the
holocaust.
It was so recent.
You know,
when I was a little kid,
I remember I was,
I was born in 1967 and when I was a
little kid,
uh,
I remember that we were like talking
about world war ii and uh,
we were talking about world war ii and
the holocaust and it seems so long ago
because it was,
you know,
at the time,
maybe like 30 years ago,
I was like 1977 or something like that
when I was 10 and it seems like a
million years ago,
but now when I think back of 30 years
ago,
like 1977 is like basically 30 years
ago.
That shit is so recent.
It's so goddamn recent.
Like I can remember 19,
77.
I don't remember a lot of things.
I remember my mother had a gold
barracuda,
you know,
um,
I remember,
uh,
we,
lived in san francisco.
I remember I remember some shit from,
from 1977.
So that freaks me out that that recently
people could have done that,
that,
that recently people could have just
decided that all jews are evil and we're
going to kill them all.
You know?
How many people did stalin kill?
You know,
how many people?
How many people did hitler kill?
Just 47.
Crazy.
You ever seen hitler's artwork?
No.
It's amazing.
He was really talented artists.
Like he could have totally just been a
famous artist.
First of all,
how dare you?
You're never supposed to give credit a
credit at all to hitler.
Like someone in the ufc q and a said,
if you could fight anyone in history,
who would it be?
I said hitler.
So fuck hitler up.
I'd kick the shit out of hitler.
That's a.
I'll bet the house that I'm going to
win.
Come on,
man.
They don't even have vitamins back then.
We'll fuck that dude.
I was stupid.
Mustache.
I can look at that.
It's pretty sweet though.
I mean he was a pretty good artist.
That is kind of amazing.
So there was a good artist.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
what else was kevorkian?
We've shown those on a podcast for
member kevorkian was creaky artists guy
yet I do not know.
I think he did for years.
You had to buy them every other week.
Now they put them in jail when he was an
old man,
you know,
the whole thing is kind of crazy.
She be able to,
you know,
should be able to die when you went to
don man.
Especially if you're in fucking serious
pain.
Like why?
Why shouldn't you be able to die?
There's a new,
uh,
hitler's chicken.
Have you heard of hitler's chick?
Yeah,
it's in Thailand.
That just opened up and they're kfc is
gonna assume because it was an old kfc
and they actually,
oh my god,
hitler fried chicken in Thailand.
Oh my god.
It's kfc and they just put hitler space
on it.
So crazy.
Why can't you do that though?
It has enough time passed.
I bet you could sell gingiss conference.
I bet if you had gangs.
Cons,
fries.
I think it's because we were.
Yeah,
but I think it's because ovens are
involved,
you know,
in,
the ovens.
I didn't think of that.
How do you know they're not frying them?
Oh,
that's true.
Yeah.
They usually deep frying techniques.
Who it.
Who gives a fuck?
It's chicken.
It's not a fucking hoe human.
It's just.
That's not long enough ago,
but you could have gangs.
Conference fries.
You could have a huge.
How about caesar little caesar?
How about that?
Seizure was an evil cut there.
We're all evil.
Cons that are responsible for the death
of millions now.
They're a cute little cartoon and it's
holding up a pizza a little season.
Do you ever think of that?
Think a little caesar.
Caesar was a and there's never been a
caesar.
Julius caesar had never been a caesar,
didn't have blood on his hands.
Romans were crazy.
They were fucking savages by the time
the fall of the roman empire was going
on.
How many of those caesar's didn't have
like a few deaths on their hands?
Quite a few.
What's up with that?
Is that the hitler?
Hitler chicken.
It's fucking crazy.
Yeah.
Well,
hitler didn't walk like that to nazi
chicken right now.
What does it say?
Go back to that fucking bottle yet.
What does it say it does to the gay
poppers?
I'm still fascinated and never left.
He's been pretending to care about
hitler.
Fuck.
Fuck that fucking guy.
Like I'm done with coke.
But poppers and not out of the question.
I talked to my doctor for my heart.
That's why they sound on the black
market gate.
Turns out joe rogan gay dudes have a 10
percent healthier heart because of
poppers.
So tell boasberg you could shove it up
your ass.
Yeah,
the effects are in brief,
but intense side effects are a sudden
surge of blood to the heart and the
brain.
So like if you,
if you want it to sound good,
wanted to answer it really important.
Ashley quick,
will you marry me on the ass?
Or like,
let's say if you're in a game show,
all right?
You get the worst advice ever.
Imagine some poor fools in front of jude
carries.
Try to guess the price is right.
And you're like brian,
red beds attached to a pump right now.
It's isn't it?
Uh,
it,
uh,
it's time slowing down.
It feels like it's time slowing down.
So like,
uh,
it also is a heat flush,
sometimes light headiness,
giddiness.
Someone's doing two to five,
five minutes and a,
someone's
got to do,
by the way,
speaking of drugs,
you see the fucking michael jackson's
shit was going on with this trial.
No,
they ain't give him this motherfucking
money though.
The worst thing they could have done
with this trial was really opened up the
world to what this guy really was.
Did you see yesterday's article?
No,
I haven't been following it at all
because of the tracks on his ass.
Oh no.
Like the skin was too damaged from just
shooting himself in the ass.
So don't like,
oh god,
this guy was fucking out there and
somebody,
a doctor that I go to,
the seek said to me,
he goes,
these people don't know what can of
worms to open up by doing this.
This guy had skeletons in the closet
that go back 30 fucking years since off
the wall.
Well,
any guy who's like doing that much to
his face,
like other craziness that he was doing,
like that famous picture of him where he
had his nose,
like have like a.
There was like a skin graft over his
nose.
I think it was in court.
Right?
You remember that picture,
brian?
Yeah.
Pull that picture up.
See if you could find that picture.
There's a picture of michael jackson's
nose.
That's the old Michael Jackson that we
used him drinking whiskey vodka with two
midgets.
Oh my god.
Is that real?
Yeah,
I think so.
You don't even know if that's real.
That's a goddamn sketch from the mantro
drunk hipster Michael Jackson.
No,
the guy do it.
That was a halloween costume.
This is the real Michael Jackson to
doves and a pair of underwear.
But go,
go see if you can find the photo of his
nose because it's one of the weirdest
things ever.
And I remember seeing that saying,
this is a strange exercise and culture
that we're seeing in Michael Jackson.
Oh god.
It just pulled it up in a freak because
for every human being,
um,
you know,
these are,
these are strange times.
That's a skin graft over his nose or
something.
Maybe it's tape looks.
It looks like the poster from silence of
the lambs.
Is that a tape over his nose?
It's hard to tell what that is.
Is it a bandage?
It looks just like skin.
It's hard to tell if that skin or some
kind of a whole face adhesive or
something like that.
But he,
I remember looking at that image and
sanken what is this guy done like with
the skeleton?
Then I remember thinking,
what must the pressure be like when
you're that guy?
What must reality be like if you start
off as a child like super famous and
loved by millions,
you know,
you remember abc is one,
two,
three.
I mean he was huge way,
way,
way back before anybody knew how to
handle it.
And he was huge as a baby pro and
watching justin bieber,
this justin bieber's to make Michael
Jackson looks like a fucking puppy.
Dog thinks so he's going to be black and
like seven years.
He seems fine right now.
It out.
It's trying to get some pussy.
Why you hating on them?
I'm just telling you what I see.
You can't do 90 miles an hour in a.
In a.
In calabasas around white people.
I see it with chrome car.
Getting his dick sucked on the
[inaudible] too.
I see almost hayden.
Do you see him oR his car around?
Nice.
Seeing it on the one on one.
He apparently as a leopard print car now
on one of those audi are tens or
something like that or eights.
Our tens,
whatever is and it's got leopard print.
I forget buying some beliefs.
Car to laugh.
I healing.
You get a razzi.
Oh,
well someone died on the pacific coast
highway because they were trying to take
a picture of a pop rocks.
He was running across the street and get
clipped.
He died while I'm looking at that.
Is audi leopard print sexy?
That is so silly.
It's so silly.
It's so silly that he would do that.
I wouldn't ugly.
Look to that car.
That's the most bad ass car,
like a.
That's everlasting is one of those.
It's such a wicked looking car to cover
that thing with.
Looks like leopard print,
but that's like,
that's the silliest.
I can do whatever the fuck I want.
Move ever.
You know he had a karma fisker.
That was chrome.
Do you ever see that thing?
That's Just preposterous.
How dare you.
How dare you?
Young man running around at chrome car.
some nice.
It'll be on heroin.
Fucking you can fucking.
People don't want a bunch of shit with
that kid.
Maybe met them.
Do some yoga.
Yeah.
Metal arc is going.
Gonna seem very friendly.
Seemed pretty down to earth.
Can consider bitches.
Fuck is.
just think of how crazy you would be if
you were just to where they can away you
would have done if you'd be kim just to
beaver when you were 15 or whatever it
is.
Fifty dollars,
million dollars.
You go crazy.
The world is your oyster.
If somebody comes to you,
says,
put your money away.
You don't listen to that person.
You're going to go,
fuck you mad.
You go to standard and fucking just by
waitresses like dog,
how much for you,
you'd be like that prince or the king of
the game of thrones,
I'll tell you,
be like be evil,
you know,
the amount of power,
like that's not the amount of power that
a person should ever attain and it's
incredibly rare that a person ever does
attain that type of wealth.
like you got justin bieber type wealth
and the fact that he's getting and when
he's 7:00
AM I boring you philosophy you only in
the fact that he gets it when he's 17 or
whatever the hell he is.
How old was he when he got super famous?
Was like 17 sunlight younger.
What is he now like?
Nineteen,
something like that.
He's like a young man now
we have this game that we played at like
would,
could you beat up so and so,
so and so.
And we like say it to like,
you know,
and I said I can beat a bieber because
not really thinking.
I was like,
yeah,
he's a little kid.
I got old man,
fat strength.
I could just sit on them or something
like that,
but then I saw him with his shirt off
the other day on some website and it's
like,
holy shit.
That duke would probably desTroy me.
He's fucking ripped.
He's a little boy
now.
Fuck you up.
Plus the thing is like a blue belt or
something.
do you think he can beat you up a ds?
Absolutely.
THat's funny.
It's your blue button digital.
Somebody told me that he know.
You know who is to michael jackson's
son?
He just got his blue belt.
Really?
Gracie,
torrance.
I'm pretty sure.
So it's legit.
Blue belt.
Fucking ustream,
man.
You streamed.
Keeps lagging out.
I don't know why you keep sucking it
lately.
We've got to figure out what's going on
with this.
But people are complaining not
complaining the mornings to shit's going
on.
Too many commercial dismissed.
Well that's the problem we're having.
We're just having a problem with cutting
out like crazy.
But is it.
What's that?
The app is good.
It's working.
But is it um,
when we uploaded to vimeo,
did we get a clean?
It's fine.
Okay.
So watch the video.
Don't pay attention to us while you're
watching this right now anyway,
and the fact that it works on the ipad,
fine.
This goes to believe that it is more,
again,
a flash plugin problem.
That's interesting.
So maybe I should try it on another
browser.
All right,
let me try it on another browser.
I'm going to shut this bitch off and I'm
going to try it.
When you're in chrome right there,
I'm going to try it on safari.
Where you have this weekend.
Jodie is got a couple of things this
weekend.
A couple of spots.
Nothing to fucking serious.
Next week I go to philadelphia.
Yeah,
I go to fucking helium.
We were talking about like great clubs.
Yup.
Any better than that?
Doesn't get any better than the one in
buffalo.
I had to change that date and I'm doing
portland in september also,
so I'm pretty excited.
Oh,
you're doing helium in portland as well.
sweet baby.
Jesus.
Pretty excited for philly though.
Got to helium.
So the bomb dude,
they.
What am I 12 going to open?
Another one in st louis.
Greg put it on safari immediately.
It lags out immediately.
Yeah.
I don't know what's going on.
You stream.
How's paris?
Jackson?
Um,
he looked like he's like 17 or so.
I mean the girl.
Oh,
I think she's like a.
She's in her teens I think.
I'm sure the 18 year old.
I feel bad about her.
Don't feel bad about all of them,
man.
I mean,
what a strange way to live your life.
If you grow up that famous,
you know,
what are you doing with that joey?
The reading your phone back on the
email.
Sending it back and this is what I'm
saying.
What?
Nothing.
I'm looking at this.
Little says he left us and he started
emailing people like joey diaz is.
He ate a candy.
I don't know if anybody noticed tHis.
You heard some chewing while the show is
going on as a half an hour.
About an hour ago.
He ate a candy and it's clearly kicked
in.
It hasn't kicked in.
You are disassociated from this
conversation.
Motherfucker won't kick them for later
on,
you know,
with just so.
Well this weekend is filling.
Next week.
Next weekend is filled.
You're working with my man,
dom,
a up at the icehouse.
Yeah,
I saw that.
You guys are co headlining a weekend.
That's the
beautiful world.
That's a great idea.
Yeah,
that's.
That's what a great fucking show.
I hope I got a great show.
They do the podcasts for them.
It's always good to see don thomas
cleaning how to be a fucking comic
again.
You know,
you work with tom.
You're like that motherfucker does it
all.
He's a real monologist.
That's a different type of savage there.
Well,
you know,
all the time.
I've known don.
He's never faltered.
Like he's always loved being a comic and
that's,
you know,
someone was talking about it.
I think it was bill burr was saying he
really loves the fact that like dom has
been in it,
you know,
he was in it.
He was like a veteran when we all
started and yet he still has a lot of
love for it.
Some guys,
they fade off,
they get older and they just not funny
anymore.
Don hasn't lost a step.
He's hilarious.
He's fucking hilarious,
man.
I watched him to stand up like before he
did that,
you know,
he does the talk,
por portion of it.
His standup is still one of the fees on
tonight.
I was done that last spot down there
last night.
And then on the way up I had a followup
at the laugh factory.
How was that the laugh?
There was 30 people.
Wow.
But it was okay.
You know,
I did 30 people on monday night and then
fucking I want to put the ha and I seen
david for a little while in front of 12
people and what damon wins.
He's making a comeback.
It's only going through 12 people,
12 people.
He always liked doing that though.
He loved it.
He would show up at 1230 at night with
pain and somebody always a and he'll,
you know what I love about damon,
I used to love watching damon work shit
out because he'll like really work
something out a killer,
have an idea on stage.
It's just Like a couple of words or a
couple of,
not a couple of words,
but a couple of concepts,
you know,
and he'll take them.
And just run with him and because he's
gotta make all these people laugh.
Like the pressure of that will lead him
because he's a great writer.
Leads him to the best lines all the
time.
I used to watch him work shit out on
stage.
Like he would write right.
But he would also work shit out on
stage.
Whereas mooney did a lot of writing,
like moonee would come in there and
something would happen.
Like you remember the airplane crashed
Florida and crashed in the swamp and
mooney did a bit about old black ladies
still clutching their purse.
I remember that they pull them out of
the crocodile.
They still clutching their purse.
Like he had that like written like
within a couple of days of,
of the the plane crash and it was a
written bit,
you know,
he did it.
so he would like capitalizing.
You always have a lot of new shit but it
would be like a written bit.
Whereas you could see damon was like
working it out while he was up there.
He would have an idea and he would just
flush it out while I was up there.
And so when it would hit him,
like the punchline would hit him,
he would start crackinG up like not like
that fake cracking up shit that bad
comedians do.
It's gross,
right?
When you see people fake laughing,
you know,
big bitch.
You laugh the exact same way every night
when you tell that joke,
that's a fake laugh,
you know,
that fake laugh.
It's gross.
But damon would like every now and then
he really make himself laugh,
you know,
I've watched him do those late night
sets of the store bunch of times.
You know,
it's
funny.
The other morning I was watching tv,
I got up and bruce lee's changed.
The world was on.
Eddie griffin came on.
I got to tell you,
a big smile came on my face before I
walked in here.
Brian and I were talking about the
comedy store and he's telling me how the
crew that hangs out there and how it's
changed and blah,
blah blah and blah blah blah.
And you know,
he's enthusiastic about it.
What brian doesn't understand this.
I already went to fucking college there.
Do you know what I'm saying?
We did our fucking time.
It's not even about you or carlos' name.
I don't give a fuck for me.
I did my fucking time.
Then I did my eight years of spots and
sundays and following dice.
When you got,
when you,
you know what it's like to have two
other sets and you go to do your set and
fucking dice is going up.
As you pull up you're like,
oh,
this is going to be great and awesome.
They're like,
dice is going up.
Like when I was,
I was talking to you,
I could still see us sitting by the back
and mooney how he would walk up to the
checkup bucks.
I'm here.
Give them the light,
you know,
and just all those little things.
That was my college,
my college.
But you don't go back to high school.
You don't go back to,
you feel like a fucking moron.
And naturally it was the comedy store
for me was law school.
It was six fucking years of hard fucking
work of snorting,
blow fucking eating pills,
eating pussy,
women,
you know,
line.
Trying to get a manager trying to go up
there and fucking get a couple of drinks
on a rocker coke.
It was an adventure,
you know,
he was saying that robert and I remember
the night I was up last night with the
night,
we're going to light them on fire,
that I'm locked in the bathroom.
People throwing paper towels and they're
on fire,
you know,
I mean,
this is fucked up.
I mean it's just,
uh,
it's just.
I still remember corey cuomo calling me
and going,
did you threaten him?
And corey,
I'm in miami.
I've been here for three weeks.
That's how fucking crazy he is.
Okay.
That's how fucking crazy robert epa
buyers,
like I avoided them after that where he
accused me of doing something and I was
out of town.
The Bestest had him in it.
Don barris.
That's so crazy.
It's going on for decades.
Chinese guy.
What's the.
Don't,
don't,
don't you do this to rob it up?
No,
no he does that indicate nazis.
Nazis the finger.
This hitler mustache finger.
Don was on stage last night and he just
runs in room.
There was like maybe like 30,
40 people in the room and just goes on
stage and so on.
One map provides all the managers have
to like get robert out or they're using
lasers and paper towels and stuff,
but robert is still a good institution.
Indians and he's in an institution like
he's a part of the store.
Absolutely,
and he still goes up every night.
Every night.
I'm nice to him.
I never do anything.
I'm always playing nice guy,
but everyone,
all the other guys always fucking throw
menus.
I've always been cool.
I've always been really neat to see
that.
Oh yeah.
I never had a beef with him till he
accused me of threatening them when I
was out of town.
don't understand that I was sitting on
the stairs.
I was sitting on the stairs and like
throwing paper towels and enlightened
them on fire and he's in there like,
oh,
what's the smell?
Fire run out of there.
You
walk.
It was really dangerous with him because
you,
your member,
especially in the winter,
he would insulate himself with plastic
bags.
He had these plastic bags,
the stuff inside of his clothes keep
them warm because he would walk home and
he'd be in downtown,
so he didn't.
He'd walked downtown like when he would
leave the comedy store,
he would walk like five miles.
That was no joke.
Like he that he did that all the time.
He,
he still does that and he goes to the
grocery store after every show,
every night he does it,
gets the exact same thing,
like a banana and like a sandwich.
And don paris does tHe exact same thing.
He follows him into it.
That's so fucked up,
man.
What?
You know,
that's one of those things that the
store had was those long running gags.
Like,
do you remember what o'brian counts?
Still does it with don burris every
time.
Brian callahan,
tom paris,
he's each other.
He pretends that brian brian pretends
that dom buress is forcing them to suck
his cock and so fights it off for awhile
and they're like put on a show.
And then finally Brian Campbell put his
lips right on.
Barris,
his cock and,
and,
and barrels will be humping his face.
It's so fucking,
and they go for it.
It's so uncomfortable to watch.
This is a new who is robert from two
nights ago and there's a girl on stage
with no clothes on.
She never wears underwear.
She always brags about fucking ron.
Jeremy.
Could you tell us on stage or on the.
YeaH,
it's totally fine.
But she,
uh,
she,
she's been like going on stage and like
showing her vagina to him and stuff like
that and he shows them to robert.
It's getting real nervous
by the way.
How durable is that?
jacket and pants jacket and pants is 100
years old.
this motherfucker's been wearing that
same jacket pants every day for a long
time.
Those are some strong threads.
Yeah,
I think he might have a few of them
though.
So this girl,
she goes on stage all the time,
like all the girls.
This is from last night,
you know,
there's mary jane and eleanor and stuff
like that.
And eleanor was there.
Oh yeah,
she's there every night.
She really.
Yeah.
But it's cool because all these girls
are on like the ding dong show and stuff
like that.
But it's fun.
Tylenol is very funny,
man.
She's a very funny stand up now.
It's interesting.
We always kind of knew she was a funny
person when she was working at the
store.
Are these all standups?
These girls?
Yeah.
That's a schizophrenia surfer.
He's got schizophrenia,
schizophrenia and he,
I used to do open mics with him and in
west hall or in a cafe while you're
talking about the point when I'm asking
him about the girls,
girls in their underwear and it's like,
yeah,
that guy.
So there's mary jane,
her don's girlfriend.
So these girls are all standup
comedians.
So the like a community down there of
girls stand.
Oh yeah.
And what's cool is that me and tony
hinchcliffe,
sap podcasts have a,
uh,
two girls stand ups that started on the
show and they've never done standup
comedy before.
And every week we get tHem,
given them one minute and they're like,
that's awesome.
Yeah.
Stand
up comedy.
It needs more chicks.
It's not enough funny checks in this
world.
I don't know when things are going bad
like they are now.
That's when more funny ones will rise.
Is more funny,
crazy bitches or wherever you shop
somewhere.
Jerry lewis did well.
He says it went off a month ago.
What did he do?
Dirty bitches.
He doesn't think women are funny,
right?
I can't stand them talking to me.
I don't think that funny.
I laugh.
There's plenty of funny women.
THat's a silly thing to say.
This is funny.
People.
If someone's funny,
they're funny.
The idea that you would say that they're
not funny because they're check.
Tell me morgan murphy stuff.
Funny to pitches.
Hilarious.
She's lyrics.
Sarah silverman's not funny.
Sarah silverman is fucking hilarious.
This girl right here,
this is katie means out of the girls
who's mom was married to hugh hefner.
This girl right here though.
Her name is jessica shores and she has a
music video that she just put out like a
month ago that already.
It has like one point 2 million hits and
her dancing around with you.
If you look at it though,
you'll let her.
I when I left last.
Nope.
I don't know.
I won't laugh my ass off.
I can't believe we're still talking
about it.
You would in a a laugh about it way.
Yeah.
No,
thanks.
I've been there.
I've done that.
Stop trying to make me sad.
You never get a hankering to go back
there and we drive by.
Do you ever wish you could just pull it
into our set?
No.
No shit.
Still you're doing the improv.
I been there lately.
Just got a text from rita.
I gotta text her back.
The improv is a I.
That bar freaks me out.
Oh,
the persian barring the bar.
I'm like,
what?
What does this recessed lighting the
fucking lamps built into the wall and
shit.
I'm like,
what are you guys doing?
Glad you said that,
because I was like,
you need a corner that you can suck at
the end.
There's no.
There's no hidden corners here.
It doesn't feel like a comedy club.
It all with white booths.
Like where are we?
Are we in miami in 1998.
It feels like a hotel room or a hotel
bar.
Yeah,
it feels like a road gig.
it feels like a gig you would do if
you're in western Massachusetts where
they had like the bar.
The club still is great once you get
inside the actual setup is pretty
fucking perfect,
you know,
and the way they have it now with the
bar over there,
it does have less noise because people
have to leave and go down that hall and
then take a right and then take a left.
So it's probably like quieter for them
that way.
It just seems weird.
I guess that that annex though,
it wasn't making any money,
you know?
Also they got rid of the annex.
Annex doesn't exist anymore.
Well
they were the bars.
We're also renting out the,
the front part of it to a hamburger
place.
So kind of hamburgers going to be that
umami.
It's actually.
Oh,
nami burger.
I don't know if I've had those before.
The weirdest thing,
the weirdest.
The weirdest thing is,
is that the murals I,
if you've ever been to the hollywood
improv,
we used to have like these big drawings
or paintings on over him.
Yeah.
And they're just this new mural that all
the people.
Yeah,
and it's huge and it's just a bunch of
comics and you sit there and you're
trying to figure out who's who.
Everyone does not look like who they are
and it looks
really like a picture.
How I,
the only picture I have is there's only
one microphone on this mural like and
there's only one person standing in
front of the microphone and this is like
a simulation theory,
but that one thing is a fucking dolphin
for some reason,
for no reason at all.
A dolphin in front of the microphone and
then you could kind of see a couple of
comics here.
Like I can't tell.
I know who that is.
Just the puppets.
That's the only photo of it.
That's the only photo I have.
I can find,
see if I can find like only a partial of
the part of the euro dolphin.
It's weird that it would have on
sunglasses too.
I dunno man.
There's no.
There's no rhyme or reason.
there's no logic to why they would take
down those other paintings.
Those pins were old as fuck.
There was like a part of history I think
here.
I think here's the,
uh,
here's the,
here's a new story about it.
The new mural.
Oh god,
there's a story in the news.
You always comedy club in west hollywood
comics for conservation.
It's happening right now.
We'll see.
Look at that mural.
There's the dolphin fast,
incredible mural over the past couple of
days here.
Let's look at it.
You can't robin williams,
you'll,
you'll sit here and look at it and you
won't even,
you can't even figure out half a
terrible piece of artwork.
I don't want to say it's terrible.
So his style does not look like the
people at all.
Like,
like if you look at Jeff Ross,
it looks like Jeff Ross,
Jeff Ross,
special needs.
That is where they have the unknown
comic with a paper bag over said,
thank god.
So now the entrance,
it's over here.
Where the,
what the fuck I'm mural.
Is that?
Yeah.
And there's so many.
Like there was somebody there that,
I forget who it was that george carlin's
pretty obvious.
Well,
some of the people like really obvious.
It's pretty obvious,
but let's see if I can get it.
I don't want to make fun of it,
but it's just shut it off.
let's.
Let's be nice,
but it doesn't matter.
That's what the comments are saying.
It's kind of weird going over there now
because people are like,
what's up with this bar?
And it was just crazy mural.
Somebody fucked up.
Somebody's got crazy and they forgot
that things are nice when they stay the
same.
Yep.
They forgot the end of the day.
Who gives a fuck?
Fuck,
fuck,
fuck.
Fuck.
Jesus christ.
Joe diaz.
You know what I'm saying?
Who gives a fuck about some fucking ugly
ass?
That's what I'm saying.
That's what I'm saying,
dawg.
What else was like a motherfucker will
movies you see lately?
Anything good?
I saw despicables a movie and it was a
good move.
They just kid movies.
So good fucking movie.
Almost good cartoons now.
Fuck television.
Fuck all that family guy.
I'm watching spongebob.
that's the shit.
You're fucking lives in a pineapple.
It's true under the seat.
It's true.
Is it good because of the three d or you
just.
Did you
just like.
The first one was great.
The first one's not bad either.
They're going to the movies.
I love all that shit.
Then it's like it's.
I mean obviously I went for my kids but
it's legitimately good movie,
but that's where they put that fucking
screen.
That's why they put the creativity and
the kid shit in the adult.
Shit.
You sit there.
my friend said you went to see the end
of the world.
We lAst night and this guy is a white
dude,
is very geeky and he went to see the
Kevin Hart means at the end of the world
you had to walk out of really.
And Kevin Hart thing was okay,
that was just too big to do stand up at
the garden.
He felt like it was just too big.
The tape day he goes at the end and he
watched the credit and he goes,
it was 30 fucking camera man.
You know what I'm saying?
30th camera man.
So it just didn't feel intimate and make
them feel intimate enough,
which I,
when you're doing those fucking places,
you don't,
you feel,
you don't feel intimidated,
you know,
there's a certain level,
like $1,800
or something after that,
it's all downhill after that.
For a guy that rants,
it's downhill for a guy who's very
slowly.
When we seen the guy in jersey,
a slow pace,
that's great.
but a guy who steps on his own lines and
I just don't like it.
It was absolutely right.
That is the issue when people laugh and
you can't hear what they're saying.
I don't like 1800 or above.
You don't want.
It's nice money.
Yeah,
we have a good time,
but I don't feel good when I walk off
the set.
I don't feel like I did nothing.
I'm just struggling to talk slow.
My patois jb.
All my timing was off.
You know?
I liked it.
That's why I'm,
I don't know where I want to shoot a
special.
I'd like to shoot it at somewhere where
it's fucking small.
I don't want to do theaters.
I don't want people to come see me in a
fucking.
They ended up punching.
I honestly,
atlanta punch.
I was a great idea.
That's a great idea.
I honestly think 300 is the threshold
for things getting different to 72,
seven,
two,
9:50
gets a little kinky,
put even carbs.
It's tremendous.
It's big though.
It's too bad.
Carbs is tremendous.
And then when you have the Little thing
on top,
that's a little fucked up too.
On top of it.
In the back it goes way back and above
this we don't sell much of a connection
is a perfect place to take this perfect
place.
American comedy co because they're not
bad either,
but there's a lot of pillars and that
spot.
I don't want to shoot in California.
That's the problem.
We do shit here.
Do we want to go somewhere to light up a
state like grand funk railroad?
We're an american band.
Will come through your town.
We're running american fucking man.
Are you kidding me?
That's a jam dog.
Listen to that will help you.
Partied down.
We'll bring cheap cheekbones refa
papers.
Yeah.
No,
that's it.
So I want to go somewhere when you do a
set in la,
it's fun,
it's great.
but they could see us anytime.
I could.
If I was ruling ck,
you jump up and down.
If I was fucking,
you know,
Kevin Hart,
I do fucking whatever.
Stand up,
live downtown,
whatever.
That's.
But I'm not and I never got to.
I don't want to do that kind of standup.
I Rather put smaller.
That's why I do good when I got on a
rant and shit in a big theater.
I it what's also,
it's a matter of how much money do you
really need?
Because if you start getting into the
eight and 10,000
seats,
it's one thing if you're doing it
because the demand is really high.
You don't want anybody to not be able to
go because you know,
the shows would be all sold out,
but you can make a lot of money Just
doing clubs.
I mean,
how much money does a comic need to
exist in this life?
You know,
if you're,
if you're living like a normal person,
you can do clubs and you can make plenty
of money.
You know,
but the show will be more like you,
like I can go see you in a hundred
seats.
You can be screaming and yelling at the
top of your lungs and ran.
I'll know every word that comes out of
your mouth.
There'll be no questions.
What did he say?
I couldn't hear.
There'd be none of that,
but when you get into those two and 3000
seat places,
there are a moment and I noticed that
when we watched that guy in jersey,
there was a moment.
There was a few moments where I didn't
know what he had said because he was
like ranting as they were laughing and I
was like,
oh,
this is interesting.
Very interesting.
Dynamics were great for a 2,400
seat theater.
The dynamIcs of chicago.
Oh yeah.
tremendous.
I rented there and they came up
perfectly,
but that's a very few and far between
that that place is magical.
Magical.
I would also consider shooting a special
if it wasn't so big in the place we did
in pittsburgh.
That was a great place to theater.
That was the carnegie library,
lord god,
that was.
That was used to be an old library,
was no library.
There's so many places.
If I could find a good old fucking
joint,
600 seats in it,
you should just do it at helium,
man.
I want to do that.
Either helium,
portland,
do it important.
They'll go crazy.
I want to do a brick wall.
A brick wall,
a brick wall.
What does portland have giggled?
We can put this up.
Giggles,
giggles.
Helium giggles is a comedy club that I
used to do in boston.
Boston.
Yeah.
Giggles was also in seattle.
A place that was run by the Vietnam vet
that would take a draw from them on
thursday by saturday.
He forgot he was and then I call them
monday asking who was then next week and
he'd go over his last time you worked at
club.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
Years ago.
Friday he had.
He forgot that bad everything.
Once I learned I would get the waitress
on saturday and find that.
What was the feature act next week on
monday nine slash 11.
What's up buddy?
Joe diaz.
Who's featuring this week.
When was the last time you were at?
My club was a year ago.
You had to be fucking spotless clean.
Right?
But he wouldn't show up until to see the
headliner and there was a curtain on the
stage and you can see this jaguar pull
up.
Oh,
that's a jaguar pulled up.
I did my clean stuff as soon as you
want.
If you only come in for one minute and I
just bombed for two minutes,
look at the back and going,
this is hysterical.
This is how much,
how?
This is how a box this guy was.
I forget the guy's name.
He's a track coach and seattle,
very good guy was
on hbo.
She's just a college track coach.
He doesn't travel as much.
He was headlining and he's a great comic
and a great monologist.
He's completely clean.
This motherfucker gets off stage and the
owner of the club goes up and he goes,
let me tell you something.
I went in there three minutes ago when
you were being dirty.
Don't ever do that in my cLub.
He's like me
and finally comes up
because I was just about to ratchet,
but I remember he's a Vietnam vet and he
got hit with a missile or something.
He sold it.
He sold the club to a mormon and yes,
we talked about the mormon.
Got mad at us and then he offered me a
week up there.
Now it's done.
Yeah,
it's done.
Yeah.
He got bad because he had sent somebody
home or said someone couldn't work there
or something changed salmon or san jose,
one of those guys,
once someone,
someone had problems with them and so I
was,
I just wanted to put the word out so
that I can't work wise guys and advil.
he was,
he was in wise guys in salt lake.
He left and he bought giggles.
Uh,
so I never did that club.
That was,
I think I'd heard about it,
but it was like,
you gotta be,
you have to be cleaned.
And then he left bobby slayton work
there.
That was what he did.
He called them.
He goes,
no,
no.
I don't allow cleaning.
But bobby slayton work there and he was
saying something like,
this is not my cup of tea,
you know,
like he,
he said it was when he was bringing up
the show or something like that.
This is not my type of show.
I just want to say that like he like
introduced the show that way and someone
was offended and he was a shimano or it
was bobby,
bobby slayton,
one of those guys
fucking went thursday night was the
capital of town and that was a seattle
gig and friday and saturday with giggles
and the.
Do you know what's fucking fantastic.
Polar live in bellevue.
Have you done that place yet,
bro?
Listen,
I've been salivary call number one.
You got call live.
Okay.
Because wHen you go to the ufc,
this guy up there made you a,
a tank for you to go under with a bond
under the fucking water.
The guy made you win a fucking video
projector that you see.
Shit.
Something with a bond.
That's number one.
Number two,
I haven't called me today.
They're telling me that he's got a cop
buddy and the buddy looked into my
warrant that crazy.
Like tHey're fucking crazy.
They're trying to get.
It's an extradition warrant.
They won't hunt me down anyway,
but if I get caught in seattle,
they're going to arrest me and they're
going to keep me in that because it's an
expired warrant.
He was telling me I have in the whole
story thing.
I go,
I haven't do me a favor.
Get me a fucking attorney unless just do
this.
Pick me another the because I don't
know.
No attorneys.
Get a fucking attorney.
I'll send them a retainer.
Right?
Let's get this warning over with.
I'm not going to turn myself in.
So wHat did I say?
I don't know.
Call me back tomorrow.
I'm going to write a check and send it.
No.
How many letters I get like please get
uncle joey to come with you to seattle.
I'll please.
I got to up there so I'm going to
fucking do this and get this over with.
I'll send ivan the,
the attorney,
the money.
I think the guy's name is savage and
we'll contact the entire.
These savage savage.
Oh my god.
Let's go up there and get it out and
then I could probably go up there with
you next month.
I'm there july 26 thompson girl.
Uh,
where am I in july?
That's two weeks.
Two weeks.
I'm a,
I'm there.
And you're going to get the cgo image
zoo in seattle and shit like girls.
Awesome.
She is awesome.
Isn't she a darling?
That more theater.
That's what I'm doing.
I'm doing me and sigora shadows a
fucking bad ass town.
We had a good time up there when I was
looking for bigfoot to drop.
They're squashing someplace I
disrespected but not really.
why did you do respect it?
This,
I lived up there with that fucking
filthy animals.
It was,
ended up choking her out.
she stabbed me.
Disrespect in seattle because of that,
you know.
And that'S why like I broke right now.
I love to get outta here and I love you
bro.
There's only one place for me to go.
And that's Colorado.
Yeah,
that's it.
But I felt like I disrespected him.
Like I would have to disrespect to
Colorado had done,
you know,
when you really.
Why?
because I fucked up there a long time
ago,
man.
You're a different human now.
That don't mean nothing.
It's a.
That's a thing in Colorado.
It's large country.
That's like god's country,
bro.
When you driving in Colorado,
you're breeding that at you and fucking
god's living room.
I don't know what the fuck did describe
to me.
One of the things about boulder is just
that you're at the base of those
mountains and you use or you leave
boulder,
you drive 10 minutes.
Welcome to the woods.
Like literally you are.
It's 10 minutes out of boulder.
You are in the woods and the beauty of
that place is so hard.
It's so stunning that it affects people.
It affects people.
It's like living around the most insane
artwork all the time.
I really do believe that.
I think that's one of the reasons why
the people were so healthy there.
I think the view,
it's not just the,
the air is clean,
which it is,
but it's also like the view of those
mountains like enriches you.
I really believe that.
I think there's something to places like
that,
especially because it's a college town,
so it was like intelligent people.
They're intelligent,
cool people at the base of a mountain,
this insane view.
Listen dog that's buying some land and
let's do this.
Let's start a farm sort of fucking
colony up there on my daughter to be
raised there.
Why not?
Let's do it.
You want to go?
I want to go.
Collin wants to go snow.
Trying them before some the girl that's
got nothing for you.
Brian canes and fucking pain.
All that shit kills you brian.
And box them up and birdcages from the
mansion.
Ship them up southwest.
I want to shoot my.
You know what man?
That's how I redeemed myself by shooting
my special in denver and why not?
Listen,
we could do.
We could go back to back.
You know we say hello.
Those motherfuckers know back to back
specials like will you do one week?
I do another the next week.
You know,
we'll do like two weeks in denver.
We could even fill the documentary.
Take two weeks in denver.
I'll open for you when you do your
special.
You overwhelming what I do for you to
bring me up on stage somewhere.
I'll do it.
Fuck yeah,
dude.
You tell me.
I'll do it.
I'll be happy to do it.
Even if I just come in just to bring you
up.
I'd be happy to this.
What's the next religion?
Ufc.
You brought me up every special I ever
did except the I'm going to be dead
someday.
That was mcguire.
Every single thing that was houston.
Every single thing I've done since then.
You brought me up.
No.
Uh,
what's the next big ufc fighter?
Brazil.
Brazil?
Yeah.
That's um.
Well no,
there's a seattle,
demetrius johnson.
John moraga.
That's on fox.
That's coming up soon.
yeah.
The ufc has been going to Japan.
Dude,
but they do the fx or fuel shows there
and I don't,
I haven't been doing those,
but I'm doing the first fox sports one.
That's a boston card.
I'm going to do that.
I'm going to be at the show,
but I'm not going to fight.
I'm going to be at the show though.
Yeah,
with two shows sold out.
Who show boom son sockets.
You got to get to Alaska,
joe the next day.
You gotta listen to me this this summer
before the time is up.
Before it gets cold there.
Go go to anchorage.
Alaska did comedy.
I did.
Yeah.
I did some fucking bear tooth lodge or
something like that.
Wasn't the name of the then bear tooth.
I think it was.
Bear to bear to theater.
It's a theater.
They show movies there and then they
have a comedy show.
It was flooded.
We went to anchorage.
Anchorage.
Okay.
You didn't go to chuck with charlie's?
no,
no.
I went to this bear to theater.
Wherever the fuck it is.
It was amazing.
They grow,
they grow.
They have their own beer there.
They grow their own pattern,
not powder.
It's like they brew their own beer.
It's amazing.
Make sure I'm saying the name right.
Bear to fudge is it?
YeaH.
Yeah.
It was amazing,
man.
It was a.
It was.
It's.
It's one of those places where as you're
up there like you would think before you
went there,
you'd be like,
who the fuck would live in Alaska?
Like my friend eric,
eric,
chris sugartree cues,
he used to live in Alaska.
There's a queue.
Makerbot ask you mager makes pool cues
like the best pool cues.
And uh,
he was,
he at one point in time he did a,
he was working,
I think he lived at a base there when he
was in the military or lived there when
he was in the military and he always
talks about going back there and I go,
why the fuck would you go to Alaska?
Man,
are you crazy?
I was thinking about how cold it is and
all the stories that I've heard.
But then you get there and you're like,
I see it,
I get it.
I've been the same thing happened to me
once.
I got it.
I get it.
It's weird.
We go outside to third in the morning.
It's blight out at 2:30
in the morning.
We,
we,
we did our show.
We took pictures after the show we hung
out.
I would just want to go party all night.
oh yeah.
I'm sure people do.
And by the way,
that myth of know pretty girls there.
Myth,
the myth of 10 to one men myth,
it's more than half of the population of
anchorage's girls and there.
There's a lot of hot ones.
I'm.
THey're like rugged hot.
what we can.
The bruise
up strip club.
I don't know.
We didn't go to the strip clubs.
You hear about it?
No,
we,
we did basically was.
We fished all day.
We're efficient.
We got up,
we went on a,
we rented an outfitter and went for 10
hours at a stretch.
So we did two long days and the first
day we did 10 hours.
The second day we actually called it
quits,
like a little early so that we could get
ready for the show because we were
exhausted.
I'm not saying you went to the strip
close,
but we didn't do any of that.
People were saYing you got to go to
anywhere we go.
and this strip club there was huge
because women come from all over the
middle and early.
Two tHousands that there's a ratio of 10
to one men to women go up there and the
dav,
a seasoned efficiencies and they'd make
a fucking thousand shaking.
Yeah,
there's another season in late july and
the silver salmon are running like,
uh,
towards,
towards the end of the month.
apparently.
That's another big time when people come
up.
And then it's also people would come up
for the various hunting seasons.
Like moose season starts in september.
People come up for that.
But god damn that places majestic.
You see eagles,
you just see eagles everywhere.
We saw five moose were there for two
days.
We saw five loose.
And there's just something about the
place.
It just makes you humble,
you know,
it makes you,
it humbles you because it's just,
it's when you're flying over,
you look down,
your jaw just drops because it goes on
for ever.
And Then forever you see nothing.
You just see mountains and trees and
mountains and trees and mountains and
trees and mountains and trees.
And then,
okay,
we're starting our descendant to aspen
or to anchorage.
And he slowly start scooting into
anchorage.
And by you get there,
when you get there,
you're like,
these people are gangster as fuck.
Like you think about how far their
living from the real world.
Like they're up there on some weird
little patch of land that they've
assigned to clear out some trees and
start some fires and a fucking half a
million of them up there.
It was like 300,000
people live in there and it's only like,
I think the whole state only has like
double that or something like that.
I think it's only like 600,000
people in the whole state,
but anchors got like 300,000
people you could live there,
man.
I'm telling that four hours away before
we even start the party.
Yeah.
We'll get to seattle,
to Alaska and get to seattle from Alaska
and to.
That's great.
What am I gonna eat salmon the rest of
my life.
You know what I'm saying?
How to get the other places.
If you could live anywhere outside of
la.
Now I know now that you have your little
daughter,
you.
I'm sure you're probably thinking,
I don't want her growing up in
California.
That's one of the things that I thought
of immediately when my first daughter
was born on diego.
So beautiful to goes to Mexico sun.
If you could go to another state,
whIch one would it be?
Colorado.
It would be Colorado.
Why not?
Yeah.
I can't figure out.
What about seattle would you do that?
If you get home,
I'll come fucking living in seattle from
september to december to credit to
doctor.
I love these people are like cool.
Yeah.
So yeah.
Cool.
go up there in september and with
uc two fucking weeks of nonstop bucket
of rain and the gutters and you can't go
nowhere and all you want to do is wake
up,
look around.
You know when you wake up here,
you got to pee in the sun,
creeping through your windows.
What do you do when you wake up for two
weeks and it fucking gray and then
there's grant in november and it gets a
little sunny for three days.
Then it's rainy again for three weeks
ago.
Relaxed,
right?
Everybody wants to know danger.
Everybody wants to be a fuck up.
It's already in there for two days and
all of sudden we got the place packed
down,
lived there for six fucking months.
Seattle is great and the people are
great.
It's great to do comedy there.
It wasn't for fucking me that long
stretch from september to december.
It rain or build up and fuck you.
There's more to life than fucking waking
up the fucking rain,
my friend.
It's like living in buffalo,
New York.
What the fuck?
What are you.
What is that called?
The protractor where you put the
protractor,
the buffalo and put the protractor.
The fucking seattle.
It's in the same missile,
the same missile.
Take our buffalo and then shooting.
Taken out fucking seattle.
They got the saMe suicide fucking rates.
You know you go to fucking buffalo dog.
It's a tough lift.
I love it.
I love it,
but there's a tough lift.
I think it's hard to fuck around with
California in july and go,
yeah,
it's nice shadows who are just in the
suMmer.
The only problem with counseling wAs too
many people.
That's the only problem that I think
that if you got to add,
that might be the move to santa barbara,
might be the move someone needs to do a
helium and santa barbara.
Do you know how bad asset would be?
That theater that we did was perfect.
We don't need to know.
Helium is in santa barbara.
That data we did for 600 seat again.
Which fucking gorgeous.
When I do it again,
say the word december,
december the week before christmas.
I love it.
That's because we still got to do with
doing vegas.
Vegas.
December 27th.
We can't we,
but we still got to do an end of the
world somewhere.
Real english.
They offered us the wilbur theater
again.
Do it boston.
No,
here.
But we have to and rather than doing the
wilbur,
we have to do the wheelchair and the day
before christmas.
That's the end of the world with the
23rd.
Yeah.
Because once a nobody wants to go out
and christmas eve.
No,
two days before christmas shopping and
shit.
December 20th.
But last time we did it December 21st
December 21st.
You sit here at halloween.
All right.
What should we call it if we don't call
it what she brings?
Stan.
Hope and honey.
Honey.
Again,
happy everybody.
Which we call it something in the world.
You ended the world part two.
The beginning of the new world.
Beginning of the new riders of the
purple sage.
Do it in denver.
I'll do whatever the fuck you want.
If you want,
we should do it.
Let's move to denver.
Bitch.
Let's do that.
It still.
Let's move to denver,
but show how about a ball to show.
Do less.
Let's move to boulder bench.
Let's do it to do a definitely a monthly
show in vegas like every month you guys
should do.
I don't know about that,
man.
I am.
I enjoy going in every few months and
rocking it.
I'll tell you the joint as my new
favorite place to join at the hard rock.
First of all,
everybody works.
There was cool as fuck as fuck.
It's
so.
It was dynamite.
Dynamite.
Great vibe.
And deck.
Tech crowd could have been better.
Joey diaz.
Amazing.
We had so much fun.
Okay,
so much fun with that was they weren't
stoners.
We just hung out at the bar.
We didn't go out to smoke one time.
I didn't go out to smoke at all.
I was fucking stolen.
That edible.
I was just talking with the players on
the planet fucked up at 9:30
by four.
I was fucked up in that whole total
three gummies before I went on stage.
Can we bear?
I've been celebrate and then I would
love to go to seattle on a regular
basis.
I wish I can get you in and all that
shit,
but I can't risk going to jail for
something that happened eight fucking
years ago that nobody.
Nothing bad happened.
Nothing.
Yeah.
That seems to go to fucking.
I didn't go to anger management.
The judge threw me out of the fucking
state for two years.
Really?
Me.
The judge told me I got to go.
That's how it was and that was it.
You gotta go,
dog.
Go joe.
You got to go.
What are you doing next weekend?
Joe?
Are you.
Are you out of town?
Yes.
Yeah,
I got family shit going on.
Um,
I don't have a gig booked until the end
gig booked out of town at least until
seattle,
but I got some other shit cooking.
I'm trying to finish up this tv show
till when it's,
it's,
it's more difficult than I thought it
was going to be.
It's more difficult time wise and the
thought I was going to be and it's more
difficult as far as like getting it
right.
It's a lot of work,
you know,
we're putting together kind of a crazy
show,
but ari's in it and duncan's in it too
and there's a lot of interviews that
they're doing when I'm not there,
like I said,
dunkin to interview some scientists and
are,
he goes and interviews from other
scientists and all these other crazy
people involved in all these different
disciplines.
So it's kind of interesting and it's a
way.
We're only hoping it coMes out.
Right.
It's a big experiMent,
right.
BecAuse he ran with a scientist.
So,
you know,
he's very intelligent man.
He's very good at,
uh,
at,
at interviewing people and talking to
the people.
We had them talk to some,
uh,
some crazy religious guy and we went to
the global future 2045 conference in New
York.
What a bunch of fucking intelligent
super freaks.
That place was filled with.
It was so fascinating.
All these people with robots that look
just like them and there were people
with bionic hands and like the,
the,
the cutting edge of life extension
science.
And we had already interviewing some
religious guy.
It was really weird.
There was these religious guys and they
were all like telling people that,
you know,
not to,
not to concentrate on,
on technology and not to be persuaded by
technology,
but the beauty of a rose cannot be
defined by science who should know why a
seed becomes a flower and that flower
becomes a beautiful part of it was like
this weird resistance sort of,
you know,
and like this weird trying to
incorporate their religion into the idea
of the future.
And you're like,
listen bitch,
she can't left behind getting left by.
You're dressed like a wizard and you're
getting left behind.
No mattEr what you do.
He got crazy beads around your neck and
you think they're important and you're
fucked.
Okay.
Because your style of living,
you can't rock it.
You can't be reading 6,000
year old books and saying and saying
they had it right.
They were onto it.
These global future 20,
45 people with microchips in their head.
They don't know what the fuck they're
doing.
Joe ideas.
I lost ya.
Gotta.
Get outta here.
We do a show next weekend at comic con
2013.
We were having a midnight show there
friday and saturday night and so with
me,
sarah tiana,
Mike Black,
yoshi,
benji,
and a couple of special guests that I
can say.
Excellent club too.
It's a fun spot.
Yeah.
American comedy was a good spot to go
and get the one,
the comicon the next weekend for friday
and saturday midnight shows.
So the 20th and 21st.
Okay.
Yeah,
and if you want to see me and were at
the moore theater in seattle on July
26th,
the boston wilbur theater on August 18th
with joey diaz and ari shaffir and me
suck upon it.
Sold out shows.
So I got july eight,
10,
then milwaukee,
we're doing a,
what is that thing we were doing the
paps or something in milwaukee?
Is that what we're doing?
August 30th.
And that's you and me.
Great beer in me.
Um,
you know,
I gotta fuck in philadelphia for the
20th and then the following week I'm
with my main man.
Dom irrera.
That's water.
Yeah.
Well brian and I actually talked about
this yesterday.
We eventually got to put together like a
real serious death squad page with all
the different guys.
We could click on the link,
like you'd have a pictuRe of you next to
a picture of duncan.
Next to a picture of everybody who's in
there.
He got one stop shop.
Go there or press a button to a perfect
ggc has a counter with all our shows on
it right here.
Beautiful.
Jill does this powerful chill.
He's awesome.
All right,
thank you to everybody tuning into the
podcast.
Thanks to squarespace.com.
Go to squarespace.com
forward slash Joe to sign up and use the
code word joe and the number seven to
get your hand made a website.
I'm doing a fucking commercial dude.
Get 10 percent off.
Your first purchase were also brought to
you by stamps.com.
If you go to stamps.com,
use the code j r e to save yourself some
cash.
And what was the other one?
A legal zoom.
Legal zoom,
legal zoom,
which is the latest of the latest of our
podcast sponsors.
if you go to legalzoom.com
and use the code rogan,
um,
you can save yourself some money.
Legal zoom is a not.
Yeah.
I'm trying to read the exact thing
you're supposed to read.
Legal zone is not a law firm.
They provide self help services at your
specific direction and if you really
nice they rubbed your balls when you
masturbate.
No,
I made That part up.
Listen,
that's not true.
This is a comedy podcast.
Fuck legal zoom.
Go,
go there.
Get your freak on.
I'm on it.
Dot coms are last sponsor o n n I t use
the code name.
Rogan.
Save 10 percent off any and all
supplements.
we will most likely be here tomorrow.
I just have to figure out what time I
can get off of work.
I'm trying real hard to get these
podcasts out again.
Jodi.
Yes.
You can catch him in the church of
what's happening now.
How many days a week you're doing that
now?
Sunday.
Six am.
Wednesdays in the afternoon.
I can't wake up early no more.
I got too much shit.
Bond day 6:00
AM.
Do you understand that fucking around
youth stream cox.
He's not even playing games.
Six am and he does it on a regular.
All right,
thank you everybody.
Thanks everybody.
Came out to vegas.
Thanks everYbody comes out to all these
shows.
You guys are the shit.
We love the fuck out of here and we'll
see you soon.
Big kiss
my mom.
Cool.