Tell me when we're up.
We're up.
I got to post it on twitter.
So Tom,
I went to the doctor.
What were we talking about before?
We started talking about like rappers
killing each other and I don't want to
stop the subject real quick because when
you know,
when that happened,
when I'm,
when the nineties,
you know,
when they started shooting each other
and coming out with gangster rap,
there's never been anything like that
because you mentioned like the beach
boys,
you know,
and they fucking hated Elvis.
They want to shoot them,
should take bitches pitches.
And there was the first time where guys
were ever able to brag about everything
about their money,
about their,
their sexual conquest.
It's like didn't ever been,
you know,
like Eddie Bravo was talking about that
song the other day.
She swallowed it.
It's not a good song.
It,
it's.
I mean,
I don't like it,
you know,
it's okay.
Mc Ren had had a decent verse on it.
Yes.
Mc Ren Ren was amazing.
What happened to that store?
I have no idea.
Yeah,
I think he's working on the new Nwa
movie right now.
If I move it,
yeah,
they're redoing the whole Nwa.
They're doing it in Wwi.
Moving using like family members is
going to play aids.
Cast that part.
Oh,
Tommy with the plugins there.
Who's good?
Okay.
Play aids.
Oh Shit.
No you didn't.
I think it was Morgan Freeman.
Morgan Freeman.
That's fucking incredible.
Jesus Christ.
Give me that power that he had.
I can nail this shit.
Do you think Jerry Curl will ever come
back?
It's too much work.
Too much better.
The fuck.
Head a head like he was like a poster
child for the Jerry Curl.
Yeah.
Ice Cube had a really fucking Nice Jheri
curls.
Good.
If you're going to get a jerry curl,
that's who you should take this picture
and your salon and say,
make me look like Chris Rock's movie.
What was the move with the c four where
they spray Jericho juice.
They're here all the time.
What was Jerry curl juice?
What is it?
Just oil is the oil.
What was that?
Coming to America.
Soul glow glow.
Get off off the chair and there's like a
stain on that to be true.
Right?
Every become Palme d'or look at the
hairstyles,
man.
Hairstyles are are insane,
but that's one of the weirdest ones
ever.
You had to put all that shit in your
hair and make it greasy and drippy the
fuck it ruins your clothes at the Afro
style.
Like the statement,
right.
Then member fades and high top fade
high.
They can get away with anything.
I remember when I was giving black
girls,
they have straight hair,
they have white girl's hair and you're
like,
how'd you get that?
Shut up.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Black dudes can't pull it off.
You know what?
I was really jealous.
I in like middle school and high school
was when black has had like a designs in
their hair,
like the headlight lines and she'll be
written bolts and shit.
Yeah.
And I'm going to do that and like you
cannot,
you will look like a fucking ass.
There's a fighter who is a black guy
from some,
some k,
one guy,
but he carves like designs,
like tribal designs and his hair before
he fights.
It looks bad.
That's the thing.
You get away with it,
but do you think a black guy could get
away with wearing like a white guy's
hair like a black girl does?
No.
Oh No,
no,
no.
You mentioned black dudes.
If that was the next thing they all
started having Bon Jovi,
bon jovi hair weaves or what if it was
just like,
like what if they use part of it like a
good boy come like Ted.
Ted Haggard just were like cool about.
And you'll be like,
what's going on?
Man?
Is it strange though?
But becomes popular and unpopular.
You know,
like a girls are allowed to have.
Everything can be fake.
You can have fake tits.
Fake hair.
Nobody gives a shit as long as you look
good.
You look good.
Good.
Okay.
Let's go.
You know,
no guy is like really?
Not Me guys are.
Don't get me wrong,
but it's acceptable for you to be.
Oh,
pretty inauthentic.
We are held to such a lower standard.
Another thing that we get like for most
guys,
like if you,
if you bay,
you shower,
you bathe regularly and you basically,
you know,
change clues that's considered like
carry yourself.
You don't have to wear makeup or
anything,
isn't it?
Could you imagine though if you found
out the dude was wearing blue contacts
because we'd be like,
what the fuck is wrong with this guy?
I almost bought some fake contacts the
other day just because that stone but it
wasn't,
it was the ones where you can.
There's like ones that you can get like
cat eyes,
like completely black and I just want to
have a pair for,
for no for no reason at all.
Do you remember Michael Jackson's
thriller when he had the cat eyes?
Yeah,
I guess it was pretty cheap.
They were like $89 bucks and you just
put them in your.
It's not like the end of the movie.
He looks Ilearn,
thriller.
Yeah.
He turns back and then the law was a
fucking great music video that was,
that was prevalent.
That was an actual event that was like a
world news.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
It was huge.
That's what we had far less channels
too.
I can't imagine what the numbers were on
just that video.
They must've been.
It must be astronomical.
Yeah.
They must've been 13 minutes and that
was like,
that was so cool seeing that and for me
it was a werewolf,
so I was even more excited.
A cool one.
A really.
That was Rick Baker that did that,
I believe.
I believe it was the same guy that did
the monitor girl from London.
He did star Wars Shit.
The coordinated dancing.
All the dancing was coolest shit.
Where's the message behind that?
You know,
little weird fucking video and moving.
I remember people were saying it was
titanic.
I remember that.
There was a bunch of protests about it.
Oh yeah.
We're upset.
What a fucking fascinated.
Just the best thing ever.
When you get a controversy like that,
when people.
When someone says this might be say
tannic.
That was when they were like,
guys fucking.
Yes.
Michael Jackson and Whitney Houston.
Probably the two most talented people
that died and everybody saw it coming.
Yeah.
You know what I'm saying?
When we talk about like really uniquely
talented people that everybody's like,
man,
you know,
how long is this going to last?
How long can you,
do you remember that?
Um,
the Bobbi Brown show being Bobby Brown?
Yeah.
When they were on the shelf screaming
and yelling at each other,
like,
oh my God,
I remember when they talked,
they were at,
they were at a dinner,
Bob,
they're fucked up,
not like buzzing,
like fucking up racks.
And they were at a hotel and they were,
they had ordered like a feast and I mean
it was,
it was crazy like how much food was on
this table and they were both just
fucking completely out of their minds
proliferated and laughing.
And then I forget what I forget who said
like,
remember when I was at had tech was
taking that shit and you had to come
over with help me pull it up my ass.
And it was like,
yeah,
I think it was the,
he was the one time she had to shit
stuck inside of her and he reached up
and he's like,
Hey,
I pulled that book out and she was like,
I'll take a dump right now.
I'm going to drop it on the one like
that was the senior,
like I'm gonna drop it on the one.
Yes dude.
Yes.
Funny
how come
my ass?
Yeah.
Wow.
Taking a dump.
You put your hand in my ass.
Do you remember what they interviewed
her?
There was an interview where the guy was
trying to get to what the fuck was up
and he's like,
is it cocaine?
Is it alcohol?
And she's like,
at times,
all of them,
like at times all of them.
And he's like,
you know,
have you ever,
have you ever smoked crack?
And she was like,
crack is whack,
whack.
I think that was the Diane Sawyer that
she said that.
And he also said,
it's rumored that you spent $750,000
one year on drugs.
And she said,
I wish
I will.
She said,
I wish it was this like down at ship
right now.
Are you kidding me?
Shit.
That'd be a good year.
But it was 700.
It was this strange ranges.
Interview men to listen to a person who
you know when you grew up,
you know the body guard.
I remember her with Kevin Costner.
She is.
She was such a talent talent.
It's such a superstar.
Oh,
amazing.
If you watch like how will I know like
the video.
I mean,
you see she's so beautiful.
Have you ever heard when they late her
lyrics?
No.
It's got food.
Her seat.
I don't know if you can play that.
I think we can play that.
Not at all.
Probably not.
Not like you will look a little sample
of it or something.
I don't know.
Let's try her range.
The range and her voice is just
ridiculous.
It's really stunning to listen to it.
Just look up.
How will I know?
Whitney Houston isolated lyrics.
Love it.
Used to freak type with one hand.
Don't know what the fuck you're doing.
A bunch of chicken scratch on that
screen.
Brian's going to confuse the fuck out of
people is a way to,
um,
take that video of your ustream and put
it on mine.
I don't know.
I could find out.
But you definitely do vimeo.
Yeah.
Uh,
people are mad at you,
Brian.
This is another old brian moment.
They get excited.
People Liking when you fuck up.
Do you notice that?
Yeah,
they love it.
What is that about?
Um,
makes it seem more real.
It's not edited.
It's Raul or.
Yeah.
People like a little conflict.
This is a dude who just sent me 19.
Tell Brian to shut the fuck ups in a
row.
Okay.
That guy's blocked.
Oh Shit.
That didn't come.
Wait,
here's one.
It's a,
it's a strange thing to listen to man,
because you know,
there's no.
You can give me a million years when all
the coaches in the world,
they listen to that.
Listen to this shit.
Control.
God.
Damn.
She was good.
She was.
Fuck.
That's a once in a lifetime voice man.
That is a perfect voice.
Yeah.
So the perfect voice and it's like a
bodyguard days hot.
It's hot as fuck.
That was the first time ever there was a
hot girl that a hot man was falling in
love with,
you know that she's black and then they
did a major movie about it.
Have they ever done that before?
Where the hot black girl and the man get
together if man,
nobody apparently even complained now
the main storyline,
you know,
like that would have to be the story.
She was such a fucking gigantic star as
a singer that they were like seeing a
movie with him.
Who Cares?
Just fucking rolled the cameras.
Say whatever you want.
We'll tie it all together.
You're working with Kevin Costner.
He'll carry you along.
She could act to act as easy as fuck
man.
Acting and shit.
I mean there's this high level acting
obviously that none of us can do,
but the regular acting like the
bodyguard.
Yeah.
You could do that hard,
man.
What'd you say?
8 million.
My Buddy Mike Star was in that movie
too.
He got beat up by Kevin Costner and
yeah,
my buddy Mike Star did a.
We did a TV show a long time ago called
the hardball together.
It's stupid.
Baseball show that,
yeah,
it's terrible show,
but it was a.
I made a bunch of good friends with
Mike.
Star was one of them.
He got beat up in a bunch of movies.
You got beat up in a Steven Seagal
movie.
Got Real mad at Steven Seagal.
Was hitting him really hard.
Really?
Yeah.
He had a wound up actually having to put
like a chest protector on because the
guy was not really supposed to hit them.
You know,
it was supposed to like fake hit him.
It's for fucking movie.
You know,
you're already seeing steven lightest.
Chest up a bomb.
Hit Him with that fucking wing.
Chung punching shit.
The Steve.
Really either.
He just does it,
man.
He was known for doing that.
You know,
he's,
you know,
he's trying to make a fucking bad ass
movie and unfortunately when you try and
make a bad ass movie sometimes you got
to sacrifice.
Yeah.
I'm going to kick you in the chat right
now,
man.
Fucking stomped on occasion.
That's what
he.
I mean that was his attitude.
He probably had a line after he kicked
it,
which made it so much where it's like
you get kicked in the.
He's like,
that's what time it is or some shit.
Mother fucker did that happen.
Like the guy that was in the movie that
always has the witty one liner after he
kicked you in the balls now man,
that became.
I mean I was that.
I think that became huge through
clinics.
Would I think he'd be the guy.
I mean,
you know what I mean?
We're like,
we're the bad ass thing happens and then
you'd go in not closed.
You pushing on the bad ass face and he's
like,
ask your mother what she thinks.
She says the Clint Eastwood every which
way,
but loose movies were the first time
that they really like combined like
action and comedy together with a dude
who wasn't a comedy guy,
but it works.
Works,
man.
It works.
Grail siloed.
Better be funny.
Fucking dude.
Come on man.
Every which way but loose was awesome
and that was back when Clint Eastwood
was stuck with that one chick.
What's her name?
Sondra Locke.
I don't remember if did a million movies
with this freak,
I guess you know,
that was just this girl and they did a
bunch of movies together,
but as soon as they broke up,
mad shit got ugly.
Really?
Yeah.
He got her like some development deal,
get the fuck away from home and you
know,
and she accused him of blocking every
one of her projects.
Don't want to do anything.
I wouldn't fuck with Clinton.
She was suing the shit out of him.
It was just gross man.
It was just when,
when people like divorce and they do it
publicly like that,
you lose so much respect for the more
vocal member of the two.
And that was one of the case with the
thing with her.
I automatically assume,
oh this bitch is crazy.
We're going to go.
She never really worked again.
You know,
Sondra Locke disappeared.
She was in a ton of movies with Clint
Eastwood,
but that was about it.
After that,
you know,
she thought it was because he
blackballed there.
But most people,
I think a lot of us probably as people
thought she was gross,
like you know what's going?
What do you do in a clip?
Yeah man.
That he can't,
he can't fuck over that movie.
Royalty.
Good.
The bad and the ugly.
Come on.
You leave him alone.
You know,
what'd you do?
I can't imagine the stories that he has.
Oh my God.
And I remember even when we played like
the old,
like racist.
What was that?
Was it?
No,
I know what you mean.
Yeah.
What was,
was made on account Mustang recently
realized man to Reno that I think that
was it.
I lived next door to like,
uh,
among family or something.
Right.
So there's all these like,
and he's like,
it's an old time,
he's like,
get your yellow ass off my loans,
like crazy shit.
And they asked him about like political
correctness and he was like,
I don't know what this shit is all
about.
He was like,
back in my day,
like we would shoot a movie and a grip
was from China.
He was the Chinaman and like that's just
who you are.
And like,
we would just laugh about it,
like we could tell jokes to people about
their race and people wouldn't freak
out.
Like if people were given them,
you know,
a lot of Shit,
right?
Yeah.
People are super sensitive.
You're not even supposed to joke around
about this unless you are,
have a,
uh,
a nationality or a minor or rather a,
um,
uh,
what's the word I'm looking for them?
Not Minor,
like a minority or a minority ethnic.
You'll come from it in my mind of a
minority and then stop at minor.
That's how tired I am.
I think that for a lot of people that
give minorities,
you know,
whether you're black people can make fun
of white people all day long,
but you,
you're walking a fine line where we make
fun of black.
Yeah.
I've seen you do some great black jokes
and I see people go,
oh shit.
See pl like the clench.
I'm going to go,
oh shit.
Because people worry.
People worry when a white guy makes fun
of black people,
it gets to be a real black.
People can make fun of white people.
I've seen white people laugh at the
lamest shit.
They'll at the end.
It's just like,
it's like a guilty last.
It's this weird.
They do that,
that fake white guy and voice.
It's like a rip off of the Richard Pryor
White Guy Voice.
We're Richard Pryor was like,
it was a really unique thing.
We'd say,
you know,
say you know,
you can't fuck with white people and be
like,
hey man,
your momma.
My mom's a great old gal,
you know,
and he,
he developed that sort of white guy
voice and everybody's sort of stole it.
They stole it and a lot of it are
terrible.
Yeah.
It's Kinda like,
come on man,
why don't talk like that.
That's not how they talk.
And they get,
a lot of them.
Give a horrible example.
It's silly man.
You could Ip,
but you can tell white people.
It's weird.
It's a weird,
a Gimme,
you know?
So for a lot of black guys,
like especially when they're first
starting out in up,
that's the first thing they go to.
Yeah,
it isn't that one of those things that
you see and you go,
oh,
he's going there.
Yeah,
yeah,
of course.
Unless you see it done like supremely.
Well,
like there's,
there has to be like a super good
example for you to be like.
Yeah.
And if the observation is really student
when you're like that,
that's some insight.
Yeah.
Dude,
you're picking apart something new or
you're doing it and like you're doing a
version of it that I haven't heard,
but everything else has been done,
you know,
so like will there always being
minorities?
Do you think there's ever going to be a
point where we're all just gray,
like a turn that would take that and
color that's happening?
Like race is becoming more really more
mixed across the board,
do you think so?
Oh definitely.
Why?
Why are people attracted to blonde
girls?
Done.
But we talked about this.
You know what I'm not attracted to as
blonde eyelashes and blond eyebrows.
I'm not attracted to blonde girls.
I'm attracted to blonde girls to do shit
with her eyelashes and eyebrows.
I liked blondes the most.
Men.
Any funny though?
That's a weird or girls who don't do
that,
like girls who have naturally brown
eyebrows.
Yeah,
and that's why they usually I gravitate.
A lot of them don't really know.
What I don't like at all though is like
bleached.
Oh yeah.
That,
that's not to be natural.
I like all kinds of blind.
I think a lot of times when you would
take a girl that's like brown hair,
some weird color brown,
he make her blonde.
She's always hot or if she's like nice
bleached blonde,
you know what's really freaking me out?
Man.
Amount of people that are putting shit
in their face.
Amount of people that are probably like
fillers in their face.
Yeah,
like the implants.
It's becoming.
They're not even cheek implants.
That's what I thought they were too.
I thought like,
remember when Mickey work did that
Mickey work losses.
Fucking marbles.
Remember that in the nineties I guess he
had implants.
Did he get implants?
Yes,
he did.
And got them removed.
Now he had chicken plants and he looked
bizarre.
Well,
I think what happened was that's when he
was boxing and when he.
He had a pretty intense like segment of
his life where he just boxed and he
boxed professionally.
He got his fucking brains rattled too.
He looks like it too,
and I think that changed him as a
person.
You know?
I think it made him this wacky
eccentric,
like remember Gary Busey,
he was a regular dude.
Crashes motorcycle becomes this wacky
eccentric.
Totally crazy.
Yeah.
He used to be this really brilliant
actor,
really talented actor like Mr Joshua.
Remember that?
And fucking.
What was that movie?
He's an exciting guy.
What movie was that?
We burned himself.
Yeah.
I forget Bruce Willis movie.
I know it was pulp fiction.
No,
no,
fuck no,
it wasn't that Gary Busey.
Yeah.
Gary Busey.
He's not in pulp fiction and he's not.
God Damn it.
I hate when.
I don't know.
I think rourke is from.
I think it's from liberty city.
Miami,
to my point was lethal weapon.
Was that what it was?
Yeah.
Gary Busey was in.
Was it lethal weapon?
I think so.
One of them was.
Yeah,
it was lethal weapon.
Hold on,
let's take a break.
Yeah,
I think that was a good fucking mood.
The creighton there.
Yeah.
Gary Busey was lethal weapon.
Yeah,
that's what it was a.
was I saying he was a regular dude and
head trauma transformed them,
you know,
and I think that that's also what
happened to Mickey Rourke,
you know,
he's a regular dude and he got so crazy
that he'd decided to be a good idea to
put,
put like plastic things inside it's
cheeks to make his cheeks and like
nobody would know.
You ever seen the photos?
Yeah.
And he had him removed and now he's just
got this weird thing where it's just
any,
anyone that fucks with their face,
it's going to look weird.
Like,
I don't know if Paul Paul Mccartney,
because I got my grandma's his face.
There was a lot going on there.
I think a lot of those dudes are just
botox and Botox and freeze their face
and they can't move.
Like,
like if you get mad at something,
you can't move your forehead and just
way better to be able to do that and
look old.
It's so silly.
It's just you don't look better,
you just look weird.
You look weird.
Your face doesn't move while you're
washing your face.
Moving these girls on these,
uh,
beverly hills housewives shows,
there's a lot of these women have
fillers in their face and then on top of
that they have botox so they have these
shiny faces that are like puffed up and
they don't move and they looked like
masks.
Yeah,
I was high as fuck once and I was in the
green room with Joey Diaz.
Joe.
He turns on the TV and it was a Joan
rivers and I just freaked out.
Just freaked out.
I was because I was like,
oh,
so baked.
And it hit me like I looked at it and
that really hit me what she's done.
And you know,
you just want to go.
Just tell her to stop.
Just tell her.
Stop doing that.
Yeah.
Just tell her and she's doing it.
She doesn't make you look better.
It doesn't make you look better.
I look crazy.
I know,
I know.
It's the weirdest thing ever.
That frozen.
So puffy face,
you know,
it's like they're,
they're injecting things into their face
because when you get older,
the first one,
first things that happens to your face
starts to lose body fat.
That's why you get like sorta sunk,
gain,
wrinkly,
lose.
So they,
they're injecting things in their puff
it up.
Oh,
it's crazy.
Look.
And she looks wild.
Then she'd look,
it's a monster face.
It's a monster.
When I see these women,
I call the monster faces because you see
them all the time and it's like,
it really is just a mistake.
You know,
it's a mistake,
you shouldn't do it.
It's out of such a fear of what would it
look like?
I'll react.
They don't want to look old,
so they'd rather look crazy.
But it's also you convince yourself that
you could fix something.
Like,
I got hair transplants and I totally
wish I'd never done it because I have
this stupid scar in the back of my head
now.
Otherwise I would shave my head,
but I got it because I was convinced
that I could fix something.
Like my hair was falling out.
I was like,
how do I fix this certain way to fix
this research,
ways to fix this.
You talked to the doctor,
I can fix it and he,
oh,
he can fix it.
Like,
okay,
I'll just get it fixed,
but it doesn't fix it.
It fixes it temporarily,
but all the other hair falls out of it.
The way I described it,
I said,
it's like you're taking a bunch of
healthy people and you're moving them to
a neighborhood where everyone's dying.
Yeah.
So they take care of from the back of
your head.
They move it to the top of your head and
then all of its neighbors just fucking
wilt.
Cowan has the exact same thing he was
talking about on the podcast and he was
saying that they.
They can pretty much get rid of a lot of
the scar nowadays.
Yeah,
they can.
Yeah.
I'm actually having treatments.
They shoot things in your scar.
It makes it smaller.
Cortisone or something.
What the fuck?
It is something but it botox.
It's not.
It's not like bad.
Like I've seen guys who have bad ones
minds really thin.
It's a very thin car,
but it's long.
I've seen dudes have big fat wide.
One is skin stretches out some change.
Do you think that should have like a lot
of bling drag.
You have a giant Jesus on the cross.
It.
It'd be a conversation piece.
It'd be nice diamonds and no one will
even know they'll go,
what's going on with your head?
Nothing.
Whatever.
Get like get an eagle.
Medallion something big eagle.
Three d,
maybe an eagle in the back of my head
Bro.
That American bad ass.
Now you're thinking with like like it's
claws will have like the American flag
in it.
Did you find it?
Maybe these colors don't run.
Did you find it weird that capes never
caught on?
Like it seems like we should have funded
totally fucked up that it never came
back.
We didn't wear capes in the fifties like
I think maybe back in the 17 hundreds
and castle times.
I think we think of that because of
Dracula.
Right?
But does that what they really want?
I think it was cold as fuck back then
and they hadn't really figured out.
Jackets,
jacket,
giant thing that they would throw over
them,
like a blanket that you run out of the
house with if you have.
If you wear a cape now you better be
able to back it up with shit.
That's a cool.
What if it had tons
of pockets for cell phones and money and
while it was like a book bag.
That was a kate.
I just think you better be cool too.
If I want to.
I want you to be a really cool dude.
You got to be a bad motherfucker for
real.
When you walk away you're like,
yeah,
just take over that stupid shit that I
saw today at the store where this guy,
grown guy probably rh had a fucking
wallet chain,
but on it had like stuffed animals.
I think there are different kinds of
pokemon texted and he had a fucking a
raccoon tail and I'm like,
you are a raccoon tail stupid fake tales
that people are aware wearing.
That's a sad man.
How old is this guy?
Is Thirty,
35.
40.
Wow.
Oh my goodness.
I just wanted a cape is better than the
Cape.
Is a more powerful statement.
Definitely the host of fear factor in
Mexico had a Cape Real.
Yeah.
When we were doing fear factor there,
they spun off a bunch of other fear
factors and one of them they did in
Mexico.
I don't even know if they fucking.
It's just like official.
This really ranked it,
but they would copy our ideas and they
would do them with no safety at all.
Like we had one where we had these
people where they are to get a.
They had a rescue,
a dummy out of a burning building and we
put them in these crazy fire suits with
a helmet on.
And we had dude standing by with fire
extinguishers when the.
They did it on the Mexican show.
They wore shorts.
Wow.
They were just people in shorts running
through a fucking house.
It was burning.
That's.
No.
Yeah,
it was ridiculous.
It was probably a regular house to.
Ours is a fake house that the,
uh,
fire department uses for training and it
doesn't burn down was covering murder,
drug deal that our country,
again,
our country and our culture is so
engrossed with in lawsuits and that
operates on them and the fear of them
that,
you know,
that actually makes things way safer.
You think about it,
there's countries,
not necessarily Mexico,
but there's countries in the world were
like,
that is never an issue.
Fall down.
They're like,
that's cool.
We want safety,
we want to be able to do things safe and
we want to be able to sue people that
don't look out for our safety.
But ultimately somewhere along the line
we're becoming a bunch of pussies with
the lawsuit thing is people look at it
as a lottery.
It's so ridiculous.
I mean,
there's people that have legitimate
concerns and legitimate gentleman
claims.
No,
there definitely are.
But then there's,
you read about just these,
you know,
it's absolutely insane things that you
pin on somebody else for things that you
did.
Like everything is somebody else's
responsibility.
You know,
about the lady that spilled the
McDonald's coffee on.
Ridiculous.
I think the overturn that,
overturn that,
and that's not even that,
to hear some of the ones that are,
pick the ones that people win and the
amounts for.
Why are you paying this person?
Have you heard about the Monsanto
lawsuit?
Speaking of the guilty of chemical
poisoning people in France,
they chemically poisoned the French
farmer.
Wow.
That's going to be a big suit.
Yeah.
They,
they were found guilty.
Really?
Yeah.
I don't know the exact story apparently
is the first such claim to ever reach
French court and um,
Monsanto A.
apparently they have some fucking
pesticide.
There's another thing they found out
that 93 percent of pregnant women,
they've,
that they tested,
they found this pesticide that exists in
Monsanto.
Genetically modified crops.
Yeah.
Man,
you know,
our politicians sold us down a river.
They,
they let all this shit go on because
this is a giant company that makes a ton
of money and the way they make a ton of
money is they patent plants.
They genetically engineer them so that
it's uniquely theirs.
And then they can decide where they sell
it.
They decide what price they have for it
and you can't do anything about it and
you have to buy new stuff every year and
buy.
If it cross pollinates with the
neighbor,
they can sue the neighbor for copyright
infringement.
It's completely crazy.
They've figured out a way to copyright
life and they've actually tried to do it
with pig parts and Monsanto's crazy.
I mean they've tried to do with a bunch
of different shit,
but this should have never been able to
get to this position.
The this is the best evidence that the
United States needs the best evidence.
Something like Monsanto,
the best evidence that our current
political system is completely corrupt
because if you were really looking out
for people,
there's no fucking way you would let a
company make a bunch of Shit.
Take plants,
patent them,
then sue people because the [inaudible],
the,
the air carries their pollen.
They cross pollinate neighbors,
plants and then this neighbor just,
you know,
where the fuck he got that shit from you
assholes.
You know,
you gotta get to sue them and you're
going to take to court and it was India
in India,
there's a whole bang fucking giant group
of farmers that have been killing
themselves because they,
they,
they get indebted to Monsanto and they
can't afford to pay their bills.
They're Monsanto's like gangsters,
but that's like mine.
Yeah,
they will.
They will shut you down if you don't
play ball.
Yeah.
Well this is crazy because you got to
think about how much political poll that
they have and the fact that they still
lost in court that,
that says a lot.
You know,
I think people are rising up and they're
getting tired of this bullshit.
It's ridiculous what these people have
allowed to take place and it doesn't
have to continue along the same lines.
You know,
what we really need is healthy food we
don't need is a bunch of fucking crazy
shit where companies come along and
genetically modified crops and then they
take those crops and then they sell them
to people with no evidence whatsoever
about the longterm implications of this,
the exposure to some of these chemicals
and what this.
What is this going to do to the
environment you're playing with God,
man,
you're,
you're doing really crazy shit when you
start altering life and then entering
that.
Let me.
This isn't as simple as,
you know,
a packaging,
a new kind of soap,
you know,
you're doing,
you're doing something pretty fucking
crazy.
Yeah.
That people are going to.
It's going to be in their system,
but there's not that much.
Yeah.
There's not that much evidence like it's
like,
or they're not that much of a history of
genetically modified foods.
I mean we need like 10,
20,
30 years to really analyze what the fuck
does the environment people and what's
the chain reaction?
You know what's,
what does the wings of the butterfly do
from the modified food to how's it
affect the ecosystem that it all of a
sudden it,
it takes over.
You know,
it's,
it's weird man.
It's weird when you start fucking with
life.
You know,
I talked to this dude was talking about,
I was just listening to the opiod,
anthony showing what's his face was on
Nicholas cage and he was talking about
the black rhinos going extinct this year
and I was telling us do this and he was
like,
well we could just bring it back,
you know,
if we were just fucking bring back the
black rhino.
Oh,
you mean like you can't,
they do that.
Can't they do that?
They're talking about doing that right
now with Willie Mamis.
Yeah.
But then it becomes the question of,
okay,
do we need rhinos though,
man,
that's just to have a couple like at
zoos I think would be awesome.
Did you see there's a video in Siberia
of a bear walking across a stream with
efficient his mouth and they.
It's really blurry and so people were
like,
it's a woolly mammoth in Siberia,
and then other people are going or a
bear with efficient.
How can the woolly mammoth has a blue
nose?
Stupid fucks.
Like maybe there's a woolly mammoth.
There's,
there's a whole industry devoted to
falsely seeing stuff.
You know,
there's like,
there's all these shows like full our
programs.
This is.
We're going to talk about the shit that
we saw.
Just people telling you saw some shit
and you're like,
that's fucking bullshit,
man.
You didn't see anything.
You know what?
I really learned that when I did that
game show in my head show,
I did this show for CBS and what the
show was.
It was a game show with hidden cameras
and the way it worked was we would.
I was the host.
I don't have a dude with a little
earpiece and I would send them out to a
place and the cameras were already in
place.
Hidden cameras were in place.
I go,
all right,
dude,
you're ready.
He goes,
yeah.
I go,
here's the deal.
You're a reporter and you are there for
the biggest story of your life.
There was a Ufo over Hollywood and all
these people saw it,
but by the time you got your camera
there and got it set up,
all the people went away.
So what you gotTa do is you've got to
find someone to get on camera with you
and,
and talk about their Ufo experience and
you got to say,
you got to get them to say that they
were abducted and probed.
Oh,
in the guy's like,
okay,
okay.
Okay.
All right.
Here we go.
And it was immediate.
It was immediate.
It was like no one said no.
He goes,
listen man,
I'm a reporter for the snap.
Here's the deal.
There was just a Ufo sighting.
Do you think I could get you to come on
camera and say that you sought?
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And then people would just start
talking.
They were like,
well,
it was bright silver and it was sort of
spinning over the,
uh,
over the hemisphere.
And uh,
what happened was they just give just
lately like detailed accounts.
It's like at this point people been so
poisoned like pop culture and by the
idea of Ufo so they can just recall
because they just have this like,
yeah,
frozen fake idea in their head from 100
movies and they can get just,
Oh yeah,
I remember what happened in that movie I
just yet.
Or there was lights and lights are
detail.
They've
seen it.
I've seen it 100 times.
It was amazing.
They just,
they just lied.
They lied.
Not only did they lie,
they lied and were willing to sign a
waiver saying that they lied and that we
were going to show it on TV.
Credible.
It was nuts.
People love those shit about stories
because they love to be the one to
report everybody.
There's a fascination with like,
you wouldn't know what happened.
Yeah,
and you get the report and then every.
Because everybody focuses on you and
they're like,
what happened?
And so if you're willing to give them
the goods,
people are willing to listen and you get
like a.
You know,
you get a charge out of out of being the
one that told everybody they love it.
Anybody like it's amazing that they're
willing to just make it up just for
that,
for that feeling.
I think people,
there's a lot of people that lived lives
of such shit.
Their lives suck so bad that they almost
believe what they're saying when they
tell you some story about seeing
bigfoot.
Sure.
You know,
it was probably a bear and it was 20
years ago and they were scared and it
was dusk and it was like more.
If he made eye contact with me,
I'll tell you this right now to the day
I die,
I swear on my,
the eyes of my children.
That was a sasquatch and they fucking
believe it,
man.
By the time 20 years have passed and
they've added all kinds of shit.
Man.
That member even told him.
I told him,
you have your memories that you have
from like anything more than like five
years ago.
What?
What is that really?
Do you really mean?
Might remember some really intense shit.
Yeah,
barely.
Barely.
Yeah,
but barely.
I mean,
you could recall data and information,
but how much of that memory can you
really pull out?
I remember making up a story as a kid.
I remember making up a story as a kid
and spending it,
the people until the point where it was
like I would just tell people in detail
for like years from like fifth grade to
like and then one day I was like,
I'm fucked.
I'm like,
I just completely made this up.
I told the story to people about it
because we lived in Minneapolis for
like,
how cold is it getting Minneapolis?
And I was like,
December 20,
fourth of 1989.
It was 74 below zero.
I'm like,
yeah.
And I was like,
it was so cold.
My teacher's ears pros and they fell off
and they're like,
shut up.
I was standing at a bus stop.
We're outside of sacred heart bus came
up.
She didn't have a hat on.
We'd never.
It was like the coolest thing ever.
And she went to touch her left ear and
it fell off.
It was frozen.
And then when she went to grab her,
right,
it fell off in her hand and her ears
fell off.
I saw it the fuck out of here.
I'm like,
yeah,
that's what happened is real.
Like one day I was just like telling
somebody,
no,
that doesn't sound right.
I'm like,
yeah,
I think I made this shit up.
Like you forgot what I made it up
because I made it up for that feeling.
But when,
you know,
when you first discovered the feeling,
even 10 years old and you tell someone
some wild shit and they'd go,
what?
You're like,
oh,
that feels kind of good.
And so like it was like a 10 year old
version of that that I told when I was
10,
11,
12.
And then when I'm like 14,
15,
I was like,
I don't think I saw this ad.
I think I was 10 years old and I told
you that my teacher's ears fall off.
Do you think that's what happened with
Oj?
That.
Oh,
that his story,
it was just became almost like
indiscernible,
like maybe this is real.
I don't know what happened.
Um,
and I think that is such a crazy reality
that we have,
that we had that figure in our lifetime
that is a spectacular climb and fall.
There's almost,
that's almost unparalleled when you
really think about it to be a heisman
trophy winning,
like unblock top,
top tier world class athlete and
celebrity.
That parlayed into this awesome TV movie
career.
I mean he was at rental car.
I was like,
dude,
that is,
that's it.
Like that's basically,
that's the top of the mountain when it
comes to an athlete's career.
Yeah,
transitioning into,
that's,
that's a model to follow.
Like it had to do it.
And then for that to be the guy fucking
just butchered people.
He says crazy.
Cut them up over some pussy and then
stole wanting to steal back his shit.
That's my shit man.
Let it go son.
And now he's locked up for another.
Like he,
he,
he beat the craziest,
like the crime that we all know.
It's so crazy.
He'd beat that charge and went back for
some dumb shit.
Some dumb beyond dumb shit on taking his
memorabilia back with the station.
Was that what it was?
The palace station.
I station man first on the UFC.
That was one.
That was my first Las Vegas Gig.
Really?
You played the power station?
The power station.
Wow.
That's locals,
right?
Those are locals and people from out of
town that don't know any better.
Yeah.
That's the place to where like you,
uh,
or people actually don't like to gamble,
like to go to those places.
They just liked to gamble because they
have better odds.
Yeah,
that's true.
Yeah.
Because if you go to like the Bellagio
or is one of the big casinos,
mgm grand or something like that,
they kind of,
I think,
you know,
they're probably better at getting your
money.
Yeah,
that Shit's mostly bullshit.
It seems like it's just,
Oh,
we're here.
Let's go spend some money.
Quick,
man.
It's weird.
I've seen people lose hundreds of
thousands of dollars watched.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
What's coming to Vegas?
I've been going to vegas doing UFC since
2000.
One,
2002.
That's when I started going to watch
2001.
I started going right after nine slash
11.
I saw Tito Ortiz took on Vladimir Matt,
you shouldn't go.
That was right after September 11.
You called that?
No,
no,
no.
I was uh,
I wasn't in the audience.
So realauction yeah.
Didn't,
didn't work for them back then.
I was just,
I was just a fan and a.
So from then you know,
to,
to 2012.
I've seen some people throw some crazy
money away,
man.
Just a weird place when you have one
area where all the rules are different.
One area,
one area,
one area we could fucking drink whenever
you want one spot.
We've got this spot and you can just
fucking 6:00
in the morning and have a drink.
You don't ever have to leave your hotel.
Dude.
We got a giant hotel where you can
wander around.
We have world class food here in every
way you can gamble.
If they had a strip club in the major
hotels,
it would really be the perfect place.
A trip club and a pool hall.
I become never have to.
You never have to go anywhere.
The Strip club would be that.
That'd be like $100,000,000
a year revenue generated,
probably would,
you know,
it'd be too much,
too much,
too dark to deck and make people leave,
you know,
make people go somewhere.
But there's places they have in Vegas,
they're like the biggest strip clubs in
the world.
Did you know her enormous that like,
you know,
Macau,
China.
Do you know what I'm talking about?
It's a place in China.
Yeah.
No,
that's theirs.
That's their vegas.
That's their gambling,
uh,
that,
that place that China use place does
something like three or four times the,
uh,
the,
the money that Vegas does,
like it blows it away.
Is it because of volume or because they
gamble more?
Uh,
I would think it's a combination of two
Chinese gamble hard,
dude.
I didn't know they,
they build the places in Vegas.
A lot of them build it just to the
standard.
Yeah.
Two for the child.
For agent sway.
Yeah.
And this,
uh,
the numbers of the floors are important.
Yeah.
The way it's set up as important and
there's things that aren't lucky.
They make sure that they do it in
accordance with what,
what Chinese people think is lucky.
Mgm,
mgm used to be.
Remember what the entrance of the mgm
was when it opened.
What was the main entrance was a lion's
mouth.
You were walking in it.
Bad luck for them.
Right.
And the Asians were like,
no thanks.
And they're like,
hold on a second,
we're going to take that shit down right
now.
They got the line right.
That's right.
They don't want to walk through a lion's
mouth.
Yeah.
Well that's because in their country and
get eaten by a tiger,
you know,
they just took that line out of the mgm,
the law and that was living in there.
It's the most depressing thing.
Terrifying.
And they attacked the trainer there
once.
Oh really?
Yeah.
There's a,
there's video of it.
Lion attacks trainer at MGM.
Yeah.
It's pretty fucked up and Polish it up.
See if I can find it.
Yeah,
they're the.
I think my favorite is the shark tank at
Mandalay Bay.
That's amazing.
Most bad ass attraction.
That's a dope ass aquarium setup.
Yeah,
they have a huge tank filled with sharks
and they have these cool ass jellyfish
and the jellyfish are all like under
these psychedelic neon lights and
they're floating around.
That's a bad ass fish tank is a crazy
video.
It's a bizarre video.
The MGM,
the guys are in the tank with the lot.
Put your hand down so I can see the mgm
guys are in the tank with giant male
lions man and for whatever reason the
lines is just like pitch here.
He gets up.
I don't know what happens.
He just finds the guy week,
you know,
he just.
I bet they're just annoyed man.
They're trapped in this fucking box with
these little pink bitches that think
that they could survive.
Like why do you think you could stand
next to a lion?
I don't care if you raise that thing
with a bottle.
Look at the size that look at.
He just decides that Jack,
the dude like,
look at that man.
Just decides a fuck that dude up for no
reason that a female jumps in and even
if their plan,
even if he's playing,
it's like whatever,
man.
Look at him,
he's just goes after that guy for no
reason and that guy was like,
oh shit.
And the other guy,
for whatever reason,
he's listening to the other guy,
so the other guy gets in between the two
of them and the lion chases him.
The guy almost gets jacked.
Wow.
How scary.
It must have been two people took that
shit with their cell phones.
Look at the size of his fucking head and
all that crazy hair around them.
What are nutty animal man?
That's crazy.
I did not hear about this.
Well,
nobody died,
but it was a freak moment and you know
if they have that hair around their neck
just so that other lions can't kill
them.
I thought it was interesting with the
girl line kind of like was like,
Hey,
stop what you're biting a human like did
you notice that?
She kind of jumped bond had been like,
can I bite him to shit?
Got Crazy.
If some blood came out and she might
have fucked him up too,
because they're the hunters,
the females at one hunters.
Have you been following this whole thing
with the judge?
Nappy tanoe that got fired Fox business
fast.
That's crazy and the whole is.
I didn't know anything about the Israeli
connection that people pull that pull
that video up.
Okay.
So we can listen to it because it's not
long and it's a shocking judge.
Judge Nepal Tano.
He had a show on Fox business where he
would really be like super honest about
stuff and you know,
really have a,
an astute,
a breakdown of how our political system
really functions and how are the
American public has been lied to from
the beginning and the way he did it is
by posing a bunch of questions.
What if this,
what if that would've been the way he
does it?
Man,
it's,
it's a different video that I was.
Listen to this.
Now that that's a different video,
what you're talking about a,
I'll find that this was the video that
got them fired,
fired.
He got fired the other day for this
broadcast.
Well,
no,
that's,
that's he.
The other video was on that as well.
I see the one that you just pulled up,
but in the other video was being touted
as something that got them fired as
well.
Apparently they were gonna fire them no
matter what,
and this was his,
his go out,
but listen to what he says that
validates an establishment that never
meaningfully changes.
What if that establishment doesn't want
that doesn't have the consent of the
governed.
What if the two party system was
actually a mechanism used to live at so
called public opinion?
What if that were more than two sides to
every issue,
but the two parties wanted to box you
into a corner,
one of their corners.
What if there's no such thing as public
opinion because every thinking person
has opinions that are uniquely his own,
what have what we call public opinion
was just a manufactured narrative that
makes it easier to convince people that
if their views are different,
that there's something wrong with that
or there's something wrong with them.
What if the whole purpose of the
Democratic and Republican parties was
not to expand voters choices but to
limit them?
What if the widely perceived differences
between the two parties was just an
illusion?
What if the heart of the government
policy the same
no matter who's in the White House?
What if the heart of government policy
remains the same?
No matter what the people want?
What if those vaunted differences
between Democrat and Republican?
We're actually just minor disagreements.
What if both parties just want power and
are willing to have young people fight
meaningless wars in order to enhance
that power?
What if both parties continue to fight
the war on drugs just to give
bureaucrats on cops bigger budgets and
more jobs?
What have government policies didn't
change when government leaders did?
What if no matter who won an election,
government stayed the same?
What if government was really a
revolving door for political hacks?
Then and exploiting the people once
they're in charge of both parties
supported welfare,
war,
death,
they allowed some big government.
What if the rhetoric they candidates
displayed on the campaign trail was
jumped after electoral victory?
What if Barack Obama campaign as an
antiwar pro civil liberties candidate
and then wage senseless wars while
assaulting your rights that the
constitution is supposed to protect?
What if George W dot Bush campaign on a
platform of non intervention and small
government and then wage they foreign
policy of muscular military intervention
and a domestic policy,
a vast government borrowing and growth?
What if Bill Clinton declared that the
era of big government was over,
but actually just convince Republicans
like Newt Gingrich,
that they can get what they want at a
big government to what if the
Republicans went along with it?
What if Ronald Reagan spent six years
running for president,
promising to shrink the government,
but then the government grew while he
was in the lighthouse?
What if not withstanding Reagan's ideas
and cheerfulness and libertarian
rhetoric,
there really was no Reagan revolution at
all.
What if all this is happening again?
What if Rick Santorum is being embraced
by voters who want small government even
though Senator Santorum voted for the
Patriot Act for an expansion of Medicare
and for raising the debt ceiling by
trillions of dollars?
What if Mitt Romney is being embraced by
voters who want anyone but Barack Obama,
but they don't realize that Mitt Romney
might as well be Barack Obama on
everything from warfare to welfare?
What if Ron Paul is being ignored by the
media,
not because as it claims he's
unappealing or unelectable,
but because he doesn't fit into the
premanufactured public opinion mold used
by the establishment to pigeon hole the
electorate and create the so called
narrative that drives media coverage of
elections.
What if the biggest difference between
most candidates was not substance but
style?
What if those stylistic differences were
packaged,
the substantive ones to reinforce the
illusion of a difference between
Democrats and Republicans would've met
won Mitt Romney wins and ends up
continuing most of the same policies
that Barack Obama promoted.
What if Barack Obama's to or merely
extensions of those from George W dot
Bush?
What if a government that manipulated us
could be fired?
What if a government that lacked the
true and knowing consent of the governed
could be dismissed?
Now he's getting crazy,
but if it were possible to have a real
game changer,
what if we need a Ron Pole to preserve
and protect our freedoms from the
government?
That's what he got fired for.
What if we can make elections matter
again?
What if we could do something about this
from the arc defending freedom every
night of the week.
So depressing that we're really in a
situation where this is the situation
now where we're really stuck here.
We're really,
this is where we're at 2012 is.
That is absolutely right.
I don't know if that was his final
broadcast,
but it was a very powerful one and that
is powerful stuff.
The other one that he talks about,
he makes connections on nine slash 11
with Israeli.
Like how it's like,
it's really weird to actually watch it.
What was their reason?
What did they announce was the reason
for firing him?
I don't think they did.
I think,
uh,
you know,
the look,
people get fired for all sorts of
different things all the time.
I'm not necessarily sure that he got
fired because of that,
you know,
but that's definitely something he went
pretty fucking.
Was this guy getting farther out?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It was pretty popular.
It should be even more popular now with
the things that he said they're gonna
they're going to take off on the
Internet,
you know,
that that video is going to take off the
Internet already is right.
What is it with the hits on it right
now?
Four hundred and $44,000.
And by the way,
there's a gang of those is not just that
one.
Yeah,
there's a gang of those that are out
there that's not just one person put it
up on Youtube.
Yeah,
it's fucking powerful shit man.
He is absolutely right to.
I mean how would,
how do you fire the government though?
Let's look,
you know,
something's going to happen though.
Something's happening.
You know,
and I think governments recognizing it
as well,
you know,
this is going to be an adjustment is
going to be some.
There has to be because otherwise it's a
dictatorship.
You know,
at a certain point in time when you're
really not doing the will of the people
at all and you're really are suppressing
the people and you really are taking
away liberties.
You really trying to turn us into a
fucking crazy dictatorship.
Really.
Not much different than that.
I don't know if anybody used this shit
without being cynical after you after
Obama,
after or just after you turn a certain
age.
Like I feel like it's all.
I really do feel like it doesn't matter.
Like whoever you vote for,
that nothing is really going to be
different.
No one has ever really like,
you know,
you start hearing the.
When the speeches started coming about,
we're tying to change Hollywood.
I'm not even.
I'm not A.
I'm a Washington outsider.
I'm about to go in there.
We're gonna change it up now.
That's the always the one where you're
like,
that's not going to happen.
Then after a certain age,
you realize it's not gonna happen.
You've realized they're not telling me
the truth.
If Obama wanted to say some really
radical things,
he could have already said it.
You know,
Chris Rock really did this really
fascinating interview recently.
We said that he thinks it'll bomb was
going to wait until his second term.
Then he's going to do some crazy shit.
I'm like,
God,
that sounds like you're wishful
thinking.
You know,
that sounds to me like are you paid
attention to what he has done?
Almost irreversible damage.
That National Defense Authorization Act
that treats the United States like a
battlefield and allows indefinite
suspension or detention of American
civilians with no warrant.
That's insanity.
You don't need that.
We're not falling apart.
We don't have violence in the streets
every day.
We're not in the middle of an Arab
spring situation.
We don't have nuclear bombs dropping on
our city.
What the fuck are you doing?
Instigating or pushing forward those
kinds of laws and legislation.
The number one thing that we're supposed
to be about is the pursuit of liberty.
It's supposed to be liberty and justice
for all.
That's how.
That's how it ends,
right?
With liberty and justice for all.
That's what we want.
And you're taking away liberty for what?
For what are you giving us extra
justice?
Is that why,
you know,
that's bullshit is what it is.
It's 100 percent bullshit.
It's not representative of the people.
It's.
It's sad and it's got change.
It's just how I was a change.
I don't know.
It scares the shit out of everybody.
Right?
Absolutely.
You know that judges are on twitter
under judge nap nap.
Oh really?
Maybe get him on an upcoming podcast.
Things so maybe even talk to us.
Sure.
He'd probably lock us in jail.
I don't know about that.
His heritage nap.
He's just a good palm made.
What's your full name?
What's his name?
Paula autonomy.
I call them nappy Tana because he has an
amputation.
I'm following them now.
He's only got 55,000
followers.
Freedom Watch.
Yeah.
Cancel that shit.
Him and Alex Jones.
We need to get Alex Jones on his podcast
also sometime.
Yeah,
Alex is going to do it.
He'll do it when he's in La.
Again,
in Alex's book and if you have an Alex
on our podcast,
you'll get a view as to what's up.
He's right about a lot of shit,
man.
I mean he's a soldier.
He's out there fucking beating the
bushes.
He daily show the daily show.
He has a whole studio.
The whole.
Yeah.
Studio is pretty fucking impressive.
It shows huge.
It's enormous.
There's a lot of people listen to it.
You know.
It's all doom and gloom though,
man.
Yeah,
I've seen.
I've seen clips of him gloom.
The best show we ever had was the time
of Joey Diaz took over.
Oh,
I remember that.
I remember that day.
Boom,
that we've talked about it too many
times on the podcast.
You'll remember that.
The most glorious things I've ever seen.
I've never been the type of person that
when you drive around and you see like a
hot chick,
like you'll wink at them or give them
kissy faces and anything.
Lately I've been doing it more just
because I realized that because I
realized you pretty much can do that and
you'll never see that person ever again.
They'll never know who you're putting
out a creeper feel creepy ones.
I'd just be like making like silly faces
at them or I don't even worse.
They don't even know you and you're
making silly faces.
It's just funny seeing people's
reactions and I love it,
dude.
How many people?
There's a lot of fear that you're
generating out some bad.
Who you out there,
Bro?
It's mostly laughter.
Laughter,
laughter.
They'll laugh.
Yeah.
Well that's good.
It's just like they look over like what
the fuck's going on over here?
Yeah,
probably that's where you just decided
to be a creep,
but this age.
Yeah.
I don't know why it started.
I think it's because it's.
I saw somebody
do it to somebody else wants and I was
like,
that's hilarious.
Did that person just made that person
like laugh and then drove off it?
Never to see that person again.
So have you ever been around the one guy
who can't hit a check?
You know that guy who you're hanging out
with them and you,
you,
you can't even hang out with them
because they'll just abandon you for a
check?
Yeah.
I remember when I was in an apartment in
Hollywood when I was like 21,
22 and had some friends come out and it
was one of the guys was that guy who
just can't stop.
So when I went to bed I had,
I had my bedroom,
we had like three friends in the living
room and one girl who we all,
we had all gone to school together and I
was offered her.
I was like,
you can sleep in my bed,
like,
not in a creepy way but like,
you can put like a fuck you,
like,
I'm going to try but I'm not going to
make it.
Like,
so anyways.
She was like,
Nah,
I'm good.
Um,
I'll sleep out here.
And I was like,
all right,
like,
you know,
fun.
And then like five minutes later I got
like a,
like a knock on the door and was like,
what's up?
And she's there.
And she was like,
yeah,
he just tried to lick my neck when I
was,
when I went to sleep.
Oh my God.
I was like,
you want to ship in here now?
And she was like,
yeah,
I was like,
okay,
that's cool.
And then I wasn't a creep though.
You didn't try to fuck her.
Did you try to spoon her at all?
I think so.
UHM.
You got to Swat.
I think she swabbed you like get off me.
It definitely didn't happen.
She came for comfort and then you just
know I didn't,
I didn't cheat cuddle with you at all?
No,
I think it was very much like because
when somebody just as leaving,
she was just leaving.
Like that shit was really uncomfortable.
I was going to be like,
well let me extend that feeling for,
you know,
I was just like,
you try to settle into a new level and
then creep slowly.
Honestly,
I can tell you this.
There's a lot of times when I was single
that I didn't pursue that stuff because
I was too tired.
And because you're too tired,
I would just go to sleep.
I was.
Why is that?
Why are you so tired?
No,
I mean like when it was late at night,
like I was a,
I was a hot chick,
what would it be?
I'd be like,
yeah,
I'm gonna.
Go Sleep.
Whoa.
That's weird.
Yeah.
I wrote checked out.
No,
but I'm saying that alcohol,
alcohol,
alcohol is not sober.
Yeah.
There's nothing sadder than having a
whiskey Dick.
Probably.
Maybe I'd be like.
I'd made it totally potential.
Like College.
They think wanna go to sleep right now.
That sounds like the best thing and I
would lay down.
Yeah,
I just got my thyroid checked.
Has got a physical using the same time.
Tommy and I.
It's so funny because he's the fucking
best doctors.
Dr.
Oh,
I thought you were hearing about Brian
getting a physical medical shit.
Did he check your asshole out because he
didn't skip my answer.
I was like,
I cleaned it for hours,
you know,
and brush.
No,
I didn't want to see things that scratch
your asshole and Maxi Pad.
Lupas a loofah.
Sponge Loofah.
I scratched it all on the inside.
That's the important.
And then I didn't do anything.
I did when I was in the shower,
I was testing.
All right,
this is what it's kind of gonna be like,
like I just wanted to like what are they
looking for?
Bumps.
Well they didn't do,
he didn't do it.
No.
They reach it and they look different.
Cancer.
See I was most concerned about my
asshole too,
so I'm really kind of upset that he
didn't.
Why were you most concerned about?
Because I think,
I think that's death would be from.
That would be from assholes that you
will get.
It won't be you smoke cigarettes you,
you worry about.
But I just worry about your.
I have weird ass issues.
We've talked about that,
but he did feel my balls up,
which was weird.
Like guy and he's just like rolling
around in his hand and goes yep,
that's fine.
Did you think that maybe if he jerked
you off you could come?
No,
no,
I had my dick is so small that it gets
checked check,
but I almost want to point it out like I
almost want to be like,
every time I'd get like a physical,
it's more like I want to be like,
you just,
you should see it some other time a
little better than let me check my cock.
He did like the thing where he had to
like pull it out and I'm like one of
those old hippy,
a guitar string,
you know,
where you hold the thing.
They like pulled it out and looked at it
and then he check on it and then took
all these blood tests.
But he's testing me for everything and
then he's like,
all right,
so when you went to all stds,
I'm like,
yeah,
I'm dating a porn star.
And he goes,
Oh,
you are you guys all right,
we can do that.
Brian's office.
You know how it is when you're dating a
porn?
He said is,
he's like,
well,
you should be fine because they get
tested every 20 days.
And I'm like,
Yep,
that's exactly a bit in my act.
And he's like,
oh,
mooch off her tier tests.
I'm like,
yeah,
exactly.
He's a funny doctor.
Then this guy's really good.
And he said,
tell Tom to start sending some hot
chicks.
And I,
and I said,
and I said something really like say his
name on the air on unethical now and
then.
But when we were in the waiting room
where I just paid and everything at that
and I'm about to walk out.
And he goes,
well it's good singer Brian Tell Thomas
said hi.
And I'm like,
okay,
I'm sorry I'm not hot for you.
Or something like that.
And it came out like when it was like
everyone in the room's like,
what the fuck?
And then I'm like,
I'm sorry I'm not pretty enough.
Nevermind kinetic element at the
doctors.
Everybody in that room probably had no
idea what was going on.
So what did he say about your lungs and
cigarettes and stuff.
Like he said,
everything was perfect.
That was good.
Now they're doing the blood tests.
I would like to second that evaluation.
What do they check when they check your
lungs did make you cancer and that's it.
They just like make it a huge deep
breaths.
Why?
They like tests layer.
They listened like all up and down your
chest and your back and then how long
does it take you to die from cigarettes?
I don't know,
man.
It really matters if you.
I think if you have cancer in your
family and I don't have cancer and some
people are genetically just don't get
it.
I think so,
yeah.
I mean there's definitely stories,
right?
Oh,
I know.
A friend's grandparents who lived into
their nineties and smoked and drank and
ate red meat and low.
They just died.
They didn't die of cancer into that old
age.
Well,
they had a good time smiling.
Yup.
Haven't been drinking.
There were some things that I read once.
I don't know if it's documented,
but that 100 percent of all people that
live to be over 100 eat red meat.
Really?
There's never been a documented of a
vegetarian
lives to be over a hundred.
That could be total horse shit.
Don't fucking crazy.
Vegans.
Don't you text me about this company?
Do vegans?
Vegans are there quickest to the
fucking.
The tweet,
the,
the angry tweet,
the angry dietary tweet.
Yeah,
they are.
And the quickest,
Sylvia,
two squiggles.
The diarrhea.
I think a lot of fiber involved.
You're going to be really shit.
And with that Vegan Diet.
I love fucking a good Vegan meal though.
I love that.
A few meals.
I'd drink that Kale shake every day.
That's fantastic.
I have a Kale Salad a few times a week
from a place where it's hard to get
grass fed meat these days,
man.
Apparently all of it's getting consumed
up in northern California.
All the hippies up there.
Love it.
It's all natural meat.
Yeah.
It's way better for you.
You just go to whole foods.
They don't have it.
No,
they're out of it a lot because ups up
north.
Look,
there's only a certain amount of people
that are grown,
grass fed meat and it's become super
popular lately.
So all these,
you know,
it's more popular in Berkeley and San
Francisco I'm sure.
Then down here and retard advil.
So they uh,
they can sell all of their cows up
there.
Why ship them all the way down to Los
Angeles.
So they're having an issue like last
Tuesday though,
the whole foods near me didn't even get
a shipment of grass fed meat.
Wow.
Yeah.
I have to go there on Tuesday to get the
meat.
It's crazy.
That's the only time they taste the
difference like it.
Fuck you.
One hundred percent.
It's a totally different meat.
It's a totally different animal because
the cow that is raised on corn,
they're fat fucks.
They're.
They're marbled.
And it's really delicious.
It's really,
really fucking yummy because all that
fat gets all like a Ribeye from a corn.
A corn raised cow is great because it's
so juicy,
but it's not quite as healthy for you
and it doesn't taste the same when you
get a grass fed rib eye,
there's much less marbling and you got
to cook it quicker because it'll dry
out.
There's much less fat in it.
So it's a.
it's sort of Syria to get better.
God Damn.
It's good though.
It's.
It's totally different.
It's almost like a game he animal not
gain me.
Yes.
It's,
it's,
you know,
it tastes like buffalo or something
almost.
Yeah.
It tastes better.
It tastes like you're eating a healthy
animal.
Yeah.
You know?
There was some steaks I've had where I'm
like,
Oh man,
like you can fill your body kind of
slowing down.
That was not grass fed beef.
Those supposed to be way healthier for
you to something about the actual animal
being healthy.
That like a lot of guys I know a lot of
fighters have switched to grass fed meat
recently.
My,
my buddy,
uh,
Einstein and listen to this all the time
is one of Eddie's black belts,
said his performance really started
increasing when he upped his greens and
unchanged to all grass fed meat.
Really?
So big difference.
Yeah.
It's just healthier,
you know,
it just makes sense that your body would
respond better if you're eating
healthier animals.
Yeah.
It does make sense for fucking up man.
Fucking eat your veggies and fruits.
Fucking up her God damn.
Monsanto fruits and vegetables and crazy
man fat fuck cows and farm grown fish
because all the fish in the ocean or Dan
and you know,
they said that the next hundred years is
going to be the last wild fish in the
world.
Within the next hundred years.
There will be no more wild fish in the
oceans.
What we'll.
We'll have out fish the entire region.
One company also say that.
No,
they think about it from an exponential
growth point of view that there'll be
more people in 100 years.
You know?
I mean,
think about 100 years ago there was only
like a billion people on the planet and
how there are 7 billion,
so it's crazy.
What's it going to be 100 years from
now?
It's going to be 30 billion.
Where are they going to get all their
protein from?
A lot of it's going to be finished.
It's easy to catch and they're going to
go.
Once they.
They know they're gonna,
they're gonna fucking just troll
everything.
They suck all that fucking fish out of
there.
They're going to eat whales.
They're going to do everything they can
eat,
they're going to see everything that
humans can consume,
and then 100 years now we're going to
have to figure it out.
It would just be an empty ocean because
that would be crazy.
That would be crazy.
Could you imagine if we actually kill
everything in the ocean within a
thousand years if people lived to be
1000 years,
why is that outside the realm of
possibility?
Yeah.
It was something I tweeted earlier today
about the garbage patch.
Some lady went to the garbage patches in
the middle of the Pacific Ocean.
For folks who don't know bigger than
Texas,
there's a giant hunk of garbage.
All plastic that's Kinda caught together
in this one swarm.
It's like caught up,
I guess in like the way the tides go is
one area where it's collected where it's
enormous.
It's bigger than the state of Texas,
which takes like more than a data drive
through.
All right,
so that's how much garbage is out there
and it's just getting bigger and it's
gonna keep getting bigger forever.
Is that a homeless person's heaven?
You think?
They all talk about it as if it's like
Disney road never had to pick.
I think the plastic breaks down though.
I think that's part of the issue is that
the salt water breaks it down for like
Jelly,
like little particles and it's really
fucked.
It's not like,
just like stuff floating.
Then you can scoop up.
Becomes like almost liquid.
Yeah.
It's fucked up man.
We're so creepy.
I'm thinking about what we do we kill
all the rhinos.
We fucked the ocean over.
We eat all the fish.
We throw our garbage in it.
You would drive by um,
trash.
What do they call it?
Trash plants.
You know,
talking to you.
Yeah,
sure.
Man.
Landfills.
Yeah.
And you see how like,
they're like,
you know,
they're a higher altitude than like the
street level,
you know,
that's just going to keep growing like
one day that's going to be like a
building of God,
you know?
It's like mountains,
like hills.
The Stan hope and I filmed the finale of
the man show in a garbage dump.
Really?
Yeah.
Because the girls were trying to con us
into taking them to an island.
There was two of the girls that were in
the old man show and we didn't get along
with them so well and they were like,
Adam and Jimmy used to take us to the
Bahamas.
We should do that.
You should take it to the Bahamas.
We'll film the final scene there.
And then we thought about it and doug
and I were like,
we should do it at a garbage.
And I was like,
we think about it,
man.
I wanted to do it in a garbage dump in
New Jersey.
I wanted to do it like the stinkiness
grossest dump.
I said,
you know,
if you're at home and you're watching a
series,
two assholes hanging out with girls who
never fuck you on,
you know,
in a place where you can never afford to
go to,
you know,
hanging on the wall.
How is that fun for you?
I go be much more fun for you to watch
us in a dump.
So much funnier to.
So we,
yeah,
that's what I felt like they were so mad
at us.
It was gross and their defense,
it was really funny that they ask for it
though.
First they were like,
what's up with the Bahamas?
And yeah,
they wanted to go garbage.
No.
Well,
you know,
it's,
I don't blame a man that culture,
the hot chip culture of asking for
things and then they would like,
you know,
rub the writers shoulders and you're
going to put us in a scene,
you know,
that kind of thing.
That's gross shit though.
Yeah.
Well,
so that was the culture of it.
There was a lot of growth going on,
but sure not none of those as groceries.
That garbage dump Netapp for all of it.
Fucking foul.
So bad.
We were eating lunch and it's fucking
garbage dust floating in the air and it
was on Catalina.
Catalina has a giant garbage do.
They really enormous kind of a trip.
It's a bummer man.
That whole society.
Then I think a lot of our garbage goes
out there.
That sucks.
Yeah,
it does suck.
Catalina for the,
for folks who don't know is island
outside of the coast of Los Angeles.
Fourteen miles off the coast.
14.
I've never gone into.
You do.
You do?
Yeah.
That's cool man.
There's no cars driving around.
Just golf carts and shit.
Yeah,
it's weird.
It's big enough that you could actually
live there.
You can go on a ferry or a helicopter.
Yeah,
I took the helicopter.
Maybe that's where we should put our
compound.
The next year.
That helicopter company crashed.
Really?
Yeah.
Helicopter Cadillac.
And somebody died.
Yeah.
It would've been new though,
right?
No,
no,
no.
You can't stop me.
You can't hold me down.
Y'All can't see me.
Not me,
bro.
Tell you what,
man.
Fuck that.
Hell God.
Grabbed that fucking Pupello my hand and
I'll spit it myself.
I got heart.
I got a lot of heart.
You can't measure.
You can't fuck up my opera and the size
of the dog in the fight.
It's the size of the fight in the dog.
This dog can hunt.
Would you live on Catalina?
But if we've got a giant piece of land
and Catalina and that's where we set up
our compounds,
I'd have to check it out first because I
don't like not having best buys and
things like that.
It's totally true.
We should.
We should seriously look into a good
place where we can all move here.
Just everybody outside of La,
but close enough.
We'll just get a giant chunk of land.
Get a few hundred acres.
Yeah.
All of us build houses there.
Do you not dope.
That would be if we could have our own
like m night Shyamalan Ding dongs
village.
Debbie Austin,
the lake.
I like lake.
How cool would it be for real if we all.
We got everyone that we know that it's
cool and we decided we're all going to
be in property and build houses there.
Yeah.
And all your friends live in like in the
neighborhood.
And fucking awesome.
If you live down the street and Chrysler
was there and
Eddie Bravo lived up the hill down
the hill and Dunkin lived over there and
already lives over it.
That would be fucking awesome.
Yeah.
That's how cults get started though.
That's what happens.
Yeah,
that would actually be the most.
But we talked about Christina and
because she also
loves a burt's wife really in the way
and that way you know what's out there.
It's Valentine's Day by the way.
I'm doing.
I just realized I'm doing it for 20
show.
I'm doing a four slash 20 show in,
in Atlanta.
Where's that place I'm doing at Brian?
Uh,
it's on my twitter thing.
It just Atlanta,
Georgia.
And your twitter doesn't want to pull up
on my laptop.
It looks weird man.
When I turn to looking at doing some
nice.
I'm doing someplace in Atlanta some high
times for 20 though.
It's for 20.
I've never done it for $20 per barrel.
Nat Cole Tabernacle you is called the
PTAB.
Fucking silly goose.
You will.
You might be the silliest goose goose's
tabernacle.
Yeah.
But that's on 4:20.
I want to,
I want to do my special there,
but I don't also have enough time,
but it would be the place to do it
because um,
the uh,
you know,
Atlanta fucking crowds are awesome all
the way.
One of the most underrated cities in the
country for sure.
And they have a great comedy community.
There's that punchline.
Atlanta has a great community.
I love the uh,
the laughing skull.
I haven't been great too.
I heard that's great.
Laughing skull.
Is that the vortex?
And I think that's in mid town and that
is um,
that's like it's seats 74,
75.
So it's like the ice house,
like the second stage and um,
that is a great tool.
My favorite clubs to play in the ice
house Friday by the way folks,
we try to do the ice house whenever I'm
in town.
March is going to be the shit.
We're going to do a gang of them on in
March because I'm,
I'm home a lot in March to and have a
lot of fucking ice house shows.
We're going to do a lot of full
weekends,
Friday and Saturday whenever we can.
But Tommy bonds will be involved in
this.
Yeah man.
Fuck yeah.
Fuck you did a shit next week.
I'm actually recording my new album and
you're going to one at the comedy works
in Denver was one of the greatest clubs
in the history of doing.
There's two clubs I'm doing the South
Club.
That's great also.
Yes.
That's awesome too.
That's the uh,
that's a bigger place.
They have a balcony.
Yeah,
they do.
If you are in Denver,
we'd there too when?
December 20.
We hit,
we hit.
We'd somewhere in that place.
Really?
Yes.
Look guys,
to find it next time we go home to my
show.
Look for the weed and where,
um,
uh,
what you say the game dictates a wow.
It is this month,
which is February,
right?
February.
And it's,
it's the,
it's a Friday,
the 24th and Saturday the 25th.
I'm beautiful.
I'm recording a new album at the comedy
works south.
I tweeted the link.
If you go to Tom Cigar Seg,
you are a.
yeah,
you gotta go,
come out.
It'll be fucking so much fun if you
never seen Tommy.
He's way funnier as a standup comedians
talking on a podcast.
Don't be.
Don't confused for
a while.
He's kind of monotone.
It's kind of sexy.
Find his voice sexy.
Yeah,
you told me.
Oh,
but so anyway,
folks,
24th,
25th,
26th,
24th,
25th,
23rd to 25th.
But the recording is the 24th and 20.
Who putting out your cd?
Uh,
well that's actually one of the things
I'm actually thinking of doing it
myself.
Do it,
do it yourself.
We'll pump the shit out of it up here.
That's what I want to know is hilarious.
You know,
tom and I met a long time ago when I was
doing the maximum tour with Charlie
Murphy and John [inaudible] and what we
do is we go to these different places
and they would have like a local guy
opened up for us.
Everyone that opened up for us was
really funny.
It was really good,
like local talent because it was the
maximum bud light comedy tour and they
really did a good job of casting the
local guys.
But when we did Phoenix,
Tommy wasn't even local.
Just somehow or another he got involved
in this.
And uh,
he was one of those guys where he went
up and I went,
Holy Shit.
I go,
this guy is fucking funny.
And it was dark and it was really well
written and we became,
we became besties ever since then.
That was fun.
And that's actually the thing I was
telling you is that every time I've
opened for you since then,
your crowds are always the shit.
So that's fine.
I'm totally a pleading to the Joe Rogan
come out.
It's always been.
You guys are always amazing audience.
Colorado's my plates.
Everybody knows that I fucking love
Colorado.
If I could convince my fucking crazy
wife,
eventually I will be back in Colorado.
I was the shit that place calls me.
I'll be back.
I got that.
That club,
Wendy is awesome.
She's my favorite club owner in the
history of club owner.
She's the shit.
She is awesome.
She's in.
She owns and runs both of them.
She's just a Badass woman.
Coolest fuck real fan of comedy.
A real friend to comedy or you know,
she has an open mic program that's
better than anybody's in the country or
anybody that I've ever been involved
with ever in my whole time in comedy.
When you do,
when you do comedy works,
um,
they'll have like a,
you'll work with different people
through the weekend,
right?
Like a different people didn't show.
And um,
other local guys that will open for you
are all headliners.
Yeah.
You have just headliners opening for
you.
They're great.
The whole show is fucking.
She takes care of guy.
She pays them well.
Her food is great.
Especially in south south.
She has a gourmet restaurant.
Oh,
Jesus is fucking phenomenal.
Really good.
God Damn.
I love Colorado snow and his fuck there
though.
80 degrees here.
Socket.
But snow is awesome when you don't have
to go anywhere.
Remember those times when you go out
your back porch and you just fucking
here.
Nothing.
Knowing the way sound just gets absorbed
and snow.
Yeah.
I love it.
Some great fucking times.
I still want to live in it.
I just.
But I do like visiting snow.
I like visiting it too.
I would like to get a house somewhere
where it's cold,
you know,
where I could visit on occasion and you
know,
I just have to get some more baller
money,
but now I'm fucked because it looks like
fear factor is going to fucking bite it.
What it's over.
I thought it was like some of the best
ratings ratings dropped that much down.
Well,
there's a bunch of issues.
I think some of the,
one of the issues is a,
let's be honest,
it's a bit low brow and uh,
NBC is trying to have quality
programming like the author uses
serious.
I think so,
yeah.
I think there's issue number.
They haven't,
they haven't decided yet.
I think it looked they've got
appointment,
you know,
I see what you're trying to do.
You know,
I don't know,
Hayden,
I love doing it just because I love the
guys that I work with.
I Love David Horwitz and Matt
[inaudible] units and Rupert and all the
people that all will be Thompson.
The director,
the other people that I've worked with
were really fucking awesome people.
They're really fun to be around.
It's like a family and I miss them,
you know,
the five years that I didn't work with
them and then I'm working with them
again for this short season.
It was really fun,
but it's not my favorite thing to do.
I'm good at it.
I've been doing it for a long time.
I know how to,
I know how to host a game show,
but I prefer doing stand up and work out
for the UFC and this.
They should move that show to hbo had
needed it.
Like you're eating fucking fish from
Janice and I think it's over.
And you know,
the other thing was like,
I was telling them that the donkey loads
were too much.
I was like,
you can't do this.
We can't do this.
Like BC approved it.
He approved it and I was like,
just because they approved it doesn't
mean you should be doing this.
Like seriously?
You could see that when I'm the voice of
reason when I'm the one who's telling
you we're going too far.
That's it.
Yeah.
Like what is happening here?
It's just they got a little crazy.
Do you want her to have an awesome show?
You know,
whatever it was,
it was a fun thing while it lasted and I
honestly believe that these new episodes
were better than any of the ones we ever
did before.
I haven't enjoyed it.
I don't see anything wrong with it and I
think it's silly that NBC went and did
that because they,
all their other shows are hurting bad.
They suck.
That Whitney show just got horrible
reviews or ratings.
I watched it the other day.
It was not good,
but you know,
it's hard.
It's hard to do a good sitcom.
It's hard to do it right.
And you know,
I heard she's a funny standup.
I never seen her perform before,
but I heard that Chris Lee is a funny
comic as well and you know,
he's buddies with Brian.
I never seen him.
He's funny as well,
so you know,
how is it that they can have to really
funny people and not have a funny show?
A lot of times there's just too many
cooks in the kitchen.
A lot of times they're trying to
accomplish something and trying to get a
vibe going.
They're trying to find their footing.
They believe in it though,
because they renewed it for another
season.
Yeah,
no,
they're both funny.
People are funny people.
You take some wild man.
I,
I really enjoyed my time on news radio,
but I got a real deep respect for the
craft of creating a television show,
you know,
and that's one of the reasons why I
never did it again.
One of the reasons why I never get it
again.
It was,
first of all,
I knew that the guys that I was working
with were incredibly talented and it's
such,
Paul Simms,
the executive producer was such an
interesting and intelligent guy and his
sensibilities were so out there.
I knew that after like working with him,
it was going to be really hard to do
another sort of Sitcom,
a real mainstream.
Even if it's a successful one,
it's hard to do crap,
you know,
you realize that,
um,
that,
how much writing is everything,
everything.
It's every,
you see these shows that are so good and
you're like,
Holy Shit,
I shouldn't say it's everything because
good writing was shit delivery and shit,
Shit.
Comics and shit.
Actors is not good either,
but it's a huge part of the problem and
part of the equation Rather.
And you need real eccentrics to,
to running.
One of the things that these guys were
there,
none of them were still.
There's a couple of them that were
standups,
you know,
that we're on the staff,
but for the most part they were just
really bright,
silly guys who knew how to put together
something funny.
It's fucking rare.
The for every matt stone and Trey
Parker,
there's 100 pretenders,
you know,
at least for at least one anymore and
you can get caught on one of those
sitcoms where you just like,
you're reading the script and like,
what the fuck am I doing?
Man?
Those intangibles to like a show airs
and sometimes it just gets legs,
peanut were drawn to it,
you know?
And then sometimes you'll feel like
everything's right.
Like we got the scripts are great.
We've got great actors every now and
then,
people don't respond to it,
man.
That's Paul.
Yeah,
I mean a lot of times it's who's the
production company and what kind of pull
they have with the network where they
decide to put the show,
but I w I would definitely do another
acting gig.
I really enjoyed doing that.
A movie with Kevin James,
the zookeeper movie.
That was a lot of fun,
but it was mostly fun because Kevin and
I have been friends since we were really
young and to to do a movement even
though it was a silly kids movie.
Yeah,
it was fun.
It's fun.
It's fun to act.
It was fun to do.
You know the thing with Leslie Bibb and
the,
you know the chick from Talladega
nights.
I was like,
this is kind of crazy.
I'm acting with the girlfriend Talladega
nights.
I hadn't done any acting in fucking 10
years,
so it was weird.
That was fun.
I would totally do something like that
was totally do a sitcom or something fun
act again,
but for the most part,
one of the weirdest things about being a
comic is that everybody wants to put you
into some acting situation.
Where are you going to do something
that's not nearly as funny as your act?
That's true.
Yeah.
Or you can see it.
Like when you audition,
they were like,
like,
punch it up or you change it,
you'll add something.
It'd be like,
that was really funny.
You're like,
well yeah,
I kind of have to do this a lot.
Yeah,
you gotta sometimes stuff up.
Sometimes they get mad and I got yelled
at one time too.
Would they say I'm the guy laughed and
then we did it.
We did it again,
and he was like,
that's just rude man.
I was like,
what?
He was like,
that's rude.
And he meant it was rude and I tagged
the line,
you know,
I made up a line.
Whoa.
And he laughed the first time and then
he was like,
it's really rude.
You need to drop that.
And I was like,
Whoa,
fuck him.
He fucked me up so badly that we did the
third take.
And I was like,
yeah,
okay.
Like I didn't even move my face.
So it was a weak bitch.
Yeah.
And I was like,
you just laughed at it,
man.
Like everybody laughed at it.
That's 100 percent ego right there.
Yeah,
he's the,
he wasn't even the,
um,
he was just a casting guy.
He wasn't a director or the producer on
it.
He was just like,
well,
he's trolling camera then.
Yeah,
you know,
whatever it was saying,
it's rude.
He's an idiot.
That was one of the coolest things about
news radio is that Paul Sanders would
let us make up entire scenes for scene.
Didn't work day fully.
It was like the secret producer on the
set.
He would just like,
rewrite a scene,
really completely do it differently.
Dave.
Always a genius.
His,
his,
uh,
ability to like see scenes and see jokes
and see like,
you know,
his sketch background from kids in the
hall and created a lot of sketches,
a great writer.
Awesome.
You know,
he got off track with his life and you
know,
had a lot of hard times we had him on
the podcast once.
Talk about is a fascinating,
fascinating story of caution,
a cautionary tale,
you know,
for it to happen if you're involved in a
terrible relationship,
it goes wrong and you know,
you have spiteful ex wife and the poor
guy man,
it's really horrendous,
you know,
and that led to all sorts of other
issues as well.
But as a,
as a writer and as a like a guy who like
because as a comedian he said,
gene,
just talented guy,
but brilliant.
Just a brilliant,
really interesting,
funny guy.
Really Smart Guy.
She's getting back on and he was,
I'd love to have him back on and help
his comedy because I haven't heard
anything about heard him.
I saw him driving one day and that's,
that's sad drive.
Well I know that he had some setbacks
are just trying.
I mean he can't go to Canada at all if
he goes to Canada.
Bill arrested him now.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
It was like some crazy amount of money
that he had a show that took off for a
little while.
You got the pilot got picked up,
then it got canceled,
so.
Oh yeah,
I saw that.
I saw a commercial for it.
It's a hard fucking world,
dude.
It is,
The world are.
Trying to create a Sitcom is not fun.
No,
no,
and the odds of you being in there so
many people out there trying to do it.
Oh,
I've written a couple.
Have you ever done a couple of scripts?
Yeah,
pilots.
Yeah.
It's like,
I don't know.
The other thing is naturally the brain
just pulling your hair out and then you
rewrite it so many times in some reason
they're like,
yeah,
you need to make some more changes.
Like I've already written it fucking 40
times,
but not only that,
by the way,
they will never let you create your own
shop because if you create your own
show,
you own the show and if you own the
that's fucking billions.
They have that thing locked down.
The only people who can own shows and
have be show runners and be executive,
those people are already deep,
deep,
deep in the business.
There's very little room for some new
new guy who hates his own show.
You know,
they,
you know,
they have.
You have to be paired up,
but some dude was already production
company.
They know what's at stake there and you
have your own thing.
Yeah.
You can't just come to them
independently and say,
Hey,
NBC,
I,
my name is Tom Score.
Me and my buddy wrote a sitcom.
I'm going to be the creator and
executive producer.
He's going to be the director.
Is that cool with you?
Yeah.
You guys are creative.
Come on in no way because that's a money
train there.
They're giving you a free ticket on the
money train.
You know you get like some Roseanne
style syndication money or Seinfeld
syndication money.
They know what's involved in that.
A successful show.
So they got,
they got that situation I'll locked up.
That's one of the reasons why so many of
those shows suck.
You know,
they got the same dudes feeding people
the same slop.
You know,
there's like,
if you look at like the showrunners of
certain,
like hit shows,
there's like two and a half man.
This dude does like a gang of them.
The one that Charles Flores brought
brawling with.
That guy does like the big bang and.
Yeah.
He's fucking Mike and Molly like at his
too.
He doesn't ask them with that makes
ridiculous money.
God.
Yeah.
He's got it locked up.
Wow.
Yeah.
Dude owns hits television.
Hit when you have loved to see the
arguments with him and Charlie Sheen on
DVD one.
It'd be great if somebody fell.
Somebody on the two and a half men set,
filmed some of the arguments.
I'm sure they have that.
Fuck.
I wish.
I would love to see that.
I just have to wait to fucking Egos,
man.
You know,
I think that's the guy who also got a.
do you remember Brett Butler?
Do you remember her?
[inaudible]?
Do you remember when she was a big TV
star?
She had a show.
I don't remember her.
What the fuck was that show?
God Damn it was Brett Butler show.
No,
no,
no.
He's aging something.
Caroline no,
fuck man.
Grace under fire.
While she was like,
she was,
you know,
she was fucking big time man.
You know,
she was the star of a Sitcom.
Yeah.
And she apparently just got crazy ego
bullshit went through and she threw a
soda in his face and said,
if you fuck your wife the same way,
you no wonder why she left you.
Whoa.
And that was it.
They pulled the plug on that bitch.
She's homeless.
Yeah.
Now she's vanished off the face of the
earth.
I mean,
she was an enormous star Dude.
She was enormous man.
And she was also an enormous star as a
standup comedian.
You know,
she was really charismatic.
You seen the homeless pitcher over?
She's.
Yeah,
she's a real hallmark for real honest.
They interviewed her and she's just,
she looks like she got to pull that up.
I want to see this video and it says,
the Golden Globe nominated actress who
struggled with drug addiction went broke
after in 1993 to 1998 Sitcom ended.
It's run on ABC.
Oh my gosh.
Crazy.
Brett Butler,
t two t's.
You serious?
One 10 Butler,
oh my God.
The actress,
a Golden Globe nominee for a role in
1993,
1998 comedy series,
struggled with substance abuse while
starring on the show,
which was in the top 10 for two seasons.
The Chuck Lorre created show was
canceled in 1998 after she was asked to
leave the set because of her drug use.
Yeah,
she threw a drink in his face.
My friend was working on the set.
He also worked on one of them,
one of the shows that I worked on on
news radio and he said,
she said in her,
Oh,
you fuck you up.
Same way you run
fire was one of ABC Vegas.
Whatever happened to the star.
Rhett Butler.
Sadly we have found out she is living in
a homeless shelter and tonight she tells
me what it is like to hit rock bottom
and Hollywood.
I almost died like Michael Jackson.
I was dying of addiction.
I would be in hell.
Bread had it all.
A hit show on prime time TV,
two years and the top 10.
Kimmy,
she made millions and lived in a
mansion.
A tough talking woman with a wild temper
and killing herself with drugs.
Was it a drug or alcohol?
Your addiction?
Everything but crack and noodles.
Pretty much.
I had A.
I had a variety of things given to me by
doctors and other things.
I'm not doing it to be coy,
but I'm not going to go through the uh,
you know what I did?
I did it till the wheels came.
You just go up to your room right now
and you don't come back down until you
love your brother.
Grace under fire was a working class.
Calm.
Done in the same vein as Roseanne and
mad about you now on DVD.
It was produced by funny man,
Chuck Lorre greater up to an event and
the Big Bang Theory,
it was filmed here on the same studio.
Lot is set at stage 14 where Christina
applegate up all night is now.
You said you hope you've been forgiven.
What would you hope you've been forgiven
for?
Making someone's day miserable over the
choice of a word in 22 minutes show a
lot of the times I've been an ass and
didn't even think I was like,
I'd call my managers know there's white
limo out here for an award show and
they'd say,
oh my God,
don't get in it.
And it should've said,
you ungrateful cracker.
Go get in the car,
go to the show.
They'll drop you out back
because she wanted the black one.
Is that what some people have?
Weird things like that.
Yeah.
All these great white hope rehabs.
The one in Malibu I called muffins were
they had a sous chef and collage class
and I'm going,
you're kidding.
And you know some won't give you sugar
and coffee and they give you drugs and
other ones.
It's just this bizarre.
$30,000
bucks a month and a lucky when you don't
die.
And people used to come up and say,
I too am a survivor of so and so and I
want to go look,
if you don't wear the t shirt,
you'll have more fun.
She left Hollywood for a farm in Georgia
where she lived with her 15 pets,
but then the money ran out and one of
Hollywood's biggest stars had to live in
a homeless shelter.
Now Brad is making a comeback,
returning to stand up this weekend and
alleys downtown comedy club.
Want to make a comeback to be Nancy
grace nightmare.
I really feel like an old dog though.
It's almost like I was a horse that ran
in the derby once the kids were coming
and going,
are you still doing this?
I think it something to do with me and
living through it.
I don't think about what I survived.
I hope I forgive.
I hope I'm forgiven and I'm just really
glad that I think things are funny and
there's no end to that and bread has
even more to reveal.
Tomorrow.
She tells me her plans for a big TV.
It creeps me out.
She got hooked on drugs.
The she creeps me out,
but you know,
just as much to lady talking to her,
I don't feel like I know anything about
her while she's talking and she's,
Oh,
she's beautiful.
She's beautiful.
She seems real nice.
I don't know a goddamn thing about her
not getting anything out of her.
That reminds me of the first time I
bought drugs.
The first time they ever bought drugs.
Tell me what you remember.
Remember the first time you ever been
married?
He told me that you had a story.
I met the first time ever about drugs.
I was in high school and I went to a
small high school so I was trying to be
like,
not make a thing to ask about it at
first,
you know,
because you don't want it to get around
and like be a.
So you were curious?
Yeah,
I wanted to try stuff but I didn't know
who to ask because if you ask like at a
small school you're like,
I could blow up real fast.
That's how Gospel traveled.
So my friend
Steve had just transferred from like the
big high school,
like from high school but like 5,000
kids.
And so it was like a weekend.
I was like,
let's get a sack.
And I think we had just seen menace to
society and we were like,
it was up.
But we were trying to totally hardcore
guys.
I'm like pulling the hat to the side,
be like he's Buddhist.
No,
but I think,
uh,
you know,
a lot of like throwing swag into shit
and being like,
you know,
hey,
it was good to sac.
You get your blackness on.
Definitely feeling it.
14 like what's up dude?
This shit.
I got your back making shit up.
Little too white,
right?
Yeah.
And so comfortable with your existence.
Totally.
And then,
uh,
he's like,
I'll hook.
I know the guy.
So this is like a Saturday night,
this long green,
like old school seventies Cadillac pulls
up and he's like,
that's the dude and this guy rolls the
window down.
And he was like,
Yo,
get in the back.
And I was like,
all right,
cool.
We get in the back and thinking like
that's where it goes down.
And uh,
Steve Steve's like,
Yo,
this is white pete.
And I was like,
what's up White Pete?
Like,
and then he was called White Pete
because they needed to give him a
distinction for his name because he was
the only white guy that ran with his
crew.
Right.
And he was like,
we didn't have driver's licenses,
so he was like exactly what we want at
that moment where we want it to be in a
couple of years.
Like he had like the whole unit,
like the oversized white tea and like,
you know,
go chain.
Yeah.
And fucking like fate.
And he was like,
what's up?
I'm white people.
He talked like snoop dogg almost.
Right?
And so we're like,
all right.
I thought he was like,
so we're going to go get it now.
I was like,
go get what I thought were just doing
this in the car.
Wouldn't go get that sac man.
I'm like,
oh,
okay.
So we start driving,
we go 30 minutes in the car,
we go to the next town over,
which is Fort Pierce,
which is definitely a shittier place.
Right.
So we're driving through for peers and
we go from a main street to like single
lane highways.
You know,
in Florida there's like,
Oh yeah,
we're on a busy.
Then we go to a single lane that has
like canals on each side.
Oh yeah.
And we drive it and then we go from that
to a dirt road and then the dirt road
off of that dirt road.
Like we're driving down like this is
some forensic files.
Shit like we're going to end up on.
There's a lot of woods.
Yeah.
Lot of brush groves,
that kind of shit.
And I was like fuck man.
And at this point like I'm thinking
about like menace to society and I'm
like I want to be in that right now,
but I'm feeling like I'm feeling really
white.
Really scared.
And so now it's night and it is,
you know,
it's like,
because he came over in the evening
already,
so it was pitch black outside and we're
on a dirt road off of a dirt road.
Like you can scream,
there's nobody gonna hear Shit.
And on the dirt road gravel path,
I see a light and the light is from a
trailer because we pull up to the
trailer and we get out and it's me,
Steve and white Pete and we knock on the
door,
that trailer and this dude opens the
door and he has this black guy has like
six dreadlocks.
Each dreadlock is like a size of like a
king size snickers bar.
And he's got snicker bars coming out of
his hair and he's like,
what's up pat?
Pat?
And he's like,
what's up White Pete?
And they give each other a hug.
And I was like,
oh fuck,
like no,
this really is like totally menace to
society shit.
Right?
But I'm told so trying to be cool about
it,
like so trying to be cool about it.
And then he's like,
these white boys looking for sac.
And he's like,
yeah,
we could do that.
So we go into,
mind you,
we're looking for $20 and we drove.
And how long has it taken?
This is from this point.
It's like we're already 30 miles south
city.
We started.
Would you just say like,
nevermind,
after 10 miles white peaches sell it to
you,
why does he have to take you on the trip
to the guy's house?
These are all the questions I have,
but don't have the balls to ask.
Like I'm in my mind.
I'm like,
AH,
like I'm 14,
15.
I'm not saying shit to this dude.
Right.
I'm cool.
Suck to get a sack,
right.
We'll try me.
So we go into his trailer and he's like,
all right,
we're going to get to the sec.
We back in 10 minutes.
I was like,
who will be back in 10 minutes?
He's like,
we will be,
you stay here and watch my place.
And I was like,
what?
Like,
what the fuck are you talking about is
what I'm thinking.
But then I just go like,
yeah,
cool.
Totally.
You're in his trailer.
And he's like,
watch it for me.
And I'm like,
oh no,
like I'm feeling like that,
like real fear.
But I go,
yeah,
no problem.
Like I watched people's houses all the
time,
like it totally fucking terrified.
And then he goes like the,
you walk in the trailer,
you're in the living room because that's
the way trailers,
right.
Walk into it as a bedroom to the right.
I was like,
waiting here on the bags.
He's like a 45 and a 12 gauge and he
goes,
anybody comes in my,
in my house,
you shoot them.
I was like,
right.
And then he was like a Sephora,
my Mama,
my mama comes home,
don't shoot her.
And I was like got it.
And except I kept trying to be cool
about it.
I was like,
yeah,
like that's what's up.
I know,
I know what you're saying man.
Look at that sac.
Totally like trying to be like.
He was like,
all right,
they walk out,
they leave me in his trailer with two
guns and a fucking message to not to
shoot everybody but his mother and I
just sit there and watch the MTV video
music awards and the whole time,
like every show that comes just I'm
rocking.
I'm actually hoping that it's an
intruder versus his mom because I feel
like if it's his mom,
she might accidentally shoot her or how
is she going to react to my explanation?
Like pep just told me to wait here.
Well,
he's getting some weed for me,
but I'm not supposed to shoot everybody,
but you,
are you cool with that?
She's like,
Oh yeah,
that happens all to like how you're
going to react to this so I fuck.
I mean I'm having a panic attack.
We finally,
they come back,
I get back in with a white pete.
He drives us back and I'm sitting there
like,
I'm like,
what the fuck dude?
That was the worst that ever.
Like I'm fucking terrified.
He was like,
yeah,
Hammond,
Pat,
pat.
Pat became like best friends.
So they became like,
like super close.
Like that was like his guy.
He would go and I'd be like,
no dude,
I don't want to hang out with pat at
all.
And like six months later when Steve got
his license,
we went and he was like,
you want to get some weed today?
And I was like,
yeah,
yeah.
So where we go for peers pull up to pat
pat's and I'm like,
God dammit.
Like she remembered how to get there.
He did.
Steve had started going there all the
time.
Oh my God.
We pull up to his trailer this time.
He gets out now this time,
like with their friends.
So this is probably gonna be a much
quicker thing.
He comes out,
he jumps in the back and he's like,
I have this role.
And I was like,
oh no,
we're fucking,
look for a sec again.
I thought you just have this.
So this time we went to this,
but this are thing.
Pap has scared the shit out of me the
first time.
But that second time he saved our life
actually because we went from his
trailer.
The second time he jumped in the back
went to Avenue d,
which is the fucking shitty street in
Fort Pierce.
Like if you're going to like every city,
you know you have like,
I dunno whatever city you're in there
like that's ever seen.
If you've been to the street where you
see open drug dealing where there's not
even some type of facade angeles,
right,
but you've been done on a street where
there's like,
there's no pretense about it.
There's just like Los Angeles.
Which part of filming fear factor?
We were actually filming the playboy
playmate addition of fear factor
downtown area and we were watching
people sell drugs,
smoke crack right there.
We were in a crane and I go,
look,
they're smoking crack.
And the girls were like,
oh my God,
they are smoking crack.
And like,
this is ridiculous.
No one's protecting us.
We're up here on a crane.
That was exactly like this where we
pulled up in,
in Steve's car and the windows come down
and we just get surrounded.
Like the car got surrounded by six guys
and they reached in their jackets and
they go at this one guy who was.
Y'All look familiar and this other guy
goes,
yeah,
y'all are real familiar.
Y'All ever been here before?
And I.
When you,
when somebody says that you look
familiar,
have any before,
how would you answer that?
I'll just say nope.
Nope.
Right,
exactly.
At that moment I go no.
And Steve at the exact same it goes.
Yup.
Yeah man.
And then they're like,
see,
I told you man,
y'all look like the white boys had been
snatching bags around here.
And I was like,
Oh fuck,
like you look like the white boys that
have been taken bags from guys.
I'm like,
no dude,
that's not us.
It seems like,
but we have been here before.
I'm like,
will you shut the fuck up?
Is in the back,
like hold on.
And he gets out and walks or talks to
all of them.
Like a,
you know,
like he's the ambassador and like I
don't know what the fuck.
Like I own these guys there was like
fucking.
And they totally let us go without,
without him we would have been fucked.
We will send noise.
What is it with his phone that's not
mine.
It's my pat pat.
Pat,
pat.
Pat is still,
I don't know what happened to Pat,
pat and white Pete.
Who knows what good things.
Probably not good things,
man.
You said facebook?
Um,
facebook.
Pap Pap.
That will be the next person that makes
up a fake twitter accounts of fee.
That was.
I had real fear.
Oh yeah.
You're like for good fucking reason.
Oh,
like when you feel your stomach dropping
your life,
what's going to happen right now?
Oh my God.
Yeah.
That's terrible shit,
man.
When I was a kid,
when I was in high school,
we used to go to dorchester to eat late
at night.
I was hanging out with this one kid I
lived in Jamaica plain before I went to
high school in Jamaica plain was like a
real shifting neighborhood.
It was kind of kind of creepy and it was
it board some really creepy places and I
became friends with a couple of those
kids and I stayed in touch with them and
then when I went to high school I went
to visit him a couple times before I
realized it was really fucking
dangerous.
Yeah,
they were going to a bad high school
man.
They're high highschool situation.
My host high school situation was very
different.
We went to the same middle school
together and middle school was kind of
okay because kids were young,
they hadn't gotten into dangerous shit
yet and you know,
this is 1980,
you know,
this is early.
It was just like when the sugar hill
gang would just come out,
hip hop,
inhibit,
inhibit of hip hop.
That was the first rap music and it was
very friendly in retrospect and things
changed radically though.
When when I left I went to a Newton,
which is nice suburbs and I lived across
the street from a river and woods near
me and shit like that.
And they went to the inner city high
school and they had some fucking tough
times.
Man.
I watched those dudes.
They were basically involved in just
just crime was everywhere around them.
It was nuts,
man.
You know,
inner city shit is just no fun at all.
And I got lucky that my parents made a
move to a nicer place and we anyway,
we would go to these places like late at
night when I was hanging out with them,
you know,
we'd hang out with some of their friends
would go,
we'd go to like Dorchester at like 2:00
in the morning to eat.
And I,
first of all,
I couldn't believe who the fuck let me
wander around at 14 years old.
Yeah.
But we were in some place where you,
there was bulletproof glass,
they would sell you food but it was
through bulletproof glass.
It was sandwiches and there was like a
slot where you would slide the food
under and it was like the worst fucking
neighborhood you could possibly be in
outside of Beirut.
You know,
we're hanging out there and some guy
goes fuck up,
like decided to finish it.
And I'm like let him go,
let him go.
Let him go see the guy like bluffed his
way out of a free sandwich and he would
walk off and he was eating it like right
at the front door,
like blocking the door like a dog.
Like it got far enough for,
he was away from danger and he was just
with no regard for how it looked.
It was just eating it,
blocking the doorway,
eating the sandwich.
And I was like,
um,
there's,
there's people don't know like how,
how bad some neighborhoods are in like
Hollywood sunset between Fairfax and
crescent heights used to be like.
And like,
you know,
I remember when I worked at a restaurant
there and one night man to two weekends
in a row,
first weekend someone got shot in the
head on the steps into Denny's,
which was a.
and then the next weekend somebody came
in,
one end into the kitchen,
took scissors,
started stabbing people with scissor,
then stabbing themselves.
But it was also God,
but it was also
like a criminal hangout because at
Denny's on Denny's,
criminal hangout,
you know what I'm saying?
It's open all night.
So that's where late night people,
people who are up all night could go and
hang out.
So it became like it was,
they just shut it down because they're
like everybody who's who's in here as
like pimp,
Hustler drug dealer and they're
murdering people weekend after weekend.
So they just shut that shit down.
But that was like,
there was a dangerous area.
Man.
Hollywood is so shitty,
shitty people come to Hollywood who
think that they're going to come.
We're going to go almost killed a guy
yesterday coming home from the doctor.
This it was,
I was probably going 45,
50 miles an hour and out of nowhere.
The car next to me slams on his brakes.
I'm like,
what the fuck?
So I slammed on my brakes even though I
had no idea why.
He was slamming on his brakes type thing
because I couldn't see over his car and
they slam on brakes and just missed this
old man dressed up as a woman and he was
just crossing the street like in the
middle of the street jaywalking and just
screaming at us like,
like,
like you could just tell you this
fucking crazy.
I like lipstick all around his whole
entire face.
Do you?
It was just an old man dress up as well,
but let's Costar from grace under fire
still pissed that bitch out of scream
and get the show.
I got to fucking bounce.
I got to go do a show.
Go Re Improv folks tonight if you are
around,
if you're anywhere near Braya,
there's an 8:00
PM show tonight.
Bray Improv.
Tommy Cigar all up in this.
But your headline in there,
right?
It's a Valentine show.
You and your wife?
Me and my wife.
Yeah,
we didn't go.
So it starts when you get there.
You won't be late though.
You can leave here.
I'll give you directions.
Thank you for this.
Uh,
this,
this weekend I'll be at the Orlando
Improv.
So if you're in Orlando,
Orlando,
Florida,
I'll be in the dirty freaks and you
gotta go down and support Tommy when he
was taping his new CD that will be in
Denver at the comedy works South on
February Twenty fourth and 25th is a
great fucking club.
Tell Wendy I said well so.
Well and also please check out the
podcast,
the podcast I've done with Brian for the
last few years called your mom's house
is available on itunes.
We're going to do the first episode
without our beloved Brian Tomorrow and
the website is your mom's house
podcast.com.
Your mom's house podcast with his lovely
and talented,
very,
very funny young lady.
And she'll be on the show tonight as
well.
That's the bright Improv,
9:00
PM.
And of course next.
Not next weekend,
but whatever the fuck weekend it is.
It is next weekend.
Not.
Yeah,
it's not this coming weekend,
but the next one,
24th and the 25th Denver.
Get on that shit.
Thank you.
Ira Up Death Squad in support Thompson.
You the fucking man.
I love you buddy.
You're awesome.
Thanks for helping Pat Patterson.
What's up,
what's up?
Thank you to um,
uh,
the flashlight for sponsoring our
podcasts from the beginning,
from the very dark days of laptops and
not knowing what the fuck we're doing as
if we didn't start off today on the
wrong channel.
We fucking slippery.
This is real.
There's not a lot of production value,
but it's free.
Okay,
thanks to thanks to everybody is tuning
into this fucking thing before we even
get their sponsors,
you know,
it's one of the coolest things in the
world to have such an awesome fan base,
to have so many cool fucking people to
connect with so many people to get all
these messages from
you guys like,
hey man,
this is what I've been looking for my
whole life.
That shows change in my life.
To show changes the way I look at
things.
You guys changed the way we look at
things too,
from twitter,
from all the cool links that I get sent
to.
The amount of support that we get from
our shows.
It to me is the coolest thing that I've
ever done in my life.
As you got the best hands,
if I'm lucky,
I'm very,
very fortunate.
We put out the right vibe and people
respond and,
and we put out this show for its real.
It's,
you know what I'm saying?
It's like there's no bullshit,
no pretense.
It is what it is.
It's 100 percent free and we love all
you freaks and we just want to let you
know that this is not something I take
for granted.
I've done a lot of shit in my career.
This is the thing I'm the most proud of
for sure.
It's a,
you guys are most proud of the,
the whole,
the whole thing.
Everything behind it.
All the moment.
I don't want to say movement though.
All the momentum behind it,
all the shows and it's a humbling
experience,
man.
When I do something like the Chicago
Theater and is 3,200
people and everyone's screaming and
cheering,
it's really the greatest.
One of the greatest experiences of my
life.
And we're gonna keep going,
bitch.
We ain't going nowhere.
Come see me in.
Um,
yeah,
go to Joe Rogan.net.
I don't even know where the fuck I'm
going.
Friday we're at the ice house.
Ice has comedy and Friday by the way,
it's going to be a.
it's a very intimate show and it will
sell out is we do them every week.
There's only 85 seats and it's fucking
awesome.
It's going to be.
We might have a red band who's gone
while I don't know the guest stars Dj
Down Town.
I think there's going to do it.
Who does all the time,
Tim and Eric stuff and really beautiful.
And you're around this Friday as well.
I'm in Orlando.
You're in Atlanta.
Okay.
That's it.
You'd already frakes thanks the
fleshlight.
Go to [inaudible] dot net.
Click on the link for the flashlight,
entering the code named Brogan,
and then go fuck yourself.
Go Fuck Yourself.
Thank you to [inaudible] Dot com o n n
it makers of Alpha,
brain,
new mood,
shroom,
tech,
sport and shroom,
tech immune,
all powerful cognitive enhancing
supplements,
immune system,
supplements and endurance supplements.
All good shit.
All natural.
All good for you.
All explained at [inaudible] dot com.
Oh,
and and it go to Joe Rogan.net.
Click on the Alpha brain link,
entering the code name Brogan,
and you will get 10 percent off your
first order.
I'm going to have that changed for all
your orders,
right?
So you can always get a nice little
discount,
right?
You fucking freaks.
You know,
I love you.
God dammit.
That's a small backpack and I'll see you
guys soon.
Check out a UFC tomorrow night.
I won't be there,
but it's going to be a live from
somewhere.
Cool.
Omaha,
Nebraska.
Oh,
Jake ellenberger.
He's from Omaha and Diego Sanchez and I
believe that's on Fx.