I'm not geeked by this. Just
so you know. Do, do, do, do,
do waiting.
I'm not a fan.
Russell Peters is it were
live ladies and gentlemen,
the Joe Rogan experience
podcast is brought to you.
This episode is brought to
you by audible.com if you
have never used audible.com
and you're in your car every day and you,
you,
you were commuting every day you're on
a bus or a plane or whatever the fuck
you're on,
you are missing out on an
awesome opportunity to be
entertained is like a lot of
time. You can, you can learn shit
when you're on a plane. You know,
if you're stuck on a flight for five
hours instead of just staring at the seat
behind you gave yourself an audible
books son, go check that shit out.
And one of the craziest things about
audible is their new application for the
kindle fire and it's called whisper sync.
And the way it works,
it's really fascinating shit.
The way it works is you
read the book and if you're,
you're done reading it at a certain point,
you stop it.
It syncs up with your smart phone.
And then there's a companion audio book
that plays it while you're, you know,
in the subway or whatever you're
doing, so you can read the book. Uh,
and then when you're in
your car and you're driving,
you could have the book read to you from
the exact spot where you left off. It's,
it's amazing.
And it's done with professional actors.
So it's not like when authors read their
own books, audio books or the ship,
but don't ever get an audio book where
Stephen King rain reads his own books.
It's fucking terrible.
Oh my God, it's awful.
And then he grabbed the sword
and stab them in the heart.
It's like, it's so like,
he's such a shit. Act as a shit voice
just doesn't work. It doesn't work.
You got to, Dj's are like that. Do you
had to give that shit up to the, uh,
professional actors, but his, um,
his writing is fucking fantastic.
We're all too also brought to you
by [inaudible] dot com and, uh,
if you listen to this
podcast at least once before,
you know what the fuck I'm selling. Okay,
go get yourself some bringing pills, son.
Go to go get some Alpha brain or some
shroom tech or any of the supplements that
we sell over it on it.
We are trying to sell you the finest
performance enhancing legal substances
available. And uh, when I say that it's,
it's not like steroids. What's brain tech?
What is brain tech? It's another
one of those. There's all, no, no,
it's called Alpha brain alphabet.
There's a,
there's another one called neuro one
that I've taken before that said Bill
Romanowski stuff. All of these things
are essentially the along the same lines.
There's a whole series of nutrients
that have been shown to have a positive
effect on cognitive function.
What does that mean?
It means that you can remember things
better statistically provable. You can,
you can solve problems quicker.
There's, there's certain things,
especially like the
memory one is a big one.
Certain things that have been proven
by some of the ingredients are in Alpha
brain and it's not like we figured it out.
Like there's,
there's a shit load of nootropics for
sale on the Internet and I would encourage
anybody who's interested in
these things to Google it there,
there's very little negative,
uh,
attached to the idea of taking nutrients.
It's not,
you have to worry about it like Ambien
or something that you can get hooked on.
It's nothing along those lines.
It's just vitamins and all it's
doing is giving your brain's all the,
all the essential nutrients that it needs
in order to function clearly. I mean,
your brain,
your body,
the whole system runs on nutrients and
most of us are living very nutrient
deficient lifestyles. It's
just unfortunate, but it's
just if you have, you know,
the average American meal, you're,
you're not going to get what you need.
There's a lot of shit out there that you
need, especially from fresh vegetables.
You need a lot of green leafy vegetables,
but you also need vitamins and
supplements too. It's like,
it ensures that your body gets the
optimal amount, amount of nutrition,
even if you're eating healthy,
it does make a difference.
One of the things that I tell you about
on and all this shit that we sell,
all the supplements have a 30 30 pill,
90 day,
100% money back guarantee.
You don't even have to return the product.
Now let's trying to rip you off anything,
any of this shit that we sell is
all stuff that I've already used.
It's all stuff that is been proven
like with a long history of human use.
A new mood is one of those. It's a
five HTP supplement. What five HTP is.
And at first learned about this through
Neal Brennan and he was telling me who's
taking it. It's a Serotonin,
serotonin boosting supplement.
It's essentially the building
blocks for Serotonin.
And when you take five HTP,
you can actually increase your
brain's production of it. Well,
this new mood has both five HTP,
which turns into Serotonin en El
Tryptofan, which turns into five HTP.
So there's like a slow release method
of a, of distributions. And what's that?
Make it get sleepy? The trip defense?
No, no it doesn't. No, it's, you know,
everybody thinks that like when
you, um, LGH l trip to fan,
it's like everybody thinks it's that part
of Turkey that makes you sleeping. No,
you ain't like a fucking pig.
That's what makes you sleeping.
Your body's shutting down. Like there's
nothing that makes you that sleepy.
That sleepy comes from
being a fucking Slob,
Jamaican food nuts now to
anything high caloric man,
anything with a lot of fat in it.
It just hits that wall inside your
body and your body goes, God damn dude.
Seriously. That's what makes
you tired. I mean, I guess it,
it'll and it'll stabilize you a bit.
Um,
zinc and magnesium can help
you sleep a little bit.
Melatonin can help you sleep a anyway,
go to a on it.com it's o and it.
Use a code name Brogan and save
yourself 10% of any and all supplements.
All right. Dirty bitches.
Boom. Strap the fuck in
Russell Peters and make some mass to Mike
are up in this bitch.
What happened
today?
Joe Rogan podcast.
We're back here.
Nice House and Death Squad studios
where we have awesome Internet and shit.
Electricity,
dangerous electrocution style,
1940s electricity.
You stirring shit the bed today for
some reason I'm using an old version.
I use dreams, so hopefully it's,
Oh really? Oh that's what happened.
I don't know. Every time I
launch Ustream and just crashes,
so I'm using an old version that it's
not doing that mix master Mike. Yes.
Welcome aboard, sir. Thank you very
much for coming down to the podcast.
We really appreciate it. Yeah, I'm
stoked. Yeah, and when we talked about it,
when Russell Peters found out about
a Russell Peters being the true music
Aficionado,
true Dj that he is really,
I had to come down here and join.
I did. I was very geeked about it.
Red Band mentioned it
last week and I was like,
I have to be there when mixed matched.
I'm like,
is there and your friends or introduce
yourself to those people. My name is mark.
Happy to be here. Thanks for
having me. Mark. What do you
do, mark? Uh, mix master.
Mike and I worked together. I booked them
for shows. I'm actually from Vancouver,
so we flight,
I flew down here for those you who've
been on a podcast for the first time.
Keep it together, keep it together,
shoot them. It's not get crazy. So, uh,
thanks for doing this man. Of
course, man. What is this a,
your app you have for your, uh, your
iPad. You have a mixed mastermind. Yes.
Mix Master Mike. It's called
wheel's a steel, um, w e w.
H. E. L. Z. So those
that want to tap it in,
it's a two turntables and the mixer on
your iPad. So you could take it, you know,
you know,
sometimes you know you don't have access
to real turntables and mixers and stuff
and you got maybe 50,
50 people over and they want
a dance break. Open your Ipad,
get the little mini adapter,
plug it into the stereo. And
so you cut it off.
You could do,
you could do a do a whole
party out of you off your iPad.
It actually reads your iTunes library.
Holy Shit.
And you can do some crazy shit with it.
Like,
so the,
the power of these things now is sort
of caught up with what you're capable of
doing with like regular DJ equipment.
Not Quite, not quite but close.
But this,
this
should pacify the Dj for the moment
until they get to the real date.
But you can actually DJ with it.
It's crazy.
Now is there like lessons,
is there a tutorial or anything where
someone learns how to Dj like that or
someone learns how to mix?
Well there's, there's a
little easy pathways pathways on here.
Like there's,
there's like little scratches that I did
on here where you just hit one button
and there's like four different scratches
as like the scribble, the laser,
the baby and the drag.
So I'll go down it and this is a scribble
and does the laser does
a baby and does a drag
and so, so that's how, those are the
sounds subs yet. But that would be good.
Yeah.
You have to do is you show people how
to do that or are you just by pressing
those buttons,
it makes those noises.
You figure it out on your own type
thing. How did you learn? For me,
I mean this was back in
[inaudible] 87 and um,
I watched, uh, well I was around a lot of
music. My, my uncle has had an extensive,
a record collection and he's played
Jimmy Hendrickson me all the time.
Jim Jimmy Hendrix,
p funk or something
by Jimi Hendrix. Like I was like, Whoa, I
want him to play the turntable like that.
And so I got a turntable and I'm
just basically mimicking my heroes.
Wow. You know what you, what
really fascinates me about Djs,
about the art of deejaying is
that this is something that was,
that never existed. Just a, you know,
50 years ago, whatever it was that this,
this is something that really sort
of manifested in our lifetimes.
And we saw guys like,
like I still amount of it,
I don't understand the electronic
music world and DJ world.
It's like we're really kind of shocking
to me when I see like this ts guy,
horrible. I had no idea.
We talked to us for advice,
they just bounded knuckles.
But you know what, as Dj's mix
master Mike and all these other guys,
they aren't really allowed to say these
things. Right, right, right. Like,
like they all come to me and they're
like, oh, I'll say it right now. Okay,
let them know Mike. No, no. I
mean, I met yesterday. He's,
he's a cool dude. I'm sure.
I'm sure he's a great guy,
but whatever.
My point was like all
this didn't exist before.
Like I didn't know that this guy was so
enormous and I was in Vegas and there
was like something at a a casino and
this dude that I know who's this a super
billionaire character, he
owns like a businesses. He's
always front row with UFC.
He's friends with the owners,
really real character.
But he's telling me how
they're going to cts tone.
He's performing in front of 50,000
people. I go, who the fuck is ts toe?
He was like, are you kidding me?
You don't know who to ask though,
is this guy's like on the party scene,
the international club scene.
You know what I mean?
So he tells me about this Dj guy and
internationally he's Jayke whatever he is,
man internationally,
this guy's fucking gigantic
and he's doing these 50 Hyundai
20 million partner or third was at
30 20 or 30 million a year. Yeah.
Something like that.
Pressing all of that shit. Okay. I'm
not comparing that to being a DJ,
but all of this electronic Lee created
stuff. This didn't exist before.
None of it exists before. No. Amazing.
It started off the right way and
then in between where the right way,
well let's start it off
and, and uh, you know, with,
with the house music which came out
of disco and then the djs would, um,
they would just play records and mix it
back in the day, like in the 80s. I mean,
I'm, I remember buying house
records as early as 86, 85, 81 86.
Wow. And you know, and we would mix
them right there and now they just,
and then there was djs.
I would go see like Roger S and a bad
boy bill and all these guys and they were
all was so hyped to me that when I go
see them I'd be bored out of my fucking
tree. And I was like, why am
I so bored? They're not doing
anything. They were just,
they would press their
own records so they,
they would have shit that you
wouldn't have and then, uh,
they would just play them
and they'd make some,
but they were so boring because they
didn't do anything. And I was like,
and I was already into deejaying then
and I was like sitting there and they'll
do anything.
You mean like she would just mix the
records but they would mix them. I mean,
which I appreciate them at least
mixing the vinyl live in of me.
But they would play songs you didn't
know and they wouldn't play anything that
was intricate are fucking cool. You'd be
like, well these are just songs you made.
Huh?
So it was their own shit.
A lot of the times I play their own shit.
Do you dislike all electronic music?
Is that why you said no,
I like electronic music
and not a lot of it,
but I mean the good shit
that's out there as good shit.
When you say though that
it started off good,
but now it's not what's the deejaying
started off the right way with the right
intent.
So the deejaying went from that to
creating your own noises and music,
which is fine,
but these guys are getting paid
to quote unquote Dj and they just,
it's the literally the equivalent to
somebody paying money to see you Joe and
you go onstage and you put on a video
of yourself when you point at it.
That's a pretty good idea.
Exactly.
I'm going to do that from now on and
kind of that's the way to do it in mass.
Like all the pressure of fucking
live for forming man. Yeah.
It's just like literally like,
hey man, I see what I did there.
That's kind of a funny way looking at it,
the pressure of live performing is
the thing that fucks with people.
One of the other points is that
just the equipment that the djs use,
so the house djs use what are called CDJs.
So they actually put cds into
now wait,
nowadays they don't even,
because the new CDJs have a USB plug,
an MP and they show but to jump drives,
you pop it in and then
so then they just press play literally.
And that's the whole show would stand
in the fist, a fist pump and, and they,
and they literally, and they fucking
congratulate themselves the whole set.
There'll be two of them are
wondering, I'm like, oh my God,
you're not doing anything.
But he's pointing at him like he's
doing some really good at that.
I could do that. I could fist
pumped the shit out of a show.
But you know the music.
But the music is a reflection of
the audience too as you look at it.
And it's suspect because I don't know,
I got nothing against homos or
anything like, no, but I'm just saying
some of the music can be
just that statement alone
will be a meme till the end
of the time.
Nobody but [inaudible] some of that
music is kind of Kinda Kinda in that
direction. Kind of ecstasy
driven I think more than gay.
And now you know what Tsos fan comes from.
It's like a bunch of those people.
I mean,
you know nothing.
No, actually he's not
even in with those people.
Those people have more sense than the,
than the masters that listen
to Tsa though. And I would say
um, well I didn't want to come off
like people that like that guy,
I'll get you out of this whole,
don't worry if you meet those
guys at a bathhouse. Yeah,
no Amanda.
But the UFC actually I know the guys
did all that. Like that guy. I Dunno.
I guys that like, yeah, I don't know.
I don't know his music
to be honest with you.
I've only heard like one thing on
the Internet. I was like, okay,
it's just not my shit.
We live in a world of sheep nowadays and
nobody has the common sense to try and
figure out what's good.
Is that it or is it just different?
No,
there can't be. It's, it's,
it's global, this thing.
And now nobody can really tell
me that that shit is really good.
It's just what's hot and this is
what this is like, oh, this is what,
this is what we should like. They're
just fucking sheep. Like back in the day,
you would have to search
out what you wanted to like.
Do you think that's the case
with all this electronic music?
Not On, well, a lot of
it like people, you know,
try to be different or whatever
and you know I, and then they're,
they're failing at it.
I got to re re very respectfully disagree.
I've produced shows for Armin van Buren
who is actually the number one DJ in the
world over at ts though.
The guy is big and you press play.
Yeah, absolutely. He's depressed. I
remember when he used to Dj. Yeah. Yeah.
That was Armand Van Helden. Oh, okay.
The van Helden use held in. Is this
another one? What's the other guy's name?
Van Buren. Yeah. That's ridiculous.
You can't be Ben held in the field
of God's Van Buren got a year apart.
So crazy.
But the argument is that
these guys actually produce
their own music, you know?
So for example, like we, when
I work with Mike, he brings,
he scratches in his own mixes
using vinyl and using Serato.
Camera's on my hands. Yeah.
Just so they could watch. Yeah,
he has sets where he just
creates a musical scratch.
Like where's on your hands?
It's sometimes you went on with, with
the, with the beach boys. I had a finger.
Can you mean like an oh wow.
Spotlights.
So you know, just on the
insurance, so that my show too,
we have cameras right on the turntables.
So I'm,
so people see that as a live performance.
Art is not something that
you're painting a picture,
you're really painting your audio, Pitney
picks out and you're doing it right.
And exactly.
And if he wants to change his mind as to
what song he's playing, he can do that.
Yeah. How much of your set
list is improvised and how
much of your, I mean you're,
you're completely in control.
A lot of it's improvised.
That's something that you just
don't get from one of those two.
Yes. That was the other guys. It's
programmed and it's program to,
to coincide with the music.
So really all they're paying money
for is a light and laser show.
So the person who should be making
the money is the fucking lighting guy.
Exactly.
Isn't it funny though,
that like with every generation,
the generation of today gets shit
on by the previous generation.
I mean, just the fact that you're
in like old school Dj Jan. Okay.
Just stop and think of that. Because like
in the eighties and the seventies when,
when,
you know,
when rock was king and when like the
Allman brothers and people were in a
Leonard Skinner and shit like that.
And then the 80s came along and deejaying
came along and people were like,
look at this fucking new ridiculous
shit that's not music exam. You're like,
listen to this new shit where they just
press play. That's not fucking music.
While you're not playing records,
it's like every generation gets
shit on by the previous generation.
That's, I mean, it's, it's, it's
the, uh, the evolution of man.
It's funny though, like we're the old
guys shitting on the, the new, uh,
the new breed. I went to see it like,
I can understand, like, you know, I,
I take it back to before it got
digital and the house Djs, you know,
like, uh, uh, like, uh,
all those other guys,
Paul Van Dyke and fucking all
those guys out of England.
I never liked the shit they played,
but at least they played it.
You know what I mean? Yeah. Right, right.
It's not about what they're playing.
It's about the fact that people are
paying money for these people to not do
anything. But isn't there an
art to creating that shit?
There's most certainly is,
right? No. There's a lighting guy who's,
there's honestly a choreographer
to their sets who, who says,
here's what I'm going to do for
you. Right. But the music itself,
it has nothing to do with the music.
The music all sounds exactly the same.
So it doesn't really mean exactly.
So, well, most of them are producers,
producers that want to be Dj's. Oh,
really? Yeah. They figure, okay,
we're making the music,
so why don't we try to learn how to Dj
and it just doesn't, Huh? Isn't. Yeah.
People, when someone creates
dope electronic music,
when there's one like beat that you hear,
that's really cool. That is a creation.
Yeah, absolutely. That's made it is sick.
It is. Yeah. So that is like someone,
someone created that. Yeah, that's
not right. That's not the problem.
The problem is passing yourself off
as a DJ. Yeah. And you're not DJ.
That's what might be called themselves.
Let's call them an electronic musicians,
let's call them that.
Right?
If they're standing up playing the
music in front of you, I'm impressed.
But that's the thing would you would, you
can't do that with that stuff. So what,
what could they do if they're
going to do a live show, say, Hey,
I'm going to just put my shit on.
I'll be back later to say
thanks and good night. Hey Go.
We just press it and walk off.
Why would they,
what are they going to
do when they're on stage?
I mean they kind of have to
do this and like pop and shit.
It created it all before.
So it's a weird sort of
hybrid of performance.
Our end we thing they're not even
doing this.
Like make Harrison Ford's and being in
front of the screen and an Indiana Jones
movie like flexing every time
Indiana Jones kick some ass. Joe,
do you ever see this,
uh, this video of Mike,
this is getting kind of give an example.
How does that compare to like
electronic music? We don't see it.
We don't see anything.
Yeah.
What about
ladies need capital?
That's good.
Oh boy.
Don't stop getting giddy.
Made a face to face just
to see how you can quit.
That's my favorite move because
it looks like you're doing a lot,
but you're really just one beat behind.
You're going to look like you're doing
okay for the folks at home. One move.
Is that, what is it? Boy, he was drugged,
but here he's juggling right there.
He was always good at juggling.
That was this.
I think that was your
strongest point. Right? Gotcha.
Did you say that was your favorite
thing to do? What is explained?
Juggling going back and forth with the
same record and making a beat with him,
making it my own beat and
kind of remixing it. And you,
what was the competition that you won?
Like a bunch of years in a row and they
wouldn't let you in or anymore? DMC? Yeah,
it was the DMC. What's the
DMC first I won the, uh,
the new music seminar in New York,
battle for world supremacy and in
92 [inaudible] the battle for world.
So this was like the
biggest battle in hip hop.
Like this is where you
battled the cream of the crop.
Who did your battle that you're
in? I, I battled, um, rock raider.
I battled Dj Honda from Japan. Japan?
Yeah. And how do you guys battle?
How does that work? It's a five
minutes to you. Five minutes for me.
And then the audience insights audience.
Do you base it on how loud the cheers are?
Wow. So how intricate the routine was?
I mean, how do they judge? Like how's the
audience judge? Well, the judge is judge.
Judge. Okay. I'm just
saying like, do they,
is it because the audience cheers the
loudest for you? No, no, no. It's,
it's actually about skill.
I could hate judges.
That was the last year of
a seminar, wasn't it? Yeah,
it was the last year and then yet we
were just up there then, you know,
I'm just like, you know, clowning
and you know, facial and you know,
I'm kind of like flipping off and the
whole thing and people like that. So yeah.
So you want how many years in a row?
Three and then they said you'd done yeah.
And then DMC, DMC decided to
make us judges. Oh really? Yeah.
We were ready to defend
for the fourth year.
And it was that rock steady
djs or was that just, it was
just me and Cubert. Yeah.
Why did they decide to make you a,
that seems like that would be Kinda
cool to have like a store of the Lance
Armstrong of Dj and that just
fix it keeps dominant. No,
because then there's guys like
Mike and Cubert that create,
they create sounds like that
other djs go, fuck. All right,
I'm going to try that. And then like
they've created between you and Kubrick,
you guys created fucking crabbing
and flaring and crabbing and flaring.
You're saying a lot of shit that
no one knows what you're saying.
And like these movies didn't exist before
these guys. Do you know what I mean?
Well, yeah. While
practicing, we name names on
the different scratch techniques and so
we came up with like a hundred scratches.
Wow.
And we named them all with the orbit,
the crab that the infamous tweak scratch
I did for the Beastie boys. And, and,
and it just said,
it's just like a log of things that you
memorize and what is it like when you're
scratching,
what is it based on?
Is it based on the sounds that are
actually on the record? Like do you know,
like different records are producing
different sounds. So you know,
like where to scratch it
and you have to like it,
it's a different kind of
needle too, right? Yeah. Yeah.
It's the [inaudible] seven.
I mean, there's different
sounds. I do love the 40 footers.
These needles that are designed just for
again, his crew. Are you
a scratch pickle? Yes.
Fuck you talking about scratch.
They're trolling us, Brian.
We have to stand up for ourselves now.
Fuck this man. His crew. Easy sign.
I'm not going down without a part of
the ISP. So fucking scratch pickles.
The invisible scratch pickles
touched the scratch pickle Joe touch it.
So did you guys come back and
does judges and we did. Yeah, we did a
final performance and then on our way,
that's how they should do with them.
I may have like champions become judges.
I get bit,
you'd get a much better reading on
who actually won fights then you do.
The way it's set up now, the way it's
set up now, there's some people that are,
judges are just, it's just mind boggling.
Is it the same way in deejaying?
Yeah. Oh, it definitely going to have
same way. Comedy competitions too. Man.
Miles are awful. God, those are discussed.
All was bad. Ugh. It's so subjective.
I've seen a comedy competitions
where the guy who won,
like you would just stand back and go,
what the fuck are they saying man?
Well, it's the whole, yeah. Cause
it's art at that point. Right.
And art is so subjective. I mean you who
knows what the fuck that judge was into.
Yeah. You know what they can and most
of the time judges are failed comics or
whatever.
Yeah.
Failed Martial artists that they hit
the bitterness into it. Right? Yeah.
And there's some that aren't some of the
great, some that are legit. Some of the,
you know, especially in a MMA,
there's some great judges.
There's no doubt about it. It's just
a few standouts that really suck.
I always have names that pop into mind
when it comes to bad boxing judges,
you know? Yeah. You hear
their name it there at the
beginning. You're like, oh fuck.
Not that part. I'll be surely,
surely Patricia Sharman.
Oh Jesus.
Not again. Yeah. Did
that the packout fight,
we were talking about this off
camera before we started. Man,
that was one of the worst knockouts
ever for like an all time. Great.
Yeah. That was a, that was devastating.
That reminded me of when
Hearns knocked out Duran.
Remember how he fucking ice
them in the second round?
Yeah,
but he didn't,
he staggered them before that and then
put them away with one punch and face
planted them.
But this was like one shot doom and he
had knocked him down at the same punch
like earlier around or early.
The,
that's something Freddie should have
said, you know, keep your fucking,
keep your hands up.
He didn't look the same.
You can,
you can't be like,
what is he a congressman or something in
the Philippines, black man born again,
Christian full time Gig as a congressman.
Too many things happening. Yeah,
but I don't think that had,
that was the fact. Right.
Here's what I think is my analyze what
I analyze the fight as he tells me shit.
If Desi, what are you telling
me? Shit. Yeah, so a nice,
he just showed us a picture of
Freddy Roach. He tells me, I mean,
you're getting that we're actually on a
radio show. No, exactly. I don't know.
I just, he just, what does he say, man?
He's gone bananas. Yeah, of course.
Going looks physically different to,
he didn't look as muscular and
there's what I think happened Joe,
and this is just me, I,
when you're fighting,
you hear the ten second bell.
And so I heard the ten second bell and
I know they heard the ten second belt,
right? He got knocked out with one
second left in that room. Right.
He was standing near his corner.
I honestly think he was getting them to
that corner and then he had counted it
in his head and figured he would just
walk around Marquez and walked it his
corner and he kind of just walked
right into a fucking right hand.
You got a little careless. He, I said,
hey, I think he miscounted and be,
I think he got a little reckless.
He just, yeah, he got reckless. He,
he'd missed a punch. Mean he was coming
forward. Uh, when, uh, mark has landed,
mark has landed perfect too.
That was like one of the best right hands.
It's like textbook.
Manny's head snapped back and you know,
to have a guy that's that good getting
knocked completely unconscious really
puts boxing in the light for us because
we never saw that with a lot of guys.
We'd never saw that. Even with Tyson,
he never really got knocked unconscious.
I Cindy's got beat up and beat down
and even the buster Douglas knock out,
which was like, I don't know how many
times it was like six years clean. Yeah.
And he was hitting him
on his way down to it's,
Tyson's still was conscious,
you know that guy's Chin was insanity.
But to see like an all time great
get flat lined. That's when like,
like Roy Jones against Glen Johnson.
That was horrible.
That was the first time
he got knocked out.
It was the second don Toyota
knocking on our harbor knocked out.
You know what Roy fucked up or Roy fucked
up his where he went all the way up to
heavyweight and then he tried to drop
the weight and go all the way down.
Tactical light heavyweight.
Yeah,
because your body does not want
to adjust like that. You know,
he got big when he fought John Ruiz.
John Ruiz.
He was a good solid two oh five two oh
six he was somewhere around there and
really muscular and moving great and
just looking beautiful. When he was born,
he boxed the shit out of John Ruiz and
he won a heavyweight title and then when
he dropped back down to light heavyweight,
he was getting fucked up man.
His body was just beaten up.
That weight cut was brutal
and when Tara knocked him out,
that was the beginning of
the end of his confidence,
the beginning of the end of his,
of his rap career.
Y'All must've forgot I
tried to. I did. Yeah. No,
I must've forgot body and had
records because I was unconscious.
Here's his rapping wasn't bad in that one
song wasn't bad. It wasn't good enough.
When he walked into the ring
and was wrapping, that was
awesome. It was good TV,
dude. There was a period of a
few years when Roy was on top,
whether it was no one that could touch
him, nobody. You couldn't even touch him.
I mean, it wasn't that early literature.
Vinnie, patsy ends and him fought.
It was the only round ever and
copy bucks history or patterns.
I never touched it. Not even
once. Didn't land one punch,
not out grazing. Hook to the body.
Nothing. Nothing. Couldn't touch him.
Couldn't get close. Yeah,
that's, he was incredible.
When he knocked out Virgil Hill
with a body shot, just stepped in.
I've talked to the liver, send them
to the body. He was unbelievable.
He was unbelievable. But
there's not, you know,
that that can only go on for so long.
That's extreme athleticism.
And he's a defensive defensive
fighter like Floyd is.
Can you imagine them to score
enough? I don't think there'd
be any hits. Well, the,
you know what it is.
For the longest time,
Roy was fighting real
smart and real scared.
And a lot of it was because of a Gerald
McClellan. When Gerald Mcclellan, uh,
got knocked out by nine, nine, Joanne
and in London, that was a ugly,
crazy fight.
And Gerald Mcclellan never recovered.
He had bleeding on the brain and
they still are basically, you know,
he's in a wheelchair and yeah, he's
fucked up and he's aligned. Wow. That guy,
Gerald Mcclellan when I was a
kid was the man. He was the,
the scariest guy in,
uh, I think it was one,
he was trying to make one 60,
I believe Macau and my man,
it was the middle weight fight wasn't
middleweight or was it because Nigel van
was a middle way, but we really should
have been fighting light heavyweight.
The kid was enormous and he was
cutting a lot of weight and they didn't
understand weight cutting
back then the way they do now.
And here's one of the things they do
know is that in the day they also your of
the day in the fight way and yes,
you're right. I think that was,
that was that then it was a postdoc who
cam, I think it was after Mcclellan even,
I think it was like a late mid to late
nineties where they started the day
before weigh ins. Now
knowing that, I don't think,
I don't think either.
Back then they were weren't
replenishing themselves with Ivs.
So what they found out is that all the
people that have had brain damage from
boxing, all of them, it comes from the
lighter weight classes, not brain damage,
but deaths where they, you know, brain
hemorrhage, Allen, the guy inside the,
inside the ring, they found out that
that's on the lighter weight classes.
It doesn't really happen
with the heavyweights.
And the reason is that most heavyweights,
they don't have to lose any weight.
It's no weight limit, no weight on
it, and their hands are a lot heavier.
You're more likely to get knocked out
rather than beat up. Right, right, right.
And that's what people don't understand.
It's like,
it's not even the big concussions.
It's the continual blows, thump,
thump, thump, thump, thump, thump.
The ones that just kind of jar
your head a little bit. Yeah,
that's my soccer players get
brain damage. Yeah. That's,
that's kinda crazy that a fucking soccer
ball can give you brain damage that
flying at you. I know,
but how weak our brains,
Jackie soccer, Bach and Jackie,
really fucking soccer ball,
it seems like you should get it
hit a soccer ball with your head.
They need to make them at a nerf.
You've gotta think twice for you.
Headbutts somebody know you only get so
many of those and you're fucking chamber.
Yeah, they're banking on their
forehead on that one. Yeah.
How many headbutts do you have before
you start forgetting second grade?
You know,
we only have a couple of you going like,
well they always say if you're
going to get hit in the face,
tried to get hit in the forehead
because yeah, at least have a,
you have a plate blocking
your brain. Yeah. It's nice
and thick. It's a good spot.
If you can aim that spot right for
somebody who knows? That's what Tyson he,
you said he would eat a jab
on the forehead to get inside.
He would wobble his way in and then Bam,
take one on the forehead.
It t he would take one to give to.
Well his style was so unique too
because he was so short for heavyweight.
He's under six feet, which is so
rare to have arguably the greatest,
if not one of the greatest heavyweights
of all time. And he's, you know,
he's only like five, 11 or
five. 10 and a half. Yeah.
And he would crouch low and so they
had this big disadvantage and trying to
punch down at this guy, especially when
you spite and we'd gone to Rita. Yeah.
When did he fight with gonorrhea?
When do you find Berbick Tyler?
He had gone, he was burning.
Yeah. What's the matter?
Are you burning? That is so
funny. What did you do to Burbank?
Oh Man. Second round I became the
youngest heavyweight champion ever.
This physical freaks that will
along with like discipline,
like when you get a
physical freak like Tyson,
he was unquestionably a physical freak,
but you get a physical freak, right?
Like him.
And then discipline and focus as well.
Like it's like the young days of Tyson.
You don't keep that shit up
for a certain amount of time,
like the amount of Rpms
that guy was spinning at.
But if you go back to the
young days of Tyson, God damn,
what a scary animal that was.
To have a guy that it was
not just the physical freak,
but was also single minded,
completely focused monastic and his
lifestyle dedicated to being a champion.
Those are just too hard to keep focus
after you get it to you, you'll just,
you want to enjoy the
fruits of your labor wars.
You're talking with custom motto.
Yeah.
While he was with customers
and Kevin Rooney, he was
doing well for a little bit,
but I don't think he ever
respected ruining the way
respected, respected Rooney.
Rooney was like a connection to costs,
but it wasn't the same guy. I wonder,
I wonder what happened if he had ever
got teddy atlas back in his corner.
Teddy and him didn't get along.
I probably would have wasn't terrible.
You Teddy pulled a gun on him because
Mike pushed up on his knees or some shit.
It was bad. Something bad. Yeah. It
got pretty crazy. Whatever it was.
Yeah. That was fucked up. Um, yeah. So I
don't think there'd be working together
on you and you all know.
So what do you guys figure fuck
doesn't work is fine or what?
I think he's done,
I don't know if you know tires
from boxing at least for a year.
I had called mark has before
that fight. Like I said, that's,
that's who's going to win. And I just
said, because Marquez seems pissed.
Yeah. He has something.
He actually, he's like,
I'm not leaving until the judges and
you could just see it and there's work
ethic and the way the fucking look in his
eyes while he was training, I was like,
that guy is going to fuck packet.
You know,
his trainer is suspect for having a knife.
Nacho. Yeah. No, no, no,
no, no. That's the physical
training. You heard about that?
Well he was in the involved in the ball
code trial. Yeah. Turned state's evidence.
Exactly. The Victor Conte
Group. Oh Wow. Yeah.
The contact was torturing him all
week on Twitter. I was watching.
That was pretty interesting.
You know,
we had content on the podcast and he's
explaining to me how the whole ball code
thing went down. And uh, you know, he
said that if this guy's working with him,
he's doing roids yes. Period.
And if you look at them,
it's body looks fucking totally different,
but did according to Victor Conte in the,
uh,
the test that they give you in Nevada,
he said, those are intelligence tests.
He goes, those aren't drug tests,
right? He goes, if you're intelligent,
you pass him. Right? He's like, Damn.
Wow. Yeah. It's like Veda testing.
If apparently is like voluntary
anti-doping association,
they come to your house random times.
You never know when they're coming.
They might, they might not come for
a week. It might be there tomorrow.
You might need to ring your doorbell at
seven o'clock in the morning and wake
you up. You know, unfortunately
come and dress them yet,
which sucks for a fighter because
they need to Goddamn sleep.
They don't want to have to deal with when
you wake and their sleep cycle up and
taking blood out of them, that shit,
that shit, they should work out. I'm,
I'm down for the whole voluntary
aspect of it, but you can't do that.
I don't think you should.
You should be able to do that.
I don't know if they test blood or urine,
but if they do tell us blood,
I hope it's a small mountain because
these guys are training and then they just
show up to do that because some guys have
said no to it that aren't even on the
gr on juice.
They just don't want to deal with the
constant testing because they will,
they will wake you up. He was like,
he was, he didn't like the, uh,
well, uh, Rory Macdonald, Roy McDonald in
his last fight was talking about how the,
he did his first test and it was
annoying. They woke them up, you know,
and he was a, when you're your fighter
man, your sleep is fucking gigantic.
That recovery time is absolutely
huge. It's like a comic.
Yeah. So I mean, as long,
I mean, there should be a way that they
can do it where it doesn't interrupt you.
Okay. It doesn't mean you can't mask
it. You know, if you're doing steroids,
all right, and they say, we'd like you to
come in at three o'clock this afternoon.
There's no way you're going to clean
your system of steroids by three o'clock.
Yeah. So they should be able to
do that. Like where you know,
you come in when the guy's not,
or they should at least go to them when
they're in the gym or something. Yes.
Yeah. You just finished
training unlimited. That's
a great idea. But, but um,
the way they say it is that a guy like
mark has is what you could do is you
build them up in the off season,
you have them on all kinds of shit and
then you slowly taper them off and then
by the time the fight comes, he test
normal. He doesn't have anything,
but he has all the results of
all this stuff in his body.
He has all this thicker muscle and more
endurance and all this craziness and
they don't test for EPO. Epo Is this, uh,
that's the shit that the cyclists use
that makes your red blood cell count
higher. So it makes you carry
more oxygen in your blood.
It's very dangerous so you can get
strokes on it. Is that what lance did?
Supposedly.
Allegedly,
but I think he passed like
500 tasks or something nutty.
He was a bad motherfucker passing tests,
cancer and, but you know this, there's
guys taking all kinds of stuff.
I heard those guys like taken by Agra and
shit. Yes, you're right. You're right.
And taken by Agra is actually
a performance enhancing drug.
Enhances my performance.
Has
lifted his shoulders up automatically.
Multipurpose. Yeah, the
on the box. But it is,
yeah, the athletes use that.
Believe it or not, no joke.
Athletes use it for endurance,
for muscular endurance.
Something about it helps the blood
flow just like the same way it does.
Your Dick is a reason why it gets your
Dick hard like that. Okay, so it's an 80
but it also gives you us cold like
symptoms does it? Yeah. Park close up.
Plugs up your nose, nose and I
got a fucking giant one. So it's,
it's a pain in the ass. Perfect for
your face though. I think it's great.
You're a handsome devil.
Don't sell yourself short
Joe. You know, Russell at one
point in time, like if, if,
if he had to choose another career outside
of music or outside of standup comedy,
it would be deejaying. It's true.
You know, I started in 85 and uh,
I had an SLB to hundreds straight tone
on a straight tone arm and they were belt
drive. Then I would scratch on them and
then the belt would stretch and fall off.
Yes. I used to put 75 cents on my needles
to make it stick. Yeah. I used to,
I used to, I stay at a
quarter, whatever do shows,
we do jokes and then spend a record then
do some more general because my two djs
are really dope, you know, spin bed.
Of course, that's one of my djs.
And starting from scratch from Toronto.
Those are my two guys and they
were on four turntables. Dope.
So scratch place instrumentals and spin
bad cuts acapellas over it and it's
pretty fucking sick cause they don't
rehearse. They just go out and play.
You should actually give him some shit,
talk on a vinyl like
fuck you blah blah blah.
Well they had and had them
scratch that they had,
they could just upload it to their Serato.
When you do stand up comedy shows,
do they play a background music?
No,
they play like when people are
walking in and they play me on,
they play me off and then they
play while people are leaving.
Maybe they should play in the background
while you're performing and you can
fucking like perform like a rant over
sending them to do the coolest music.
Henry Phillips in Doug. Stan hope did
that. Did you ever listen to that? Yeah,
that's my favorite of Doug's a cds.
I think it's something to take the edge
off. I think that's what it's called.
It's awesome man.
Because they caught this crazy groove
while they were doing it and Henry's
playing like was he
playing Acoustic Guitar?
He's playing acoustic
guitar behind it and uh,
Doug is talking and like
goes with the music.
Was it acoustic guitar was at
Piano Guitar, didn't Mitch?
Mitch Hedberg did one too with piano.
I can't remember.
I wasn't when I was in New York last year.
Jeff Ross had keyboardist on
beside them on still rolling. Yeah.
Yeah. Guys have done it. Yeah. The,
the one that I really liked though
is Stan hopes, Stan hope. And um,
that other dude, um, they uh, they,
they just do Henry Phillips. They were,
they were friends.
So like the music,
he knew what the bits where so he knew
like where Doug was going and like how to
ramp up and it was fun. It was like,
it made it cooler. It actually,
it actually aided it.
So you have a,
a new CD that's coming out or new download
tomorrow coming out that's completely
free.
It's on my website.
It's called the bolt one 17
mix. Is this your free time? Uh,
releasing like a free for everyone. This
is free. That's great. What's on it?
It's a just a bunch of craziness.
A Lot, a lot of scratching.
I, I like that. A lot of scratching.
What happened to DJ? Hurricane?
How'd you get his Gig?
Whose Dj?
Hurricane Kane was the DJ before I got,
before I got on. But he was
not a good teacher. Yeah.
Funny is when, you know,
the guys flew me out,
they knew me and I used to send the
boys like Dj videotapes and stuff and so
they were like, Yo, want to fly you
out to work in the studio? I'm like,
you kidding me? I mean, this is
my all time favorite rap group.
It's like joining fucking led Zeppelin.
You know what I mean? I was like,
fuck yeah.
So I went out there and stayed with them
for like a whole week in the studio and
did what we needed to do,
did 10 songs,
and then they pulled me into this one
room. We all sat in Florida was like, Yo,
we want you to be our DJ.
And I'm like, Holy Shit.
Then immediately I thought about a
hurricane. I'm like, what about her game?
He goes, oh, he's just a
rapper. Don't worry about him.
He loves, he loves rapping.
He's not a DJ. So, um,
the next day they sat around
this conference conference
table to give hurricane
a call and um, they, they reached
him on a four way. They go, hey,
and he's like three Amigos, what's
up? What's going on? Um, cane,
um,
we got this other guy and um,
we really like them and we want
them to be our DJ. He's like,
we're really, and he's like,
well, it's my birthday today.
Oh,
I called him on his birthday.
Oh Shit.
Happy Birthday.
Yeah. And it was like, that made me feel
real bad. I was just like, wow, how rude.
I wasn't in it to do what
I did, but you know, just,
it just worked out the way it is
sometimes you've got to do
what you gotta do though.
If you're in a band and it got shot.
L L used to have his DJ cut
creator who was not a good Dj.
And then on his like second album, he
brought in a guy named bobcat. Yeah.
Who was a good DJ,
but he kept cut critter or onstage.
But bobcat would do all the scratching
and everything. It was like,
this is my homie. I got to give him his
job. I got to kill him, keep his job,
but I need somebody can do this job. So
they had two people doing, yeah, two Djs,
but only one would do something.
Wow.
Well that's pretty loyal of him.
Like he had the homie that wasn't
capable of doing what he wanted,
but he wanted to keep
them there cause you're my
homie. But I got another guy that could
do it too, but keep you on the side.
It was kind of confusing,
but he had two DJ's.
Jazzy Jeff told me a story
about when him and uh,
he was on tour with a ll and back in
like that around 87 or something and they
were in the hotel room and Jazzy Jeff
and Bob cat got into a little battle in,
in his room, a Dj battle
in the room, his room,
he was doing shit that like a bobcat was
really dope. So he could do everything.
But then Jeff had to step it up and did
some shit that he couldn't do and he was
like, all right, fuck it.
Can you imagine if he in the room next
to these motherfuckers and try to get
some sleep? They're having a DJ battles.
Well, I'm sure it wasn't very loud.
It's like what you guys have
like families to call right now?
Like we're on the road.
No Dj battle in the room.
That's hilarious.
How do you,
so when you DJ battle and you just like
one person will go and they'll go for
five minutes and the other person goes,
if it's like a friendly battle,
it's just like, hey, you guys can do a
cut. You try and copy each other's cards.
Okay. And then one guy will
get more intricate and you
be like, all right, fuck it.
You win. That's what happens. What
happens in the real competition.
It's like there's no friends
involve your friends on the outer,
but not when in it you can, you're
going to, you're getting flipped off.
You're getting personal,
personal. They got,
they got little phrases on their vinyl
that says, fuck you and your mother. Fuck,
fuck, fuck you and your mother and dead.
That's towards you, Huh? Yeah. Yeah.
And they'll have just for that moment,
and they'll have your name,
they'll have your name, they'll say
it mix master Mike and you know,
really sucked or whatever.
Wow. It gets personal.
All they do that type of shit. And so
they turned comedy. It turns kind of calm.
You're like, people are laughing. Wow.
So did they make their own records?
Is that what it is? The
press, her own vinyl? No,
they would just find sound
bites from other records. Yes.
What was that guy in Denmark says?
Mix Master Mike on it.
You have to find like the right spot.
You can a Beastie boys song.
You could get a Beastie boys song.
Yeah, I think her name's, and this song,
that's one of my favorite videos
by the way of my favorite song.
Just how it's set up. My
Man Adam lesson piece. Adam,
how hard was that? Was that one of the
worst days of your life? Yes, I can even,
I know I couldn't function for three
months after that. You couldn't function.
I couldn't cause I mean Adam was the one
that I was calling and he was the one
that got me into the group.
How did you find out? Um,
I got a call from ad rock called me
in the morning and he said, you know,
Adam is gone. And I was like, fuck.
Did you just go? It just got real.
I knew, I knew he was suffering,
but I didn't know. I didn't know.
I did not understand what you were saying.
You met when Adam died. Yes, I did.
I did not understand. I thought you were
still talking about joining the group.
That's what I've, sorry.
No, no, but you know,
you mother fuckers are not
clear or yeah. Um, having a PR,
a close friend, you,
you'll lose them like that.
It's such a weird thing just to know
that someone can just not exist anymore.
But I was, that was, that was Vernon
Forrest for me. Yeah. When he got shot,
I was all fucked up. You knew Vernon
really well? Yeah, it was, uh,
it was one of my best friends. Yeah.
I was pallbearer at his funeral. Wow.
He always seemed like a nice guy.
He's a fucking awesome dude.
And he had Shane Mosley's number.
Man. That was a crazy little,
it's funny,
there's like certain fighters that even
though like you look at boxing math,
he say, well Shane Mosley beats this
guy and that guy beats Vernon. Yeah,
there's no, there's no logic beat
Vernon. It doesn't work that way.
You know Vernon just had
chains number. Yup. It's crazy.
He like Jane couldn't beat him.
Just like how my cas has was,
you know, pack yellow, at
least beat him a couple years
packet has the ability to beat mark has,
he just has not really
well decisively done it.
First of all,
the test has an iron jaw.
His jaw is made out of fucking steal
that guy. It takes a tremendous po.
A lot of Mexican fighters just
refuse to go down and yeah,
that's also his heart in his
will as it was incredible too.
So like that his resolve inside the
boxing ring along with his power and his
ability to take a shot and then returned
fire makes it a dangerous fight for
pack. Yeah, because pack y'all
has those sort of brawling fights.
Pacbio gets in these,
you know,
these crazy fights where
he's like swarming on dudes,
which is how he ran into that right hand.
And he knew, he knew he had him hurt.
So he's coming after him as he
had him hurt worst time too.
The other thing is that people were
saying that Pacquiao, like, um,
becoming a born again Christian
might have a killer instinct.
Yeah. Well that too. And,
but also might've kept him from doing
some supplements that may be he used to do
and uh, changed his, uh, his
training style because of that,
because physically he
did not look the same.
He didn't look as muscular as he used
to look. You know, it goes with age too,
right? Yeah, absolutely. But
it could have been that also,
he didn't train the same way because
I remember before he had done,
he was going back and forth as to whether
or not he should do a strength and
conditioning. Like you felt like
doing strength and conditioning, uh,
helped us insurance. But then he felt
like it slowed him down a little bit.
I remember he went back and forth,
whether it was one or two fights where
he stopped doing the strength and
conditioning and just did like straight
box and workouts and felt like he had a
better result so it could be that too.
He also has a, I think he's going to end
up suffering from compartment syndrome.
What's that on your eye? Calves.
Cause he's got really muscular calves.
A lot of fighters with muscular calves
developed compartment syndrome and
because you're on the
balls of your feet so much,
your calf muscles are
so big and so strong,
they tighten up and they
seize on you and you,
it's really fucking painful your work.
Cause if you notice in between
rounds they were at Kaos camp. No,
but I'm saying they were
rubbing his calves in between
rounds where they really,
yeah.
Well I thought there was Marquez.
I think they're rubbing Marquez calves
because mark has has problems with his
calves. Cramping. He's had
that in previous fights.
Yeah. He's got boxers legs though. Marquez
Manny has like fucking athletic legs.
Yeah, he's got those giant prince
and I seem legs. Yeah. Crazy fucking,
that's where all the
power comes.
A lot of people don't realize that.
You look at a guy's power punching and
you think that it's all from his own
fucking crazy thighs and calves.
It's the guys who like Tyson
has kind of thighs and calves.
Fuck means that's where
we had skinny ass ankles.
Did he really tighten at some
skinny ass ankles? Really? Yeah.
How would you know I'm going to fight
mattress ankles. Come over here.
Let me see those games. You know
what? I got gigged by the way.
I was at the grove couple of weeks ago.
I bumped into Eddie Bravo. Oh yeah.
I got all nervous when I talked to
them. Really? Why? I don't know.
He's a nice guy too, but I just, you know,
I'm like cut to me as I'm a fan of things
that the man and I'm a genuine fan of
thing, so when I meet
people that I admire that I,
I know I can't do shit they can do right.
I automatically go, holy fuck. Yeah.
It's weird that someone
special still get a little,
a little star struck when you meet
someone. Cool. Yeah. That's strange.
When you did a David Letterman that
wouldn't that the check it out video, uh,
was that all one take or was it, did
you guys get that a few times? Cause I,
that was one of the most memorable uh,
videos where you, you, you started off in,
in the, in the studio and they
started off coming out of a subway.
That was all one take, one take for
real. And it was all in intake. Really.
Guys came in from the subway.
That is bad ass. Yeah.
So they were using wireless mikes
walking down the street. Oh my God.
That's incredible.
And this was one take,
one take and I can hear them
in my monitors. So I'm like
doing it as, as if there were there. Wow.
Cause I'm in the audience performing
by myself. I just awesome.
I always felt like I'm doing a Dj show
and then I got some guests that are
coming in. Wow. This is amazing. I never
saw this before. One of the best videos,
all your videos were always great,
like intergalactic,
your live videos that you always had
your own sense of creativity and what you
guys did that was so unique compared to,
you know, along with your music thing.
So you, and that's, that's what I think
he's really made you guys one of the best.
Well, you know, what are my real
love with the Beastie boys became,
uh, it came after you got to
fight for your right to party.
Like I thought that was cool. Like I
was listening to that shit in my, uh,
my kitchen with my sister stern,
her friends when we're in high school
were like, wow, like brass monkey,
what a cool fucking song.
But then I got ahold of Paul's
Boutique and I remember thinking, wow,
these guys are fucking crazy.
Like they're doing some freaky shit.
Like they went from being
like super duper mainstream.
You gotta fight spire.
Right?
They went from that to like to
like who they really were. Yeah.
It's the joint bow. Exactly. Yeah.
They had some really cool fuck.
As long as it got [inaudible] posts
were good cookie bus. This cookie.
Most bothered dude. Yeah man. Cause I,
I remember going fuck these cooky puss.
I was like cookie puss.
I like both things here.
And then how long did you work
with the Beastie boys for?
I was with the boys for 14,
14,
14 whole years. Yeah. Shoveling the
world and the studio just, you know,
that must've been nuts. It was
incredible. Those are the glory years too.
I remember walking up on stage and
seeing like 400,000 people. I'm like, Oh,
oh my God,
Germany.
Oh my room. And he asked
this boot fucking, that's
ironic. Then read Jewish guys
laying out in Germany.
I felt like
this little fucking Spec.
Oh my God.
That's the craziest thing I've ever heard
in my life. And I'm on and I'm like,
can all of these people here this shit?
I mean,
can they all hear this shit
or the speakers big enough?
Oh my God, that's amazing.
And um, yeah, that's the biggest
crowd ever. Like his biggest,
what's the biggest crowd anybody's
ever performed in front of it?
That's a half a million times.
All right. That sounds about right.
It's gotta be close to the most.
That was the most for me.
It's in one of those random places like
Brazil or our Australian or fucking
Josh showed me a photo of him on
stage that he took from the audience,
from the stage. Uh, he was
opening for Larry the cable guy.
Larry the cable guy
does football stadiums.
He just fucking football stadiums
and moved up, dude. I mean, you, you,
you can't believe how many fucking
people are there to see him.
And Josh took this barrier with
cad cam. Dude, football stadiums.
How many people are in a football game?
It was like 50,000.
He's doing 50,000 seat shows
that it was a sea of human
lievable. This was me in Brooklyn.
Wow. This month. Oh my God.
What the fuck is that? I did the,
uh, the Barclay Center. What,
how many people is that?
Uh,
that night was only like 14,000 or
something like that. Only 14,000. Fuck you
humble brag.
I say only because you know,
fucking Jaycee had played seven nights
for 20,000 feet, but still, dude,
you're a comic. You did
14,000 people. That is a car.
You didn't know whether your standards,
Michael,
you have a phone in front of you.
You should have googled his ass. Hey,
check this out. Here's the Germany
who lied to me. But it was like, yeah,
my mix master Mike is a big fan.
Oh Dude, this of course. No,
this Mike knows you do comedy.
This is nuts, man. That is
slide to the next one is
San Jose the next night. Or
God, dude, this is crazy.
You're doing these giant places.
How many people is in San Jose?
San Jose was like 10 God damn dude.
What is that like? It's awesome.
Chokes doing jugs for that many people.
It's gotta be different than
you and music for him. I mean,
I would think that it's,
what is the feeling like connecting
with that many folks and it's fun.
It's, you know, it's one of
those things I, you know,
that it's not going to last forever,
so you really fucking enjoy it. Yeah.
You know what I mean? It's
like, I know eventually,
probably sooner rather than later I'm
going to be back in theaters and then back
in clubs.
So
why do you say that? Why would
you, because you're going on here.
What are you talking about?
Well, no, you just, you know what you
gotta be prepared for that. You can't,
I don't want to expect anything from
the game. I was just happy to receive.
I should just happy what
you, what you're getting. I think
it's going to keep going, man.
I don't think it's going to
be any difference. Yeah. Here,
here they are in Germany. It just
to show you the crowd size of, uh,
of what it looked like. Watch they go
to a shot right here. That's right.
Take them off to this like,
oh my God.
That is just saying,
please, please do routines. Because like,
Oh my God, for folks at home listening
to this and instead of seeing it,
if you listen to him,
B three, you can imagine this,
this sea of human beings,
that's what 400,000 people looks like.
Wow.
Because, because, because,
wow. Do you enjoy doing the cuts to the
songs that you grew up listening to?
Of course it's been fucking dope.
Um,
what did the thing with those crowds
is you get pissed bottles thrown up on
stage. Yes. Bottles. His bottles. Yeah.
You guys common like it happens
all the time. It does happen.
The guys piss in a bottle and they just
hockey if there's just how kit and it's
supposed to be out of love and
it's like, how's that? Come on.
Who said it's out of love? What we
do to get caught? The dude, the dude,
the dude smoking hag.
Yeah. You're smoking hash.
You probably least likely to throw
a bottle of pissed at someone.
You'd be like ultra sensitive and
paranoid. I'm like, damn, this fucking,
it's not going to work out for
me. Throwing this bottle. The Pis,
what if they do some DNA tests on that
test? They'll start thinking crazy shit.
You know what does my pet has a very
distinct, yeah, yeah. For diabetic.
And what if you took a multivitamin?
Yeah. What is your asparagus eater?
And everybody knows it,
but to do scratching on the brass monkey.
The actual scratches.
Yeah. With that song,
I was getting so fucked up
out of my mind in high school,
drinking big 40 ounces and whatever,
MD 2020 to brass monkey and to be up
on stage was like weird. Like wow.
You just let the government know that
you drank when it was illegal. Okay.
Right there. You were retroactively going
to jail. You're going to be in trouble.
They're gonna move to Canada,
MD, 40 40 mad dog, 2020 mad dog.
2020 is strawberry farms.
That stuff,
that's the shit that makes
you want to fight. Oh my God.
I don't even know what that stuff
is. Oh, you don't? Oh, I'm Canadian.
A friend of mine that is a mark.
No, I don't know what that is.
If you have a beef with somebody,
this guy's letting go. Oh, nice.
A friend of mine and I,
we drank mad dog 2020 and old English
and watch superfly I those mom's liquor,
like a breakdown of it. Look, yes,
yes. Alcohol, right. Whatever it is,
it's designed to make ghetto.
People do terrible things. Exactly.
It's designed for that.
That's what it does to you.
It just complete and it's shoot like these
giant jugs of like shit beer that get
you fucked up and it's designed
by the government. Exactly. Yeah.
Makes you shoot loads in the people back.
It's not a healthy bus dad in that
Cisco, I haven't had that. Oh yes.
It looks that Cisco was this kind
of same thing. Yeah. Another,
another form of 2020 where are you from?
You're from the bay.
I'm from the bay area.
Yeah, from the Yarra. Yay.
From the,
Yay.
That's a,
that's a terrible way to fucking go
out on the town on some malt liquor.
That's a terrible way. It's a terrible,
terrible attitudes or approach. Reality.
The mountain liquor was American beers,
so I never drank. I was 31 really?
Yeah.
I never drank.
I never did anything till I was 31
what made you drink at 31 what was it?
There was a chick that was a, I was
in South Africa and she was like, she,
she was asking me why I didn't drink.
I just said I didn't,
I didn't like the taste of it. I didn't,
I didn't know I was a control freak.
Right. And then I was like, why do you
drink? She goes, it makes me horny.
And I was like,
I'll have two of these plans.
I don't want it to be horny
alone by that dot. Yeah,
but it hurts and you to be confused.
Wow. This is what trunk feels.
And I was the happiest drunk ever. I was
scared that I'd be a miserable drunk. And
I think if you're a miserable drunk,
you were at Clinton real life.
He just barely keeping it together.
That's what I was saying. Alcohol,
just out your shitty personality.
I mean I know a lot of people who are
actual alcoholics and they were real issue
with not knowing what the fuck
they're doing while they're drunk.
But for other people they get a little
buzz and just get country with you.
They know what the fuck they're doing.
They have those thoughts all the time.
They just don't entertain them.
And then they can a couple of drinks
and then they say all this shit.
They been thinking about you anyway and
you're like, you're gross. Giggle a lot.
Like a fucking little girl.
I'm a sweetie.
I want to hug everybody when
they're drunk. When I'm drunk,
I want to be everybody's friend. I want
to make sure everybody gets a drink too.
So I buy it by everybody and I'm
like, Hey, come on. What do you want?
What do you do? Need Segura and Eddie
Bravo, we're in. We showed up in Sydney,
we were there for the UFC and,
and a cigarette and I had a show
and we were a day early. So we said,
what do you want to do? Let's go get
fucked up. We made a conscious decision.
I'm like, my kids aren't here. I
don't have any responsibilities.
I'm walking to the hotel. It's on the
same block. Let's get fucking hammered.
So we went up to this bar and
literally just took over the bar,
but everybody drinks. I spent
thousands of dollars. Everybody in the,
I know you have,
I bought everybody in the bar drinks.
We just constantly round of drinks for
everybody you want to do you want to
Drake mother Fucker, get away.
Give me a high five and we just,
by the end of the night,
we were just hammered eating food.
The whole evening was a blur,
but one of those old school nights where
you just really go off like that and
your planet.
Yeah, it's fun. The only problem with
the next day, the next day might,
my head was in a vice while I
was on stage. I was like, oh,
I got fucked up on Friday
and not even that fucked up,
but I got fucked up on Friday and I,
I,
I ended up just not doing anything
Saturday night and watched the fight and
drove back to La is what I did.
But you watching the in Vegas,
I watched it at my house. I
couldn't get tickets. Yeah,
you couldn't get any tickets. Right. I
wanted ringside and I was like, fuck it.
If I, if I can't be ringside at that
fight, I'm going to watch it at home.
If that's the one you
want to be there for.
Are you going to be in Vegas for
July or December 31st 29 I want to,
I want can I can, yes. Yes. That's why I'm
asking is the one I really am cause I'm,
I'm scheduling a little squirrel and those
away right now. Yes, please. Yeah. Okay.
You got it. Yeah. That's going to be a fun
one. Who's on that bill? Cain Velasquez.
The Santos. Big Boys. Yeah. Yeah.
What you, what do you think? Well
look man, you always had a lot of time
off and I'm not, that's a good or a bad.
Well you had a big
fight though with Silva.
He fought bigfoot Silva
and beat the shit out.
He just ran through them like a
fucking hot knife through butter.
It was beautiful. It was a perfect
fight for him. He like you literally,
he just ran through them,
did everything perfect.
But I think that cane already
has been knocked out by junior,
so we know that junior can win.
We know that junior,
if he connects with that haymaker
haymaker right hand like you did.
We know that he can win.
But the question is can junior deal with
canes pace if cane doesn't get knocked
out in the first couple of rounds,
that's the real,
the real plan for cane is to
drag jr until like the third,
fourth and fifth round because
cane has ridiculous endurance.
His endurance is just insane.
Like he does conditioning drills
and he beats like lightweights.
It's really nuts for God.
It's 240 pounds that has
the kind of conditioning and
the pace that he could put
on.
So for him it's like imperative that he'd
get out of the first and second rounds
and make junior slowed down a little.
Cause junior's slowed down in fights.
He slowed down in the Roy Nelson fine.
He slowed down and fights.
You can't slow down against cane cause
cane and the third round it's the same
gas tank that he had in the first round.
So that's when it gets really crazy.
If Cain forthright Santos has ground game,
it's very good.
You don't ever see it.
You don't ever see if it's because
it's not going to get a job.
But also because it's
takedown defense is insane.
It's take down the fence is fantastic,
but the reason why it's
takedown defense as goods,
because he fucking works
on it tremendously.
He works on all the
aspects of his wrestling,
not just the take downs but take
down defense and take down all fence.
I mean he took down Shane Carwyn when
they fought and it was almost like to
prove a point and his and his
ground games as far as submissions,
it's also top notch.
People don't realize it,
but he's like a high level brown
belt, almost a black belt. He remains,
you might've be black belt now I,
I'm not sure, but whatever it is,
I get word from the people that have
trained with him like, and he's,
and he's bad motherfucker on the ground.
Like you just don't see it because he's
knocking everybody senseless, you know?
And he's, he's so good with his boxing,
but he doesn't have any holes in his game.
I mean, he's the fucking UFC
heavyweight champion. You know,
you really can't get to that position
if you have any holes in your game,
you know, and especially what
like three Carwyn suffered.
I'm a little out of the loop on
what's, because a knee, right? Yeah.
He tore his name.
I was really looking forward to that
fight with him and now it's Carwyn has had
a bunch of surgeries so far because
Carlin has been through a lot of like
physical trauma,
not just in fighting but in football.
He played football and uh,
you know,
he said that's where the majority of his
injuries came from looking at all sorts
of back problems.
And he had a,
he had to get surgery to open up
his spinal column and he was still,
when I saw him, it was like maybe
six or seven months ago and we were,
we were talking about and he still
wasn't 100% and he's still, you know,
like things are starting
to move better again.
But he was in constant pain
before and it was a numbness,
numbness in his hands and shit like that.
And Kang had his elbow scope before the
Franklin fight. How far out? September.
Wow, man. That's crazy. What
was that fight in October?
No, if I was in November.
Whoa. So he played it just about six weeks
out. Yeah. Yeah. That's what they say.
You can get back to full
training after six weeks.
But for him like that wasn't enough.
I bet he probably trained while I was
still sore. It's fucked. Telling me, hey,
it was training.
One of the Sore Anderson Silva defended
his title against Travis Luder five
weeks after he had knee
surgery on both knees.
He had both his knees scoped and meniscus
and like barely trained and caught
Travis Luder in a triangle.
So it clamped down with his knees operated
on knees and elbow the fuck out of
him until Travis tapped. There's a lot of
guys that take crazy chances like that.
And Anderson's followed
a fucked up rib to,
well Anderson has like planning
a, yeah, do g all the way down,
right? I mean, yeah,
if you get a chance to watch that
guy in the next couple of years,
you've gotta he got to go live,
folks.
You gotta you gotta see this guy
before he retired? Dude, I had to,
I had a chance to hold his
belt and really, you know,
really it was like, fuck,
I'm holding his belt. Fuck
yeah. Wow. My favorite fighters,
I mean there's Bruce Lee and then for
me there's Anderson Silva like Anderson
and this a lot. He's fucking
highly unbeatable. Fuck.
He says what he does to guys
now is spooky. It's not even,
it's not even fun to watch anymore.
The last fight,
the last fight where he kept
going to the cage going, Oh yeah,
you can get me right here.
Yeah. Or Stephan Bonner.
He just picks back up against the
cage. It's like, come on, come on.
Come on over here. And yeah, that's the
niche of the solar plexus. That's true.
That wasn't nice.
And he's done that to two people in a
row now and did that same knee on the
ground to chill son and then
standing up to Stephan Bonner. Yeah,
he's a master at driving.
It flexes.
His body doesn't reflect the guy
you would think who's doing that,
you know and bond or is not a walk over.
You know he's not well liked
Guy Anderson's really strong.
He's a lot stronger than people
think and it's technique.
It's fucking technique is amazing.
His technique and his reflexes,
his speed and his ability
to cover distance.
He can sneak up on you before you
even know what's happening and blast.
You like his ability to close the
distance is really like inhuman or they're
going to try and make the Jones fight.
John Bones Jones. Yeah and Anderson.
That's most likely cause it doesn't
look like GSP wants that right now.
It looks like GSP a wants to defend
his title at welterweight first.
And the other thing that GSP is thinking
is that if he goes up to one 85 he's
not going to be able to
go down to one 70 again.
Just like with Roy Jones
we were talking about that.
You gotta be real careful about that
because once your body commits to a new
size, it does not want
to go back. And like,
especially over like a couple of months,
whatever you're training campus,
you could have a real hard
time unless you're super,
super disciplined about your diet from
the moment your last fight is to now
you're going to have a hard time
cutting that weight cause you're,
you're going to have to trick your body
into getting smaller. And if you don't,
you're going to be weak as fuck.
You know,
so he wants to make sure that if
he goes up to one 85 that this,
he's going to stay there.
Yeah. He's got to have,
I think it should have two more fights
before he considers moving off. Well,
I think he's got a fight. Johnny Hendricks
or Nick Diaz. Those are the two first.
Johny Hendricks, the one with
the beard. Yeah. And that
crazy left hand. Yeah. Yeah.
Johnny Hendricks. I think
nick and him need to settle
that Johnny Hendricks. Well,
nick and him could settle that business.
That's very much a possibility. Um,
I would definitely love to see that
fight. I would love to see that fight. Um,
but I would love to see the
Hendricks fight as well.
I would love to see DNS versus Hendrix.
You know,
I think that's another
interesting too. Well, you know,
I don't know if Nick Diaz should
have to fight an eliminator.
I think if anybody should
get a title shot, it should
be d as if I had a gas. But,
um,
I couldn't be mad at you.
If you wanted to put together a
Diaz versus Hendricks fight Schick,
that would be so sick. That
would be a sacrifice. God Damn.
That'd be a great fight.
You know what else I want to say?
I want to see conduit versus Rory
Macdonald. I want to see that rematch,
especially after Roy called them out and
after the fight and you know, he said,
you, you humiliated me. Like I said
it, it was crazy way so uncomfortable,
but he wants to fuck him up so bad.
The kids lips are trembling. You know?
I think that'd be a
really interesting fight,
especially when you see how God damn good.
He looked in that Bj fight his
combinations, footwork, shields, condit.
Right. Um, when was this?
It's didn't knife fight.
I don't want mine to be Mac.
Maybe pre UFC.
They don't think so though. But
this is a Joe. What if Rory,
what fought with fought Bj in his prime?
Um,
would have been [inaudible] BJ's client
shirt. Certainly would've been. Yeah,
they fought in a,
I think they fought in rumble on the rock
before Jake shells and Carlos condit.
Yeah. They know they did
fight. That's right. Yeah.
Jake shields beat him by decision.
I think it was rumble on the rock.
Yep. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Rumble on the
rock. Yeah. Jake beat him by decision.
Jake's uh, quite a bit bigger,
uh, at, uh, well, you know,
he fought a lot at one 85.
Actually, I want to take that back.
I don't think he gets
bigger cause I think Carlos,
if you wanted to confide
in [inaudible] 85 too,
if he just bulked up a little bit.
And Jake's not really a natural a
middleweight. I mean, he fought middle,
he fought Dan Henderson. He fought,
uh, some, some Robbie Lawler guys.
He's a small guy. You know, he's
a Vegan. Yeah. Yeah. I've been a,
I've been a Vegan his whole life.
Really? Yeah. Vegetarian at least. Um,
I mean sometimes he'll, uh, he'll
eat eggs I think. Um, and uh, maybe,
maybe some, uh, some, uh, you
know, dairy or something like that.
But for the most part he's at least a
vegetarian. He's a really nice guy. Yeah.
He's a great guy. It's just like a really
fucking chill dude. Yeah. Yeah. Well,
you know, his, uh, his temperament,
like when you're around them,
you would never imagine it'd be
so ferocious inside the cage.
He just one of those guys that has this
unbelievable ground game, like his,
his ground game,
his Jiu Jitsu is so fucking strong,
but he can't make his striking like that.
The levels are so different. He has
this like black belt level, ground game,
like sick ground game,
and then he has this sort of blue belt
dish stand up game and you can't really,
it's really interesting.
Some people's bodies or what maybe
the athleticism that they have,
whatever it is, it doesn't work for
striking. It's real weird, you know, like
striking.
And I always find striking in MMA a lot
different because he can't really plant
your feet the same way,
right?
So it's more impressive when
somebody gets knocked out in a,
in an octagon for me because they
really had to fucking plan that shot.
Right.
As opposed to w w what Russell saying
for people who don't understand is you
have to stand in a different stance.
Uh,
you have to stand like more square and
you have to always be worried to sprawl
or to deflect any sort of take
downs and your leg got a check.
So you stand a little bit
of so many other things.
You've got to so many variables as
opposed to like a boxing stance where you
don't ever have to protect your legs.
You know,
you just can't stay tight to your body.
The problem with that is
when I watch boxing now,
all I think about his leg kicks.
Just someone,
some nasty motherfucker like Pedro Huizar
slamming us Shin into your leg there
and Pedro, his uh, whew.
That's at all the guys
I've ever seen kick guys.
He's the one that scared me the most.
Pedro his are used to kick dude's in
the legs. He used to just go, God Deli.
You would like hearing them
inside and you're shooting.
It sounded like a two wooden
sticks connected. It was horrible.
It sounded like someone picked her head.
Liberty fucking giant thighs are
two huge thighs. I've seen him.
I saw him at the Beverly Hills Jujitsu,
kicked the back to that mother fucker
kicks hard. It's not just like,
it's not like you, I wonder how hard
that is when you see him kick a bag.
You know how much the bag weighs and see
the bag fucking intent from his giant
shins.
It sounds like someone's hitting up a
big side of beef with a baseball bat like
right in me ass part. Just funk. He's,
he's the one that all the dudes I've
ever seen like kick anybody that that
scared me and made me the most
uncomfortable watching it.
So I see that in boxing.
No,
it's just like see like why wouldn't
you just kick some of these legs?
It's right there.
The real,
the most exciting striking would be a
professional moy Tai if they really get,
if they got real money involved and
professional Muay Thai because like people
love the UFC.
But quite honestly a lot of people liked
the striking aspect of it more than
they even like the ground aspect.
Yeah.
I mean you know,
but now we got this new generation
who grew up training everything.
Yeah. And the first gen, the
first wave was I do this,
you do that and now and then
those guys that, okay I did this,
now I'm learning that now
it's like I know everything.
If you could get someone to bank roll a
top level Moyie Thai guy finding a top
level boxer and let the Moitai got kicked.
The boxer,
you would see like people really open
their eyes as to how silly just circular
boxing is. If you've got a
guy who is able to, you know,
keep you off with the tape and then
slam a couple of leg kicks in, yeah,
you got a useless leg by
the end of the first round,
you can't move right anymore.
It can't Bob and weave right anymore and
then he starts attacking the inside of
your leg and he starts elbow and you in
the face and he's grabbing the back of
the head and kneeing you and the body.
It wouldn't last like you have a,
you have a couple of minutes to get off
good punches and hurt him. If you don't,
he's slowly going to chip away at your
foundation and then you're, you're fucked.
Like we were watching boxing.
We're really watching a very
flawed method of fighting.
It's a good idea if you're
fighting in a bar, if you don't,
you don't want to kick somebody as
you weren't slippery shoes and shit.
It's good to,
you know,
to know how to stand up because if
you go to the ground with someone,
there's a whole group of people they
could all start punting you when you're
down.
It's better to be able to stand up and,
and boxing is the best
way to get that off.
But for like just a competition
of fighting, it's like man,
there's a lot of holes in that sport does,
you know if guy could take you down,
I've forgotten kick your legs.
If a guy can elbow you,
forgot can grab you and need
your body and your face.
You're utilizing all your weaponry.
But it's funny how it's
still like super popular.
Like the watching of like the Marquez
fight in the pack can't fight.
That was probably like the most
watched sporting event of the year.
Packing on May 23 million
and mark has made six. Yeah.
Just when you think that the
s the sport is going to limit,
it's like people are still interested.
This still great fighters,
this new wave of fighters.
I mean obviously [inaudible] amazing
Broner could Canelo Alvarez. Yeah,
that's a great, they talking
about making that fine. Oh my God.
Cause he's do Canelo and um, and Broner
that owner, is that what the next fight?
I think Bronner's. Got It. I
think Broner could outbox him,
I think boners and hit him here. Is He?
I think Broner yeah. Is a lighter weight.
Well what does Alvarez funny one 54 what
is 47 or 54 one of them will Alvarez.
Let's find out. How about a Floyd
vs Canelo I floated out outbox him.
Yeah, but that's all that's left
now. That man he got knocked out.
I mean he's got not that many
big name fights man. Yeah.
See this kid was born in 1990.
She's crazy.
That Canelo's that's,
he's the little Hussein.
He beats and he's a red headed Mexican.
That beats the fuck out of people.
So that is so strange.
What a weird fucking cat he is.
His father.
And all of his brothers have dark hair.
Yeah.
Somewhere there's an Irish family.
His mother with a Mexican kid
once a month is a redhead.
All the other brothers have dark hair,
but his mom's a redhead and that's where
he got it from. That's amazing, man.
That kid is a beast.
A beast with no neck.
Yeah. He's the lightweight
champion. So he's one 35
that's Canelo's one 35. Yeah, that's
Oscar's boy Oscar. Like I think, I mean,
he's obviously going to grow out of that
weight is going to end up at one 47.
Well,
it's a third [inaudible] 15.
No, he's fighting. Well, I'm
sorry, let me rephrase that.
He started out his first weight
class where you want a title. He,
uh, he beat the current IBF
lightweight champion. I fucked up,
but he is, um, uh, fighting
as a welterweight now.
And I think that's where Broner has got
to go because he can't make him wait
anymore. He might've been fighting as a
welterweight his whole career, I think.
I think, um, I'm incorrect.
I think what it's saying that
his third bout of his career, uh,
was uh,
a guy who at this point in time is IBF
lightweight champion Miguel Vasquez.
So Vasquez was welterweight and drop
down to light weight. They just,
they phrased it funny. Um,
he's um, yeah, he's uh,
he's only fucking, what
is it, 22 years? 22 years.
That's ridiculous to be like
that high level at 22 years old.
Our careers are older than him. Do you
realize that? Yeah, they are. Well I'm,
my career is two years
older than this kid. Yeah.
It's fascinating watching the young
people like this come up, these,
this new new breed and he's a monster too.
He's a scary fucking kid.
He had his kid gets dudes down,
you can take a punch to,
it's like a fucking Wa walking.
I think he was,
I think it was very gentle with
Moseley when he fought him. Really.
I think it showed him a lot,
lot more respect than he should have.
Do you think he's just being nice? Just
like, I really do think he's being nice.
I think Delaware of, hey listen, Mosley
and I are partners. I'm a lot of things.
Do you think you can not beat the
shit out of exactly. Just beat him.
It was his last few fights,
man. Especially the, uh, the,
the Kermit citron fine. Oh,
he beat the shit out of, he's a killer
man. He's a killer. He's a killer.
That's a fucking hard way to make
it live it, man. That's a hard way.
When you leave a boxing match,
like, um, did you see, um, uh,
Berto and, uh, Guerrero fight great fight,
but at the end of the fight when Burritos,
eyes,
both eyes are completely shut and
you're at home going, fuck that.
Fuck doing that for living.
Could you imagine if Berto had been
more active instead of having that 14,
15 months off? He wouldn't, I
think you could have squeezed,
scraped that a decision. Maybe. I
mean, maybe even or not, who knows?
But the bottom line is he was prepared
and Guerra was prepared. And Guerra,
I'll beat him. I mean, he's a beast
to, and you're talking about, um,
Floyd versus core. Arrow
is a beast man. Um,
I don't know if he can get in on Floyd.
Floyd is just such a master box or I don't
think he deserves a shot yet. I don't,
true desert beat the fuck out of
Berto like that. I think. I think so.
I think, I mean, why should I
beat the fuck out of him? I mean,
closer to decision than that. If Floyd
is going to be picking his fights,
he should pick more competitive
fights. The surgeon, Sergio Martinez,
that would be a great fight. My team
is a lot bigger than him. A lot bigger.
You know, they're one 54 really
know Sergio can't really, I mean,
he can make one 54 it's a
struggle. So yeah, Floyd,
he doesn't cut any weight when he gets,
if he's fighting at one 54,
he's not a big guy. Martinez as much
bigger than him. I think it'd be awesome.
You get store or Shavez Martinez rematch.
I was at gray fucking fight the good
fight. Oh. Oh. When Chavez knocked,
almost knocked him out. But
the 12th round Brown. Yeah.
It was like Meldrick Taylor,
uh, uh, Julio, Cesar Chavez.
Was that Chavez a fun when he beat the
shit out of her fucking ruined metrics,
correct? Yes. He came out
with a couple seconds,
three second last Richard Steele stopped
that fight and needing to rightly show
fucking Meldrick Taylor was
never the same after. Yeah.
But even though that, that was
like there was a brutal beat down.
It was the, the, the,
the craziness of the pack out knockout
it clips that like the seeing seeing pack
on like face plant like that, that
was one of the most drum I was scared.
I genuinely thought he was dead.
He could have been dead. Yeah.
That was one of the most traumatic
losses I think I've ever seen. And Yeah,
the only other Asian, they hit the
canvas like that was Ducote Cayman.
He didn't even hit the, it's
like that back wilted. He wilted,
he wilted over a barrage of punches and
then his head, that guy in the podcast.
So I'm going to try to get boom,
boom. Manzini on the podcast. Yeah.
My publicist says he knows him apparently.
He awesome fucking awesome. Man,
Y'all watch that guy? Yeah,
he does. I watched that guy
fight a hundred times, man.
I'm,
I don't know how many times a week,
but when I was a kid was he from Rhode
Island reminded me of Pennsylvania.
He was a bad mother fucker. But Youngstown
was he from Youngstown? Youngstown,
Ohio. Oh yeah. Him and Kelly Pavlik
can't down because another one,
their kids crazy.
He was supposed to fight ward,
but then ward ward got hurt and training.
Just recently. Andre Ward get hurt.
That guy has the best right now. He's the
one of the best. He's, he's incredible.
He's an incredible technician.
That's the guy that Nick Diaz is doing
is a lot of his boxing work with. Yup.
Do you have a lot of sparring with that
guy? You know, you wonder what Dee has.
His boxing is so fucking sharp. We've
sparred Andre Ward. Dude, come on son.
I'm one of the con fight Saturday. If
you want to go all, you really can't.
I'm going to be in the UFC, UFC fight
that Saturday. Oh, Nelson versus, yeah.
What time is the confines? What time's
it start? Um, probably it's in La,
so I don't know. Oh, it's in La at the La
Sports are right here. Oh really? Yeah.
And what's what's going on with Amir Khan?
Was he to him and he's fighting
Carlos Molina and uh, he's,
he's training that Andre Ward's Jim now
with Andres Virgil Hunter. Oh really?
Yeah. So he left Freddy Roach.
Freddie? Yeah, he left Freddy.
What did he desired Freddy?
He fired Freddy.
What did he decide that Freddy was
given? Pack out too much tension. No, he,
I actually, he told me how it was little
bit of it, but Kahn told me, he said,
you know, he called Freddy after and
spoke to him personally and said, right,
you know,
we had a good run.
I think I need to switch up my game
and learn some different things.
That's not a bad idea,
man.
Sometimes just doing that alone is
really good for a fighter. Just listen.
He said he's been doing it.
Learning things with Virgil hunter that
he never ever did in his boxing and
fresh starts are so important,
especially if you can have a fresh
start with someone who's got a different
approach. You know, I know
like gray Maynard, uh,
went from extreme coture to Aka and
he's very happy with doing that.
Like it was a big, big, you know,
big change for him who up to San
Jose to start training there.
But apparently he's experiencing
some great results with that.
I think anytime in your life
you make like a big change,
you force your brain to start re examining
everything you do because the drive
to work is the store
you go to is different. You
know, everything's different.
Like it's almost like a little
fresh start is in your existence.
That shit's important for
a creative person too. You
know, and boxing and spine,
the May believe it or not is
creative because like you're,
you're creating those combinations as
you're throwing them inside the cage.
You can't become predictable.
Yes, absolutely. Absolutely.
And that predictability,
even though people don't,
people think of creativity as being
something that's always constructive and
artistic and not destructive,
like kicking someone's ass,
but really kicking someone's ass can
be creative because there's a lot too.
There's a groove and a flow to like a
contest to like a guy attacking and you
countering and you moving
and him reacting. There's
like a lot of orchestration.
And when that's why like
a guy like Anderson,
when he like leads guys
and he's sizing people up,
then all suddenly front kicks a dude in
the face and knocks him out like he did
in the Vituro fight.
He saw like a movement.
He saw that that's what happened
with Congo against rich. I'm rich.
Must've been watching his legs the whole
time and kind get with the right hand.
Well also,
rich should have never taken
that fight at that weight class.
He hadn't fought in that
weight class since 2006 he
had to move up. Yeah, he was,
no, he didn't move down. He had to been
a loser. Fuck load away. Wow. The looks,
the photos of the, that
they got of him. Uh,
entering into the Wayans were horrific.
He looked like he was in Auschwitz.
I mean, it's crazy. It's
faced with so sucked in.
He dehydrated the shit
out of himself for that.
And that's one thing that's really hard
on your body and it's hard on your body
when you're 20,
but it's really hard and your body when
you're 40 and Kang doesn't have to do
that. Congress losing like a little bit
of weight probably. But Kang is like,
one of those guys had fights like closer
to what he actually ways maybe it goes
up five, six pounds.
Well that's healthy man.
That's actually an intelligent
way to do it. Yeah. The um,
the guys who cut a
tremendous amount of weight,
they take a risk and they
also get sick a lot. Um,
that's what happened with
Mike Swick this weekend.
Apparently Mike's Wiki gotten
sick the week of the fight and uh,
he just didn't look up self against
Matt Brown and Matt Brown was on fucking
fire and uh,
just chaos.
Mike was a horrific chaos too.
But that if you look at that fight like a,
that's a perfect example.
Why like weight cutting can be tricky.
Yeah.
I'm a big,
I'm a big proponent of looking at whose
bodies dry when they get into the ring.
That's, that's big too.
Always what I do, I go,
who do you think's going gonna win over
here. Let me see them enter the ring.
And I'll tell you,
unless I saw when I saw mark has walked
in the ring and go and he will and he's
sweating like crazy. Right?
Yeah. I mean he's very hydrated.
What, What's interesting about
the mark has packout fight though,
is that I watched it, um,
with the Dana White and um,
Sam tripling and while we were watching
it we were saying like, he, like mark has,
is not throwing that many punches.
Like he's like being like way more
conservative and his punch output was
economizing. Yeah. We were
wondering if it was that,
and we also wonder if it was just the
fact that he put on all that extra muscle
and he'd been doing, like they
showed him those a 24, seven,
they showed all the of and how he was
trying. He was definitely in. Yeah.
Well look if fucking paid off.
He never knocked them out before
and then one punch flatlines him.
I mean he never even knocked him
down before he staggered them. Yeah.
Knock down a third round
and this one and then a,
that was a great knock down to was. Yeah,
but he didn't go after him after that.
You notice that? Oh no, he took his time.
He didn't want to run into anything.
Look what happened.
Jackie out tagged him.
Had Him hurt back peddling the whole time.
He could've,
he could've stepped it up a little bit
cause he really just let him off the hook.
Who knows when it,
well it worked out.
No sense of being critical cause I
remember when I would train and my coach
would tell me, don't fucking step back
and admire your work. Get in there,
watch it later.
Does anybody that I compare when
I compare the great boxers is you,
how would Russell Peters just handled it?
What my coach would tell me.
I really don't think so. You know,
showing them a bitch way. A Yoda,
Yoda. Do you think they'd pop?
Gail's done. You think that will,
I don't think he's done. Do you think
you can come back from a knockout?
I think he come back, no doubt. I
think it wasn't a war of attrition.
He got knocked out and that's, that's the,
at least the easiest way to come back.
Do you think about the amount of
blows and he's already taken though,
like cause like that really has an
effect when you get KOD like that.
And then on top of that you've had,
how many fights is he at?
Is he had 50 plus fights?
Yeah. How many fights?
About 56 think about how many
fights I guys had and all the,
the blows that he's taken in those fights,
all the blows that he's taken and
training. There's gonna come a time or he,
I think he's got about another
two years left on it. Yeah.
I think he's very prideful. And he
did. It was embarrassing for him.
Especially when he looks back at it.
He doesn't want to go out and be
remembered like that. Yeah, he does it.
He's such a nice guy,
man.
It's hard to watch a really nice guy get
knocked out like that. Yeah. You know,
he's such a sweet, no,
no mean bone in his body.
I mean, you know, um, it's
just that one matchup.
It's too bad that him and Floyd never
fought, cause that would have been gone.
Damn.
Fascinating.
Yeah.
I always said Floyd was waiting for Manny
to get into a few more brawls and get
work himself down and then, and then come
in and fight them and when real easy.
Yep.
Exactly what he was doing.
Look for, it's not stupid,
but he fucked up with this one.
He should've taught,
caught him right after that last
fight. Right after that, he, uh,
he lost his title to Bradley. Yeah.
But the Bradley fight was bullshit.
He won that fight.
It was one of the worst decisions.
That was the worst decision ever.
That wasn't right. That was,
he should have stepped in, right? Yeah.
Yeah. Maybe. Maybe he has a mirror
match with Bradley now. Enough of this,
let me get fuzzy. You know what, Bradley?
I don't know what Bradley's
doing and what his, yeah,
he's kind of fallen into
obscurity somewhere.
I think when you get knocked
unconscious the way man, Manny did,
I don't think you're even
allowed to fight for a long time.
I think you have to wait
at least six months off.
I think you had to take six months.
All Amir got knocked out in July.
Not like that. Yeah, that's true. It's
different going to knock out. That's,
that's unconscious face down for 10 15
minutes. You know, people can say, oh,
there's no difference. Concussions
and concussion. That is a severe case.
That's a severe concussion.
There's a difference between that and
getting rocked and the referee stops it
because a lot of those guys are never
really out cold if you're, you know,
and is it like people say that
like, well, there's no difference.
Even though the the brain is,
if the brain's getting concussed,
whether or not you lose
consciousness is no difference.
I got to think that when your body says,
you know what,
let's just shut the consciousness down.
We need vital functions only.
Let's keep this fuck
knowing where you are.
I got to think that that somehow is
worse than just a regular concussion.
Your bond is shutting off.
That shit can't be worse.
And I don't know what kind of statistics
they've done on that medically,
but just using simple logic,
you would have to say that losing your
consciousness because of a punch is worse
than not losing your consciousness when
your brain has so much trauma that it
shuts everything down and
there's no more thinking.
That's got to be a bad sign. And
when that happens, like in a,
in a MMA fight, you know, I don't,
you rarely see the guy again for like a
good solid six months because you need
like three months of no head contact,
no nothing.
And if you go back in the gym too soon
and you start boxing and sparring and get
thudded and wobbled when you're still
recovering from that earlier concussion
mean who knows how much shit
is going on inside your head.
Who knows exactly who knows
what connective tissues
have been separated and who
knows what part of your brain's
been damaged? Who knows,
who knows exactly what
the extent of it is.
And if you don't take that time off
and let your brain really heal up.
I have a friend who got hit in the head
with a golf ball and he said he wasn't
the same for six months.
Oh, I have a, there was a kid who it's uh,
a fan I guess. Well,
yeah, he's a fan. He, uh,
his family hit me up because
he was a 17 year old kid hit.
He had diabetes and his friends and him
are going to play golf and he went to
sit by a tree to go shoot as a insulin.
His friend shot the ball,
it ricocheted off the tree and hit him
in the head and he'd say he was fine.
He walked away and then he just collapsed.
And then he was in a coma for like two
weeks. When he came out of the coma,
he was in, he had full amnesia,
full, didn't remember his name,
his mom, dad, nobody. Whoa.
So he went into um, wow.
Rehab for the next, uh, three to
six months or something like that.
And so they could try and work
as memory back. And then, uh,
before he had the accident,
he was a big fan of mine.
And one day one of his friends came
over and put on my DVD and the kid
remembered every fucking word out of my
mouth and I started crying when I got
the email and then I went
visited the Guy Cause uh, he, it,
it started triggering back his memory.
Wow,
that's crazy. A Golf Balk and make
you forget who you are. Yup. Yup.
And it ricocheted,
it wasn't even like direct hit.
And is that to to the temple or is that
like to the penal gland at where's that?
It must have been right in the
temple temple area. I think the
pineal glands in the middle somewhere.
I don't think you really get
to that sucker. Right. It's
in the main, yeah, the, the,
the back of the head supposed
to be real dangerous.
That's why strikes the back of
the head or in legal in MMA. Yeah.
But what's interesting is a kick to the
back of the head when a guy standing,
if your roundhouse kick a guy, a lot
of the impact is the back of the head,
but that's legal and that shut
in your screen off right there.
The neck kick, especially a
neck kicks in. A lot of boxing.
I was trying to catch you and
you into right. Well the, yeah,
you're kind of chopped down.
Like Ernesto who style they
chopped down with that head kick.
I remember that guy. That shit
goes over your shoulder. Oh,
hang down your neck and night and night.
Speaking of Dutch fighters,
what's Overeem?
Overeem is fighting and a February
or January through December rather,
December 31st that same card, the 29th
year coming to, yeah, 29th. I said 31st.
Jesus Christ. I can't get the date right
on New Year's eve moments. Yeah. It's um,
I'm not even doing a New Year's eve
show this year. As a first year.
I'm having a party at my house. If
you in a car, maybe I will do that.
You're going to come. Um, shit's been
bed's going to be playing too. Yeah,
I'll be playing. It's been,
it'll be playing guys.
You're going to have djs at your Parnell.
How SpaceX Steve Wonder
probably come play night.
Stevie wonder even have to play.
Do you know Stevie wonder and columns
if you want fucking throw down,
but catering, I'm asking you a
question. This is Stevie wonder.
The same Guy Dj Steve One at one at one
day. Oh, his name is Steve wonder. Yeah.
That's ridiculous. You can't call yourself
Steve Wonder God does a Stevie wonder.
How the fuck can you call
yourself Steve wonder.
I think it's in honor of Oh and
honor. Um, how about the girl fights?
Joe Ronda Rousey that's going to be in la.
In Anaheim.
I like some of those girls Cyborg up too.
I like those girls with Cyborg.
He's a beast.
She's up to about one 55 solid is knowing
body fat ever going to beat Cyborg and
no one's ever going to beat
it, right? Oh, who knows?
They bring in an actual cyborg. Her
and Rhonda Rousey. Ronda Rousey,
her and Rhonda Rousey would
be a big fight. But, um,
right now the first ever UFC female fight
is the headlining fight in UFC one 57,
which is a live from Anaheim.
It's Ronda Rousey versus Liz Carmouche.
I hope I'm saying his name correctly,
but Liz Carmouche is like the
first openly gay fighter, uh,
competing in the UFC cause she's getting,
she's a lesbian.
It was a big old lesbian
chicken ass, so, okay.
Called chicken. Big Old Lesbian, right.
Yeah. Nothing wrong with it. It's not,
but you know, she listens. She's a good
fighter. If you love policy, I love Pussy.
Right. Liz loves pussy. Okay. So we're
on her team. We're on team puts it.
She can't wrestle, but you
should see her box. [inaudible]
was coming. It just took some time. Did
shoulders on it again to silo bitch,
son of a bitch. Yeah. This, uh,
January 20 or December 20. I did it
again. 29. December 29th garde is a,
this is a good fucking guard. It's
junior dos Santos, Cain Velasquez,
Tim Boetsch versus cost of
Phillipo. Okay. So that means that,
um, oh, okay. Overeem is not on that card.
Overeem is on the
February super bowl card.
That's a career fucking card.
He's fighting big foot silver.
That's Joe say Aldo versus
Frankie Edgar to sun.
I like all though, dude,
that it is this, this card,
Josie Aldo versus Frankie Edgar.
Alistair Overeem versus Big Foot Rashad
Evans versus little nog and John Fitch
versus Damien Maia. Holy Shit.
If that's the Superbowl card.
Yeah. If they don't get hurt,
that's the deal though. Please. No.
Aldo reminds me of a,
reminds me of Cambooya does.
He wasn't like that to me.
He's like the MMA gamble.
Why did say that they look similar and
they both have that fucking crazy third
world
mentality. And then I made
a Cuban like Cuban. Yeah.
Islander. Yeah. But you know, all
those obviously Brazilian, right?
There's an intensity that people have.
They come from extreme poverty.
It's pretty hard to match. You know,
that their shit is not bravado.
It's fucking real. Yeah. You can
match it a little bit with, uh,
with hard work and
discipline and you know,
and just being focused and trying to win.
But there's like a fucking real worry
that you have when you're not sure where
your food comes from. That's hard to
fuck with. Exactly. No, that's, I'm like,
Roberto Duran Duran was so great.
Yep.
Grew up in utter poverty and it was just,
they just walked through. He was really,
really nothing else to
compare it to readily.
Can everything you have is soft to
them. Yeah. You soft pitch. Yeah.
Everything you do with soft to them.
Yeah. Whatever happened to big country,
big countries fighting this weekend.
Big countries fighting management country.
He's a bad month flops
sentiment I can do dude. Yeah.
He's fighting Matt Mitrione this weekend.
This weekend is the finals of the
ultimate fighter. So, um, the, uh, the,
the main guys are going to compete and
then there's a couple of a undercard
fights as well in the
main event is a mitre on.
It was supposed to be
him versus Shane Carwyn.
But Shane Carwyn, uh, got injured again,
fucked up his knee and mitre stepped in.
Uh, I remember I texted mirror
after he fought Nelson. I
said, good fight. He goes,
I go, that son of a bitch
wouldn't go down. He goes,
I know my niece is
paying the price for it.
It's the dude. No one has a chin like
Roy Nelson. He's that. He's an animal.
He's ridiculous, which is a record
like 15 and 15 something like that.
You can beat him. You're just not
going to beat him. Exactly what I mean,
there's a lot of good fights on the
under car to a bunch of good fights.
There's a big one is a pat
Barry vs Shane del Rosario.
That's a crazy fight,
man.
Shane del Rosario was a Moy Thai
champion world champion and Pat Barry is,
you know, one of the best kick
boxers in MMA and that, that flight,
he's going to be crazy in
the weight bearing has been
fighting lately. You know,
he's going to go after him.
This is who won the ultimate
fighter then this year or
who's in the final for that?
Then the final fight is between,
uh,
Smith and Ricci. Hmm. Those are the
two guys that made it to the finals.
Apparently. That's what, you
know what? No, I'm sorry.
Those guys are not that.
I don't think that's true because they
don't tell you yet because I think it has
to air this week. Oh, I might be wrong.
I have to find out who's a, I don't know.
I know if it's been set, I haven't
seen this week's episode, so I don't,
I'm not sure if they're hard to.
I was watching it on. Um, it's,
the shows are hard to find. I have not
been able to label it down for a, I mean,
lock it down for when fuck is on.
I don't watch anything when it's on.
Everything I watch is on a DVR.
Now you gonna Sneeze when he goes
about 200 kids not getting laughed at,
laughed a lot of discipline as
an for a light to staring that.
Isn't that a weird thing? You
get it. You're almost sneezing.
Literally looking around for
a fucking light. The, um,
the Dvr is the most incredible
invention of all time.
I never watch anything
like when it comes out,
sit through their bullshit
commercials pitch,
I can fuck my fucking dvrs full of that.
Uh,
what does it call to that universe?
Show that fucking Morgan Freeman how?
Through the wormhole.
Yeah. All of that shit.
I have 20 of those on my DVR and
it's almost what I'm like, fuck,
I got to delete some that and Louie,
I don't,
I don't delete through the wormhole dude.
Just cause if I come home baked from a
show and I want to fucking blow my mind,
I'll sit there.
I'll watch through the Rome wormhole
and then I'll go right to the isolation
tank. That's mine. That's my
strategy. Just think about you.
Just freak out. Just go in there
and break shit down. Freak out.
Have you done that yet?
Isolation tank? No. You need
to do that. The murderers are,
you have one? I have one. You can,
you could rent one. You know, you
can go to the float lab in Venice.
They have a place you can go
and I think it's like 40 bucks.
And how long were they need to be in
isolation for? Just an hour is great.
First of all, even if you just want
to just for relaxing one hour's fine.
You know, like I'll do it sometimes
in an hour during the day.
I don't even like trip out.
I just go in the name,
the tags because I'm ignorant to it.
An isolation tank is filled with water.
The water is heated to the
same temperature as the
surface of your skin and then
there's eight to 1,800 to 1000 pounds of
salt in the water depending on how big
the tank is.
I just got a new one.
The new one's a thousand now used
to be 800 pounds, salt water,
but this one has more water.
It's like the kind of amount
of salt where you float. Yes.
There's so much salt in it that you
lie in it. You're completely buoyant.
You Bob up and down like a bomber
and you don't it. Once you relax,
you don't feel the water because
the water's the same temperatures,
your skin and just for relaxing like
there's never a time where you're that
relaxed where you have that much, that
much like tension relief from your body.
It's an excellent source of
magnesium because the, uh,
your skin actually absorbs magnesium
from the Epsom salts and it's like one of
the best ways to get magnesium into
your body. It's hanging in the Dead Sea.
Something like that.
Sound like,
but it's wake trippier because
you're in total silence.
You close the lid on this thing.
You were in total darkness.
You don't see anything,
you know, feel anything.
You don't hear anything and
it feels like you're flying.
So your brain has no sensory
input. Nothing's coming in
and no signals that like,
like right now we're sitting down.
You just a signal from your ass,
you know that feeling the
chair and saying, man,
Rogan and red van should get some
fucking better chairs in this bitch.
They make my back sweat. Yeah,
we were going to work on it.
We're going to get something.
The leather is,
should we get those air on chairs or
those are the shifts. Those herb Herman,
they'd give you some error.
You know,
we got some good ones from the
office depot for the other studio,
but we've got to replace,
there's an activator in the back of mine,
like an activator, like some Jheri
curl type shit. Activate who you see,
you're in the hip hop world. Most
people would know Carol Hockey, Matt,
but activator, unless they maybe
saw, um, what was that? Uh,
the last dragon shogun.
A Harlem show gun.
Bruce Leroy. Bruce Leroy. Yeah. Yeah.
Bruce. What happened to that kid?
Bruce Leeway who was still fighting.
Still doing while he's very good man.
And he's getting better all the time too.
So there's the, that fight this weekend.
Pat Del Rosario. Then there's
Jamie Varner versus Melvin Gallard.
That's a great fuck. That's my fight.
Melvin's on a hit and mysteries.
He was one of the past to now, right?
Yes. Um, you know, Melvin is a,
he's super physically talented,
but uh, you know, he's,
he's a bit of a wild child and
it's a fucking tough game, man.
It's lost some fights. Lost the last
fight. Serone he's fighting tough guys.
You know, you fight tough guys. You win
some, you lose some. The way he, uh, um,
knocked out, um, fuck is
his name. Evan Dunham.
We knocked out Evan Dunham was
fucking stunning. I chose you.
What Gallard can do at
his best at his basket.
Lard is one of the most
dangerous guys at one 55.
He always reminds me because of the,
I always get him confused with
a fucking another short, stocky,
black. I used to have
blond hair, short, stocky,
black guy who used to have
blond hair. Hmm. Mellowing Lord.
And I didn't know there was another
guy who looked just like him. He was,
or he had big fucking Kevin around them
then. Yeah, that's what it was. Oh yeah.
Well Kevin Ran, let's wait.
Bigger man. Random. Oh, was
the UFC heavyweight champion.
But they look similar. I mean not,
not, you know, but there, yeah,
cause it's like random in the champion.
I know he fought for the title.
I don't think for the title.
He didn't win it. Right.
I don't think the title up for grabs.
Right.
A lot of people thought he should have
won that fight. He got staff. Right.
And no pictures. Yeah, it's disgusting.
Pull those pictures up and
you never had staff like this.
Kevin Random and let that staff
go for like a couple of years.
It looks like you've never seen staff
like this. This is the craziest shit ever.
You could see through his skin
to the actual muscle tissue.
He had giant holes in his skin.
Yeah, it's nutty shit ambulance
and it's amazing the hospital right now
because he has staff in his stomach or
something like that. Staff
is scary as fuck. Yeah,
this is disgusting. Check it out.
Check these photos. That's disgusting.
That look at that whole fuck his staff,
when he lifted his arm up, you could see
through his fucking skin. You see what?
You've got a whole, when you can with as
a shadow in a fucking staph infection.
That's, I mean, I don't even know
how you fix something like that.
Fix something like that. Like that's so
terrifying. The shit eats your body away,
man.
You can fucking girl Nigga.
Then you can put your wallet in there.
You can put your Dick in there.
Is that staff too? That's a heel.
Oh my God, I got to go have
dinner with the family after this
staff. Is it terrifying? Fucking thing's
fucked. Yeah. That immersive stuff.
That's what's really scary is it
people are taking antibiotics,
they don't finish their
cycle. And so the, the, the,
the by the bacteria that remains,
that survives the assault by the
antibiotics become super powered.
It's like extra strong because
it's resisting being poisoned.
So it develops into a stronger strain.
And so then people get it and they'll,
the antibiotics don't work
on it because it's a strain.
It's become resistant to antibiotics.
Right.
So these poor fucking people that
get it, they're doomed. I mean,
you're in a life or death struggle,
which with which should be easily
cleared up by, uh, antibiotics.
Yeah. It's insanity. We're
living in, it's the human world.
We're living in my friend.
You get the knife and start carving.
It's true. You could carve it, carve
it out, try to chop it right out. Yeah.
But then, you know, it happens
at a melon school wound.
You have an open wound and that stuff
is probably systemic by them. Any,
any sort of infection that you have is,
it's going to go to that.
That's the problem with staff, I believe.
Especially when it gets systemic,
cause it like you can get it again, you
know, Shit's not good. It's not good.
So when you play with Travis Barker,
you playing at the same time with him.
I Jahid rums or Travis Barker.
I'm just laughing at the AEA segway there.
Red Band. Well I'm just getting all these
people telling me like talk more about
deejaying.
So don't bring it to them ever.
Well I was as a fan of mass gas,
ask questions you want but
please don't ask questions.
So that's a question I know. Now
that's a question I asked. Uh, cause I,
I see that you have some shows coming up
in San Francisco with Travis Barker and
I think he's a great drummer.
Yeah,
Yep. Um, you know, a couple
months back and um, you know,
rest in peace to, you know, Dj am, um,
who that was their original thing
and they released a mix tape.
You the Travis was play the drums
and Dj am was and that's kind of an
interesting style of doing it,
like combining mixing with,
with live music.
It's awesome. So when you passed
he called me up, he was like,
I couldn't think of any other DJ and
we'll love to love to take you on a tour.
And we went on tour together,
opened up for Lil Wayne and um,
got this bus.
He actually bought a tour bus now so we
can go and do whatever the fuck we want.
But we have two shows. We have
a, we have residencies in, in uh,
in Vegas.
So we do shows twice
a month. What's it like hanging
out with little Wayne crazy.
Please tell me crazy.
What is it like tell us
deposition, right? Yes. I loved it.
The definition was hilarious.
No, he can't save. You can say,
Whoa, I love it. What is
it like hanging out with,
if you could get past like 20
people to get to him, you know,
I guess it's worth it. He's
like really? Like, I dunno,
I think he's on this mushroom skateboard
thing. Mushrooms or board thing. Yeah.
What do you mean he's just switching
off all the time? You know what I mean?
Like he does like different shit. He's
in the different things. It's Kinda,
it's Kinda confusing cause
it's like you're, you're
this gangster rapper, right?
But then you got all this type stuff on
and you're skateboarding tight stuff,
tight pants, leggings. I don't
get it. Nothing against it, Wayne.
You know what I mean? It's a
look, whatever, but it, it, um,
are you criticizing little Wayne's
look and you're like, yeah,
I don't understand the
jeggings and then the sagging
jegging leggings, but they're jeans. Oh,
I don't like those, those skinny jeans.
But they're worse. They're like fucking,
it's almost like, oh, fucking, yeah.
It's almost like leotards with no feet.
I can't wear those.
When I say I don't like those,
that's not for me. But, uh,
if you've got a little skinny legs,
it's kind of a look. I hate when,
so I see people that are,
even though you can't be even slightly
out of shape and where that, right. Well,
that's why you ain't him. Yeah.
Because I'm like, well I can't wear it.
So that's like showing off your skinniness
for shorts flaunting it in fact.
But my dude is definitely under
the influence of something
of
statement.
But my dude is definitely under
the influence of something.
It's a combination of some shit.
I don't know because like,
do you think that he's mean?
He's constantly got to create new raps
and shit and constantly performing and
touring.
You know,
he probably wants a make
shit up constantly just to
keep his mind fresh and keep
new ideas entering into it.
Of course.
And I think that's when that person
will learn how to play that guitar.
You know what?
I don't know.
I don't even know how to
get to as a guitar and still
walk with a guitar all the
time.
Oh that's awesome.
And so if you weren't confused really,
he's like the fuck is that about like
walking around with boxing gloves on and
I'd be Kinda Fun. Yeah, that's
right. Like what are you doing bitch?
I became a big fan of his when he did
that deposition. That was awesome.
It was ridiculous,
was great.
Cause he was responding to some nonsense
way of talking that this guy had roped
him into the system. I mean that's what
a deposition is. They talk to you legal,
you know,
they ask you these silly questions
and you know is your name and fracked,
you know,
you know what he's fucking name is.
He's writing kind of stupid question.
Is that you ended up losing that case.
Really? That was the one against the
acuity three ray was the case about,
what was it about Quincy Jones?
His son was doing a documentary on him.
And you made music with them. Right?
And what happened? What went wrong?
I think it was about the rights to use
the music or he didn't like how he was
going to be represented.
Oh yeah.
He was trying to block it and then now
he had to give the deposition but he lost
a well bitch. Oh well when you done
Margaret Gremlin, let's be honest,
I. E. T. Let's listen to him.
2008 I don't recall.
I don't recall that.
In the summer of 2007 you were
arrested in New York City following and
performance at the beacon theater.
Do you recall that police in New York
City discovered a 40 caliber pistol on
you, on your person? I
don't recall that need.
Did you recall that in late 2009 you
pleaded guilty to attempted criminal
possession of a weapon out of her?
That
I'd like to get it
to the point where he says that you
can't save you the end of 2009 it was,
I don't know if this is it.
I need,
this is just as I call at eight months
this clip. I think it's just his,
all his, I don't recall know.
We don't need to see it,
but here's the funny one is good too.
Hey, well that's not the
question. Like what's your name?
He rushes.
That's a stupid ass question.
You just saw me on a given an interview
with her. Okay, so that was he. Oh,
did you perform it?
The virgin mobile music fast
in 2008 with Kanye West?
I don't know.
I know I did for fun at this bad
as bitch birthday party recently
thick.
Isn't it something that you would remember
if you were album the Carter three
was the biggest selling
album of the year in 2008
isn't as something that I
would remember that. Yes.
Isn't that a personal
opinion type question?
Question
the fuck.
That's fine. I didn't know what a guy
would remember. If his memory sucks,
how can he prove what someone's memories
like you know there's some shit that I
ordered the stuff from your
website. I've met people, Bro.
I've met people that I know I met before
but I cannot remember and I probably
had a good time hanging out with
him. Like, hey dude, what's up buddy?
How are you friend?
I pretend I know everybody when I meet
them just in case I always do just in
case. Oh memory. It's fucking
faulty as shit. It is fucked up.
So that's why who a Reagan got away with
that shit during the country hearing or
the member with the, did you sell
weapons to Iran? It's like, fuck,
I don't remember. I really
don't remember. You can get away
with that too when you get
old. Yeah. Damn. Just not,
not feeling so I feel
so good with the memory,
but if Reagan had been on Alpha brain,
then his shit would be suspect.
Russell Peters checking his Twitter,
checking the Twitter,
saying what they're saying. They're
saying, you fucking suck, dude.
That's how you bullshit. True. They want
to live your life a little angry at you.
Did you gather Russell?
They pitch.
They're sick of listening to me instead
of mix master Mike is that people are
saying that don't real. The real
DJ talk. You know it all isn't.
Only the cunt would do that to you. Only
con would send that maybe to think it.
Okay. I could see somebody thinking it,
but to say it to actually say it to you.
Yeah.
You're responding only to cons.
I don't respond or you just don't have
a good point. Why read it? Why let them?
That's when you hear him. That's
when you unfollow. Unfollow.
You got to block. I do. Black
people walking report as spam your,
oh, that's good too. Because if
you don't do that, you're going to,
you're going to have, you know, just
going to be inundated, but assholes,
especially if you're one of those guys
that are only responds to the assholes,
then he got a problem. That's true, right?
Dana white does a really good job of
that. He's ridiculous. He loves me.
It's comedy for him. He loves
doing that. He gets crazy.
I don't understand that shit. I
think it's silly, but he likes it.
It's like it's fun for him. Whatever
joy you had a question for you. Okay,
Mike. Um, on FIFA fear factor,
do you actually have say on what they eat?
Like me? Oh, you have no.
Say if it was up to me,
they would have never had an eat
donkey. Common. We still be doing it.
Did they get taught taken off already?
Yeah. Yeah. It's done. Donkey Kong.
I'm actually happy it got taken off,
but if it was up to me,
they would have never had to do that.
I would've said that's [inaudible].
There's a couple of times, there's a
lot of crazy shit they did on that show,
but I was down with almost
all of it except twice.
There's two times one where they had a
ride bowls. I thought that was ridiculous.
I, there was a crazy idea. Actual actual
balls and two, they had a drink come.
I'm like, that Shit seems
wrong. Siemens wrong. Donkey,
donkey come and donkey
urine. Wow. Yeah. Yeah.
It's actually cows ear and was
cows even donkey come for what?
For 50 g's if ti no, a shot at
winning 50 gs. That's a shot.
Gave them 50 grand just for
drinking donkey comp. That
would at least make sense.
But uh,
that was,
I mean we did 148 episodes during the
first run and I think we did like seven or
something, maybe eight during the
second run. But that was out of those,
all those episodes,
there was only twice where I was like,
get the fuck outta here.
This is crazy.
And the donkey come and the
bowls with the two riding a bull,
it's just ridiculous.
That is just a mechanical bull.
I can go with even a mechanical
bull, you can get fucked up, but uh,
old below for your fall real bowls.
The way they launch you through the air,
like you do not want to be a part
of that. You can do it. Yeah,
you can do it if you're a
bad mother fucker of your,
some Donald Cowboy Cerrone type dude and
you're like fucking getting, you know,
flying through the air because he just
wrote a bowl because that Thursday night.
Yeah, exactly. You
can't survive that shit.
But the reality is that's a risk
where the reward is not worth it.
Okay. First of all, you're not going
to win. Everybody gets thrown. Yeah.
Nobody has ever written a
bolt to eternity. You know,
you get on that bitch and you've got a
few studies tamed ones yet if you're a
bad motherfucker,
you can last for eight seconds.
Just think of how ridiculous that is.
Even 10 seconds is a bar that's way
too high. Most people can't do it.
So they give them eight
for the pros fucking pro.
Only as eight seconds. That's
this new band on the show. What,
how long did that stay on the show?
On the show that it was a,
the people who lasted the longest, that's
where it was. And what was the longest?
Oh not long. Six seconds.
Five seconds. Just a lock. It
was just like he, you know,
just, he just jumping up trays.
Not like a method to his madness.
He just going crazy and if you judge it
right like the first time that you don't
have to recover for the second time and
you get like an extra second depending
on, but I don't think people
did it more than a few seconds.
They didn't have the horns did they?
Yeah. Yeah. The horns or cap though.
They have like a little cap on the horns.
But the bottom line is these,
the stomping is what you
really have to worry about.
Even we put chess plates
on them and helmets.
You don't want to get stomped on the head
by a bowl when you're wearing a helmet.
Okay.
Cause I don't know how much it's really
going to protect your fucking skull.
You could easily get a cracked
skull while you wearing a helmet.
On a bull stomps on you and
they're just getting launched.
Launched through the air.
There's a girl was 98 pounds,
his tiny little girl
and she got on the ball,
they open the gate and the bowl with
the first buck just sent her flying off
like a pillow, Bang, and she landed
like flat on her back and she was good.
All the wind knocked out of her and
everything else. Like you guys are crazy.
This is such a stupid, stupid,
stupid thing to make people do.
But when you,
when you have a whole bunch of people
like say if you're doing a show like that,
what happens is you got like,
there's 12 people there, right?
And say a one of them is totally in
charge and the other ones are in charge of
creating this stuff and the other one is
the network and they all get together.
What do you think? Wow, I think we can
do it. And you're thinking we'd do it.
Then you bring the stunt guy over. Well,
you know, we've done it. I've done it.
They can do it. No,
there's no voice of reason.
There should be one guy who's like the
voice of reason. Well, all this guy does,
he has no vested interest in the show.
Just does yoga all day, you know,
reads books and he'd come to him and,
hey man, we're thinking of doing this.
And the guy goes, no, you go, okay.
Okay. We went to the voice of reason.
We were getting a little carried away. We
almost had him drink. Come cause me, man,
look, I can rarely get chicks to swallow
my own coach. You got a fucking spider.
I refuse to believe that.
I think chicks lining up to
gobble you go there. There's,
there's the hit and misses. You know what
the funny thing is about on the show,
girls got a choice between come and and
Piss and girls were choosing Commonweal
rapists. They were like, it seems
like it'd be easy to do. Wow.
In Europe it would be pissed and shit.
But you're talking about German.
Oh, Germany when you were there,
I think you saw too much with that
400,000 seat show. No, I'm, yeah.
German porn will turn
you off.
Porn if that's the first horse.
Have you ever done DJ and with a a
like a full band, like a rock band.
I mean instead of just
like drums with Travis.
Have you ever done it with other assorted
instruments? Yeah. Joining with a,
with Tommy Lee. Oh yeah.
Yeah. But he's again though,
does Trump's right just jump me at him.
But if you've ever done it with other
musical instruments like guitars and all
that other shit, no. It's just saxophone
[inaudible] morning. It's kind of boring.
Why is that? I mean it's just, um,
it's, it's just too traditional,
you know what I mean? Oh
really? Yeah. For me, I mean,
you know, bands do their thing.
I kinda like them.
I like for them to shine on there.
But you could have like a good guy with
doing a guitar solo and then you copy is
cuts with the cut or
something. Yeah. For me,
I got all these instruments and I
tried to mimic them. So it's just like,
do you get into any other type of music
other than I'm a DJ music or like or hip
hop? Like what kind of
Shit? Indian shit. Indian,
Indian Bollywood. A half an Indian right
here on the phone. One on the phone.
Robert's face Indian. She's
lucky shit. Hey, what kind of,
what kind of Indian
Bollywood Ravi Shankar. Oh,
do you like dollar Monday? Yeah. Yeah.
Tunic tunic to the happy Indian guy. Do
you know that song? I don't know the song,
but I've seen the guy I know each
time and pull that song up to nick.
I think it's called tonight's just type
in dollar mainly? Yeah. Dollar men.
D D a h l e r m. E n. D.
I to knock to just cut
to a s t. U. N. A K?
Yeah.
Dollar d a h l e R M e d.
I. O. N m e d. R. A. H. I.
M. E. H. D. I. That's called.
I called this guy the original Gangam
style and a yeah, and to knuck.
T u.N a.K is the space. He's
a bad motherfucker. Dude.
This is the happiest guy. You've got to
see him and he's doing this whole thing.
The video is fantastic because the video
is him with his crazy terbinafine and
he's fucking dancing up a storm.
It's just all around you got busted
with white slavery by the way.
I'm involved in some sort of fucking
slave trade operation. We'll, yeah,
we'll something something shady
went down or he got framed. But uh,
have you found a Brian da
I'm looking at right now.
D a l e r space m.
E n.
D. I. N. H. So it's still
high from this joint.
We gave him that yesterday. Yeah.
M E H Harry go MDI to knock tune.
Listen to this.
Ah,
sunrise,
beautiful Indian.
Show me all the majesty architecture
that looks like
it's like fucking
asteroids coming to space.
And one of them is him
check guy out
appearing everywhere in different
clothes from different asteroids
or these dancing and singing to a south
and he's a fat fuck.
Big Fat ass round face
sculpted Justin Bieber tight in his gut
and the he's lovable, clump, clumping,
lovable. I got to get it for you.
I have a dollar Mandy
doll. Oh No, you don't.
In Toronto you can see there are my
mom's house or in one of my boxes in the
House leaders dancing.
It's so ridiculous.
They made dolls of him and you push
the button and he did this leg,
his arms started moving and stuff.
I love the song. I was obsessed with this
song for a couple of weeks. Hey Gang,
I'm sorry. I should definitely team up.
Uh, do you do wet like Ebony and ivory?
Um,
don't you think the,
isn't that guy like he's
successful enough on his own?
I don't think it needs to bring dollar
Mindy into the mix. Yeah. Unfortunately.
Dollar never really caught on.
Not In the wide mass.
He could have easily been like huge in
India. That's like just as good. Yeah.
That's like still a billion pixels and
style and at least a billion people still
like, yeah, he's easy. But isn't he
in trouble? Didn't he get in trouble?
I don't know. I never heard that. Yeah.
There's something happened to him, man.
Did you, did you work on
the sound from way out? Uh,
the in sound from way out know that that
was such a interesting album because
it's a complete instrumental album and
I actually didn't think I was going to
like it,
but I love that album and uh,
introduced me to a lot of different
artists that were similar like Midecky
Martin and wood and things like that.
Do you enjoy, did you enjoy that,
that album or it was one of my favorites.
Yeah, we played it a lot of it live.
Wow. Yeah, it was awesome that, that's a,
that's one of the few cds that I still
always have in my CD collection cause
that's always a great CD just
to throw in as, you know,
like have you people over
exactly. It's timeless. Yeah.
It's not so in your face it's right.
The boys,
the remaining members having a plan,
do they know what they're going to do now?
They're just laying low right now.
Right. Just doing benefits,
trying to help the situation, uh,
the family and just trying to
help the situation over in, uh,
New Jersey and you go,
oh, okay. Yeah. Okay.
The Sandy Hurricane Sandy that
they're doing that. They live there.
They live in Manhattan. Yeah. Yeah.
Were you there for that? I wasn't, no.
I was on this side.
It must be some crazy shit.
It was some crazy shit to see like New
Jersey and the boardwalk just gone.
Yeah.
It's weird to see those photos of like
the foundations of the house dude.
I mean you don't see that shit
here in America. It's like wow.
Yeah. Well we haven't really
been around that long.
That's what's really hilarious.
Yeah.
We have this idea of like
what the weather does,
but it's only based on like a couple of
hundred years that people writing shit
down.
It's true.
You get more than three or 400 years
ago and like who the fuck knows what
happened?
Exactly.
Now you get like a couple of thousand
years ago when it regarding whether all
you have is ice core samples and that
gives you sort of a good idea if you drug
dig holes in the right place but you don't
really know about like hurricanes and
shit. It's like, it's, it's hard to know
what kind of damage. Yeah. That's kind of,
they know how cold it gets and no hot
it. God, they know certain storms,
but there's storms that have happened
that have just wiped out and completely
change entire ecosystems. One storm,
boom, everything's dead. It's,
you know, we're lucky. We'll know after
the 21st we really have to worry about,
it's not even storms we really have to
worry about as volcanoes and asteroids.
Those are the two big ones. We haven't
experienced either one of those. Yeah.
And then that whole alignment is
coming too, right? Yeah. Dude,
we're all going to die. No, I don't think
that alignment is, I don't think that's,
I think that's all bullshit. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. According to astronomers are,
yeah. Like, um, what's his
name? Um, Neil degrasse Tyson.
He says that it happens like on a
regular basis, like this, this alignment,
like it's,
it's what people are calling this
alignment with the center of the galaxy.
It's really just a misunderstanding.
They don't really know what they're
talking about and it's sort of repeating
some shit that somebody else said that
doesn't know what they're talking about.
And it's like this the same sort of doom
and gloom mentality that led people to
think that y two K was going
to kill us all. Exactly. Yeah.
Because if there's no fucking electricity,
you're going to have a hard time doing
shows because it's really hard to do
shows as a DJ without electricity. I mean
you could have a fucking acoustic show.
He could do standup comedy through a
toilet paper roll and get of a beatboxer.
Yeah. What the fuck do you do?
And if the mouth, your scratches,
air scratching. Yeah. I mean solar
flare, he didn't have to get,
so you going to have to solar power,
solar power DJ equipment.
You're gonna need to come up with
a cut called the solar flare.
What would that be like? Well there's
a flare and then there's like,
oh there's a flare.
I would cause the solar flare.
You would cause this whole front there's
a two click flare. What is a flare?
How do you do a flare?
A flare is when you moved
the fade or like a millisecond off
to cut the sound off in the middle.
It's definitely gotta be displayed person.
But you know,
there's certain scratches that put
together and there they work differently.
Him and his crew created those.
Who's the baddest motherfucker in
deejaying ever. Is there a consensus?
Okay,
it makes sense to you.
Does it mix master Mike?
Are you the baddest motherfucker ever?
He says he's not even blinking.
I have to say it was more of a, how dare
you ask me that? Well, I don't know.
I mean I would say that's what,
that's his way of saying.
There should be no question. Who's like
your number one rival? That's the case.
My number one rival. Yeah. Like the guy
out there like keeps you on your toes.
What's my, was my partner, Dj Q,
Bert. And um, he was kind of like
the other side. I mean when I
first showed him this scratch,
he turned into a monster and then
we used to battle and go at it.
He beat me once.
I beat him once in a big battle.
Do you think that that
scratching and this type of, uh,
using records and shit is a transitionary
art form because like if everything
goes digital and everything goes from,
you know,
like solid state mediums to nonexistent,
do you think that this a,
it'll be like actually considered
an instrument soon in the future?
I think it should already be considered
the way certain people play it because
you really are playing it much like, look,
he use a guitar to make certain sounds.
He didn't really create the guitar,
you know,
you use the same strings
that everybody else uses.
It creates a certain
sound and that's what,
and putting it all together
is what makes it beautiful.
Then taking music that somebody else made
with a guitar and it's on a record and
then creating, turning it into
something really different. Yeah. Yeah.
What do you think of when you hear like
real obvious samples? They'll like, like,
uh, can't touch. This is like obviously
Rick James Super Freak, you know, like,
um, vanilla ice, ice, ice baby.
Obviously under pressure, you know,
it's like there's,
there's something that happens when
you have a song where it's like you're
taking some classic hit and then
morphing it. It's like can cheat.
And a little beauty of it is to,
you know,
be a Ninja about it and smash it.
And what people don't even know it yet.
Obliterate it. We played some shit
and Russell Russell pulled out some,
some things that we didn't even know.
What was it that you did that too? It was,
it,
it takes two to make a thing go right.
Well it wasn't all some song you
played and go ahead. That's from, yeah,
it was like the beat. I was like, that's
from like, I remember what it was,
but he picks out like two or three
things that were smashed up together.
You guys have like a educated ears, sorta
like a, some all Yang can tell wines
j unit, you know, you have a connection
to I Dj Q, Bert you to Joe. Oh yeah,
yeah. He actually, he was the one that
does their run DMT, uh, uh, shirts.
Yeah. That's hilarious. Have you,
has he checked into doing DMT yet?
No, not you. A Mike. There were thoughts.
There were thoughts of doing it, but
the thoughts never seen that. Oh yeah.
The Guitar Ufo.
Okay.
What are you talking about? This guy,
a Cubert. His old partner made a,
a turntable, had a mixer built
into it and it was called a Q LFO.
Ah. And then some guy took the cue
FFO and built it onto a guitar,
neck, everything. Oh
Wow. Where's, let me see.
That's what the picture that's
Cubert actually on it. Oh Wow.
It's funny because I went with Cubert that
day to go see the thing still. So I'm,
I was there videotaping him,
um, cutting on it and stuff.
Super Creative. That run DMT shirt.
Brian. Yeah, he sounds Amanda.
It's a on this store,
so I'm guessing that's him.
I don't know where I bought it from.
I bought it from somewhere online.
I don't know if I bought it
from his store. I think he's
the one that created it.
That's fascinating.
What do you think about DMT,
Joe? How was your experience?
How do I begin any crazy
patterns from the other side?
Uh, well what it is, you know,
it's the most potent
psychedelic known demand. Yeah.
Basically it's like right up there.
This is a few other ones that rival it.
Salvia divinorum is pretty potent
and a so as a five methoxy DMT,
that's pretty potent to,
it's actually even more potent I
think gram for gram than and and
dimethyltryptamine, which is
the visual effects, the empty.
It's pretty life changing shit, man.
Just to know that it's possible.
Just knowing that it's possible.
It's sort of like really
puts your ear first of all,
your understanding of the universe into
perspective because you go through your
life and as your experiencing life and
doing things and traveling and meeting
people and going places.
You're a formulating a
database of possibilities like
these are all the possible
people that I can meet. These are
the possible scenarios. Oh my God,
I'm in front of 14,000 people.
This is a possible event.
Who would have thought and you accumulate
all these different experiences and
you put them into your view of the world.
Then you do something like DMT and Dmt
is so strange and so gigantic and so
impactful and odd and impossible
to describe and you know,
using any words to try to piece
together the experience of,
of a full blown DMT trip. Is it
ridiculous? It's a waste of time. There's,
it's inadequate.
The words exist to describe experiences
that everybody has in common,
whether it's large groups of people,
whether it's life or death or violence.
Those words to describe DMT do not exist
and you have no frame of reference for
them. They have no point of reference if
you haven't experienced it. And that's,
that's weird to know that there's
something that's so different from regular
life that if you take it once,
you never look at regular life the same
way again because the possibilities have
now changed because you know that a DMT
trip as possible because I would have,
before I did the empty out
of never imagined that that
was available and that if
it was available,
it wasn't something that
was being discussed on the
front page of the New York
Times every fucking day where scientists
weren't getting together with world
leaders and trying to figure out
what it means, what it's doing,
what it does to you,
why it changes your life,
how much would it benefit people to have
this experience? Should it be regulated?
Should it be understood?
Should it be encouraged?
Like what should we do with this stuff?
Instead,
it was like a secret and then instead the,
the trippiest thing about it was what I
would talk about it and I would do like
videos about it and then people would go,
what the fuck are you tall?
I never even heard about this.
I'm like,
how is it possible that you're learning
about one of the craziest things that
any human being has ever experienced ever
and you're learning about it from me?
Like how is it possible that
no one's talking about this?
It didn't make any sense.
I didn't understand it.
And then you find out that your own
brain makes it and then you find out that
it's also in a million different kinds
of plants and then you find out that it's
super illegal and it's like
what is going on with our laws?
What is going on with our system of
government where one of the most life
changing experiences you could ever
possibly have and it's illegal.
Like you,
you can go to jail for it.
Like it's absolutely massively beneficial
to thousands and thousands if not
millions of people. And
it's illegal. We're in a,
we're being run by madness.
That's what DMT lets me know.
But DMT lets me know that we,
our system of government,
the system that we're born
into is just fucking madness.
The system of trying to stop people from
doing shit that you don't understand
and you've never experienced.
That's madness.
Just that alone that opened me up to that,
to,
to forget about what I've learned or
what I felt when I was having a DMT trip.
Just the fact that someone who has never
experienced it tried to keep it from
you. Someone who doesn't understand
it and it never actually had it,
is trying to tell you what
it is and trying to regulate
it and try to keep other
people from doing it. That just shows
you how crazy we are. Fucking man.
You function when you're on
it. No, no. You don't exist.
It's the only drug I think that I've
ever heard of or taken other than a,
against Salvia. It was supposed to be
very debilitating to your eyes are closed.
Yeah. Yeah. You close your eyes,
you take it and you just fucking
vanish into another world.
You literally go into a fairy world.
He'd go into this weird world of extreme
lights and colors that shouldn't be
able to exist in patterns and
logos and shit. Yeah. What is it,
what's the craziest thing you've
ever experienced? Craziest, craziest,
psychedelics? Anything.
Oh, fuck. Mushrooms.
Just straight mushroom caps. Yeah. Um,
drinking orange juice with it. Yeah.
And waiting for Ufo to come
and they might come to actually
saw some Ufos and you know,
I got my turntables out. I'm
scratching and I was, I was on one.
You were on a Ufo while you
were scratching. I want it
to be, you want it to be?
Yeah. Fuck yeah. Maybe it's
just took a couple more grams.
He would have been in it. Fire
in the sky. Well, it's like,
that's the thing about
those hallucinations.
They're so God damn strong.
Like the hallucinations that
you have while you're on a,
any sort of visionary plant
like mushrooms, when you
take a large dose of them,
it's almost like, is this a different
way? If I tapped into a different reality,
am I actually here and when I go back
to regular reality and I sober up,
does that mean that this never happened
or is it that this does happen,
but it only happens when you're on
mushrooms, but it is real. That's real.
That's real. Yeah. It feels
real. It feels real. It is real.
I don't think regular people who ever,
who
have never tripped really truly
understand that sentiment.
It seems like something that is impossible
to describe because when you come
back, it's just so still and so odd
and weird. Like what just happened?
Is it still with me?
No,
it's quiet right now and I'm
looking and I'm like, okay,
I'm going to go with my
frigerator get some breakfast.
Well that's the weird
thing is just knowing,
having the knowledge that
that's available, you know,
and Drussel you didn't drink
at all until you were 30 ones.
You're pretty straight laced. You don't
fuck with anything, Huh? Just alcohol.
You ever get a contact high from
hanging around? People like me? Um,
I think I did once. I didn't, I,
I just watched TV if we hotbox Greg
Fitzsimmons in here once sent that
motherfucker on stage and a
delirium. Nice. Yeah. I don't, I,
I've never been in here and that's really,
I've been curious about it or anything.
What if you met a hot chick and she said
she smoked weed and made her horny? Nah,
really? I, you know, when I did, I have
tried it. Yeah. And I didn't like it.
What didn't you like? I didn't
like the coughing. First of all,
you have to try a vaporizer or eating it.
I have also done that.
I had a Brownie ones and I
did not like the way I felt.
I was literally literally
clinging to the bed.
It's not surprising space cookies.
And I did not like that. I was like,
I don't want that again. Yeah, they
can do some things to you, man.
The body change your life. Yeah.
But you, but you like alcohol.
I don't like alcohol. Not until you
were 31. That's true. Just keep, we try.
We have a little, I've tried it and I
didn't really, I don't like to slow down.
Ah, I need space. We'd need weed.
It makes you want to speed up. I,
I like, you know,
maintaining at this function,
but my brain working a little faster.
So then why are you drinking?
Because my brain gets slicker when it's
drunk. Really drunk. I get buzzed. I,
I'm not, I'm not even
getting hammered, but uh,
how do you feel like your brain is
slicker when it's, do you feel like my,
I must lose your tongue.
Devil.
Aye.
I, I can, I can, I can. I'm a Mac.
When I got some alcohol and weed. Holy
Shit. I'm happy with myself. This,
this lady's right now that are ready
to take up that challenge like this.
This motherfucker talking shit.
It's true.
I'm going to rub up on Russell
Peters next time I seen him. Please.
He's very single now.
Well, very single. And uh,
we'll be in Vegas December 29th.
Well, yes, I will be to you.
I'm going to get in on like the 28 so I
can go to a punk ass party on the 28th.
Where's his party? I Dunno. He
just got some party on the 28th.
You're going to wear tap out
clothes or no, no, I can't do that.
I've told them, hey man, congratulations.
But I can't wear that shit.
You can wear a Kangol hat though. I can
work angle Kango never went out of style.
They never went commercial. No, they
did. They kangols official like, yeah,
it's official like fishing.
It's like Adidas never goes
out of style. Yeah. It's,
it's become a brand,
a trustworthy,
longtime brand Dutch never that out.
They couldn't,
you couldn't keep it together
cause von Dutch morphed into Ed.
Ed Hardy didn't it?
They couldn't keep it together.
Even in Ed Hardy morphed into fucking
like von Dutch and Ed Hardy with both like
Krispy Kreme donuts. It's like you,
you gorge, you don't just have one.
You go crazy and then you flood the
market and then it's over and then people
are sick of it and then affliction came
in. Right? Yeah. It's all it, all it, all,
it all went bad after
that. I was, I was never a,
I guess you could say I just by fucking
five packs of Hanes Vnx and I'm a happy
man. Yeah. It's like the most
comfortable shirt ever. Right.
And then they're disposable, you
know, they get a little off guard,
this colored fucking throwing them out
or clean your house, you know. Dot.
Merera doesn't,
uh,
doesn't ever pack socks or underwear and
just goes to a town than buy socks and
underwear and throws him out. That's
ridiculous. You can't, can't do that.
Charlie Murphy gets new shoes every
time he goes on stage. Oh, that's Eddie,
Eddie Griffin. It doesn't, I think
Charlie Murphy does it too, man. Yeah.
Eddie Griffin gets a white air
force ones every show. Every show.
If it's a two show night, you
get two parents. Come on son.
I think it seems a little dated now
that you want the air force ones.
What have you been paying attention to
this cat Williams meltdown. I didn't know.
I think there's a pool as to when
he's going to end it all. Thank Doug.
Stan helps numbers. What's
he got a wonder? Yeah,
I'm standing on pass him in
the celebrity death pool.
He has his own website and I zone
betting website or something like Doug
Stanhope Cause I think, I think somebody
told me, bitch, what's He mad at?
I don't know.
Kat Williams.
He's mad at everybody and just slap smack
your mother fuckers. The microphone.
The other, yeah, yeah, yeah.
He's smacking people, audience
members, and just squares.
Now he's not even hitting like we went
to target and just hit the cashier.
He slapped him, he hit
his assistant, allegedly,
I don't think it's a legendary dude.
He hit a dude that works for live nation
allegedly and he's hanging around with
shook night. So she's probably like,
you know, like a pit bull shit. And I,
it's just like genesis,
what the fuck is wrong?
You know,
it's sad for me to hear there's the,
here's him just talking to
a target employee and then
like the guy has his hands
on his chest too. So you know, he's the
night like being threatened. Any worry.
Mr. Williams. I'm a big fan. Yeah.
And bams slabs right on the face and the
guy just slowly pulls out his phone and
calls the police while catches stares
at it up again. Let me see that again.
Let me back that up. Well, it's,
it's, it's a security camera.
That's why it's so small.
Right. Let's see. He's a cat
talk much bigger than that.
And then a Bam and it was a hard slap.
They're just better
videos out there and then,
then he just stands there and watches him
for a while and then he just rolls off.
And when it is a handicap cart,
things that's drugs are not good drugs.
That's drugs.
He's on a bad trip right now, dude. Yeah.
That's like, uh, he's, he's on a bender.
You know,
it's,
you gotta be real careful when you're
talking to a guy like that and they do a
rational shit. So unfortunate because if
you go back to like his, his early work,
you know, it's like a standup
work. I think he's hilarious. I
love watching you drive the
pimp chronicles. Yeah. He's
so funny, man. So good.
He was so funny.
I don't,
I hate to see someone who was really
good spiral and like that spiraling back
hard, worse than anybody we've ever
seen. Worse Than Martin Lawrence.
But wouldn't Martin just rented a traffic?
That was it.
Do you have a gun on him and
something like that? Yeah. No,
I didn't end up cat had a gun.
Katsman collar.
W Cat's been covered a lot of things.
Like what is it about entertainers, Bro?
I don't know, 14 years of the Beastie
boys. You must know some shit. Too much.
Too much. All at once.
Too much all at once.
They seem to have mellowed
out as whatever you need.
Well, hello Mr. Schwartz. Come check into
your, uh, your room. Whatever you need.
I'm telling you whatever you need.
Is that what it is?
Whatever you need gave me that. Look.
Whatever you need, you need to him.
So is it just that you have, you're
the one calling all your shots? Yeah.
You have access to everything.
Definitely.
What's the nuttiest shit you ever saw
on the road and nutty. Nutty as shit.
Like 50 fucking girls showing up
with a bowling bag full of coke.
Like what's the nuttiest shit you
ever saw? Oh, the nuttiest shit. Well,
I did have a girl come and run up
to the stage and bite me on my neck.
What
she, she, she did will a smooth,
like though, she was like, Hey Mike,
how are you doing? I
got this record. I went,
sorry. Error. How hard she
bite you. Pretty hard. She on.
She was trying to take a piece
of meat off. Yeah, it was
fucked up. I was like, wow,
okay.
Did you fuck her and forget about it.
Did you fuck her luck in 1960
or something puncher? No,
those girls been still
in since high school.
This motherfucker fingered me in
the back of the car. I was like,
I don't want to be that guy, but
I got to go. Let's end this bitch.
I got to go meet my daughter for dinner.
They're already at the restaurant.
You beautiful bastard.
Listen Mike,
thank you very much for coming on and
people want to get ahold of your, um,
your um, your iPad app. What is it called
again? It's called mix master Mike.
Wheels of steel and it's w h e, l, z.
And if you go to mix master mike.com,
is that where they can find a link to
your new album? Yes. Download it for free.
For free. I love it. I love it.
I'm going to download that shit.
I'm going to listen to it this
weekend on the way to Vegas.
Thank you very much for coming on man.
We appreciate the fuck out of it and
if you want to follow Mike on Twitter,
it is mix master Mike with the eye is
a one m one x master and the next eyes
also one m one k. E. You figure it
out, bitch. Just take away the eyes.
I put in ones. Mike, if you want to
spell Russell ps named correctly,
it's two s's and two L's and you go
to the Real Russ or pee on Twitter.
What's your Twitter dude
at Mark Rasta. M. A r.
K. R. A. S. T. A. If you want
to throw some pussy Mark's way,
he will either take it or not.
I'm just going to tell you right now,
I'm going to deflect to Russell's want
to send this thing. Oh, you're right.
You're not saying, oh Russell, please.
I'm all about all the shit
that's going his way. I want it.
Yes,
and also follow Copeland entertainment.
That's c o p e l a n d underscore
e n t and also fall red band red,
B. A. N. And if you don't
follow me by now, how dare you.
She always also say that Skullcandy
we're wearing his McMaster's.
Mike says Skullcandy headphones
in. They're great headphones.
We love these. Yeah,
we didn't even know when I
came here and he gave me,
the ones that I'm wearing here are
special mix master Mike versions of the
headphones that he created.
It's funny because a,
the Skullcandy guys have been sending
us these we use in both here and at or
other studio. They're,
they're dope. We love them.
We use them for all our podcasts now. So
there you go. Free Plugs, skull candy.
We don't give a fuck. We ain't really
in this for the money bitch. Sort of.
How do we give one of these bitches
away? Like this is a special, uh,
what you're going to have to figure
out how to fucking send that shit.
We're not going to get around to doing
it. I don't have any headphones. Yeah,
that's what you do.
You give it away to Russell Peters.
This is how I'm going
to give it to a recipe.
I do need new headphones so
it works out really well.
And once we develop a
proper infrastructure, I'm
going to get started now.
Fuck boy, you're older folks.
The odds of you getting it.
Let's be realistic.
There are probably a fucking million
to one. So Russell got it. Except it.
Deal with it and move the fuck on.
Goddammit. Is that desk squad stickers?
Triple m master Mike stickers.
Beautiful. Beautiful, powerful
mix. Master Mike in San Diego. No,
I'm not going to be in San Diego tomorrow.
I cannot make it.
But you will be with Jason
Team. Sarah Tiana, um,
Tony Hinchcliffe and Billy banal.
It's going to be a great show.
That's a great show.
And it's a really hot club.
That American comedy
company is a a sweet club.
It's like the perfect dimensions for
comedy club. It's tomorrow night.
What's the tickets? Uh,
it's at American comedy.
[inaudible] dot com and a tomorrow.
I'm going to give away 20 tickets a buy
one get one frees tomorrow. Oh Jesus.
So check Twitter for that. Check Twitter
for that. Alright. You dirty fucks.
Thanks everybody for
tuning into the podcast.
We will be back tomorrow with the
great domme motherfucking Ira,
my buddy and a Sunday afternoon. It's
going to be afternoon now, not night,
Sunday at four o'clock with Dennis
Mckenna. All right. Sunday, Sunday,
Sunday at four. Um, thanks to
audible.com for sponsoring this podcast.
If you go to audible.com
forward slash Joe,
you will sign up and you can get 30 free
days and one free audio book and you
can check out the substantial number of
audio books they have available there,
including sex at dawn,
which is what I'm reading right now.
This a really fascinating book that we
will be talking with the author on the
podcast, Chris Ryan and
uh, I think this was named,
let me make sure that's his name.
I don't want to fucking,
I have no too many names. God
dammit. Chris Ryan, sex at dawn.
Sex at dawn. Yes, it is. Okay.
But it's a fantastic book
and it also has, um, the uh,
whisper sync, uh, audio book companion
to it that I was talking about.
So in reading it, you can read
it. If you have one of those, uh,
Amazon kindle fires, you can do that.
The kindle fire HD I think it is.
You can read it and it'll also pick
up as a, an audio book as well.
That's pretty dope. So if you check that
out, go to audible.com forward slash Joe,
you will save you guys
scratching. All right. Um,
so go to audible. God, you guys are on,
on, I hear you bitches. I'm fucking with,
sorry. Can't be talking over
cognitive commercials. Go
to [inaudible] dot com too.
That's our other sponsor. O n
n I t. Use a code name Brogan.
Save yourself 10% off any and
all supplements. So again,
that's audible.com forward slash Joe to
get 30 free days and one free audio book.
And that's it. The end. Um,
if you want to find out about the comedy
show, if you didn't pay attention,
all the information,
go to death squad.tv.
And if you want to go to the end of the
world party with Doug, Stan, hope, honey,
honey, Joey Diaz and me. There's
only, I think a hundred tickets left.
That's at the Wiltern December 21st,
2012 when the Mayan calendar comes to the
end of the long count in the shit hits
the fan or not. All right. We'll
see you fucks tomorrow. Thank you.
Bye Bye. See Ya. Keep it again.
Hmm.
Okay.