Here we go.
Three,
two,
one.
And we're live.
Tony Hinchcliffe.
Hello Jake.
The fucking snake.
What do you know,
Joe?
You've never heard it before.
I've heard it a couple times.
I've heard.
Hey Joe,
I heard you shot your old lady down
times as well.
There you go.
I got to tell you,
man,
I watched a documentary last night and
it's fantastic.
Appreciate it.
It is.
If that thing doesn't bring tears to
you,
uh,
you need to go to a doctor.
Yeah.
You're not human man.
No doubt that his Dallas is a fucking
saint.
He really is hard headed,
you know?
Uh,
without it.
I'd never made it.
Yeah,
because I'm
junkies like to lie a lot,
you know,
and alcoholics do too.
But it was a tough,
tough road bed and he guided me through
it.
He never gave up and I can never thank
him enough for what he's done for me and
given me my life back and not only my
life of my family,
I've got my kids back to her.
They're all digging me now.
I'm a great grandfather.
Would probably the best grandfather
ever,
you know,
I'm just saying because it's true.
I'll picture anybody else.
The detailing of your recovery though,
in him taking you into the,
what does he call his house?
That house?
The Accountability House.
Accountability Crib.
Yeah.
I mean he's a special guy.
I understand.
I mean,
no man in his right mind would bring one
much less two drunks into their home.
You know,
you got to expect tragedy.
There's going to be something come back
out of this.
And uh,
he was able to hold us together,
man.
And they were a couple of brief,
brief moments that does,
that kind of escalated and got kind of
stupid.
But he wouldn't give up man.
Well I got to know Dallas when he came
on the podcast and one,
one thing that you get about him as this
guy,
he,
he's not just about himself.
Like he is really about helping people
out.
He gets a buzz out of helping people.
Yeah.
Which is to me is just so amazing and
I've picked that up off of him.
I searched people out now in the crowd
that have are having a hard time walking
or you see something going on or they're
overweight and you go and,
you know,
I'm so and so,
it gets me in the name Jake the snake.
I can talk to them.
Hey,
you ever thought about trying some DDP
yoga man,
because it works and if you've never
done it,
DDP Yoga is without a doubt.
The number one thing out there for
getting healthy,
it makes your body healthy,
makes your mind healthy,
you know?
And uh,
for him to be out there,
he's just a soldier.
Yeah,
he really pushes all day long man.
And uh,
here's a guy that,
that,
that could be handling in a totally
different way,
but he still picks up the phone and call
somebody and thanks them for buying the
program.
Yeah.
Hell does that mean what does do that?
He does because he wants to know.
And the next thing you know,
he's on a 25 minute phone call and
they're sending him photos of the before
picture and then he wants to look at an
after picture.
You in six months from now,
the stories,
you've got a million of success stories.
We played a video when he was in a
vagina man who was a paratrooper.
I could barely walk.
I mean he had done a bunch of paratroop
missions,
you know,
parachuting out of planes and landing on
his knees.
His knees are destroyed,
legs destroyed,
back,
destroyed.
Everything's fucked up,
but he starts out barely can stand,
barely can walk.
Two Kings,
two kings.
By the end of the video,
this guy's running,
he's running,
he's doing full yoga poses and it's
these animal incremental steps,
incremental steps,
but he kept getting better,
kept getting better,
and that is.
It's so symbolic of your journey in
life.
If you just decided to give up and
decide to just fuck the world,
I'm just going to just eat and drink
myself until they live in.
You have been there.
You could talk.
Stay there a long time,
but then you turn it around.
But that's,
that's.
I fucking love that.
I love stories like that,
but it's a one in a million shot man.
Unless you have a diamond Dallas page in
your corner,
because it wasn't only about Dallas
help,
it was the whole group,
right.
See Dallas,
you know,
he came up with the idea of him and
Steve,
you as a business manager,
whatever.
And uh,
they said,
look,
here,
we're going to bring you back through
this.
We want to film the whole thing.
I'm like,
I don't know about that because I got
burned bad in film here while back,
you know,
and they just cut me a new one.
Man,
they lied to me and didn't.
But anyway,
it happens.
Film,
this whole thing and it's the end of it.
If we put it together and you don't like
it will never go out.
Really.
You're gonna get me that,
right?
You're going to invest this money and
this time,
because we,
I stayed there for three and a half
years because it took me that long to
get clean.
That's amazing.
You know,
I couldn't go in for six months.
I've done that.
I get them going for four months.
Held the time I went in for four months.
Man.
I go across the stage and get my
diploma,
so to speak,
from finishing this course,
being in Rehab for four months,
I go out the other side,
pickup a payphone and call my dealer.
He meets me outside and the doorman with
a big rock in a stem.
Thank you.
I made it,
but that's the insanity of the disease.
The disease.
We'll let you sit in a place for three
or four months and not touch you.
What are you even come knocking on your
door?
Because it knows right now you're locked
into your own to do this,
but it's open.
They're doing pushups in the corner,
man.
Waiting on her.
As soon as you get away from these
idiots over here teaching you bad
habits,
Jake,
uh,
I'm going to get you where you need to
be.
And that was the thing of being there
for that long period of time.
What was the feeling like when you did
slip up?
Because a couple of times,
four or five times I did,
it was horrible.
I wanted to die because not only did I
feel like I let myself down,
lay him down and that really sucked
because here's a guy is opened up his
wallet incident.
You come live with me.
Don't worry about your damn bills.
I'll take care of them.
Excuse me.
Oh Damn.
Damn.
Sure.
In that,
you know,
you don't have to talk to me about this.
Scrabble.
Yeah.
I'm moving in with your brother.
If you go pay all my bills,
man,
when I get healthy,
but I never found was going to take
three years.
Wow.
Let's see.
He would take,
you know,
if he had to go do a con or go do some
music,
go to go to a movie or something.
He had people that worked for DDP Yoga,
specifically Garrett,
and I'm a young kid named Dylan,
who I really got the kid messed up,
you know,
because he had to share a room with me.
I don't wear clothes.
Okay.
What kind of freaky?
Here's this old wrestler that I idolized
for years and I'm seen as junk.
All gray hair and everything.
Seeing the snake and the bat,
I accidentally bent over picking
something up right there by his bed.
I had no idea my son was in his mouth.
But uh,
yeah,
Dylan,
he lived through some horrible things
and Gary did too,
but
Dallas always made sure I've taken care
of,
you know,
he,
whatever he had to do the first thing
you have to do to take care of Jake.
And he put me first.
I didn't expect that we would.
The solidarity and the comradery that
you guys all have an razor Ramon as well
when you guys were all in on the house
together,
like the experiences that you guys
shared working together and then still
in life,
you know,
you guys have a bond that's very,
very.
It's very hard for most people.
Yeah.
They can't get it.
It's like guys that are in the service
together,
there's just something that becomes.
They become brothers in one and with
Dallas,
you know,
the thing about him was he's never went
down that addiction,
that addiction road.
He used to run nightclubs,
but he never became an alcoholic.
He's a freak.
Piss on him.
Screw him.
He got a better car than I did.
Okay.
I get that,
but I liked my cars.
No,
ma'am.
My cards now are awesome.
My life is so good to go from hell
because that's where I was at,
man.
You have no idea what it's like to wake
up and be angry that you woke up.
You didn't want to.
You want.
You want it to be over and there's been
so many years were like that for me that
I wouldn't go out shopping.
Lists was 3:00
AM,
so I didn't want anybody to see me
because I had gotten to the point.
I hated myself so much.
I'm begging God to die.
When I would hear another wrestler died,
I'd get angry at God and curse him for
not taking me.
Instead,
when Piper died,
we were just talking about rodey before
art.
Man.
I was so pissed off that he got to go
before I did and that's wrong,
man.
I mean,
even when I tried to Odi a couple of
times,
young really tried.
I took 100 value.
She's a surgeon,
milligram volume.
Woke up it.
All I've done is puke on my shelf and I
said,
what a fucking loser you are.
You can even die,
right?
You're a piece of shit.
What kind of mindsets that mine is the
torture that people put themselves
through,
that people get the wrong idea about the
shit man.
They think,
yeah,
their elbow,
they're getting fucked up,
man.
They're happy.
No,
we're not.
we're not happy.
We're not enjoying getting high.
I could enjoy and getting high 30 years
ago,
but the problem was I couldn't live
without it.
I mean,
I would feel like my heart was going to
burst.
I couldn't breathe.
I was scared to go anywhere.
She was it,
everything or anything.
Like what,
what,
what was drawn?
What was pulling you?
What drug or what happened and what was
it?
Booze.
It for me,
it was more everything.
I,
I'm lucky I didn't get to in the heroin,
you know,
I probably wouldn't have beat that one,
but uh,
yeah I would because that's,
this is what I'm meant to be doing right
now.
But to go through 25,
30 years of doing cocaine,
that's amazing.
You know,
I think Vince Mcmahon for affording me
my addiction because without it I'd be
in prison somewhere because I would have
killed somebody for my drug.
No,
without a doubt.
I would have knifed and whatever.
Man.
You guys got a ball.
What's this done?
Life meant nothing to me,
man.
It gets to a point where you put
yourself in such a dark hole.
There is no lie.
None at all,
and it takes somebody special.
You couldn't have sent me to rehab right
then.
I'd have been out in in minutes.
Even when Dallas offered me a job to pay
the whole trip and you'll move in with
them.
We'll feed you the best damn food on the
planet.
We're going to get you healthy.
We're going to get the bullshit out of
your system.
I'm like,
yeah,
yeah.
I'm going to last about a week because I
knew me and I'm like,
dude,
if I'm making it a week,
I'm going to be doing good because at
the time I couldn't do 24 hours not
doing cocaine.
Wow.
If you wanted me to get up out of bed,
pray me some go.
Okay,
wow,
that's where I was at because life was
too ugly
to want to go out there.
When did it start?
Did it start when you pro wrestling
career started or before then?
Uh,
no.
the cocaine and alcohol alcohol was
always.
I mean,
I started drinking when I was 11 or 12.
Whoa.
My uh,
grandfather was an alcoholic drug slash
drug addict because it started with an
oilfield accident.
He got his legs crushed and uh,
he refused his legs cut off.
So he stayed in the hospital for 18
months.
Well,
back in the 19 twenties,
the way that they fixed you let it heal
then rebreak it,
you know,
that's what they did.
They didn't put bars and metal in there
to straighten it out.
They'd let it heal and they'd break in a
different way.
Oh.
And they kept him,
kept him on morphine for a year and a
half.
Was the end of the year and half.
They patted him on the back.
See you.
He had little itch going out there,
didn't he could.
So he could walk.
So it worked.
But it took you a hooked up on morphine.
Which back then,
it wasn't like today you can get on any
corner.
Right.
He went to alcohol.
I remember in the sixties,
which is 40 years later.
They not trusting him to come to the
doctor's office.
Will,
they didn't trust him to take the pill,
the pill,
the pill being a.
Oh my God.
What's it called?
Keep you from drinking.
Um,
and abuse,
you know,
he'd taken an abuse bill.
You're not going to drink it,
but it's a pita.
I mean,
I've drank on an abuse when it's been
two days since I'd had the pill and I
have a drink whether you have no idea
how scary that shit is because
immediately you start throwing up and
you start pissing and shitting your
pants.
It happens that quick and then you have
to start with the sweats and all this
and you'll wind up on the floor during
the Heebie jeebies man,
that sounds strong and abuse as well.
They didn't even trust him to take the
pill.
They said,
no,
no.
You take a taxi to the doctor's office
and we'll give you a shot.
Who We know you're not going to take
that pill.
So He'd do that every morning and he'd
go outside and get in the same taxi and
because we lived in a dry county,
he would take that same taxi over to the
next county and get a fifth of whiskey
train,
get before he got home.
Now the rest of his day spent shitting
and puking.
Wow.
But yet tomorrow he gonna do the same
thing.
Oh my God.
That's the hell you know.
I was doing the.
You're doing the coke and stuff,
man.
I'm hating myself the whole time I do
it.
I'm not getting high anymore and I can't
put it down.
I can't turn away from it because
there's hope in that.
What's the hope for no more pain?
So just that it numbs more shame.
Shame.
Shame is something you put on yourself.
You know you can't shame me,
man.
I have to do it myself.
The man who was their man in,
because I'd went through some ugly shit
as a kid.
Being sexually molested,
my sister,
being molested too,
and then my sister and murdered and we
got all these things thrown in there and
I was hating myself because I didn't
protect my sister better.
Um,
you know,
life happens.
What you do with it.
That's one of the things that Dallas
preaches,
you know,
is about.
He got all this stuff out there,
man.
It's going to come at you.
I just want you to do with accounts.
You don't deflect it.
No,
you bring it to you,
you chew it up,
you spit it out,
swept,
sift through the bullshit and you go on
is something I couldn't do because they
got personal with me and I would lock
down.
I'd shut up because that's how I handle
things.
I just didn't talk about it.
When you've been sexually molested,
there is no good moment and that screwed
my head up and it still messes with my
head.
I desperately,
desperately want to have a relationship
with a woman.
No true relationship.
Finally,
it's 63 because I did have relationships
before that I was constantly sabotaging
them because I didn't trust women with
those.
The last one,
he raped me and beat me and threatened
me and told me that my dad killed me
because you know,
my dad was seven foot and weighed 425
pounds so he could get the job done.
I just wanted my dad to be proud of me.
So all these things are a factor now.
Quiet while the wife beats me and made
me do her and then beats me afterwards.
Dude,
sex and sex.
If you're doing it like that,
the coal rape and that Shit's screws
your head up for life.
Now what do you do with it?
Well is a kid.
I hid that shit,
man.
I stuffed it away.
I didn't talk about that.
Are you kidding me?
When do you remember the first time
talking about it to a high school buddy
of mine?
He says,
you're so fucking lucky.
Manual.
Your stepmother still fucking hot.
She was.
She's 22 years old because my father is
a child molester for Christ's sake.
Of course she was on,
but it wasn't hot to me because that's
my mom know.
And then the bds afterwards.
That's fucking confused as you got all
this shit going,
man.
So you start looking for a way out.
And for me as a kid,
my grandfather would get drunk and
forget where he hit his liquor because
he had to hide it from her grandmother
because she knew what he was.
She had dealt with it for 50 years.
So every time she found a bottle on the
farm she'd break it.
And that's it.
So he would hide it.
Chicken,
my house,
different places.
Well me and my buddies from girls
straight with go out and find it.
Get 12 years old,
11 years old.
Then we got smart and started selling
into the other neighborhood kids and
make a buck.
That was my beginning of the drink man.
And uh,
you know,
as time goes on,
man,
you start smoking weed in the pills.
What else is next?
Because I'm still not forgetting.
I'm still remembering this shit.
And you go out and you try to have a
good time with people and then you
realize something's different than you
because drugs it put you to sleep.
Wake me up,
you know,
downers.
Wake me up,
the council,
I wired,
he gave me five Percocet,
brother,
I'll drink a case of beer and dance all
night for you.
Really go out and have three or four
wrestling matches.
Let's go to the.
If I tell you
when I've messed my neck up and 89 when
he was a guitar,
when I wanted to go to the gym,
my regimen was to wake up,
go downstairs,
starts coffeemaker.
Take two men,
10 milligram percocet them in my mouth,
chew them up and wash them down with
coffee and hit the gym.
Jesus.
I loved it because I was on fire man.
Plus the percocet made me a little
gnarly.
Made me want to punch in.
Really?
So you get a good workout in anything
good from percosets.
That's how screwed up my wiring is.
That is.
So you talked to any drug and they'll
tell you their wiring.
Yeah,
things that make you go to sleep.
Wake me up.
Things that wake you up but me to sleep.
So the,
the pain of pro wrestling,
which is probably one of the most brutal
professions and the person can embark
and write and think about all the days
that you were on the road,
all the many,
many matches,
all that physical pain probably
justified the drugs even more.
I didn't even care.
He didn't care about the fact.
I don't.
I felt no pain.
I wrestled none afterwards.
No.
I was wrestling in a guy in Louisiana,
Ernie the cat lad,
you remember him playing for the Afl San
Diego chargers.
He's in the hall of fame football and
wrestling.
60 nine slash three slash 50 bad ass son
of a bitch,
man,
you know,
but back then they had chopped box and
he had like 15 knee surgeries and that
was in his career.
But we were wrestling and my bone came
out of my arm compound fracture and he
goes,
kid you're arm.
I'm like,
yeah,
I see it.
It's gone.
And he's like,
get away from me and I,
I'm trying to get to him.
And he started puking on me.
I'm like,
motherfucker,
you're puking on me.
Your arm and your arm is fucking bomb.
Dude.
Finished the match.
Fuck you.
I'm getting out of the way,
man.
He could pick up a bunch of shit.
You finish off your opponent by having
them nasty smelling shit to.
But I was fine.
I got back in it.
No,
I was sitting there and I was always
saying,
this is a strange thing.
Not a blow on the bone.
It feels cold.
My blown that bowl.
Oh Wow.
Whoa.
Fifteen minutes later I'm in the car.
Holy Fuck.
But you felt it.
The adrenaline's gone.
You've been in the ring and he knew what
this light's.
Adrenaline's going.
Nothing hurts.
It feels good.
In fact,
you know what?
I would've thought that he would look at
the bone and go,
Ooh,
I've got to handle this.
Now.
Did you wrestle fucked up?
No.
Wrestled,
struggled,
straight bird know I've been going
through a withdrawals at the time.
But uh,
no I didn't drinker either before,
before match.
And I didn't like it,
but I did it that way because it's my
and my thing is another wrestler to take
care of my opponent.
I noticed that after a,
if I have like a fun set or something
like that,
doing standup comedy that I like to
have,
like if it went,
if I tried something new and it will win
extra good,
I like to have an extra drink or two
that night.
Would it be like that for you in
wrestling?
Would you get more messed up?
It was like Madison Square Garden or
no,
I just went to sleep.
Go sleep was such a premium back then
back in my day we were wrestling seven
days a week,
seven days a week.
Well except for Saturday and Sunday.
Then we wrestled twice on Saturday.
Twice on Sunday.
Jesus,
like you might do the La Coliseum,
2:00
in a rental car and drive to San Diego.
Seen Wow.
The next day you might be in Omaha at
2:00
and then you'd be in Des Moines at 7:00.
Now you're driving all this in between.
You could fly.
You drive.
Well,
with me it made it even worse because I
got to drag that fucking snake
everywhere.
80 pound box of shit.
Be like currently.
Carry this around with a bad back over
there.
Hey folks out there.
Pray for him.
Man.
He's over there.
Who and moving back here.
He's making fun of young Jamie and Jamie
as a minor and it's very difficult to
talk about injuries when you around
snake.
I want to bring it up.
Totally threw me under the bus.
Told me before when I first got here was
like I pulled my back the other day but
I don't want to mention it in front of
Jake.
The snake because it's embarrassing.
Should be embarrassed.
Torres,
man.
Giant tortoise band giant.
It was horrible.
Jamie's a good man.
I will not stand here while he
disparaged him.
Shelby's though,
isn't it
dealt the snake did.
Was a snake a problem when you would get
on planes and ships them?
Twenty four slash seven.
Could you keep it secret or would they
let you on the plane with it?
Oh,
I never said anything to anybody.
It just brought it up.
No,
I just put it in a trunk.
A little blanket around the bag and then
locked the truck.
You carry it on or what you check?
Check it.
Wow.
Poor fuck.
It's like,
why is it so cold in here?
Forty thousand feet off the ground.
You goddamn noise.
The snake,
man.
You laugh about it.
It's like,
wait a minute,
I'll get a trade the snake out after 10
days.
Yeah,
they can't take it.
I'm like,
really?
So a fucking snake can't live through
the fucking scheduling,
but yet I'm asked to do 90 fucking days
straight.
So you have different snakes?
Yeah.
About every 10 days,
which used to be funny because people
say she brang Damien.
Like if you notice it Damien,
some weeks it's five years,
put middle.
It's not shrinkage honey.
So your seven days a week would go on
for the whole year.
Damn.
They just worked.
You know,
we,
I wrestled steamboat nine 93 days
straight and about three days in I had
to call my wife and her come take me
around because I'd gotten dumbed out to
the point that I couldn't think.
So I'd get to the airport,
know that they want tickets,
but I have no idea where they're at and
I can't read anymore.
I'd look at stuff to read,
but it just wouldn't.
It wouldn't work.
So I just ended up making fucking
exhaustion.
Wow.
Exhaustion.
You just get so beat up,
man.
Your body's hurting so bad.
People say steroids,
man.
We were taking steroids just to try to
get healthy to heal.
And that's what the shit was invented
for recovery.
You know that they invented in World War
Two,
believes what the story was for the
prisoners of war because they didn't
want the American soldiers to come home
looking like they did.
So they put them on slow fucking boats
and fed them for three months and guys
put on 30,
40 pounds.
They say there would have been another
war.
They'd have brought those troops home
coming from concentration camps for the
Germans or the Japanese and we'd have
seen the way they were.
And of course now that you can see some
of those old films of the way the Jews,
they were being slaughtered and
everything.
And a bag of bones was.
It did.
They didn't want to bring those troops
home.
So they invented steroids and started
popping everybody when that shit.
Wow.
And bring them back.
But we did it really just to try to tee.
Was it hard to get them right?
Yeah.
Right.
Well did they help you get them?
You know,
they say they helped me,
but
I will tell you there as he just said
enough already would
do is we would get booked and Hershey,
Pennsylvania.
Now when somebody told me this story
first and like this is an old wives tale
because shit like that don't really
happen.
You get to get downtown Hershey,
you go to the locker room all of a
sudden.
So much.
Or they need to see you in locker room
three.
That I do not go in there.
And there's this doctor there and he's
got suitcases over here.
Boxes here.
Suitcases here.
Boxes there.
What do you need?
Good.
Excuse me.
What do you need up down?
What are you asleep?
Those are good.
I'll take.
How many can I get?
$300.
Got It right here.
Wow.
Steroids?
Yeah.
Absolutely.
What do you got?
I'll take that.
And he was a grocery shopping and uh,
it used to be funny because the guys
went all,
Hey Jacob going to carry my shit for me
who will be going on in Canada?
And I'm like,
sure,
it's going to cost you a percentage of
your shit.
Give me 10 percent of what you got.
I'll carry it across the border for he
is Christ.
So Israel the dice.
I got eight or 10 guys.
I'm getting all their shit.
Where am I hiding in the snake bag for
crying out loud.
Of course you put that in the bottom of
the snow and that bag.
No.
And you get over there and they go,
we need to check the back of their
brother.
I'm gonna.
Tell you right now I'm moving back,
moving back for it.
Because that motherfucker is pissed.
He hasn't eaten in three weeks and he's
a little army.
Well,
if he does buy,
she went well.
When he does bite,
you try to hold.
Still hold still yet because if you jerk
is going to rip your flesh,
which is true.
If they tell you,
if a snake bites you,
whatever you do,
don't jerk away.
Excuse me,
sir.
Your rottweilers chewing on my ass hole.
Please kindly remove him.
No,
you jerk and you fight to get away.
Did you?
You use different kinds of snakes too
though,
right?
Yeah.
I use pythons and cobras.
When you use the Colbert,
did you?
They defang them?
Yeah.
Dammit.
Had minimize them.
I didn't define them date,
so they had.
They don't have things.
Oh,
by the Cobra.
Cobra is don't have things.
They have teeth.
Oh really?
Yeah,
it really sucks.
So they bite you no matter what.
It's like to him it's like chewing a,
you know,
have you ever fished and got a cat that
you're send me.
Fill the spiny mouth.
That's what their bite felt like,
but it doesn't matter what it feels
like.
It's what it looks like.
There's a over there
and the viewers don't know that at all.
Especially when you're a little boy
watching it.
I mean the Saturday morning that you
selected it on macho man,
Randy Savage affected an entire
generation nut I've ever got.
I.
Oh,
there's no doubt.
I mean,
it affected me so deeply as a kid.
If I'm ever laying around with a girl
and I'm having a little problem in the
woods,
key department,
it happens at 63 a.
You put that on,
you know,
and uh,
I put the video on it instantly.
I'm kidding.
Really?
Oh brother,
that's your hardest man.
Why?
Holy Shit.
Watch me.
Watch.
That was.
This was literally the ultimate bad guy
putting a snake on a good guy and look
at the.
Look on that kid's face in the corner.
That park jumped up,
finger up his ass or that kid is gonna.
Have a goddamn heart attack,
but you have a heart rate monitor on
him.
One hundred 80 beats per minute.
I had a conversation with one of my good
friends,
Pete.
You know Pete,
when he saw this,
you have a good friend,
but quick question I want to ask you,
but check out.
This is the kind of quality friend.
I have a dealer.
When he saw this,
when I,
when he saw this as a kid,
all on the same day that I saw him,
he ran away from home.
It freaked him out so badly.
When you put this snake on my arm,
he packed it.
He didn't even have anywhere to go.
He ended up coming home later that night
after it got cold or Kid,
he packed a bag and just left.
How old was he?
Oh Geez.
Probably.
Probably,
probably I would guess,
you know,
11,
12,
something like that.
Kids.
You're raped that day because jake.
Right.
Okay.
Oh No.
Let me tell you the real story on this
whole thing.
You want to hear this job?
Here's how it really went down.
I've been waiting 30 years ago.
I got the done with the python because
that motherfucker tell you the truth is
killing me.
You know,
weight.
One hundred pounds and then he would
bite me and then it would be 30,
40 stitches.
That was 37 stitches there on it.
Oh my God.
You got the vein.
Make actually committed suicide that
night.
Look at that shit.
It's cool,
isn't it?
I mean,
this was just handles it a better bite
when you're doing a great job,
look at that thing.
Sinking it's fucking teeth into him and
then at the end the little stream of
blood comes through and that was the
final.
Oh my gosh.
I'll try to get a blues.
I'm trying.
I couldn't get a moose.
Oh my gosh.
Struggling to get him off blood.
Finally I had to prize mouth open to get
him off.
And by the way,
this is one Saturday morning.
So it's this,
you flip the channel.
It's a little old school cartoons that
weren't even like entertaining.
You know what I mean?
And then there's this chaos on another
channel and it's so obviously real.
Oh yeah.
It's.
So obviously she's terrified of snakes.
Well,
if he wasn't before,
Piper pulled a gun on me one time over
snake,
man.
Really?
What happened?
I snuck up behind him with a snake and
he fucking heard me.
Jagan went,
yeah,
he,
you know what?
You're fucking doing.
Any job.
You don't even get a fucking pistol and
polarized motherfucker.
I'll kill you.
I'm like,
okay,
Roddy.
Again,
when I get it,
I get guy was shaking their fears,
their store,
here's the store.
I'm in the locker room behaving myself.
In fact,
I believe I was cleaning the wash cloth,
black boards off and making it nice for
everybody and
macho walks in easily.
Already going to do it tonight against
story.
Fucking going around.
We're going to get down and do it.
Sounds great,
and it's like we're going to take care
of business first.
What built the snake?
Has he been fixed or not fixed?
You mean poisonous?
He goes,
yeah,
that might be the fuck.
I'm like,
Randy,
of course he's been fixed.
He goes,
maybe as in maybe he has to.
Stranger things have happened in the
wwe.
Somebody wants to match your match.
Intercontinental Levy,
we championship title.
It's just the UN had poisonous snake
going,
I'm the fucking rest is history.
He was dead stage to jump.
I'm like,
dude,
are you fucking Jake?
I'm just telling you this.
He has to blank.
You know?
Wow.
Like what?
He goes it that we got to go at it right
now.
Me and you and he's up in my fucking
face with his fist like,
fuck man,
what the fuck is wrong with you?
Don't play no fucking games.
So I got to sneak out man.
I'm psychotic motherfucker.
Like any special place you want it to
bite me like my deck and like,
where's good,
how about the leg?
I'm like,
fine.
So I got to cobra out and pull my pant
leg up.
Shimmin m a little bit and stuck my leg
up here and he fucking beat me three,
four seconds.
Let's go march.
It was like,
no,
don't fucking move.
Take no lecture.
Do,
don't fucking pit bull shit.
Just fucking sit there and want to see
the boys go through your body and chewed
me filing.
After about 10 minutes,
she's like,
let me get.
You're going to be on camera.
Sorry.
I didn't fucking make you happy.
If I'd known you want me to die,
die easily.
You'll be tonight brother.
You fever once the snake lids below me
bringing back may want you to begin
because I want this idea to fucking
bullshit.
Fucking beat money.
Yeah.
Can you dig it?
Dig It.
All right,
we're out of here.
Wow.
Motherfucker,
you wait.
Pissed man,
because it's one thing to get bit in the
heat of a moment.
But to sit there and fucking cold,
have to hike her fucking pant legs up
and let a fucking snake chew on you to
make a motherfucker happy.
Come on,
give me a break.
We're asking a lot.
So if all those people were there,
I wouldn't have felt anything.
Just sit there and like in the locker
room,
cold,
really much pumping other.
So I remember during the match,
we do.
Imagine a time in the ropes,
get the snake out,
came,
let's make sure he's happy.
And so I turned my back to macho man.
He doesn't see me and I fucked paint.
Brush hell out of his fucking snake.
Man pounded that motherfucker yet met a
second time.
He's fucking mouthful and brother and
he's looking for anything to fucking
bikers.
And I just went whoa.
And took him the macho man and he
latched on and he's true and he's shown
me how much you're doing a great job.
Just ready.
You look so believable.
Goddamn fucking nuts.
What did they do to the snake?
Remove this poison glands.
They moved the venom sex.
Yeah.
So there's no venom in its body damage.
They replaced it with fucking stuff for
bullying plants,
man.
You know,
they say like silicone silicone.
Oh yeah.
Sailing time better too.
So,
uh,
they just cut them out.
It's just like an operation or cut them
out and fill them with silicone manager.
They can't regrow them.
Oh Wow.
Wow.
So they can't,
otherwise it would regrown yeah.
Creepy fucking animal.
Huh?
Frightening.
Especially as a kid.
And that did shoot you guys up at big
law apple.
They did.
And I couldn't imagine what we talk
about.
Ninety one.
Wow.
Yeah.
It fucking rock world,
Bro.
Yeah.
Me and my little kid to watch a real
snake and actual code that couldn't get
laid for months.
Man really sticks in your room.
You're not fucking lying to me.
I'll come on.
Wow,
please baby.
And you really did have the snake in the
bathtub bathtub playing in the water.
Oh Wow.
It's like 4:00
in the morning for a fucking drug junkie
to walk in the bathroom.
Now I'm paranoid is motherfucker anyway
because I'm fucking all this shit and
now I got to look down on a 15 foot
snake.
That's fuck.
Got His mouth open.
Looking at my fucking little Dick.
Are you serious?
I'm not pissing.
What do you mean?
I gotta take a shit.
Nah,
not anymore.
So I go in the other room.
A piss in a fucking bottom.
OOPS,
I missed.
What the fuck?
Just pissed enough.
Wow.
Yeah.
Don't walk in my room.
Barefooted.
Squish,
squish.
What did you feed it?
I didn't.
You didn't.
Was one of the only out there for 10
days.
So.
So what,
how often they eat once ever.
Six weeks or so.
Oh really?
Really?
The action and the flying and
everything.
They'd only live for 10 days.
They had to get them off the road and
let them heal because of snakes.
A lungs go the entire length of their
body.
They're very tiny,
so they get pneumonia really easy.
Of course being in minus 40,
it doesn't help either,
but they do get pneumonia really easy.
Would you have to get a new snake?
Was that your responsibility?
We had a guy in Stanford,
Connecticut,
he was Charles Manson revisited.
This guy was a freak brother,
Stanford,
Connecticut to weird plus he had a farm
in down Connecticut and they did not
know that he had over a thousand snakes
in that farm on that building in about
150 of them are poisonous because he was
collecting venom for different,
for different pharmaceutical companies.
But uh,
I remember one time having to get a
snake from him and he flew to Omaha and
you know,
he'd been working with me for a couple
of years.
The Albert Man will take care of you
tonight,
but I think it was jake like will take
you to strip joints on this family.
I know it's not necessarily,
hey bro,
let me take you out.
So we get there man.
I use just kind of like sitting there
and it was head down towards the table
looking at his beer and right job.
And I'm like,
this motherfucker going,
you know,
so the dude pick her out if you'll take
a price I'll pay for.
It was a mobile and buzzing.
He goes,
Oh jake,
just take my snakes.
Oh,
excuse me.
I just want to go back to the room and
play as much snakes and what?
Change rooms?
Different floor.
He was a real freakazoid into snakes.
Is he still alive?
Yeah,
he is.
He was in Florida when that bet
hurricane hit down there and he was
working in a gator farm and poisonous
snake venom collection point and they
had like 800 snakes down there.
Right.
So the hurricane hits and just fucking
levels of place.
Why?
I'm calling for days trying to get ahold
of him,
see if he's all right and finally get a
hold of me.
I'm like,
dude,
why are you so fucking happy?
Because that was the best time of my
life,
man.
This is fucking like God's made this.
Especially for me.
I'm like,
what are you talking about?
He goes,
I get to find all those snakes.
You get to find them.
Let me think.
You're going to dig through all that
Shit,
all that shit and a lift up stuff and
stick your hand down and holes and shit
to find these poisonous snakes.
Fuck you out for your fucked up.
What is it with Florida and snakes?
Connecticut,
man.
Whatever.
Nobody wants to Florida.
It's like a magnet.
He was in Connecticut men and they asked
him to go do anything for the boy's
Club,
you know,
introduce them to snakes and blah blah,
blah.
Would be great,
you know,
eight to 12 year olds.
So he gets in there and he's talking to
them about this Mexican rattler.
Now,
first thing you know about snakes is
yes,
they can be poisonous and poisonous
snakes.
Children.
What happens there?
They're not healthy.
They weren't you.
They can kill you.
Yes,
that's right.
So that's why you should always keep it
up.
Oh my God.
Oh Lord.
Okay.
Look,
he's accidentally bit me.
You know,
I've been bitten now.
So I think what I'm going to do,
somebody called nine.
One one.
Um,
we're gonna.
I'm just gonna.
Explain to you what I'm feeling right
now.
So if you ever get bitten,
you'll know what you're gonna.
Expect to feel after you've been bitten
with talking with these girls.
Know their fees.
Fucking bite,
man.
Yeah,
he's fucked.
And he knows that he's fucked because
here's the thing about Mexican
rattlesnakes,
not many of those in Connecticut.
So you don't have any answers.
I've been,
um,
do you?
Oh Jesus.
No,
they got to fly it in from fucking deal
Atlanta or wherever.
So by the time they get that shit out
there,
man,
he's fucked up.
And they went out and they cut all the
meat off one of his bones on his finger.
So you got like this gnarly.
So he had a necropsy right?
Yeah.
I've seen a video or a website rather
detailing this kid got bit in the arm,
no meat had to get him somewhere to
safety.
But it took hours,
that medivac helicopter,
his whole arm rotted away,
down to the bone.
So they had to take meat from his legs,
get it off and put,
you know,
they had to do skin grafts all over.
I think he went through like 16
operations.
She's awful.
They had a stitch them all together,
like pull the meat of his arm together
and stitch it all together.
I mean it was a giant 10 to 12 inch
patch of his arm.
Was Gone,
yeah,
it fucks you up.
Really cool looking thing that it does
is it causes all the small capillaries
in your eyes to burst.
So your eyes are like blood red,
except they're bumpy.
Uh,
you know,
like he closed his eyes and I run my
finger over his eyelid and you just feel
all these little bumps and crevices and
cat damaged.
Weird to take for him to recover.
He's in the hospital for a couple of
weeks,
man.
He was a,
he had to put him in a coma for like six
days.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
But he cool.
He cool.
Is He,
does he have a tolerance to regular
venom?
Because I know a lot of those.
Building a tolerance to different ones.
Yeah.
They make themselves get bit a cobra.
I think he's pretty much clean on this
guy.
Sounds like he's going to end up being a
super villain of some kind.
He could be mad because I swear to God
he is Charles Manson.
Wow.
He looks like Charles Manson looks
weird.
Like anyway,
he smiles just like,
dude,
that is not healthy,
you know,
all.
Fuck.
Wow.
He's a true.
Imagine what this guy would be like
without snakes.
Thank God snakes exists where you have a
steamboat,
you know,
come up with a Komodo dragon thing,
to,
to combat the snake back in the day.
I don't know.
So of course,
that's who Albert Albert was,
the guy with a Komodo dragons,
so he had some pottery was growing up in
the mountains and he took one of the
dragons with him to get it out in the
sunlight.
So they put it in this fucking station
wagon and they go up in the mountains
and they actually walk to their place
where they get their stuff growing.
They closed the over up,
leave the window down.
That much
take off,
come back window's busted.
Oh Jesus.
Or Jesus' horrible teeth marks on all of
it where this fucking Komodo dragons and
chewing his way out of this shit.
He was in a wooden Katie.
He chewed his way out of the wooden
case,
but he got out man and took off.
And I guess it's about two months later,
man,
I was like in Indianapolis and waking up
and listening to the news and the espns
on or like what was thought to be a
prehistoric monster was found running
across the backyard.
Ms Dot Gibbons Hills,
chasing her poor little poop when we get
back,
see our monster.
Wow.
They come back and I'm sitting on what
the fuck.
Be prehistoric hacking.
Got to see this shit in the fucking
thing.
Goes back at fucking Albert's fucking
thing,
man.
It's the thing that had escaped two
months later,
he had gained like 35 pounds.
Everybody's dogs and cats in the
neighborhood.
A couple of kids to who?
That is such a ruthless animal,
you know,
those things are so ruthless that the
little baby Komodo dragon smear shit on
themselves so that the grownups don't
eat them so that their parents don't eat
them.
They roll around and shit so that their
parents don't eat them.
Because uh,
when Komodo dragons are eating
intestines,
they shake the shit out of intestines.
They don't like to eat shit.
As weird as that is bad attitude.
I had a problem with cocaine.
Imagine that they eat their fucking kids
so the kids know this.
So they somehow or another like no to
smear themselves and shit.
I'd learned pretty quick.
Yeah.
You see your sister get chewed up.
I see them avoid shit but eat your
sister.
Yo.
That shit.
Is Salvation some good shit.
It had gained 30 pounds.
That's fucking crazy.
Yeah.
Let it loose in Florida.
They won't even notice.
Fuck everything else they got down.
Yeah.
The Florida everglades is so crazy.
Python's man.
So,
so bad that they're eating alligators.
They did this study.
They found that they couldn't find any
raccoons.
They couldn't find any swamp rabbits or
march hares,
I guess they call them.
Yeah.
Everything got killed by python.
So then the pythons moved on to
alligators.
Yeah.
Alligators.
They don't have a real man.
I've got a picture of an anaconda
swallowing an 800 pound horse.
One.
It's got the head in the front legs
already treated inside picture.
You know,
I need it.
I'll get you.
I need that fucking shit.
See if you could find that.
Jamie body is like this big with his
back.
He probably can't pull it up.
Jamie,
he's coming at you hard and weapons.
I bet.
In all your years you never thought
Jake,
the snake would be roasting you.
Live on the Internet,
believe Dat and mail it back.
Injury and nailing a pull it up.
Reference.
Got you bro.
I'm not just a short phase in a pretty
Dick.
Short dignam pretty face.
That's it.
Did you ever low the day that you came
up with the Gimmick of having snake?
God,
Yah.
Imagine what everybody else is traveling
solo.
Here's the thing.
I come up with this idea like in 1975
because I listened to Monday night
football and they were talking about
Kenny Stabler.
Remember him playing for the raiders.
I remember the name of 10 quarterback
man,
swing it and boy he gets sling it man.
And he also liked to party man.
So I've dug him,
man.
You know what I'm saying?
Motherfuckers.
Cool brother.
I mean super believe he took all the
linemen with him out to the bars.
They didn't show up a 4:30
in the morning.
Now here's the thing,
do the coach keep them from playing?
I don't think so,
but he did tell him you better fucking
win.
Yeah.
That's all.
What's his name?
Told him you better fucking win because
if you don't know Marsha last bucket.
Oh yeah.
It's tapered.
Took them out there and they won the
game.
So.
But uh,
I don't know.
But I love the Kenny Stabler the snake
thing.
And here it is actually.
Yeah,
there you go.
Fucking hippo at eight.
A hippo.
Jesus Christ.
Oh,
well it's got to be a baby.
Hippo doesn't look like it's too fucking
small.
Yeah.
But hippos are huge.
Baby Hippos.
Probably.
Probably big is your Dick.
A lot of things.
There we go.
Whoa.
Which is pretty mentioned because they
can't gurgitate they had to pull that
shit out.
That's insane.
But we,
uh,
I was riding down the road last Monday
night football and I'd be too much,
man,
if a fucking wrestler,
you know,
smoking some weed,
curious snake around and fuck with the
other restaurants,
drinking.
And it was more and more and more.
And uh,
next day I woke up with my idea and less
carrying a fucking tonight what the fuck
was I thinking?
I'm terrified of snakes because I'm
terrified.
But how do you connect that to the
football player?
Because he was Kenny the snake.
Stabler.
Oh,
here we go into snake.
it was just bad ass,
man.
I wanted to be the snake too.
So you were already Jake Roberts and.
No,
it wasn't even j Dot Robertson.
And then I,
I looked for a name,
the snake.
The snake.
Fuck that guy.
Like a guy with like a golf shirt,
flaky snaky.
He's got a 40 foot putt.
He blames the snake.
Has a bad back.
Not even,
not even blake would have a bad back.
But,
uh,
you know,
what the fuck was I thinking because I'm
terrified of snakes.
I'll never do that fucking gimmick.
Fuck that.
But I did go and said,
okay,
I got to think of a name and Jake,
the snake that works.
Why am I thinking that?
And at the time of the TV program was
Dallas.
Who's the bad guy?
Jr Jr.
Jake the snake.
Wow.
And I came up with robert's,
I'm a snake.
Well,
after years of throwing it up there
occasionally and getting.
Are you fucking serious?
Wrestling is not a fucking circus stuff.
Fuck it ain't.
Excuse me bill.
Watch fat.
Fuck steven bastard before vince,
before vince in the wwf.
What organization was it?
Mid south.
And um,
they Just fucking told under no
uncertain terms that we've ever,
you know,
I'm like,
wait a minute,
you don't want me to carry a snake,
but the guy I'm wrestling has got a
fucking hockey match,
colon.
And every night he fucking head busted
With it and you have me carved my
fucking forehead open so he can bleed
everywhere.
But it's not A circus.
I get that totally.
You bet.
Ya know.
So blow it out the window.
Then I went to fucking New York and
that's when vince vincent me with the,
uh,
you're going to be wearing a purple or
lime green span to excellence.
I said,
ain't no fucking fag and I'm not wearing
a 85,
86.
I'll foRget how long vince has been in
the game.
Oh hell yeah.
He bought that guy out,
the guy that he bought,
he just went to every territory and just
said,
oh,
I'll give you this amount of money.
I'm just taking your cleaners with my
heart.
I'm giving this to you because I'm
taking your all your television.
Yeah.
So crazy.
All the people that was all split up
into territory.
So everybody had their own business and
reinforced age might be another one.
Territory.
You know what's really crazy about
vince's?
How fucking jack is like,
what Is he?
Seventy five,
64,
65.
He was on the cover of men's fitness,
uh,
with chains around his neck real
recently.
Yeah.
Jack jumped in about growth hormone.
That description used to work.
I think there's a lot more going on than
just growth hormone.
Well,
I'm sure there is a feeling.
It's a stack.
You gotta.
Look at this.
This is him.
Seventy three.
What in the fuck is that?
How is that as the billionaire tunc that
isn't sane.
Checked his back is 73 years old.
Was built like brock lesnar.
That is insane.
He's the man.
Imagine like seeing this when you were a
kid,
like this is what grandpa looks like.
You'd be like,
what the fuck is going on with grandpa
and grandma daddy?
That is insane.
Seventy three years old there is on this
planet who works as hard as he does,
but there's no other way.
It's possible.
I mean the guy is,
he's he's everywhere and at one the one
video where he runs to the ring and is
on his way in,
dives into it and slams his thigh into
the siloing,
blows his fucking quad off the ball and
then still plays it out and does it
sitting down.
Must have been in unbelievable agony,
right?
He can't even stand up and he's just
sitting there sitting on his butt and
they.
Everybody has to like improvise,
but this guy sitting on his ass because
he's.
He blew his quads off of his bone.
Watch this shit.
Look at this.
I mean,
this is fucking crazy.
I did the same thing and tour.
Look at this.
He dives in,
slams it and look at it.
His leg gives out.
You've done at that point,
your adrenaline.
Oh,
you're thinking is get the fuck up.
That's all you're thinking,
but it's crazy that he's just sitting
there.
The funniest part of this is this is the
final moment of the royal rumble.
This is a huge long buildup and it's
controversial because they both went
over the top and landed,
so there's this tide,
so all the reps are trying to figure out
what's going on,
so it makes it even funnier.
That vince's just sitting there,
the owner stretched out,
teased tiesta was that jesus christ,
he's so much bigger than he is now in
guardians of the galaxy.
Forget protein diet.
That's all natural,
bro.
That's vegan stuff.
yeah,
she's kind of being stuck.
It's incredible.
I mean,
just the fact that that guy was able to
do that.
I got to bring this up because we were
watching this in the greenroom.
Rip before we get to dAvid arquette is
wrestling.
Did you know this?
Yeah.
David or kevin?
Blood got a light bulb smashed in.
His head,
cuts all over his face.
A fucking two by four.
Two by four.
And what is the worst shit you ever get?
Hit with a guitar,
a guitar.
Oh,
that's honky tonk.
It was a real guitar.
That's really surprising to me because
it always appeared like the honky tonks
guitar was just an exploding.
They'll work after that.
What is this wcw world heavyweight
champion.
David arquette.
Wait a minute.
He was there for awhile,
but it was a highly controversial
moment.
Heavyweight champion.
How much does he weigh?
40.
That doesn't make any sense.
He is definitely built Way bigger.
He's way thicker than he's ever been
before because when they showed him on
tmz,
he was running around.
He looked jack on dvds,
got diva size.
now you can find the video that the tmz
video because it's kind of fucking
hilarious.
Is really.
And just goes to show you what happens
though,
man.
It's a lunch that you get for it.
You know wrestling.
I hated wrestling growing up.
Hated it because your dad did it because
my dad did it and he was home,
so I blamed the wrestling for him.
Never being home.
Bottom line was he didn't give a fuck
about kids except those eco rape.
And look at that.
He got hit in the head,
oh jesus christ.
That guy stabbed him in them gowns with,
with a fluorescent light bulb that he
just shattered.
By the way.
You can get that dust in your eyes.
Glass does,
but look how big he is.
Yeah.
He's our kid was never that big before.
He's looking more like an eddie
guerrero,
right know.
Kind of a hilarious look at jackie is
the.
The thing about david doing this is that
like he just got sober a Few years ago
and he's doing this to keep life
exciting for him,
you know what I mean?
And I just was doing it or just doesn't
have any movie roles coming in now.
He's,
he's,
he's okay.
We'll do it.
I didn't know he's okay.
You would use agent.
Well,
I went,
no,
but he's wrestling.
AgEnt argued you shock.
Who's fucking jack?
Dude.
I mean,
I'm very impressed with his physique.
Got into executive producing a bunch of
stuff.
Like he's one of the executive producers
of like cougar town.
Oh,
these with his ex wife.
All these massive show runs back in and
get stumped,
but you see where you're still getting
pushback from the guys.
He goes,
no,
I'm going to lay doWn here.
I'm not gonna fucking get hit again.
Oh,
and then he just hit him with a chair
that broken glass on it.
This is some high level production for
50 people in the room.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's all though the blood and
everything.
Jesus christ Function glass and arrange.
Brilliant.
Yeah.
That is crazy.
Now that's.
Then he leaves the fucking.
YeS.
You could tell he was pissed.
He didn't go the way he wanted it to.
Do you think he's pissed?
He was pissed.
Do you think they planned the whole?
Nobody fucked him.
Somewhere in there.
You get fucked.
You think so?
Because you've seen the him going for
the guy.
Then the guy just took him over and they
started and got Back on him.
He wasn't expecting that.
He was.
He thought he was going up and then you
see him.
Then you seem just fucking get up and
just fucking storm out of the fucking
ring.
Why?
When you stay and she gets fucking ass,
obviously you can't see.
He's trying to get to him.
The guy won't fucking let him.
Now watch guy takes him over and he's on
top of me looking for the one,
two,
three.
He got the one,
two,
three.
See,
he did not want that to happen to watch.
This
just gets up.
Fuck it.
I'm going home now.
That's interesting because you see this
from the eyes of professional.
I see this from the eyes of a layman in
the crowd and I don't see that.
That's fascinating.
You see a double cross double girls.
No doubt.
That's why you got the three count on
him.
You know he didn't look like that.
DaVid arquette sitting back knowing that
jake,
the snake is doing commentary on his
match.
I'll have david kidder day job.
Ah,
sister over a year.
Outrageous.
Listen.
Just needs practice.
Young buck.
I mean,
didn't.
Dallas didn't.
Dow started when he 36.
Imagine that and the crazy part is you
were one of his original mentors and the
guy that shit I'll fucking teach you
because eVerybody else said you're too
fucking old.
Specifically ric flair.
Ric flair told him,
dallas,
you've been a manager.
You do this.
Well you do that well,
but your third year six,
get a grip on.
You know you're too fucking oldest
start.
And when dallas told me that,
I'm like,
fuck it man.
If it's you're running your dream.
He says my fucking dream,
man.
I Want it.
Fuck it.
I'll teach you.
And that's When I started.
I moved in with him and then we had the
inFamous snake accident in his house.
What was the infamous naked?
I got busy with a girlfriend and forgot
what I was doing upstairs.
I was washing the snake off and went
back downstairs to check on her and she
caught me by surprise and raped me.
Horrible.
But it was great.
So I stayed and then I went,
oh my god,
I forgot to sneak upstairs.
So I ran back upstairs.
Realized you'd been doing a half hours
in dallas is just coming out of his
bedroom.
He's like,
what the fuck?
You been in the shower the whole time?
I'm like,
yeah man.
I just thought,
yeah,
I'm sweating.
You look at me.
I'm in the shower yet my mistake was in
there,
so I'll get my shit.
Get it right out.
He was widely the sharp dallas.
I was watching some soap out,
man.
Fuck.
Get a grip man.
Leave me alone.
So I go in and plugging bucket.
Snake.
I can't find the fucking snake.
Not in here.
Oh my god.
Which kind of snake was this a cobra?
Cobra.
They had three.
They had three cats.
Oh no,
that's what I thought too.
Oh no.
So I started looking for it.
Then I had to fess up to dallas.
What was going like doot,
doot,
doot.
You gotta find that Motherfucker.
My wife would be home in 20 minuteS.
I'm like,
what?
Holy shit.
You know,
I'll fight any mammoth fucking woman.
HAle.
no,
they will fuck you up.
I run from women.
They fuck you up with your sleep and
shit and fucking fuck you up again
because we have dick's.
We think,
you know,
they love me because of my dick or
whatever.
And you give them an end because they're
going to hear you so much and then you
fall asleep.
Actual murder action.
We're here we go.
I've been married three years.
Experience is very different than mine.
Well,
I've had three successful marriages.
Nobody died.
I did 13 years.
My first wife,
13 years,
and my second wife poor month third.
So I'm getting better a lot better.
But it sounds like you're talking about
prison.
I did 13 years about marriage.
I said 13 years.
That's like sam kinison and 80.
So it goes,
it goes back to my experience.
Right.
You know,
my experience is unfortunate because
one,
I've been through.
I left home and get this close to me.
We're about to get started getting real,
which is what I really want,
but then I got to push you back because
I can't handle it.
I want to get back to this,
but what happened to the cats?
Okay,
well,
long story short,
I couldn't find them this long as long
as I was there.
How much?
A.
Well,
right before she got home I thought I
would do the man thing and get my car
and run.
That's what I did.
That is what he did.
Fucking.
I had a slick fucking 84 corvette that I
knew would not look good with high heels
going up and down it.
Right?
Because that bitch,
wonderful lady.
She was a wonderful,
wonderful woman.
She was going to fuck you up.
She gonna fuck everybody up.
Right?
And if I'm not sleeping with you,
you're not going to talk shit like that
to me.
Right?
That's true.
I'll listen to it if I'm sleeping with
you.
But that was it.
I had to leave.
I came back two days later in my
defense,
two days later.
And when I got there,
I see all these workmen carrying sheets
of sheet rock,
sheet rock.
I'm like,
what the fuck?
And then donald's had told me they were
going to do some remodeling downstairs
and I'm like,
oh,
they're working on my fucking room.
Right?
It's so cool.
And he's like,
dude,
got 15 minutes.
Package should go what?
You got to get out
one little snake and I've got to go.
That's really bullshit.
Dallas.
And uh,
yeah,
they couldn't find the snake either.
So they wound up calling some people
professionals.
And the only way they found it was by
carrying out several walls and they
finally found it.
One of the walls.
What did he do?
Climate event and got in the bed
wherever,
I don't know.
And got into the wall and up.
Fuck.
And they had to follow it through the
house.
How did they find it?
By running out of walls?
They were quite upset.
I believe so,
yeah.
My kitchen worked on once and after they
sealed the drywall in the back,
I heard staycations cat.
So my cat spazz bad.
She's like,
shit.
I'm like,
she's in the fucking wall.
So I had to go get a hammer and a,
I had a club and the wall and then pull
her out.
Covered in fucking that's where they get
the music.
Boom,
ba boom,
ba boom.
Sweet cat.
Had that kevin.
Nineteen years.
Wow.
Here I am in Australia.
This is like 1993 or four.
And um,
there's a japanese superstar named 100
uses lighter,
I mean just top of the top brother.
So he's on tour with no problem.
But first night he's in was,
we'd already been there two nights and
these people come in,
these jobs come in and they start
plugging in the ag ag ag,
either in japanese.
So there's another guy and then english
transferred and boom,
boom.
Bottom line is he will not stay in the
same bucket.
And dresser was jake.
He's terrified as do the mongo get it on
him.
No does matter.
He doesn't even think you should be here
because of jake.
Okay,
fuck him.
Let him go where everyone I'm give you.
I told you I wouldn't get it on you if
my word is not good enough.
Fuck off.
So he goes and gets another dressing
room on the other side of these
coliseum,
on the colosseum in rome.
We across there,
he wrestles,
goes into shower,
comes out from the shower,
he's drying off.
He looks up in the mirror in the mirror.
He can see a pile of cobra is come up
out of the toilet.
It was looking around the room and the
rest of him still on the toilet.
and then he goes back down.
He screamed.
He runs across the fucking building
nude,
which got everybody's attention.
The police get involved.
It comes down to jake words,
your fucking snake.
I really can't find it.
So he had gotten out of my locker room
and went into the toilet and took off
and come up in that toilet over there.
She got on a fucking airplane that night
and went the fuck home.
Manages the snake that he was scared of
her did and then went and found the
place where there was the most feared.
Yeah.
I wonder if that.
I mean,
it only makes sense that you sent your
parents.
They would go after prey animals,
right?
Prayer.
My animals are terrified of them.
They probably have a sense of fear.
The fucking toilet you imagine that goes
to the toilet.
I mean,
I still have horror stories and bad
memories of sitting on a toilet and a
snake just by the balls and that that
happened to,
you know,
but I had those fucking dreams come to
me because I had those snakes all those
fucking years.
Especially after that no one can travel
that will again.
How'd you get the snake back?
I didn't.
I left him over there and fucking in
Australia.
Sorry.
Now he's taking over the country.
Jesus christ.
Where's that fucking snake?
It's in melbourne.
That's where I left him.
How long do those things live?
Like how long?
Thirty years or years.
So it's probably still alive and the
toilets savy of that auditorium was
looking around and eat nash.
Man.
Can you imagine some poor women sit down
on the toilet?
Oh,
that feels good.
Oh wait a minute.
That's not right.
What?
Wow.
He'll sneak up the astraea,
climbed in the fucking toilet and went
to the one guy that was terrified of
him.
Yeah.
unbelievable.
I remember when we did the andre andre
is supposed to be afraid of a snake.
Oh yeah.
And he faints and fakes or heart attack
and he's laying there.
Poor Bobby Eaton.
They're checking a panel on his chest
because he's supposed to act like he's
had a heart attack and somebody goes
give him mouth to mouth bobby and like,
are you fucking kidding me?
Fucking giant fucking giant breath you
had man from drinking.
I'd rather.
I love the giant the jasmine been when I
first got into wrestling referee in like
1974,
so,
and they came to me in this,
look,
you're not refereeing tomorrow night,
but we want you to drive andrea around
why?
So you were a referee before you were
progressing,
which is actually the best way to start
because you get a feel of it,
you get a feel of it,
you learn how to feel people and you
learn how to judge people.
You don't know how to read people in the
crowd.
You can read them.
But um,
I got the uh,
take care of andre thing.
They give me a van,
said andrea,
I'll sit in the back,
kind of a beanbag chair,
just taking him to the bill and he'll do
his thing.
Give him a ride back to the hotel.
Cool.
Seventy miles,
no problem.
Eighty miles,
whatever.
So we'll get through the show and he's
like,
beer.
Okay.
He talks,
he walks even,
you know.
So I stopped and getting beer.
I'm like a six pack my damn self there,
andre.
And he goes to cases.
It's an 85 mile trip.
Yeah,
two cases.
Fucking two cases.
I guess he wants some his room.
Right.
So we'll get back in and we start
driving.
I don't know about you guys man.
Back.
Even when I drank,
until I get into that first third or
fourth hour,
I gotta piss like every time I have a
beer on to piss.
I don't really buy beer.
I just rented or rented.
Then I go get rid of it.
But.
So after you know,
30 miles I pulled it andre.
Sorry I got pissed.
You know I'll get out of this.
Get back in the van.
You don't know another thing.
Mirror.
Okay.
Take it easy.
Fucking tired.
I heard the pop,
pop,
pop.
He fucking,
he fucking with me.
We go the closer I got to piss again.
Finally get there,
gets out of this.
I'll get your beer.
He goes to finished what you drink?
Forty eight beers.
Yeah.
Right.
Like off of your big goof.
You know he leaves.
I get,
I get in there.
First thing I do,
I'm checking with my hand.
Make sure I'm not putting my hand in
piss because I figured this motherfucker
got to piss.
He drank two cases of beer and do not
have to piss.
I don't care if you've got drained me,
but damn it.
how can you do that?
I mean,
I felt so inadequate.
This guy drinks 48 beers and didn't piss
48 beers and 80 miles.
Yeah,
that's nothing but his hand would cover
that beer up subbing.
Handsworth.
Just an amazing athlete.
An amazing man and to be in the ring
with him was he was unbelieved when hulk
hogan hoisted him up in the air,
in that photo of him with a regular
sized can of beer.
That is insane.
Doesn't even look real.
That look real.
That's a 12 ounce.
YeAh.
Yeah.
That's a 12 ounce beer and it just
vanishes inside his head.
See if he can find that video of when
hulk hogan picks him up over his head
that that was fucking insane.
How much did he weigh?
Five 5,500.
Fifty pounds now.
Five hundred 50 pounds.
Just hoisting over your head with a bar
with an olympic bar is impressive,
but to do it with dead weight,
with a man
thing about it is it wouldn't happen.
Liz,
andrea,
warren,
g two,
right.
Of course,
because he's going to boost himself
course.
I remember him being a ring one night
and he says,
yeah,
you fucking insane.
Like,
look at this.
This is insane.
But if you look,
we're andre and jar.
Yeah,
she helps it.
He helps him pulling stale.
He had me pick him up and slammed him
one night and he's like,
[inaudible].
I'm like,
no,
fucking whether you know.
Yes sir.
And I went under and I all of a sudden
he's here and I'm like,
holy fuck.
I've got him still.
He would use that athletic energy for
that and my legs just started to fucking
buckle.
Yeah,
you gotta drop them fast.
Three hundred pounds.
There is a biggie.
Look,
I'll leave,
but hogan was flocking jazz,
you know,
I met him later in life,
but I had met him earlier too.
I ran into him on the street once and I
couldn't believe how fucking big he was.
The second time I saw him he was shorter
because he had so many back surgeries
that has disks,
had been fused and he's still at giant
human being,
but he wasn't as big of six,
eight,
no more hybrid.
Craper told me when I was friends with
piper,
he told me that when hogan did that slam
on andre,
just like he could feel it just going
all the way up.
Is that true?
I can only imagine.
I clothesline audrey
when I,
you know,
I came in and doing hard because andre
warner did hit him hard.
Right.
Which I used to say that's the most
frustrating thing in the world right
there in her watch that you're trying to
kill a motherfucker and you don't even
know it.
So your name is hard as I could and he
didn't know.
So when you reach out and just.
I mean he used to hit me and I'd be
falling.
Right.
That's a lot of energy.
Me falling.
He reached up and grabbed me by my hair
and just zinc pulled me right my fucking
feet and just ripped a fucking see look
here.
Look at that look way to 60 there.
Wow.
That's so crazy.
Look how fucking big he was.
He was so good.
You did a horrible thing to be one night
in the room and he knocked me down.
I'm on my back and he stands on my hair,
enriched on,
grabbed my arms and pulled.
Just rip my hair out.
Wow.
Did you guys plan shit out like that or
did he just improvise that out there?
We went out there and played.
He liked me.
I liked him a unreal test.
you say if you don't man up to him,
he'll fucking eat you.
Oh,
could you get to see the documentary
that they made on him?
On hbo
savage now andre?
Yeah.
No,
no,
no.
I didn't see it.
It's really great.
You'd really love it.
I don't want to hurt too much.
Yeah,
it made me.
It made me cry.
So yeah,
it makes me cry.
You know what that man went through?
What did he go through?
Which just people pointing and laughing
in pain can.
Constantine was unbelievable.
Yeah.
Because of wrestling.
No,
because because of the growth,
just january growing,
continuing to grow,
you know,
it's.
Think about a water daily days.
Well,
a bed don't fit too well.
Right?
Let's talk about hotels and bathrooms.
Where's he going to go?
Right.
Where does he sit in the bathtub?
No,
that's the only place you could yet.
We're still going to take his ass,
didn't they?
He's got to squish it and they just got
it.
No,
he just fucking turned the shower on
man.
Let it dissolve it.
How'd you,
how would you like to do hot yoga and
that bathroom with that shower.
Praying god damn shit in the bath tub.
Airplanes.
Cars.
Well,
you know,
giant helmet.
So did he have his house set up for him?
yeah.
wow.
It's another thing we're paper told me a
great story about,
you know how everybody would always.
He would just get so harassed out in
puBlic and they were out drinking one
night after shows and they were in on in
some college town,
like we'll say madison,
Wisconsin or something like that and
they're having some drinks at a bar and
piper was like,
these kids,
these frat boys,
you know,
they noticed that a few tables away and
someone there,
an empty beer can hits andre in the back
of the head and hits the ground.
You know,
andre looks around,
oh,
and they're hanging out.
A couple mInutes later,
another empty beer can hits.
Andre growls a little bit harder and
then a third beer can comes.
And andre stands.
He had hits him in his head.
Andre stands up,
you know,
it takes them awhile to get out of the
booth or whatever.
Wherever they're at.
Any nice guys get up and they start
running and they chase andre chases
them,
but when he gets out of the bar,
they are in their car about to pull
away.
And andre literallY goes under the car
that's out front of the Bar and flips it
over.
there's a cop,
a half a block away who pulls up and
arrest them for fucking with andre the
giant.
He flips their car with them.
Those guYs mess with me.
I two beer cans.
We were wrestling in montreal.
It was his birthday picture.
He could do a backflip,
standing on the top rope and do a flip
where you land on his feet when he first
started.
But uh,
I'm wreStling him and then we had this
little thing we'd do where you get me in
the corner and then he just still let
wade into me,
you know,
which was pretty easy to,
to register.
And then I would slide down and then
he'd grab each side of the rope under
the last drop.
Of course he's got these ropes all that
night he wanted to do it and then hand
slipped who saw all of a sudden his ass
plans right here.
And just,
you know,
I heard fucking vertebrates and I'm
like,
can I breathe?
I just want to know if I give a brief
because I couldn't.
At the moment I was like screaming and I
turned over on my side.
we got,
how bad is it because I figured I'd
figure my sternum was broke,
whatever,
and he sits on me and I'm laying there.
I'm Trying to get some a breath,
trying to let everything come back and
I'd seen the lights coming in.
At first I was going to pass out and
then I hear andre laughing when I hear
the referee saying,
andre,
why are you laughing as hard?
And I'm like,
what?
And I could feel my shoulders is
vibrating like,
and he's 13,
you know,
on the giant can fart.
How long?
About 40 seconds.
He's like,
but it was a steady flow.
It wouldn't mean he got up.
I had like a wiNe stain on my shoulder.
That amazing,
amazing guy,
man.
But I used to think to myself,
the fans really don't like me because
they're putting me out there in the
fender,
cheered me on to charge into that
fucking big giant you want me to get
killed on show fans or fishes?
What are Y'all doing this to me?
Don't cheer me.
Tell me I'm a stupid fucker.
and to get out of the ring for the giant
each.
You know,
fun and that was that hard to always be
a great bad guy or did you sort of
relish in that?
Being a good guy is so boring because
people expect you to be nice.
They expect you to this picture with the
baby,
but as a bad guy you can do anything and
it's okay.
You know what I mean?
And then you get to see how far you can
take people.
You know what I mean?
Some people freak is kind of bugs.
People freaks them out a little bit to
thinking about starting a riot,
but that's when you know you'Ve done
your job right?
When you can get people to step out of
their comfort zone and come into the
ring after you.
Now you'Ve done the job.
Did you have that happen?
How many times?
I'll probably 30,
40 times.
Thirty,
People charge the ring.
Well,
it got bad.
It got bad couple of times.
One time was the worst one.
Being in dallas,
Texas,
which is like 60 miles from my hometown.
What started it?
Uh,
with wrestling sting.
The guy stood up about nine rows back,
reached inside of his jacket,
pulled out a nine millimeter and got
three shots off before they got him.
Oh,
I'd already dived underneath the ring.
Staying being the stupid.
Yeah.
He's in the ring.
You staying?
I'm not coming back,
bitch.
You know this guy got three shells off
me.
I remember going into the back thinking
to myself,
you fucking got them out there.
You take them that far.
You're making people do shit they would
not normally do because they got him.
But here's what they brought into the
bag.
and you're like,
you wanna to press charges.
Press charges.
No,
just reload the motherfucker.
put it back out there.
What the fuck do you think?
Press jar.
Of course.
I want to press charges,
man.
He put three holes in the building of
the old fucking atory in there and
dallas.
He shooting or was he just shooting at
the ceiling at me?
Yeah,
related my ass.
I had a woman 75 years old.
Cut me with a box cutter.
What's?
Yeah,
and the first time she'd ever been to
watch wrestling.
What?
What did you do to start that?
She had been at home with her grandkids
and they were watching me wrestle and
they were like,
oh granny,
they'll get so and so.
Jake roberts,
he's,
oh,
he's so bad.
He is.
Somebody needs to wash his damn mouth.
Alice open spank his ass.
What that man needs.
You know,
somebody should have straightened him
out earlier in his life and they're
like,
oh great.
He shut up.
You wouldn't have done anything.
He'd run from him too.
I would not run from that man.
And they basically challenged the
grandmother not knowing it.
She's a little off.
Next time I come to town,
she gets fucking ticket.
She's going to show those grandkids.
She's not afraid of me.
Wow.
Jesus christ.
I came down the aisle.
I got security around me and all of a
sudden my securities.
ThIs is fucking great.
Turn to see what they're doing.
There's a woman that's down and they're
all over and thinking,
well,
she have a fucking heart attack,
man.
What's going on?
Hey guys,
what's going jake?
She fucking cut you man.
I'm like,
oh,
you're full of shit.
Look at your arm.
Holy shit.
The fucking chicken.
How bad did she cut?
You know,
30 stitches.
Jesus christ box.
You just didn't realize that you don't
feel the box cutter.
You're sharp.
So I get to the back with her.
He said,
I hear the story.
You know what actually happened?
And I just looked at it and said,
can I hug you?
You want to hug me?
I'm like,
yeah,
I do.
Yeah,
Come here.
And I hugged her.
I started crying.
She started crying and jesus goes up the
wife number two or three.
That's why it only lasted for a month.
She ran out of blades.
Go.
What the fuck,
man?
You're a better man than me.
What you did kick her though was a good,
solid,
nice,
gentle to jesus.
all your teeth.
Uh,
yeah.
Yeah.
Well,
I'm going to root canals one.
Really?
Yeah.
How long did you fight?
Not that long.
I wore a mouthpiece.
Fifteen minutes.
Twenty minutes.
While I move a lot.
There's a big difference in amount of
punishment that you would take progress.
Punish me.
Take sparring or fighting
16 slash 17.
Root canals.
Jesus christ,
man you,
and as you get older,
the teeth deteriorate and those root
canals,
that tooth just winds up turning into
dust and they start breaking off and
pieces and stuff.
And man,
it probably didn't help in my spiral
down either,
man that I couldn't go eat,
you know,
I had to be checked and see what I was
going to eat and make sure I just put
new poly grip in and you start eating a
steak with polygraph and then boom,
it breaks loose and next thing you know,
your fucking mouth bleeding because it
broke loose.
And ryan,
you havIng to go to the bathroom,
you know,
makes it a date.
So nice.
You know,
there's nothing that says love chewing
on your girlfriends and your teeth fall
out on our belly button,
you know,
it just turns them away.
That sucks,
man.
You know.
And did you.
You never warm out.
No,
you can't do the wrestling.
You swallowed it.
That's the difference.
But,
you know,
I,
I got real fortunate that,
uh,
some people out of dallas,
they got one in vegas,
also g for it's called,
uh,
they,
should look at,
we see you're having a problem.
We see you doing,
you're talking.
And I talked like this because I didn't
want,
right?
Because my teeth were constantly coming
loose and it didn't matter how many
times I got new ones,
but they still sucked.
So these people g form and they finally
came to resident's room real.
I'm like,
yeah,
right.
So he told me implants.
Well I didn't know a lot about that
shit,
you know.
And uh,
they uh,
come back to me and they said new to
dallas and I'm dr goldberg who was
saying his name and the blue 11 implants
in.
And uh,
it was pretty bad,
man.
I had a bad day.
It's hard tO medicate me and put me out
because I,
rachel's level's too high.
So during while I was out and they were
pulling teeth,
getting ready to put the things into
screw into.
Evidently during all that process,
I just stood up and started pissing on
the doctor
personally,
everybody in the room and chasing them
and complete fucking idiot.
Was tHis why you were so busy?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I sobered up,
but see they had gave me so much shit to
put me out that I keep moving this
bullshit going.
Hey,
fuck you.
And I'm fucking get me digging.
But this is.
I'm saying this is like during your
sobriety here.
Yes.
So this is recently a year and a half
ago.
Jesus christ,
they did this for my teeth,
man,
being locked in a small room with jake.
The snake,
he pulls his dick out,
starts pissing out.
And you think you got to medicaid,
got bars in his teeth.
He tried to give him some safety.
What was even nicer was the next day,
they didn't even hold it against me.
I know I woke up the next morning,
I don't remember them taking me to the
hotel and put me in bed or any of that
and I didn't know what the vaseline on
my ass was for.
But anyway,
I'm just kidding.
But I woke up the next morning,
I'm like,
who's fucking closure these?
Because they basically undressed me
there and get the piss all off of me and
put new clothes on me.
I'm like,
what the fuck's going on?
Did they have to buy clothes for you or
the reserves that got somebody out there
at the place in the.
They dressed me and I came back the next
morning.
Um,
I haven't been there for five hours a
day before they sent me down and said
this won't take.
But about 15 minutes over a year.
Right.
And they come in and here's your new
teeth.
Put them up and screw them in.
Man,
I could bite a bumper on the car.
No shit is so unbelievable.
If anybody out there to have an issue
with her teeth,
man,
get them fixed,
but you know,
fix the right way.
Don't fuck around with getting partial
plates and all that bullshit.
Go ahead and bite the bullet.
It's expensive.
It no doubt it's expensive to change my
whole life.
That is the guy that did my hair,
you know what I mean by lobbying?
I wanted there because jake,
the snake has hair.
Well,
jake,
the snake at the end of the line didn't
have no fucking hair.
It was all gone.
And uh,
some people in atlanta where I was
living,
paramount,
plastic surgery and stuff.
They said,
look,
we'll give you a head of hair,
man.
you know why we're jake the snake,
man,
we love you.
And that's like 30 slash 40 grand,
man.
I know you love me,
but you're going to do that.
Really?
and that's one of the things in the
movie.
You know why the people come up with
money for my shoulder?
Oh my god,
I cry so hard at that part of that movie
when they,
when you guys are expecting,
what knows,
it's 17,000
in the 24 hour span,
which more than paid for my,
almost had enough to get a tip job,
which I was going to happen,
put on my back that way you'd have
something to play with it.
You have to get down to your shoulders.
a labor room tear.
No,
it was a tutor,
coach person,
bone spurs,
bone spurs.
And one of the spurs was over two inches
long.
And here's the great news.
I think I've got it back.
You got to spur back.
I can move my arm and I can feel that
fucking thing in there.
Go across a muscle.
It's like,
are you fucking kidding me?
But you sure?
Yeah.
Did you get an mri?
Not yet,
but I tended worn off.
But what I'm getting at here,
and he's like the number of people that
reached out to me,
condensed shit from me that didn't have.
People didn't even know.
It just blows me away.
Well,
just
think about how many people you touched
over your entire career and how many
people ran away from home.
Yeah,
macho man got bit
and it's crazy because back then
everybody's like,
this is the scariest guy.
We hate this guy,
bu this guy.
and then it's like years later they
realize,
whoa,
that guy moved me.
Like,
it's like originally everybody was
afraid of you or hated you.
But it's like,
it's all in retrospect when they
realized,
holy shit,
this guy,
I can help him.
This guy,
man,
he earned it from me.
He deserves this guy changed my life,
blah,
blah.
Scene in the movie when it's unexpected
and the guys are in the ring and they
play the music and you start walking
around with a bag snake in it.
Yeah.
That's pretty Incredible.
It was after all the shit that you had
been through
with sobriety,
all the shit that I stirred up while I
was drunk.
Yeah.
You know,
because I mean,
it amazes me how many people have
forgiven me for the things that I said
or did when I was under the influence.
Man goes,
let me tell you something.
There is nothing more viral than a drunk
addicted,
hating motherfucker feel like I was and
I wouldn't have.
I had,
did not mind going after venture.
Anybody else?
You know,
I hated life.
So I wanted her to say I don't give a
fuck if you hate me.
You know,
guess what?
I hate me more than you could aid me.
Loser.
You are going to make me much.
You know?
That's what amazed me.
People helping me.
It's like all those years that I used to
cringe when somebody would say,
hey,
would you,
oh my baby.
I'm like,
hold your baby.
You don't know what the fuck I am.
Don't make me do that because it would
hurt me inside to pull that kid in and
smile and lie.
I'm not a good liar when it comes like
that.
A guy like vince wanted me to do a
commercial one time a just say no
campaign.
that's hilarious.
Let me fucking do this.
you know funny bins,
right?
Right.
Because I know what it's like not to be
able to say no,
they're no worse feeling in the world.
Man.
Here you got something on his hand
that's going to kill you are you got
live over here and there's green
pastures and all this happy,
happy,
and you're going to have a good
relationship with a woman if you're just
going to take the poisonous tree.
You know what's ironic is that your
movie,
your film,
your story and who you are right now is
one of the best.
Just say no commercIals they could ever
do that may be for real,
because you can't just say no,
no,
no ridiculous bullshit ever said.
Yeah,
and when you show that in the film that
you want to say
no,
I mean this is one of the more powerful
things about that film is not just that
you succeeded but that you tried and
failed several times until you succeeded
and you detailed all of it,
all the warts and all,
every single step of the way.
it's a very brave movie,
man.
It really is shit out.
No,
no you didn't.
That was tough.
but now I'm getting to do the right
thing and for me I'm doing this comedy
thing and it's not really comedy.
I just go out until road stories and
shIt.
You know,
I could have the storage module,
I just told you much.
I do the same stuff in buildings,
but I've wrestled for 36 years,
so I've got about 10 shows to do and I'm
still on the first one going around with
it and I've been doing it for two and a
half years now,
but now I'm enjoying it so much.
Not because I'm making people laugh
because I'm getting connected.
I'm getting to connect with people that
are needing help.
People come to the show and tell them,
hey,
give me the icky man.
Afterwards we'll go find a place and
talk in some of the stories I have met.
Make my story sound like a fucking walk
in the park,
man.
I mean some of the horror stories I've
heard where people are going through and
suffering through and their story.
They're paying their anger,
you know,
pay my shit,
looks weak compared to what these pigs
and I'm getting to hear this and I'm
getting to help them find the way.
And then I get to hear the stories of
the success stories.
Hey man,
I didn't start getting cleaned out her
about you starting to get clean.
And I started to try and,
hey,
guess what jake?
I got two years in now.
I got four years in that.
Those are great.
But the best is the letter from the six
year old says you helped my daddy.
My daddy loves you and I love you too.
Because my dad,
he lives with me now.
Wow.
Oh fuck me man.
You know,
wow,
you can't buy that shit.
Can't buy that.
So I get what dallas does.
You know,
when he helps people,
he gets a high off of him.
God bleSs him.
He should get high off of it because he
spends a lot of time doing bro.
a lot of time.
That's the one thing I always thought
about dallas.
He may not be the smartest guy in the
room,
but he's smart enough to know that and
he'll go find that right answer.
You know,
whatever he was dealing with.
Me and scott,
he didn't know how to be an addict or
what that was about.
So what'd you do?
He contacted all of his buddies or his
ex buddies that had been through it and
he went and he read and he read any self
taught man.
He used to have a problem reading.
We've got it down now.
So here's a guy that overprepared for
everything.
Yeah.
As far as I'm concerned,
but well,
that's also why you started ddp yoga to
figure out a way to heal his body
itself.
Yeah.
Now he shared.
Not just sharing it,
but promoting it
worldwide if you ever done it.
No,
I haven't.
Well,
I mean I did do a little bit of it years
ago.
I looked up the.
I found a little bit of it on youtube.
I never got the actual program
to the program.
You can make it as easy as you want or
you can make it as difficult as you want
and that's the beauty of it because you
could get somebody like nimble nuts over
here with a sprain,
sprain,
angina.
Ah,
diners warped out of shape.
He can't help himself.
God,
it's like the snake when it tries to
find the japanese,
he just likes playing with round things.
You'll there,
doesn't he?
The knobs you.
He's stroking the knobs.
Unbelievable.
Cool things about ddp yoga is the,
you know,
you see all those before and after of
the physical transitions of people.
But with those pictures don't show is
the mental presence that you get.
I mean I was,
I was in chicago doing gigs a few years
ago and this was after I got to see your
movie when it first premiered,
I actually think it was david arquette
that got me and my.
Because we made friends at the comedy
store years ago.
He got me and my buddies in on a.
You guys had your premier on sunset
boulevard at that.
I'll take your word for it anyway.
And so I had already seen the movie,
but scott was the net that and I don't
believe you were there either and make
the big ones.
Yeah.
And so I was in chicago doing a gig and
it's one of those morning radio shows
that I didn't want to have to do that
friday morning,
6:00
AM pickup or whatever.
I just flown in and I almost,
I remember I almost called in sick to
that radio show because I'm like,
I'm doing,
you know,
I don't want to.
I am just tired.
I don't want to do it slow getting
there.
Yeah,
sure.
The back of his spirit flight.
But I ended up not calling in sick.
I'm like,
let's just do and make coffee and the
hotel and get the fucking car because
that's what you do.
Right.
Exactly.
And as soon as I get there to like,
man,
cow in the morning,
right.
They're like,
you'll never believe who else is in
studio with a.
You're a wrestling fan,
right?
I'm like,
yeah,
they're like,
Scott Hall is also going to be here with
you.
I'm like,
you gotta be fucking kidding me.
And I remember,
oh,
brushed your teeth.
And I remember,
you know,
I remember hoping because I just seen
that movie.
I'm like,
oh man,
I hope that,
you know,
I hope he's still in good shape and
everything.
I hope everything's cool because I know
how hard it is to stay clean as an attic
and and my god,
if he wasn't just and,
and you know,
you as well here today,
it's like,
it just completely present.
Not.
You can't even tell.
You've probably had 20,000
concussions in your life,
you know,
I mean just,
they're looking around laughing,
smiling.
My mind was blown that he was as
present,
if not more than a lot of the other
available older,
most let more progress.
Slurs that I had met,
you know what I mean?
And that I had met,
he was in it.
He was being funny.
He's reacting towards june.
Yeah.
It was an on the job compared to the guy
that gets scooted in on that wheelchair
that can't walk.
And when he's first starting with the
chairs,
you can hear his bones cracking.
Oh yeah.
When you heard his hip.
Oh,
it's a wonderful man.
And it was just
to replace it in the first one sucked.
The second one man,
they went through the front.
That's the way to go.
I went in at 7:00
AM at noon.
I jerked covers back until my daughter,
me,
my pants,
or I'm walking out naked,
put my fucking pants on,
put my feet down and walked straight
out.
No cane,
no nothing.
Really.
In five hours you can do that.
Not supposed to.
The doctor was yelling at me as we were
leaving the building.
What was he saying?
You get back the fucking blow the whole
thing probably,
but I use walking in a crosswalk to
connect the two buildings and I had
already went up to the bottom and I was
going to the car and he's beaten on the
fucking window.
Light was like a full hip replacement.
Severed the top of the femur and they
put a new joint.
They screw it.
You ever seen how they do it?
Oh,
it was marlboro.
Drive it in.
There is a god damn huge bolt that goes
in the center of your bone and it goes
right through the bone and screws in
place and then you have this new joint.
The first one I had was brutal because
the whole joining calcified,
it took him three and a half hours to
get it out.
Oh god.
And they said they finally went to like
bring in the big hammer,
you know,
they went from these shiny silver hammer
to get clogged fucking sledge out from
the truck and bring it on.
And you know how a cauliflower ear your
starts,
right?
Yeah.
You know what it is yet?
The breaking cartilage.
Yeah.
Blood blood,
blood,
blood calcifies.
So blood becomes really turns into a
rock.
You get that in your nose and he's
getting.
He had that in his joint,
so he basically had rocks in his joint,
completely calcified.
That's fucking arm wrestled for three or
four years like that.
I'll show you guys and we can come back
and talk about it.
What I would do is couldn't do anything
with this yet.
No one can hear you,
unfortunately when you do this.
And then I would sleep and grabbed the.
Yeah,
yeah.
I was bending the femur.
The femur was born.
So you,
you are putting so much torque in that
you were blowing your hip out of socket.
So your left hook and rotate out of
socket.
But it would been the femur bone.
Fuck that.
I did it for the doctor and he was like,
oh my god.
Because when I first witnessed seeing
the dogs,
like how'd you get it?
And I saw when I drove.
He goes,
no,
how'd you get to the room?
I'm like,
oh,
what is impossible?
I've seen your expert.
There's no way you can walk the fuck I
can't.
And I showed him.
He was like,
oh my god.
He runs out of the room of my.
Okay.
I know I got
cancer.
I'm dying.
That's the difference between a regular
person that when a guy like you,
like your tolerance for paints probably
through the fucking roof,
he probably just so accustomed to it.
Recognize it.
yeah.
Well obviously with your Arm broken when
you wanted to keep wrestling,
don't you don't recognize pain because
it's just somethings you do.
You know.
There were times in my career where
people are like,
stop,
like it's okay.
I'm all right.
Well it's a lie because you are not
right.
It's just adrenaline flowing so much and
you're so jacked on that shit.
You know?
That's the real drug and adrenaline.
Alright,
with that,
jamie will show you how to do it,
but your back in this,
I think the tension from this spring
trap,
you're will save your life,
man.
Now when you do in these traveling
shows,
you doing them in comedy clubs,
what are you doing?
How many clubs,
bars,
hotel,
convention room,
whatever.
That's got to be great for you too
because at the beginning of the film,
one of the things that was evident was
that you missed,
you missed the whole excitement of
performing.
It was.
It was missing from your life,
so now you've got that back,
but also healthy,
healthy,
positive,
and then also helping people.
Absolutely.
Man,
it's such a joy to help people,
but it's.
You know,
when I first went back,
man,
because I abused myself so much,
my memory was shot.
I couldn't remember shit man.
And then as I tell one story,
a little glimmer will happen over here
and then then I'll talk to somebody in
the crowd and they'll mention,
I'm like,
I didn't wrestle that guy.
The hail you didn't tell and I don't
remember wrestling this guy doing this
with that one and they make me remember
stuff.
Like I said,
now I've got like 10 shows waiting and
at first I had to really struggle to get
one show together.
Did you write them all out?
I did in the beginning.
Now I just write bullet points and I can
pull them back up,
which was so nice to do,
you know,
because I was an appointment with my
speech.
Wouldn't finish sentences.
And then just,
you know.
No.
So in the film you did it with mick
foley.
Are you doing them with mick on the
road?
No,
no,
no.
I'm doing good ones now.
Great.
Never seen my show now.
Can just shut up and getting a car.
Got to turn the mic.
I opened up for a few years ago now.
Reframing your god damn Sure.
Never closed for me.
You're a wrestler.
I'd say maybe I can get you into tv.
Squash match,
kid squash.
Match.
When you just go in and pummeled with
god for three minutes and squashing,
lay them out on the floor.
He doesn't even get to breathe,
you know,
so that was like you're telling another
wrestler,
hey,
I'll see if we can't get you into squash
match every.
It's like saying you know,
you're a piece of shit.
I'm just going to use you and toss you
over in the corner when it's done.
Was that like a rite of passage?
do you have to do squash
matches?
A lot of guys don't know.
We did back in my day though.
He started at the bottom and you work
your way up now you've got guys who go
to school for three months.
Yeah.
They never learned their art.
Well,
when you go into school to learn
wrestling,
and this is not something that existed,
it didn't exist.
Is it kinda like school for standup?
Exactly.
Yeah.
I think it's exactly like that.
Like there's,
there's classes that I teach is stand up
and the good thing about it is you get
at least you start doing it like whether
or not they're actually teaching
anything is very debatable.
And the things that they are teaching is
all in ring technique and torches and
the crumbs are right.
And the thing that you know,
us die hard wrestling fans now miss with
the product is exactly what you
specialized in,
which is psychology cutting promos.
I mean he wants to cut a promo.
I remember against hulk hogan where you
said something like if you plant grass,
grass will grow.
If you plant rice,
rice will grow.
And if you plant fear in your opponent's
head,
ah,
I remember,
I'll tell you the best interview I ever
did back in the day,
we'd have to do 70 or 80 interviews back
to back.
And the tv guys,
tv guys used to fight for getting me
because they knew it was going to be
fucking cakewalk.
Some guys,
you know,
like The ultimate warrior,
those guys take 26.
Go ahead and they'd sit there like
pulling teeth.
But for me,
my nickname is one take.
Jake.
Yeah.
So give me something.
They throw a word out there,
not just do the whole fucking interview
out that word.
Just fucking around.
So I'm there one day,
I'm like,
oh,
I got one guy that got one.
Okay jake,
what are you gonna do?
Just so and,
and I went in there like,
we're not getting any sound here.
I'm like,
motherfucker,
do I tell you just to roll it?
Just rolling.
So I do it again,
making no sound for like 30 seconds and
then only.
Oh,
tell the little boys next to you that
you're not scared of jake.
Why don't I just made you get up and fix
the television?
That wasn't broken.
Didn't you come to the tv like I said to
you,
did you couldn't fix it.
Tell your wife I said hello.
Wow.
Chilled interview shells from head to
toe.
You're sick.
Fuck.
Also the,
the life that you were living,
you could probably pull those dark
thoughts out like other people probably
can't sit in a bar man
and a right shift and the next day I'd
pick it up.
Oh my god,
what the fuck was I,
you know,
it just horrify me.
But yeah,
sometimes you can pull the dark out of
bad moments in life when you had
experiences.
I mean,
I mean just trying to kill yourself with
pills or whatever the fuck you were
doing.
The darkness that you had in your life,
like my sister being murdered and shit
and my mother,
my mother was a 12 year old girl and her
mother was dating my father.
Her mother was my grandmother passed.
My father left that and went into a 12
year old who girls room and raped her.
That's me.
That's how I got started and then later
in life my father was raping.
My sister did not know it and he raped
another daughter.
Did not know it.
Always heard whispering.
So people whispering in,
even in the,
I don't know what the books are,
problem.
Not getting the ring with somebody that
had that knew my dad and they beat the
fucking shit out of me because they
hated him because I'd seen some of the
shit that he did.
You want to believe that of your own
father?
You don't want to believe that because
you don't want to believe that dude.
I was the girl that you met earlier.
Cody.
She is the first daughter of mine that I
held in my lap.
She was 22,
22 before I would ever pick up.
One of my daughters said my in my lap
because I was afraid of,
turned into my father.
Never wanted that.
I never to be someone that abused a
child because I didn't abuse.
I knew what that shit was like.
I knew what it did to my fucking head,
getting right and getting sober warning
to talk about it helps a lot.
It makes it better.
You don't cure it,
you know you never get over it,
but I can deal with it now.
I don't have to go medicate.
It went.
Now,
when you talk to these people that
you're also helping your medium that
also have these problems,
how many of them have also been abused?
A lot.
You know what it's like to be sitting at
a comicon and a look out there and
there's people in your line and your eye
contact.
Contact your kid.
He looked at the kid and they look at
you and you're like,
for motherfucker,
you're going through it too,
aren't you?
And I can tell it.
I know that putting kids,
being sexually abused,
he can see it and I hate that feeling
because then they get up to the front
and you're like trying to talk to them
and they're like,
shut down completely,
and then the fucking asshole is next to
them is probably doing the bullshit.
He's wanting.
My contention,
man.
What chance did I have him getting good
attention?
Not much.
I keep going back to the kid.
How can you tell you?
Just feel it.
You know,
it,
smell it,
taste it.
If you see the fear,
you know,
and you see the way that the dad
communicates with them and you see their
reaction,
they won't look at you with their eyes,
you know,
really hard to get them look at me in
the eyes,
really is.
No,
I remember I told somebody one time that
probably the one thing that helped me in
my early life about going through all
that sexual abuse in bullshit was I
learned that a lot at a very young age
reason.
I learned that a lot because it helped
me get me to a safe place.
You know?
Uh,
I learned to judge people and their
attitudes,
you know,
I knew what buttons to push and what
buttons not to push with my stepmother
and I knew what was a safe place and if
there were key words that come out from
her,
I knew to fucking go hide.
I had to start reading this shit and I
had to start coming up with storylines
and stuff to get me out of shit so I
wouldn't be put into the position to get
gotten again.
When you're learning that shit at 12 and
13,
brother,
you're getting some fucking knowledge,
but it's a motherfucker man,
you know,
just to have to go through it.
And uh,
I don't know,
brother,
there was ever a reason to,
uh,
bring back the big one gas or bullets or
whatever.
Hang,
I think paint perfect for anybody that
abused kids.
My,
a public fucking fuck.
Five years in jail.
Fuck you mother fucker.
Put you dancing on the end of a rope
that get people's attention.
Might stop some of it.
Yeah.
I don't know how to stick with what
would they do that would stop it
completely,
but it's.
It's one of the most disturbing
characteristics of people that that,
that that's even possible.
Nobody wants to talk.
Nobody wants to talk about the damn
shirt because here's what happens to the
kid.
No,
nine times out of 10,
they raised their hand and they say
something.
Then this group comes in,
this group comes in,
cops come in and they say,
this ashes that lays probably just
exaggerating this,
that this age,
you have to go home with them.
Whoa,
fuck no.
You can't put that kid back in that
house.
Right?
What jesse have now.
Or you end up in an orphanage where
you're eating right again.
Yeah.
Who does?
Share at an orphanage and more than a
predator.
And that's the other problem is a lot of
kids,
they get abused like that.
Wind up abusing other kids.
Absolutely.
Even what you're taught.
Yeah.
Sandusky at that whole charity for kids
have this whole like thing,
nut map.
Yeah.
I'm going to open up the abused
children's home.
That way I know where to go get one
knew that the kids were damaged and they
would be used to it.
Oh,
you know what we,
what we call love.
It can be an ugly thing.
You know?
Sometimes your kid looks to get his ass
kicked because that's the only type of
loving knows that's true.
You're a powerful man to have gone
through all this and to be able to
express it so honestly to to everybody.
I mean that,
that.
That is an amazing thing because the
pain of your experiences has not stopped
you from expressing all of the,
all the downsides of it,
but also that you've come out of it on
the other end in a Very positive way.
I mean,
you're a great guy to be around your
funniest shit.
You,
you have amazing stories and you're
clean.
Now.
I'm funny in a room like this,
but there's not any competition come
along,
joe.
Just me.
Fuck.
Where do you go from here?
You know lapdog 27.
No,
tHat's amazing.
It really is.
I just want to help somebody else feel
what I felt.
Yeah,
because I don't want them to have to do
the things that I did to quit feeling
because I'll tell you,
it's a whole lot easier to pick up
cocaine and forget about it than it is
to go through counseling.
Go through this,
go through live hip 25 fucking times.
She know you go into counseling and they
say,
okay,
tell us exactly how it happened.
Do I really fucking want to do that?
What do you want me to do that?
So you can use it over there and Jack,
what?
What's your not on this because that's
what we're thinking,
right?
What do you want me to remember it?
I want to fuck fucking forget it.
Forget it.
Right.
Tell me how to remember it.
I got it down.
What was ultimately what was ultimately
the thing that allowed you to stay clean
when you had faltered five or six times,
whatever it was,
what was ultimately the thing that
allowed you to get past all this and
just to embrace sobriety and being
healthy?
I think it was just
realizing that I wasn't going to fail
this time and that came from dallas.
Not giving up on me.
See,
I was scared that he was going to give
up on me.
so it's almost like you were failing so
that he would give up on so I can get
that over with.
I know it's going to hurt,
but god damn it.
I can't deal with this thought of how
much it's going to hurt.
I'd rather it hurt right now and you
kicked me out and then I can go over
here and get something that'll make me
forget about this bullshit.
So it's always hanging over your head
that you're going to fuck up.
And finally,
when I realized,
no matter how many times I've looked up
to so much going to be there and uh,
again,
man,
three years,
I don't want to live with me for three
years.
My shoe dude,
I texted him.
Well,
I texted him as he's a saint after I
watched that documentary.
I'm like,
dude,
you're a saint.
He just wants to help people man.
And,
and you know I'm not going to sit here
and hard sale is product man,
but ddb ogilvy's singly the best fucking
thing you can do for your body and your
mind.
He's going to have you eat good food
diet.
There ain't no fucking diet.
Oh,
we asked you to do is not eat certain
shit.
This,
by the way,
shit,
he's just asking you to step off of
gluten.
Is that bob dairy?
Okay.
What'S the problem with that?
Cheese?
Okay.
You want cheese?
You can have cheese,
you can have sheep,
cheese and goat cheese.
Clinton.
Oh fuck you up.
Like couch.
He's tough.
Well,
if you look at how healthy the guy is in
his sixties and how flexible he is and
how,
how mobiley is and we want to judge like
him,
his back is fucked up,
but he could do everything and it's just
because his muscles are so strong all
around his back is completely supported.
Lists the old story of you,
if you.
If you don't use it,
you lose it,
right?
Yeah.
I'm listening from listening to him on
your podcast.
He talks about how he doesn't extreme 10
minute stretching to start his day and
I've really,
really put that inaction.
It's still stuck with some stuff from
animals.
He was like,
no,
watch the dog in the morning for fucking
gets up.
What does the dog do?
Stretch those paws out in front of him
and arch sat back and he watched dallas
do is fucking work,
right?
Wait a minute.
Downward dog and now you're doing the
arch in the bag.
Like a fucking cat.
What the fuck you bastard.
Yeah,
he's a smart man.
He's a powerful man too.
I mean he just what he has in his head
in terms of his vision for helping
people and how he's able to see that
through and that having that
accountability crib and putting
everybody through these workouts on a
daily basis.
I mean the amount of time invested in
helping you guys.
This is fucking amazing and not just you
guys,
but many,
many,
many people
in my only fear is not going to get out
there about,
oh,
he's getting out there and mark is
lucky.
We were helping a whole other world that
doesn't know him yet.
People have known about him more and
more.
I know you really appreciate your show
them what it did for him that he should
have just fucking rockfell rock doesn't
fucking world because it's feeding that.
I mean,
it's feeding his ego and keep going.
It really is true.
Doing something nice.
Makeshift,
feel good.
It doesn't really get talked about
enough.
Bad news channel.
Why not right now?
You're right,
my brother.
Happy shit.
Right?
There's a lot of that.
Well,
you know,
people are scared.
They like watching fear based things
because if it bleeds it leads.
But if you're hurting so bad.
Yeah.
Well I think the problem is even calling
it news,
you know,
it's adverse events,
but news is almost always negative and
so you know,
it's calling even calling it the news.
Like what does that mean?
News,
what's news?
This shit happen hours.
It's not news.
This is just events.
It's like the show is events,
but what,
what,
what dallas is doing is showing people
that there's another path and in his,
his yoga program and just how positive
and energetic that guy is.
It's contagious,
you know,
and having him on the podcast man,
the number of fucking messages that I
got afterwards of how many people that
have benefited and how many people
started taking this program and started
taking his yoga or any yoga and cleaning
up their life and just inspired by it.
It's amazing,
you know,
that makes me very happy when I can help
a guy spread that kind of word that,
that makes me very happy.
Yeah.
I just want to get out there.
I've chosen this platform of doing these
shows and building so you know,
because you wouldn't do me any good to
be in the building where there's 5,000
people because I can't spend time with
each one of you,
but if it's a 150 in a comedy club will
be five or 10 people that want to talk
about 150.
I got time for that.
Yeah.
If it was $5,000,
I'd be overwhelmed because not because
of the show shows easy.
He's just fucking memories.
I'll pull it out and had some jingles
for it around,
you know,
say a couple of cute things and I'm not
getting to them.
That's,
you know,
that's,
that's my,
that's where I wanted,
you know,
when it's been a good show,
when I go and talk to a couple people
and I can go back to the hotel room and
just like,
which is basically the opposite of how
you would go back to a hotel room when
you were wrestling.
Yeah.
I want to forget now.
Right now I'm doing shit to forget about
and you can go back and chill.
I can go back and smile.
That's beautiful.
Yeah.
I'm getting the,
you know,
I'm hoping that,
I've,
I've had enough miracles happened to me
in the past four years to believe that
there's still one more miracle left for
me and I hope the hell I meet her soon
because I don't want to.
I don't want to be alone anymore.
Man.
You see,
I dish up that stupid and I'm going to
tell you guys made a lot of you guys
listening and all was like,
come on jake,
you're killing my buzz man.
Well maybe I am and I'm going to tell
you something guys.
A woman is a great thing to have,
but you can't have too much than to have
too many.
I know.
I experienced that.
I went from a small town kid and
gainesville taxes where if you got laid
twice in a month by two different girls,
yours,
you're the man and the double standards
that we have for women that if a woman
goes out and gives,
she's not a stud,
she's a whore.
WHat the fuck's wrong with that?
It's us.
Well,
jake went from small town to a bigger
city star.
Oh my god.
You named the price.
You make it nice.
Hey girl,
why don't you and your girlfriend come
do a little show for me.
Use this toy,
that toy,
this toy bringing the dog or comes to
the clown because that's what it got.
It was never enough.
It had to be one more idea.
One more goofy thing to do as a girl or
one more sexual position or how many can
you do in one night?
What'd you do with the donkey?
It's a joke,
bro.
We're friends.
We have dictionaries or I can anyway,
but other words I couldn't fuck no more
because now I've got a problem.
What's the problem?
It takes some pretty weird shit to get
my fucking brain busy.
I went from heaven,
that diva at home,
that foxy hot.
Most I could ever want to.
having to get my shots.
Shots,
shots of testosterone so I can pray to
get a hard on for because there's not
all this outside stuff going into the
night.
Fucking kidding me.
You can't get your take are for this
motherfucker over here.
Then that would do anything for you.
Love you.
Everything,
but it also had to probably have to do
with all the years of doing steroids.
Your will.
Your body doesn't produce testosterone
the same anymore.
if you do the years of steroids.
Yeah,
well I can still get the woodman and he
brought the donkey and fucking wood all
day long.
The extreme excitement,
but that might be part of the issue.
The excitement was
having a door.
You can make them do anything you want.
Right.
That's the kitchen on healthy,
right?
That's very unhealthy is the kink.
Exactly.
So you got our to into the kink and then
regular stuff wasn't stimulating.
Get me happy.
He as the old joke about the couple that
are embedded going,
what's wrong honey?
We can't.
You can't fuck anybody else either.
Fuck.
you know,
you're trying to think of somebody.
You get your shit going.
She's trying to think of somebody to get
her shit going.
You're both living a fucking lie.
But I had to abstain from sex
for several years to get the fire back.
Fire his back.
Nobody wants to put it out.
You can find a gal,
a gal,
a woman.
He's available.
Women,
not girls.
Girls.
Stay home on a woman.
I'm going to experience.
I'm going to hook you up on a date with
my mom.
If I can get Jake the snake.
If I can get jake the snake,
they'd be my stepdad.
My life's complete for penis is bigger
than yours.
I'll take her probably is okay,
and she has a pet donkey,
so.
Right,
but we're going to fix that back in one
moment.
And you want any dating apps or
anything?
No problem.
No,
no.
You don't do that shit,
right?
Well,
you don't want an old fashioned girl
fashion way.
You just put it out there in the
universe right now to millions of
people.
So what's going to happen is at your
shows,
and we'll get a lot of bullshit that I
don't want to know.
This is going to be these gals and think
I'm the one gentleman help right now
listening to this podcast right now.
There's girls in the mirror right now
with a blow dryer brush and getting
ready for jake.
The snake
you on instagram,
you've got xannies in nashville.
You got to check those dms.
we got to teach you how to check your
inbox.
Yeah.
Do you check your inbox inbox?
Now?
You got to be careful with the ones,
with the numbers of their names.
MosT of those bitches are fake.
If you go to their pages and there's
only two photos and none of them have
any text in them,
don't get suckered.
Don't get fished.
Fished,
you know,
catch fish.
You gotta.
Be real careful trying to fuck with you.
They're trying to get money from Nigeria
will help you,
bro.
Yeah,
but listen,
not feel comfortable where you're next.
Where,
where do people find your gigs?
And we're going to send this out there
to all the other women.
Actual women,
you know,
social media man.
Jake,
the snake.
Dvt on instagram.
And do you have a website?
But yeah,
I'll get a website,
man.
Jake the snake.
Roberts,
not jake the snake.
Roberts.com.
Is there a contact thing on there at
jake?
the snake roberts.
Compare yourself?
Uh,
photographs.
Just know that my daughter will read
them first.
Okay.
Settle down.
Ladies.
Pitchers.
She doesn't read with jake.
The snake.
Roberts,
man,
she's the best.
All right brother.
Listen,
this is an awesome podcast.
I really appreciate you coming in here.
And your film is fucking fantastic.
It's the resurrection of jake the snake.
It's fucking excellent diamond dallas
page for showers up.
We just did two hours and 20 minutes are
you should.
Yeah.
Flew by dallas.
goes fast for somebody sucking your
dick.
Thanks.
By the way,
shout out to dallas.
he's a fucking amazing human being.
Young tony hinchcliffe.
Tell people you're going to be next
dallas,
new year's eve.
I'm going to be in baltimore.
Addison hyenas.
So again,
just did a bunch of.
Just did 11 pack shoWs in Texas for kill
tony's and five standup shows and uh,
thIs week and we're doing dallas,
new year's eve,
me and jeremiah watkins featuring for me
two shows in one night.
Baltimore at the gooby is at the end of
november.
And those dates for england or coming up
on my website in probably at the end of
this week,
tony.
And maybe someday you and I,
you got to do it.
Couldn't be in the same town and me
doing a good show and you have somewhere
else.
Yeah,
absolutely.
End on a positive note.
He's a bad guy.
He's got to go liked.
Hang out with you,
man.
No,
we will actually be able
because I do wonder some movies out
there.
Remember that not just porn
and I have a wrestling podcast to get
you on.
We do it at the comedy store.
We'll do it,
man,
because you know I'm trying to get a
deal with a club there in vegas,
man,
because I'd like to do the whole
residency thing and beautiful and then
have a podcast.
I live right there.
The building was promoted to fuck.
Yeah,
we'll put it on twitter and instagram
the whole day.
We all need to buy a hotel first and put
me into that fucking hotel doing my
podcasts again.
We're putting in the universe.
Ladies and gentlemen,
bring it to see where it comes.
Thank you so much tony hinchcliffe.
Ladies and gentlemen.
thanks
really good.