And we're live.
You don't have headphones.
There you go.
Alex Niles Gray.
Hello.
How are you guys?
Great job.
I think you got to turn that sucker
around and see that one.
There you go.
Nope.
Oh my goodness.
This is Joey Diaz.
And when Joey Diaz couldn't figure out
the headphones.
Welcome folks was going on.
We are in the middle of building ncn.
I've,
I've heard the rumor,
the thing that you got us kicked off on
really the last time that we spoke to
you.
We were doing a kickstarter campaign to
build Antionne and it was like three
years ago and we're in the middle of
another one because we started building
it and we need a little more money to
finish the interior.
Now we've got a three story,
12,000 square foot building with a new
roof and incredible spaces to exhibit
visionary art.
So it's,
it's there and I guess it's just a
matter of time,
uh,
about finishing it and more money
weekend,
the quicker we'll be able to finish it.
Are there images of it right now
currently in,
in construction that people can view?
Oh look at that,
Jim said,
Whoa,
that's amazing.
Where did you get that?
Looks like really old brick.
That's cool.
Looking brick 18.
80 two was built in.
It said we were saving the carriage
house from 1882.
So explain the process.
So it started out as a carriage house.
Yup.
And you save part of it?
Yes,
we surrounded it.
Wow.
Oh,
so we surrounded it with art side.
The building low.
Jamie,
scroll back up.
Hold on.
Don't go anywhere.
Get back up to the top one that you.
Yeah,
look at that.
Wow.
That's just one room on the third floor.
That's where the sake.
Okay.
We're just going to be three floors.
Yeah,
we're going to put criss cross kind of
scaffold a lattice across the angels.
Um,
let's see.
On my instagram,
I suppose there's a more recent feed of
the interior now.
We've gone a couple of the actual
angels.
They were 10 angels in the previous,
um,
chapel installation there in New York
City.
And I always wanted to,
he went to the wrong Alex Grey went to
some way.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's relevant,
isn't it?
It is.
It as well.
Let's see.
So there's the space,
there's one of the angels over there
that's a uh,
yeah,
well this,
this is the plan to corner one of the
angels or the four corners that,
uh,
the direction of the building that we're
kind of recycling the carriage house has
the corners of the buildings pointing in
the cardinal directions.
So I thought that a feature of them
there will be angels or the North South,
east,
west,
and part of the whole thing is getting
the four quadrants together on top of
the building.
There's a steeple head that is basically
a four faced being that,
that is the people,
the four directions coming together.
Envisionary oneness.
So it's as a building,
it's a big basically godhead.
And
is that a real image of the actual
outside of the building with the angel
on it?
No,
that's that.
Yeah,
that's the computer a model that was
made by one of the Disney animators,
Ryan toddle.
He's a guy that is responsible for
running the,
uh,
one of the digital animation teams that
did Zootopia and frozen.
And he's an amazing a modeler.
Go back to that.
Look at this outside of this building
that might be the coolest looking
building on the planet earth.
Go up a little,
but you'll see a,
one of the coolest things about the
video that,
uh,
is in there is that it shows that kind
of spin around of the building itself
that was done by these amazing nurse
that's from the front.
So you've got a kind of evolutionary
thing going on on the side.
Oh yeah.
And then it gets to the,
uh,
the front door,
which is Adam and eve,
uh,
creating a better world.
So it kind of brings together those
mythologies of those narratives of
development.
Can you,
can you zoom in on the Adam and eve?
Jamie,
is it a zoom as it is guys?
Is that a caduceus in the middle of
them?
Not See,
actually down below a way down below.
There's a,
um,
it,
there you get to see.
Oh Wow.
So you really did the caduceus and then
sort of replicated the DNA,
which a lot of people believe was what
the caduceus was based on the first
place,
right?
[inaudible].
It's all growing out of some mushrooms
there at the base.
Alex did the drawing and then it was
sculpted in teak.
Whoa.
Full size four by eight foot doors.
There's two of them.
And then we had it scanned.
We got a grant to have it scanned and
then it'll be on the door in metal.
So it will be cast in metal.
The originals will be on view inside
because they're made of teak
friendships.
So it's what kind of metals are going to
be cast in bronze site.
Wow.
That is so cool.
Yeah.
And so what is going on with the
evolution thing?
So the evolution,
there's the lower hominids they become
homo erectus.
And then what does that child like thing
with arms up in the air?
Well,
I wanted to add,
thanks for noticing that.
I'm on the end of this paint brush,
which is kind of flying up and
indicating a kind of upward trajectory.
There's a drip coming off of it and that
drip also act like an eyeball.
The center of the eyeball is the earth.
And uh,
there's a skeleton,
a child and the person who is fully
ground woman and man on either side and
they each are reaching for the planet.
Now that question is,
who's going to get the ball?
Basically the skeleton or the human?
Yeah,
a will that,
will we be handing this to the next
generation or are we just going to blow
it?
So the skeleton sorta represents death
yet represents the end of the line for
the human species,
for anybody is a.
didn't even introduce your page.
The instagram page is what does it.
Was it Alex?
Great.
Column C O s m [inaudible].
This is a build [inaudible] dot com.
This is the,
I'm a kickstarter.
Then how long has it been going on for
now?
I'd say about 20 days
were there.
We have a 40 day campaign.
We're about three times where we were
less.
We did this a campaign the same length,
the same days,
three years ago in 2013.
And we're three times ahead of where we
were.
I wait,
we,
we actually,
um,
well we did 160 percent of our goal the
last time.
So we're,
we're,
you know,
we're challenging ourselves to even
higher.
What I meant was how long has it been
under construction?
How long it's been since September of
Twenty
15.
Okay.
So you're,
you're,
so,
you're an obit.
Um,
so what is the ultimate end date where
you believe this all be constructed?
Well,
it really depends on the money that we
raised to do the exterior.
The interior we're going to have done by
2017 and we're aiming at the winter of
2017.
It should be doable,
you know,
everybody's telling us
this is the interior will open the
exhibition and then we'll see,
you know,
who knows.
I mean there's,
there's indications that,
you know,
like you don't know how much money's
going to come in.
This campaign is only to finish the
exhibition interiorly and then uh,
you know,
if we still,
which I think we will need to raise
another at one point $5,000,000 to do
the sculpture or exterior,
which is done by a three d print out.
It's a three d print out 20 feet high by
eight by eight.
And what is the substance?
It's manner.
Well,
it'll be finished in a glass reinforced
cast concrete,
but you print out the foam,
then you make the mold,
you make a fiberglass mold.
There's about a couple of dozen molds
that will be needed to do the sculptures
and there's a place right across the
river from us.
Thirty minutes away that does this.
So that's convenient.
Oh yeah.
We were thinking coming to California,
there are places that do it out here,
but uh,
we found a place so close and they're
doing the Brooklyn Academy of Music and
some of the big buildings in the city.
Has anybody done anything even remotely
like this?
Well,
you'll see theme parks where things are,
but the glass reinforced cast concrete
will make it enduring,
you know,
like it,
it'll be if they don't knock it down
with a wrecking ball,
it'll be there in a thousand years.
That's the building itself is a tomb.
I mean,
it's,
it's made to be a enduring.
That's our mission.
So the mission is to have this thing
survive you.
The mission is to build an enduring
sanctuary,
visionary art,
to uplift a global community.
That's our actual mission.
Do you guys have a caretaker when you
pass?
Have you already thought of like when
you move on to the next dimension,
who's going to take over this thing?
It's a church
is that it became a church in 2008 and
so the church churches generally a run
by the it's board and the staff that
works there,
but you know,
the board of directors are the people
that owned the church.
We actually lived there,
but our house that we built there will
be long to the church.
Everything we're doing there will belong
to them.
It's a 40 acre compound basically in the
Hudson valley seed.
Uh,
that's,
that's where it's happening.
There's 21 people working there now.
Wow.
I trust you guys with a church.
No,
I don't trust a whole lot of people.
I go,
yeah,
they're not gonna.
They're not going to get crazy.
But what I would worry about if I was
establishing a church is not me.
I would worry about what people are
going to distort the message afterwards.
Oh yeah.
That's always the real issue.
The real issue is whenever you have
something that you're going to call a
church or religion or have a sacred area
where you take it very,
very seriously,
you're going to have at least one person
who has an elevated
profile.
You know there's going to be one person
or people who run this thing that other
people are going to look at like they
are different than us.
They are elevated.
They are the people that are in charge
of this,
and when people have that feeling that
they feel like they're the elevated one
guy,
that gets tricky.
That's so slippery.
It's so hard for people to manage.
Here's one of the ways that we try to
avoid it because we never claimed to be
enlightened ourselves.
You know,
we're aren't as well.
I trust you.
Yeah.
Where
we're creative artists and like a lot of
artists,
we feel like when we're really doing our
thing that there's a spiritual element
of that,
that your creativity and spirituality
somehow seem like they're very strongly
connected.
There isn't any mythology about it.
You know,
if we're basically emanations of a
cosmos that's creative than we're little
embodiments of creative energy and that
creative energy can be used for the
positive or the negative in how you,
and it comes from the way that you view
the world,
how you're going to take that.
And so as an emanation of creative
energy and artists is just a,
you know,
like an obvious symbol of that.
And uh,
so we see that throughout history that
all the religions,
whether they agreed or disagreed,
all used creative expression to get
their message out.
And so it's one of the things that
unites all the different wisdom
traditions and unites a lot of other
stuff that's out that would consider
itself outside of religion as well.
I feel that creativity itself is the
original kind of religious impulse that
it's the way of knowing oneself,
the way of knowing God.
It's a,
it's a means of worship.
I mean,
we look at the,
the cave art and you say,
you know,
they weren't talking about sex or
something or disagreeing necessarily as
religious kind of ideas and things like
that.
They were making a mark of meaning and
left behind something that was
meaningful to their tribe and I think
that that's still what we're trying to
do and you know,
I,
I think religion because it scares the
shit out of really intelligent people
for good reason because it's such a mess
in the world and created such a mess and
so much divisiveness.
Something that's supposed to be about
love that's caused so much heartache and
damage and so,
and what I think is that when I told my
friend Robert Jesse,
I'm from the council on spiritual
practices.
Well,
I'm spiritual,
but I'm not religious.
You know,
you saying,
you know Alex,
we can't let the fundamentalists own the
word religion.
Russians too important a word and what
we need are courageous experiments in
religion that could help us to get to
the
other side of the bell curve,
the evolutionary edge.
Is there an evolving edge for religion?
Could we get posts secular in the world?
Can we imagine a world where people
have.
Most of the people of the world have
taken a sacrament of one kind or another
and have realized that there's an
infinite intelligence at the basis of
the cosmos that they are a,
you know,
an expression of.
And that ended life is a divine,
um,
display spectacle,
you know,
that,
that God's gone to a lot of trouble to
create.
And,
uh,
so,
you know,
from the perspective of today what you
know,
because toynbee when he was writing
about civilizations,
talked about,
you know,
every civilization needs a spiritual
core.
And as it planetary civilization,
you can't have one religion dominate.
It's impossible.
It's just not.
No,
it's not possible.
And so how do you unite a world
spiritually?
Well,
my candidate is create the creative
arts,
you know,
that all of world cultures have some
means of creative expression.
We get to know that culture through
their music,
through their know painting,
sculpture,
various kinds of things.
And that how we,
uh,
get to know each other and see our
connections,
you know,
and so as a potential,
something that's been used by all world
religions,
you know,
in something that has a defacto for the
people who don't believe in God anymore.
Many of them still believe that artists
are trying to do something authentic and
truthful to their,
to their inner being.
Isn't the word religion fairly loaded
though,
and what isn't,
what's important?
The idea behind what you're trying to
do,
right?
The idea is that you're trying to make
this sacred place.
You're trying to make this amazing place
where people can go and see expression
and see,
you know,
the purity of your creative vision.
What,
why,
why connect that to a loaded word?
Because it's,
as Jesse said in my book,
I think it's,
it's too easy
to run away from that.
It's a,
it's
a,
you know,
how a bad neighborhood gets,
and it's just like,
oh my God,
it's only criminal.
So live here.
And then some artists show up,
you know,
and they start having their studios and
various things like that.
And sooner or later,
a really beat up neighborhood will start
to have some vitality because creative
energy,
creative energy starts to infiltrate
into destructive energy.
What I'm saying is if the artists would
move back into the world of religion,
we might clean up the neighborhood a
little,
you know,
and make it a more habitable for people
to want to look at their relationship
with spirit through even the lens of
religion.
But why?
Why religion though?
Because religion is associated in most
people's minds,
the deities realia religions associated
most people's minds with aiden and
traditions,
ancient traditions that oftentimes
stifle your behavior,
tell you what to do,
control you and offer horrendous
consequences for not complying.
That's what a lot of people think of
when they think of the word religion.
So here's this thing,
but you hope,
but let me get to this real quick.
You have this thing,
this beautiful thing,
like why even put a name to it?
Why,
why label it?
And when you're labeling it,
you're connecting it with all these
other religions that are so problematic
and you're going to have to explain your
way out of that.
Why do that instead of just have this
amazing center,
um,
because I feel that we're a maintenance
lead connected with whatever that
religious impulse,
and if you look at the,
what is the primary religious experience
that is a mystical experience
regularly geo to reconnect,
to connect up,
to link back because that was the word
man.
Yes,
to really link to reconnect to what the
self to God,
the Self and God so that that's the
actual origin of the word.
Religion.
Religion says it a Latin word and
French,
French and it's to reconnect.
So the idea being that the religion or
these churches were set up so that
people could reconnect with God.
So they go about their day.
They were filled with troubles and
strife and all sorts of stress and they
can go back to the church and they can
reconnect with God through religion,
through if you go to Egypt or you go to
a.
You just came back from Venice and you
go to some of these religious cathedrals
that are a thousand years old.
You go to these pilgrimage places and
there is tremendous power because a lot
of people invested a lot of love and
energy into a center and they built a
shrine to whatever they believed that
spirit to be.
And that is part of a long tradition of
a connectedness with,
uh,
you know,
their lens into the infinite.
Whatever religion you're looking
through,
iconic,
an iconic,
yes,
they're a hell of lot of trouble when
you get to the secondary,
uh,
religious,
you know,
experience,
which is everything else that you think
about religion,
the primary religious experience.
Every religion started with a mystical
experience and people are having those
on acid every day now,
you know?
And so what he,
a disconnect from that whole tradition
where people were connecting to the
infinite before and you say,
this has nothing to do with that,
you know,
or do you say,
hey,
religions fucked up.
But what if we reimagine it?
What if we reimagined God,
you know,
and can't,
can't we do it?
And say,
this has a lot of,
a lot going for it.
This quest for the infinite,
absolute mystery.
That's at the core of our being and the
core of the cosmos.
This quest to know that it leads to
science that leads aren't.
It's the.
It's the quest to know the truth about
the nature of reality and so that quest
is another reason why I think that if
you harness that to creativity,
just artists,
artists hate dogma,
you,
you can't have a dogmatic.
I mean our artists always disagree and
you're always going to have new vantage
point.
You're always gonna have one evolving a
point of view.
That's part of the trouble of religion
is that they get,
you know,
this is the right way and it's only like
this.
We're not going to look beyond our
boundaries of what,
you know,
people made up long ago as the way it's
supposed to be in another century when
you know,
we didn't know any of the stuff that we
know now,
so that does make sense.
So any good religion ought to their view
of reality,
at least science ought to be
incorporated into it.
So you couldn't have a truthful religion
without science.
Are you planning on writing something
out like the tenants of this religion,
the ethics of this religion,
we actually have liturgy.
In order to become a church you have to
submit liturgy to the irs and the state
attorney general and then we had to.
I'm familiar with what's our word,
liturgy,
like a,
like a document,
you know,
like stuff that you use on a regular
basis in,
in your ceremonies,
so you have that in order to be
recognized for it don't have to do,
but it's part of the irs a requirement
and estate attorney.
Do you have a liturgy?
Liturgy?
You can say no.
Yeah,
you probably could probably apply and
maybe you know,
it's all in your head relax.
It's like a guy has to look over what
you're doing and really question it and
see if you've thought it out and stuff
like that.
Alex published art psalms,
which was a poetry book and you've seen
so that was really submitted.
That was submitted as our,
as cosmic liturgy.
Perfect.
Um,
well that's,
that's work is really fascinating is the
tax exempt status of religion.
Religion is so odd in that way,
that worshiping and being in a place
where you worship,
even if it's very clear that there's a
lot of profit being made,
you don't have to pay taxes on that.
I just want to tell you this little,
just a touch of the history of why we
became a church because it wasn't really
ever our intention to become a church
all the way from the beginning when we
19,
85 and we visioned the temple
simultaneously.
Alex and I on our first Mtma a journey
lying on the bed.
We both came out of it having vision.
This circular,
a building in 1985.
We had recently moved to New York
together doing mdm back in 1985.
Jesus,
but we both saw this temple and we knew
that this was sort of like our,
our joint mission.
This was the thing we were going to do
together.
You know Alex always.
We met in art school,
so Alex always had his art and I had my
art and we shared a studio,
but this was something we were going to
do together.
So we never thought we would become a
church to know,
but here we were building the sacred
site and then all through our life
together,
you know,
we uh,
started visiting sacred sites like we
just came from St Mark's and Venice and
we see sharp cathedral and you know,
we go there with groups of people and
you know,
like go on pilgrimage to these sacred
beauty,
beautiful art places.
But anyway,
uh,
the way we became a church was um,
a friend of ours who started Sirius
satellite network.
Actually,
she's Martine Rothblatt,
but she,
she loves the work that a actual lives.
Alex's work,
she's a collector,
she loves the work.
We're doing awesome with the community
and all this.
And she said,
you know,
you're doing everything that churches
do.
You're doing weddings,
baby blessings and morals.
You have,
you have a prayer book,
you know,
basically arts and you're doing
everything that churches do and you're
not getting any of the benefits of what
churches get business thinking.
No,
she's so smart.
Really?
And she paid a lawyer.
She is the one that funded,
granted us,
you know,
getting together with our,
with our guy who,
who when we went through the process
with us,
it took a good long time.
You have to basically write a lot of
essays and then they give you more
essays and it was maybe three times
through essays and you write them all
and then you submit the liturgy and
eventually just at the moment we were
moving to the country.
It was like the same minute.
The church status just magically came in
after four years.
It was like all like coming together,
you know,
so as it is though,
we have 40 acres and then we had to
fight with our town over,
you know,
every church in our town and there's
every,
there's mosques and Buddhist stupas and
you know,
lots of Catholic and every kind of
Protestant.
And they were not paying real estate tax
and we have this 40 acres and they were
raising our taxes 15 percent every year.
Meanwhile we're not making any money.
Alex and I are volunteers that caused
them by the way.
And so we'd make nothing.
We just give it away and the whole place
we're giving away it belongs to the
community and the community is everybody
whose spiritual and creative,
but it tends to have a lot of
psychedelia files.
People who feel like they've,
they've experienced the divine and they
want a place to go ahead and talk about
it.
They wanted this in the city when we
were in Manhattan for five years.
It was just a place where you could go
and talk about this because it's legal
to talk about it and we would always
have security and make sure there wasn't
anything being passed around because we
can't get into trouble because we were
like a really legitimate.
We're doing this in legitimate way.
We have to took us four years to get our
permits to do this building.
You add security to make sure that
people didn't pass drugs around.
Well,
we can't have anything visible.
What you do that is private is your own
business.
If you can behave yourself,
we don't.
We watch out for you and we.
I understand that,
but you had a bunch of people actually
watching people to make sure we always
have security.
They're gentle giants.
We call them gentle giants.
You have to have security when you're
having.
We have hundreds of thousands.
Well,
some of our full moons are from hundreds
to a thousand people.
We have large groups of people.
That's what,
what happened was a sham and told us
that,
uh,
we,
we had this whole idea of this temple we
wanted to build,
but where's your community?
You know,
building a temple is the work of a
community.
He said,
so we're going to start full moon
ceremonies in your home in Brooklyn.
So we did.
We started in January of 2,364
consecutive,
full moons ago.
We started them in our loft in Brooklyn
and then we went to,
we got a place in Manhattan,
12,000 square feet.
We did it for five years.
Then we found this permanent location in
a whopping journey.
York,
it's in the Hudson Valley.
We were like 65 miles from the city.
You can get there on the train,
but we found this lovely old retreat
center all kind of imploding and you
know,
and we've been working on at one
building at a time,
the carriage house,
which is turning into an theone,
the first temple of visionary art that
we really came there to build his
building for.
Actually we have a 10 bedroom Victorian
guesthouse and a office in our studio.
So we have,
you know,
we have six buildings to work on and
we're on building for.
But uh,
anyway,
that's.
This is like a little retreat center
that we're leaving to our community,
our spiritual,
creative cosmonaut community.
It's fascinating that Martin was
involved in it because she's also
involved in artificial intelligence.
I interviewed her for the Scifi show
that I did.
Yeah.
And she has this robot version of her
wife Bina four,
eight,
48 or whatever.
Yeah.
Well,
she started a church.
She being a started a church called the
terrorism movement.
We need to start a church.
You should.
Joey Diaz already has a church,
which he just joined his
Joey Diaz as the Church of what's
happening now.
There's some great churches out there.
I really just think it's why should
these Catholics get it all?
You know what I mean?
We shouldn't get it all.
No.
I think after you involved in like the
100th child molestation,
he probably should take.
You're probably take it away and that's.
That's like super conservative number.
That's horrible.
That crazy religion.
Religion doesn't uphold that.
That's just awful people.
Yes,
but
awful people all throughout that one
religion.
I mean there's gotta be some sort of a
connection with suppression,
suppression of Sexuality,
suppression of ideology,
forcing people to behave in a certain
way and these blow backs and the also
the fear.
I mean I was raised Catholic and I went
to Catholic school when I was a young
kid and I remember I didn't go to
kindergarten.
I just went right into first grade and I
remember the fear,
the constant fear that they injected in
you this,
this idea of what religion is.
It was great for me because it,
it just queered me off religion so
young.
So early off I was like,
oh,
okay,
well this is all nonsense was before
that.
When I was young,
my parents were getting divorced and my
parents are splitting up.
I was really scared.
I was really nervous and I was young and
there was a lot of violence going
around.
There was a lot of yelling and screaming
and I needed something and so I remember
when I was little I was always talking
about God and it was just like,
well,
there's got to be.
If all these people around me are out of
their mind and everyone's crazy,
there's got to be God.
So I was actually excited to go to
Catholic school.
I was excited to go to church.
I thought of it as well,
me,
maybe these people that these relatives
in these family members that I live with
are all crazy,
but there's going to be a place that I
can go where I'm going to be able to be
loved and it's going to be calm.
God has rules and everyone's gonna
follow them,
and then I went there and I was like,
Oh,
good Lord.
No Pun intended.
This fucking places worse.
I was like,
these people out of their minds and my.
My parents were going to put me in there
for second grade and I literally told
him I'd run away from home.
I was like,
I'm going to find my way out of this.
I'm like,
I'm not doing this,
and it was seven,
you know?
I was like,
this is not happening.
Well,
you have already become rational.
It's seven.
You knew
you had a bullshit detector that was
always acutely attuned.
Well,
that's one good thing about growing up
in a really fucked up household is that
like you,
you,
you're,
you have a constant sense of danger
because you're around danger all the
time.
So you don't get to sleep cuddly.
You don't get to like rest calm and you,
you,
you have an acute awareness of all the
possibilities.
So I mean ultimately that was a great
thing for me.
I can,
I can really see how that it heightened
your ability to also to always maintain
that mindfulness,
that over everything.
It's what,
it probably allows you to do so many
things.
It's also,
there's,
you know,
there's always a balance between
mindfulness and paranoia.
You don't want to be that guy that
carries a gun to the bathroom.
You know,
there's,
I know a lot of people that have
surpassed this,
uh,
awareness and gone into this like acute
paranoia.
I have this statement that I've been
saying a lot lately,
but I think it's important to bring up.
I don't think human beings are designed
to take in the bad news of 7 billion
people.
I just don't think.
I think the numbers that we deal with on
a daily basis with all the different
stories of the world,
they are too much for us to handle.
It's not how you're supposed to deal
with what's going on in your community
with a watchful eye on the rest of the
world.
You shouldn't be deeply engrossed in all
of the most disgusting aspects of the
rest of the world.
Twenty four hours a day.
And I think that's one of the real
problematic issues of our time with
social media and with the news that
people have this distorted sense of what
the world is.
They think this world is just filled
with violence and horror.
No,
the world is fine.
It just occasionally has violence and
horror.
There's just so many people and the
world is so big that if you look at all
those people and this giant globe that
we're on,
then you can kind of get a sense that
the sky is falling,
but you know,
but if you go outside right now in
woodland hills,
it's beautiful.
It's nice.
It's always the worst thing happening in
every area.
Sometimes it's not,
but it's so rare.
It's like occasionally they give you
some good food with her feet and your
poison.
You're about to die.
They slip you a piece of fruit.
Just.
I just don't think it's good for us.
I don't think it is and I think that's
the same thing with someone who grows up
in a bad environment.
I think you could.
You could get a distorted perception of
what the world is and think that that
the bad environment that you're
currently in is the entire world and it
can shape your perceptions and your
interactions and therefore shape how you
react to other people and shape your
actual reality.
You know,
it's one of the things that have truly
tried to impart upon people that I've
learned and I believe that how you treat
people and your interactions with people
literally change your reality,
and this is from mistakes that I've made
and this is from positive
decisions that I've made because I think
that when you look at life in a positive
way and you try to treat people kind and
you try to be nice to people and you try
to move forward with that,
the people that you interact with,
they will get that.
They will most likely respond more
kindly to you and the world changes.
The world literally changes in front of
you.
It's billiard balls.
Yeah.
You know,
have have kind act that could be sending
waves.
A smile could actually prevent somebody
from committing suicide.
That's all it takes.
Maybe you should just go ahead and end
it.
Well,
I heard from some from some kids who are
really desperate and I going to jump or
am I
not?
Some stranger looked at me and smiled.
That's and that stopped me from doing
it.
Alex,
what still have meat?
Acid stopped me from,
from killing myself
because for me,
I wondered whether God exists.
Just like your question when you were
seven,
you were hoping that there was something
that was not a it,
you know,
that there was a center of peace
somewhere.
I guess now I don't know that I would
ever call God at center of peace.
You know,
I would say that that's one aspect of
the entire,
you know,
meet storm of being alive.
I love that word,
but what I read express,
meet storm.
You should make a t shirt
says meets dorm.
That's a great band.
Radical band.
Hudson Valley.
Meet Storm.
We have a grinder attached to industrial
fan folks.
I wouldn't think about it that way.
I was thinking about a bunch of people
just jumping around,
getting crazy.
There you go.
Word.
Well,
I thought of that when I saw the last
judgment,
but I make glands.
Well,
speaking of Catholics,
so you gotta look at the good things
like even probably some really terrible
stuff happened in those Howard halls in
the Vatican,
but again,
really awesome art.
Yeah.
Have you ever seen the Sistine Chapel?
No,
I'm actually going there this summer.
We spent an entire day from nine until
five.
We got there,
the front of the line and got in
the way all the way there.
You got to run all the way through the
Vatican.
Well to know you don't want to do that.
Yeah,
you do.
Why do you want to run?
Well,
we went to Chapel Sistine Chapel.
Oh,
so you got to take it and then get there
in time when it kicks in.
We were there all day from nine to five
drawing.
We just sat.
We got a seat and we were just drawing
all day and our focus,
it was just unbelievable and the
drawings came out really amazing too.
And so we had been to Vatican before,
I have to say.
So when you go to the Vatican for the
first time,
you have to walk through so you can see
all the amazingness of the way there
because the sistine chapel is at the end
of the tour,
you know,
you'd go out there and then afterwards
you come back.
So.
So you,
you know,
on the way you want to take a look,
but we had already done that so we were
like made the decision,
this was our day to draw man,
you know,
so I got it.
I just,
that was all I wanted to see.
Anyway.
So it,
everything else is just a blur and then
you get to the Sistine Chapel is quite
fascinating that you're looking at the
work of someone who lived hundreds of
years,
500 years ago.
Amazing.
And he didn't like everything that
Castle Catholics did by the way.
He did.
Well he didn't,
but he did like being Catholic.
Okay.
He,
he really did.
He wrote about it and was very eloquent
and he loved being healthy,
but he didn't like the pope telling him
to paint the Sistine Chapel for
instance.
Look at that,
look at that.
How long did it take for him to do that?
I
don't know.
Years and years.
They last judgment is the one that was,
I guess I've always called my favorite
painting of all time.
That's the meat storm.
It's like a,
you know,
and there were no clothes.
I'm a figures on that.
They,
Michelangelo was still alive when they
got,
um,
a,
uh,
what they called it,
he was,
uh,
he was a good fresco painter,
but he became basically Michelangelo's
breaches,
painter,
you know,
he was always thought of as the one who
added,
you know,
clothing and drapery over the genitalia
that Michelangelo had painted.
He loved the body and he,
uh,
made one,
I would call an anthropocosm out of it,
want a kind of a temple of humanity.
And it was very much about the nobility
and connected with the Greek idealist.
That Greek idealist tradition is a
psychedelic tradition from the
neoplatonic in the platonic,
you know,
socrates and all the rest.
So that wave was just getting,
uh,
he,
he was there when they dug up.
They,
Lao coon,
you know,
the Greek sculpture with the snakes and
the crazy stuff that it really deeply
influenced him.
I just wanted to say that the purity of
the religion place where it,
it's really true,
you know,
like that beautiful,
what would it actually means at the,
at the core,
at the heart core of any religion is
expressed through the art of that
religion.
So you know,
the other stuff is crap.
You know what I mean with the way people
act towards each other and stuff.
That's their own deficits and their own
obstacles coming out,
you know,
all over the place.
Even the pope's that have been horrible
and allowed,
you know,
uh,
child molestation to perpetrate those
people are sick people that has nothing.
They don't represent the purity of the
religion,
which is the representative and they
are.
But what is that?
What is the purity of the religion and
doesn't vary depending upon the
individual.
And why does it,
why does that?
I don't think anybody,
every religion that what we're seeing is
the purity of one man's expression.
His,
his view is beautiful view of the world.
That we're so fortunate to be able to
still look at
true 500 years later.
What does that have to do with
Catholicism?
I think that because he was part of that
tradition and he was marrying the ideas
of the Greek ideal and the ended
neoplatonic,
uh,
which was all about universality,
you know,
it was really more about it.
They,
as much as we're saying,
you know,
all religions are connected and are
basically talking about the,
the one spirit that moves through all of
us.
You can call it creative spirit and I
prefer to call it something like that
rather than,
uh,
some of the names that get so heavily
weighted.
But I'm comfortable with the word God.
To me,
God means just ultimate mystery.
Yeah.
We discussed this a couple times on
previous podcasts though.
How weighted that word is.
It is.
Well,
one of the things that I think is
amazing about the Sistine Chapel,
when you're looking at the two fingers
touching,
when you're looking at all these
beautiful images,
those images,
they become what people think of when
they think of God and they think of
religion.
Those images,
they almost like it takes a form on and
in taking on that form,
it gives you a structure to house the
ideas and the ideals of these religions.
Like in seeing something,
a visual representation,
it
becomes a real thing in that.
It's an idea that's an idea that becomes
embodied by that art.
I grew up in the Jewish tradition,
which is a non iconic tradition and you
know,
this is the Christian tradition really
is.
It is a story of a person.
They were born,
they taught,
they,
they healed,
they died,
they rose.
And in the Jewish tradition there is,
it's an non embodied.
So I,
you know,
I resonated with that when I first saw
God in Lsd and it was really not a
person's face at all.
But I recognize that this is what people
are talking about when they're talking
about God,
which is this energy that's,
you know,
interconnects everything,
it's like the force more than a face.
So,
but that was my experience of God and I.
and,
and in that experience when I was 20,
I recognize this is what people are
talking about when they say God,
it's not physical.
Yeah.
Energetic.
What I'm just saying is that in this guy
creating these iconic works,
yes,
he gives it a structure.
It gives it like a scaffolding.
And in that scaffolding of these
beautiful paintings,
you can kind of like form your own
categories and have your own like
chapters in your mind that exists that
someone,
it's almost like makes those things
real.
Whether or not they ever were real,
whether or not they're ever angels on
clouds,
it's almost inconsequential because the,
the result of it is kind of the same.
If you believe that it's real.
If you believe,
and this is where religion gets so
fucking squirrely because are you saying
that Adam and eve were the only two
people in the world and everybody came
from them?
No,
absolutely not.
Are you saying that there was a snake
and he told eve?
No,
no,
no.
But if you operate your life as if those
things were reality,
and if you operate your life under the
ideals that are transcribed and
described in these beautiful paintings,
it will become a real past in the sense
that it will have a real meaning to you.
It gets real weird in that way.
And that's where I create weird art in
general.
And your art is particularly important
because the things that you paint,
you can actually see.
I've seen a lot of the things that you
paint.
Maybe not specifically,
but one of the things that I remember
when I was first introduced to some of
your art,
I am,
I saw,
I forget which one it was.
I forget what you have seen so many of
your pieces,
but I remember going,
oh,
this guy's seen it like 100 percent.
You've been there.
Like when I thought of tryptamine
experiences and I saw your art,
I was like,
oh,
this guy,
he's a.
He nailed it.
I mean,
some people have come kind of close.
They've kind of.
But even though what you're showing,
it doesn't exist in a static form,
in the tryptamine dimension,
like there's no way you can take a,
you know,
you take your phone and you take a
screenshot and you don't,
you want to,
when you're in there,
you went to press that button and say,
God is,
say that now.
That's good.
Now can I just press the movie?
How can I capture this?
Well,
the problem also is it changes every
fraction of a second.
The,
the,
the beautiful thing about the tryptamine
experiences is that whatever visual
you're experiencing right now will morph
into something else.
And it was one of the most important
lessons that I ever learned while
tripping was um,
in a dmt experience.
I had a bunch of negative thoughts.
I don't remember what they were about,
but our member,
the visions that I was having turned
dark and like do like a dark green and
black and twisted.
Like there were contorted and
compressed,
like a visual representation of negative
thinking.
And then I realized that these,
whatever these things are with entities,
thoughts,
whatever they were trying to express to
me the actual negative consequences of
thinking like that,
that it showed me in a visual form,
and then I relaxed and thought positive.
Eddie literally bloomed in front of me
like a flower and then change into this
wildly beautiful geometric pattern that
was like dancing in front of me.
And I realized at that moment like I'm,
I,
I realized to myself,
I said,
I have to remember this,
I have to remember this and I have to
figure out how to express this because
this is a,
an incredible realization that it's not
this like abstract idea that,
oh,
you think negative,
negative things happen.
Think positive.
No,
you're literally manifesting energy.
You're manifesting a certain kind of
energy with negative thinking.
Or it's one of the reasons why we like
getting away from negative people when
someone's like really negative and
complaining and whining.
He just like,
oh Jesus,
I got to get outta here.
You're like,
you really feel like they're going to
suck me in other vortex.
I've gotta I've gotta escape.
Yeah,
there's,
there is,
um,
don't see,
you could think of it like an Amoeba
around your physical body,
cloud of
pulsating thought forms and uh,
as you're imagining a,
you know,
a,
the beautiful elements of life and
things.
It's,
it seems to be in a kind of order and
uh,
and maybe kind of wafting upward it.
These are like,
uh,
the,
the spiritual positive,
uh,
kind of frameworks.
Sometimes you are seeing life through
when you're tripping,
you know,
and seeing the connections between
things lines forming and things like
that.
The,
the more kind of organic geometries
that,
that show up,
you see this intelligence of life and
the,
uh,
the light of divine intelligence that
came through for allison,
like in the language,
it seems to be weaving things together.
And when you're in touch with that
infinite light that seems to be the
source,
then that is you can keep it upwardly
moving and very evolutionarily caught
cosmically consciously moving forward.
And when then you're thinking regretful
thoughts or thinking negative thoughts
and anger and things like that.
There's a constriction that goes on in
your heart I think,
and kind of shuts things down and that
kind of,
like you were saying,
twisting in,
curling in and,
and darkening and,
and things are,
are all things that when you're
journeying,
you see them manifest literally in the
flow of your,
the theater of your imagination.
And so I think you really beautifully
described that.
Uh,
just in that I was totally there.
I think it's a disease of consciousness.
I think it's very similar to catching a
cold that,
you know,
uh,
you don't see the cold,
you don't see a disease,
you don't see it,
but it affects you.
And I think there's an analogy to be
made about diseases of consciousness
that you can get locked into these
terrible ways of looking at the world.
And I think that's one of the most
important things about what you're
trying to do in terms of building a
community.
That if you can build a community and
build a,
like a conscious ideology that that is
sort of a prescribed to people and
establish a very positive and loving
environment.
You can spread that.
Like you can spread a disease,
you know,
or for no better word,
a lot of seeds of love or whatever,
whatever you would call it.
I mean you could do it the wrong way,
you know,
you could do it what the Nazis did and
do what gang is Khan did and do it.
Some horrible people throughout history
have done similar things and a lot of
ways because there are diseases of
ideas.
They're diseases of consciousness or you
could do it the right way or a good way
or a beneficial way or positive way.
And it seems like throughout history we
almost have to see those negative ones
to learn the consequences of,
of letting these things happen.
I mean,
it's one of the reasons why Germany
won't let in the scientologists that
like,
Hey,
we've seen what happens when cults
takeover,
okay,
we've got a deep history with fucked up
group thinking,
so let's just not let you guys in.
And it's what we were talking about
before the podcast.
We were talking about trump and what's
going on in this country right now.
And I was saying that I think it's
probably a good idea to have this moment
where we realized like,
oh,
we really have to pay attention.
Like we,
we can't just sit back and not
participate anymore because liquids
happened when it's a mockery.
The hold system is like been exposed by
this one guy as being a joke.
And it's always been a joke.
It's just been a joke that we've
accepted,
you know,
and we were talking about Hillary and
all the criminal investigations that
she's under.
And that somehow or another,
this one person who we know is insincere
is a better option than this other
person who we know is a jerk off.
Like,
what?
Where's the right?
And where's the.
I don't barely been an election where
that isn't true.
I thought Obama was a pretty clear
choice and there was a lot of
celebrating afterwards.
But of course then he disappointed
people like he's predicted he would at
his inauguration.
He said,
I'm not going to make everybody happy
and you're not going to always be happy
with me.
He,
he,
he predicted that and he came through
with that.
But I remember all the elections of my
life.
It was like,
you know,
I mean,
I always voted for the least worst
person.
You know what I mean?
I mean,
I think Al Gore was,
was,
was up there.
He was really good and I,
you know,
and I actually won and he actually won
where the,
uh,
the coup took place.
Right.
There were corporate America took over.
Yeah,
it really did.
I mean that's.
Well,
it's also where the system that we're
voting under is exposed.
They're still using pieces of paper.
And then also the,
the.
Did you ever see hacking democracy,
the Hbo Hbo Documentary on the Diebold
Systems?
Oh my God.
I'm.
So,
his brother was a vice president there,
work there,
there before
they,
uh,
before they were making voting machines.
Whoa.
Yeah.
They actually changed their name after
that documentary.
Is that they establish a voting machine
where you can,
I recommend everybody watch hacking
democracy.
I think it was from,
I want to say 2007 or something like
that.
Yeah.
But it was a documentary where they
exposed that these voting machines,
not only can they be manipulated,
they were designed to be manipulated,
they were designed to have a third party
entrance,
like a third party could enter in data
and it's just madness that those
machines are how our election got
decided and you know,
they've since then cleaned it up and in
some way,
but still it's a dirty system.
Doesn't it seem like we could actually
have some encryption that each voter
could vote online?
Exactly.
And do it in a minute.
Sure.
And uh,
and we'd know.
Here's a perfect example.
Banking.
Everyone.
Banks online who,
who doesn't bank online who doesn't buy
things online,
trade credit card transactions with
people like,
Whoa,
we gets hacked.
How often?
How many people,
how?
Okay.
What percentage of it is it enough to
shift an election?
I would say it's probably not.
I would say it's not.
I would say if you could make banking
secure,
you can make voting secure phone.
They couldn't even get into that guy's
phone.
You know,
they,
you can do this and so they should do
it.
Well.
Representative government is not
necessary anymore.
We can communicate instantaneously with
people all throughout the world.
We're not talking about sending a raven,
you know,
this isn't the 13 hundreds.
This is.
This is an interesting time and we're
not taking advantage of the resources
that are available to us,
but as far as representing the actual
people,
but I think there's also a problem with
that too is there's a lot of people that
are just completely uneducated,
uninterested,
Slovenly,
lazy people and we have to energize
those people.
We have to reinvigorate their ideas of
participation.
Enough community and you have to say
like,
look,
you can't just sit on your couch and eat
twinkies and watch beverly hills
housewives.
You can't do that anymore because if you
do,
you're not allowed to complain about the
world being fucked up because you're a
part of the world being fucked up and I
think in two weeks weaken energize
people until we can give people the
sense that they actually can participate
in and it is just a bunch of human
beings that are trying to figure out the
right and the wrong way to do things.
I think there's a lot of that going on
right now.
I think there's this ebb and flow of
social media and positive aspects of it
and negative aspects of it,
but ultimately I think a lot of that is
just us learning to navigate the
landscape.
This new landscape is digital,
interconnected landscape that's
unprecedented in human history.
We don't.
I don't think we can understand it
because we're a part of it.
I mean,
I think we can sort of.
We're talking about it,
right,
but I don't think if we look back in
history and they a thousand years from
now,
look at this day,
the way we're looking at Michelangelo or
Leonardo Da Vinci or gang,
this con or anyone,
you look back and you go,
wow,
what a crazy time.
That's nothing compared to today.
Today is the craziest time ever.
The emergence of artificial
intelligence,
the emergence of a very bizarre method
of communication where you can
instantaneously reach people on the
entire planet where data is shared like
that.
Well amongst hundreds of millions of
people instantly.
It's a new world.
It's a fucking crazy new world.
It's a birth.
It is literally like a birth,
it's like an organism coming out of an
egg and poking his head out and right
now the shells being chipped and the
heads popping up,
but this fucking thing's going to merge
and it's gonna fly will turn.
Dr Dan talked about the noosphere,
you know,
about the thinking layer of the earth,
and that's really what enabled,
I mean,
you talked about it in the mid,
Mid 20th century and uh,
so this thinking layer,
a thinking atmosphere that's around the
earth now through satellites,
through
all of the,
uh,
interactive technology that we're
currently speaking on,
you know,
is a new body for the soul of humanity.
You know,
this is now,
uh,
what we're,
what we're working on now is the theo
sphere.
That's what we've got to tap and access.
Now.
We have a connectedness with each other
now as a symbol that shouldn't really
clue us into something important.
If we look at other nature systems like
the,
my celio intelligence weaves the woods
together and that we have our entire
soil and makes it alive.
Really,
uh,
these are spores a connected by fibers.
And that's what we are.
Well,
if you can explain what what's going on
in the Pacific northwest in regards to
that,
like how enormous the actual individual
organism of my sealy connection is.
And the Pacific northwest.
It's essentially like someone described
it.
I might've been Mckenna as like a
thousand gray whales.
That's how big this organism is.
And it's essentially one interconnected
mushroom.
Like,
whoa.
Yeah.
The biggest thing on earth being on
earth is a mushroom.
Exactly.
Well,
it's the oldest being as well.
You know,
we're more like mushrooms than any other
plant.
Yes,
yes.
They,
they actually breathe in oxygen and
breathe out carbon dioxide like people.
You know,
I've been incredibly fascinated over the
last few months with plant intelligence
and with plant communication and
calculations and this idea that plants
have some sort of a consciousness.
And one of the things that I've been
tripping out about is acacia trees,
where if an animal eats them and the
wind carries the scent of the Acacia
tree being consumed,
the bushes and trees downwind smell it
and become bitter so that it discourages
predation.
And animals were starving.
The downwind animals were starving
because they wouldn't eat the bushes
from the trees that had taken the scent
of the trees that were up north.
I mean,
it's madness and they were literally
sending out a signal to the other
plants,
hey,
hit the alarm.
We're getting eaten.
And they're communicating with each
other.
Absolutely.
It's the underground and overground a
network of plant intelligence.
So I think of basically the festival
culture as being mushrooms that are
growing out of the underground
intelligence graves and stuff like that.
Those are the little fruiting bodies.
Coachella though right now.
I don't know what kind of a is southwest
man.
Bernie man this summer.
I just want to tell everybody out there.
Come and be part of the Dr Bronner Foam
Dome Camp and get yourself sprayed with
foam and see us do paint our mural.
So Dr. Bronner's soap.
So we're going to be in the maps.
Brawner camp.
The maps is the multidisciplinary
association for Psychedelic Studies.
Many of us know and they have the Zendo
where people go when they need some help
and then there's also a.
wait a minute.
What's that mean though?
That's where,
you know the rangers,
when they go around and they find people
who are triple,
I'm having a bad time.
They go to the Zendo and they take care
of them.
They're,
they're,
they're helped the Zendo.
Oh yeah.
We,
we have a Zendo at cosmo.
It's,
well,
it's a place for meditating and chill
out to get away from the frenetic energy
and just have a place of peace
from that smells like feet.
It's really beautiful and it sounds
strange,
but it's made out of wood and bamboo and
cardboard.
So how do they construct that out in the
middle of the bringing in pieces and
ended up like they do everything else
there.
Wow.
How long does it take to put that
together?
People come over like a week or two
ahead of time depending on how complex
you could put together.
But we did a dome in 2006 with maps and
I'm Matt Atwood who did the
infrastructure and uh,
it was called the n theone village and
it was deadly [inaudible] village for
years.
Alex named it.
So now we have empty on growing and
causing.
But it used to be,
uh,
at,
at burning man.
But anyway,
it's.
Did you go?
No,
I don't go be around that many hippies.
It's all kinds of people.
But it is the freest place on earth.
Certainly infested with hippies though.
Let's be honest with ourselves.
Well now the people who are using
Sacramento I to take objection for a
moment and speak for the hippies
because.
Because I think that this is like one of
the last places where it's okay,
you know,
like it's no longer okay to say nigger
or queer.
Okay.
Got or you know,
to have that,
you know.
So if you're a Hippie,
maybe you could call another hippy,
a dirty hippy kind of a hippie.
I'm essentially a weird version of a
hippie.
I don't fit into the mold because I'm
also a cage fighting commentator.
The diversity and,
and you know,
the burning man used to have the genital
portraits studio and the portrait
studio.
Will you punderdome you would love was
like,
I should know.
Fuck man.
Range guns.
You should.
They have open bars
there and they're giving it all away.
The thing about burning man is it's a
gift economy,
so it's an experiment in gift economy.
You not once you get in and it caused
something to get in of course,
but once you get in it's like you don't
take your wallet out,
you can't pay for anything and there's
no bartering.
It's only gifting and people give it
away.
Yeah,
there's the thunder.
They're like nerf sticks.
It don't really hurt each other,
but they.
But they knocked them to try to knock
them off of their perch there.
Although they're swinging on those ropes
in that dome.
It's a dome frame.
Anyway,
there's all kinds.
There's 80,000 people there.
It's the best,
biggest,
most amazing environment.
It's like being on the moon.
It's like not like being nowhere else on
earth.
You have to always carry your ma,
your dust mask and your goggles and your
hair covering and your camelback.
It's so drawing that you have to be
drinking like a couple of gallons a day,
you know,
just to,
there's no insects there.
There is not a blade of any kind of life
there.
It's like walking on the moon seriously,
except you can breathe,
but you have to have a face man because
the dust storms just come up at any
moment.
It's anyone done a documentary on it
many,
many over the years.
So when you're there,
there's dudes taking cameras in your
face.
Isn't that sort of.
Do you have to have permission?
Everything is very regulated now and I
understand they're behind,
so I'm hoping they'll have some good
because they'd been.
Yeah.
That was an infrastructure where you
said that like somebody offered you a a
beautiful cake and buying land.
Land is good for our community.
We should own our own places of of
attraction because that is the way you
gain transformational power,
power to transform.
You basically have land in place and you
build that infrastructure,
this culture,
the way it's structured.
Isn't that beautiful?
It's really cool.
It really is beautiful.
The center part is called the Playa and
it's about nine feet across from from
end to end.
Like big circle,
the biggest nine miles,
feet,
nine feet,
nine miles across,
and you can walk the whole way.
A lot of people have art cars,
miles,
well from,
from edge to edge,
that's incredible.
Outer Edge.
It's managing people.
It's good.
Sixty to 80 and it's payable and
everybody takes care of each other.
You have to have your own food.
You can't.
You got to come in there with water,
food and everything and you're not
allowed to pull her or drop anything on
the ground.
If you,
if you have and they have full showers.
Broader camp is,
you know,
you get foam.
Do you know they have a big foam dome
so.
But you got to collect all that water
and they collect them in these great big
gray water tankers and take them away
and bring in fresh water.
It's like they're practicing setting up
a village in,
in light of the apocalypse.
I'm telling you this is the practice
ready?
Yeah.
These people can go in and in a week or
two.
I mean the government,
I mean the army went in there to study
this because they could do this in a
couple of weeks.
They put it all together.
So it's very much apocalyptic
preparation.
You know,
you would think you would get great
benefit from seeing it and get material
out of it.
You should come be with our camp,
you know it,
the,
it is the week that leads to Labor Day
weekend.
So that's like the first weekend of this
is the first Monday of the first Monday
of September is Labor.
So it's the weekend before the Monday of
Labor Day and they have the temple burn
is on Saturday night and Sunday night
and the man is burned on Saturday night.
So when the man is burned,
you know,
100,
800,000,
80,000 people come together to see it.
It's like everybody comes in a big
circle around the man.
Where's the man?
There he is.
I think it'd be like you're gonna get
the fuck out.
And you know what?
They have a thousand fire spinners
around the man.
You have to.
You have to audition to be a fire spin
around the man,
but they have about a thousand of them
and they're spinning whips.
My friend Joe,
they're spinning swords and poor boy and
and all kinds of Hula hoops are are on
fire.
It's the most amazing thing and you go
there on your art car,
you're not allowed to go in,
apply at all unless your car is approved
as an art car.
That means it has to be show some art
cars.
Our cars are incredible.
They've got big ships like rolling along
the Playa,
you know they have gigantic three
stories.
Structures that move to kind of be
enhancing the environment they do and
they have to be all they have to be art.
And the reason why they even do them at
all in one big way is so that you can
get on the top of them so that you can
see over everybody else.
When you go to see the man and you can
see all these fire spinners that are all
around this.
You want to be up high,
so you're part of dinosaur,
your party,
your parties up there.
It's all you got your own Dj.
Seriously,
this,
this car,
it's got its own Dj mine where Alex
painted it and we're going to be on the
Mayan Warrior this year.
Check out the line.
How does that work?
People pay year round to park these
things in,
in girl latch.
You know an outsider is the non town.
It's like this town that grew up around
Bernie man.
They have like one store,
you know,
it's like you drive into this moon like
planet.
This,
this place is where wallboard is made.
Okay?
So if you peeled off the paper,
that's what the Playa is like in.
It's like a skin.
You're not allowed to drop peanut shells
or anything on the ground and you have
to collect everything.
So it's extremely.
And
you,
you learn about saving water,
you can't believe how much you try to,
you know,
save water,
love the mine.
That's beautiful,
isn't it?
You?
What did you use to eliminate it with
all the painting is our.
We'll just click,
click on one,
stuck on it,
stop flipping around.
Just go to that show.
The mask painting area that me on all
over the course,
you know,
how do you power that thing?
They do it.
Jay do it.
They all do it.
They all have to have light on it.
You can't even have a bicycle on the
plier without leds.
But what is what is illuminating this,
I mean this is for people,
for people listening alone.
This thing is filled with beautiful
lights and this,
the flower of life is in one of them.
And what are the other ones?
The blue ones above the flower of life.
There's more flower,
the flower of life.
But also notice that there's a second
story and if you scroll down a little
bit,
you'll see there's a third story.
See those people up there.
That's loyalty.
Those are the DJ's and the royalty
royalty.
I'm just joking,
but really it's like,
you know the people who own the Mayan
warrior up there and they're best
friends.
Oh,
I thought it was your friends.
Oh No,
no,
no.
It's painted it.
It was a commission.
This.
They brought it from Mexico City on its
own trailer.
They drove it from Mexico City to cause
them.
I would've thought that it was a Trojan
horse field
border.
The border patrol have everybody out.
Well,
was all enclosed in this trail.
I was enclosed to the.
Definitely
don't worry.
We looked.
There's no Mexicans in here sneaking
across the border and will ask for your
Trojan horse.
Alex's collectors are probably
the most well meaning,
you know,
they have the most means of all Mexicans
I would say.
What are those stacks?
The stack things is two stacks.
Yeah,
it looks like Sydney blogs.
Those are speakers.
Disco,
you're all going to go deaf.
You bring your own Dj baby.
What if the music's annoying?
What kind of music are you playing?
Only cool shit.
We to see these are people that produce
our events in Mexico City and they
sponsor us going down there and doing
it,
you know,
like for events for a visit.
And we've done it a few times.
So they'll do a workshop,
they'll do a day lecture,
you know,
they'll do a and then they'll do an
evening event and given any event it's
an electronic dance music party at a
big,
a big place,
you know,
and we're on stage painting.
So these are producers that they produce
for bigger names than us.
I mean way bigger,
but we do our thing down there and so
we've got a bunch of bikes behind it as
well as that.
With that is.
Or is that people parking their bikes,
you know,
they come up,
they hey,
can we come up and have a ride
to though you to have one of these?
Some people have motor.
Well you have to have a.
well I don't know.
We'll find out there though.
Don't they give you ear beatings?
Don't they find you?
And then go.
How's
your hair covered?
Hiding.
Completely
Open.
Why do you want to have?
Well we go in and we,
we,
we paint our mural.
That's when we see our station.
You can always come and find us at the
foam dome at our 32 foot mural that will
be painting the wandering around with a
gas mask on and goggles and head dress
in the middle of a gypsum forest.
Sounds so ridiculous.
This guy,
for sure.
Some of these people are extremely
wealthy.
Looking broader.
These people.
This is the,
I would say the highest festival I've
ever been to.
That guy's definitely broke.
Guaranteed.
You must be saved up all year.
Now he's met that guy.
It looks like the alien that they found
when the movie alien.
The guy that's a guy from Google comes
to this guy from Google.
The children of the inventors.
You sound like a spokesperson for now.
We're either.
We've only been.
This will be our fifth time.
She.
Let me go back to that one.
The girl has got that blue one above
there.
The blue light one.
That seems like some industrial
strength.
Gas Mask type shit.
Seems like particle mask.
What about dust?
You have to have goggles.
I sent sense your enthusiasm.
I appreciate it,
but fuck that place.
When I was 14,
it was the first time we went.
We were invited.
Every time we've gone,
somebody who's brought us our daughters,
our daughter,
when she was 14 and we were there,
will smith goes to burning man.
A lot of freaks should use it like a
mecca.
You go watch.
It's a higher.
If you're a freak show every year,
five times.
Seems like this is a great idea in a
shitty spot and this can be recreated
somewhere habitable.
How about that?
Perfect.
In so many barriers.
The reason these are,
it's an art festival.
They make a sculpture it and they put it
on the bare ground.
It's like going into a white gallery,
you know,
it's like going into like a white out
and then you put an object there and
frankly you've got a lot of space around
it so you can really look at any man's
sculpture,
sculpture.
It's about seeing the art,
so it's not for everybody.
I think that it's an extraordinary,
a outgrowth of visionary culture.
I'm totally joking around obviously when
I'm mocking it,
but that's my nature.
This fire fire before know we.
We were.
We have a sculpture at cars and that was
on the plier to two stories sculpture at
at and we're getting another one.
People with them afterwards,
they went someplace to put them.
Will cause them.
Has 40 acres,
so we're gonna end up with probably more
so they're going to ship burning man
sculptures.
We do that.
Oh,
you going to ship it to us?
We pay for it.
That's amazing.
That and it that.
That's incredible.
And you go out there and you just visit
all these sculptures.
It's nine miles of sculpture.
You just go ride your bike from
sculpture to sculpture.
Many of them,
most of them are interactive so you can
go inside of them.
You can climb up in them.
They sometimes they have swings and a
lot of them have fire coming out.
That's incredible because you can.
You can light things on fire there.
That's what makes it so exciting to us.
This is the Belgium,
the Belgian waffles,
Kate,
Kate Rod,
which sculptured cause what?
Cade Rod,
but she does a laser cut cold rolled
steel sculptures that are,
that are interacting with their pods.
You sit in them,
they're real comfy there.
Oh,
this is amazing.
We're looking at,
for people that are listening,
we're looking at Mars.
One,
look at verse one,
sculpture.
For people that are listening,
we're looking at this geometric object
that's circular,
but it's got squared edges.
What would you call that?
What does that,
what does that a sacred geometric form.
And these guys are.
They're from San Francisco.
We know these guys.
Um,
and this,
whatever this geometric form is,
what's making my chandelier?
This?
Yes,
they're making my chandelier's for,
for Ian.
I'm going to have chandelier's,
uh,
that were light where they turn and the
light falls on people.
It's environmental.
It's called Jamie a fest.
Three hundred a sneak peek at the
coolest art coming to burning man.
So you could see this,
uh,
online.
If you go google it,
it's really stunning.
This image.
Okay.
So there's a magazine that has a bunch
of these images.
Oh God,
that's amazing.
That's cool.
Almost worth going.
Yeah.
Maybe if you bring a big tour bus,
bring an Rv,
you little.
You don't want to come,
Joe,
if that.
You want to come with him.
Are you
kidding?
No,
we don't care.
How long does it take to get out there?
Where is it?
Let's see.
Tens of thousands of people do come
from.
Where is it?
It's a black rock city out in about an
hour from Reno,
Nevada.
It's probably got a lot of nuclear
energy out there,
right?
I will do those tests you ever see that?
Um,
the animated Gif.
It's like a little movie of all the
nuclear tests
that they've done in Nevada
might explain a lot about what's going
on out there.
I've done hundreds of them just to,
to digital digital.
They did this thing from like 1940,
whatever it was the time when they
detonated the first atomic bomb to
present at the bottom of a see that once
was made of crushed shell and you know,
it feels like sand,
but if you walk on it,
he won't be able to use your feet in the
middle of the winter.
That's what I'm saying is if you're out
of your feet,
you won't be able to use your feet in
the middle of the winter.
Tracking the cracking.
Even in the middle of winter.
I did it once.
I'm just telling you it,
it,
it.
I had to walk back from the man to our
camp without any shoes because I lost my
shoes and I walked back through and it
feels like sand at first,
but then it's like knives.
He likes little tiny little knives.
They're like shells.
It's like crushed,
crushed shells and it messed up your
feet and all winter I was dealing with
cracked feet,
happy feet burning.
See you have to wear boots and really
cover and it gets to be like 110 degrees
in the day and 40 degrees at night.
Sounds like you're trying to keep me off
trying to keep me off the thing.
We're building a place at caution that
is going to how some of the sculptures
and have little sculptural areas,
so we have these small gatherings by
comparison to that.
They'll never be huge like that though,
but hundreds of people will gather so it
can still feel kind of tribal and
community oriented,
but a lot of the same music is enjoyed.
We always have fire circle and we always
have fire spinning.
We actually teach fire spinning it cause
of getting,
not of hand like fire.
All that fire spinning around there.
Those people are the most cautious.
And we also have a relationship with the
fire department.
They're in our town.
We have a sheriff on property,
uh,
at the,
at each event where there are large
numbers of people.
And so we,
you know,
safety first,
but there's ways of doing it.
So when do you anticipate this entire
thing?
The entire cause of them.
We should tell everybody.
That means chapel of sacred mirrors.
That's what caused them stands for.
And when do you anticipate that being
fully operational and
inaction?
Well,
right now it is open.
We're open like four days a week so that
people,
we have an ongoing stream of people who
just are visitors and there are a small
art exhibits that are on display now.
We're working on anthon.
That's where the grand exhibit will be
housed and they exhibit that we had on
display for five years in the city that
is not currently on display.
The sacred marriage are not there,
but they will be in the new space.
And so the new space,
as we said,
we're thinking we'll open sometime in
2017 probably toward the end of the year
and then,
uh,
as,
as we can,
we will build the outside of it,
you know,
the sculpture,
it's just a matter of how many years
it's gonna take.
It's gonna probably take a few years ago
when the power go lotto.
Yeah.
Then you were able to do.
Donations can come in all these things.
We get donations.
I think all these things can happen.
I mean,
the kickstarter thing.
Look Joe,
you were really helpful to us when the
last time we did the podcast,
there was definitely a Rogan bump that
happened to the kickstarter that took us
to a new level.
Say good news is that there's probably
what,
how many more million people listening
know,
like how many years ago was it that you
guys came on last three years?
So that was,
we're getting pilot 4 million downloads
a month,
probably tripled that night,
I'd say three years ago at least triple.
And then with the youtube.
Youtube.
Yeah.
So let's say we're in the neighborhood
of 30 million downloads a month.
Joining us and being a temple builder,
joining us,
um,
I think that there's going to be a lot
of people that are excited about it.
I think what the idea behind it is
beautiful.
The idea that you guys are leaving it
for the community and building it for
the community.
Beautiful.
And uh,
that's one of the best arguments for
religion that I've ever heard and best
arguments for having a religion be tax
exempt that I've ever heard.
I mean,
you guys are literally doing it for
other people and you're doing it for
everybody.
It's awesome.
And you know,
your artwork is just a huge fan of what
you do.
And I just think that the design itself
is literally,
like I said,
probably the coolest building on the
planet and it's a real.
I mean,
what you're doing is essentially an
extension of the great works of all
these,
you know,
when you're talking about the sistine
chapel or if you're talking about the
Egyptian pyramids or any of these sacred
sites that exist all throughout the
world.
You're doing a modern version of that
and it's,
it's amazing.
It's really,
really cool.
50 greatest works I think will be on
view there in their original form,
but the actual paintings that alex roped
with his own hand and some of them have
become really iconic to people.
There are a lot of people out there that
have Alex's posters and tee shirts.
Oh,
I have a bunch of plays and everything.
But to see the originals,
that's a study for other artists,
clay,
the prints that a lot of people have,
the limited edition prints that they
have of paintings that wonderful labor
intensive artists is made.
I've never heard that word or that word,
limited edition prints that I've read
it.
I just thought that was like leaky or
something.
Well,
the other thing about anthem
is that it's going to display the work
of the International Visionary Art
Movement.
And uh,
these are,
I mean,
if you liked my stuff,
you should see some of the young people
that are making art out of their
journeys.
Now they're,
you know,
they're evolving beyond,
my work.
And uh,
also I think they're building an
encyclopedia of these dimensions of
altered states that people can say it
was something like that,
but it's very specific in that if you go
back before the 19 sixties and you look
at the art really didn't represent the
trips.
It,
it just didn't.
Um,
and you look at it now,
there's a giant body of art that
represents these psychedelic trips that
really didn't exist before.
So in a lot of ways it is a quiet new
chapter in the world of art that one day
I think people are gonna look back on.
And once we realize the ridiculousness
of the prohibition on drugs,
especially on psychedelic drugs,
nontoxic,
non-problematic as far as like health
repercussions.
And you wonder like what,
what was it about our restrictive
society that put this sweeping
comprehensive ban on psychedelic
substances in 1970 and what were the
ramifications?
What was,
what were the consequences on society?
So there was no organic,
there was no eco eco careers,
there was,
there was no,
you know,
save the planet,
talk climate change.
We never heard about that.
Growing up.
There was,
there was people that were talking about
it and they were circling,
certainly people that we're recycling
and composting and doing things along
those lines and trying to leave a
smaller footprint back then aware of it,
but as far as a gigantic global
conscious movement and also the urgency
that's attached to it today where people
are stepping back and they're looking at
islands disappearing and you know,
they're looking at the rising sea levels
and they go,
well blah blah blah,
blah,
blah.
This is real.
This is actually happening inside of our
lifetime.
There's a lot going on that I think
we're,
we're in the middle of and I think this
visionary art that,
that is going on right now,
we're sort of in the middle of that.
I think as we look back on it,
or as people passed us,
look back on it,
they're going to say,
this is a very specific era.
This was an era.
Like if you go back and look at
religious history and you look at the,
um,
the enlightenment and you look at the
various styles of art that's connected
to religion or cultural change,
you know,
you see these big shifts.
I think the visionary art of
Psychedelics is a big shift.
It's huge.
Yeah.
I think that it's the,
it's showing that the big news today is
the Sacramento,
uh,
sort of reformation.
You know,
that there's a return of the sacrament
to the West.
It's been demonized and hidden for
thousands of years.
Now it's back and you're not going to
get rid of it.
Now it's here because we need it.
There's nothing that's going to turn
consciousness around toward a sacred
planet that wants to save itself from
self destruction like psychedelics.
There is no greater prescription,
uh,
for soul medicine.
Then this is the stuff that is curing
all of the traumatic stress of,
of the vets,
you know,
marijuana is part a,
is leading the way in the medicinals and
opening the door literally for the
sacred drugs,
the return of the sacred drugs.
Now we don't even have a context a
established in America,
but it's beginning,
you know,
the UDV church one,
their right to use the sacrament.
The native American church has pod.
There is legal precedent for religious
use already.
The best there has been throughout
history except for the last couple
thousand years.
Well in,
uh,
in this country,
as you were talking about with Mtma,
I mean,
just a really the last few decades.
Yeah.
And I'm five methoxy dimethyltryptamine
and I bought that stuff online,
like in the 2001 or something like that.
You can just order it from some chemical
company.
They sent you a bottle of it and get the
whole world hot.
I remember that.
Yeah,
it was great times it.
Yes it was.
And uh,
somehow we've got to find a way to
incorporate these sacraments.
I think they're being incorporated.
And I think one of the things that you
said that you just sort of glossed over,
but it's incredibly important is that
marijuana is the door opener.
Yeah.
Marijuana is the guy that you let into
the party that has the magic dust and
they went and he blew it on everybody
because once that gets in and especially
edible marijuana,
edible marijuana is a psychedelic drug
and many people don't know it.
And that's one of the reasons why when
people eat brownies or something,
they'll say,
oh my God,
someone laced the Brownie.
No,
that's what it is.
That,
that is the most potent form of
marijuana is the editable form of
marijuana.
And it is very visionary and especially
in high doses,
it's incredibly introspective acid,
like in a lot of ways you know,
you,
you get a perspective that is life
changing and shifting and it's one of
those directional shifts where even if
it's a small degree of change over the
course of the rest of your life,
that small degree of change could equal
a very large shift in the direction that
you're going as you continue down your
path.
That slight turn to the right will make
a huge difference five years from now,
10 years from now,
I think marijuana becoming legal in
Colorado and we are seeing not just the
positive benefits in terms of the
community you're looking at that are
making way more money than they've ever
made before.
You're looking at housing prices,
real estate prices going up.
People having a new sense of community
where they like,
oh,
there's others like us.
It's like a magnet for freaks and
they've all flown into Colorado and set
up shop there.
It's fascinating.
I did a show there a couple months ago
at the Belko theater and it was amazing.
It was like this place has changed in a
year.
I recorded my last comedy special.
I'm about two years ago,
two years in August in Colorado,
and then I did the most recent one about
six months ago in Colorado.
The most recent show that I did there,
and I could feel the shift when you
driving down the street,
you see the difference.
There's pot everywhere.
There's people are smiling.
The lowest incidence of drunk driving.
They've ever recorded.
Lowest incidents of violent crime.
Everything is dropping suicide rates.
Yes,
and money.
Money that the state is making isn't
insane.
They literally,
you have a surplus of taxes.
It's an attractor.
They've made more money from taxes from
marijuana than they did from alcohol for
the first time ever.
No one's ever done that,
and you've got this happy community and
now Seattle is entered into the mix.
Now Washington DC's enter into the
Mexican November.
California's going to vote on it.
I guarantee it's going to go through it.
Oh yes,
of course it is.
Try to extend a little blessing New York
way.
Okay.
Because New York is so far behind.
I'm so ashamed of us.
Come on.
We got to move into action and our
people little happen.
Just love it so much.
I think that just the.
The ideologies that are were in place
that stopped it.
There roading.
Those people are too old.
They're too out of touch.
They don't understand the mindset of the
young people and they've really
underestimated the power of this
movement.
They.
This is a wave and you can't suppress it
anymore.
You can't lose of people that are
upwardly spiraling.
Okay.
The people that are healthy,
all positive ecological,
save the planet educated more thinking.
It's such an attractor and so everybody
wants to be part of.
They wonder what's.
What is that?
We'll have a power.
It's what we were talking about earlier
when we're talking about plant
intelligence,
there is an intelligence in marijuana
and absolute undoubted intelligence when
it exists.
I think in all plants that exists in
funguses as not that
not all plants are mirroring systems
inside of the human body like cannabis,
since it was the probably the original
or one of the original culture
cultivated plants.
I think that humanity over the millennia
worked out a symbiotic relationship with
this plant and so we have the
endocannabinoid system and then the,
uh,
and I would say that probably many of
our health deficiencies are because
we're not getting our cannabis thc
efficiencies and uh,
no.
Well,
let's try.
The Ama in the thirties went to Congress
and said,
please don't make cannabis illegal.
It's in half of our Madison,
you know,
for 87 years.
It's been part of the American
Pharmacopia.
Please allow us to continue to use it.
No,
it was struck down and so it's been
repressed a sense then.
And a lot of it has just been pure
racism actually.
That's the cause of it.
Well,
that was what those recent papers were
released about the Nixon administration.
That's one of the ways they demonize the
black rights movement,
civil rights movement,
and also the antiwar movement is they
attack marijuana and they attacked
psychedelic drugs and that was the
reason why they pass that sweeping
legislation in the first place,
was just to be able to have a reason to
arrest those people.
They knew they could attack the
communities and attacking those
communities.
The best way to do it was to go after
the drugs next and hated them.
And Nixon was a traitor to America.
Nixon was probably with Bush,
one of the worst we've ever experienced.
And through his hatred and venom,
we have the drug war that now for over
40 years,
we've just been laboring under the boot
of a fascist trader that want resigned
from office.
He was,
he was,
he was impeached really?
And that I wanted to say,
go back to what you were saying about
fungus,
because people sometimes ask,
what does l,
what is Lsd,
what does it,
what does it look like?
What is it?
And I wanted to mentioned that,
uh,
recently there's microscopic images of
what it is,
is it's fungus growing on Rye.
So there's these microscopic images that
you can call up and look at that.
See the LSD.
It looks like a field of little tiny
mushrooms.
That's all just microscopic.
Well,
do you remember the,
um,
the revelation that they had the few,
few years back when they were trying to
figure out what caused the Salem witch
trials and one of the leading theories
was that they had had a late frost and
the late frost had caused these funguses
to bread,
herbal or God to grow on bread and that
when that happened,
these people were experiencing very acid
like effects from eating bread.
And then they started freaking out and
blaming people for it and thinking that
they were being possessed.
And it was a whole wave of paranoia that
came from that unbelievably fascinating.
When you think about it that way,
it really is.
It's actually the,
uh,
to be cured from ergotism.
Um,
this,
uh,
Bishop,
Flo bear,
he was responsible for sharp cathedral
a thousand years ago,
basically prayed to Mary and said,
if you'll cure me of this ergotism,
uh,
which is very dangerous,
but it leaves so many visions,
I will build you the most beautiful
tempo ever built,
you know?
And so he was cured and he did found a
sharp cathedral.
But,
uh,
as a result.
So that's one of the core things about
ergotism Ergot,
but the coolest thing is definitely lsd
and Hoffman's ability to stabilize that.
Uh,
yeah.
and then,
so basically the coolest thing about the
psychedelics to me is that they,
uh,
in the end,
the science that has been done as the
Good Friday experiment and Roland
Griffiths work and that has basically
given us the best evidence for the
existence of God because 65 percent of
people who take psilocybin in it safe,
set and setting in there spiritually
inclined,
we'll have a full blown mystical
experience that's now science.
It's proven.
So a majority of people who take a
psychedelic basically in a positive
setting and they don't know,
they're not a priest gets sold
themselves,
you know,
not a borderline personality.
If you're stable,
priest gets zone.
Yeah.
That's important to put out.
You know,
because I think that a lot of people
think that psychedelics are for
everybody,
but they're not.
Unfortunately,
there's some folks amongst us that have
a very difficult time with just regular
stable sobriety and mental issues.
No,
but I think in the end they're going to,
with science,
with medicine and science,
I think what's going to be found out is
that,
uh,
these psychedelics are going to cure
schizophrenia.
I really think that when they,
when they use it properly,
because that's what the science is doing
now,
they're experimenting with all kinds of,
with schizophrenia what science is,
if there's any studies with
schizophrenia.
But I,
I,
because it mirrors schizophrenia,
it may be,
um,
I don't know.
I think that research will be done
related to all kinds of psychological
illness and um,
but anyway,
it's curing so many things that can cure
a cluster headaches.
And the studies are,
you know,
like Harvard,
Yale,
Johns Hopkins,
all that big,
all the big universities that can,
that maps can get funding for their
funding.
All that
maps is really fascinating and amazing.
And what they've done is just add a,
a,
an actual intellectual perspective on
psychedelic drugs and undeniably
researched really well documented
perspective.
That's so important.
When I had,
um,
my first experiences with,
with maps,
I remember thinking like,
thank God there's someone like this out
there.
Some someone like Doblin out there,
Rick Doblin,
who has taken the super intelligent
approach to recognizing what
these substances are and what are the
positive benefits are and how can you
get these things slowly but surely
through the legal system and that's what
they're doing now with Mtma.
That's what they're doing now with the
studies that they're doing on a soldiers
with posttraumatic stress disorder and
all sorts of other people to police
officers.
Anybody rape victims?
Yeah.
Violence victims.
I think that's,
it's so important.
It's just the,
these are really beneficial things that
were being denied and were being denied
by people who haven't experienced them,
which is the most ironic aspect of it.
It's like something having penicillin,
but they won't let you try it.
Yeah.
Because,
you know,
they don't use it themselves and we know
that such things as Ibogaine exist.
There is a way to interrupt opioid,
uh,
addiction and the addiction process.
This is a potential cure for,
uh,
the many millions of people who are
currently opiate addicted.
Ibogaine therapy has been working out
miraculous results for people.
It helps them turn around their lives
and,
uh,
to uh,
stop needing the chunk two to three
days.
Yeah.
That's,
it's a treatment.
It's literally miraculous.
We know it exists.
It's a,
you know,
the Department of Defense.
So how to be using it for our poor fats
that have returned from an unrighteous
battle.
The whole cause of their suicidal
behavior,
I believe is because they were told to
go buy into an unrighteous battle.
It was a war waged on lies and only to
create basically to kick a kick the
Hornet's nest,
you know,
to keep an endless war going.
It's working pretty good.
Well,
posttraumatic stress disorder.
What's really fascinating about it is
that there's this reaction to stress too
intense stress,
traumatic situations and that your body
has.
This is almost this intense anticipation
of a constant battle of constant stress
and that that can be interrupted and
that this is.
There's really no other method.
I mean,
you can go to therapy all your life and
slowly perhaps slowly erode the memories
of this and give yourself some
psychological tools to manage these
experiences.
But as far as like something that can
sort of stop it in its tracks,
there's never been anything that's
demonstrated that has the power of
psychedelics.
Post traumatic
stress disorder studies are showing that
85 percent of vets that have at and are
otherwise untreatable are,
are having success after one treatment
and maps got a grant to do a second and
third trial.
That means that people 15 percent who
didn't,
uh,
you know,
really feel relief from posttraumatic
stress disorder,
get a second turn and a third term.
So it's,
it's amazing,
uh,
many
the substance,
but it's the psychological therapy
relationship.
Well,
it's also the reset,
the reset,
the control,
alt delete for the mind,
the resetting of the consciousness that
I think so many of us operate on
momentum.
We operate on the momentum of our past
and that's all we know.
And that's sort of the,
the,
we,
we were,
were connected to that momentum,
like a safety blanket.
Like we,
we believe that this momentum equals the
future.
And then it's very difficult to get out
of those grooves that are so deeply
carved in our consciousness.
That's right.
And almost nothing does it,
but MTMA will allow you to get that
distance and a for you.
And in order for you to,
uh,
transform out of a phase,
you know,
the psychologist basically say that you
have to be able to look at your
subjective state from an ob,
you know,
another objective observation on that
subjective state.
And so that's literally what's happening
with the,
uh,
Mtma your distanced from it.
You can look at your behavior or your,
uh,
what happened to you in,
with more dispassion.
You can have compassion on yourself,
you know,
and,
uh,
start to forgive everyone involved.
And it's,
it's a miraculous,
uh,
and life changing,
which then leads to new neuro growth,
uh,
in both suicide and a MDM May.
They've been charting that there is new
neuropathways.
Uh,
not only does it just feel it that way,
but it literally is that way is changing
your minds,
changing your brain and your mind.
Alright folks,
the kickstarter,
tell people Jamie,
put that stuff up on the screen.
Show people how to get to it.
And if you could give out the url
builder.com,
build and theone.com,
e n t h e o n.com build and theone.com
three bunkers liquid.
Whether those folks a hundred and twenty
two thousand six hundred twenty six
thousand dollars is already pledged em.
Yeah,
it's calming.
Wonderful Art.
Great rewards.
And we will put this up on twitter today
and we'll put it up on facebook today
and we'll let everybody know what.
You guys are.
Awesome too.
Appreciate you very much.
All Right Ladies and gentlemen,
we'll be back tomorrow with Alison
Rosen.
Take care.
See you soon.
Blah Blah.