Her low freak bitches.
I trademarked it because I said,
you know what it was,
it was starting to like,
you know,
physio when I was like,
I was really passionate about it because
it's something I was saying again.
I didn't have nobody around me,
no.
Used to have friends with me all the
time.
I'm training,
whatever,
whatever.
They all left.
They was always moved on.
So for me,
I was like,
no entourage,
nobody to push me.
I got to push myself.
So I started talking to myself,
something that I ever did.
And that's a whole nother story.
I wanna tell you in the book why I
refuse to talk to myself.
Why does your feet tell me?
I was saving it for book talking,
but I'm still really,
I'm selling the book,
man.
Let me know.
Put up links.
If we go in that route,
then I already know.
Come on Doug.
But no,
the reason why is because,
um,
I had an uncle,
my mother's brother Anthony Par Ham.
He was her only brother.
He went to the military,
he went to the Vietnam war as a child.
You know,
he's a young man,
18 years old.
When he left high school,
he didn't have to because it was all
sisters and he wanted to because he
wanted to go because everyone in the
rented town,
Petersburg,
Virginia,
excuse me,
Jarret,
Virginia,
everybody from his town,
the young men will go on its own cousins
and everybody.
So he went,
he came back,
um,
disturbed.
He came back different than when he went
in and he was actually missing for quite
a time that they were going to declare
him dead when he showed up one day,
um,
with a trench coat on army boots and
naked and hosie street in Brooklyn.
So this led to him being mentally
disturbed all my life.
He would talk to himself.
He lived with us.
I slept in a twin bed here and he slept
in the bed there and he was with
alcohol.
He drank,
he became very violent.
You know,
he beat my mom up one time really bad
cause I had eyes up and him talking to
himself with something.
I grew up all my life watching and I'm
like,
amy crazy.
You called amy amy,
you crazy.
You can't.
He told me to itself so,
and I got older,
I would just refuse to even have a
conversation with myself.
Oh you crazy if you,
and four years ago I started having
conversations with myself.
I was like,
Yo,
you know what champ,
you got to go.
And I start saying,
let's go champ.
And I was like,
ma'am,
I asked,
my wife was so you think I'm crazy cause
I spoke.
She was like,
yeah,
we already know you crazy.
You know what I mean?
So I'm like,
you know,
and it just,
and that was my mantra.
It became my mantra.
You know,
my friend told me one of his mantras was
to be the man,
you've got to be the man.
When he was tired,
he was running mile 18 to beat a man,
you've got to beat the man,
be the man.
You gotta beat a man.
I was just saying to himself and I was
like,
you know,
I need a mantra,
and I was hitting the bag one day and I
was tired.
I was like 400 pounds.
I was like,
let's go champ.
That's gonna Chair.
That's her chair.
You know,
and it's in the head champ.
You know when I'm feeling pain,
you feel in pain,
you're feeling down.
Tell yourself,
let's go champ.
Let's go champ.
To what I hear you when I work out.
Sometimes it's yours.
I thought she didn't push it through and
set as yours.
It's yours.
It's everybody's.
It's the people's man.
The people.
The people gave me this,
the universe gave me this,
that people,
the people
linked into it and it's not mine,
it's ours.
We just want to give each other
positivity and love and I meet people
from everywhere.
Chan,
I'm a little nuts because I go to every
city or country and people say,
chair,
but I'm in the lobby or I'm in this
town.
Could I meet you?
And I say,
come over to the hotel.
And they come.
You know what I mean?
They call.
I mean,
you might have to stop that when you
went a people.
I'm the people's champ.
I'm free.
I'm here for the people.
Wow,
man,
that's strong.
Uh,
things.
And when I went to,
I interview Senator Mark Pocan last week
about,
he was the one that wrote a letter to
the government.
He wants to keep Kratom legal.
He thinks that,
you know,
it should be allowed for everyone.
And I said to him,
what do you think about marijuana?
And he was like,
I just think it should all be legal.
And it was the first time I was ever in
the presence of somebody that works for
the government saying that they think
that weed and Kratom and all this stuff
should be illegal.
And it's because he had a good head on
his shoulders about the problems that
people face every day.
You know,
it's not black and white.
Like I live in this gray area,
I don't,
I,
I'm in a lot of pain,
but I don't want to take opiates and I
shouldn't have to take opiates.
So where's the pressure coming from to
turn this stuff into a schedule one
drug?
If there's no,
if there's no negative response by the
body,
you're not having people die of
overdoses.
Is there an ld 50 rate on this stuff?
Well,
if you look at it,
you know,
I mean you're saying where,
where's the ld 50 explained?
We should probably explain to people
lethal dose at 50% meaning if you take
50 rats and you give them a pound of
this shit,
50 of them are 25 and die at a certain
show.
We've heard about,
you know,
there's been no deaths from marijuana,
right?
Right.
Yeah.
Freedom is the same thing.
No,
no deaths.
There have been zero deaths and there,
there have actually been 15 deaths that
have been brought to the FDA and the dea
is attention.
Those 15 that's,
I actually went and interviewed one of
the,
one of the mothers,
the kid was on three psych meds.
He was withdrawn.
He was honored with withdrawing from
three different psych meds.
I have a black box warning that says,
warning,
if you're a teenager,
you might commit suicide.
Basically,
and this kid committed suicide.
He didn't die from a Kratom overdose.
He died from committing suicide.
And his mother wants to blame Kratom.
She doesn't think that the,
uh,
the psych meds had anything to do with
it.
And I don't want to say that Kratom had
nothing to do with it.
We don't really know.
And what I really call for with Kratom
is just more research.
Like I want people to put in the money
to do the research,
to make sure that this is safe.
And let's see if we can solve this
opiate epidemic.
Let's see if we can crack down.
You know,
basically lower the amount of opiate
prescriptions we have in this country.
I just read an article the other day.
One in seven people in America are going
to be affected with addiction problems.
Wow,
that's crazy.
One in seven.
Yeah.
That means somebody in your family,
that's insane.
Somebody in your family will be be
affected by it.
And that's 10% yeah,
that's weird.
[inaudible].