The Joe Rogan experience,
Joe Rogan podcast all day.
The everybody Zol Taiwan.
Is that correct way to say it?
Perfect.
Istvan.
I do it right.
Perfect.
Nailed it.
Now,
when you're a guy who's a trans humanism
expert,
and you sound like a robot,
you're names.
I mean Zoltan you sound like,
oh,
like an evil robot from another planet.
I mean,
the name sounds like no one,
no insult meant no,
no,
of course,
of course.
You know,
it's,
it's a pretty bizarre name.
Esoteric in America.
Strangely enough.
It's the most common Hungarian name is a
really.
Yeah.
So like you say in a movie theater in a
hungry,
you get five people to turn around.
So,
uh,
but,
you know,
in America,
yeah,
it sounds a bit.
Spend a bit spacey.
So Zoltan is like the equivalent of joe
exact because like when someone says
Joe,
like if you're in a crowd,
I assume it's someone else always.
There's just so many.
Damn Joe's.
So Zoltan is the Hungarian Joe.
Yeah.
And it's,
it's,
it's amazing.
You save on the street and you'll get
people turning around for sure.
Now,
um,
that's,
uh,
it's very funny though that your name is
Zoltan and you are a trans humanism
expert.
I mean it's,
the irony cannot be lost on you in that.
No,
and a lot of the median points that out
too because uh,
it is,
uh,
you know,
I'm pushing ideas that are pretty
bizarre.
There are certainly far out there and in
the name sort of just emphasizes that
aspect of it.
What do you think when it comes to this?
So this is a very controversial subject
because I think there's a lot of people
that are resisting the inevitability of
this,
uh,
this relationship that we have to
technology the,
the continuation of this inevitable
relationship.
There's a lot of people that for
whatever reason don't like it.
They want things,
they want to go back to chopping wood.
And it just,
it seems like there's some people that
are digging in their heels when it comes
to technological progress.
What do you think is like one of the big
reasons for that?
Well,
I think anything that's foreign to
people sort of scares them.
And as human beings,
we have a kind of a biological
propensity to just take our time and
adapting.
And unless it's like a snake in the
grass,
people don't react really quickly.
People tend to like want to take it all
in,
discuss it with their family,
their friends,
government and whatnot.
And so we have this huge,
almost like I would say,
a paradigm shift about to occur where,
you know,
we're doing things like already starting
to put microchips in people's heads.
We're uh,
you know,
we can take photos from the atmosphere
and look at ourselves.
It's surveillance issues.
I mean,
this is all drone use.
there's a million different things going
on with technology and science and it's
coming so fast so quickly.
It's scaring a lot of people.
People that not normally be
so frightened if it was like
individually had come at some separate
time,
but it's just coming all at once.
And uh,
you know,
just even looking at the equipment in
this room,
you know,
even 10 years ago,
a lot of this wasn't like it was.
And so,
uh,
you know,
if you're not accustomed to it or if
you're a little bit afraid of some of
the change you might back off from and
say,
well,
what is this?
This is too weird.
But,
um,
you know,
for those of us who love it and who see
it as very useful and functional and
improving wellbeing and health,
uh,
this type of technology,
this type of change is,
is,
is really great.
Do you have any apprehensions at all
about the,
the sort of exponential growth of
technology?
Well,
I certainly have lots of apprehension.
I think the biggest thing I'm worried
about,
and you've been hearing about this in
the news recently is,
is artificial intelligence.
This idea that there'll be another
entity on the planet that is smarter or
smarter than us,
equal to us,
this kind of thing and could potentially
become so much smarter than us in such a
short time that it could literally
literally changed the way you know,
our earth actually is.
And um,
I've also done a controls all the
machines in this room and all the
airplanes and stuff like that.
For whatever reason,
it could certainly stop the earth,
I'd say out or at least progress and as
we know it.
Is that a good thing?
Is that a bad thing?
These are.
These are very touchy and difficult
questions,
but the thing about it is certainly
scary and that's the one thing that I've
kind of agreed with a lot of the experts
lately saying that,
yeah,
we probably need to have some type of
oversight.
I was recently at a speaking on an
artificial intelligence and singularity
conference and that we were on a panel
of five experts talking about ai and a,
someone asked,
well,
who is regulating artificial
intelligence development?
And all the experts had no one said
anything because no one said there
really is anything regulating this idea
that may be and potentially eight to 12,
probably 20 years there will be this
entity that's smarter than us on planet
Earth.
That,
that seems a little bit of a disconnect.
I don't really like regular in
regulatory things,
but um,
maybe for this one is something we'd
have to.
So I have a lot of apprehension when it
comes to that single concept,
but most of the other technologies I
think um,
as long as the historically they are
increasing life spans and are making
people live better,
poverty is going down across the world
because of technology.
So,
uh,
from a statistical point of view,
technology has helped and I'm pretty
pretty sure it's going to continue to do
that,
especially if it's made kind of freely
available to everyone.
It seems like there's two schools of
thought when it comes to artificial
intelligence is the Elon musk school
where he's like,
you know,
hey,
we might be summoning the demon.
I mean that was his exact quote,
which is terrifying.
And then there's the other school of
thought where people are saying like,
you don't need to worry about it because
they will only react in the way that we
programmed them to react.
That when we create some sort of an
artificial life form that will have very
strict
parameters of what it can and can't do.
You know,
we've seen that in science fiction
movies before.
Like they have a protocol if they can't
harm human beings,
you know,
they have these,
these things that are programmed into
their behavior patterns that cannot be
overridden.
But I think the real concern,
at least my real concern is that we are
giving birth to this new superior form
of life.
And then the way I've described it is
that we're essentially a caterpillar
that doesn't recognize that it's going
to become a butterfly.
That we are toiling away creating this
ant hill or whatever we're doing.
We're.
We're just involved in this constant
growth,
constant technological innovation
process.
And we don't even realize that.
Our whole purpose here was to create
this new thing was to create this new
life form.
Now.
And I'm a big proponent of that entire
idea because as I point out in my,
my book,
the transhumanist wager,
a lot of what evolution is going towards
is not what we think it's going or what
we wanted
to go towards.
Which is,
you know,
human beings,
family,
all the institutions of marriage and
stuff like that.
Continuing.
I actually think what evolution has
really been leading to is the creation
of a,
a really incredible superpower,
a,
I don't want to say God,
but something that has omnipotence,
something that is something that is
perfect and it's in its form,
the universe just becoming alive through
us.
And,
you know,
we're very early in the process of that.
I would say we're,
you know,
I don't know,
five,
10 percent along along the way.
We're just kind of kids in the universe.
But,
um,
the idea is eventually,
uh,
artificial intelligence and,
you know,
the key,
the way I worked through my apprehension
of artificial intelligence is I would
like to merge with it.
I would like to have it so that we could
connect it through a neural implants or
whatever it's going to be into the
machines.
So it's not like the machine's leave us.
It's like we leave with the machines and
that's the natural state of evolution.
Therefore we actually become that and
it's like you said,
you know,
the Caterpillar idea where the butterfly
actually then becomes something else.
And that's where I see not only humanity
going,
but also,
um,
the,
the kind of evolutionary course of the
universe which is sort of moving towards
this a much more incredible of an
intelligence,
incredible energy forums.
Whatever it is that's going to end up.
I think we're going to end up being done
the most important things that humans
don't.
Don't
miss the train.
I wonder if one of the things that
people are concerned with is that we
enjoy a lot of our flaws and if,
if we keep improving,
if technology comes along and gets to
the point where a human being becomes
free of any irrational thoughts,
free of irrational emotions are.
And maybe even any emotions we were
missing out on rock and roll.
We're missing out on Charles Bukowski.
We're missing out on,
you know,
muscle,
all the stupid
shit that makes life fun.
It's going to be like completely
irrelevant.
And we're not gonna.
No one's gonna be getting drunk.
No one's going to be making dirty jokes.
We're going to miss out on like fast
food,
like ridiculous ice cream Sundaes.
You,
you know what I mean?
It's like there's a lot that we enjoy
about life that is ultimately ridiculous
and as we continue to get smarter and as
technology takes us to this point where
we can kind of eliminate a lot of the
biological protocols that are in place,
that's,
that caused these flaws,
what will we be left with will be these
weird robot creatures now.
And this is one of the most,
I think,
important philosophical dilemmas of the
kind of thing I just spoke about where
we're evolving into some type of
incredible intelligence is what if it's
super boring,
you know?
And what if it's just not much fun.
You know?
So I think what's going to happen is
along the way we're going to find out
how much we miss.
You know,
somebody you said the ridiculousness of
life,
you know,
I also don't know if life can actually
evolve and progress just through pure
logic or pure rationality.
I think chance is very important in
life.
And I also think being creative and
creative must,
to some extent involved.
That ridiculousness at least must
involve the question of asking why now
it might get more logical and rational
as we go forward,
but I'm not sure we're ever going to
completely be the perfect mathematical
model that we would want to be A.
I'm not even sure that if we had perfect
intelligence,
if let's just say hypothetically we
became that perfect intelligence.
We might purposely sabotage ourselves
just so that we always have that element
of irrationality in our lives to keep us
on the go,
to keep us moving forward,
to keep us evolving.
So I'm.
So that's the first part of that.
I think the second part of what you're
speaking about,
the.
The interesting thing that I always tell
people,
because I get asked this question a lot,
is that right now our current perception
of the universe is pretty limited.
For example,
our ISI can only see about one percent
of the light spectrum.
Our ears can hear far less than one
percent of the,
of the sound waves and what's possible
in the universe.
So our actual ability to determine what
is in the universe is completely limited
and in fact so limited that were,
were just basically getting tiny bits of
it as we get.
Um,
as we progress forward,
I think we're going to have apps,
more applications towards getting a
better perception and our senses of what
the universe really entails.
We'll all have night vision.
We'll have be able to see different
types of gases in the air and we'll,
we'll have different types of feelings
that are based in with this,
these kind of hypersensitive and that in
itself will give us so many new
experiences.
And I try to tell this to people a lot
that we're actually going to become much
more complex.
We think this is our world around us,
but actually if you and I had bionic
eyes,
we'd see that there are maybe a
different organisms
in this room that are also interacting
with us.
And that's something that.
I'm not saying it's gonna.
Maybe take us down a,
either a smart or a bad path,
but it's something that could be
different,
that could take us to other ideas and
other ways of experiencing the world
that makes it so it's not either boring
or makes it so it's not so,
you know,
so kinda crazy though,
I don't think that humans are ever gonna
end transhumans at least to start with
are going to give up some of the
ridiculous aspects of their life because
I'm.
One of the things that motivates us is
fun and one of the things in,
in human experience that is fun is being
ridiculous.
So I think you need that creativity.
You need that creative element in the
species.
Yeah,
I agree.
I worry about the,
just the sheer amount of data you would
have to process if you could see all the
gases in the air,
all the organisms that are in the air.
Um,
I was camping regionally in Alaska.
We're in a Prince of Wales,
which is a essentially a rainforest,
so it rains all day every day.
And uh,
we were in the,
um,
like this,
this area where it's just constant
downpour,
100 percent humidity and I was in my
tent and I turned,
I had like little headlamp on,
I turn the lamp on and looked in the
tent and the tent was filled with
moisture,
like little tiny droplets of dew or
floating in the air and the entire tent.
And it made me think like,
if you could see all the microscopic
particles that are in the air
constantly,
I mean you're,
you're breathing in particulates,
you're breathing in all sorts of
pollutants.
You're breathing in farts and gases and
things from cars.
And,
and there's actually organisms in the
air.
I mean there's,
there's codes that are spread by people
coughing.
They cough.
It gets in the air and those organisms
float into your body and infect you.
And that's why we tell people,
cover your mouth when you cough,
you're literally spinning out life
forms.
And then those lifeforms contaminate.
Other people are worried that that would
be like almost too much data to process.
Now.
I mean,
imagine if you walk on an airplane and
you could see everything and you see
people coughing.
There's like,
here's the virus,
the virus,
you know,
you're right.
It would be a,
it would be a pretty freaky experience,
but I think the thing is we're probably
at that point,
you're going to have so much connection
either through neural implants or just
some type of connection to machines that
were.
Our data processing is in our brain and
however,
whatever kind of servers were attached
to will allow us to make sense of it
all.
Because right now I know you're saying
it's like,
wow,
there's no way I could process it.
Life is already pretty complicated to
process when you're going through a red
light or run.
Someone's running a red light or
something like that.
But hopefully in the future we'll have
all these neuro,
a enhancements that will allow us to
take that kind of stuff on and take more
of it on.
And uh,
you know,
there's,
there's just so much that's going to
happen when we start increasing our
brain power.
You know,
for example,
when they talk about artificial
intelligence,
we're talking about something that could
be 10,000
times smarter than the smartest human
being within a year to have it actually
existing just through.
It's upgrading of a thousand times
smarter and that's just the first year,
maybe the second or third year.
It's hard to know could become,
you know,
then thej curve takes off and that's
where the singularity idea comes from.
But um,
if we're attached to that and we're able
to keep up with that,
we're able to kind of process it.
Then,
you know,
all these things we start seeing are
going to make more sense and we'll have
so much more capacity to understand.
I think right now when we tried to
imagine it,
it's like wow,
way too much,
but in the future I'm hoping that our
brains are going to be like,
you know,
a thousand iphones just connected.
And then our ability to make sense of it
all and uh,
that,
that'll,
I mean,
I,
I look forward to the day when I can see
everything will be able to see your
heartbeat.
I'll be able to see right through the
walls,
whatever people are doing in the in the
building,
we'll hear the planes will know it,
you know everything will will see the
airwaves.
Have you seen the movie lucy?
Yes.
So you know,
she starts getting to that point when
she said she understands everything.
Everything is totally interconnected to
her and she has that processing ability.
It doesn't overwhelm her.
In fact,
it kind of becomes a magical to her,
sort of like a some kind of saint or
some kind of guru.
It just feels the entire universe and
I'm hopeful that that's what it's going
to be like though.
I'm not really sure.
You know,
that may be too optimistic,
but I'm hopefully will be so
interconnected that will actually be
able to be much more part of the
universe in terms of sensing it and
feeling and understanding it than we are
right now.
That's the big concern that people have
is when,
when folks,
like you say,
I'm hopeful because you know,
like you take the elan musk possibility
the way he's describing it need to take
what you're saying.
You're like,
I'm hopeful in the mosques and the
demons are coming,
you know,
it's like,
well,
hopefully not.
That's that,
that concerns people,
right?
No,
of course.
And,
um,
unfortunately,
you know,
I always try to back away from any kind
of totally qualitative or,
you know,
totally from statements because if I say
anything other than it's going to
happen,
then all of a sudden you're this guy
who's pegged,
you know,
a definite thing and the promise,
anything we're talking about in futurist
issues is always speculation to some
extent.
And no one's ever really got it right.
No,
no.
And most people are wrong.
Um,
the question is,
how close are you to getting it right?
If you're at 20 percent,
you know,
wrong,
that's pretty good.
If you're 70,
80 percent wrong.
So,
you know,
futures try to attempt to speculate
based on statistical analysis,
historical patterns,
what things are gonna happen and then,
you know,
first just throw out their ideas and,
and hope that some of them stick and
occasionally one becomes totally
accurate.
And you know,
that's the way the species moves.
But uh,
when I say hope,
I'm certainly not trying to pretend that
I'm,
the universe is going to be the way I'm
saying it could go very wrong and it
could turn out even better than,
than I'm hopeful and it could just
be a lot less a magical than I'm hoping,
you know,
I've seen some critics,
some really well educated critics.
I was reading this piece written by this
biologist who was criticizing the whole
idea of transhumanism and Kurzweil in
particular.
And what he was saying is that
essentially we know so little about the
human mind already and we're still just
trying to wrap our heads around the
processes that are going on that we're
just beginning to understand as far as,
you know,
synapses,
neurons,
the where memories are stored,
how to manipulate them and just the
various processes of the mind and his
take on it was that it's so incredibly
unrealistic that we'll be able to
duplicate this by 20,
45.
Like that's the idea behind it,
right to 20,
45 initiative.
But my take on that,
when I was reading his,
his piece,
I was saying,
I think he's being particularly critical
of it because he's.
He's saying that what these guys don't
understand about the human mind is that
there's just,
there's,
there's always processes that go on
behind the scenes that were,
we still don't have a handle on,
but my take on it was it,
we don't really have to have a hand on
it if we can or handle on it.
If we can replicate them.
Like if they can replicate it with
technology,
we don't have to know how proteins are
processed and all these different
various things that create a biological
computer would,
which is essentially what the human mind
is.
It's not necessary if we can create
something far superior and something
that's based entirely on artificial
intelligence and artificial technology.
Yeah.
No,
and I,
I'm,
you know,
first of all there's a lot of critics
out there that are coming at
transhumanist ideas,
futurist ideas and you just have to
remember that especially in America,
about 85 percent of the people are
religious Christians and a lot really
that far much.
An ABC poll told me 83 percent was out,
I think in early 2014.
Do you know what the problem with that
is?
I have a whole bit about this in my act
and it's the only idiots answer polls.
So you're getting 83 percent of idiots.
Have you ever installed a pole?
No,
I have never answered a poll.
Jamie,
have you ever answered a poll?
They go,
I don't think most people answer polls.
No,
you're right.
And I think 83 percent seems totally
high to me,
but I think even if it's a lot lower,
let's just say it's 50,
60 percent and let's just say,
you know,
there's another 10 percent that are
various other religious ideas.
The problem is we've been kind of
brought up in a Judaeo Christian or an
abrahamic culture.
You know,
we celebrate Christmas,
Easter,
these are where there's so much
religiosity and basically set into place
and a lot of these ideas,
you know,
transunion is one of their most
important goals is that they want to
live indefinitely.
That that's really the,
the center of a lot of the most
important goals for the next 10,
20,
30 years is they don't want to die.
We want to use technology and science
to,
uh,
to live.
At least they at least have the choice
when we're gonna die.
And if that sort of flies in the face of
so much of the major,
the world's major religions,
because a lot of it is kind of based on
you want to,
uh,
be a good person so you can get to that
afterlife and have your either seven
wives or whatever it is that they do.
Seventy two virgins,
whatever it is that they promise you.
But I'm trans humanists were like,
no,
actually this is perfect.
What we're here right now,
this,
this earth.
And what we'd like to do is just make it
so we don't have to leave it.
And we could stay with our families and
we could stay with our loved ones so we
could continue in our jobs or
professions and stuff like that.
And that really conflicts with a lot of
the American point of view of,
you know,
how,
how is it that,
uh,
what's gonna Happen in the future?
I mean,
as you probably know,
I think it's still 100 percent of people
in Congress at least are claiming their
religious now,
I don't know if it's a truly 100 percent
how many are pretending,
but either way you still have a
president that swears on the Bible to
get his job.
These are things that fly in the face of
trans humanism.
And I think until that changes,
um,
there's going to be a huge amount of
critics out there that are saying this
is a,
this is a dangerous idea.
And um,
you know,
you could,
you can paint it a different direction.
Say,
well,
transhumanism is just a label.
It's just science and technology.
All religious people want that anyways,
you know,
or at least want some of the benefits.
But I think at some point there will be
a clash because when you take death out
of the picture,
a lot of the main philosophies,
a lot of the main ideologies of the
religious religious texts fall away and
they're not necessary anymore.
And I think that's going to create a
pretty big conflict here in the next
five,
10,
15 years as we climb to crawl to that
spot where a lot of people start
realizing,
wow,
we may not die.
We may live indefinitely.
What does that mean for,
uh,
you know,
the environment,
what does that mean for politics?
Was that mean for country?
Is globalization and stuff like that
pop,
you know,
population as well.
So,
um,
I think there's going to be a lot of
issues with that in the future.
And I think that's where you get a lot
of your critics from.
That's fascinating because this guy that
I was talking about,
I was not religious at all.
The biologist,
he's an atheist.
I think there's a lot of atheists that
have issues with the possibility of
transhumanism just as much as people who
are religious.
But I think there's definitely something
to this idea that you know,
no one knows what happens when we die
and that's,
that's confusing.
It causes a lot of conflict and we've
sort of created placeholders for that.
We've created with religion.
We've created these.
Whether you believe in religion or not.
The reality is no one truly knows what
happens when we die.
If you have faith that the religious
texts of your choose choosing are
correct,
that's all well and good,
but the reality of scientific data is
that there's none when it comes to what
happens when you die.
There's none as far as like where did,
where did your soul word,
your personality come from?
There's none,
there's no data.
We have no
idea.
Is it nature?
Is it nurture is DNA,
is it epigenetics?
What creates a person's personality?
Who are you?
What's inside of you?
Is there a soul?
All of it's just pure speculation.
Is it consciousness trying to form some
rational reason for your existence?
All of it's speculation.
So I think when we start talking about
circumventing the whole reality of
biological death,
going around it and coming up with
something that allows you to live
forever,
there's some people that think,
well,
we might be missing the whole point,
like this might be a gigantic cycle of
life and death and life and death and
continual improvement.
And just like everything else that we
see around us,
just like our technological improvement
is constant and consistent.
That might be the same thing with,
with life itself,
like with,
with us stepping in and stopping this
process with technology in some sort of
way,
we might be fucking up the whole process
of the universe.
The other hand.
It might be.
That's the whole reason why we have
these thoughts in the first place.
Mike thought of us being this
caterpillar that becomes this butterfly.
Our whole reason for existential angst,
our whole reason for this fear of death.
These.
I remember when I was six of seven,
seven years old and I was talking to my
parents and I was asking them,
what happens when you die?
And,
uh,
my stepfather said it's probably
nothing.
It's probably just,
you probably just die and that's it,
and I was crying.
I couldn't wrap my head around it,
but for a seven year old,
it's terrifying,
and I've said this before,
but I'll say it again.
Everybody likes to go to sleep,
but nobody wants to die and they're
probably incredibly similar,
but this idea of having this impending
end to this experience,
it might be one of the motivating
factors for us to create this artificial
life,
to create this artificial intelligence.
This thing that we have that freaks us
out worrying about death might be part
of the motivation for us to transition
into something new.
No,
I.
In fact I totally agree with you.
In fact,
my entire book is really based on a very
singular moment when the main character
basically almost dies and he realizes
from that point forward,
and that's what the transfer is.
A novel.
Yeah,
it's a novel,
but that's exactly what you've said is,
is the transhumanist wager is once you
realize that you could die and that's
potentially as a seven year old child,
that's it.
You into something you can do about it.
Especially in the 21st century where we
have so much science and so much
technology at our disposal.
Then you make this kind of wager where
you're saying,
you know,
I'm actually going to dedicate my life
to try and accomplish that because I
don't like it that I have to die.
And that's essentially what the
transhumanist wager it really is.
But I think the interesting thing
is that philosophical conundrum of,
well,
if we take death out of the equation,
is life as valuable as it is or are we
messing with the mechanism of evolution
and are we mixing with the mechanism of
growth,
um,
of,
of whatever the universe is going into.
And I intend to.
I'm not,
you know,
as I've said before,
I want to live forever.
I want to live indefinitely,
but I'm not necessarily wanting to have
it so that that's a kind of permanent.
I just want the choice and that's what I
think is most important.
And when I,
you know,
people in the transgender community,
we've actually been shying away from the
use of the word immortality anymore
because we've realized that a lot.
It's just kind of scares people.
They really think we mean in mortality
and we don't necessarily what we mean is
we just want a choice on when and how
we're going to live and if we're ever
going to die,
it's under our circumstances.
Um,
it's on our terms and um,
so I,
I use indefinite lifespans,
uh,
a lot more because at least lets me say
when I might want to end my life,
if ever.
And I actually wonder too,
I thought,
you know,
if you're going to live indefinitely,
would god potentially,
if someone was God,
would God maybe committed suicide some
point because it's just an idea.
No,
you know,
if you were,
if you were God and you had all power,
is that something that would be the
thing you wanted?
And uh,
I'm revealing like plots in my sql.
But anyways,
the idea is maybe an omnipotent entity
would say to,
to create a cycle of renewal.
I will end my existence.
I will commit suicide.
And uh,
and then the whole system perhaps
restarts itself as we had talked about
earlier.
You know,
maybe you create parameters in your
existence.
So that all of a sudden you,
uh,
there is renewal,
there is creativity and it's out of your
control.
Sometimes you have to,
uh,
you know,
I know that for example,
day traders,
when they're playing stocks,
they,
um,
some of them have such problems that
they'll purposely set their codes so
they can't get into their account,
but they won't remember it.
They'll just type it in,
type it in short term memory and then
stop it and the way they do this so they
can't trade anymore if they've been
losing money and they having a bad day
or something like that.
Friends of mine were doing it in college
and I sometimes wonder if maybe a grand
spiritual entity would do the same
thing.
He would program into his own existence,
problems,
issues as we had talked about,
ridiculousness of life because that's
something that keeps us moving forward
and maybe God would even programming
killing himself or herself or itself,
whatever.
Whoa.
That
is a,
that's a heady concept.
And Iowa have always wondered why it is
that it seems like we need conflict in
order to find resolution.
It's like I think if everybody lived in
this perfect state of bliss and this
Utopian existence,
we probably never get anything done and
one of the reasons why we get things
done is because we're constantly worried
about overcoming struggle.
We're constantly worried about
overcoming potential aggressors or you
know,
things that could go wrong and
overcoming environmental issues that
we've created and so we're.
We're coming up with technological
solutions for those things,
for every new power source we come up
with,
whether it's nuclear or whatever.
There's always some sort of a byproduct
of that that we have to deal with and
some sort of an effect that it's having
on the environment that we have to
mitigate and it seems that this constant
Yin and Yang is sort of built into the
universe to stay.
I was telling you about my trip that I
had in Alaska where I was camping in the
rain was awful.
It was wet and cold.
It was miserable,
but when I came back to La,
I was so happy.
I called my friend Steve who took me on
the trip and I was like,
do I have never felt better?
I feel fucking great.
It's like the sun feels good.
It just feels good to be driving.
It feels good to be able to go to a
store.
You know?
There's so many things about life that
are so amazing that I don't necessarily
completely appreciate until I go like
into the wilderness.
When you go into the wilderness and then
you come back,
you can really appreciate the city and I
feel like these built in struggles,
this Yin and Yang of life is why we
appreciate things like you don't
appreciate really cool people unless
you're around a bunch of assholes.
You know you don't appreciate funny
people unless you're around people that
have zero sense of humor and then you're
around funny people and they just feel
so good.
They warm you up.
It just feels fun and I really wonder if
that is.
I mean,
we think of it as just life.
These are just the realities of life,
the unfortunate realities of life and
one day we're going to get our shit
together and we won't have all those bad
aspects,
but is,
is that real?
I mean,
or is this like,
is it all just data?
Is it all just a part of the code?
Is it all just a part of the algorithm
that moves whatever we're doing forward
and that in that sense you need
conflict.
It's built into the system in order to
create entropy in order to create
movement in order to keep everything
going so that we eventually make that
fucking cocoon and become that
butterfly.
Yeah.
No,
I mean the conflict question is,
is such an age old philosophical
question because it's like you're always
striving for perfection,
but when you actually think about
perfection in itself,
it doesn't sound like the thing you
actually might want really wanted was
the journey.
Right.
And you know,
and that's why I think they say,
well,
journey is,
you know,
most of the or half the fund at least.
And,
but I,
I tend to think,
you know,
as far as like from a transhumanist
perspective since we're,
so we're,
so I think miniscule in terms of what we
are as entities right now.
I know our brain power is a whatever,
a billion neurons or how many however
many billion there are.
But the idea is we could create an earth
that's full of servers
and a,
or as I like to say in my,
uh,
in,
in some of my writings,
you know,
the empire state building could be
filled with servers and that would not
mean like waiters.
No,
no,
but,
you know,
basically computer chips,
servers,
that kind of thing.
And the thing is we could create
something far more complex than the
human brain and if we're tapped into
that and now we can get into something
more like the death star even that's
just filled with computer chips and
servers,
you know,
if we get to something that huge,
our intelligence could be millions,
millions of times more what it is now.
Um,
and if that happens,
we have no idea that types of conflicts
that would come from that.
We have no idea,
maybe the conflicts are also a million
times greater.
Maybe conflict is something that you
always go through and maybe you even get
to the end of some perfect entity and
you actually can't get in,
um,
you know,
or you get stopped by some kind of
physical thing that could happen.
Uh,
it's so,
it's,
it's awesome to think about it because
the bottom line is from a philosophical
perspective,
currently I can't see a world without
conflict.
Um,
it just,
uh,
it would almost be like the world didn't
exist.
What makes it exist to us is that we
have all these trials,
we have all these tribulations and these
things happened to us and uh,
we're happy and sad because of it and we
feel it because then we grow from it.
Um,
so it's hard for me to even understand
the world,
but I think as we get more complex,
I think as we're able to tap our brains
into mega giant machines and increase
our intelligence,
it will probably become that much more
complex.
And I think the conflicts will also
become much more complex.
And um,
and so I'm not really worried about a
universe,
at least in the near term,
at least in the next hundred years to
300 years without any conflict because
the universe is still so big.
There's all this types of exploration in
it.
We have to figure out exactly what pure
energy is,
will,
you know,
will trans human entities eventually
transitioned into something like that?
Um,
and to subatomic things and whatnot.
And there's so much to explore.
I think it could get a,
I think we'll probably find that there's
more to explore than we ever thought and
will probably be just as lost in the
universe and stuck in conflict as we are
now.
Perhaps even more so as we,
as we grow more intelligent.
And even if we do create this
unbelievably credibly complex system of
computers that run everything.
We've eliminated emotions and we've
carved out this Utopian existence.
They're still asteroids.
They're still super volcanoes.
It's still hurricanes and tsunamis and
earthquakes and all sorts of things that
we.
It's not even on the remote horizon.
US controlling natural disasters,
not even in,
not,
not even for a fraction of the natural
disasters that that potentially can come
our way.
I mean we were not even considering how
to control super volcanoes.
There's no technology so far.
There's nothing they can do and I was
reading
about.
I got on this trip one night I'll do
this and just really fucked my head up
and I.
I hate doing it right before I go to
bed,
but I got on this trip one night about
super volcanoes can.
I started reading all the super
volcanoes that exists currently and the
reality of what has happened when those
have gone off and there's one in
Indonesia that they believe there's a
lot of people that have pointed to as
the possibility of why all humans can be
traced back to original ancestors.
That they think that this one,
that blue somewhere.
I believe it was like 75,000
plus years ago that they think that when
this fucker went off,
it killed most of the people on the
planet.
It's an Indonesia incident,
enormous,
bigger than yellowstone,
and they think that the remaining few
people repopulated the earth and that
the seven plus billion people are
directly related to a 70,000
years ago.
The survivors of this super volcano.
That's crazy and that's terrifying.
And if that happens again,
there's not a damn thing we could do
about it right now.
We're constantly worrying about getting
faster Wifi and make it an electric car
that go more than 300 miles without a
recharge.
But the reality of natural disasters is
there's always that nature reset button
and that nature reset button could come
in the form of a five mile wide rock
that slammed into the Yucatan and killed
all the dinosaurs or that gigantic super
volcano in Indonesia that killed off who
knows what percentage of the population,
but they think it could be as much as
like killed off everybody.
But for a thousand people,
that's a real possibility that's being
bandied about.
And that's something that we're not
going to be able to stop.
No,
no,
definitely.
You know,
I,
uh,
about two months ago created a,
the transhumanist party,
which is the kind of first political
organization about it and the third we
had three main goals and the first is
try to make it so that everyone can live
indefinitely.
The second one is just a spread,
a kind of a general,
like we want people to think positively
when they think of technology and
science set of being so critical.
But the third one deals with existential
risks and it amazes me that we spend so
much money at a walmart or Mcdonald's or
going to Disney land when we have
problems like a super volcano that
exists.
Things that if you think about at late
at night,
it keeps you up because it's so
horrific.
And what's amazing about is that it's
not just super,
okay,
it's,
we've had existential risks facing the
planet for,
you know,
they've happened,
we know they've happened.
We can see that they've happened.
And still we send such a small amount of
government budgets towards protecting
the species as a whole.
When you know,
you would think from an existential risk
point of view,
it would be the first thing you would
probably tackle.
Uh,
I actually thought this sort of with
Ebola,
I thought,
you know,
I can't believe that we don't a
$100,000,000
and wipe it out.
Why don't we just as a,
as a world,
get together and do it.
It's not like we're,
you know,
we're worth 200 to 400 trillion.
They say the,
the world and it would probably take 50
or 100 million to,
to wipe out the disease.
Why don't we do it?
Why don't we wipe out malaria?
Why don't we map out the things?
Is it really that simple though?
It's probably not that simple,
but no one's tackled it in with more
than a fraction of that amount.
And I think if you actually put the
world's best scientists together and
really said,
you know what,
some things really are scary for the
human race.
This is something that we need to go out
there and attack first before it gets
out of control.
And um,
I just,
I find it always so strange that
governments don't treat this seriously
and I think it's because as a politician
you can't because it sounds so far
fetched to talk about a five mile wide
asteroid hitting the earth.
It sounds like.
Yeah,
yeah,
I'll worry about that tomorrow.
But the reality is as soon as something
like that happens or a title wave
happens,
for example,
in kills so many people,
um,
a few years back,
then you start thinking about that.
I think it always takes like some kind
of giant cataclysmic disaster to
actually get people to say,
today I'm putting my money where my
mouth is and we're going to actually go
out and try to stop some of these
things.
And like you said,
it was super volcanoes.
There's nothing we can do,
but certainly with asteroids and stuff
like that,
there are some things that we can do.
And certainly with diseases,
uh,
there are things we can do.
And I'm,
I'm kind of a,
you know,
I'm always bummed out because I feel
like our governments don't treat the
risk to the species seriously enough.
They treat,
you know,
social security,
tax issues and this kind of stuff,
you know,
it covers the headlines,
but what's really important for the
species,
for all seven,
almost 8 billion of us soon,
is a,
is making sure that we don't all go the
way of the dinosaurs and that just takes
a matter of money and putting some of
the best minds to insane.
Let's just.
Whatever it is that you guys and girls
need to do,
just please do it.
The malaria one is terrifying.
I was listening to radio lab.
You have to listen to that podcast.
I haven't,
but I've heard the name.
It's a brilliant,
brilliant podcast that,
uh,
I think it's put out by NPR.
I think those are the folks who do it,
but it,
um,
they had an episode where they were
talking about mosquitoes and they were
talking about malaria and they said that
half of the people that have died ever
since people have been around,
were killed by malaria.
I've,
I've had malaria and malaria.
I've had a whole bunch of God when I was
20.
I did this a long sail trip.
And,
uh,
as a result,
I got a whole bunch of stuff like a
hepatitis,
a dandy fever and malaria,
Dang fever and malaria.
I had it all at various places.
And so I spent about four months in the
Solomon Islands,
uh,
and,
but I also kind of went through the
North Pacific Ocean after the South
Pacific and basically on a sailboat,
you're just,
you're going to get it unless you're
taking.
And I was even taking prophylactic a
malaria pills when I got malaria,
but,
um,
it,
it doesn't always work.
There's more than chloroquine that
you needed.
You needed math,
mcqueen and whatnot.
And the problem is they gave me crazy
nightmares so I didn't take the proper
prophylactics,
but I eventually got it,
went and tested there,
and then just sat on my boat for three,
four days.
And then I did a methlick when treatment
for malaria,
which is essentially,
you take four tablets times three days.
So you take 12 altogether.
And I don't know if you know anything
about Larry or mefloquine,
but it gives you an,
it makes you hypersensitive.
So when you look at a sunset,
you get incredibly emotional and it's
like a great thing to write poetry on,
but it totally messes with you,
which is why a lot of people,
at least when I was sailing 10 years
ago,
tried not to take it as a prophylactic.
But um,
so it worked.
I got rid of it.
I was,
I was an able body 22 year old person.
So you're pretty much able to go through
a lot of things.
But um,
I have been around a number of villages
in that trip where people have died.
Children die all the time and I still,
I'm not sure what the numbers are,
but I think it's a 715 million people
maybe are still dying from malaria a
year or have died in the last.
I don't know,
something.
Something crazy.
When you think about it,
you,
you think,
wow,
why don't we just go out there?
I mean this is why Bill Gates is
targeted.
This is one of his main initiatives with
his,
his incredible wealth is to say,
God,
this,
this is one thing we could literally
just take out 627,000
malaria deaths this year.
Yeah.
Whoa.
I mean it's,
it's,
uh,
it's a huge amount when you think about
in terms of it's far more than war.
It's,
it's far more than anything else.
And think of like,
so we spent all this money on war.
We could,
you know,
take a little bit of that budget and pr.
You know,
UNICEF has a different number.
They say over a million.
UNICEF says over a million people die of
malaria every year.
Wow.
So many.
It causes 300 to $500,
million infections and over a million
deaths.
This is John Hopkins also says that.
So I'm assuming it's probably somewhere
around a million.
I think when you're dealing with
impoverished countries,
right?
It's very difficult to keep track of how
many people know too.
And I think a lot of the people were.
I got,
it was,
there was no telephone in this village.
There was no anything,
I was just anchored off there at a surf
spot and um,
and I must have gotten it through the
time that I was sailing through some of
these outer islands.
And uh,
there's uh,
you know,
maybe once a week there's a boat that
comes through with supplies,
but that's why people die from it
because there's really nothing there
except the basic drugs to take care of
it and it doesn't always work and stuff
like that.
And there's variations of it as well.
So.
So some people try to just ride it out
and not take the drugs because they make
you so wacky.
Well some people actually,
once they get it are too weak to walk
into the clinic.
So like in the Solomon Islands for
example,
it's just filled with these giant,
a giant mountains,
but there's a lot of hills and so you
have to Kinda cross ravines.
And I was so out.
I mean I could barely even get up.
I didn't really eat.
I just could drink water and I kind of
laid in my bed all day.
And so if you have it and you're an
adult,
you either have to send your kids to get
it,
but you weren't,
you're not going be able to climb a
couple miles to go get the medication.
And so if you live in some outer tribe,
away from a clinic and most assault,
there's,
I dunno,
a couple hundred islands in the Solomon
Islands.
No one has access to the same thing with
Papa New Guinea.
There's not a huge amount of tribes,
but if you actually try to get anywhere,
it's all highlands full of snakes and
whatnot.
So even across a mile and that kind of
territory is pretty tough stuff.
So if you have to go 20 miles to get
pills,
it might just be safer to take your bat,
not use all your energy and uh,
and try to ride it out so your immune
system is capable of your healthy young
22 year old of surviving.
And sometimes I think it's just luck.
So for example,
I was already on a chloric when at the
time,
so I already had some resistance to
certain type of,
uh,
malaria.
Oh I see.
But once I had tested for it,
because I got basically got feverish and
all this and I went and tested before I
was got really bad and they said,
yeah,
it looks like you have it at this little
clinic.
And uh,
so,
and I was too far away to sail to
anywhere.
And um,
at the time I didn't have any real
services to be air evacuated out.
And also,
you know,
I had been sailing three,
four years already.
You don't,
you can't leave your trip.
I had a whole bunch of incidences.
You can't leave your boat every time
something goes wrong you just got to
deal with it.
And so I just went back and took this
lithium treatment and so I,
I had the cure for it.
And the cure is a,
at least in the Solomon Islands at the
time was you take this regimen of
laurium 12 tablets over three days and
that should,
that should take care of it.
What a crazy trip you went on,
man,
you,
you sail for three or four years?
So No,
I sail for around seven.
Yeah.
And it was a left from,
uh,
from Los Angeles,
Santa Barbara or Los Angeles and went
through the South Pacific,
spent four years there and continue to
end across the Indian Ocean and,
uh,
a Mediterranean.
So I've done some crazy stuff.
A lot of that stuff was when I was
working for the National Geographic
Channel,
so I was kind of set up where I would go
and do short three to five minutes.
I'm kind of filler documentaries in
between the longer segments of a new
show that they had.
And uh,
so I'd stop places and film and um,
and I'd create these three to five
minute news pieces.
So it's really fun stuff.
Did some crazy,
crazy,
a fun stories,
but,
you know,
a weird stuff.
Yeah,
I would imagine that would be an insane
life of adventure all those years on a
sailboat.
Just sail it around.
And,
and,
and in the South Pacific as well.
Uh,
you know,
the South Pacific was the best part
because I,
uh,
I wasn't working at the time.
It was later that I started actually
working and doing the national
geographic stuff.
And um,
that was great too,
but the South Pacific,
I was just there with about 500 bucks.
I spent literally four years in the
South Pacific,
including the time I was at the
Solomons.
The Solomons is,
starts getting into the North Pacific
and A.
Yeah,
what a wonderful time.
I was 21,
just finished school,
was sailing around and a half reading
books on the ocean.
Yeah,
a couple of times I had girlfriends come
with me for a month or two.
And so it was really like a,
I was a surfer and I was a paraglider
and uh,
so I would do just all sorts of
activities all the time and spear
fishing.
I was what a lie was hard to talk about
because it's like I have kids now and
I'm married and house and all that.
So I'm probably can never go back to the
days of youth I wandering around in the
Pacific sailing going by the wind.
Oh,
glorious.
Yeah.
So it was a,
those were the days.
That's kind of the opposite of
transhumanism though,
isn't it?
It,
it,
it is.
And um,
and I was very low tech at the time,
you know,
when I first started sailing,
they didn't even have gps.
We,
I used a sextant for the first few
years.
You use one of those crazy Christopher
Columbus thing.
That's all they had.
Only the military had access to the GPS
system then.
So no one private people weren't allowed
to travel yet.
I had a GPS system on my phone or my car
that was cd rom driven and it was in,
I want to say the early two thousands or
maybe even the late nineties,
it was somewhere around 2000 ish and I
got one of the first ones and it was
such an inaccurate piece of shit and it
was really slow and it was only good for
California.
Like I had a stick.
The CD in there was a slot that it would
go into it.
It's so hard to imagine a world where
gps didn't exist.
I know,
let alone be on a boat traveling around
the world on this boat with no gps.
That to me,
it's just incredible.
Oh,
it was,
it was really.
It was fun.
And the sex thing is so awesome because
you actually use the stars to navigate
same stars.
We teach kids to my daughters.
I'll point out and be like,
you know,
and the whole life was so magical.
I mean,
it's still cool.
I love what I'm doing now.
But there was something much more a
human and a just youthful about that
entire period of my life.
Human.
Isn't that a strange word that you just
used?
I'm not sure.
What is your whole thing is
transhumanism and you're talking about
this incredibly low tech adventure as
being one of the highlights of your
life.
So I'll tell you exactly how that
switched.
After most of the sail trip,
I was actually covering a story in
Vietnam for nationals for the National
Geographic Channel.
We were covering a story on bomb
diggers.
And uh,
what did they do is,
and there's about,
I think five to 15,
10 percent.
It's hard to know exactly,
but at least five percent of the
American bombs dropped by America in
Vietnam never exploded.
So what you have is you have millions of
tons of metal lying around the jungles
just sitting there,
overgrowth is all around them,
and in most of the rice farmers market
make a dollar a day.
So ultimately what's happened is a huge
community of farmers have said,
well,
why don't we salvage the metal,
sell the metal,
and will make 10 times what we would
make in a season in farming.
The problem is that the DMZ,
the demilitarized zone,
quite a bit of parts of Vietnam are
filled with landmines and dealing with
these unexploded bomb.
Some them that as long as this table are
about pretty close to it,
um,
are incredibly dangerous because you
have to dismantle it and take the metal
to a dealer in the city and whatnot.
So a lot of the bomb hunters,
what they call themselves,
and there might be 10,000
of them in Vietnam,
um,
ended up losing their lives,
are losing their legs on landmines.
And so I went to cover the story because
it's an awesome story,
totally fascinating.
But,
um,
I had a very close incident on one of my
final days when I was,
I'm covering the story,
cameron hand is my guide came from
behind me.
We were walking on a trail guide came
from behind me.
I stepped off the trail to look at an
impression because the way you can tell
where these unexploded bombs came,
is that a part of the jungle,
there's an impression in the,
uh,
in the earth and that he came and
tackled me and I said,
dude,
I'm holding my camera,
you know,
so we all went down and then he pointed
out,
he said,
look right here.
And in the ground there was this like
little silver thing and a little black
thing actually.
And he said,
we probably a landmine and you almost
stepped on it.
And,
uh,
I just kinda sat there and I thought,
wow,
that's a little too freaky for me.
After I had already,
like in the years proceeding this,
I'd had a,
all my diseases on the sailboat.
I had been to a number of war zones.
I just,
uh,
about a year earlier had a huge kind of
bunch of incidents in the cashmere,
a Indian Pakistan conflict,
which I covered.
I did a humanitarian kind of war peace
there,
and I was the,
the,
the landmine incident was the one that
sort of in my brain said human to
transhuman and I thought I'm not doing
dangerous things anymore.
Actually went home after the incident.
It just,
there was some,
there was a shook you up that much.
It was like a philosophical bomb went
off in my head and I said,
you know what,
I'm,
I'm 28 years old.
I've been doing crazy things for huge
amounts of time and getting very lucky.
Um,
I was working at a nonprofit
organization,
Cambodia called wildaid and we were
doing undercover work to busting
poachers,
you know,
we were literally,
um,
I'd go with a team of militia.
Uh,
we were a nonprofit and we'd go into
places and free live animals that had
been confiscated for food and we'd,
you know,
literally arrest the poachers because
they have China and Cambodia have this
illegal poaching system.
But it was,
it was like I had just come from about a
month of doing that and it was like a
little bit too much for me.
All.
It was just too much danger,
too much hecticness.
So the landmine incident was the one in
my mind that changed it.
And I said I went home.
That's when I essentially began working
on the book and I'm the transcripts
wager,
which has sort of launched me into this,
uh,
this public career of promoting
transhumanism.
I'd always been a transhumanist as
someone wants to use technology and
science to upgrade myself.
But this was the time that I made it
personal.
This is the time that I said,
you know,
I'm,
I'm done having fun and just writing
journalistic stories.
I'm now going to actually dedicate my
life to something that means a lot to me
because I don't want to ever have to be
facing death.
The landmines certainly would have
killed me,
I think,
or at least made me to such a.
You almost always lose legs and it's
just a little too much for me.
So I came back and that's sort of how my
career of the church trajectory of
transhumanism for me took onto this
quite public
roll.
Wow.
That is,
first of all,
it's incredibly terrifying to think that
there's that many landmines still in
Vietnam.
I've read that before and I kind of put
it aside,
I guess in the back of my mind,
but those poor people that lived there,
I mean the Vietnam War is just such an
unbelievably fucked up time in history,
but it's so incredible how peaceful the
Vietnamese are and how forgiving and
accepting the Vietnamese people are
about us invading or oh,
I shouldn't say us.
You know,
the,
the troops of the 19 sixties and
seventies invading Vietnam and all the
horrific things that happened there.
But that,
that the fact that no one's freaking
out,
but there's that many bombs that just
occasionally go off and kill some poor
farmer.
I know.
I think America should go in there and
clean it up,
you know,
because it's ridiculous.
The amount of bombs that are.
There are such a staggering number.
You could never cleared up with 10,000
Vietnamese farmers who have given up
their fields,
and again,
it's,
it's happening all over the country now
in Cambodia and Laos bomb diggers are,
it's an entire culture,
mostly young kids.
And a lot of my documentary was on
actually filming the amputees that lost
their legs or arms when something went
wrong.
And your viewers can watch this,
the national geographic video still up
on this one.
It's called,
um,
I think it's just,
you would google old Istvan Slash
Vietnam and go to youtube and it'll,
it'll appear.
Um,
it's,
it's called bomb diggers I think,
but are just Vietnam,
just a,
it's a four minute clip,
but it shows like,
you know,
what,
what these people go through on a daily
basis.
I just go out with a shovel.
They go out with metal detectors and
they're like,
d.
and every step they take is out for a
whole week.
I was freaked out.
It was like [inaudible] the DMZ is just
filled with.
No one's been there.
There's no villages in that immediate
area because it's just too dangerous to
live some people,
you know.
So there's thousands of those thousands
and thousands and what's worse is that
bomb digging a is attracting a younger
generation and they make so much more
money than rice farming,
like literally a 100 times.
If you find one six foot balm,
you can feed your family for a year and
you could find in one day.
So in one day's worth of work,
you can make more than you could in an
entire season.
So the
bomb is just the metal of the bomb or
the bomb itself.
Unexploded.
It's no,
it's just the metal.
They dismantle it and they sell the
metal that because they're only making
$1 a day in their farming.
So it's.
So they're so poor,
you know,
and they're very like,
you're right.
You nailed it.
The totally nice people and they were
happy to help me with my story.
Um,
but,
uh,
there,
the whole thing is so bizarre.
That's incredible.
And what do they do?
How do they dismantle these things?
So they have experts.
If they find a big one,
they carried into their village and this
is another problem.
They fucking pick it up.
Yes,
yes,
that's the whole problem and then they
hammer it apart.
It's just,
yeah,
it's crazy and sometimes like half
villages go up when they make a mistake.
This has been a problem that's happened
in Laos is the like,
so yeah,
it's a couple of documentaries have now
been made since I did this and I think
in 2002,
2003,
but a couple of real documentaries
because now they're a nonprofit
dedicated to saying,
hey,
don't go bomb digging that you might
make a fortune in a day.
You might change your,
you know,
your,
your family,
your wealth of your family,
but it's not worth it because look,
every,
for every 10 people that go out,
two or three end up with amputees or
some end up completely dead and stuff
like that and so much more dangerous
than just farming.
And has there been any effort whatsoever
by the United States government to go in
there and clean it up?
You know?
So I did the story a long time ago and
that point there wasn't much.
They just gave a lot of,
I think money to make up for it.
But I actually don't know what's going
on now.
I know that the nonprofits had been
working on trying to get them money.
God just so it's so hard to think about
it.
It's so hard to think that you're not
responsible for all the bombs that you
left behind.
That wouldn't be one of the first things
the United States deals with.
And how difficult would it be to do a
sweep of the entire country and find all
the bombs with the problem is like in
the area,
the DMZ is all pretty big hills,
so it,
it's almost,
you couldn't be able to get tractors up
there.
It's just there's too much vegetation
and everything's overgrown so nobody
knows what to do.
It would be much easier just to throw a
lot of money at it and uh,
and try to,
you know,
get the UN or somebody to go in there
and sweep through it with metal
detectors.
Yeah.
But what the fuck man?
I mean,
how,
how is it possible that they have just
left all that shit there?
That's just what,
that's so dark.
They bomb so much of the country.
It's really like,
it's such a staggering,
it just when you actually study the
numbers of how much they dropped,
I think they drop more.
I'm not 100 percent of this fact,
but I believe they dropped more bombs in
Vietnam than all other wars or something
like that combined of the amount of
bombs and because at the time that's all
they did and um,
you know,
and when you think about it's just
literally millions and millions and
millions of,
of bombs and tons of bombs and of course
huge percentage that just never
explodes.
So wow,
that's terrifying to think that that
could be there 100 years from now.
They're still potentially could be death
and your kid could step on one or it
could just,
you know,
it might be just ready to probably
doesn't,
you know,
I don't know.
Thousands and then are just ready to be
ticked off for one reason.
One Ms dot wire or something like that.
I don't know.
But it's a,
it's a serious problem.
And every,
if you look in the news,
every now and then you'll say,
oh,
another explosion happened here.
Again,
it's also not,
it's also quite substantial in Cambodia
parts that were bombed there and,
and whatnot.
And Laos,
and then they have all the internal
wars,
some of the countries.
It's not just us at bombed at some of
the other countries,
you know,
north Vietnam bombed,
these kinds of things.
So,
uh,
there's a lot of unexploded stuff all
over.
So you see this bomb,
you almost step on it and then a switch
goes off and you decide to change your
focus.
Yeah.
So I,
uh,
I had been interested in transhumanism
from the time I was in college.
We were given an essay on Cryonics,
um,
you know,
the,
the field where you actually put dead
people into some type of freezing
compound and then in hopes in 20,
30 years you will be able to have the
science to regenerate them and reanimate
them.
And our English class was asked to write
an essay on it and then debate it.
And uh,
so it was the very first time I was
introduced to it at about age 20.
And I started reading about
transhumanism and sort of fell in love
with this concept of using science and
technology to become superhumans,
you know,
uh,
just we don't need to worry about death,
we don't need to worry about disease,
we don't need to worry about,
um,
you know,
the kinds of things that plague our
biological beings.
We can use science and technology to
overcome it all.
So I spent,
you know,
a lot of the next 10 years as I was
sailing,
just kind of reading about it,
being into it without doing anything
about it.
But then after this incident,
I came back and began working on that.
The transhumanist wager a,
which is the,
a novel about transhumanism.
It's kind of an epic.
And I'm the.
It took me many years to write the book
because it's a pretty long,
complex philosophical novels.
It's at least 30 percent of the book is
pure philosophy.
So while it's a novel,
it's not a novel in the sense of,
uh,
you just read it and storyline.
It's actually huge amounts of just pure
academic philosophy going through it.
And the book did really well.
And,
uh,
you know,
I've been talking ever since about it
and uh,
uh,
it's gotten me a lot of trouble because
it's pretty controversial in what way?
Well,
essentially the main character jethro
nights,
uh,
he says he will do anything to live
indefinitely.
And so naturally the book goes out of
its way to create an environment where
he can't do what he wants.
It's,
he's fighting a religious,
he's fighting against religious entities
in America that are saying we don't like
trans humanism,
we don't want it as part of a anywhere
in America.
So they sort of outlawed.
And so he,
he kind of becomes a sort of a terrorist
for his own ideas.
But the problem is,
um,
he'll take it to all these extremes and
in the end forms his own
nation called transfer mania,
a floating seasteading platform.
And I'm a volunteer ambassador at the
seasteading institute.
I know you've done something about,
we had Joe Corcoran.
Yeah,
yeah.
And,
uh,
and I.
and so I kind of did a big,
about a third of the book,
discuss the seasteading where a $10,000,
some of the smartest scientists in the
world work on creating the ability to
live indefinitely.
But then the world says,
no,
this is not right.
And um,
and they say we're going to take over
your country.
And jethro says,
no,
we're going to start a world war and we
have the technology to do that.
And he ends up defeating the planet and
making it into a transhumanist minded
planning.
What kind of crazy fucking thoughts
going on in your head,
sir?
He uses authoritarian ideas,
and this has been the controversy of the
book,
is that a lot of the transhumanist,
especially the older one,
said,
hey,
we like it that you're writing about
transhumanism,
but we don't like that you're taking the
such extremes.
But jethro is a militant leader.
He's a,
he wants to.
His ideas to spread and they want to
keep taking away from.
They also in the book,
kill his wife and do all sorts of other
things.
So it's a novel where it's an epic from
kind of his early childhood to the end
or near the end of his life where he
transforms the world against everyone's
willing.
What makes the book controversial is
that nobody likes jethro.
He's sort of this incredibly arrogant
machine like human being,
yet he's the good guy of the book and
yet you sort of cheer for him because
you know,
he,
even though he sort of a authoritarian,
he sorted,
you would like him because he's driven.
He's like the greatest fighter you've
ever met who just,
he's not,
don't tell me about rules.
This,
I'm just the best fighter,
you know.
And on one hand that's very admirable.
On the other hand,
we have rules for a reason,
but jethro breaks them to get what he
wants.
And he made the transhumanist wager
where he really like.
He says,
I'll put anything,
I'll do anything to achieve it.
And that's where the controversy comes
in because clearly if we all did
anything we wanted,
we'd be in a,
in a pretty hectic place,
both politically,
government,
a Swiss society,
all these different things.
And so I,
uh,
the book has won a lot of praise and
just as much criticism and there,
if you look at the,
the Amazon reviews,
it's like an e,
there's like a huge amount of one stars
and a huge amount of five stars,
but not much in the middle.
And nobody said,
you know,
everyone hates the book because they
call it,
you know,
they say,
well,
this is an evil character.
And,
and you know,
the people that like it say,
no,
this is a character who actually wants
to fight for what he believes in and uh,
you know,
revolutionary leaders or sort of like
that,
they,
they just,
they take us to different places and
they use different methods that um,
you know,
certainly are questionable.
But again,
it's a fictional novel and you can take
it for what the artist's worth.
Well,
this is where it gets complicated
because you are planning on actually
running for president on a transhumanism
platform.
Now when
you've written a book about a world war
that gets started by a good guy with a
transhumanism agenda and now you're
wanting to run for president people go
this Zoltan Guy,
this motherfucker think about his name,
his name is Zoltan and he wants to run
the planet and he wants to be a trans
humanism.
He wants to be a robot.
You're turning into a robot that's going
to start a world war two,
run the planet.
Yeah.
So that's obviously not true,
but no.
No,
and of course that is the most difficult
question.
I'm going to be asked probably a lot as
I move forward with the really going to
do this.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
I mean it's already said.
I've sort of stake my entire reputation
on it at this point.
We have some big,
big publicity events,
but do you think that you could possibly
win?
So I don't think I could win this time
around.
I think there's virtually no chance.
I think if you look at how far the
transhumans party might do by 20,
20,
24,
where I would potentially do it again,
I think we might have a much better
chance of making a dent now.
I don't want to be unrealistic and say
that we could actually win or that I
could win the presidency or anything
like that.
But I'm,
I am definitely advocating for a run
that's taking all my time.
Like I'm literally dedicating now,
you know,
my,
all my waking hours towards this party.
Really all the infrastructure that
takes.
It's really complicated.
I mean,
I'm,
I basically,
I'm working with advisors.
I'm working on the different.
There's so many logistical things that
one has to do,
including just dealing with taxes for an
entity like this and registration
process,
a manifesto.
But in the next week or two,
most of the infrastructure will be in
place.
Uh,
we're already have a lot of it in and
have a number of officers now.
And,
uh,
we're,
we're going for it.
I mean,
I'm going to stake everything I have on
it.
My wife has given the approval,
which is important because I got two
kids and her and we're going to do a lot
of campaigning.
We're gonna have some great events.
In fact,
I'll probably,
hopefully be down in a few weeks to La
to start a documentary on it without,
which has a great budget by the way.
And so I think there'll be a lot of
things coming out about the
transhumanist party that are going to
work really in the favor of getting
people to think about what would it mean
to have a political,
uh,
you know,
person running who actually wants to use
technology and science to change
politics.
Not just,
you know,
oh,
politics,
let's dabble a little bit in science
policy,
but I actually want to use technology
and science to dominate politics.
I think we can solve most of humanity's
problems and,
and run a much better country.
Uh,
if we put politics and medicine and
technology sort of at the forefront of
the government currently we're at the
forefront is a lot of other issues that
defense and uh,
uh,
you know,
I dunno.
Taxes and all that stuff's very
important of course,
but,
um,
I'm an idealist and I would like to make
it so that we can.
Everyone can live longer.
Everyone has the choice to potentially
not die.
Now I'm pretty convinced that if we put
a trillion dollars towards conquering
death,
we would probably achieve it.
Most experts actually feel that way too.
That the amount of money that's actually
going into life extension science right
now is so small,
literally hundreds of millions.
But if we actually could quadruple or
maybe make it 20 times,
then we could take the 20,
30 year window and make it into 10
years.
And that's one of the platforms is that
we're gonna have the parties to say,
well,
we're going to take money from our wars,
are far off wars and put it directly
towards important things.
Education,
science and technology,
and also life extension science.
So,
but to enter your,
your,
your somewhat dangerous question for me
publicly.
Um,
I,
I'm distancing myself from the book
because it was,
it was a moment of writing something
very artistic and trying to write
something very philosophical.
But the philosophy of jethro nights does
not work in a political campaign,
and I'm,
I'm doing my best to disassociate myself
from his ways,
even though I,
I'm the creator of the philosophy and
I'm the one who sort of spent all these
years developing it,
but I would never work.
It would never work in America as we are
today.
We live in a country that's very free.
There aren't a bunch of religious people
trying to stamp out transhumanism in the
book.
He lives in a war environment.
That's part of why he fights back with
war.
So luckily,
you know,
we live in a pretty awesome country.
You can mostly do what you want.
And um,
I'd like to convince people to do a lot
more than just building bombs and uh,
and some of the crazy things that they
do and spend it towards science and
technology and it hoping that everyone
will eventually like it.
Everyone will eventually live better.
Everyone will eventually kind of be
taken to a new era where you know,
their families and their loved ones
don't have to die.
We have all the benefits of technology.
Like,
we don't have traffic in La,
like I told you,
I mean these are kinds of things,
you know,
driverless cars that are going to
improve everything.
And I think if more people embrace
technology,
we might go a lot further,
um,
as a species and also as a country.
The obvious question,
um,
when you say if people live forever or
people could get to a point where they
don't die,
we can conquer death.
We have too many people.
There's 7 billion people on the planet,
right?
Is that what the number is now?
Yeah,
I think it's.
And it's going on fast.
Yeah,
it's going up fast.
Los Angeles,
as you said,
we were talking on the way about you
traveling on the way over here,
how difficult it was to get here because
the traffic is so bad.
You know,
there's 20 plus million people in Los
Angeles.
What happens if they keep having babies
and no one dies?
Yeah.
So you know,
this is one of the most challenging
questions and most challenging ideas
about the problem with transhumanism
right now is when we advocate for
technology and science to change
people's lives.
And make them live longer and better.
The first question everyone says,
well,
hey man,
we've got environmental problems in the
world and I agree we do.
I,
I'm a believer in some of the climate
change problems.
I'm a believer in,
you know,
a overpopulation.
I'm not going to in any way try to deny
some of these things.
I actually think the science stands
pretty strongly for it.
The question though is whether tackling
that broadly,
I'm tackling environmental problems with
the kind of ideas that we're trying to
do right now.
I'm less population a recycling and you
know,
and stuff like,
you know,
just the basic things we're trying to
empower ourselves to be a more green
world.
I'm not 100 percent sure that that is
the accurate or that is the very best
path we can take a.
Now this gets kind of SPEC speculative
and I don't actually endorse this
necessarily as,
as a kind of a political platform,
but I'm pretty quiet.
Pretty convinced that within 25 to 50
years people will start downloading
their consciousness into machines and
stuff like that.
So there's this idea that maybe we'll
start using a lot less resources 100
years from now,
um,
because people will live in digital
lives and virtual lives.
Uh,
you know,
maybe we'll all live.
Maybe the entire population will fit
into that,
uh,
empire state building that is full of
servers as we had discussed.
Um,
and maybe the earth will have a chance
to grow back or come back to what,
you know,
it's formed,
but that's not the,
uh,
you know,
that's just one of the kind of
speculative ideas that trans humanists
might use to counter some of the
criticism that we get a about
environmental prompts.
I'm personally,
what I'm for is for a lot of the green
technology,
that's the stuff I want to see.
I want to see solar power increase.
I want to see money going towards that.
I want to see money going towards the
windmills.
green types of technologies that not
only can make a whole new generation of
wealthy people and give millions of jobs
to people,
but it can also,
at the same time help the planet.
So,
you know,
I take this two fold approach,
one is very speculative in the future,
there'll be space exploration and all
these other things.
We might figure out a ways that don't
make us so dependent on the planet,
but the more important ways that we're
going to spend money on the type of
technologies that really make the planet
better,
you know,
get people to move into cities,
make them green or a leave,
open spaces their loan.
And I'm a big animal advocate as well.
I worked with wildlife.
A lot of my national geographic work was
with wildlife.
So I'm,
I'm,
I'd love to see the species replenished.
I'd love to see it so that we can
actually go to national parks and have
the kinds of things that we all hope for
where you see deer and you could take
your children out there and uh,
and especially in afterwards.
So much poaching and stuff like that.
Of course.
Um,
you know,
in America we do a pretty good job with
protecting our wildlife.
But,
um,
I'd like to see us be more of a leader
on the international front staying.
We actually need to say stop it.
It's crazy that the tiger population is
literally on the edge of extinction,
literally gone.
There are more tigers in Texas than
there are in the wild.
It's incredible.
It's sad.
It's terrible because they are an
important part of the,
you know,
the ecosystem in all the places that are
at.
And uh,
one of the stories we covered was the
Siamese crocodile when I was in Cambodia
and um,
there's a couple in captivity,
but basically the last time someone saw
one was like 13 years ago in the wild.
And so it's gone,
you know,
it's,
it's essentially gone.
And uh,
when you think about it,
you're like,
well,
that's a certain species just basically
gone and why is it going on?
People were making boots and stuff out
of it's tails and whatnot.
So I would like to advocate for policies
that kind of make that happen less and,
uh,
generally increase our environmental
consciousness with money instead of
building bombs,
hey,
let's,
let's spend it on building electric
cars.
Let's spend it on other ideas.
Even more unique ideas than that.
Well,
there's a lot of things to discuss
their,
first of all,
um,
the beginning of this,
you were talking about downloading
consciousness into computers,
so you're kind of advocating a non
biological life.
You're kind of advocating life inside of
a server,
a virtual life,
and that,
that will be the future of life that is
really hard for people to conceptualize.
It's really hard for the average person
who just likes to go on facebook every
now and then,
post pictures of their dog with a
fucking boner had,
you know what I mean?
Like one day you're going to live in a
computer like that's going to.
It won't be just your photos in a
computer,
your mind,
your consciousness will live in a
computer,
your body will die and you will exist
in,
in ones and Zeros,
in some sort of a program like that to a
lot of people that doesn't seem like
life.
Um,
it could get to a point in our lifetimes
where it is indistinguishable from life.
And that is in fact,
one of the freakiest ideas that's
bandied about today by people far more
intelligent than me.
This is not my own philosophical stoner
ramblings,
but the concept of living right now in
some sort of a computer simulation,
and this has been discussed ad nauseum
amongst physicists and scientists that
we're going to come,
there's gonna come a point in time where
we will be able to create some sort of a
virtual life that is absolutely
indistinguishable from the life that you
and I are experiencing right now.
If that's the case,
how do we know we're not already in it?
You know,
that's,
that's the big mind.
Fuck,
right.
That's the big mind.
Fuck.
When it comes to quantum theory and
when,
when people start talking about virtual
realities is that we may already be in
one.
I did my senior thesis at university on
brains in a VAT exact same concept.
So it was,
I spent like a whole month writing a 24
page paper.
It's crazy.
In fact,
after writing the paper,
I was like,
it took me like a week to even become
normal again because you,
you can't,
you can't choose.
And that scares me,
you know,
you can't say I'm not in one arm in one.
And um,
yeah,
it's,
it's a totally freaky concept.
Not only that,
you,
you can't say it and it's going to
happen if we don't,
if that super volcano doesn't blow,
if we don't get hit by the media,
there's going to come a point in time if
technology continues to increase,
whether it's 50 years from now or 100
years from now or a thousand years from
now,
our ability to control reality itself
will reach some sort of an epic point
where we can create a virtual reality.
I'm sure you've messed around with
oculus rift.
I have,
I,
I haven't tried the new one.
I tried.
My friend Duncan is a,
he's um,
he's got the old model and now he has a
new model.
Here's the developer's kit and the old
one I put on,
it was all pixelated and weird,
but it gave you the sense like,
wow,
this is kind of freaky.
He called me up.
He went to some sort of a virtual
conference that they had in Los Angeles
and he called me up just ranting and
screaming.
It's over,
man.
This is bigger than the printing press.
This is bigger than the Internet,
like this is fucking over.
We're gonna,
this is gonna be reality,
and he was just freaking out so much so
that I'm scared to go and try this
headset on.
But he was talking about going into some
virtual room where there's a person
playing the piano and you you interact
with them and you feel like you're in
the room with them and he said it was
the freakiest thing he's ever
experienced in his life because it's all
in like four k hd super,
like,
like really,
really clear video.
And they apparently the way they do it,
they put cameras all over the person's
body when they film.
This camera's on your hands,
cameras on your legs.
So everywhere you look they have it
covered and it's just a matter of the
processing power of being able to keep
up with all the different potential
views that you have.
Same as when you're going into a
computer,
three d generated world,
like a video game like quake or
something like that where you're going
down corridors and you could look up and
look down.
They have it like that.
But they have it in complete the read
dimensional hd video to the point where
it it's indistinguishable from actually
looking at these things in real life and
that's just now.
I mean,
what does that going to be like 50 years
from now when they figure out how to do
something on your head where they put
you know,
electrodes or something where they can
stimulate parts of your mind that can
give you the sensations of the feel of
the wooden floor giving slightly under
your feet,
the texture of a wall.
As you run your fingers by you will,
you'll be able to feel that on your
fingertips and then a thousand years
from that,
what happens then?
I mean,
What happens then?
What happens then it keeps going and
going and going and going,
and if you extrapolate,
if you look at where we are now and you
look at the future,
it's almost impossible for us to not
reach a point where were
indistinguishable where reality and
virtual reality are indistinguishable
from each other.
No,
I couldn't agree more.
And if you try that stuff on,
that's really the.
It's sort of like the landmine thing.
Once you've tried that on,
it really is such a freaky thing that
you realize,
oh,
this is here today.
Okay.
It's not perfect,
but in 10,
15 years common,
it's common.
And I think a lot of.
I think a lot of younger people get that
because they either tried it or they're
cool with it.
They grew up like my,
uh,
my 11 month old or a 10 month old
daughter is already quite adept.
She's already pretty quite good at using
like the ipad and skipping through
things.
She doesn't know what the APP's mean
yet,
but she's only 11 months and she's just
growing up with this technology.
And so for her,
I think to put on a virtual reality
setup,
it's going to be in 10 years or 15 years
is not going to even dent her.
She's not going to be scared of it.
She's going to be,
have heard the word,
she's going to be,
have heard transhumanism for the last 10
years.
It will be like stepping in.
Um,
you know,
I think when people first talked about
cars,
they must have thought,
well how weird,
what do you mean we're going to get rid
of the horse?
And then the next generation thought
will,
I can't believe you guys were in a horse
and sort of like the way we talk about
either fax machines now or you know,
the new generation is going to take it
and run with it and they're not going to
be afraid of it at all.
I think it's people our age that are
already still,
we're like a little skeptical and then
it's people above us that are really
still out there and they have to
actually test it to see it.
But in 15 years,
no matter who tests it,
it's going to be so real.
I think the philosophical dilemma there
is that people are gonna say,
well,
it's not real life.
And people like myself,
we're going to say,
well,
why not,
you know,
what makes that real knife just because
it's created,
um,
you know,
through a machine how to say this hasn't
created through a machine.
You know,
what's the say?
This is so different.
You touched something in there and it
feels maybe even more real than it does
now.
You know,
maybe the touching of wood there as we
had talked about,
if you have sensors on your fingers,
it's not just touching wood will be able
to determine the strength of that would.
I can't,
you know,
we can do all these things right now,
but for example,
I'm writing an article right now on I'm
blind people using,
uh,
artificial robotic eyes,
bionic eyes to see and they're now
basically kind of doing a surgery where
they put something into your eye and
then they can program it through these
goggles that you wear and blind people
can now effectively see.
So it's like,
look,
the character on star Trek.
Yes,
exactly.
That's exactly what it looks like to it.
It's called,
I think the argus two is one of the
latest ones.
But,
um,
the,
uh,
the point though is that part of my
articles,
what are they doing now?
Because last year they went from like
black and white to upgrading the eyes to
color.
They can program in the certain types of
lights that hit color into your nerve
cells,
but soon they're going to start
programming things like we talked about
gases or you know,
eventually it's just a matter of the
machinery will be able to have whatever
capabilities you can give it.
It's not a,
you know,
you were not limited anymore.
Our eyeballs are limited to its biology,
but if we have robotic that ties
into the nervous system,
our nervous system can understand
anything.
The reason we don't see much more than
we see is because our eyeballs are
frankly,
they're quite poor when you give a,
when you think about what kind of
mechanisms are out there that can really
be attached inside there.
And uh,
so the,
the articles about what is the future of
the 10 year future of Ra,
a bionic eyes.
And I'm a pretty big believer that
within 10 years we'll have bionic eyes
that are almost equivalent of the human
eye.
And probably within 15 or 20 years
people will start replacing one of their
eyes for the bionic one.
And the reason they'll do so is because,
like I said,
you're going to,
it's not just seeing one percent of the
universe anymore,
the computers and the programs and the
devices will be able to see far more.
You're gonna be able to see through
walls.
You're going to be able to see,
and this is,
this is stuff companies are like
literally working on right now.
This is blind.
People have already seen this happen in
2012 and 2013.
Now they're starting to upgrade the
software and you know what happens when
they start upgrading things.
It's then it's like,
okay,
we got the apparatus in place.
Now let's see what kind of magic this
can do.
And this is just the eyeball.
The same thing's happening with the
human heart.
The same thing's going to be happening
with the ear very soon we're going to be
replacing place parts in ourselves and
going for upgrades and our lives are
going to become much more complex,
better live longer,
but also experience will be different.
Experience will be sort of like virtual
reality.
It's such a different experience that
once you've gone through it,
you realize it's kind of,
you know,
I've heard you talk a little bit about
drugs in the show and I'm a big
proponent of,
of experimental drugs myself.
I think it's,
I think it's quite great for,
for kids to do all sorts of stuff,
including adults.
I will.
You just fucked up your presidential
chances right there.
Oh,
no way.
That's great for kids to do drugs.
Well,
not,
no,
I don't.
I don't mean kids.
I mean,
you know,
a 20 somethings 21 year olds and above
those youngins yeah.
Uh,
we're,
I'm 40 I guess kids or anything,
you know,
in their twenties,
in their thirties,
right.
Fucking wacky kids.
But ultimately,
you know,
whether we like it or not and whether,
again,
I'm not running on some presidential
campaign to try to be the guy who
pretends these things.
It's,
I'm luckily not at that point yet.
Maybe in eight years I'll have to wash a
lot more what I say,
but right now I'm a big.
I think you will.
I think eight years from now we're going
to be able to know exactly what you mean
without you even have an accent.
I think eight years from now we're going
to have such amazing access to each
other's minds that are getting closer
and closer.
Possibly.
Yeah.
I don't.
I don't think you're going to have to
worry about people lying anymore.
Well,
that would be great because then they
won't,
we can't.
We can know when they're pretending
stuff,
you know.
And,
and the truth is,
I think all of us in many of your
listeners,
we all realize that there are lots of
things out there that the government
considers illegal considers terrible,
that have been very useful for artists,
creative types and basically people in
general to expand their consciousness.
And I think,
you know,
the technology will be also some new
form of enabling us to
expand our consciousness.
Like I said,
if we have a bionic eye and it allows us
to see different things that's going to
mess with our consciousness in some way.
And you can combine that with all sorts
of things.
And um,
I'm a big advocate and in doing
anything,
as long as it doesn't harm someone else,
I think it's open game.
I agree.
And I think that when you,
when you think about the possibility of
improving our organs,
I think we could also look at the
natural world and what we know about
like for instance,
look what dogs can smell like the,
the incredible ability that some animals
have to see things like my friend Matt
from,
he lives in Alaska and we were talking
this weekend about fishing and he was
saying that sometimes when they fish
they'll catch sharks.
And when they pull them out of the,
uh,
the ocean,
like the catch them accidentally when
they're fishing for halibut.
And when they released them,
they on the surface of the water and
eagles can see them from a mile away.
They can see a fish just swimming on the
surface of the water from a mile away.
And they'll just show up.
They show up and they grab it.
It's like their eyes,
like our vision of what that could be.
It's so,
but think about like you can see a fire
in the distance and aunt has no fucking
idea that fires out there.
You know,
Jamie was showing me this photo of a,
there was a huge fire last night in Los
Angeles and from a distance it looked
like,
like a bomb had gone off.
It looked like a missile would hit some
apartment building.
It was a huge,
huge fire,
melted signs that we're saying on the
1:10
now we can see that.
But to a worm,
they have no fucking idea that's going
on.
So we already know that biologically
there are animals that have organs that
work far better than the ones that we
have.
So we're completely aware that their
ability to smell things,
their ability to hear things.
I mean you can just ruffle your fingers
together slightly across the room.
And my cat's ear will like turn like
that.
She can hear shit that I couldn't even
hope to hear in a million years.
We know those organs exist.
We know that their capacities are far
beyond anything that we have and if we
start giving people cat eyes and cat
ears and dog noses and you know the
ability to do that mean we will
radically transform human existence just
based on not even fantastical like
science fiction versions of these
organs,
but organs that we know exist in the
biological world.
No,
a hundred,
100 percent.
You know,
so my,
my articles,
one of the funniest things about the
articles that it's quite possible within
10 years of blind person will see better
than a normal biological person where
they'll have the ability to see,
you know,
a 150 miles and they'll have ability to
see various tiny things that are.
The human eye can never see that.
That's how far technology has come where
a blind person has better site than a
real person.
Now it's not here,
but it's definitely probably going to
happen within the next decade.
Well,
I have reading.
He's a little little glasses as I'm 47
and as I've gotten older,
one of the things that's happened is
most likely from fucking staring at
screens all the time.
My closeup vision starting to suck,
like when I can,
I can read like my,
my iphone,
I can read it.
Fine.
No,
no issues at all.
But when I start reading small print,
like all small website or something like
that,
like I need to put on the reading
glasses in there.
One and a half.
What regular vision is like?
So it's one plus 50.
That's,
that's like robotics.
I mean this is like this is technology.
I'm putting something over my eyes.
It changes my eyes right now.
It just goes over and some people they
get Lasik,
they changed their,
their actual lens,
they cut it,
they do it with technology,
they changed the form of it and then
some people get artificial lens is put
in when they have issues or or you know,
they get injuries and I know fighters
who've gotten artificial lenses put into
their eyes.
It's gonna.
It's gonna Creep up on us.
I think it's like people with hearing
aids and you know,
some folks have artificial hips.
I have a friend who was an artificial
hip.
I have another friend who is an
artificial knee,
you know,
and these,
these are becoming more and more
commonplace where they are taking parts
that are not working well anymore and
replacing them with robotics.
I was just doing an article apparently I
think around 300,000
people in the world have this cochlear
implant which is actually inside and
that's 300 thousands.
Not like $300.
I mean that's a huge number around the
world that are having,
hearing problems that have this,
that decided to go undergo a surgery
that involves her skull and head
essentially and have this implanted.
That's great because um,
and those people apparently here far
better and now society is changing.
It's just going to take,
it's going to take take interviews like
this where people hear about it and you
know,
if you hear about enough times,
all of a sudden you're like,
oh,
well I know someone else did that or
this dad,
you know.
And eventually everyone will sort of
hopefully start to say,
well,
this is great,
you know,
and,
uh,
I think the big thing is really getting
a lot more government funding for these
kinds of things because sometimes it
seems so speculative,
but if we improve the world,
improve people's biological beings and
their livelihoods,
it's hard to argue with that kind of
logic.
It's just the skin better.
It is getting better.
And as we said,
when it comes to technology,
if we don't blow ourselves up or the,
the,
the universe doesn't send a rock our
way.
It seems inevitable that we'll continue
this progress.
It just seems inevitable.
And I think there's a certain duty that
we have,
especially folks like you have that have
the scientific know how our knowledge
and the information to inform people
that this process is underway and you
better prepare yourself because there's,
there's no getting away from it.
As long as we are human beings,
we are never satisfied.
There's a horsepower revolution right
now with cars.
It's gotten completely on hand and
totally ridiculous.
I don't know if you're aware if you're a
car person,
but in performance cars,
they've reached this staggering level of
performance.
At the highest end,
they have an American car now called the
challenger Hellcat.
I drove one when I was in Denver.
It has 770 horsepower.
It's fucking insane and it is a run of
the mill,
not run of the mill,
but it's a standard production car.
You,
you get it from a Chrysler dealership or
you go to a dodge dealership,
he pick up an srt,
challenger it,
drive it off the lot.
You don't need to go to some flight
school.
You don't need to show any incredible
proficiency with high performance
engines and they have cars now that
regularly hit zero to 60 in less than
three seconds,
less than three seconds and they're
going 60 miles an hour.
That's insane.
I mean this is far faster than race cars
have a couple of decades ago and it's
going to get faster and faster and
faster and if eventually we're all going
to be driving like formula one race cars
around.
I mean,
it's going to be that bizarre and it
exists in everything.
We're seeing it now in internet speeds.
We're seeing it in processor speeds and
computers when they.
When they eventually do go public with
quantum computing,
it's going to reach an entirely new
level.
I don't even understand quantum
computing.
I've read several articles on it,
tried to wrap my head around what the
fuck it means.
I don't get it,
but apparently in my crude understanding
of it is they're going to be able to
create computers that aren't just 10
times stronger than the,
you know,
this Mac book I'm using,
but a million times or 10 million times
or 100 million times where they have
processing power that is literally
unimaginable.
Like we will get to a point again,
whether it's 100 years or 500 years from
now,
we're going to get to a point where we
are masters of the universe where we
literally become gods.
We become an entity that has the ability
to manipulate all matter all the time
and my issue with that is when this gets
into the hands of everyday folks,
we have a problem already in this
country with guns and the problem is
mostly people with mental health.
The gun problem in this country is not
nearly as bad as people think it is.
This is what I mean by that.
There are 350 million people in this
country.
The amount of actual mass shootings we
have is very rare.
When you consider how many people have
guns.
These are.
It's a mental health issue,
but the issue is you're giving a one
individual who is mentally ill,
they have the ability to get in control
of this device,
a gun which can cause all sorts of
incredible damage.
What happens when it's not,
you're not talking about a gun,
you're talking about something that
manipulate matter.
You're talking about something that has
the ability to radically transform the
environment in some sort of a way that
this responsibility
can't be it.
It can't be
overemphasized.
It's it's.
We could get to a point where an average
human being has the ability to create
worlds.
We,
with the average human being,
has the ability to completely alter life
as we know it for everyone else who
exists on this planet,
whether that's a thousand years from
now,
whether it's 500 years from now,
if we keep going,
were these technologies will eventually
getting into the hands of regular
people?
How do we stop that?
I mean,
how do we stop doing is that is the real
question.
Do we concentrate on mental health?
Do we concentrate on,
on getting people to live in harmony and
peace before we create all these
technologies?
Or do we sort of figure it out as we go
along and have it catch up?
Well,
that's a lot of question.
No,
no,
but again,
this is back to why I had,
was trying to do the transhumanist party
is that I'm trying to introduce these
concepts into politics because for
example,
I just was reading an article and they
said,
you know,
the average kid can go spend a thousand
dollars on Ebay and create this kind of
very professional microbiology lab in
his bedroom where he could then launch
potentially very dangerous diseases if
he knows what he's doing.
And I thought the thousand dollars,
you know,
a 20 years ago that would have been
$100,000,
so no one would have had access to it
except you know,
and these are the kinds of things where
I don't think a lot of government
agencies,
politicians are actually thinking about.
They're just saying,
oh,
we'll push that off to some other day
because it's so crazy.
But it's really not that crazy anymore.
What's happening is more and more people
are getting more and more access to
power and that's why hackers,
for example,
might be able to at some point in the
future bring down entire systems if
they're able to do that.
So you know,
your,
your questions on how do we stop that?
Do we try to make everyone,
you know,
live in harmony.
I'm not a big believer that because to
make them live in harmony is probably
too.
We've tried that for ages,
you know,
programs that make everyone live better.
We're too competitive as,
as a species.
I think you need to use technology to
not only advance the species but sort of
to protect the species.
And this,
this is difficult because I,
I try,
I try to hold some libertarian values
and those values include not impeding a
technology,
not impeding the right to use the things
you want.
But I think that technology can really
help guide us if we use it.
Like everyone talks about surveillance
for example,
and how,
you know,
all of a sudden we live in this great
surveillance world.
We're,
everything we're doing is tracked and
watched and there's all these cameras.
But the reality is actually,
if you look at it,
a lot of the surveillance has made the
world safer and better for,
uh,
for our children,
for ourselves.
And yet we still,
a lot of us have the freedoms that I
think we all want it.
I mean,
I still feel like a very free person
almost all the time,
not happy paying taxes,
whatever,
everyone else the same way.
But the bottom line is we live in a
pretty free world and that's technology
has made it safer at the same time
without really compromising our
freedoms.
I think we can continue going down that
path where we can use technology to
continue to monitor people,
a monitor the kinds of things that make
it very dangerous for an individual to
get,
you know,
a subtype of power in his hands that we
can remake universities or whatever.
Or just the microbiology lab where he
creates a virus and then releases it
into the water supply.
I think we can use technology to stop
that.
But at the same time,
I think we can use technology to grow
the species as a whole.
It's a very fine balance because we're
probably going to have to give up some
freedoms.
We're probably going to have to accept
that,
um,
this idea of absolutely no government or
this idea of too much government,
you know,
governments are going to have to change
as technology grows,
technology is going to be leading
governments from here on out.
It's tech,
it's government's gonna have to look to
technology to find their solutions.
Not,
oh well,
let's use technology on occasion to
solve this.
Um,
technology is in the driver's seat and I
don't think a lot of people realize that
anymore.
They think they're in the driver's seat
or they think we can still control that
all.
But the reality is our life is so
determined by the amount of structure
that progress and technology has put in
our lives.
It's no escaping it anymore and yet it's
done very good thing.
So I think we need to continue with it
and put more of our faith into it.
And that might mean more regulation,
more observance,
more tracking.
Eventually we're all going to be
interconnected with chips.
So this idea of,
you had mentioned earlier,
maybe in 10 years you'll be able to read
my thoughts.
I have,
um,
recently put on some of the,
uh,
the head reading equipment and done a
few articles on it.
The brainwave reading stuff is
fascinating.
I'm a singularity university professor
Jose credential.
Uh,
we were at the world future society.
I'm in Florida a few months ago speaking
together and he said,
so spoken language won't be here in 20
years.
Bice said spoken language won't be here.
So I did an article on that and he said,
look,
brainwave.
He works at Singularity University as a
professor there.
Any brainwave technology is increasing
so quickly in the last two years.
It's jumped in another two years.
It's going to jump in 10 years.
We're going to have the ability and you
know,
just last year or I guess it's about
eight months ago,
a man in a person in India and a person
in France had the telepathy thoughts and
they were without saying a word to each
other.
He said hello.
And the other one said Chow.
And that's just the start in five years
everything is going to.
Can you explain that technology to
folks?
Sure.
So basically it uses this egg
technology,
which is a very complicated word to say,
but I'll just say it's that technology
and essentially the brain creates
certain types of waves when you have
certain types of thoughts and various
places of the body and very various
places of the brain and the headgear you
have can read it and it knows based on
algorithms,
based on a lot of repetitious practices.
If you're thinking like fly a helicopter
for example,
the army is working on flying
helicopters with using these brainwave
headsets.
It nose lift,
it knows,
turned left and knows turn right based
on the soldiers,
you know,
repeated like saying okay.
Experimenting and saying okay,
this always means the same thing and
they've put it so good together that
they know when you say hello and they
know when you say goodbye now.
And if you can send that to another
person and then it can stimulate that
person the same way.
It's able to an a very basic level right
now.
Tell that person that what you feel or
what you,
what you actually said,
except it comes through in that feeling
and your thoughts and I'm not,
I'm not a scientist,
I'm not doing it very eloquently,
but that's the basic structure of it.
And the idea is eventually we'll have
signals going in and signals coming out
that ultimately can make us here these
things in our head,
you know,
I mean we're hearing stuff in her head
right now,
but we're doing through our senses,
but if we bypass the census and just go
right to the neurons and stimulate them,
it'd be the same thing.
And that's essentially what they're
trying to do with that,
with that type of technology.
It's very primitive right now,
but it's growing so fast and there's a
huge amount of people that think the
brainwave reading headsets will become
the next iphone technology,
which is,
you know,
why,
why do we need an iphone when you can
just wear this little device in your
head and you're like,
tell your,
you know,
tell your wife this or tell you,
I want to take out pizza here.
I want to reserve a flight,
you know,
we're going to have Siri that's going to
be much more improved in a few years and
all these things will be digitally just
done through your thoughts.
So you know,
this singularity professor who I totally
believe said we probably won't be
speaking to each other.
We'll be at,
we'll be at a conference and everyone
will be plugged in and you'll be
thinking these things because it's a lot
easier just to think it and you know,
and is that different than what we're
doing right now with our headsets,
like I said,
the ears,
the interface.
But if you just go right to brainwaves
and stimulate those places in the brain
that know how to recognize it will learn
this new form of communication.
My article is based on,
um,
whether,
whether we'll need second languages
because google translate already
translates things instantaneously.
So,
and I suffered through six years of
Spanish and I've been working on trying
to teach my daughter Chinese and Spanish
right now and I,
my wife,
and are like,
yes,
we must go through it.
But I said,
well,
do we really need to,
what if we all have headsets that do
instant translations with anyone on the
planet through our thoughts?
You know,
and this is the kind of thinking where
it's like,
wow,
that's real transunion thinking because
maybe all second languages will die out.
We will.
We'll just go to one language.
In my book I talk about bond,
which is there's various types of
languages out there that are better for
communicating a scientific ideas or
logical ideas and they don't consider,
you know,
English has all sorts of imperfections
in it and that's why it's sometimes
difficult to learn in.
Most languages have imperfections,
but a couple of scientists have worked
on other forms of languages that are
much more easier,
for example,
to program into a computer.
There's types of languages that a
computer can process a lot more simply
than,
for example,
English.
If you're trying to teach a computer a
language and because you know there's
feminists and a masculine types of
endings and things like that that can
trick things if they're irregular,
but certain languages don't have any
irregular things.
And so scientists worked on these
languages,
but the idea is that eventually we might
arrive in 20 years at a perfect language
that we'll all use.
It'd be our communication will be a lot
quicker and more expedient,
simpler,
and um,
it'll all be done through brainwaves and
uh,
you know,
the world will be a very different
place.
I mean,
think of it without just one single
language,
just thinking about things.
So it'll be some sort of tower of Babel
type shit.
We're going to have that inside of our
head with some technological
Lee created translation device that
allows us to utilize this universal
language that computers create.
My,
I feel so dumb just listening to this.
my mouth is starting to unconsciously
go slack.
I'm glazing over and I talk about it,
but I don't know any of the ins and outs
of it because the kind of,
you know,
the question of like how technically do
they do this?
The scientists that are working on this
have spent their entire lives on this
and the other scientists that are trying
to look into it don't even know what
they're doing.
And they're experts on it and then you
have people like myself discussing it's,
it's amazing,
but you know,
it's true that it happened.
And that's,
I think the more important thing is that
they're developing these things and
especially these brainwave reading
technologies.
There's now a number of companies that
are selling it and I'm sure at the local
target and uh,
you know,
that's already here.
God,
that is so crazy.
But she's so hard to wrap their mind
around the potential of something like
that.
Some,
some sort of an bit.
I mean,
if you think about like what originally
what Morse code was,
did he did,
did,
did.
And now you know,
you send a text message and now you can
talk into your phone and send a text
message.
I have,
um,
uh,
you know,
they have that google voice thing that
you can,
um,
or uh,
not,
not google voice,
but you could use google voice does
work.
Well,
you could ask Google questions,
but I have this,
um,
this,
uh,
application on my phone with the iphone.
It's a notepad and I,
when I have ideas when I'm in my car,
I just talked to the phone and it
transcribes it and it's almost perfect
except for weird words and it doesn't
understand generally like if you said to
it,
concentrate on new technology that makes
sure that people can see like eagles,
it'll do that and make it perfect.
I'm gonna.
Have you ever messed with it?
No,
I haven't,
but I've seen it like,
watch this.
We'll do it right now because it's just,
it's just so crazy how good it's gotten.
Like you just press this little button
right here.
Concentrate on new technology that
allows people to see as well as eagles
do.
Bam.
Perfect.
Absolutely perfect.
And I just talked like a normal person I
talked to,
like I would normally if I was trying
to,
you know,
send a message to someone who was trying
to communicate to someone and it takes
it and it's doing it right now while I'm
doing that.
Wow,
that's incredible.
You should,
uh,
you should type in the Google the mine,
waive reading post photos to twitter,
you know,
they now have devices where you can
actually post directly to twitter and
facebook by thinking it based on those
devices I was just telling you about.
That's incredible.
My thought was the difference between
Morse code,
which they created a language teacher
did,
did it it,
they had to create a certain amount of
sounds that may mean an ass,
a certain amount of sounds that mean a
zero,
you know,
there was all these different or an o
rather.
There's all these different sounds that
correspond with letters and then you had
a piece that together and create a
language out of it or create a word out
of it.
Now you're able to just say the word and
it transcribes it,
but eventually if this technology comes
to fruition and you'll have a thought
and that thought will be transcribed to
a universal language that someone in
India,
someone in Zaire,
someone in South America,
anyone anywhere,
no matter what they speak,
we'll use this language and it's
possible that there won't be any other
languages other than this,
you know,
like we used to.
Cursive used to be standard.
I mean,
I had alert at growing up,
um,
my kids don't know it.
They don't know what it is.
My daughter is six and they don't teach
cursive anymore.
It's gone and they're going to typing
will be gone to typing.
Probably by the time my 11 month old
gets to six.
I'm wondering if they're going to even
do typing because a lot of it will
eventually just be what you said,
verbally speaking or thinking,
you know,
and,
and it's all,
it's amazing.
All these technologies that we thought
were so breakthrough eventually get to a
point when they're so obsolete and you
think,
and then you try to tell a younger
person what it was like and they just
look at you like,
I don't get it.
Why did you do that?
Do you have a voice navigation system on
your car?
Um,
no,
I just use everything on my iphone.
I'm for a transhumanist.
I'm not very,
uh,
high tech with that side,
just like talking about it.
No,
but I don't actually have that much
technology in my house.
In fact,
we don't even have a television.
You don't have a television now,
you know,
we just.
How do you watch TV then?
Have,
we don't have a TV.
We just uh,
we watched dvds and stuff like that on a
computer,
you know,
we have a big giant screen.
We just don't,
we have no TV whatsoever.
Not even local access.
Oh,
I see.
So you have a big TV,
you just don't have cable or satellite.
Yeah.
So with the Internet we just use the
Internet for everything and it's just
kind of like.
It's funny because I think TV is one of
those things where for 30,
40,
50 years it was such a mainstay and then
all of a sudden you're trying to teach
your kids and say,
well they hear it at school and they're
like,
well we don't have it.
It's not nearly necessary anymore,
you know?
And eventually I'm not even sure a big
giant screen TV will be necessary.
Might just be,
well I guess one thing that you carry
around or an eye and a ipad or something
like that.
I mean it's constantly in flux and
that's the great thing about it is just
constantly changing.
I mean,
um,
yeah.
I wonder if will you know,
if in five years you'll be using a
laptop for what you're doing now,
might just be using probably be
something more projected from a hologram
or something like that from the ceiling.
Yeah.
I've seen those and I've seen the,
you know,
the,
the new watches that exists,
like on like a little bit of a fitbit
thing and it projects an image on your
wrist and you could touch it and play
with it the same way that you would like
a touchscreen on a,
on an actual phone.
I mean this following that I have now,
I got this big iphone,
I have an iphone and I also have this
big Samsung Galaxy s five.
And with both of them they're so big and
so good that I oftentimes I go on the
road,
I don't use a laptop anymore.
I answer all my emails on this,
on the Samsung and it's just,
it's plenty big for images.
It's plenty big for a web surfing.
The only reason I even use a laptop is
because the companies make,
it's another programs actually work with
each other and sometimes the laptop is
the only way to make it,
you know,
with the sock flash and stuff like that.
And they do that purposely because they
want you to buy as many gadgets as
possible.
But,
you know,
eventually they'll,
uh,
you know,
I,
I heard something like 30 years worth of
technology now fits into an iphone,
you know,
30 years because you can watch movies on
it,
you can music on it,
you can do all your,
if you're in math class,
you can do your calculators and stuff
like that.
And television is now on an iphone,
so that's how small it's gone.
But I bet another 30 years it's going to
get to something you're the size of your
thumbnail and inside your head.
And uh,
you know,
we'll have all this recording will be
done with no equipment.
Just probably be big giant tables.
Yeah.
I remember my first computer,
I had some crappy Mac that I bought that
I don't even think it had a one gigabyte
hard drive.
I mean,
I don't think,
I don't think they existed back then.
I got a computer in 1994 from comp USA,
which doesn't even exist anymore.
And I,
I think I'm pretty sure it was less than
one gigabyte.
And then I remember in the future I,
I ordered a computer that had a four
hard drive
and I'm like,
this is fucking crazy for getting the
bites now my phone is a hundred and 28
gigabytes and it's this little tiny
narrow thing.
This has a case on it and it's narrow
and it just slides right into your
pocket.
It's got a 128 gigs,
you know in this one,
the Samsung has cards,
you slide in new ones,
he can stick in 64 gigs,
128 gigs.
You can just keep sticking in little
tiny SD cards.
They're so small and there are 128 gigs.
I mean it doesn't even make sense
anymore.
And you know,
with the cloud,
the cloud is definitely where the future
is.
It's,
it's going to be no more gigabytes on
our phones.
Everything will just be interconnected.
Will all have these floating big giant
databases above us.
And I already am,
use the cloud for a lot of my stuff
because I do a lot of videos and photos
of the kids and it just adds up too much
space on the actual phone.
And uh,
and I realized that,
you know,
you could run programs,
you can just run entire computers in the
cloud now,
you know,
it's just all about the new programs
coming out and eventually everything
will just be probably a hologram screen
connected to somewhere way up there.
What,
I mean,
it's obviously metaphorical but will be
interconnected that way without actually
even having much of a device.
So yeah,
it's,
and that's probably five years away that
what I'm speaking about.
I mean,
I think the cloud is probably one the
most heavily invested things of gadget
technology that they're trying to do
right now.
And eventually we'll all be
interconnected to the story.
I just did an artificial hearts,
you know,
it's such an interesting story because
they just did the second completely
robotic artificial heart surgery on a
patient in France and robotic hearts
have been around for 10 or 15 years or
maybe even 20.
But they were always,
um,
a way to keep someone alive until they
found a transplant heart,
but they're now starting to do robotic
hearts that replace the real heart.
And that's it.
That's the only heart that person's
going to have for the rest of his life
or her life.
It's so far been two guys and I'm so.
We've just,
in the last 12 months,
we've crossed that with now robotic
hearts are no longer just a temporary
replacement.
They are the final replacement and
they're all Wifi,
uh,
in,
they all have wifi.
Things about in my article is like,
if you want to be in a fight,
you could pump up your heart with your
cell phone,
for example,
if you're in the ring and then you could
fight that much better if I'm a surfer
and big waves or if you want to meditate
or sleep,
you know,
you could put it to sleep.
Boats,
you're heart goes slower,
you know,
instead of these are the ways you're
going to be able to control the
technology in your life.
And the interesting thing I found about
the,
uh,
the story I did was Dick Cheney or the
former vice president had this kind of
little device that was attached to one
of his,
uh,
the valves in his heart and uh,
I don't know if you'd read,
but he was actually afraid of terrorist
attacks because that was wifi controlled
as well.
That was an episode of homeland.
Yeah.
Know they used that kind of technology
to hack into someone's heart.
So the technology is coming.
It's crazy,
but they're going to start doing that
and when people are actually really
worrying about that kind of stuff too,
it's actually here today and I'm so,
you know,
it's just a totally brave new world.
But it's also pretty awesome because
when you think of the possibilities of
having a robotic heart and now you want
to go,
for example,
uh,
you want to be a go free diving.
I like free diving and you want to go
down as far as you can,
maybe a couple hundred feet.
Um,
this is the kind of time you could
program your heart to actually work with
you.
Like I said,
do you want to sleep or do yoga or even
have sex,
you know what I mean?
All of a sudden you could program your
heart to be a different person than you
might've been normally.
Well,
that was one of the things in trance,
a transcendental man where they were
talking about the potential using
nanobots or artificial blood cells,
the you'd be able to hold your breath
under water for an hour,
just just,
you know,
just using these artificial blood cells
that get created.
They just.
Yeah.
This last year was one of the big things
for that where they now have some kind
of injection when,
for example,
someone has a been a drought for 30
minutes and they can inject it into your
blood supply.
It's one of the first things that are
trying to put forth that they can now do
it in an accident like that,
but it works in the same way.
We're allows you to hold oxygen in your
body a lot longer than you normally
would have.
And so of course,
yeah.
You know,
one of my very first opening articles
after the book was on the transhumanist
Olympics,
and this is this idea that instead of
having so many strict regulations
regarding drug control and what
technology you can use during real
competition,
why not make it competition where you,
anything goes,
we're weightlifters can use any types of
enhancers and,
uh,
you know,
and athletes can use any type of
technology they get their hands on and
uh,
you know,
it's crazy because,
for example,
if you did this thing with,
um,
you know,
the oxygen cells,
maybe all swim races will be underwater.
It's considered that,
you know,
all of a sudden you can be,
one can go underwater long enough.
That's why sometimes when you see
backstrokers,
I used to be a swimmer.
They kick as far as they can under water
because they can go faster.
There's less resistance problems.
No one can hold their breath long
enough.
And so all of a sudden,
if you could do that,
it could change the face of swimming.
Um,
and the same thing can happen with
almost any sport that you think of,
especially powerlifting,
when you actually need a burst of
energy,
instead of lifting what they're lifting
now,
they might be able to lift three or four
times that with steroids that are just
designed for it to give you 10 seconds
of just pure rage.
But the problem with that is what we
look for in competition,
what we look for in sports is someone
transcending the ability of the average
person with discipline and focus and
drive and will that they work really
hard and concentrate really hard on
their technique.
And then they get to some point where
there a Michael Jordan or some
Olympic power lifter.
If you could just program it in,
what would be the point of watching it?
We would like to eliminate a lot of the
really magical moments in sport because
we're going to create a bunch of super
athletes,
but on the other hand,
if you don't do it,
you know,
my take on it is going to be that we're
going to be able to manipulate
biological bodies in a way where you're
going to be able to literally create an
incredible hulk like someone is going to
be that and if we're watching athletes
that are totally natural and have all
these limitations,
but your mailman can jump over your
fucking house.
Like we're going to be bored with
regular sports.
They're not going to have the ability.
But W who is going to watch football if
everybody's the hulk,
you know,
I mean if you have a team of 16 hulks on
one side and 16 hawks and the other and
it's all about moving a ball across the
line.
I mean,
what kind of a fucking world are we
going to be living in?
And I think that's,
you know,
from just even a commercial perspective.
That's why I liked the idea of having
two separate types of sporting
endeavors.
For example,
you have the stuff we have now because I
totally agree with you.
I've been an athlete my whole life.
Did water polo through college and stuff
like that.
The idea is,
you're right,
the whole point of it is that I worked
my butt off and I got.
I was good at it,
you know,
and.
But it's kind of cheating if someone
gets to take a drug just because the
scientists developed it and he had more
money and that,
you know,
to do it and then they're better.
And that's why I think maybe two fields
could be created like one transhumanist
Olympics won Olympics,
whatever it is,
sporting cheap.
The regular people would pretend,
well yeah,
not transhumanist cheat mean that's what
you have.
And I mean that was the big argument
about Lance Armstrong.
Lance Armstrong got busted cheating and
they,
they took away his tour de France wins,
but if you want to go back to the person
that hasn't tested positive for drugs on
the Tour de France,
you got to go back to like 17th place
because everybody was cheating.
So it gets to this point where like,
is it cheating and everybody's cheating
or is it just some unfortunate aspect of
this competition that people don't admit
what they need to do in order to be able
to race like this?
Well,
I think everything will,
if you do go the transhumanist
competition route,
everything was sort of become like race
car competition where you have a really
good driver but then you have engineers
behind him that make the vehicle so that
he can get that far.
And.
And that's part of the cool thing is
like you're like,
well he has this engineer from Porsche
or whatever,
and they become sort of celebrities or
you know,
in the transhumanist Olympics world,
I think scientists would maybe become
celebrities as much as,
or you know,
become popular figures because you would
really say,
well,
he's the one who made this athlete and
the athlete and this athlete do all
those records.
So it would be kind of different.
I think maybe even a different word
should be used.
It wouldn't be sports anymore,
it might be something new because it
would be something so different.
You would be taking the coaches and the
engineers and scientists behind that
athlete to a whole nother level.
Yeah.
What would that be?
I mean,
I think part of what we love about
sports is the fact that we know it's so
difficult to become a great athlete.
It involves like the dedication of like
go back to the movie rocky.
Like one of the things that people loved
about it was that he got up when he was
tired,
he hit that alarm clock.
He drank the raw eggs,
went jogging,
you know,
he was doing all these things that he
didn't want to do to push his body to
reach this level of fitness that allowed
him to go and fight Apollo creed.
You know,
a guy who really was out of his league.
He rose the occasion with hardwell and
to heart and will and determination and
hard work that that's what excites us
about sports is that we know it's hard
to do if it becomes easy to do.
I mean if the average person can go to
some transhumanism clinic and get a shot
of nanobots and become,
you know,
some ultra man,
some,
some person that has capabilities far
beyond your normal biological body.
We,
you know,
we might lose interest.
We might lose interest.
No,
you're right.
But you know,
the,
the problem is what you said and you
nailed right on the head when you said,
well,
what are you going to do in the mail?
Man is a better basketball player than
Michael Jordan.
Just because he's on these,
you know,
he's taking these things or you know,
a 10 year old who puts on a certain
exoskeleton suit,
just runs as faster than a horse and
then,
you know,
it doesn't matter what if you're in
Olympia Olympia,
a sprinter it,
I'm sorry,
but aren't sports kind of silly in that
sense.
I mean we're concentrating on this,
this thing that we talk about this,
this competition aspect of our lives,
but if we reached some incredible
transcendent point in,
in,
in the
physical abilities of people because of
technology,
does it really?
The sport really matter anymore.
I mean it's kind of a silly thing to
concentrate on about this being the one
thing that we're going to lose.
Like who gives a shit if that ball goes
in that net,
you know,
he made a basket.
Woo.
Does it really change the world?
No.
Or is it far more impressive that the
average person no longer has the
limitations that the biological body?
Yeah.
No,
I mean I,
I,
I think to some extent probably.
Well,
you know,
I guess when we care for,
I don't think sports will fade away
because sports has become one of the
greatest methods that people use to
become great,
you know,
that it's one of the inspiring events
that we have as a species that brings us
together and so it's hard to see that
going away.
But I guess if everyone has access to
this incredible technology,
they may not be necessarily like so
involved in it right now.
For example,
the Super Bowl is one of America's big
giant events.
I'd never,
I don't really understand why it's that
way,
but um,
it's hard to see that changing anytime
soon.
Even if we get really crazy access to
technology somehow that's become
kind of part of our culture,
these,
this type of competitive,
friendly,
competitive,
uh,
you know,
endeavors that we do.
The World Cup just came in.
I remember that was like when,
when do you actually have so many people
all thinking of the same thing?
Well,
isn't like steroids and you know,
and even supplements to that to a
certain extent,
aren't they essentially look low level
engineering of the human body.
I mean it's,
it's like a low level genetic
engineering.
I mean that's what you're doing when
you're adding steroids,
you're adding a chemical to a system
that forces that system perform and
exemplary matter.
That's really not possible without the
steroids.
Now it's totally.
I think it's totally fine.
Yeah,
it's.
They may say it's unnatural,
but what is unnatural?
I mean in today's Day and age,
everything is on natural shit.
Everything's on natural.
Well,
I mean every grading it.
It's true.
If you will.
Where the fuck did that come from?
Well,
from a certain perspective,
everything is kind of like,
you know,
if it comes from certain elements,
it's,
it's there,
it's natural.
Use it.
What if you use it,
if it's useful and functional,
well,
isn't everything that human beings
create?
In fact natural because we are natural
and we have.
We have a built in curiosity and a built
in thirst and hunger for innovation.
That is.
I mean,
how much different is that than a
natural animal that for just for food.
I mean that is what they do.
I mean,
it is natural that they dig a hole in
the ground and find the routes that
they're looking for,
the,
the animals that they want to eat.
All these things are natural.
I invest.
Why I,
I've been.
Everyone says,
oh,
so zoltan the transhumanism stuff you're
doing is so unnatural.
I say actually,
it's potentially the most natural thing
that you know,
we have done.
Becoming robots might actually be a
incredibly natural process,
uh,
for human beings one day.
And uh,
you know,
that's just,
it's evolution.
So how can it not be a natural thing?
But you know,
just,
it's all perception.
And if people want to twist it and say,
oh,
it's just too weird for me,
it's not in any way that it's just too
weird for them.
It's not in any,
like big statements saying that it's
unnatural for us to transform ourselves.
Whether we're creating steroids,
whether we're putting microchips inside
her head or whether we're just putting
on an exoskeleton suit and climbing
Mount Everest.
I mean this,
these are,
they're always going to be natural
things.
I wish people would see that technology
more as a natural phenomenon rather than
some type of like,
outside thing that comes in as an alien
and that we're slowly started using,
you know,
I think if you had told someone a
century go,
hey,
we're all going to be interconnected on
the cell phone and this and this
internet and we're going to be doing
video conferencing across the oceans.
Uh,
people would have looked at you and said
he's got mental problems.
You know,
it's crazy.
And now everyone does it.
I mean,
I,
I know they have cell phones and some of
the poorest villages in Africa.
It's incredible how far it's come and
it,
there's nothing unnatural about it.
It's in fact,
it's just amazing stuff that's going to
keep getting more
amazing.
That's the one thing that gives me the
most hope about technology is that
somehow or another it will raise up the
level of the quality of life for people
that live in poor areas.
And the cell phone is a perfect example
of that.
It used to be Gordon Gecko on the beach
with that big ass brick phone in,
you know,
in Wall Street.
And that was like,
wow,
this guy's got access to a phone and
he's walking on the beach.
This is super high tech and now you
know,
I've been to Brazil and seen people in
the favelas,
in these poor neighborhoods that have
cell phones and have smartphones,
iphones or android phones.
And this is becoming more and more
prevalent all throughout the world in
Africa and all these different places.
Um,
I think the quality of life and as far
as the access to health care as far as
the ability to communicate with each
other as far as the access to modern
comforts,
that's the one thing that gives me the
most hope about the exponential growth
of technologies that I hope it elevates.
The quality of life for the people that
are stuck in the lowest one percent,
five percent,
10 percent,
whatever it is in the world.
That slowly,
that life will be a far better,
far less suffering,
far,
far easier existence.
And that they,
in fact with this technology can
concentrate on other things because the,
uh,
the technology frees up a lot of
resources and they'll,
it allow them to raise up their quality
of life,
raise up their education,
raise up their healthcare,
raise up their government,
like all of these things will in fact
raise the.
We look at Africa as a perfect example.
We look at the Congo,
which is this incredibly rich area in
terms of resources but incredibly poor
in terms of the quality of life for the
people that lived there.
And if we could somehow or another raise
that up where like the people that live
in the Congo have the same quality of
life as the people that live in the
average American city city.
You would have a radically different
world,
a radically different world.
I mean,
it would change everything like that.
That could be one of the biggest changes
that technology brings in the world.
The elevation of the quality of life,
of the average person on the planet.
No,
and I totally agree.
In fact,
it's one of the big reasons I'm such a
big proponent or a promoter of the
Internet because the one thing the
Internet has done,
I did a huge amount of reporting,
I think 13 or 14,
you know,
a Muslim or Middle Eastern countries for
National Geographic.
I went to various places and,
um,
it,
the great thing about the Internet is
it's offered a sense of democracy and
even though a lot of those places still
don't really have it.
This is why we had some of the uprisings
I think recently,
is that you get enough people on the
Internet and they find out things.
They're like,
wow,
this is what some person is doing in Los
Angeles.
Why don't we do that here?
And that's happened because there's
computers or cell phones that are slowly
appearing in these places that never had
access to that.
It's inevitable to stay in your culture,
especially if it's kind of some type of
authoritarian culture.
If you have access to that kind of
information because it makes you upset
and you're gonna,
you're gonna revolt.
And that's brilliant.
That's why cell phones are so important.
And just even regarding the malaria
thing we talked about earlier in the
Solomon Islands,
one of the reasons so many people die
from malaria is they can't get access to
the drugs.
But if you can call someone and have
them,
a healthy person make the walk over the
mountain,
they can bring you the drugs.
But the problem is,
in the past there's been no way to call.
There's no telephone lines,
but cell phones have enabled that to
happen.
Cell phones is one of the main reasons
that a lot of villages in Africa,
I'm sorry,
a lot of villages in Africa have cell
phones for this reason,
for literally medical reasons so that
people can come in and take out sick
people when otherwise have to walk days
just to get into,
you know,
to get them to help.
And so,
I mean,
this kind of technology is literally
changing the face of how especially poor
people live and making them live better
longer.
And so that mortality rates are just,
everything's getting better.
And I'm,
I'm totally hopeful that tech.
Everyone says,
oh,
you know,
big brother for technology,
or uh,
you know,
it's a new world order.
I have a lot of conspiracy theorists had
always leave me threats,
but I keep saying that,
you know,
you threats,
oh,
they leave me threats because I'm,
you know,
now saying a lot of stuff like I
advocate for using microchips and
people's heads and,
and using technology as means to improve
life,
but they think it's all part of the
elite trying to control us.
And I always say that,
but the fact is that all people around
the world are getting more and more
access to this technology that's
improving their lives.
You know,
if that's what the elite do.
I'm not saying there's a lead behind
anything,
but if that's what they do,
then that's a good thing because it's
happened that way.
It's not an elite thing.
It just happens to be that it costs a
lot of money to develop technology at
first and it takes a few years to
trickle down.
Maybe it takes a few decades,
but history has shown that most
technology has trickled down from
wherever it came from and that some of
the poorest people in the world have
access to a,
to a lot of the development that has
come through the pipeline.
I had the,
uh,
a few weeks ago I debated John Zerzan.
He's the leading philosopher of the NRA.
I'm kind of capitalistic.
Well,
he,
he's a,
uh,
he's based gonna,
anti civilization philosopher.
He really advocates for going back to
entirely primitive lifestyle.
And uh,
we had a debate at Stanford University
and it went well.
He's a nice guy,
but he,
he,
he represents kind of the anarchists and
my book has some anarchist theme so I
can't completely disassociate myself
from some of the radical and
revolutionary ideas that are there.
But at the same time,
he advocates for things that would
absolutely harm some of the poorest
people in the world.
Harm,
uh,
basically everyone by giving up the
things that have made us live longer and
better when you actually,
my wife is a doctor,
so she's done a lot of work in Africa.
When you take away technology and
medicine and modern science from the
people,
especially the poorest people,
they have a very hard time surviving.
They go right back to the way a lot of
tribal people had lived for long times
where people die from a cavity,
people die from the simplest of
infections.
Um,
we now have ways to deal with all of
that.
So lifespans are growing grain that just
growing in America,
they're growing all around the world.
They're growing in Africa and they are
getting better.
So what does this guy want?
What does he want to happen?
So I'm like a primitive way of life.
Like,
yeah.
So he advocates,
he says that all harm came from
basically the development of technology
and kind of,
um,
basically when we lived in tribes and we
were in very communal tribes,
we were much happier as human beings.
I've heard this shit so many times
before.
It drives me bananas.
What's this dude's name?
John Zerzan,
spelled Z E R,
z a n.
and we literally just had a big kind of
public debate at Stanford University
recently.
And it went well,
but it was a little bit crazy.
The NRF has outnumbered the
transhumanist in the auditorium,
like four to one.
It was a little bit sketchy actually.
And they're there.
The black bloc guys,
you know,
the,
the guys that go through the Oakland
riots or when you have riots and they
put it on the black stuff,
the black masks and whatnot.
No.
Oh,
you know,
whenever you see like the,
the World Trade Organization,
the people that kind of go to those,
they're called black black people.
They usually,
they try to make themselves completely
anonymous and any was.
There are some of those guys there.
And it was a little bit sketchy because
it was a,
it was a pretty heated.
These guys think that all transhumanists
are aiming to turn the world into
robots.
So they actually feel quite angry.
They,
they really,
they're like,
you want to kill us by making us become
different types of entities?
And Trans humanists say,
well,
you guys want to kill us by taking us
back to a domestic,
you know,
into this kind of very primitive
lifestyle where most of us couldn't
survive because we'd all starve.
There's not enough hunter and gathering.
So they want to hunt.
Yes.
They want to take us back essentially to
a hunter and gatherer lifestyle.
And that's,
that's,
that's their platform.
Yes.
That's 100 percent of their platform,
the whole world hunter and gatherer
hunter.
One hundred percent and the whole world.
But that doesn't work with 7 billion.
No,
no,
I know that.
And they,
they know that too.
Yet they advocate in the same way that
like,
um,
some people advocate things that they're
trying to make a point that technology
has made human beings unhappy.
And our point is that technology has
made human beings live better and longer
and happier.
And so they advocate
for that.
And it's a big,
pretty big movement.
I mean,
there's certainly a lot bigger than
transhumans.
So all these guys,
they hunt for their own food.
They know that vegetables,
they're all hypocrites in that sense.
And because even this is not criticism
of there and there's really no way for,
for example,
for to even get a Mr Jersey on to a
debate.
He had to fly in from Oregon to malaria.
We use speakers,
he wears clothes,
but he has a watch.
So anyways,
John Sears on is the,
he's the,
he was the confidence of the unabomber
and that's why he.
He's kind of taken over the unibomber
position.
He will,
he knew the unibomber.
He knew he was,
he was a good friend of his who was
there during the entire court
proceedings.
Oh,
fucking Christ.
So this is why I had a lot of threats
because you know,
when you're debating him,
you're sorta debating some of the ideas
of the unibomber who still has a large
following.
You know,
the UNIBOMBER,
they screwed his mind up.
And the Harvard Lsd Studies,
I actually don't know that much about
him.
Oh my God.
This.
He was a part of those original lsd
studies and I believe it was the sixties
before they made lsd illegal and they
fucking torched that guy's brain.
I mean,
they,
Harvard did a bunch of series of
experiments on people with LSD and the
results of those experiments are all
classified,
but there's a documentary called the net
that went into great detail.
I believe it was a German documentary
that talked about,
but it's very public.
It's public knowledge that he was
involved in the Harvard lsd studies and
it's very likely that they cooked his
fucking brain with extraordinary,
extraordinarily large doses of Lsd in
these clinical settings and who knows
what kind of tests they ran on these
guys and.
But he came out of that,
went to Berkeley and made enough money
essentially teaching just to be able to
build this house,
this little small cabin up in the woods
and start his plan to murder people who
were involved in the creation of
technology.
I mean the fact that anybody could leave
out that just look only purely at his
philosophy and leave out the fact that
they cook this guy's brain on acid and
who knows what kind of dosages.
I mean if you go back to some of the
studies that they did in the 19 fifties
with soldiers and they did studies with
housewives,
they,
there was varying doses like to give
people a couple,
you know,
like what would be the average hit,
what you would call a couple of hits of
acid.
Now I don't know what the actual dosage
would be,
but they would give them 100 hits,
you know,
they would give them totally
differently.
They would cook their fucking brain with
this stuff and this guy came out of
those studies and there's a direct link.
There has to be.
I mean there's a direct link to several
people that have undergone large doses
of LSD and severely diminished mental
capacities afterwards.
So really diminished abilities to
rationalize reality to,
to view the world through same.
The
same lens that they had before they took
it.
It really can fuck people's heads up and
this guy was one of them.
So the fact that this guy is a proponent
of penske's ideas.
Yeah.
I mean,
if you look at the worst case scenario,
you know,
the I,
robot scenario,
the,
the summoning,
the demon scenario put,
there is some potential that we could be
doing something horribly bad by creating
accelerating technology.
But if we don't,
what,
what did,
what are we doing?
We're limiting ourselves to being
animals.
Well,
let's throw away fucking weapons.
Let's kill things with our face like
Jaguars.
Do you want to go super low tech?
Because everything is technology.
No fucking stone ax is technology course
so he doesn't eat.
It's funny enough,
he doesn't even advocate for a lot of.
He says domestic affairs and he doesn't.
So he was really good friends with for
awhile and then they had a falling out
and in the process has become kind of
the leader of that movement since
because key has been in prison,
we're probably not representing his
ideas accurately but,
but,
but so zero's and essentially you know,
he,
I think he knows what he's advocating
would kill billions of people.
However,
I think know his main message is that
technology,
because for example,
he blames,
he says school shootings is our,
a result,
the increase of school shootings in
America are a result of our discontent
with technology and these are wanting
some of the things we debated about it
at Stanford.
And um,
and I disagree.
I think there are anomalies in the
system.
Their mental health issues.
There are exactly.
And mental health issues happen for a
number of reasons.
And you know,
perhaps the most,
you know,
if everyone has people with mental
health have access to guns,
it just goes wrong sometimes.
Yeah.
And then the media explodes it and you
know,
but ultimately I think,
you know,
and a lot of people feel the same way,
that Sarah Sans ideas are way out there
and he's not taking in the whole
picture,
which is what I feel.
But at the same time,
you know,
he,
he's in charge now,
or at least he's written a number of
books,
were a lot of people follow for
potentially millions of anarchistic
around the world that are taking very
serious issue with.
And so they have kind of are some of
those same people that are now,
I think they attacked recently a google
bus,
a bus,
and there's been some other attacks
including physical attacks.
I'm not exactly sure what happened with
the Google bus.
I think there was some physical attacks
with it,
but they're basically,
you know,
it's,
it's combined with the occupy movements.
It's,
it's all those sort of fringe groups are
starting to say,
well,
there's too much surveillance,
there's too much government.
Uh,
there's too much this,
there's too much technology involved.
And of course transhumanists are pitted
sort of against it all.
Saying actually technology is improving
the lives of everyone.
And you guys couldn't even send your
text or do arrange any of your movements
without all this,
without
all this technology.
So what's happened is,
ever since that moment,
I have been sort of under attack as the
guy who went against their Zan and we're
probably going to have another public
debate because him and I liked each
other.
We were fine talking to each other.
Yet we represent totally extremes.
And he really does advocate going back
to a,
a,
a truly a hunter gatherer lifestyle.
He doesn't do that himself.
No,
he doesn't hunt.
I grow my own food.
I grow vegetables.
I have chickens that I get eggs from and
I hunt,
but I just don't think you can have.
It's not for everybody.
People don't want to.
My friend Steve Rinella,
who's the host of this show,
mediator.
It's a hunting show.
He has a really great point.
He's like,
we've allowed.
Society has come up with all sorts of
methods where we don't have to do
everything.
We don't have to be responsible for
eliminating our own waste,
for getting rid of our own garbage.
We don't have to be responsible for
digging a hole and burying it.
We don't have to be responsible for our
own sewage system.
We don't have to do that anymore.
Society figured out a way,
like there's nothing wrong with a
supermarket.
His idea is that,
yeah,
there is a disconnect when you just pick
up a piece of meat that's neatly wrapped
in Saran wrap and the little foam,
you know trey.
But that's,
that's a part of progress,
it's a part of civilization.
You can go back to hunting if you want.
It is an option,
but it's very difficult to do and most
people are not going to do it.
And that's the reason I like it.
I like doing it.
It makes me feel connected to what I'm
eating.
But you don't have to do it.
There's nothing wrong with going to the
supermarket,
you know,
and the,
the,
this idea that we need to go back to a
hunter gatherer lifestyle.
This is a short sided idea because that
life fucking sucked.
You know,
people die,
they broke their legs and they were
dead.
Get a cavity and they die from cavities.
I mean,
it's just infections,
skin infections,
dead,
you know,
you had an open wound,
dead septic,
dead,
no antibiotics,
no.
All that's technology.
It's,
I,
I find that incredibly shortsighted
know,
and I,
um,
I have had the luck.
One of the ways I actually even got
involved with National Geographic
because I had visited a tribe in Vanuatu
on my sail trip and I was the very first
a foreigner in this tribe in 1995 and
they had never,
I think only two or three people had
actually been off the hill or off the
mountain.
There are a couple of mountains,
mountains to get through in this
mountain range and been to the ocean and
seeing even a town.
So most that people had never seen
anyone outside of people in their
village.
And so I was the very first one to
actually get access into this and I went
back later for National Geographic and
filmed them.
But I have actually seen firsthand a
truly indigenous and authentic tribe and
almost about 40 percent of the kids do
not live until they're like twelfth or
13th
year because they die from various
things.
That's no way to run a society when you
losing almost half of your population,
people you love because of stupid
things.
Snakebites,
malaria,
uh,
disease.
Uh,
you know,
I mean stuff that we can deal with.
Well,
that's why primitive societies are so
into fertility.
Rituals.
There were so incredible infant
mortality rate.
It was just ridiculous,
you know,
I mean,
so much death and it's not a place to be
happy.
It's not a,
it's,
uh,
you know,
I remember I've never been in that
village.
I've been there a couple times,
never been in that village when it
wasn't in a state of mourning.
It's always in a state of mourning.
Mourning their,
their rights late last month,
[inaudible],
they're never going to be in a state of
mourning because someone is always
dying.
And when you have a society like that,
it's incredibly difficult to come up
with technological innovation because
you're constantly worried about staying
alive,
feeding your family,
fighting off the enemy,
whether it's an animal nature,
whatever it is.
Yeah.
No,
totally.
And this is,
it's like,
you know,
in our debate we,
I talked about this,
said,
well,
this is what is so great about,
um,
about,
you know,
our society is that we have time,
leisure time to dedicate to the things
that matter to us.
For example,
you know,
you get a cavity,
you can replace it with a fake tooth and
look,
I can eat steak again.
You know,
as opposed to a,
well you've asked all your teeth,
now you're stuck eating shrubs for
whatever it is.
You know what I mean?
It's worse than chewing gum.
Yeah,
I know what you're saying though.
I know exactly what you're saying.
It's like I think people they fuck up
with this either or thing they fuck up
this black away too far.
It's not a black and white issue.
It's like it is complex and we all have
unlimited amount of technology that we
must use to exist in this world today.
Whether it's close.
If you live in a cold environment that
is technology,
whether it's a vehicle,
a house,
all these things.
We.
These are human creations and human
innovation.
A fucking house itself is a human
creation and if you want to live in a
house,
then you want technology.
I mean that.
That's reality.
Do you not like installation?
We'll guess what installation was
created by humans.
What are you going to use a lighter gets
with that as fuck face.
That's a technology,
right?
We're going to start all your fire with
flint.
Of course,
if you're not,
you're a hypocrite.
Yeah,
no,
of course.
And that's the problem with those
perspectives.
And they are taking the either or
instead of saying,
well,
what is the middle ground?
And I think,
you know,
I guess it's important also that
transhumanists take a step back and try
to work with other groups and say,
well,
there are times,
and I agreed with a few of his points.
There are times that technology does
alienate us or make us forget some of
the better parts that we've just talked
about.
Like,
well,
what do we really want to live in a
universe that's totally robotic?
Maybe it's boring.
So there are,
we do need to keep some of the
ridiculousness as we discussed in our
lives or some of the,
uh,
the chaos.
But,
um,
uh,
an advocation should going and just
advocate going back words to such an
extreme.
It was such a farfetched
idea.
But,
um,
you know,
I,
I think,
like I said,
it's a big movement and there's a lot of
people that have gone down that path.
Well,
there's nothing wrong with it,
for the individual that's involved in
that movement.
If you want.
Look,
there's plenty of area in Alaska if you
so choose to go and get some land and
build a house and live off the land and
live a subsistence living.
If that's for you,
you can do that,
man,
you can do that.
You can live like that.
And there's a bunch of shows dedicated
to the people that do it.
Lena,
life below zero,
one of my favorite ones is fine.
You can do that.
There's nothing wrong with that.
But to think that society has to do that
too,
man,
you're digging your heels in on a
process that is impossible to slow down
the train left long time.
There's no changing this.
I mean,
we,
this is what we're about now.
It's what we've been about since they
invented metal.
You know,
it's,
it's been a slow process that combustion
engine,
tires,
roads,
all of it is almost an unstoppable
process.
Three d printing is fascinating to me
and that was one of the things I wanted
to bring up when it came to Africa,
when you were talking about the ability
to use cell phones to get medicine.
I'm fascinated by the ability to
actually produce things that produce
things in like things that are necessary
for survival in these villages.
The the ability to instead of have goods
shipped in to produce them and
ultimately maybe even possibly produce
medicine if technology continues to
improve to produce whatever nano bots
that we're going to be able to inject
into our bodies to have a machine that
makes those things so that you can
literally fix people on the spot in any
remote location with these types of
technologies.
I mean,
I think that's something that we have to
look forward to.
You know,
if eventually you can have something
that fits in a backpack that you can
take anywhere in the world that
controlled by some type of wireless
signals and you could promote your like,
you know what?
I need something for this person because
they broke their leg and make it right
there on the spot.
I mean,
imagine what it would do for huge swaths
of the population that are actually
don't have access to that type of.
I mean you could create the malaria
medicine right on there.
So I mean it,
it absolutely stands to change the
world.
And I think three d printing is probably
one of the most exciting things that
have happened in this decade so far.
You know,
as far as things in the press and things
that we're looking forward to.
And I think it has the possibility of,
of totally transforming manufacturing
itself.
There might come a time when everyone in
their house has one and anything that
you need,
whether it's a lava lamp or a,
you know,
a,
a table or A.
I mean you'll be able to create parts of
it or create it and put it together and
everything will come with plans,
you know,
and we can do now with printers,
with,
with photograph printers.
They can print these beautiful high
resolution photographs from a cell
phone.
He take your cell phone,
I don't know how many megapixels these
things have now,
but this new iphone,
the Lens in the camera on them,
it's beautiful.
So you take these incredibly rich
pictures and then you print them and
there's large foot and put it on a frame
and you would never know if you looked
at that frame photo that,
that came off of a regular computer
printer from a cell phone.
I mean,
it's amazing and this is something that
didn't exist 10,
15,
20 years ago.
It's just the technology wasn't
available 20 years ago.
Ten years ago.
They looked like shit.
Today.
They look amazing.
Totally.
And you know,
in the future you're going to probably
print them in your frame and put them
right there on your desk and you're
done.
You know what I mean?
It's,
it's going to be a hologram.
Yeah,
you're right.
Future,
you know,
it's going to already be that.
Which is a crazy.
Have you seen this new technology that
they're using?
What was that shit called?
The with the little elephant and the
guy's hand that was with um,
uh,
the,
the one we did with Lewis from unbox
therapy.
I'll find it,
find it.
I don't know if you even know about
this,
but there's some incredible.
Is that Google that's working on that,
some insane new technology that allows
them to project three d images that are
moving with shadows on your hand.
Like what?
We would have star wars.
You know,
you haven't seen this.
No,
I don't think so.
How dare you magically magically put
this up,
put this up so he can get a look at
this.
But there's a,
there's a website that shows some of the
demos of what's going to be capable,
what's going to be possible with this
technology,
but it's unbelievable.
There's a,
there's one that really gets me because
I have daughters and there's a tiny
ballerina dancing on this girl's bed.
I mean,
look at this.
Oh Wow.
That's brilliant.
Yeah.
There's,
this guy has this for folks listening to
this magic leap l e a p is the name of
this technology.
You can google it.
This guy has his hands open and there's
a small elephant floating and dancing in
his hands and they're going to be able
to project things that aren't really.
They're out in the world and,
and have,
you know,
floating dragons.
I mean,
they're going to be like,
there's a picture here.
We're looking at of these kids looking
at these beautiful sea horses that are
floating above their desk in their
classroom.
This one gets me,
this little girl watching a ballerina
dance on her bed.
I don't know what the projection
mechanism is,
what the technologies involved in like,
what you know,
is it,
where does it come from?
I'm not sure,
but God,
it looks insane.
It's literally incredible that.
I mean,
imagine all the billboards that are all
going to be taken down.
You're just going to project stuff,
but that's just cause car crashes
everywhere.
You know?
It's not a real elephant.
No,
it's an elephant fucking magic leap
shit.
I mean,
there's a whole host of problems.
It will change the entire world of
advertising.
It's just like know the whole thing
because you'll just be like,
but.
And then it'll change the entire thing.
That's.
I haven't seen that yet.
I'm surprised.
When did that come out?
It's pretty recent this month.
Okay.
How dare you not be on the cutting edge,
new,
the transhumanism guy working too hard,
I think you to get on the twitter with
the young kids today.
Well,
we didn't find out about the Lewis came
on it,
explain it to us,
but it's um,
it's mindblowing and this is obviously,
look,
you're pretty in tune with this stuff
and you weren't aware of this and I mean
how many other technologies are on the
verge of announcing that these guys have
been working on for years and you know,
these folks are about to put out and
just we're not,
we're not aware of yet.
When that came out I was like,
oh,
this is one of those leaps that I never
saw coming.
You know,
you're looking at that guy's hands.
If that's real,
if that's a working model that's not a
CGI representation of what they're
actually going to be able to do.
That's mindblowing stuff.
Totally.
I hope it's not like the hover board
thing where they were,
they did you see the hoverboard
commercial that came in and it was like,
it was like,
oh,
but then it ended up not being real,
but then I think in the last few months
they actually did do one that was sorta
real or sort of.
Yeah,
but I'm a surfer and a skateboarder,
so I look forward to that kind of thing.
It just sounds like it's something I
dreamt of,
you know,
when I was a young kid.
I think it's going to be like a
combination of like that hoverboard
technology along with those scooters.
What are those things called?
Those gyroscope scooters.
Now I'm talking about what are those
guys segues.
Yeah,
those segways.
Have you ever written a segway know?
Amazing,
amazing,
cool.
Kevin James,
a good buddy of mine and he was doing
that move the Paul Blart mall cop and
you know,
in that movie he's riding around in this
silly segue and uh,
he got one because of he's like,
dude,
they are amazing.
And I was like,
yeah,
you're riding a scooter.
Is that really fun?
But I rode one.
I'm like,
this is incredible.
You lean forward to make it go and you
lean back to make it stop.
You turned like you shift your weight to
turn with it.
If they're amazing,
really amazing.
I know that they haven't.
Like you can just rent them for a
vacation vacation.
They're really fun,
man.
They're really.
The problem is when they run out of
batteries,
you're fucked because George Bush was on
one,
it went out of batteries and went flying
over the top of it because it's just
stops and it just falls down.
So like when the battery's out,
like you fucking tilt forward and fall
flat on your face because the gyroscope
is somehow or another balancing your
weighed out,
like as you're moving with this thing,
it's sort of correcting,
like going back and forth with you and
when it runs out of batteries long,
how long do they go?
Just good question.
I don't know,
how long can those teslas go when they,
they,
uh,
even those things.
I mean those are amazing,
but they're only good for like 300 miles
on the highway.
Right?
Right.
Yeah.
The,
the,
the electric car thing is going to be,
I mean they're going to,
don't they?
They accelerate far quicker than the
horsepower engine.
Not Quicker but comparable.
Like we were talking about horsepower
wars,
like these new teslas,
the Tesla Model D,
I believe it's comparable to like a
really high end,
like a
sports car right now.
Like I think they're doing zero to 60 in
under four seconds.
They that ability with an electric car
and especially because I think they have
four wheel drives is not as much
traction issues as they have with some
two wheel drive cars.
They're getting there,
you know,
and it's also,
they don't have gears the way like you
have to go first,
gear second gear third,
they just go,
you know because it doesn't have a
combustion engine,
doesn't have to sort of regulate the
power through a transmission the same
way as a completely different kind of
transmission.
So it's all,
it's all pretty amazing stuff.
I used to race motorcycles growing up
and I've been following a little bit of
the electric motorcycle market too,
which just slowly developing.
I didn't even know about that,
but it's not nearly as complex and I
don't know if anyone's making any money
yet,
but they're of course trying to do the
same types of things and they're trying
to do the same types of things with all
sorts of vehicles now including
watercraft vehicles and boats and stuff
like that.
And so the entire market it could
literally change.
And you know,
one of the technologies I love most is
the exoskeleton technology because I
have a feeling that within five years
now,
I think Panasonic is releasing its first
exoskeleton commercially in the next few
months,
at least according to some articles I
did.
Um,
and uh,
it's post costs around $5,000.
I don't know how many are going to be
available.
I'm not sure if it's even on schedule
right now,
but it was a few months ago and
apparently going to be able to walk a
little bit on and lift some very heavy
stuff.
But I'm assuming within five years
you'll be able to run and play sports
and think of some of the activity.
First off,
it's going to change the way a lot of
old unfit,
obese people handle their existence
because either a,
I,
I'm,
you know,
a lot of them can't go outside right
now,
are a lot of them can't get to the goal
from the bathroom to the frigerator
comfortably.
If you're wearing one of these things,
it's going to be a lot easier for a lot
of unfit people to move so that could
revolutionize American specialist since
we have so much obesity and diabetes and
stuff like that.
But I'm pretty sure in five years you're
going to see a lot more sporting events.
Uh,
like things like people running with it
and that'll,
you know,
you just look outside.
People will be jogging and their
exoskeleton suits and they're probably
going to be very soon able to jog as
quickly as maybe horses or even as one
day they'll probably be able to outrun
cheetahs.
It's really just a matter of,
of technology,
you know,
fuck,
10,
55,
60 miles an hour or something,
something crazy that might be 20 years
out.
But the thing is the x.
The great thing about the exoskeleton
technology is that it offers the ability
for a lot of people to use it.
So you know,
some technologies like only 10 percent
of the population would actually use it,
but exoskeleton technology is uh,
uh,
will get a huge amount,
will become probably a,
you know,
a multibillion dollar industry very
quickly.
It already is.
I think I wore one of the cruder,
one's not,
I shouldn't say cruder,
but it's fairly prototypical model.
And uh,
there was a show that I did for Scifi
called Joe Rogan questions everything.
And one of them we went to this place
and I put the suit on and it kind of
walks with you,
it like Kinda like makes your legs walk.
And for people,
we had a guy who was paralyzed from the
waist down and he used this and you
could walk around with it,
but it's attached.
But a tether to this power pack and it's
very large and no,
they're totally bald still.
Yeah.
But it's going to be smaller and smaller
and the power supply is going to be
smaller and smaller.
And as battery technology continues to
evolve,
that's when things are going to get
stranger and stranger and Harvard right
now is working on a soft one,
like a soft excos exoskeleton suit and
they're,
one of the reasons we're working on is
for military people that are carrying
these really heavy backpacks and it's
not supposed to be something sort of
like the steel one where it helps you to
walk.
It's,
it helps you to walk,
but it's not supposed to be like you can
lift stuff with it.
It's just supposed to help you go much
further distances without getting tired.
So it's like adding 20,
30 percent of your walking capacity to
you and you know,
I've seen already the test on them and
Harvard and uh,
it's,
it's pretty brilliant.
Brilliant.
Have you heard about this armor that
Harvard that hardens on impact?
The Harvard exoskeleton.
Oh Wow.
What do,
what do we see in here?
Walking in it.
Yeah.
This is the soft.
That's incredible.
This is the one I think that will really
catch on because people are going to be
a little bit afraid of the metal thing
to get into.
But this is one that I think,
you know,
a lot of people say,
hey,
it's just like a drug.
It's an outfit.
That jogging outfit.
Yeah.
Wow.
And some of the tests that they're doing
with this stuff is.
So this makes you stronger and it can
make you faster and you got a little
fanny pack back there with some
batteries on it.
Yeah.
That the battery packs are gonna get
smaller and smaller.
And that's so interesting is these
people are working on this technology
that people that are working on battery
technology will develop smaller and
smaller batteries and it'll get to a
point where they all work together and
just create these things that we just
can't even wrap our hands around right
now.
Yeah.
Well I mean I look for it because I've
been a motorcycle rider most of my life.
I think the exoskeleton business is very
similar to,
to kind of like what more cycle writing
is.
To me it's recreational.
So if you could put on an exoskeleton
suit and go play different types of
sports or go climbing or,
and stuff like that,
you might find yourself able to do
things that you never would have done
before,
um,
and uh,
and have strength more strength and more
endurance and stuff like that.
So I think an entire recreational,
like,
you know,
um,
enterprise is going to occur because of
it where people start using exoskeleton
technology in the same way that they
would use recreational motorcycles or
recreational boats where we now go do
exoskeleton things together.
We climbed mountains,
climbed cliffs,
we never would've been able to climb
just because we can lift ourselves
instead.
And we have grip that we never would
have had.
Let's play catch with a boulder.
Yeah,
exactly.
You know,
that's crazy.
Stuff like that.
No,
but I mean it's pretty.
It could change.
I think a lot of recreational things and
I'm,
you know,
I think it's also,
like I said,
it's going to be so much money to be
made in that the technology is going to
grow a lot quicker than perhaps other
fields.
So I'm totally excited about it because,
uh,
as I told my wife,
I ruined one of my articles.
I want one for Christmas.
I want the first one coming out.
They're pretty expensive,
so I'm not.
Have you heard of this artificial skin?
They've developed?
It's bulletproof that's made out of
spider silk.
It's,
it's a,
it's an artificial skin that they
believe they're going to be able to put
on human beings.
It's gonna.
Make people bulletproof.
You know,
I've heard of the artificial skin.
I haven't heard of the bulletproof
article.
Discovery Dot Com.
If you want to see if you want to google
it.
For the folks who are listening to your
bulletproof skin made from spider silk.
This is so crazy.
Spiders are coming to the aid of burn
victims.
This is one of the things that they've
figured out a way to use spider silk and
combine it and some sort of a way to
create artificial skin.
And so this Dutch artist,
along with forensic genomicists genomics
genomics consortium in the Netherlands,
created a Swatch,
a swatch right,
as I said,
of nearly bulletproof skin,
made from spider silk and human skin
cells.
That project takes its name from the
maximum weight and velocity.
A type one bulletproof vest can
withstand from a 22 caliber long rifle
bullet.
So this is the image that you're looking
at it as.
That's a bullet that's headed towards
this piece of artificial skin that
they've created.
And the idea is as this technology
grows,
you're eventually going to be able to
replace human skin with artificial skin
that's bulletproof.
What's.
Oh,
that's awesome.
That's another like,
wow,
look,
now nothing happened to me.
Yeah,
you car accident.
I didn't even get scratched.
Yeah,
I'll be
fine.
I mean,
and it's,
it's gonna come a point in time where
we're going to see people removing their
parts and changing,
exchanging them.
They could see the impact of this.
Watch the show.
This again,
Jamie,
you could see the impact of this is so
crazy.
This is on new scientists have this
bullet hitting this spider silk skin.
And looked,
it just bounces it out.
I mean you see the impact of the bullet,
but it,
it doesn't break the skin,
which is just fucking insane.
I mean it's an artificial skin that
you're going to be able to replace your
skin with some day.
I,
I can't.
I can't imagine.
I mean,
I literally can't imagine mean it's
hitting it.
You're going,
you're still going to have to deal with
the impact of the bullet.
When there was other stuff that I was
talking about,
this armor that they've created for
motorcycle riders that hardens on
impact,
that you can mush it in your hand.
It's pliable until it receives an impact
and they do a demo with it where they
have a hammer and they're playing with
it and towing it and pushing it.
And then he hits it with a hammer and
it's hard as a rock.
So you could have this armor on,
fall off your motorcycle and it protects
you.
Like as if you're covered in an
incredibly hard like polymers shell or
something like that.
Sounds similar that you know,
they now have the bicycle helmets that
inflate when you fall,
it knows that through a balance and that
you can like if you're going to fall and
there's going to be an impact,
it inflates like very instantaneous,
sort of like an airbag so you can,
you wear it around your collar and it's
just like something right here in
school.
Oh,
so it protects your neck and I felt like
one of my articles,
I mentioned it because I thought with
aerial skiing where they're doing like
four or five jumps,
if you know you're going to blow it,
it could just,
you know,
right at the last moment a full body
thing.
It's this kind of technology that kind
of like blow up stuff could protect us
from a lot of things.
You know,
in the future I suppose we could wear
suits that protect us from our own
idiocy.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean what if the entire know,
I don't know if it would work for
something like airplanes or something,
but eventually we want to get to that
point when we are invincible.
Really,
nothing we can do can harm us and that
that's going to be great.
I'm,
that's why I said that's the stuff
jamie,
you're showing on the screen.
This is this,
uh,
this is this impact stuffs a cc the
skies,
moving it around,
but now watch when he hits it with his
hammer.
Nothing.
Wow.
Just stop.
It's just showing how pliable it is.
Yeah.
I don't think that's the same stuff.
I don't know if the same one,
the one that I saw when he hits it,
it's hard as a rock.
Okay.
But I mean it might be just a different
kind of impact.
Resistant like it gave in a little bit.
The stuff that I saw,
he hit it with a hammer and just like
dunk,
like he was playing with it is pliable
and then when you hit it with a hammer,
it's just hard.
Bang.
I just a million things coming.
Totally.
It,
it.
And it's great because it's just going
to make us all safer without and make
us,
you know,
we're going to be able to do crazier
things.
I think that's one of the things I've
loved seeing about.
You've seen this in sports in the last
10,
20 years there doing stuff when we were
kids like bicycle riding,
you know,
I can't believe they're doing double,
triple stuff flips and stuff.
Even in surfing the stuff they're doing,
the waves they're writing now,
you would've thought would've just
killed everyone,
but they do it and you know,
that's one of the great things about a
lot of the technologies just allows us
to do new things we never thought
possible and push ourselves to new
limits.
And I think the future is probably a lot
bigger than the past has been.
So there's going to be a lot more
craziness that we,
uh,
we all see in full,
I think every day there's so much.
So many companies working on the
weirdest stuff.
Yeah,
I agree.
I think we could probably do another
podcast in six months in everything
we're talking about today will be
obsolete now.
There'll probably be some new stuff six
months down the line.
And that's,
that's a big part of what exponential
growth is about,
right?
It's the growth happens so quickly that
as time goes on,
it happens quicker and quicker and
quicker.
Quicker,
Yeah.
Until it's just,
you know,
and then you say six months.
It could be three months at the time
after and then one and a half of course
that's pretty quick,
but eventually it will be like that.
Eventually it'll just be,
the spike is straight up and you know,
I'm not.
It's hard to.
It seems almost impossible to think like
that,
but when you actually look at the
modeling it,
it actually is like that.
There are huge amounts of new companies
working on stuff.
Every day they get an idea,
they think something else,
they get funding and they just,
you know,
it's crazy world we live in,
man.
It is crazy getting crazier.
Totally and changing rapidly and
becoming more brilliant I think as as
the,
as the days go by.
I agree.
Listen,
this has been a fascinating
conversation.
I really appreciate you coming on the
podcast.
If people want to reach you on twitter,
it's Zoltan Underscore Istvan Ist v a n
z o l t a n underscore I,
s t e v a n a website.
It's.
Well,
there's two of them.
There's a transhumanist party.org,
and then there's a.
You can either go to Zoltan,
Istvan Dot Com,
and your book,
the novel.
My novel is the transhumanist wager and
you can get it on Amazon.
The kindle is only ninety nine cents
right now.
There's a special and then there's also
a paperback copy if your readers want to
get it.
Beautiful.
Listen,
thank you very much.
I really appreciate you coming on.
It was really fascinating conversation
APP.
Let's do it again,
but absolutely.
Thanks so much.
Oh,
it was fast and let's do it again in six
months when the world's gone to come
even crazier.
Totally.
Thank you.
Appreciate it,
man.
Thank you very much.
All right folks.
We'll see you soon.
Bye.
Big Kiss Mom.
No.