Hey everybody,
what's up?
This episode of the Joe Rogan experience
podcast is brought to you by stamps.com
what is stamps.com child? I'll tell
ya, that's how I talk to myself.
I just give up on bringing in
other people and the conversations.
I just fake it fake
like I'm talking to me.
stamps.com is an awesome
way to send shit online.
Well actually from your home rather a
without getting in a line, I should say.
You don't have to go to the post office,
get everything measured out.
You can do it from your house and print
actual u s postage right from your desk.
You can buy it on lawn.
You print the postage,
do it all with your computer and printer.
The mailman comes and picks it up and
you're done. It's a beautiful exchange.
It's the best way to send things,
especially if you a,
you sell things from your
home. Um, our friends, Tom
Skinner and Christina Palicki,
they use it for the podcast. Your mom's
house. Brian uses it for desk squad.
Dot TV when he sends out tee shirts.
All our friends who send
things through the mail,
love stamps.com it's a super easy way
to do it and if you click on the old
school,
the microphone in the upper
right hand corner and entering
the offer code, j r. E,
you get a no risk trial plus $110 where
the shit including a digital scale up to
$55 a freeze postage. So don't wait. Go
to stamps.com before you do anything else,
click on the microphone and the top
of the homepage and type in j r e that
stamps.com j r e eliminate all the
hassle of going to the post office during
this busy holiday season.
stamps.com offer code is j r e were
also brought to you by carbonite.
Carbonite is a way to back up your files
automatically from everywhere you are.
Did you know cliffy be,
I bet you didn't know that 33% of
laptops are stolen from the office.
It's the Chinese 28% from cars and 12,000
laptops every fucking week are lost at
US airports. That's insane. 12,000
laptops is a big pile of laptops,
a lot of porn I Dick Pics.
I know that
Brian Red Van.
But if you have carbonite,
you'll have peace of mind that you're
backed up. Files are always safe,
no matter what happens to your laptop,
backs him up automatically
and continually,
no matter how many computers your
business has or where they're located.
We use it for the Joe Rogan experience
podcast. It's very easy to use.
Go to carbonite.com today,
offer code is j r e.
Get yourself a free trial with no
credit card required plus two free bonus
months with your subscription.
That's carbonite.com and the offer code
is j r e and we're also brought to you
by [inaudible] dot com and since
this is the second podcast today,
I think we're fucking set enough.
Um, I think I'm done with sponsors.
Go to ana.com o.
N N.
I t use the code Dane Rogan and save 10%
of any and all supplements because if
he'd be is here,
let's get the party roller Preston
experience
trace fast commercial day.
I'm not fucking around cliffy be,
I get to those pitches. I just hack 'em
out. Cut to the chase, cut to the chase.
You're a free man. Look at you and
all right. You're a bad motherfucker.
Dick Sling and video game controller
and you're out there a free man.
After 20 years of servitude,
you worked for a epic games for a
fuck load of time. I met you there.
Jesus Christ was like five years old.
It was a long time ago.
You were a young lad running a big
company like that I was having in my first
marriage back then too.
You got a different thing going on,
but it's a good way if you're driving
a Lamborghini or out of Raleigh,
you first visited, it was a
viper. Oh, that's right. And
it was fucking terrifying.
Those are terrifying.
Are you talk about like a poor Paul
Walker and though the pores career,
I mean that's car was squirrely, has held
to like really fast in a straight line.
Well those cars were super fun,
those vipers.
But the idea behind it was
the most ridiculous thing
ever. No anti lock brakes.
Yup. No traction control 500
fucking horse by the earlier ones.
And if you weren't careful getting
out, you would burn your leg. Yeah.
Oh that's a side pipe. And then to add
insult to injury, the top of the car,
if it was the convertible,
you had to take an Allen wrench and
unscrew the thing and then get a friend to
help put, it wouldn't even
fit in the boot of the car.
You had to leave it at home. So I and
I used to live five minutes from epic.
I'd sit there on my second monitor and
I have the WRL doppler hub and a storm
was coming.
I'd have to like drive the car home.
Otherwise he'd be the Asshole
Stop Layla Guru. Right. So stupid.
You can't put the roof inside the car.
That's the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
Dave Perry, he had one for awhile. We
were big on the viper for some reason.
And he told me the story,
went to dinner with like some,
some say gay executive and when
he was a younger developer and a,
he had the top off and this is Las and
like Laguna and it can never fucking
rains. Right. And uh,
he said it's just started pouring and
like he just walked home because he didn't
want BV and have the embarrassment of
driving the car or the SIG executive
seeing him the next day. He could
see he was starting to rust already.
He traded the Fucker, ran as fast as he
could before the waste actually hits.
So somewhere out there, there's a guy who
wound up with Dave Perry's Rusty Viper.
It's probably worth a couple of bucks
because of that. Really Dave Perry.
But yeah, I mean it's a, I worked,
I started working with them
when I was 17 men and uh, I was,
I was emotionally like 12. That's
insane. Working for epic games.
It's 17. How old were you when I met
you? Uh, mid twenties, I think. Yeah.
That was way before gears when you guys
were just working on the tack of gears.
Yeah. Come in with Dunkin. Was it Duncan?
Trussell? I think it was Dunkin. You,
you played a the trolley. Good night.
Good Nights. Yeah. It was just there as a,
what's his name? Joey Diaz fucking
be asthma and uh, he's a, he's,
he's good actually.
And uh,
we went to Jillian's and that was
like downtown and downtown. Dude.
The last time you visited Raleigh, even
since when you visited then versus now.
It's like night and day. Yeah. It's
like a mini Austin now. Really?
We have the hipster infection.
We've got fucking
food trucks. See if he could do
something about that. Dude will open.
I opened a restaurant right there.
Did you really? Yeah. With my partner.
Is this a giant six
foot eight Irish fucker?
He used to bounce in Southie back before
south. He got gentrified. How old is he?
Uh, he's 43. Those guys don't last
long. Yeah. Yeah. Six foot eight. Well,
we're going to take one key man insurance.
Yeah. You got to keep that guy. Yeah.
He's a, he's a, he's a rock star though.
He handled most of the day to day ops.
He's been in the restaurant business 25
years. One of my best friends and uh,
yeah, it's in a gentrifying
neighborhood, Italian comfort food.
It's called the station on person.
We were just there. I'm about,
I want to say like six
or seven months ago,
Duncan and I did a tour of North Carolina,
which is where he's from.
We did that and we did the, the mountain
joint. Yeah. Ashville, Ashville,
which is amazing. Yeah. It's beautiful
out there. But they hate the tourists.
They do, but they do for a reason. Yeah.
But the tourist bringing the money.
That's true. But when you
go to Asheville, my feeling,
and I don't want to
Romanticize it too much,
cause I really liked doing that with some
small towns. My feeling, it was like,
oh my God, nobody knows about this. Like
this place is like at the perfect level.
Like the perfect amount of you can
walk around and it's like very little.
Like seediness. Even the homeless
people were pretty polite. Yeah.
Just a bunch of Weirdo. Even in
downtown Raleigh, you get to know him.
There's like,
oh there's the guy with the bags.
There's the guy with a cane who talked
to everybody and the ad actually become
like friendly and shit and they don't.
Instead,
they didn't like San Francisco where
they actually physically touch you fit.
San Francisco is one of the worst
spots ever. Fucking grab you man.
It's just like,
come on man,
we're coming off the freeway of in the
Uber on the way over and there's these
three d hipster looking dudes
playing music with a sign.
You need gas money to get home and home.
Of course they list is Portland
and I'm like, you know,
at least you're doing something for
it. Singing for your supper. Right.
Long drive me to come by. Rollie should
even made a comment. Yeah, we couldn't.
We had a young and I had
to do, yeah, any time.
And then we had a drive to
Asheville the next morning,
but it was really beautiful up there.
It's really the mountain ash Asheville's
beautiful. But it also has that like,
feels like they took it like
a kit for like a hamlet,
like of a town to like put it together and
it's like, oh, the mountain vibe to it.
Like this Bavarian thing going
on. Yeah, it does. Right.
It's got this weird sort of,
it's just interesting.
What did you drive down the slopes where
they were reminded to be careful with
your brakes and there's like runoffs
for trucks and everything going down the
hills. Yeah. He has some
serious fucking hill.
You gotta be careful with that chat
is the mountains especially in the
wintertime, right? Yeah. Yeah.
It's beautiful out there.
It's fucking incredible.
Unbelievably gorgeous. Like
as we were driving up those
hills, it's like, wow dude,
I love it out there. You know, and
I've said this a million times,
the west coats is fucking fantastic. The
problem is the word got out, you know?
And if I get around to
starting a new game studio,
I pay a programmer of 75 80
grand in Raleigh, the he or
she can live like a king,
great house, a great schools. The
downtown's just growing exponentially.
And it's just a,
you know,
it has certain political issues
that have been in the news lately.
Get her done that, uh, that
those assholes all be voted out.
But I don't want to get
into too much of that.
It's too early for this bad stuff going
on there. Just, you know, GOP has got
lost their fucking mind,
like GOP making,
trying to shut down all the abortion
clinics and all this crazy sure.
Old dudes now that's the problem.
Or an old white men are currently
terrified young men with balls become
libertarians and only the ones who
are trying to hide from the gay become
Republicans.
So you've got this weird thing where you
got old dudes and young guys that are
gay trying to pretend they're not
well and that's when you were pressed
something that much.
It bounces back five times.
People right now fucking screaming. Good.
I told you this fucking cock suckers.
A liberal dude.
Our fucking marriage has been in shambles
since they legalized gay marriage.
It's just been horrible for us.
Legalizing gay marriage fight.
I said to stop watching gay porn because
I felt too insecure about my abs. Smart.
You should be careful.
Really ruin your mind.
It's like doing acid one too many times,
you know that's out there.
You know those abs are out there and
you look at yourself when you go to the
bathroom, you're like, Shit.
The point where I'm in the car and
suddenly like I start feeling this little
like Mirabelle right around here.
What are the abs you speak of?
I know to some crossfit or
something. The idea. Do you have,
what's your workout routine? Do you do
crossfit? I do kettle bells. No, no.
I don't go to a crossfit gym. Fucking
coffee to me. Yes. Very called to it.
Like my best friends into it.
Not One of the reasons I love him is
because he doesn't talk about it all the
fucking time. I think
it's culty, but it's,
it seems to me to be a good thing to be
culty about if you're going to be called
[inaudible] health. Those people like
really motivated. I met a lot of them.
I've never met any of them
that espouse weird culty shit.
It's all just a fitness culty. I
had a friend of mine, dear friend,
but she's got hardcore into it and she's
like showing us how shredded her hands
are is like a badge. I'm like, that's
not the practice. Yeah, I saw some,
there's some photo shoot that
some woman did who's like,
I guess she's a NASCAR mechanic
or something. That's Chris.
That's Christmas Abbott. That's the
girl I've known her. I like, I know her.
She lives in Raleigh and she didn't want,
you were talking about Tanya
was as my friend used to work.
She works at epic right now about to
have a baby actually and a great girl.
But um, she got so hard corner
crossfit and she was just was like, no,
you can't wear gloves. You have
to suffer for your work. Yeah.
There was a video of the fucking
crossfit founder or one of them, uh,
doing these kipping pull ups.
Like,
he's one of the head crossfit guys and
he's just mangles his hands and he's like
proud that his hands are like cut open
from all half the crossfit videos.
You look up a Christmas girls in it.
She's totally cool and she's like a
local celebrity and she's like the first
female to do a NASCAR pit, I believe.
A fucking body. That shit's ridiculous.
She's she shredded and you wouldn't
know it when you meet her like,
like she's like a whole
celebrity in that whole scene.
Like she's totally chill and cool. You
mean in the crossfit seen? Yeah. Yeah.
Well I found out about her on,
I think on mixed martial arts.com there
was a website about a thread on the
message board rather about her and
I'm like, yeah, that's a weird thing.
But that really strong muscular, pretty
girl like that. That's so you know,
if you've got to do is or any of that.
That's my thing about tattoos also. Right?
Like if you're going to do it, do
it. Like go on out. Right. Like
I say, I have a star on my butt for my
mom. You know, I'm just like all the way,
right? Mom, you always [inaudible]. I
mean, I got an [inaudible] state symbol,
my butt and that's my thing.
I just got two shitty ones that I got
when I was like 20 something and they're
flash and they weren't even
custom designed and like,
do I regret it? You know,
we were sitting, I was visiting with, uh,
my wife's family in Florida this summer
and uh, Destin, the old fun in La trip.
Right. And it was cool.
It was fun. But, uh,
Lawrence baby sister is 19 and she's just
getting into dragons now. And I'm like,
and she looks at this Tattoo, this
Shitty Dragon Tattoo. I have my shoulder.
And she's like, did you just get that?
And I'm like, look at it. You know,
it's like the old sailor anchor. It's
like bleeding. What is it? Let me say it,
a dragon date. It's just like, yeah,
this is just all elaborate trick to
get he beat to take your shirt off.
It's cute little gut. Two cute
little dragon. Yeah. But I,
I was bold 19 year old and I'm like, lacy,
I like dragons. Before it was cool, like,
oh, you know, she was wounded.
When was it cool to like
dragons now it's cool.
But it was always cool to like track
and just isn't dragons driving has been
around admitting when I grew up that if
I was a dork and the dragons and things
like that dude, it was not
cool for the cool kids. Yeah.
Well when I was in high school,
I remember someone was like shitting on
me because I read the Lord of the Rings,
you know, it was into the hobbit books.
I'm like, that's my, that's my point.
Exactly. So it's cool to be nerdy,
right? Yeah. When did that change? Uh,
about eight years ago. Video Games. Why?
What made it change? Uh, video games.
But you think it's a cultural thing?
It's like Big Bang theory, right?
Like if you get, like I tell people like,
yeah, I gotta go to comic con next week.
And everybody's like, I'm so fucking
envious of that. And I'm like, okay.
And like if you ever read a comic,
like do you know who half these people
are and a bump me out this year.
Have you ever gone? No, we may.
We saying the guy is saying
he's envious is just rather no,
he actually isn't actually,
people actually really want
to go to comicon because I
mean it's not just comics,
it's video games.
It's pop culture.
In one minute you'll see like John Fev
Rhogam we'll go walking by then there's
like a person dressed up as Princess Leia.
That sounds like two things.
I want to avoid that stations you
want to stay here. But Joe, Joe,
the thing is it's like, just get John
Hopper players. Dude. Just kidding.
The cost players are fucking amazing
these days. Like the amount of word they,
there's,
there are girls and guys who spent all
year working on an outfit and then just
show up and they let go like dry from
like Boise and sleep in their friend's
floor and ocean side. I've been there. I'm
not in the actual event itself. I went,
we were there, uh, doing shows that
I'm a American comedy company. Yeah.
And I just was down there for the fun
of it, but we had to cut out early.
Just fucking a lot of fucking people,
man. It's, it's, it's madness.
It's still is just getting a hotel room,
getting a ticket.
You have to have a good connection
through like Warner brothers or something
like that. And we were only able
to be there. I mean, I love it.
I fucking live for it every year.
It's like everything I love in one place
and it's just very sweaty. And uh, we um,
had to leave early
cause my wife's, uh, uh,
one of her bridesmaids was actually
getting married back in Louisiana.
She's from New Orleans, so I
was like, damn it, I had to
miss out because you know,
you go to like the entertainment weekly
party there and it feels like prom.
It's just so many cool.
There's this whole like Josh Sweden
circle of people like Nate filling in and
all of them that just are who
these people are used to be.
Go from firefly and serenity man
and like Buffy and all that. Right.
You know the firefly and serenity.
What does that, what does that,
what the fuck are you talking about?
It's like you're not speaking my language.
This is only 24 hours in
the day you wear this.
How would you even know about these
things? Why would you allow him to answer?
It's your memory to the point where you
think that another grown man would know
what the fuck you're talking about.
Shitting on Scifi classics right now.
Firefly and serenity. I'm like
what dude? Watch them trust. No,
I've heard serenities Badass.
Yes. Ready? He's fantastic.
But most people are not going to know
what the fuck you're talking about was my
point. I actually no, I went
to the, the like my Scifi show.
Was it the uh, they were at the
premiere. I like a lot of the guys,
they played clips.
It's really great stuff,
but most people are not gonna know
what the fuck you're talking about. Oh,
fair enough. You fucking, you guys
are so deep and I've heard a Buffy.
Well, I've, I have a whole like
there's like a 10 year rule where you,
anything that was like cool 10 years ago
you can reintroduce it and then people
act like it's new. Like
zombies, vampires, people like,
like things like if you go back
to like Buffy the vampire slayer,
who the fuck would have thought that
would become like as huge TV show and why
didn't they use the same Buffy magic buff?
These agent fucked up that deals
Kristy Swanson. Right? I don't know.
She's not as Buffy as she used to be.
I think it was probably the reason,
you know, they really look at
Luke Perry who's also in any,
that'd be creepy if you had
Luke Perry and that TV show.
Luke Perry was it a TV show because
his hair's not as straight anymore.
It's kind of wick to the side.
Like a classic thing of 30 year
olds is high school students. Yeah.
That way we do like the dude's hairlines
like worst thing fucking nick Cage's
and he's playing a high school kid that
don't buy it and he wasn't like a Tom
Cruise 30 either. Tom Cruise at 30,
looks like Tom Cruise at 20 minutes.
Very similar to Tom Cruise at 40,
which is very fucking similar to Tom
Cruise at 50. Now. It's a big difference.
This isn't vampirism going on there
or something like Cindy Crawford.
She was hot as fuck. She was dude, it said
Luke, that's that nineties look. Yeah,
that's right. He was in Buffy
the vampire slayer. Yeah.
That was not the vision that
Josh's originally wanted.
The studio of fucking total
in the director totally
changed what he wanted to do.
That's why he went on
to do Buffy as the show,
which wound up being like this
cold classic. Really like what it,
what was the difference between what
he wanted to do and what they want.
They want to do it campy and uh,
the name like Buffy the vampire slayer,
he went into being cheesy and
campy. Right. And so for the show,
the whole point of the show was that was
demons and vampires as a metaphor for
high school shit that people go through.
Right. She finally sleeps with their,
her to crush angel and he
turns into a giant asshole.
You know what someone needs to do,
man, La Femme, Nikita style realistic,
Buffy the vampire slayer
like Buffy fucking up like
those 30 days of night type
vampires like something
really scary, something freaky
and scary instead of this,
you know, true blood. It's like,
it's like the high concept ones,
which are really good.
Like the idea of like a really
hot chick who slaves vampires.
I got a buddy of mine's concept,
but he means doing a comic book. Uh,
you know the whole Zombie
thing, right? He's fine.
I think what I think is the last take
you could possibly have on zombies,
it's comic, but call
the other dead. And uh,
it's Josh or Taylor who wrote gears two
and he's doing it with a Kevin Eastman
who was one of the teenage
mutant Ninja turtle guys.
And the idea is the
Zombie apocalypse hits,
but it's just the animals
that get infected. Hmm.
So it was a Zombie animals
everywhere. The picture, any,
any animal you want everything from
like a fucking alligator through like a
honey badger, like anything. It's just
when, when I was talking about Buffy,
I think that people take concepts
like that and they're like, well,
we know how to do this.
You know, let's do this.
Let's just like the rest of these shitty
fucking movies that are basically the
same. Do them exactly the
same. It should win in the end.
No twists, nothing. Nothing's going to
pull you out of the art form itself.
So you guys are talking about black fish
recently? Yeah. Fucking dude. Depressing.
Very depressing. Yeah. They were
saying about the captivities like,
you know the F is at her now.
She still looks fucking hot as fuck.
It's Kristy Swanson. Now
wonder what happened, man.
What kind of a disagreement there was
where they didn't use her as Buffy.
You never know. Right? Like Twitter.
Maybe you could've been that she was
like too much of a woman and they wanted
someone who looked like a high school
girl because it's Buffy is supposed to be
in high school. Yeah.
That's so ridiculous. Sarah.
Michelle Gellar is not high school.
I could fat how?
How many years did they do that though?
I thought you were going off for it.
I think six or seven seasons.
I haven't watched it all out and
they must've been like, damn,
we've got to get this pitch
out of high school. I tried it.
They did at some point.
Yeah. Fuck, she's married.
She's verified though. How many followers
does she have? 12,000 isn't that weird?
Like in how they get verified,
these publicists,
the publicists getting a black eye.
We got verified because my
agent has a buddy who's over
at Twitter. Oh yeah. Yeah.
That's something. It's that simple,
dude. I've had three publicists try,
but I keep on getting denied number
of people that hate you at Wikipedia.
I really think I fucked somebody.
Ex girlfriend or a girl,
current girlfriend or someone just listens
to the podcast and want to kill you.
Fucking,
it's really that simple.
Some guys like don't soil
Joe Rogan's podcast and like,
what the fuck does that mean?
Because like drop prowl and
take a dump on the table. Soil.
It could you do possibly soylent.
What ideas did they have in their
fucking BD minds? Talk about RSS feeds.
Dude, I gotta fucking abusive relationship
with the walking dead. Speaking is,
I'm over it.
I'm feeling good abused boyfriend.
Did you ever read the book side of
them yelling at me? No, I didn't.
The comics were stacking, told me they
were amazing. What happened was, uh,
when frank Darabont left
it, like the, the, it just
started getting wildly uneven.
Oh, he left. Yeah. Frigidaire. But, uh,
there was a controversy
over the direction or money.
I don't remember what it was,
but it had that great of Buffy Frank
Darabont vibe to it at the beginning,
you know, with Green Mile
Shawshank and at that heart to it.
And he's in the mist was actually
a really underrated movie.
It was spectacular for awhile. And, uh, it
just, you know, this last ending though,
I mean, I don't want to give
away any spoilers for anybody,
but I felt like an abused boyfriend.
There was a whole,
there's a whole relationship
in the books between me,
Sean and the governor that was fucking
amazing that they barely scratch the
surface of, I think she, uh, in the
comic books, she nailed the governor's
nuts to the floor at one point.
If I recall,
like it was some pretty
hardcore shit and cut.
He can get away with that in a comic book,
put it down on a TV show and
you're going to get people protest.
Here's the thing, man, the amount
of like you see World War Z. Yes.
I didn't like it. I just wasn't a fan
of it. I liked it. I didn't love it.
I liked it.
The problem is,
is they get to the point where
the budget is so fucking huge.
They got a paper ad pitch. He's
probably getting points in the back end.
So they had that,
that line where it's gotta be PG 13,
they can't make it are so the Gore on
the walking dead is 10 times gorier
Nastier than you would be in the PG 13
movie. The Gore, the walking dead though.
I really have issues with,
I have issues with how easy
knives go into heads first.
Like butter knives go right through
foreheads like nothing to four.
It is a fucking tough bone.
Try stabbing someone in the
forehead with a big knife. Yeah,
that shit is not easy to get a try
to get a knife through some bone.
Just from personal experience. That would
be so gross TV show if you actually,
it was like,
like it was just like extended scenes
of trying to put nice things like the
stabbing scene in saving private Ryan.
Show me with a cadaver that you could
stick a fucking knife through its head.
That easy. That's ridiculous. You can't
do that. That's fucking hard to do.
Well that's the favorite
Internet mean was who's willing.
The lawn and the walking
dead like all the,
all the grass is cut it about their faces.
They look beautiful.
The girls always have the same length
hair. No one ever cuts their hair.
They all have like a subtle
hint of makeup on all.
It would take us one good shot of a hairy
leg. On a girl to just be like, sold,
sweat the details. Yeah. There's no
hairy legs. This one abused me this last,
this last episode. I see what
they're doing. I was like,
yeah, you know what, man,
you're just fucking with me here. This
isn't necessarily that good. It's just,
dude, this shows just drag
on to drag on breaking bad,
which ended it fucking perfectly.
It's hard.
It's hard to fucking keep a show like that
going on. I'm sure you need a defiant,
creative visionary. Like somebody who's
going to put their foot down and say,
here's what we're fucking doing.
Sound like you're pitching cliffy be dude.
Cliffy bees ready to step in and
take over the walking. What you need.
A defiant visionary.
What you need.
Look at a guy like the guy like Ken
Levine who makes bioshock infinite. Right?
He's stuck him. Yeah. He's
stubborn as fuck. It's so let me,
let me pitch this to you. Okay. Uh,
it's an alternate universe that
they can't think. It's like 1930,
where this guy made a giant floating
city called Columbia. And, uh,
it was basically a bunch of tea party
evangelists went off into the sky and
created the utopia that
eventually turns into a dystopia.
And you go there to find a girl who can
create a rift between dimensions and
there's a robotic George Washington.
That sounds pretty dope, dude.
It's fucking with it. And it sounds
pretty, the ending is like twilight zone,
unworthy, like, and that's really, yeah.
One thing we've been doing like late at
night in the wee hours in the mornings,
I get up at noon every fucking
day as we put it in the old,
the Blu blu rays at the
twilight zones. Oh, I love them.
And we're burning through every single
one and they're fucking fantastic around
SkyFii like almost every night.
And it's like, it's like,
it's like Shawshank redemption once
it's on, you got to go the distance.
You got to watch the whole
thing. I watched the um, uh,
the William Shatner one the other day,
man, the man on the plane. Oh my God,
it was so good. So fun to watch. And
then a w, w the one with the, uh,
there's one where the astronauts
crash land on an alien planet.
They land there and they
find tiny little people.
And then this guy becomes like
a God, Oh shit, you got that.
I got it before it becomes like a god
to them. And then at the end of it,
it turns out there's another species
that's like as big to us as he was to the
little people.
And then he gets essentially squished
and they just in rod sterling man,
the intro is just slice. Like
they might have like, you know,
zooming over to him and he's like
always smoking. He's like, you know,
sitting in a wing, back chair
in front of a fucking fireplace.
Imagine if you will. Well,
he was so original to, when
you stop and think about it,
there really hadn't been anything
like that. And he was tapping,
he's tapping into lake, you know,
key Scifi writers of the time. Right.
Just so much good shit.
What was that?
I think your laptop says laptop.
Okay. Um, making sure that, but just,
you know, the effects, you know,
they knew what they could show
and they knew what they couldn't.
So it's very light and affects
the characterization, the sets.
Sometimes you can tell
it's the same like diner.
They've repurposed 15 different times
for the different episodes separately.
Brian one the other one would
William tractor where uh,
there was like the little thing that
told the future which one was a,
there was like the little machine
that tells the future. Like, you know,
you ask a question. Yeah. That
was fucking brilliant. Yeah.
That you just had footage of a bioshock
infinite. It's downloadable content.
Another one I watched recently
was the one with um, the uh,
the puppet that was running the show and
they were robbing people and the puppet
was doing all the robbing. It doesn't
ring a bell. Yeah. It was like a, an uh,
the little kid knew that the puppet was,
that the puppet was actually
real and the little kid was like,
and on the old man who is, this is the
puppet set them up. We were watched.
The one with the Trans
dimensional hole in the wall,
the little girl goes through.
So you go back and rewatch all
of those in so many movies.
Just took the same idea and updated it.
Like there's the one with the guy can
hear people's thoughts and that's what
women want the Mel Gibson movie.
Right. Well that was cool.
What was that guy that you just
showed Brian? That guy's face? Yeah.
This is from that bio shock.
What was the,
go back to that as a scene
with that guy's face.
The graphics or be there that guy.
So Sandra Cohen,
eyes wide shut. This is
amazing. It's a, it's a,
it's actually a Zit on they put on PC.
I don't remember. I played on console.
I don't know. Yeah, I played
the DLC on PC cause yeah,
he's the only the only games
you would ever play over a PC.
First person shooters. Right. Joe?
Me. Yeah. I only played online too.
I wouldn't play against the game. I get
bored too. These, yeah. Well that's,
you know, every time I go to
event human there, that's boxhead.
Some guy comes up to me and he's like,
Yo man, it's all about the multiplayer.
And I'm like,
there it is all about the multiplayer.
This is the game that I
would highly recommend if you
want to play on a computer
instead of a console.
Oh, this looks amazing.
It's one of the best games ever created.
This looks so good.
And does this available for Mac to Yep.
I think so. This will waste my day. Yeah.
This looks fun. Shit man. It's really
beautiful. Sky Hooks and shit. Yeah.
See the good thing about that is I won't
really get me addicted because it's not
online. Yeah. If it was online, do
they play multiplayer? I think so. No.
Oh Dude, look at these zombies. Bad
Ass. Yeah. The idea is that they're uh,
their kids creepy and there's a
whole dirty, there's a whole, well,
you can go now with the
dude. It's brilliant. Wow.
Is there so much creativity
involved in video games these days?
I had a chance a few years ago, uh,
to bring Josh Sweden over to e three,
and he walked out of there.
He said, I did 15 minutes.
I just saw more creativity than I've seen
in Hollywood and years. Yeah. Like when,
you know, like when halflife came out,
I remember thinking really clearly,
why can't someone make a movie
like this? Like, why is the, why?
How come the video game
gets to be so cool? Like,
can't these same guys figured
out how to write a movie? Well,
what's gonna happen now is,
you know,
with the advent of Youtube and people
being able to create their own content,
you know,
people can do that and they can put it
up online and it could become an online
sensation. Right. That sound
Neill. BLOMKAMP got to start.
He did these shorts that he put on
Youtube. It's like lost in, uh, those,
the one about the robot and Africa,
I believe.
And then he wound up doing a Elise
IOM and district nine, no shit. Yeah,
that's how I got founded. Wow. That makes
sense. And uh, he can see his style.
He was going to do the
halo movie at one point.
But so much of creativity is
just finding an outlet for it.
And when you're talking about something
specific about making a film or making a
television show,
it's so hard to get to that outlet.
It's so hard to get to the point where
any of your ideas can actually be seen by
people.
You have the torque of it being,
making the art that you want versus
it being commercial products and we'll
itself, well not only that,
actually getting it to that point,
like if you want to be a director,
Jesus Christ, good fucking luck.
Good luck in getting to
direct a major motion picture.
Like that's a long ass road.
Look, you've got to figure out,
you got to prove yourself to a lot of
people along the way. It's very difficult,
especially if they're gonna Trust,
you know, 50 a hundred $200 million.
Now when you add in marketing costs,
I mean the thing about the gaming industry
right now matter and it's like it's
fundamentally broken for the consoles
because what you have is a disk based game
that then can only come out at $60 and
then people traded in or they just rent
it and then the marketing budgets
are trying to out weigh each other.
So you know, a hundred million dollar
marketing budgets so you can get on,
you know, NBA commercials or football
commercials or Superbowl ads, Jesus.
And then he said so much money and they
annualize it, right? And then, you know,
I'm walking around to e three this year
and there's some fantastic looking games
where I'm like,
that's probably not going to make money.
That'll barely break even.
They'll make money on the SQL with to
finally start making money when the
annualized. Whereas A, I'm a fan of the
other way, just like developing your,
your community while you develop your
game. You know, you have new concept.
I put it up in sub reddit and see what
people say, you know, when you had,
and you need, you know, release a
Beta release in Alpha, you know,
let people let people buy items
before you can even play the game.
You heard about that. Uh, Chris
Roberts, a star citizen game, no.
Guided a Kickstarter raise 2.5 million.
And then he has the ability to
essentially buy space ships for your,
it's like a dog fighting Sim. Like
got Luke Skywalker Shit. Right.
And you can basically buy your shifts
in your fleet and walk around in your
hangar and sit in your ship.
You can't even fly it yet.
And they've raised $30 million so far. And
crowdfunding of course they have. Yeah.
And it's like,
it's also the whole thing's genius
and he's the guy made wing commander.
And I think that, you know, my whole
10 year rule is like, you know,
the space sims where your dog fighting
everything like spaces cooler than ever
right now. And one of the cool
things about, um, uh, about quake
when I was playing quake online all
the time. So they always put demos out.
There was always like a new game that
was coming out in the demos would be
released first and everyone downloaded
them for free and everyone got online.
And then once the game came out it was
like that may more people wanted to buy
the game.
What they've done.
Well the problem is just getting a game
out takes so much work that like right
now, uh, you know, I was talking to a,
I believe that's not public knowledge.
I can admit that. Um, basically if
you're releasing it, it's friends.
I don't want to betray,
you don't want to betray their competence,
but let's call him Santa
Claus. In Rudolph, you want
to have a Beta Santa Claus.
Tell Rudolph, uh, an
upcoming online shooter,
you want to have a Beta
before the game comes out.
Cause if your game's fucked it launch,
it takes you two months to fix that.
Going through Sony or Microsoft.
And by that time everybody's treated your
gaming and they're onto the next call
of duty. Like you have to
get it right the first time.
I think we're going to get to a time in
our lifetime where someone's going to be
able to make a game like this at home on
their PC by themselves. Well, they, uh,
at the spike VG x that they announced
the game called a no man's sky,
which I'm like,
that's kind of a cool name,
but I'm going to totally
mispronounce it as no man's guy.
Shitty double o seven movie. Oh yeah.
Like a led Zeppelin song or something.
It's a space theme that's procedurally
generated and, uh, four guys.
What does it mean? It means
basically every world is different.
It's all just done by code. Uh,
yeah. Here we go. Look at this shit.
Every hour dudes doing this
and they gotta be working.
The Guy said for his previous game,
he mortgaged his house for it.
That's how much they care.
I Bet I could sell them at a raw.
So basically you, you do is you go
from, you use exploring this planet.
He's underwater. He comes out of
the water, it goes into the forest,
hops in his spaceship.
It goes,
flies all the way back out
of the atmosphere into space.
Dog fights with people through asteroids.
Wow. And four guys made this. Yeah.
I don't know if it's all guys, but for
people. For humans. Yeah, let's call them.
Hey guys, like you would say
that even if it was girls, right.
Be Allowed to do that still it's,
so this is all just taking that from us.
Cliffy being shitty to say guys
in a room of mixed company. Well,
I had tweeted a no man's sky wins the
title for most misogynistic game title
sarcastically. No Man's sky of
it's funny. And people like,
actually wouldn't it be feminists because
there's no men. I'm like, retweet what?
Then there's,
there's people Uber on the way over
here and people tweeting me like your
fucking duty too.
I'm like,
sarcasm does not translate well on the
Internet with these kids sometimes.
Well with some of them,
the problem is it's just so many of
them out there dealing with millions of
people bound to hit a few retards going
now to 15 now you're at a million plus
now, right? Yeah. Do you see even read
your ad still? Yeah, I read them. Yeah.
I mean I can't read all of them.
It's not possible. It can't respond.
I don't have enough time,
but they just want to know you're
reading or replying to some of them.
I try to retweet interesting stuff and
then that way I think it's been a really
positive exchange for me too for,
I've gotten a lot out of being connected
to people on Twitter because they're
always sending me interesting articles
and ideas and knowing that I'll retweet
them. You've trained them well. It's,
it's like it's a cool thing to do.
You know people like being retweeted,
it helps them get more followers and
if you're a guy that he regularly posts
cool shit, you can become
like a portal to information.
Yeah,
it has a bunch of guys that have follow
on Twitter that are just regular folks
would regular jobs.
They just like cool shit and they find
your articles and they tweet them and
then you retweet them. And so we go
back and forth like all the time,
especially with technological
advancements and essay stuff,
all that stuff going on right now.
It's like,
I don't want to put my
tin foil hat on, but, um,
the more I hear and the more
comes out, I'm like, fuck,
really? Then Nsa Shit, I'm,
I'm just trying to dwell on that as little
as possible because it's so negative
and it feels so helpless and
it's just such a weird thing.
The idea that we're like about to
relinquish all of our privacy to other
individuals that are no
different than you or I, they're,
they're just fucking people and just
because they're in some form of government
and they're trying to, you know,
keep quote unquote us safe.
How about we examine all your
actions that you're doing,
that you are doing to keep us safe
before we let you access our email? Oh,
you've been accessing our email for
a decade. I was working on a uh, uh,
a game in epic that was canceled,
but I was a, I don't want to,
I'm still under NDA with them but
I don't want to get it too much.
That's a nondisclosure agreement.
Some of the things we were googling I
know is sitting off a light in the NSA
cause you know like as far as far as like
a revolution and terrorism and things
like that. And it's just, you know,
like some sort of red flag was going off
and it's a post Patriot Act man. Yeah.
It's pumping a bunch of fucking
paranoid people for sure.
I mean if you really stop and think about
how few actual terrorist activity you
see in America and how many
fucking people are in America,
they've done a great job in that respect.
Well that's the difference also between
a perception fear like you know, people,
people tell me fly safe. I'm
like fuck off, drive safe.
But it isn't when you stop
and think about it. I mean,
and I'm not advocating in any way,
shape or form that anybody should
have access to any of your emails.
Cause I think that's a really ineffective,
shitty bullshit way of trying to protect
people because by removing all of their
privacy, I think that's a
bullshit way to handle it.
But if you look at what
the job they have done,
if the really is a bunch of terrorist
activity all over the world,
they've done an amazing job of
keeping shit from happen in America.
I think it's not a black or white case.
I think there's good
and bad on both sides.
The problem is just a fucking human
nature problem and she can't have ultimate
power. You can't have it. Whoever. Yeah.
There was an article I believe where
they're talking about easing people's
pornographic habits to shame
them for political reasons.
If they need and they were spying on
world of Warcraft players, come on,
you fucks. Unbelievable. This
just came out today. Well,
the other problem is people are
willing to give up so much of it.
They're doing it because
they're being tricked.
I mean that's like saying someone's,
you know,
willing to suck your Dick for cocaine
and they don't even know it's aspirin.
I mean,
it's like you're thinking you're getting
some cocaine and you're getting an
aspirin. You're like, God,
what the fuck happened?
You're not really getting anybody
to save you and I really good.
You're going to die anyway.
We're all gonna die. We're
gonna die in car accidents.
We're going to die of cancer. We're
going to die of being old. It's just,
it's going to happen.
You're getting on dialysis on me.
It's going to fucking happen.
What's the point?
The idea that you know you're going
to protect all these people from dying
because you're going to
stop terrorist activity,
and the way to do that is to
remove all freedom. You start,
you'll okay is happy about this life.
If this life is living scared and living
where you're being watched every step
by random people who's going
to profit with everything,
follow the chain of the profit by that,
that all should be illegal.
You shouldn't be able to profit by any
protections like private prisons and all
that to keeping people alive and healthy
shouldn't be able to profit over that.
Policing every,
everything should be nonprofit.
The idea that they have a giant budget
and these people get to make big salaries,
make donations to charities,
like do your homework with,
with how much of the money actually
goes to the cause versus quote raising
awareness versus, and what the CEO
of the nonprofit makes all of that.
Like the reddit listed out of list of
a bunch of them at one point like the,
that goodwill is basically like just
selling all your clothes for money and
things like that.
Just like crazy.
This is a bunch of shit that gets done
in this country that should get done by
paypal. Like paypal donations.
Like that's what the presidency,
that's what the government
should get. Like paypal
donations. We think a good job.
We'll give you a nice tip and then
that's how you keep the society running.
And the only way you ever get paid is if
people like what you're doing and they
choose to donate and they donate what
they can and we make it like, you know,
everybody's proud. Just like people
are proud to serve in the military.
People were proud to donate to
the, to the government. Yup.
Donates not steal all my money at Fox
and I say support the troops because if
you get my assets and getting
shot at, but yes, absolutely.
But if you think about like the
idea of donating to the government,
it's actually probably a pretty good idea
because you would only want to donate
to things that you believed in.
You would only want to donate to things
that you've felt actually fit for the
good of the people.
So the people in the community would
decide like what's good and what's bad and
that's how things would get voted on at
Kickstarter like right. Yeah. It's just,
I think this is probably a stupid idea
because it's too much shit. I did,
I mention to people will say like the 1%
we control everything cause they donate
the most money for their field.
Whatever their interests are of course is,
which is basically what it,
what's going on right now.
We'd have to keep corporations from
doing it. Only make individuals do it.
You know,
the problem is it's like,
it's almost like a game where you start
off and it's already a thousand to zero.
You're never going to catch up.
The game is five minutes long,
you're never going to catch
up. You started off with
this massive deficit. Yep.
And if you grow up in the United States
and you're trying to do anything where
you're, you're trying to govern
people or control wealth or you know,
the amount of fucking momentum that's
already been put in the other direction is
so crazy.
[inaudible] my own personal success.
Back to the fact that my
family was middle class,
my dad bad dad worked for Polaroid and
the fact that they had an extra like two
grand to buy an apple too, like that
was the jump off point right there.
And I took to that thing
like a fish to water.
It was originally supposed to be for
my brother and uh, I just steal it. No,
I just started using it and he
wasn't using it. He was too busy.
He's too busy chasing pussy at the time.
Pouch Kabob bow. I actually found it.
SB nation.com and like a polygon
and all that, you know, he's uh,
he's done well in his own right.
But anyway, that's not the point.
So you got into that just
from one purchase that your
parents were able to like
I to take my brother's eight
track and pretend it was a computer
because I want her computer so fucking bad
listening into like fucking
hall and Oates and all that.
She used to pretend it was a computer.
Yeah. That's hilarious. Yeah.
You like eve had a pull towards computers.
I've,
I've had a technology boner since I
was a kid. I love technology. What did,
do you have a background in
any educational background?
I went to cal poly Pomona for six months
and I dropped out cause I dropped out.
I hated it. I dropped out. Uh, when Jazz
Jack Rabbit started making enough money,
that's the first successful game I did.
It got me my first car,
which was a 99 red Saturn.
Uh,
I got my first apartment
over outside Pomona and uh,
basically also also my mum
wouldn't run the air conditioning.
We were over in Laverne and it'd be like
summer, like 120 degree. She's like,
she'd be like open and went out cliff.
And I'm like,
it's like opening a fucking oven.
Like it's not doing anything. God,
that's hot as fuck. Yeah. Now when you,
when you get into it as a video
game designer, right? Do you,
what account type technological
knowledge do you have to have?
Do you just have id? And they said like,
this is how I'd like to gain to play.
This was what I would like to happen.
You start off with verbs. Like what,
what are the verbs that you're doing
this game? Are you kicking, punching,
fighting, exploring, right?
Like figure out what type of thing you're
going to make. And for me, uh, you know,
I've always,
guns are easy and that's why everything
I've ever made pretty much has a gun in
it. You know, if I get
back to making games,
I'm not gonna make like a polar bear
fighting simulator. It's a very boring,
when you have a video game,
you can't shoot somebody else.
It's our way of interacting.
It's, it's touching, right?
And as much as the baddies are coming,
shooting people in the face at 60
frames a second through iron sights will
always be fun at the end of,
and especially when it's somebody like
who's like your friend or you know,
online, a random person. Right. Yeah. But
it was, I was just attracted to it, man.
I just, I made my first game and a little
adventure game when I was 11 and, uh,
just, you know, started cranking. All
the kids were partying in high school.
I was sitting at home and
working on games. Yeah. Yeah.
20th high school reunion recently, by
the way. Wow. What was that like? It was,
you know, I didn't know what
to expect going into it,
but everyone was really fucking cool.
Oh, that's nice. You know, and like,
I'm not mark Zuckerberg,
but some of them were making little
comments and jokes like, and I'm like,
look guys, I mean, I did okay, but I
didn't fly her in a fucking private jet.
Calm down.
Did you get a involved?
But you need to get marijuana
in your life. I was in Boston.
I remember I'm from Boston. Yeah, that's
a harsh place. I was a sub the suburbs.
It's north Andover. It's super cute
up there. What were you saying?
Did you get an Oculus rift?
Yeah, I'm actually an investor
in it. Oh really? Yeah.
I'm going out there and
Wednesday to see the,
apparently they have some really
good breakthroughs they've gotten,
did you see the jerk off breakthrough?
No.
They have oculus rift attached to
a jerk off machines with the guys.
Like the Japanese guy was like, he's
in it right there. Yeah, they don't,
they don't want to talk too much about
the whole porn thing. How dare they,
how dare they not know the truth.
Horn drives technology is, you know,
that's really gonna drive technology
because everybody sees the writing on the
wall. We were talking about it a little
bit before we got online here was, uh,
did you see Don John, Don
John? Yeah. It's the, um,
what's so what's his name from uh, Joseph
Gordon leave it wrote and directed it.
Scarlet Johannson. It's
about the, oh no I didn't.
I know it's a great movie and it's really
fun. Well, his whole thing is like,
he's basically addicted to online porn
and like he finally beds the character
scar Johanson who's gorgeous
and immediately goes out
to his laptop to run one
out and it starts off like his
laptop booting up sound. He's like,
just the sound of that
makes my cock rock hard.
And he's going on about all the people
he likes and everything. And I read,
there was a story I read online,
it was talking about real life,
dawn John's guys who've become so addicted
to like how good modern pornography
is that they get ed and
they can't get it up.
And so what happens is there's the
younger generation of young dudes,
because apparently the each we
start looking forward is 10.
That's when you start
looking at the average,
the average young dude right now in,
but girls,
and I don't know actually they didn't
mention girls too much. Um, they,
maybe they start reading 50 shades of
gray to get an early age or flowers in the
attic.
50 shades of grey is more for a gal who's
been working for 10 years and has kind
of given up on excitement.
Yeah. My wife read it.
She said it was just kind of dumb. It's
supposed to be pretty stupid. Yeah.
And I'm just talking shit. I don't
know. Well so back to the whole,
the porn thing is that a,
and so they found that like the older
generation guys from their thirties who
have that problem with, with Ed
from too much porn, like they can,
they can bounce back in a couple of
months, but the kids take so long.
And the reason why is
like when we were young,
we'd have to find our brothers hustler
underneath their bed or whatever. Right.
We, we had like, you know, analog
porn right now on your phone.
You could just watch like super slow Mo,
whatever,
the most filthy shit imaginable
pursuing my phone. Look at that screen.
You sexy bitch. Fucking huge. It's
either a really small Joe Rogan,
a really big phone. It's a
note three. Nice. I mean I,
I'm a droid guy guy cause he has the
s three is fucking terrible. Like I,
the s four apparently fixes all
the problems as far as nice.
I've played with that. I almost got
that I got this instead because I was,
I'm just greedy. Everyone's like, why
aren't you get an iPhone on? Like I just,
I don't refuse to fully
drink the apple koolaid.
It's good to stay away a little bit.
Just in case the apple falls apart.
You still have options. My wife and my
wife has the iPhone. I have the droid.
I can see the best of both worlds
in nine times out of 10 the APP,
like if there's an app that's on the
iPhone, that's an app that's on the droid.
Droid one just barely works.
Barely was fucking focus problem.
Instagram's terrible. Yeah. So
it's so clunky. I used a god, I um,
I got the shit at my house.
I'm addicted to have apps in my house.
I got the hue it.
Have you seen that basically it replaces
your light bulbs with these LEDs? Yeah,
we have, I'll give you an antibiotic. We
have it here, we just never installed it.
And so a fucking, then I have
the, uh, what's the, the nest,
which is to controls or Hvac
from your phone. So I'll wake up,
I'm a little warm in the morning,
go to my phone,
lower the air conditioning temperature,
and then it learns throughout the week.
And then nest just is introducing a
thermostat that I got also where you can
basically a,
if it's a smoke detector actually,
and instead of just going
like right off the bat,
it just goes when it gets a slight
puff of smoke, it's like, oh, small,
small digita detected. Right.
And then if it says it, yeah.
And then you can just wave it away as
opposed to scaring the shit out of your
dog. Right. And then, uh,
if there's more smoke then it eventually
builds to full alarm. So what the,
what these guys are doing over there
is essentially taking all these, like,
I wouldn't say Apps,
these utilities that people just didn't
think about improving them and their
apple buying them there. They're making
them work and they're just brilliant.
Yeah, they're great. It also
has carbon dioxide or whatever,
the oxide oxide, carbon dioxide. Just slow
down.
Think about what you're saying right
before you say it and you can get through
it. But yeah, man, it's a
I technology. I just like,
we have a three d printer at the house.
We've got the rift,
I got the idea of a three d printer.
Would he printed it? I got it.
That's how I was saying I'm gonna print
custom butt plugs for all my buddies for
Christmas. That's sweet.
Um, yeah, my wife,
my wife printed with three d halo pistol
and like she basically had had a print
every single part like the
and just assemble the whole
damn thing and it's like
life size and it's just,
it's just,
it heats the plastic and then it just
basically does it bit by bit and you can
download things from thingiverse.com
and they're also going to be able to do
with the metal, right? Like, yeah.
This is just like plastic gun control
will be a thing of the past. That's weird.
There's a guy right now who could,
who made up,
we've made a plastic gun that could fire,
uh,
the first one round than several
rounds and the data that you can't,
once the data's out there, that the
genie's out of the bottle. You know,
it's like I say about about
trying to delete a tweet.
So I tried to suck a fart back in your
ass. It just doesn't work that way.
And so you'd be more successful, suck
in a far back in your ass, you know,
fair thing. If you worked on it
for years, he had a good prolapse,
you could probably,
this is things that people can do that
would shock you like pussy farts in a
microphone. You can do man, people,
some people have special gifts.
When I'm on a plane it seems like I fart
and it sucks back in like it does it
for like hours on end and
not see your neighbor.
You fuck dude sitting there
going, [inaudible] spill
it and you know your shit.
Now,
this guy,
I made the mistake of going from American
at Delta one time in American has
these seats that absorbed the farts.
It's like cloth,
but in Delta it's like this kind of
rubbery thing. And so the far just tits,
it goes fucking straight up.
Who'd be a very smart move to develop
some sort of a fart free airplane.
Well there's somebody made made underwear
that has some special filter that had
carbon filter. Yeah, exactly. I'm
not going to work on Joey Diaz.
I got news for you. I wrote a blog once
about a fart that he took on a plane.
I was next to him and I was writing and
he was lying there with his hands on his
stomach and, and uh, I
saw him like lift up,
like he adjusted his weight and
before it was too late, I, I,
it hit me like a Zombie Barak,
like a truck.
And I had headphones on.
I was listening to music and over the
music I heard the woman behind me go,
oh my God.
It was so,
she goes, oh my God, dude.
Fuck her farts are always, always
fucking funny, but it was so bad.
I had to put my shirt over my face.
I had to duck down.
I was on a plane once and a dude
farted on Melanie Griffin's head.
This is how it works.
I was on a plane and I was flying from
New York to London and it's a long flight.
And when we were on the Ohs, actually la
to London, and when we're on the plane,
Melanie Griffin lied down.
She went to sleep or her,
her thing extends and this guy lied down
and he went to sleep and he was a fat
guy. And if there's a fact,
if there's a fart on a plane,
you always look to the fact that it's
it just, just the way it is, you know?
Fair enough.
Everybody does got fucking crop dusted.
It's sleep no more in New York City
recently. You ever hear about that show?
So Melanie Griffiths, head, Melanie
Griffith, head in this guy's ass.
We're three feet away from each other.
He was turned sideways with his ass
facing her or she was turned sideways with
her face facing his ass
in perfect alignment,
just a few feet apart.
Like how was that even happen?
Like if you ever thought in the universe
when you were watching a movie with
Melanie Griffith then and that one day
I'm going to get to Fart in her face.
Her face going to be three feet away and
I'm just going to open up on her face.
Little curly hair,
kind of like moves in the breeze.
It was weird to see because I was
awake or wake up or did she? She moved,
she did something.
It's like inception where
she'd go trenching and like
a sewage bin or something.
It was a horrible fart. I
kissed her. I opened it on her.
I can't stay the proximity. So
strange. Its power. I mean what,
how much would it cost to say like Melanie
Griffith, there's a guy, he's weird,
you know he's a nice guy,
but he wants a fart in your face.
He's willing to give you $5 million. He's
the problem. He's Brazilian. How much,
how much would you have to
pay or to partner face me.
Monster took one for nothing. Right? And
the mug three feet away. And the guy,
he's the guy opened on her.
You think he knew he farted hard dude.
There's no way like pushing the,
he wasn't asleep ed either cause he had
been moving around a lot before he cut
that Fart, you know, would
probably had upset stomach. Oh Hey.
You know something about the pressure
change to just pop people just like the
Fart. I think if you're
around people that just fart,
most of the time people hold
it in until no one's around.
But when you get in a plane, it's
11 hours. You're like, fuck it.
Melanie's got us off. And I fucking
love Fart and elevators. Do you, I'm,
that guy is terrible.
I'll live in a condo right now.
My niece and my neighbors don't like me.
And so,
and just like walking the dog and just
why don't you neighbors like you? Um,
I installed a, okay, so here's the deal.
Living in the condo right now and I bought
the condo next door and I cut a hole
in the wall.
And so then in that Condo I put in like
a theater room and then I put it in a
450 gallon hot tub. You can see
where this is going in the condo.
So you haven't parties. Yeah, well,
so I was building basically the ultimate
Pussy Palace right when the love of my
life showed up. Like whenever
they finish the final bit of tile.
And I was going to be like, I'm going to
be a bachelor. This is going to be great.
Boom. My dream girl appears. And
I'm like, Oh, well that was fun.
And so then, uh, when I
had the tub installed,
I didn't have an overflow
valve installed. Oh, Jesus.
And this is during like crunch time,
I think I'm like year three,
a few years ago and I left the
water on. Oh, Jesus. Now, yeah,
I went to dinner and the three
condos beneath me flooded.
Oh my God.
One lawsuit later with my Hoa,
which is still pending. It's, uh,
it's been an interesting journey.
Needless to say, they had a star ceiling.
It's still pending. Yeah. Where's we're
working on coming to terms for it. It's,
I don't want to get into the details,
but I had a star ceiling at it. The,
the tub filled from the ceiling and see
match how the guy below me felt like
it's just like a fucking
freight train. Dude. That's so
crazy. How much was the total
damage? 80 grand. That seems cheap.
Yeah. It sounds like it'd be
a lot more than that. Yeah.
If it was la would have been, yeah, yeah,
yeah. That's probably what it is, right?
Yeah, I'm right. 1 million couple,
man. I was thinking millions. Yeah,
that seems like a lot of money.
But yeah, it's a, so, I mean,
we bought a house when we're here to
renovating and we're gonna be moving up
there. So Carolina is pretty fucking
awesome. 80 ground dude. Yeah.
I mean go move. Really just to get
out of here. It really is the move.
The only thing that would suffer
it would be the podcast guest.
You wouldn't get as many cool guests.
We have a direct flight finally. Yeah.
But I'm not flying back and forth from
fucking North Carolina. All I know.
If you live there, you live there. And
the other thing would be flying to gigs.
Yeah. But it's a better move, man. I,
I've Nvu it's a better move
because it's not a backwoods town.
Raleigh's a great town. Great
restaurants. Bioshock infinite in Quincy,
Massachusetts. You know,
I mean, come on man.
What is that one restaurant that you
guys have that fucking insane barbecue
place. The pit. Yeah. Holy Shit is,
that's where all the celebs go. Yeah.
All the celebs. How dare you just,
we're just talking about food here man.
And why did you have to go there? I
don't know. All the celebs go there.
That's what Joe Rogan goes.
It's delicious food man.
There's like how many restaurants
did they and they are like,
it's fucking exploded.
Yeah.
There's a lot of restaurants there and
we noticed that when we're back there.
But then pit places, a lot
of great walkable spots
now. Like we just, you know,
take our bikes around and shit
and it's just fun. You know?
So it's not too many people.
That's what it is.
You spent $400,000 for a house out there.
Forget it. You're good. You're good.
Like it's, it's great. You can even might
can get great house in apex for 200 wow.
Just unreal.
And like my protector,
my brother lives in orange where you
can get a starter house for 800 grand,
you know, and it's just fucking
California man. You know, we can,
we briefly consider moving out here. And
I looked at the real estate. I'm like,
I cannot justify to us if you're
gonna live in La. It's like, you know,
we, we poked around in hidden hills,
which was beautiful, but it's like,
you still can't go to like, you know,
Santa Monica, Beverly Hills for dinner.
You just can't, you can't, you just got
to go over the hill, go over to Panga,
get a fucking chopper depending
candy's not bad. Yeah.
Everybody wants get silly and
tried to go over the four or five.
That's the four or five.
It could be two o'clock in the afternoon,
two o'clock in the morning. It doesn't
matter. It's a fucking hard, yeah,
you always run into packed. They were
doing construction on it the other day.
It was really late at night.
Somebody that's my driver is saying over
here was saying Obama came through and
just like,
right,
right when he got into town was right
when everyone going to work and right when
he left was when everyone was leaving
work and it just, everything's shut down.
Really? Yeah. Well when I was
there it wasn't that, it was just,
they were doing construction and they
had narrowed it down and it fucking two
o'clock in the morning and it was
just bumper to bumper traffic. No get,
that's why you get ways did
I think there were false,
they were acquired by Google for like a
billion. It's just brilliant app. Let's a,
he eases pain profits and
that's that simple. I want to,
I don't want to let it slip. Joe, did
you ever hear about sleep? No more.
What is sleep? No more. It's if next
time you're in New York fucking go.
It is this interactive theater.
Bear with me.
It's got this like 1930s kind of speakeasy
vibe about it and it's essentially a
retelling of Macbeth in the
setting of this old hotel.
And the actors all act around you.
Everyone has to wear a mask who's not
an actor and you're not allowed to talk
the whole time.
And they're like,
we find lady Macbeth the after like this
dinner scene and she was like losing
her shit and she likes strips down and
starts trying to wash the blood off of
her hands in a tub right in front of you.
And one of my buddies like actually Mondo
interacting in sponge bathing the girl
like, it's fucking,
there's like the, you know,
there's a a bellhop there who's like
hooking up with everybody. Um, they don't,
they're not guys sat,
find a lot of images or videos
of the experience because
it's very low key there.
I think they're actually bringing
it to La is what, uh, what am I for?
My friends told me other day,
just just go. We went twice.
The second time was an entirely different
experience and you're just, you know,
there's like a candy shop there.
You can just dig in and eat the candy.
There's little like letters,
notes that are part of the fiction
that you can solve yourself.
It's almost like a video
game that sounds incredible.
It's not like one of those crazy
ass scary haunted house type things.
It's not scary. It's just cool. And you
feel like, like our first experience,
we came into this room, it looks
like a World War One type of uh, uh,
hospitals set up.
There's like a,
a nun nurse who's looking very despondent
and she goes up to the window where
there's like this fake forest they made,
which was convincing enough to hear
crickets and everything and she just jumps
out the window and starts running
through the forest. I look over,
my wife grabbed her hand,
we just like jumped out the window
and she started following her is fine,
where she goes and like a whole
tab low played out in front of us.
Fucking phenomenal.
And it's not like,
not a lot of people know
about it for some reason,
but tickets aren't that
expensive. You know, you go
there, it opens at a speakeasy.
There's people who were actors and in
character playing their parts, you know,
that's how it's fun. It's fucking
cool man. And that was really nice.
There's like secret passages and shit.
We were, there's one actress who was uh,
sitting there,
he's playing out a Tablo on a sofa and
there's one lady who stood in front of
her with a mask on and she grabbed a
lady's hand and pulled her into this like
closet and I went to follow in.
The door's locked and they were,
had this some sort of one on
one encounter with the actress.
Like one during the dinner scene they
were all dancing and one of the actresses
grabbing, there's one of the guys with
the mask on who was a participant,
just started ballroom dancing with
them. Just like, cool shit man. Wow,
that's pretty bad ass. Everyone respects
it. People aren't with you learnt Dicks,
you know, like nobody talks. It's
just cool. It's over in Chelsea.
I can't recommend it enough.
That sounds really cool.
How long do you think it's going to be
before someone creates some really bad
ass artificial environment
for like the rift?
So we're really incredible world
of Warcraft tidewell places.
The thing is is the biggest mistake
with the rift was putting doom three and
team fortress on it. Why is that?
Because their games are not made for Vr.
The pacing of the Vr game and like the
the screen Bob and they mount the gun
moves and everything that can contribute
to nausea, you need to make like a,
a scuba diving sim or space dog fighting
Sim, that kind of thing. Like you know,
or missed flight game where
you're exploring the island
and mimicking the pain.
The pacing has got to be a lot slower.
It's like when Bungee put first
person shooters on consoles eco,
you couldn't have the quake three
ut pacing. They had this, you know,
master chief jumped very, very slowly.
You know, he didn't run incredibly fast.
Right. And people like took a, you
know, half a clip to take down.
That's how they designed the game
for the console controller. Right.
It's the same thing for the
rift. And I think, you know,
I'll porn jokes aside man,
like that I,
you know,
and that one simulator where I sat
there and looked down and saw my little
virtual legs and I could see that I was
in a space ship and I looked around,
I was like boom. And I, even when I saw
the early version of this, I'm like,
I want it under this, someone
invest on it. Cause uh, the thought,
if you probably haven't seen the High
Rez have, you know, if you ever want to,
you make it out to Orange County,
I can make an intro and you
can check out the latest stuff.
I've got the low rise a development unit
and it's fun just sitting there playing
with butterflies and stuff like that.
But I could see where I got sick just
walking around and that, you know,
and like I had to sit down. But yeah,
they believe right now that, you know,
the seat of Vr experience is the
ideal one. Right. And you know,
just they made this,
somebody made this one demo and
they're crowd sourcing the killer app.
Essentially.
They're just having developed the
developers who like help solve all the
problems, which is fucking
brilliant. Just one APP.
We have to keep your hands on your
keyboard and not move your hands.
And first the fly comes out and cause
you're sitting at a desk and it starts
bugging you and then all of a sudden
like thousands of fly start like going
around and the three d audio
is fantastic. And so, you know,
the whole idea is like you want to itch
yourself cause that little thing goes
off in your head about the bugs,
right?
Then a velociraptor comes into the room
and just start screaming in your face.
And then, uh, something, I think,
oh that a spider starts crawling up
your little virtual arm and like, see,
then you can hear it like
chewing on your ear and shit.
You could probably find it on youtube.
I don't remember what the
fucking thing was called,
but that's kind of cool stuff that they're
doing. Right. Wow. But yeah, that's uh,
you know,
they,
they solved a lot of the VR issues
with just field of view and they keep
cracking that problem by peeling with
at that onion of what VR is. And, uh,
sooner or later they gonna fully crack it.
And when you see the unreal engine
four demo on that shit and that like,
there's like this hell night that's like
eight feet tall and stands in front of
you. I mean, your ass puckers
you can't help it, you know,
when the snowflakes are falling,
you stick out your tongue,
you want to like catch them.
It's pretty damn convincing.
That's why I'm more excited for things
like the rift than I am about next gen
consoles. It's like, yeah,
it's new consoles and they're
cool and they're better.
That can hopefully finally just,
you only have one input,
but at the same time they know is not
a lot of great games right now. And uh,
I'm on Linkedin. It, it'd be
possible to do like unreal,
like to port unreal over
to, uh, to that, well,
my last words when I left
epic and then when I,
cause it gave the whole
like speech was to a,
I told him that he shot fees for
closers. Yeah, yeah. ABC Great.
I watched that speak to you about
once every six months. And then, um,
when he pulls up the fucking brass balls,
I told him a reboot,
unreal or unreal tournament,
especially on the first
unreal and unreal engine four.
Cause the idea for that game was
fucking golden. It's like, oh,
it's the Bermuda triangle of the galaxy.
So you could do whatever
the hell you want.
And the thing that we
lost a bet that game was,
it was just as much about exploration and
like a sense of wonder as it was about
the combat. You know, it felt,
it felt mysterious. You know,
he had the giant hubs and everything and
had a little bit of, like I told him,
if they redo it, it would be
essentially [inaudible], you know,
Skyrim that game to introduce
that, but PSI Phi. Right.
It'd be fucking to crush it. Unreal
is a fun game, man. It's really,
really exciting.
When it came out the first time you had
to do battle with that crazy dreadlock
thing was fucking that was, yeah, that was
my whole sequence. I designed that one.
Um, the uh, that was held developing that
game was that, yeah, we were in Waterloo,
Ontario, Canada, which
is like a college town,
but it didn't have a fun college
town benefits of like cool,
shitty bar that I saw and I didn't
even, I didn't drink back then. Anyway,
insert drinking.
I was like 25 and uh,
basically to spend a year on and off up
there from southern California in like,
we've just all just up at digital extremes
working on that game actually. Um,
you know, talking to all of the people
who worked on it, it's like, it was like,
it was our nam or something.
It was like such a to lose,
we're 16 plus hours a day, man.
Like eating the local fast food.
It was fucking horrible.
This is before Internet porn too.
So I'd actually go to the quickie Martin.
I'd like pick up those like, you know,
swank and all those like Raunchy
Hazmat at times. Dude, good time.
When I left the apartment complex,
they had rented for us.
There is a pile of porno magazines
that must've been like that limit.
They're like a thousand of them and I
just left him there for like the land to
deal. Yeah, they used to,
they used to be the only way you could
get porn either to buy it and he had to
step up like a man and never sound like
that and never found my dad's stash.
Never ever. I found mine
after, after he died,
my mom confirmed it and now he's had
those pulling on Max and I'm like, fuck.
Where were they just had like some porno
dungeon probably at a locker. Yeah.
Probably kept them somewhere.
Yeah. Wait from prying eyes.
He didn't have a spanky wary.
Maybe had like a special hollowed
out logs kept in the woods,
in the woods jail the night look around.
But did you ever find,
I found support in the woods.
It was France and in the way I did as
something awful thread about that a while
back that like everybody, every
young men in America, you,
you flip them growing up here, you
found it. And I always said it was,
it was always swank or Rhonchi ass
ones. It was never like playboy. Yeah,
it was always Sherry. Yeah, Dude.
It's somehow like the subject of
blondish came up the other day.
I was chatting with a lawn
edge Wantage do you remember,
do you mean Janine Lindemulder
the porn star? She,
she did this whole stripping act with
Juliane where it's just like a much is in
the nineties you know too much. Listen
to what you're saying. You're saying.
It's like, well, my point is,
have you seen Jeannine lately? No.
Brian can Google that.
Why?
I'm trying to get this computer because
she was in the cover of the blink when
any two album.
Remember she had the nurse thing,
she looked for eight and she was
gorgeous and she baked yet she's just,
I mean, it's rough, man.
I don't want to say it.
I don't want to make fun of the girl.
No, I just, it's, it's sad, man.
Sorry, I'll start off business. It's
hard out there for porn actresses.
Here's that oculus rift thing that you're
talking about with the spider crabs
here. This is wild, man. Hey Brian.
What is this thing that this
computer's do one at the bottom. What?
It was like this little bubble that's
telling me everything and macro SX.
It's like voiceover or
something like that. I don't
know what it is. What's that?
It's accessibility. It's probably in your
general settings. He probably hit it.
When you
find out what it's setting us for that
it's that wheelchair or something in the
settings. Really. That's your Mac
imploding after you spilled your drink on.
It can't be that. That doesn't
happen. I don't see that.
Wheelchair settings. What does that
accessibility, where the fuck is that?
It's probably probably the top.
Okay.
No to, there's a hot key for
it. Yeah. This is probably
a hot key on your keyboard.
Also. I do not see accessibility
in any of these options.
Users, parental controls? No.
Find out where it is. Man.
This is ridiculous. I'm still on
PC. Do you really? Yeah. Well,
so we got those a an I'm going
to no way fucking affiliated,
but we got the razor blade laptops
and like normally when you get a PC,
the amount of like OEM
bullshit on accessibility.
Like you buy the thing and there's like
8 million like Hewlett Packard desktop
manager and all sorts of Shit in the
computer just runs terribly and you just
reformat the damn thing. But this
thing at three icons on the desktop,
like none of that bullshit.
Uh, here's the, the flies
flying around that does look,
oh, you see fucking crazy. And uh, the,
the five one is what sells it.
The velociraptors are not the
most convincing philosophy.
What do you find when you're talking
about like a good PC build for a laptop?
Like what,
what is a,
a company that you go to that has like
the same kind of quality that apple has?
Well, with we'd said I buy power.com and
you had, you had bad luck with it. Yeah,
I'm honestly, well the, when we
get around to like building it,
I'm going to just use the wisdom
of the crowd and see what,
like the Twitter verse says,
so you got to build your own laptop
so when you buy I'm going to,
I'm going to go to the place where I can
customize and then they ship it to my
house.
I'm not going to like write like a Falcon
northwest type of deal or like a real
like hardcore desktop PC. Right. I'm
laying am my eventually going to go,
I mean just on the laptop right now, but
when you want to do some serious gaming,
like I can play League of legends on it,
but you know when it comes
down to first person shooters,
I play the bioshock infinite DLC on my PT,
on my razor blade laptop.
And it's just like the keys are too
small for the good wasd movement. Right,
right. I mean, you know, my
big, my fucking big fat fingers,
I'm like accidentally hitting the
wrong buttons. The wrong time.
You make me want to play
games, man, I want to do it.
You've seen that league of legends and
the fact that they had their championship
and they filled the staple center,
like that game is so big
that they basically had a
sporting event. Wait a minute,
they, how long has this game been
out? It's been out a few years. Um,
and they filled the fucking,
yeah, basically this top
down strategy game and a,
with all these unique characters and
like saying there's not even an investor
much of a single player
component to the game.
It's more of a multiplayer of strategy
game and people cosplay for it.
They dress up as all the crazy
awesome characters. Yeah.
There it is at the staple center.
How many of you guys seen some of
the hype videos for the performance?
How many of you guys know that?
Where's,
I think it was a couple of Korean
kids wound up winning. This is insane.
Look at the size of that fucking crowd
free there to watch people play games
free to play game.
How much did they pay to get in there?
To Watch people play a game?
Uh,
I don't know how much it
was for tickets for that,
but I'm guess everyone's cheering
and shit, dude. It's, it's,
wow, we're in a movie,
right? We're in a movie.
And so that game was
pitched at ea years ago and,
and ea basically laughed him out of
the room and now just crushing it.
They're hiring like everybody,
all the developers in La and like,
they make these awesome cinematics
also to support their, uh,
kind of what the Ip is
and what the universe is.
And then crazy characters like I'm playing
as this like little girl who has like,
um, she can pirate telekinesis
or whatever, you know,
firestarter shit. And um,
she has this like little bear with her
little stuffed bear and like through
magic, the bear becomes giant flaming
and a tax people. And I mean, it's a,
it's an incredibly deep game. Wow. Every,
everybody has a giant stiffy
feed the concept of e sports.
Now they want to make an esport
game. And it's like, dude,
you have to make a great air tight game
first before you could ever consider
even doing that. But I mean it's
beautiful graphics. Oh, it's,
it's got that it just beautiful
art style. Right. And, um,
I think they're about to move into a new
facility that got to be up to like four
or 500 people. Easy. God dammit.
It's old John that they call it.
The mobile is like, uh, what was
it? Online battle arena and um,
that whole genre is just huge these days.
I just could still shoot her guy
if they can. Yeah, I am as well.
I can tell you if I, if I'm
able to get a studio going, uh,
want to make a PC shooter,
like that's like let's Sony and Microsoft
fight it off for the next few years
and you know, the, the Pc, you know, you
know as well as I do Joe Communities,
everything, right? Like it's so much
of it is like creating your own,
you know,
religion,
your own brand and the pcs where
the community gathers for Reddit,
for youtube videos, for everything.
And you can have some of that.
They were working on it with consoles, but
you know, the PC is not going anywhere.
Well, you know what, you can't fuck with
the accuracy of the mouse. You just can't.
They tried. I've seen all those
other things fucked with them.
They can't mess with a really good mouse.
And keyboard is just the such for CISE
movement, the way he can move around.
You get that muscle memory and people
are just popping off head shots.
I mean it's, I mean, especially getting a
little older, it gets a little harder. Um,
but it's uh, it's fucking awesome
and like that type of thing.
Translating to pro is just
compelling to me. Yeah. People like,
I've had conversations with people that
I can't believe you were addicted to.
Games are so stupid. I
mean, you could, you know,
it's just a story that somebody wrote.
I don't think you get it.
Like when you're playing multiplayer,
what you're doing is you're
engaged in this fast twitch,
very realistic,
hyper sensate sensation filled experience.
It's good for you.
And in the back of your head,
your brain's compiling the code
of the day. This is good for you.
Sounds like a crack dealer. The
first one's free. You're a dealer.
Klutzy beats is that one of their awesome
cinematics they put up for the game
and it's just like where you got kind of
get to know that gambit looking guy and
then there's, it's bad ass
fucking awesome graphics. Yeah.
That's west Borland. He's in the
game. Right. Cause it looks like,
it looks like one of the outfits that
he wears West Portland, the guy from um,
a limp Bizkit that bad ass bass player,
guitar player,
whatever it is wouldn't things. But
yeah, so a lot of people right now are,
they are trying to get into that whole
thing with that genre and they're just
like, dude at that point like blizzard's
coming out with a game and the genre and
blizzard I think is going to
have a shot at doing well.
But everybody else
initially, dude. Wow. Yeah.
If you're the fifth one in then you know
you're gonna wind up being like the is
cola to Pepsi and coke and all that.
If you could figure out a way
to use an Omni directional,
like one of those circular treadmills
and a really good accurate gun that you
actually hold and carry with a strap
that you put over your shoulder.
They have that dude, did they really
have something really good though?
Like a game? They haven't made a game
for you. It's called the Omni. Um,
I got to use it at comicon.
And what it does is essentially you're
strapped into your waist and you don't go
anywhere and it's a super slippery floor
that's kind of a bowl and you put on
these special shoes that are
super slick and if you didn't,
if you weren't strapped in,
you fall, fall right over.
But because you're strapped in,
you have the illusion of walking again.
I was full and running on the thing
playing halflife two. Um, again,
the problem with that was the pacing of
halflife two is done for a person who
just holds WASD and
whips their mouse around.
And if you just try and dump it on
the rift with the Omni, it's just,
it's an exhausting experience where
you're lucky to get three kills there.
It sounds like someone's a pussy.
Fucking get in shape and chief hat,
this is awesome. This is what I needed
in my life. This would change me,
this kind of shit. We'll fucking change
me. So they, that's a workout man. Yeah,
we're getting some wicked shape do.
We did a Kickstarter for that and they
raised a bunch of money and I Amandla
where do you, where do I put
away my credit card information?
That's fucking bad ass
man. I love it. Yeah. So,
and it totally takes up a small footprint
in like your room, right? Ah. So it's a,
it's, it's cool man. It's just, it,
it right now for the time being,
I think seated VR is the way to go
until they solve all the problems.
Like it's like walk before you run.
Like let's, let's figure it out.
Just regular Vr Dad, I want to run, I
want to run with a gun. Let's do this.
What are you saying? I'm not falling
over bitch, you might follower.
I'm not going to fall over. No, no.
When you have that, those God was on,
I mean I was just trying to like grab a
butterfly at one point and like, whoa.
You like lose yourself cause
it's kind of like a, it's,
it tricks your mind into thinking you're
actually disorienting and the low rise
makes sense. The low Rez, when it
has a screen door type look on it.
The High Rez one, it's like, it's
great. And I mean, you know, the,
the tech technology only gonna get
lighter. It's gonna get better faster,
the whole nine yards.
So it's just that it would like at this
stage of the game that they would come
up with something like that.
It's like,
well VR was supposed to be the big thing
in the 90s right? Man, lawnmower man,
his lawnmower man.
I thought the graphics in that movie
was so awesome and they don't hold up at
all.
But one more man is another one of those
Stephen King books that became like, ah,
an okay movie. But God damn, that book
was bad. I never actually read the book.
It's fucking great.
I mean,
cause this is the whole William Gibson
Cyber punk thing and it's like, dude,
do you know how many years it's
been since the Matrix? Like it's,
I think it was 98,
99 and the SQL never happened.
Well the sequels that did happen
are terrible. Yeah. What is, uh,
who is this Doug Benson?
That's right. Yeah,
it was stone and he was like
getting sick on it. Dude.
You saw the viral video of
the little old lady who, uh,
put it on and she's just like, am
like wow. Meet CNN and everything.
Like she's like,
did you go to Tuscany to make this and
all this stuff because they have a demo
where you're kind of, you're
in, you're in Tuscany. Right?
It's just virtual reality stuff. But
she was so convincing to her. It's like,
think about just, you know, the non gaming
applications of the shit. Like imagine,
you know, if, you know,
you have a travel app where you can
just go and experience like, you know,
Venice or Tuscany or whatever. Right?
That kind of thing. For virtual tourism,
right?
Well,
that's going to be what movies are not
going to go to a movie and sit in front
of a screen like a dummy.
Not Everybody can afford to
have a theater room or a big TV.
So imagine if you're like a college kid
and you want to watch a movie in Imax,
you know,
you put this on and it's,
they have actually have a
theater demo where you're like,
you can look around and see
the seats next to you and it's,
there's a big screen in front of you and
it's, you feel like you're at an imax.
I could totally see that and I could
see you being in a virtual reality where
you're in a movie theater watching a
movie and everything goes horribly wrong.
And you look around the theater and
you see zombies Werewolf's and shit.
I could imagine they could make a
pretty God damn immersive experience.
I knew a guy who is making
a game for the rift and uh,
his demo was basically that
you're playing a, you're,
you're sitting on a sofa
playing a video game on your TV,
in the virtual environment and then weird
shit in your inner ear and your, your,
your fake living room.
And then it's like a dark and stormy
night and then weird shit starts happening
all around you.
That would be dope as fuck if they had
a theater where you're sitting there in
your seat and in the theater,
your seat goes down into the floor and
out pops an Omni directional track like
that thing,
whatever the fuck all on mill
Omni treadmill and then you,
you pick up a gun that's on the treadmill
and everybody gets locked in and you
all like Eh, are interactive in the movie
together, stormed the beach, you know,
fucking wild.
That would be mad if they,
I mean it would be a completely
different kind of entertainment.
And one of the problems,
the a movie where you go and sit down
or games are too fucking scary on it.
Oh I bet. Right. Cause when you turn and
like, you know, monsters right there.
Did you guys ever play slender man?
You'd have a heart attack.
What is slender man? Uh, it's PC,
first person, little mini games.
So there's this whole,
you know,
they'll all the internet
memes and things like that.
A few years ago this became like a thing
where like the Internet created this
mythos of the slick, creepy, skinny,
scary dude. And whenever he'd show up,
the kids would vanish,
right?
And someone made this little game called
slender man that you can download and
it's essentially you have to go find
ate scraps of paper that are, and it's,
you know,
they're random where they're going to
be and it's a dark night and you have a
flashlight in your,
in a forest.
And if you basically see slender man and
you look at them from too long, you die.
And so what happens is nothing, nothing
happens at first. It's real quiet.
And you'll get, you'll get the first
piece and all a sudden you start hearing
this like factory, like pounding starts.
It's very ominous. And then he, you know,
you turn around and, and at the
end of the, he first shows up,
like at the end of the road,
he's like any,
you just can barely see this really
skinny, creepy guy. And then they'll,
they'll deliberately like put them
around corners and like there's,
there's a part we have to go in like a
little warehouse to get a piece of paper.
And the pacing of it is so wild on
this entire youtube videos of people's
reactions to slender man,
like falling off their chair and
the graphics are simple. His shifts.
I was worried about really skinny people.
I guess it's cause
they're fucking hungry as
shit and they're willing to get
desperate. What's that? That,
that that goes back to the, the grays, the
alien thing, right? Like that's skinny,
slender ice thing, right? Yeah. I can some
things, but this is a person, right? Yeah.
The quality of this video, it looks like
sound like a commodore 64 right? Now.
Remember that video that somebody made
where it was like Johnny or something
like that? It was a, uh, like a little
alien rubber thing. Rubber Johnny. Yeah.
What was that? That was a, it was
a viral promotion for something.
It's like an la based artist.
Really stirring it up. Pull that up.
That was rubber John. It was
pretty upsetting. It's weird man.
It was one of the weirdest things I
think I've ever seen on I got under your
skin. Yeah, right. It's like that kind of,
that's why I like insidious is one of
my favorite horror movies. Cause the,
a lot of the heart har references in
it. Subtle here. See that one? Yes.
James wan and the scene where
um, the, ah, the mother,
they think they're free of the haunting
and they're at the new house and then
the tiptoe through the tulips
starts playing. Yeah. This is,
if this was like on Fox News and
past as like some alien film,
people would remember when alien
autopsy was out of the box. Totally
dating. Like, wait a
minute, wait a minute.
What did you just really make me watch
35 minutes a TV to show me a rubber suit.
They're not going to fucking
find big foot. Quit looking.
See My tweets from last night.
No. Oh my God. I was going crazy.
I was watching big finding big foot and
uh, I was, I was getting mad, you know,
cause they were talking crazy shit.
And uh,
they had this woman on and they were like,
she's a pull up this picture of Brian,
if you can see,
it's like the woman says Kelly,
they talking about how they found big
for the, like Kelly's very artistic.
So she decided to sketch what we saw
that day and she unveiled this fucking
picked click on the picture though,
so you could really see it.
She unveils this picture. Wow. And
you know, she's Kelly's very artistic.
This is what she decided to. So the
fucking guy, the big foot expert,
he sees that picture. He goes, wow,
that's anything other than
the worst piece of shit,
big foot drawing and it history.
It looks like the man and the wing
from the twilight zone, it's worse.
The man on the wing was more
realistic and he looked like a furry.
That is one of the worst
drawings of all time. You know,
they should have said like,
oh, that's interesting. But
instead they're like, wow,
dude. I had a friend send
me a photo years ago, uh,
to the characters that jazz jackrabbit
game I made that w happened to be,
she was staying at a hotel
that happened to be happening.
A having a furry convention was,
that was her story. Anyway, and uh,
there were two people dressed as these
characters as furries that I had created.
I'm like, that's
hilarious. What if I done,
we were in Pittsburgh once accidentally
and it was a coincided with a furry
convention.
We were there for the UFC and the,
all the hotels were taken up and they
had a hard time finding hotel rooms for
fighters and people because they
were all taken up by furries.
And when we were at this one hotel,
the guy told us that the people that
were there that were staying asked him to
put a litter box in the lobby
so they could shit in the lobby.
Wow. That's, that's, that's some
dedication. He said that they were like,
they're basically the guys, our argument
was, look for this whole weekend,
it's all fairies. And he tried to
say, look, it's not all furries.
We have regular guests here too.
And they're like,
we'll put it in the corner
and it only be for like,
they wanted to be able
to shit in a letter box.
I mean maybe the guy was trolling,
but I don't think so. I mean,
I'm not saying the guy who told me this,
I'm saying the guard,
I mean because they have little lake holes
that they could fuck through in their
suits. But so then what it yet that's the
tattoo. I um, I remember who got that.
It was at that goes, uh, that's this jazz.
That's the thing. That's what, you know,
dude,
that's what I miss.
What people getting tattoos of stuff I
came up with that was the biggest like
gas like and you know I,
I met this summer,
I was at a Pax East conference in Boston
and it's like really normal looking
hipster girl comes up to me and pulls up
beside of her shirt and she had written
the oath that the gears took or like
tattooed on her side and I just,
I I came up that shit on
like a Tuesday like Ah,
rod needs this for the okay cool.
And like the in the in like the the key
or stamp and it's like if you Google
gears,
tattoos,
Brian,
it may maybe a very strange nerd gas
them when you come on that that thing,
she has that thing written on the side
of her body. You shoot a load on that.
If you're like a real super nerd and
you're banging a chick hot check has got
that tattooed on our side.
Like wow,
must be pretty intense orgasm the whole
generation of girls now that just grew
up playing games and it's no big deal now.
Yeah.
What were we talking about right before
that there was something we were talking
about where I was going to
the litter box and the forest.
So the guy told me that not only did they
do that is these are all gears tattoos
were showing on the
eastern versus raising.
Not only did the guy say
that they wanted that,
but they also wanted to be fed and bowls.
They wanted them to bring bowls up to uh,
the room,
like their food so they can
eat on the ground like a dog.
So I've seen the furry outfits
haven't tried, went on,
but how do you like there's
gotta be a mouth hole and,
and for the whole back thing,
like you have to a trap door,
like the old school minor
underwear, right? Oh yeah, yeah.
But then you can't shit in the litter box
and you have to take off the, depends.
Take off your furry off it and then
drop the shit in the letterbox.
It's a matter of sure.
Defend the pens like a last ditch effort.
If you can't figure out how to get the
suit off and imagine like did have this
clean very often like the,
the stench of the sweat and every ladies
you could get will usable it's west
best way a fair enough.
The um,
the people that were staying there,
which we're working there,
whether it was interesting because it
wasn't just one person that was telling us
his stories,
it was like one guy came over and told
us about the litter box and another guy
came over and told us about bowls and
they want to be served in bowls and they
were all living might be legit then it
was just one dude or isn't enough legit.
I think there's something no one's
telling you not to be a fairy.
I just want to get that
out there right now.
I don't have any judgment on furries.
Whatever works for you.
If you enjoy doing it,
who cares?
But I would imagine that a lot of people
that like to be anonymous like that
also have some other peculiar quirks.
I,
has anybody ever done a study?
I've always wondered like where
does that fascination start?
There's oof fucking know, right? Like
your humping her teddy bear as kid
could be.
Don't like people.
People been mean to you and you wish
you lived in a world of cartoons,
some playful, childish world where
you just don't even see people's face.
He just pull on the hatch and bang them.
That's brownies are the creepiest ones.
These grown men that love
like my little pony. You know,
I didn't even know about that until
that show we did the other night.
Some guy pulled it out.
I have it.
I had a my little pony doll in my pocket
because I have a three year old. Yeah.
He just told me to hold up.
You still have it.
I gave it to her and give
her back to her. But um, um,
someone said that there's a bunch of men
who were into my little pony and they
call him bronies.
I mean,
I can't believe I didn't know about
maybe I did know and I just refused.
There's so much stuff there's ever hit
her about the utility kilt. Utila kilt.
Yeah. It's like a kilts that
has all these pockets and shit.
And they sell them at comicon.
It's like a thing there's like
dudes are wearing around. Yeah.
So underneath nothing, just balls assuming
nothing. That's like the greatest,
like what do you think's what's under
there? What do you think's under there?
Yeah, they uh, they have been doing
that for years. You see this shit.
So how the conventions,
I think it's so they can collect swag.
If you're a guy walking around in a skirt
with no underwear on, that's so hack.
Huh?
Cause girls had been doing that forever.
It's like you're stealing their thunder.
Fair enough. I'll tell it to them.
My Scottish friends, yeah, they were
actually probably doing it before skirts,
right?
Yeah.
I've had Scottish friends who told me
they wear the kilt out and they get more
attention from girls to grabbing
their balls all night. Really?
How they're hanging around with dirty
bitches. Watch a ball grabbing wenches.
That's what I say. Where are they? This
is taking place. Band named the ball.
Having the winches should and if it's not,
please make it so you could still make it.
So they were all touch tunes out at some
of the bars around here. What does that,
it's basically looks like a giant iPhone
in the wall and then you can play music
through your phone for free for a fee,
but you can pay to like twice the feed
of plate. Make your song playing next.
It's fucking awesome. Really genius.
Every song. That's fascinating.
We will go to like a redneck bars and
like play the most non southern music.
We were at one and we put on a
electric six this gay bar. Oh Man.
Like the locals didn't know about the APP
and they were trying to figure out why
isn't it playing like my music.
I will not take it to a gay bar.
And then we put them Brittany and
why does it work? Who controls it?
The person who there's basically a song
queue and then you can interrupt it.
Yeah. Yeah. Basically if you pay extra
to make your song next, then you're next.
Yeah. It's a total dick move. It's, it's
great cause there's that guy named gamble.
Highly loved this guy who I'd
recommend looking at Mommy's on spot.
It sounds like a big black
porn star with a cowboy hat.
He has names gambling.
He has this song about gambling and fuck
and you and your mouth boy is a song
called balls in your butthole.
Anything play that song really loud it.
Most bars you can just sit there
and just love life. Look there.
It's called dogs in a bathtub.
Ball's in your book. I'm saying,
but the act of doing that is called
Doggie in the bathtub because it's hard to
keep the dog in the bathtub.
Doggie in the bathtub. I might,
my buddy of vo that one time.
Um,
I don't understand that Doggie in the
bathtub because it's hard to keep a dog in
the bathroom,
but it's not hard to use that APP and
turn the music on while I was talking
about putting your balls
and someone's ass. Oh,
okay.
He's the shit out of me.
There's videos up that if you look at
the Google guys videos of guys putting
balls in someone's arrows buttholes while
fucking him. Yeah. Yeah. Putting them in.
I still have friends that don't know
Google it. You'll eat the pickle jar.
I don't pick a job routine. We're not the
guy's ass. And then it broke. Oh yeah.
One guy. One girl. It's rough.
Whatever it is. One guy. One Cup. Yeah.
That's one of the roughest I
ways to deal with that guy.
The chunks and interview.
He survived it. Yeah.
I heard it was a breakaway
glass that they use.
I would like the fake stuff for the
movies. Really interesting. Are you sure?
That's what it's really heard.
Yeah, but candy glass, right?
This, this, I heard shit.
It's not good enough.
In 2013 Mr Reichel BME is fake.
No, some of it wasn't fake. That
video was, no. Some of it all.
It was all BME.
Paint.
Olympics was was a series of images that
people had gathered up online and taken
and put it into a video.
As far as was it a real pain Olympics
like people were like practicing to see
who could cut off the mostly
wind? Definitely not. It was just,
they called it the BME paint Olympics
because BME was a website that was around
for Shannon Lariat. The guy who ran it
was a friend of mine online. We interact,
I think he died without all the categories
of crazy buddy modification, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I'm
pretty sure he died. Um,
but he was very friendly online and he
sent me a free membership wants when I
wrote a blog about, um, I forget what
it was. Something about, you know,
me being curious about body modification,
like all these different weird
things that people do like, you know,
like put plates in their lips
and different tribal shit.
So he sent me all the really extreme
shit that he has on his website,
which just like dudes Cox
split down the middle,
this is all like way before you'd
get this from a Google search,
like you had to know like
not style projects project.
This was exactly what I was going to say.
I found out about him from style project
and uh, I find the older, right. Again,
I can't live like when I hit my thirties
I can't look at that shit anymore.
Well you know what it is,
man.
You've seen it and you know what it does
to you and if you're stupid you keep
looking, keep wanting to feel like
shit. I still have never seen two girls.
One Cup. I have no desire.
It's not bad. If you're,
if you're a person who's seen,
you know the murder videos and
all this stuff that you've,
I'm sure you've seen two girls,
one companies,
shit is that pain Olympics video reel,
so he would look at whether you're
doing this, what does it mean?
Where are you getting this answer for it?
It's like crowd source creator
of the Bma Payment Olympics.
I did an interview with him a long
time ago for a parody of the BME pain
Olympics. Yeah, that was the one we cut
up the video of the BME paint Olympics.
Final round was a parody of the BME
pain Olympics where people form and same
body modifications in
front of a live audience.
This video though was a
video just making fun of it.
Like where the guy is actually a chopping
off his dick. It was actually right,
but no,
some of them are real dude.
I'm pretty sure on some of the different
things that were in that video that was
compiled.
We're actually actually really happened.
Like people did actually cut themselves.
This isn't,
I mean there's not like a shortage of
those videos out there of guys doing it
and they just compiled a
bunch of them together.
Yeah. Um, when we were
in like late twenties,
we'd look at that shit at epic all the
time and then like eventually we got an
HR department and we had to like shut.
They tell you to stop.
Yeah. Did they really? How dare they,
you created such amazing pieces of
work while you were doing all that.
They think they know better.
They can tell you what the fucking thing
doesn't matter. His legal issues, dude,
you know the legal issues.
Here's what's legal.
It should be legal to watch that stuff
and it should be legal to fire anybody
who complains.
That's what I say.
If you're working in an
office and someone's like,
you have quite a few bees
over there, watch and goes
get their heads chopped off.
Oh, I don't want to see it. Like
then you don't fit in. Yeah, get out.
Well company culture starts from the
top of the food, the very top. Yeah.
But when you have to create as a
very specific work environment,
God that's gotta suck.
Like if you work like you sell insurance,
you have to have like very specific
code of conduct and ethics. No Fun.
The thing I, the thing, I don't
like his fucking politics now.
Like the the ladder climbing off bullshit.
Disgusting.
And it also like you're
seeing like, like those, um,
when people get together at like have
like a corporate retreat here and they all
sit around the dinner table and like we
were next to him the other night at a
restaurant and one guy was talking
and toasting and everybody was like,
oh Christ him again.
And they just this weird culture,
you know what valve valve a,
the video games.
Yeah.
They fly their entire company and the
entire company's families to Hawaii for
like two weeks every year. Wow. That's
bad ass. I'm like, fuck. Really?
Like out like you know.
As much as I would like to think
I got along with my coworkers,
you know when I go on vacation to Hawaii,
they're kind of the last
people I want to see my movie.
They're all just banging each other and
Hawaiians to drink an APP. Swingers,
swingers,
subcultures.
Fucking the shit out of each other
all over the beach and who gives it?
They used to do that for too.
Do you want to fuck the fuck my wife,
I have two weeks out of the year.
Everything's cool. It's like that movie,
the purge. It was the worst
fucking [inaudible] of the year.
They all go to the big guy,
let it just fuck on lava rocks.
Just like wild animals shredding their
ass to whatever they can until they can't
do it anymore.
And then they go to the fucking
hospital and covered in black sand.
They come back home
and they blog about it.
Jesus started talking shit about each
other. Valve doesn't give a fuck.
They can do whatever the hell they want
now. They made a lot of money, right?
Well what they did was they made steam,
which is essentially a publisher and
like they just raking in money from that
and they can do whatever
they want game wise.
There's just some next level
shit up there, man. What
have they created? A mood.
Video Games have Valve Korea.
They did a Dota too. Um,
which is one of those mobile type
games like League of legends.
Halflife of core stand for multiple
Liam multiplayer online battle arena.
How's that kind of strategy?
I would know that dare you lose in
the New York crane. Firefly. Now this,
how dare you? There's a lot of
people out there. Cliffy big dude.
I could never live in fucking
Seattle. No, it's just the gray man.
You can never live in Seattle.
Brian. I put a good enough up there.
It is beautiful. I love
it up there. Yeah. We, we,
we jokingly look at like the whole
weather app on my wife's phone. It's like,
you know, San Diego, Sunny Raleigh,
pretty good. Seattle, Gregg, Gregg, Gregg.
Beautiful though.
It's so God damn green cause it's
so easy to grow shit up there.
God damn the forests are immense.
That's so incredible when
you driving around up there.
If he makes gray with green, you're still
gonna get shit. I think people that,
I think people that go up there though,
Brian,
I think what they do is they just
take vacations every year. Yeah.
They go somewhere like really funny.
Nice and sunny like Hawaii.
When you live in Ohio though,
it's pretty known that it's the
one in the gray skies I think.
And then like percentage
wise and it's Ohio. Yeah.
And because it's just always cloudy,
always rainy and I think it's maybe the
number one. I hate to getting dark early.
Shit.
That's the worst.
Yeah.
That doesn't bother me that much.
I think it's important to have a mixture
and I agree with you that I would way
rather have California's weather where
it's always sunny and pretty nice all the
time. Then going back to Boston and
deal with those fucking gray winters.
Cause those winters were horrible.
Dude. What's up? Pressing? That was up
there visiting a a while back and I was a,
what's wasn't Quincy. We went to some
other town, I can remember to visit.
My buddy drew,
who's a writer on bioshock and we're at
an Irish pub and having a pint in some
random girls talking to him and she was,
and it was a really cute street
right there. And she's like, ah,
why do you think of a town? And I'm
like, that's lovely. And she's like,
why do you have Quia? I'm
like, as I said, the town
shit is fucked her just to prove a point.
Then she's thinking even want
to query on show you Joe clear
married dude. Well you should use
a rubber dick. Then other respect.
Then she carry rubber deck just to
just to put women in their place. Yeah.
There you go. Days of
clouds. Seattle, Washington,
226 days of heavy clouds per
year. Wow. That's 62% of the time.
Portland, Oregon, slightly last Buffalo,
New York. Slightly less. It's birds.
Wow. Yeah, a lot of
Ohio's. Yeah, it's rough.
But you know what I was going to say is
that I do think that California has the
better set of weather, but I think there's
some benefit to experiencing whether,
I think there's a benefit to being
in the rain. I think it's nice,
it makes the environment better,
it's healthier, cleans out the,
I like having seasons in North Carolina,
if you have seasons of the year is
fucking fly right by seasons are nice.
It makes you appreciate the warm
weather. And then, you know,
in the middle of January we'll go to
like the Caribbean for a week or two and
just fucking in getting them,
I'm a beach guy, dude. However,
I was in Edmonton like couple of weeks
ago and it was fucking zero. Yeah.
And I came back to La and it was eight.
I got a buddy of Louise's working at
WB Games in Montreal. He, I did the,
the new Batman game and he would tell me,
he's like,
get off his bus or get out
of the subway or whatever,
go into work and like the 10 minute walk
to the actually get to the officer's
beer would freeze. Yeah, that's totally
hear such good things about Montreal.
But like if I go up there to visit,
it's gonna be in the summer cause I just,
I'm done with winter.
Right. It's just rough ice.
Two gigs in Montreal in the winter.
They should do while the comedy works.
Montreal when I was living in New York
would fly up there and it was, you know,
minus 10 minus 15 did you ever have to
adjust your ax depending on where you are?
Do you like depending on like, you know,
in French Canadian crowd for example,
I should have and that's why I failed
many times in those environments. Yeah,
no. Yeah, it depends. You know,
there's two of thought. One School
of thought is do something
that everybody's going to like.
That's the Jay Leno School of thought.
Like, Hey, you know my contract,
I could do my act anyway. Yeah, I can
do it in the little kids. Then man,
I have to take Samson.
Jada guys didn't want to do the act
that Jaylen Leno actually said to me.
I asked him once about Bill
Hicks Cause Bill Hicks road.
So I'm like really mean shit about him
and he's like, ah, I don't know. You know,
a bill didn't want to do what
everybody wanted to hear.
They wanted to do what he wanted to do.
And I think there's only one way to
really get your audience and you have to
like continue to do what you want to do.
And there's going to be nights where
the people don't want to hear that shit.
It's going to be if they
don't know who you are,
especially if you have a dirty act. It's
tricky situations. It's tricky to do.
So a lot of guys would ride
a lot of material that maybe
necessarily it was more
utilitarian, it served a purpose
then it would be like their,
their actual expressions throw that in
there if it felt like it was going on.
I love video games, I love movies, but
I so fucking love comedy. It's fun.
Like I saw, um, Colin Cane Gilson him at
all. No, I don't know Ellie based guy.
He said he's up and coming and he
sees like just imagine Dane Cook.
If he was completely just filthy and
massage, you just hurt my feelings.
I'm going to pee. And why don't you?
No, I'm just kidding. I like Jane.
I'm friends with Tina. I started out
with doing really, but I do have to pay.
We talked to him.
Yeah.
Here's something interesting is that the
tie the top 10 unhappiest cities, uh,
which is crazy cause it's almost the
exact same list that we saw that cloudy.
Like the first one is Portland,
Oregon. Second one is St Louis,
third New Orleans, New
Orleans, Detroit, Cleveland,
Jacksonville, Florida,
Vegas, Nashville. Again,
Cincinnati to Ohio's Atlanta. It looked
Raleigh's not anywhere on there. Yeah.
It keeps being voted. One
of the top 10 cities, man.
I was thinking if I could go anywhere
I'd probably go Texas for the same reason
why it's not as expensive as Austin,
La Austin. Austin is one of my,
my on my shortlist of other places.
I'd love to live.
Elijah Woods said Fuck La and decided to
just move to Austin city. Really? Yeah.
I was up there for south by
southwest dude. That's my,
one of my favorite cities.
And that's why I call Raleigh Mini Austin
cause it's like this little kind of
like mini sea of cool in the
middle of this GOP rolled state.
And uh, you know, I'm fucking
doubling down there. You know,
it's like the coasts are great.
You know,
it's like if we go two hours away to the
beach man and like you could just like
the beach real estate in
Carolina beach is like,
you get a condo in the water for 300
grand. Like it's, and then cause you,
cause you got to Wilmington Wrightsville
which is a little bit old money. Right.
And like the same condo would be like 1
million bucks, but it's like, you know,
you and you, did we go to the yacht
club today or that kind of vibe? Right.
I'd rather be hanging out with all the
fucking rednecks is they're awesome.
Why was just say rednecks are awesome.
Well I come back in and cliff has
been a totally different person.
It's a strange why.
Why was gears of war number two and
number three never reported by the, uh,
to the pcs but yet gears of
war one and was, you know,
a myriad of reasons. It's a,
the only way to really succeed in that
space at the time was to put something on
steam and, uh, it was just
man hours at the time.
So it wasn't an easy conversion from
the ECZEMA. The controls also were,
it didn't translate that well,
you know,
with the whole cover and
everything like that.
Has anybody ever figured out how to do
a keyboard and mouse for console? Uh,
know what they do is they just
make it the twin stick thing.
And what they do is they,
they,
they assist your aim without
you really realizing it.
And so it's called friction adhesion.
So if I'm moving across her over
you and halo, if you ever play it,
it's slightly slows your
cross here a little bit so
it helps you and you're like,
damn, I'm good. Cause
it's actually pretty dope.
If that was like real technology
and actual war, you know,
fight the cursory like found people,
oh that bullet bullets that go around
corners and everything if the the future
and you know at least he saw that
Darpa robot that carries or was Boston
dynamics that can carry like 300 pounds
for him. Right. Exosuits and yeah.
How about those fucking
robot dogs that you can kick?
Yeah and it won't fall down. They have
a button motorcycle like that too. Yeah,
I've seen that. Fucking impressive.
We've got some wild shit coming out.
My biggest problem right now is
just data everywhere. Like a medic.
We're all addicted. Did the feed.
We're addicted to data, news,
news stories like everything breaks.
Things go viral and be like that whole
instance that the executive producer for
like the bachelor who was on the plane
around Thanksgiving with the lady who was
claiming that she was being a bitch and
he sent her some drinks and told her to
eat his dick and it turns out
with the whole thing is fake.
He just made it all up and
it was too late. It had gone
viral. There it is. Look,
yeah, that's incredible. It's crazy. Looks
like a bunch of broken legs and Bambi.
That's like some metal gear,
solid shit right there.
That looks like two men like facing each
other to packages like the fake donkey.
So weird like uh,
like a couple of drunk college kids
trying to move their futon or something.
When those things are acting on their own,
that's when we know that's
going to be a weird thing.
When you see those coming over the
mountains of Pakistan with fucking machine
guns on top of them or Amazon in the
drones. We never really talked about that.
The Amazon, that was more PR
thing for them though. Yeah,
because the amount of hurdles they'd
have to get through for that to happen.
Why don't you explain
what you're talking about?
Amazon was talking about using
actual drones to deliver packages,
which is one of the most ridiculous
things I've ever heard in my life.
That would mean you would have to like a
drone would fly a package to your house
and drop off in front of House.
And a lot of people thought that maybe
that can happen in a hundred years from
now or 20 years from now.
But Amazon's kind of front and talking
about how they're going to deliver dude
with that.
Only a person who has a gun is not going
to try and shoot those fucking things
down 30 to insure them. Right. All right.
Well I'll get mad too. Flies
over their property. Yup.
Also just think about if
this did start catching on,
we would have to say goodbye to sunsets.
We would not see the
clouds or the sky anymore.
We just have thousands of these little
fucking robots flying around to dropping
off tampons. But at the same time, dude,
I haven't gotten into a target in a year.
Right. True. It every, everything
online. But yeah, here's the, uh,
the packages come to this thing I guess.
And then that gets picked up by a drone.
Uh, so supposedly this is real because
it seemed like a practical joke for the
longest time, unless they're just
planning an April fool's now.
Maybe if it's not important shit,
you could just fly it around like that.
But it seems like,
man,
that's not really what shirt I and want
to get my new espresso maker. Yeah.
30 minute delivery though is what you,
they're trying to would
be even in Raleigh with Amazon prime.
We ordered some shit in the afternoon.
The next day, boom. Done.
So this is real. Wow.
This is fucking strange dude.
I think it's them projecting like remember
that old video, um, where it's like,
have you ever,
you know,
second night to your kid or on
a video phone you will write.
That becoming became strangely true.
I think they're kind of projecting
a little bit further forward.
People are going to shoot those fucking
things. Even like kids with BB guns, dude.
Yeah. I just want Amazon
platinum where if I'm home,
the take the shit out of the box and
then they take the box and the wrapping
away. Well you could actually
just shoot the package.
What you could do is
like as the guys flying,
if you had a high powered rifle
and you're looking out the window,
you can just take the package
out from the sky. Yeah. Boom.
And he delivers a package with
a big bullet hole in it. Yeah.
People are gonna get mad too if you're
flying over their fucking house. Yeah.
Eh.
Well they, they're probably planning
on urban areas originally, right.
Where it's already normal black people
urban.
How did urban become black people done?
What the fuck happened there?
That's weird, right? It's very weird.
Like the only like black people I live
in cities or something like a euphemism
for even just want to say is it's
an urban crowd. They want to,
they want to say black people if
they don't want to get in trouble.
So they say it's an urban crowd,
but yet you go to urban outfitters and
stuff is whitest place you've ever been.
Urban outfitters is the opposite of urban.
Right.
That's the dumbest name for that place
ever. It's a hot topic. It's a hot topic.
Suburban outfitters. Yup. Yeah.
How was that urban outfit?
And we have to make a fucking agreement.
I don't know what urban actually means.
I mean I was scared to go in the store
for the first five years. It was open.
That's racist. You thought you were
going to get ganged? Yeah. For you.
Horny free chains. Dude,
I fucking hate the mall.
I don't know if I'm just a grumpy old
man. I just can't stand going there. Yeah,
it's a good place to find stores.
What do you hate about the mall?
It's not forced to you and goes. Yeah,
yeah, it's definitely inefficient.
So don't go. I'm all about
efficiency. Yeah, but it's cool.
You could try clothes on, you
know, buy things, clothes,
clothes and food are the two things you
buy in person. Right. Everything else.
One click that in your phone.
So we got off track,
but I wanted to ask you like
if you were going to buy,
you said you would build your own laptop
PC, but like when you buy one now,
like what company do you [inaudible]
we got the razor blade for the laptop.
What does that mean? It's just, it's
a razor used to make like the Oh,
the Razer mice. Yeah,
same company. The laptop.
And then they just crushed it with
this one. It's a fantastic laptop.
I met that dude, the guy who
calls himself, raise your
guy. Me and Lou Morton who,
who's one of the writers on news radio
and a couple other guys went to, uh,
he had a bunch of prototype mice. That
was back when they had that weird mouse.
Remember how they had one leg?
Yeah.
You remember that thing
or that is super accurate.
They had like a 2000 DPI sensor
long before anybody else did they,
I mean it was a really sensitive mountain.
Super, super play to the core. Yeah.
But it was also,
it would like,
it was kinda getting old
school because it was a ball.
It was still a right and you'll get,
wasn't laser y'all me shit up and
get all the dog hair and boogers.
And the problem was
they were trying to pretend that
that shape wasn't retarded. Yeah.
I remember they had that ridiculous,
totally unergonomic shape.
It was like a duck's foot. Yeah.
Yeah. It was flat. It was weird.
I used it though cause it was so
god damn accurate put up with it.
But I went back to, uh, do you
remember the, um, that a gaming mouse,
that logic tech gaming mouse. That was
the shit. Is that the white one? No, the,
the um, logic has, it was a gray one.
It was like a mouse that was invented
just for gaming and it had like this real
small, almost like deer hook size, like,
or cow hooves. So sort of this is the
optic was an optical or, no, it wasn't.
Not initially, but it was so good. It
wasn't as fast as far as like picking up,
but it felt so good in your hand that it
made up for the fact that it wasn't as
fast.
John Ramiro just went to
like a 20th anniversary.
I think it was at least 20 or 25 for
a dune did. He's doing well, man.
That was the guy.
He was one of the,
it was him and Carmeg and he was like the
guy who went on to do that crazy game.
Um,
what was the fucking game it took back?
What the Fuck Ramiro Ramiro to doom quake.
Right.
But after he left like a ton,
I was fucking fun man.
The game did not get enough respect.
He was one of the first people to be
progressively bullied by the forming
internet. Oh. Like the other one wanted
to hate him is too sexy. Beautiful.
Drove around in Ferrari's
and shit. [inaudible] pull
up video of Dika Tauna dude,
what does dyke aton I had like
some really fun multiplayer,
like the one on one and [inaudible]
was really fun. The rocket,
it was a little bit imbalanced.
Little rocket launcher.
I'll go to Dallas and I stayed in my
hotel downtown and I look at that building
and it just, I see it as a cautionary
tale for if I started a studio.
Like be careful, you know, like,
well you gotta explain to people that
don't know what the fuck we're doing.
Sorry. Sorry. So John Romero was one of
the key creatives behind doom and quake,
which are basically invented
the first person shooters genre.
John Carmack went to Oculus, by
the way. That's another side note.
I knew about that months in advance.
They had to keep my mouth shut anyway,
dropping information. He was like video
games, first fucking rock star, right?
He's the guy I wanted to be
growing up. Right. And uh,
then he started his own company with
idas money that was made from tomb raider
and he started in the heart of Dallas,
got the biggest,
most expensive penthouse suite
he could find insane real estate.
And he did the whole Gary Oldman get me
every one like hired way too many people,
wait too many fast and basically overshot
and his first game then it became so
much money though PR disaster for
him. Um, but deus ex came out of that,
which is a fantastic series a,
an Akron oxys just underrated
little role playing game.
I know so many people who work there and
we're there firsthand and a lot of them
still work at epic. What was the name of
the company again? Ion Storm Ion storm.
And they became infamous because
an ad agency had made an ad, uh,
that said John Ramirez in. But to make
you his bitch. What is this bro? Yeah,
I remember it down. What does this
bride dyke, Katana, this is, it will,
you'll be surprised how many old games
the graphics don't hold up man. Oh yeah,
but your memory of them, right?
Yeah. I can't hardly remember,
but I want him to see the multiplayer.
If you could find it. It was really good.
Multiplayer was fun. It was like
old school. Um, quake one. Yeah.
Remember how quake one was like really
fast and you would,
you know,
when you were running you were
really running fast then quick to,
they slowed it way down.
I'm just, you know,
there may be a market for a new one of
those soon, if you know what I'm saying.
He's winking at me folks and he's
clearly heterosexual. He, he can't say,
but he's working right now on something
just like that. I think. Sure.
You're going to tell me any more. It's
a fucking materials, dude. I don't care.
Okay.
That's why I'm getting it.
But it's how do you think you know people
that these kids who play call of duty
know what the proper like
there's dot Qatada PC shooter is,
I think a lot of kids don't
these at these events.
They're still playing counter strike and
team fortress two look how bad ass this
is. This is fucking, he had like
a pretty good but a four barrel,
like an 18 barrel shotgun called the shuts
cycler. Yeah, that was cool. You had,
you started out with like a thing,
you have your punch people and then you
had to run around and I enjoyed those
games too.
We had to like collect the items,
the time when the rocket launcher
would reappear. That's the,
and they'll look at the f like
just flowing through the level.
Right and anticipating the sound cues
and knowing where they're coming from and
the one on one battles and everything.
Yeah.
Well people who've never
played these things,
they really are never going to understand
how much like thinking is going on
simultaneously and movement
of your hands and fingers.
Like it's incredibly intoxicating.
It is.
It's not like people think of it
as like, Oh, you're playing games.
Like what are you doing? Pretending
some fucking shit's going on. We'll,
we'll go kill the werewolf. No, it's your,
you're online in real time with someone,
you know, that could be fucking anywhere.
And with the technology that we have
today and you're playing this incredibly
quick gain and get all your senses are
firing and everyone's on mountain dew to
that now. I bet they're
all on Adderall. Right?
I bet these kids are Adderall at the
fuck up or I scoured energy drinks times
three. Did they say that? Like a
amphetamines and Fed Amines? Uh,
we're like one of the best things that,
uh,
you could ever take if you were playing
a first person shooter. Really? Yeah.
Because you can get locked into like a
really intense battle for a long time and
you wouldn't lose concentration.
I'm like taking him Pheta means
to play fucking video games. Well,
so what would happen? Imagine
like with the, you know,
if some of these twitch first person
shooters become big in the east sports
scene is they'll have to start screening
for it. Just like blood doping probably.
Yeah. I would imagine you have
millions of dollars at stake, you know?
And if that guy has that extra
edge yeah. You know, it's,
it's the whole La Lance
Armstrong thing, right? Yeah.
I would think that there's probably some,
I mean maybe it makes shitty
judgements though. Yeah. You know,
maybe that's too much. Maybe your,
your two fit, but I know muscle memory,
it's strategy, right? It's all there.
But it's not just that there's also like,
it takes away nerves in a weird way, you
know? And part of competition has nerves,
part of comedy.
That's like a big thing in the,
in the pool world and a professional
pool guys used to take amphetamines,
he's take pills and they would be able
to play for 10 12 hours and they didn't
have nerves. Like their nerves would
go away because they were like,
one of the things that
crystal meth people do,
they make terrible fucking decisions
because whacked out of their mind,
they don't even know that they're there.
Like they're barely aware of what the
fuck is happening in front of them.
They have a completely
distorted perception of reality.
Well along with that allegedly
and apparently comes like
an ease and competition
because for things that
don't require cardiovascular,
like you would obviously had a heart
attack if you tried smoking meth and
playing basketball.
Apparently for some people smoking meth
or taking math and playing pool like
works really well. Let's let's, you know,
watching football and watching the kicker,
it's like, you know you have one job.
No pressure. Right? Don't fuck it
up. That's a terrifying job though.
You got a bunch of fucking gigantic
super athletes running at you,
dude for four forties I grew up like in
New England as he know and sports were
forced on my fucking throat by my
brothers and I hated them and I was like,
Hi Shane. I'm going around. I'm like video
games and a only like a few years ago,
it's, it's just really started
enjoying the NFL. You allowed yourself.
I fucking love it. It's chest with 280
pound dudes. I would definitely like it.
I just can't watch. It's too much.
I have any time. Yeah, fair enough.
It's like I spent too much time obsessing
about a million other things if I
wanted to get involved in
football too. Yeah. Like I,
I've tuned into those like Fox
shows when they started having these
conversations. Well Denver's got
to get off the backend. What,
what's going on with it and bowls.
Pittsburgh. Pittsburgh doesn't fix this.
I gotta get out of the,
for me it's a whole,
it's a whole new game to learn that I've
ignored my whole life and I'm willing
to admit that I don't know a lot
about it and it's just, you know,
I'm rooting for the saints because my
wife's from New Orleans and they just did
it.
Team has a lot of heart.
Drew Brees is a fucking stud and it's
sick excuse to drink beer on a Sunday and
it's just fucking fun to watch,
man. It seems like it's fun.
I mean it's kind of like a
gladiator type thing, you know,
you're watching like some sort
of an organized war. It's just,
they don't actually kill each other.
Just need steel balls to make it out
to another, a couple of UFC events.
That one that you and Charlotte, that
was fucking amazing. That was a good one.
That was a long time ago,
man.
That was a totally different
experience than the UFC today.
Somebody on Twitter was like,
oh, you're going to, you know,
show Joe Your Med knowledge of MMA.
I'm like, I don't know shit. I'm like,
I'm not going to try and fake it.
Like I went there, I'd appreciated it.
It was fucking fantastic.
And I felt like a savage cause
like at the beginning I'm like, oh,
this is so violent. By the end I'm
like, fucking kill him. Get on.
How dare you cliffy being someone's
playing too many video games. Yeah.
It shouldn't say kill him. That seems
rude. The, um, the, the level of athlete,
those very, very high. Now back then,
I mean we were talking about what is it
like 2005 or four or something like that.
It was in Charlotte. It was a long
time ago. I forget the exact year,
but the level of athlete has gone up
considerably since then. It's, it's right.
Look at the old school videos of football
players and how big they were and how
fast they move versus these guys now,
how much changes there have been though
in the last decade? I don't know.
Honestly it's a streaming.
Is his strength training gotten better?
I mean did the MMA is,
it was,
it's still a relatively new sport
compared to the other ones and you're just
starting to also,
you're just starting to get like the real
top end athletes to come over to MMA.
Whereas before you were getting guys,
you know,
who may be like wrestled in college but
they didn't have a professional outlet
and in the UFC came along and some of
them reluctantly went into the UFC.
Now you're getting these guys that
grew up wanting to be a UFC fighter.
That's cool. And they saw it from the
beginning and never forget to what,
why I like hearing the crowd,
like get all crazy and cause somebody
was coming through and realizing it was
Dana White and like how they just,
they just worshiped him and how fucking
cool that was and how he turned that
thing around and it's cool.
Yeah.
Well there's a lot of factors involved,
but without Dana it wouldn't have
happened. And he's, he's a nut.
He's obsessed with it and it loves it.
I talked,
we talked about fights last night
for about two and a half hours. Wow.
I called him last time we talked about
the Mark Hunt fight and all this crazy
shit that's going on right now.
And next weekend
I,
my buddies who were bar
owners will deliberately not
have the UFC fight on why?
Because they,
some of them believe that it attracts the
type of guy who like wants to get in a
fight that night. So two
to three hours, you know,
he's going to show up having some drinks
and he's going to happen to a lot more
than you think. I know a lot of bars
in Ohio that does the same thing.
They stopped having the fights.
What bars do you know in Ohio?
My friend owns a bar on that,
that it's like a pool bar.
I think they used to play there,
but then they always had
fights there so he's like,
wow. Yeah. Well man, you add alcohol,
alcohol and a bunch of people watching
people kick people's asses and getting
their ass kicking.
Boners yeah,
dude. Even in Raleigh at 2:00 AM at
some outside some of the bars, man.
And you see and get to fucking get you.
Imagine if there was a club,
uh,
men,
women club were men and women went there
where they just showed porn all over
the place.
They showed like big widescreen
videos of people having sex.
Did you imagine how, I mean, that would
like turn rapey really fucking quick.
Like very much like how the UFC,
like if you have the UFC and a bar,
people want to beat ass.
If you had I think first of all peoples,
it would be really interesting like
as a study if he gets some scientist
involved and seeing what me,
you couldn't really manipulate people
like that unless they volunteered.
But how many more people who watch the
porn wound up hooking up that night
versus how many people who didn't watch
porn and went to a regular bar? Yeah,
I dunno actually that'd be fascinating,
but I mean what kind of
porn are we talking about?
Hardcore like fucking gagging,
Mascara, spit everything.
There's a Martinez
that in Los Angeles,
I think me and Duncan went there once and
in the back that just showed a woman's
gaping asshole in this day
and it was just on a
projection on the wall.
And you're just sitting out there
looking at this girl getting like,
like wasn't like silver lake
or something like that. Yeah,
of course there's a bar called like a
cozy car or something in San Francisco
where like he just does he car. That's
my nickname for him. Uh, but the cozy,
cause they have like all
the old playboy like, uh,
issues and pictorials like laminated and
the tables and everything that's kind
of mesmerized.
Well that's Kinda interesting.
The old ones especially because it's
like you're watching a piece of history
isn't even porn anymore when you know
that that lady is like 80 now you are not
beating off to that. I don't care how
hot she looked back then. You know,
there's very few people that beat off to
pictures of naked and Marilyn Monroe is
pretty issue was it says,
hmm, that's ancient.
I had a friend of mine who just was in
Delhi in India and she's speaking of like
Raby and she just like, you
know, she, she wore the full,
very little makeup just full on, like
showing no skin and everything. Shit.
She said, how many times
did she get her ass grabbed?
Didn't leave.
Like one of them was like an official,
like a guard at the Taj Mahal and uh, that
was, um, Kimra Verde. But it's just a,
my other friend who happens
to be Indian was taught,
we were talking about the Indian
rave culture and she says it's same.
It's fucking rough.
How did it happen?
How did it India become a place where
all these gang rapes keep occurring?
I mean,
is it being over sensationalized in the
media or is it really that fucking thing?
What I gather it's, it's pretty, yeah,
she felt very uncomfortable to share her.
Her Facebook posts is like, you know,
India, you were amazing to visit, but the,
you know, some of the vibe I got was
really a little unsettling. Wow. She just,
she did like this world tour guys.
Damn, that's weird. What is that?
And it's,
it's,
it's very weird when you see it and it
also coincides with a population of a
billion people because I always assume,
and this is just based on what I've
seen in regards to money and how people
treat each other,
and when you have too many people,
when you have like too many
people, 20 million people,
whatever, a billion people,
you lose the value. It's like, it's
like there's no value in people.
There's too many of them. They
become invalue. They become, uh,
they become a problem to
be around. Epic had a, Ah,
there's weird cultural things to epic.
Had a partnered with 10 set before I left.
As I said, I sold a bunch of stock and
everything and we got this like, you know,
what would you like to know if you're
gonna release a game in China and here are
things that are culturally allowed and
things that are kind of you should avoid.
And one of the things that was a big no,
no,
you couldn't have in your game was
any exposed bone like ain't no skulls.
If you had a Somby, like he couldn't
see any of the bone in it. It's just,
it was considered really like
you can't do it for some reason.
And the other thing was that if
there is a certain type of fear,
I remember what it's called,
where you're afraid of,
of densely packed holes like coral,
like in to avoid those kinds of patterns
in your game because a bunch of people
get freaked out by that. Apparently
densely packed holes like coral, freakout,
Chinese people.
That was what the pad,
the whole pamphlet said there's a name
for it, something of phobia. Right.
It's a coral, a phobia. It's not cause
it's not just coral, it's like you know,
any sort of surface that it's very porous,
like that spongy type thing. Right.
And that's a cultural
thing. Yeah, it's cultural.
I don't know of it
existing in other places,
but I think apparently when they have a
billion people and you have, you know,
5% of the people affected with it.
While you may want to, you know,
keep that in mind.
It is weird when you see how far people
go off the track when it comes to like
what their culture accepts
and expects of each other.
Like how bout Muslims where you're not
even allowed to draw Mohamad if you draw
him. Yeah. You know, like
little kids, Christian kids,
they can draw a picture of God with a
beard and the clouds do it as a part of
their,
you know,
first grade there's a Dutch cartoon is
to actually did it and like drew him with
like a bomb turban at one point and he
had like Fatois just issued for him at
the park. Yeah, yeah. Cause you're
talking about them earlier. Let's go.
They got in trouble for it.
Book of Mormon committed to,
it's amazing that you could get that
far though, that a culture can get me,
you can call it a religion if you want,
but it's basically a pattern and behavior,
a pattern of behavior that a bunch
of people are willing to follow.
The get so far that if you write down or
draw your guy that you believe in just
drawn up.
I'm an atheist,
but I have friends who are very
religious and it's like whatever gets you
through the fucking day, if you, you know,
the thing is if you're
not hurting anybody else,
whatever it fucking works for you. You're
like a Beatles Song, man. You know,
you wanna, you wanna lead
people fucking tell him, uh,
you know what happens when you die.
Yeah,
that would definitely help
you ever see the movie.
Tell them that you found some magic shit.
Yeah.
You found some magic shit
that I'm telling you.
I'm going to sending me
information. I, Hey, I'm just a
conduit. I'm not, you're God.
Yeah, but you're God's talking through
me. I want you to suck my Dick.
I don't know why people,
people want something.
They want to be a part of something.
It's that tribal nature.
Fuck those guys over there. Why?
Because we're us in there. Them.
There's definitely that.
Right.
And did you even see it with
a nerd culture where it's
like, you know, are you a,
are you nerdy enough? Are you a real
quick, you're really using a Mac. Yeah.
And it's Mac or PC.
Same reason I'll tell my friends
like what kind of hardware I have.
Like in anything cause it's like, oh, you
should get a so and so. It's too much.
Or you're using the empty God. Yeah Dude.
God to this. So yesterday like you know,
getting like a TV for the gaming
room. Oh, that one's too laggy.
You shoot this guy and there's
always a better one coming out.
They should wait for it. Just not
ever have anything fucking Neri cons.
You have the both x-box nps for the new
one. You can just start shit right now.
So we're trying to get no,
I'm just saying it did.
Do you prefer one over the other one?
I'm all about Nintendo right now. Yeah,
the new Mario is fucking fantastic.
That new Zelda is great.
I tried the Xbox with your TV though.
Oh you don't have cable? Yeah, no,
we just use like Netflix and Hulu and
all that shit and we use Chromecast all
studies in the future,
isn't it dude?
I just seems like it right at time one
are made their own bed man. And you know,
more and more people are
cutting that fucking cable.
Netflix works so well. Yeah,
it's so well, I want everything
streaming on demand right now.
Hulu plus works so well. All of
them work so well. I love, uh,
I love iTunes. I don't, I watched
the walking dead recently on TV.
Oh my God. I wanted to fucking kill some
parsley. It was every fucking 10 minutes.
It was a commercial. I was like,
this is such a bad way to watch a,
a gripping show.
All of the sudden it's dancing
potato chips and it's like,
it's like from the fifties and
sixties right. It's like a stay over.
Well you know what it is,
man.
It's like television in the current
form where you have to watch it.
When it plays, you have to watch it
live. It's like silent movies, man.
It just doesn't work anymore.
Yeah, it's stupid. Yeah. Well,
so do you driving around La proper?
Like the amount of signs I've seen
for Netflix and Hulu original series,
like it's totally taking
over and they can take,
they can take more risks in those areas.
And same thing with the youtube
explosion, right? Like you know,
it's so many places are just getting
like little warehouses out and like
whatever,
you know,
city at to out here and
they're just making gold like
Freddy Wong's videos. Man.
Well,
there's so many pizza huts.
They're doing these weird videos too
where they just stand in front of a camera
and they start talking about something
and then they have all these quick edits.
It's like, you know, I grew up in this
click edit and then into the well,
and when I was a kid we like,
there's almost like no room for air and,
and they,
they,
they've edited like every breath or
pause in between every word and they have
this weird fast editing style. It's
like the draw my life stuff also. Right.
But it's really prevalent.
Like what,
how did that fast editing weird style
of Youtube video becomes so mimic? Well,
let me ask you a question.
Like
for me, when I watch a youtube video,
if like it doesn't get interesting.
And then the third was the first 30
seconds I'm out. I'm like, I'm done.
Just like Geeky let, let's
get going. Yeah. I'm onto the
next video. Yeah, I guess,
do you know what I'd like to believe the
number one youtube subscribe person is
this kid. He's like, like finish or
something as names like Pubi die.
And he just streams videos of him playing
games and talking about them all the
time. He just gets insane views.
That's weird on the dean. You suck.
You can't predict it knows you're
good bone structure. Rebecca,
who's got finally released
a sequel to Friday,
did she really? Cause I saw that
online. Was that bullshit at Saturday?
She really did make a song
called Saturday. Come on
man. And she put it online.
Yup. Okay. Million views and later I
didn't know that. Terrible. How bad is it?
Well she's kind of acting like she's a
little hung over and she partied too hard.
She's trying to get street credit.
Yeah. Talking about getting,
I'm thinking she needs the next one
should be Sunday fun day where she's like
drinking bloody Mary's getting all
fucked up or their friends too and coke
trying to stay up the side.
Leading the cycle continues
blood under sox doesn't where it came
from. I did not know about this. Oh
hell yeah.
You're not in bed. Oh my
God. Oh my God. This is real.
So that sin too crazy.
Oh, she's got like a Miley parody girl
in here at some point, twerking and shit.
You know what? Here's the deal though.
This could have worked if it wasn't her.
Yeah. If they had no one in this video
was singing and they didn't show anybody
singing.
There's enough people out there that
are almost retarded that they would buy
that.
It's the postmodern,
Rebecca Black.
It's all like me and my
friends from the Palisades.
We're going to sit around and pretend
that this is what we do. Well,
we push each other on skateboards. We do
when we're high on Ahcccs. Yeah, right.
Like a cousin of mine, but my mom's
clothes were all in the water.
It looks like we're having fun,
but actually Billy just drown and we're
trying to find him or four who fell off
the dock and we can't tell his mom because
we have his car and he's fucking key
doesn't work because it's
underwater. Dude, fucking
Internet, man. This is weird.
He's like, dude, dude, dude, like couldn't
find his pants. I mean, it's crazy.
They're nutty.
You know,
she got up at two o'clock she told you
it's two o'clock in the afternoon. Right.
Going to bed at like five which didn't
give a fuck. She went to bed at noon.
She went to bed at noon and got up at
two ready to fuck again. She's crazy.
She's doing blow.
She's fucking balloons full of
helium up around music factory
dude. When we were in a
that's like the, yeah,
they're the ones who
do all those meetings.
Those vanity music videos for like
the Bridge Orange County girls.
What are those?
It's like the Friday at all.
The company that it's called art music
factory. They'll come to you though.
So they, they, they basically
your Bat Mitzvah, you get
a music video or whatever.
Right? Oh my goodness. Don't
even play that Jamie. You fucked.
Scare the shit out of me right now.
I've had too much already.
I'm starting to shake.
It's like,
like not drinking coffee and drinking
cops all at once. I can't handle it.
It's too much girl band. Yeah,
there you go. Somebody tried to,
somebody tried to tell me like I walked
into a bookstore and the co why is,
why are they playing one direction? I go,
Eh, wrong question. The real question is,
who the fuck do you know that this
is one direction? Yeah, totally.
God Damn grown adult. It's a
cycle dude. Every 10 years,
a couple years ago I'm like, oh boy.
Bands about set to come back and Yep.
Just that trains on time. I, yeah,
I just felt that and I saw it in Vegas
for the first time in the elevator. I go,
what is this? I had to ask my friends,
what is this? Oh that's the new one.
It's a new boy van Mike.
How come I didn't see them coming here?
And they're huge already.
Like instantly.
It's such a weird
psychology for young girls.
They like those very like androgynous
dudes who were very nonthreatening of
course, cause they're dabbling in
the world of sexuality. You know,
if you had a bunch of fucking Andre
Arlovski lemonade fire open chess playing
guitar, sticking their tongue out with
giant rolled sock cock in their pants,
like in leather, you know, tight pants,
big giant thighs, custom made thighs,
you know,
it has to bother giant legs and is big
snake like cock pressed up against this
upper hip. You know, that's
too much for a little girl.
It was just starting to learn our ways.
Just starting to figure out what our
friend means the end of every month and
Japanese boy bands or even worse. I don't
know if you've ever seen those. Oh yeah,
I have.
And K pop.
There's a lot of weird and druggies shit
going on with Japanese people. They,
they're into a lot of
weird androgynous shit.
There was a guy who was an Androgynous,
a kickboxer. He's actually very good.
He was a,
he was in the Mangia I guess that is some,
some character or Manga. Manga.
Yeah, that's how you say it. Yeah.
Character Jessop but he was
a bad ass. Kickboxer let me
find out. Let me say like,
give me shit. I'll kick your
ass. Yeah. No, he was legit.
And he was fighting in a k
one max. Dude, I saw a video.
Did you know Seattle has this a law where
if two people agree to fight there you,
they can just fight in the street and
then somebody falls and they have to stop.
Say that again. What? So
Phoenix Jones is that real life
superhero? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's called willful combat
or something like that.
You combat and there's a viral
video of him in the suit. Dude.
He just would not leave him alone. Who's
hammered in Phoenix? Just dropped him.
Yeah.
That's guys are fucking hilarious.
Is that guy dresses up like a
superhero and he's an MMA fighter.
He's a really bad ass fighter. Yeah. Yeah.
This is a woo shinny shin.
This is the androgynous Japanese boy band.
There's a whole thing. It's Korean. Are
They Korean? I think this one is, yeah.
Right. The same thing I like with they
move. I'm going to tell you right now,
I'm not ashamed to admit it.
Yeah.
Pretty good.
Production values.
Yeah.
That's K-pop.
Gotcha. Hero. Uh, Nakashima.
That's a the dude's name pro.
Pull up a video. Him, Brian, you, y.
U.
I. C. H. I. R. O. Nagashima k.
One kickboxing is videos
of him looking like a girl.
He comes out with a dress on a skirt and
a crazy wig on and he's dancing fucks
people up. It's even cooler that
he goes. Yeah, he's bad ass man.
I've seen the dude fight a bunch of times
and apparently when he first started
he actually wasn't that good and got,
you know,
people were like teasing
him because of his, uh,
his outfit and all those shitty then
two and then he got really good dude.
That's fucked up.
You play counterstrike with people who
are better than you and you get better.
Cliffy beats dropping knowledge,
I think had to be the best you you can be.
That's the PSA. The more you know, I
think I went to his last a UFC fight.
He hasn't fought since then. He was
like, oh, this is against Kraus.
He's probably gonna get fucked up below.
Krause's a bad dude.
Push it ahead though. Yeah, but look
at this dance is like this. This is,
he has this whole like choreographed
thing that he comes out to.
Holy Shit, he's the best he's
fighting now but cross though.
Who's a multiple time
champion from Holland?
I don't know who won the fight but I
would imagine cross it have an advantage.
This is must be in Japan.
They use the k one max was like a big
kickboxing organization to deal with the
fact that there was a lot of like really
talented guys that were at a lighter
weight cause Japa Japan put really high
level boxing worldwide on the map with k
one and then the k one
was all heavyweight guys.
So they went from that to a k one max,
which is all guys.
I think the weight limit was like, I
think it was 160 pounds. I'm not sure,
but like go, go ahead. So you
could see him fighting this
dude. He was bad ass man.
Even though he, oh he got k
the fuck out. I said, man,
he's fighting Albert Cross. He's going
to get fucked up. And I was correct.
Look at this. Boom, Bang. There's
your wig, here's your concussion.
There's your skirt pull ahead,
pulled way before that so you
could see like some of the fight.
He's actually a good fighter.
Just the guy he's fighting is like super,
super high level. You really should
never be in against this guy doing.
He's like some blow out but he's,
yeah, he's like a step below.
But what they would do in Japan,
they didn't give a fuck man.
That's the first round two, that's 50
minutes and 50 seconds in the first round.
Put it up to the beginning when Japan
would have a lot of freak shows.
That was one of the things that they had
a real problem with with pride and uh,
some of the matches they would do in k
one they would put too many people that
didn't have any chance at all together
and they would have guys just get
slaughtered. Just guys fight guys that
they had no business fighting these dudes.
And this is one of those instances.
I is a beast.
Crouse has been around
a long fucking time too.
I think he's probably
got a hundred fights.
He's fought like the best of the past
to like high level competition and like
this of like Holland
kickboxer and he kind
of embodies that style.
I think John Cusack's character and say
anything had it right when he said it's
the sport of the future. John
Cusack was ahead of his time, Bro.
John Cusak is great on Twitter
by the way. Say that. Yeah,
I've got John Cusak speaks his mind.
He's a very intelligent and Rob Delaney
of uh, Nona I think so maybe online,
maybe on Twitter. My favorite thing
was, uh, he tweeted a shrinking,
uh, drinking come makes
pineapple juice tastes delicious.
And then I retweeted that and I got close
to be right. I've got victory. It's the,
he's flipped the joke though, cause it's
supposed to say drink. I get it. I get it.
Which was fucking everything. Everything
he tweets. It's just amazing. Uh,
it's fucking one of the
best Twitter's out there.
Why are you saying that Brian it
disagreeing. Let my stomach hurts. Don't,
don't disagree Bryan, the shits rude
dude. I fucking love him on Twitter. Okay.
You guys are going to fight.
I'm going to leave the room because I
don't like to be here for this shit.
Whatever you do, do not put your name
and the word Kimmel and the same thing.
All right. Do you won't
find it anywhere? No,
don't put his name in the word Kimmel.
You're holding your tongue,
Brian. You tell me this
after the podcast then. Huh?
Wait like there's something you're
withholding. Nothing. Nothing.
I don't follow them on Twitter.
I don't follow him on Twitter,
but I saw him on camel once and
it was one of those performances.
I guess he probably wasn't happy
with it either, but it was so like,
who is this guy?
How did he get on Campbell?
And then I looked him up and was like,
Holy Shit.
He's huge on Twitter and everything and
they had never seen his life. Comedy,
twitters, you know, he got in early too.
And I think Twitter is one of those things
where you literally can go viral and
just be a regular person who says
something funny and one person sees it and
they sent it to other people in.
The next thing you know you've
got a million followers. Poppins,
a lot also is when Twitter
first came out they,
I guess they added to the people
you should follow lists. Yeah.
And there's so many people.
Like I met a comic the other day that
has like almost a million. I'm like,
I've never heard of this guy.
And he told me it was because that
Twitter put him on some list once and then
every time you signed up for Twitter
you automatically just added him.
So that's a good list to get on.
Yeah. But I mean the thing is is you,
you guys know as well as I do like
the risk of having a lot of followers.
It's not necessarily mean there's a
lot of engaged followers. Like I'll,
I'll just click on,
some people have like 2 million followers
and I'll tweet something relatively
funny and like it'd be
like three retweets. Right?
And then you get like somebody
who has like, you know,
100,000 and then they tweet something
really funny and next thing you know,
5,000 retweets. It's not a precise
science, but it's fun. Yeah.
There's a lot of people buy and Twitter
followers and they don't really even get
Twitter followers. They get like robots.
Yeah. It just makes your number look good.
Yeah. Bullshit. There's a website,
you can look up people's Twitter names
and see how many are real fake Bot.
Oh really?
They know how many got in trouble
because he was buying a whole bunch of
followers and they during the election.
Yeah. But it's not bad. Is it bad to do?
Like if someone does that,
it makes them look less legit.
That's what it makes it look correct.
But yeah, because then, you know,
you have a comedy club or somebody
goes, wow, this guy has 2 million hits.
That's a lot of people that
we can get into this comedy.
Take those numbers very seriously.
It's what if you were funny guy,
say if you're funny guy and uh,
people don't really know yet,
but you're pretty good.
And you find out that you could do that
and then all of a sudden you can get
work. I could see people justifying
that would only work so much.
You're funny already.
I mean it's like,
let's take a guy like a that people don't
know, like, okay. Like perfect example,
a Joey Diaz five years ago, five years
ago, nobody knew who Joey Diaz was.
If you could get Joey d as 250,000
Twitter followers and then like let a club
know like, Hey, this guy, 200,000
Twitter followers, people love him. Okay.
That seems like a lot. Okay, well
let's try them and then boom. Yeah,
but none of this, that's what we're saying
is this, Twitter flowers aren't real.
So they wouldn't come to this
show. Uh, yeah. But they would get,
he would get hired, he
would get, it wouldn't work.
It would only work a couple of times until
the clubs go, wait a second, you know,
bringing in in the ass.
Yeah.
Maybe he had an offer to tweet about
some sort of new Doritos for like money.
Like how much I was like, how much
free grand a tweet. Oh three granted,
tweet for real. I could buy some
dirty, no, wait a minute. Hold on.
They pay you to tweet about Doritos.
The offer. I couldn't do it.
I was employed at epic at the
time. Oh, that's interesting.
How many people are getting paid to tweet
and what is the most I need to start
doing it. I want to make
sure I'm not going to do it,
but I'm going to make sure
that everybody knows right now.
I've never been paid to tweet ever.
I've been accused of it before,
but when I tweet about something, if I
like it, it's just because it's cool.
That's, that's, that's the key ran and
it's like you can start taking that money,
but then you're Craig starts
going down. You can't, I tell him,
I don't think you can't. I can't. I was
saying, unless it was something we could,
but if you did then nobody would
believe anything. If you're like,
I like this thing. They were like, do you
like it? Are you being paid for? Okay,
well let's, let's have a, but
how about a, for instance,
what if you're a known enthusiasts of
certain things like you like Nice cars?
What if Ferrari says, hey, we want to
pay you to tweet about the four, five,
eight Italia. All right,
it's fucking awesome car.
You want me to just let people know that
I think it's awesome. It's indisputable.
It's awesome. I would do that. But
you know, if someone stainless,
so it's four five beats a little
girly looking actually, how dare you?
How dare you? Are you an [inaudible] guy?
Put that next to the event authority.
That's a B. That's a bitch car. That's
for guys. You need way too much tension.
It's not good for you to an event to door.
That's like silly. What are you Batman?
What are you doing with that?
Stupid. If it's blacked out to,
you should see it in Raleigh. Dude,
it's a funny, you have one of those,
an event to door.
How dare you?
How dare you drive the Aventador
and she drives the Giardo Llp.
Five 60 to Bojangles.
See the Giardo is much more realistic
vehicle to be driving around event doors.
That's a fucking Batmobile.
It looks like.
If you would ask an eight year old what
his dream car would be, how fast is it?
It's pretty fucking fast. It's was
six to 16 2.8 is it scary to drive?
It's not as scary as the
older Lamborghini's. They've
refined it a lot. Traction,
control and all that. Yeah. Yeah,
they are. Conditioning works. Right?
So if Aventador came to you and
said, hey, we want to pay you,
you would do it now they should pay me
retroactively because I tweeted out of
the damn thing all the time.
They should pay you.
Listen to how arrogant coffee be is.
He wants money from Lamborghini.
This motherfucker, he believe this shit.
He thinks Lamborghini owes him money.
Unbelievable. No. [inaudible]
it's a niche business.
You should be happy to
support them because if it
wasn't for Lamborghini making
Lamborghinis,
nobody would be making Lamborghinis and
you'd be left out in the car with no
Batmobile. Fair enough. What would
you get if you didn't have that?
Would you go Ferrari or do you think
it's too girly? Mclaren. Mclaren, yeah.
Mclaren is don't sound good.
Yeah, that's a problem. These are,
there's something missing.
You know that new car.
I've got up thing up Mclaren's new car.
I've gotten this unbelievably classic
poner too lately. Like the Shelby Cobra.
Yes.
And then I,
there was one at a car show
and I've learned at that
the real ones go for like a
million. Oh yeah. Like I had no idea.
Yeah, but you can get a replicant.
It's just fun to drive. Exactly.
You know, probably better.
You can get a bit better brakes and shit.
Everything as well.
Those guys would get those old muscle
cars and they have them stocked.
Like I get it. You're driving like a
little time machine. I like, you know,
you like the fact that it has like shitty
steering and shitty breaks. Safety man.
Safety is fine. Yeah. It's like a rhino
on rollerskates and those fucking,
I'm fucking like a,
I lost my fucking nephew a couple
of years ago in a car accident.
I'm just like fucking safety.
Safety, safety man. Well,
people have asked me about this recently,
I think I've talked about on the podcast,
but I got rid of this Barracuda that I
had because I was driving on the highway
and I got home, I pulled into my
driveway and I was, I was making a turn.
All the sudden the suspension
came detached from the
frame and the front wheel
went sideways and stuck up into the fender
like at a nowhere. I was just turning,
I mean I was in my driveway,
there wasn't,
there was nothing crazy I was doing and
I was on the highway just minutes before
that going like 70 miles an hour.
And if that flew off,
I easily could be dead right now.
And so I got it all fixed.
Look at that fucking thing
that it's sexy as shit,
right with yellow and black like
that fucking Bumblebee from hell.
That's awesome.
So I got it fixed perfectly.
I brought it to a place
that it was too low.
It was bottoming out and the bottom
of the bolt was hitting pavement on a
regular basis. We broke off
actually. So I had to have the,
I have the whole thing reconstructed,
done correctly,
and then got rid of the fucking,
the Lambo is,
have the button to raise the
front up by like four inches.
There's a company that's doing, um, um,
a VX challenger and it's
fucking bad ass man.
They've figured out a way.
Is that an Vieques XV XV challenger?
Hold on.
They take these old cars like old muscle
cars like barracudas. Yeah, that's it.
Pull this thing up. Xv Challenger,
they take these old muscle cars,
but they put a modern suspension in it.
It's completely designed
just for this car.
So they figured out how to take these old,
like really heavy cars and just completely
redesigned the suspension to her.
Drives like a corvette, but it looks like
an old muscle car. Oh look how wicked.
That's awesome dude. Have you seen the
other then? He's sting rays gorgeous.
Oh yeah. It's incredible. Like for
just American muscle mass sport,
the uh, the guy who does the
smoking, tire.com, the, uh,
he does a bunch of videos for
drive as well. And drive tuned. He,
he sent me a tweet about it
immediately. He's like, he, you got to
find out how you can get in one of these
things is the most incredible car that
corvette has ever built. It's
insane. It's just gorgeous.
Like nailed it everywhere. They nailed
the interior. They nailed the exterior,
they nailed the specs.
They nailed the performance.
They nailed the build quality
like people are driving and going,
this is like a fucking masterpiece.
This is those.
Those Audi sedans lately
are just gorgeous too. Well,
GM has been knocking it out of the
fucking park lately because they also have
the new Camaro and then the Camaro
z 28 which they just released,
which goes around the Nurburgring as
fast as a Porsche nine 11 turbo for like
less than half the price. It's the
scariest, fastest car I've ever been.
It was a benign 11 turbo,
one of my older coworkers.
That thing was just fucking terrifying.
Yeah.
I had one of those at one point in time.
I had a m nine nine six nine 11 turbo,
which was the first water cooled
one broke down like crazy.
Fun fact is a,
they used my event doors sound for some
of the reference for the new Forza game.
Well that was one thing that Lamborghini
got right is the sound Lamborghini and
for Ron shoot out the back of it. When
I, when I get past 80,000 rpm. Yeah,
there's a video where you uh,
guys cooking a sausage using the back
of an invented door cause so many flames
were shooting out of it.
My wife's like, honey,
you may not want to read that at the gas
station. That's bad ass. I would done it.
And what is the, um, the
actual horsepower? God,
it's like six something,
six 98 or something like that.
Apparently there's a game where, and
I haven't done it yet, where you,
you put a hundred dollar
bill on the passenger,
like dash and tell them if you can
grab that in the next four seconds,
he can keep it because the, the
forest is so strong. Really? Wow.
Well it's a honestly, man,
it's way too much. It's orange.
It's just driving an orange
car. You silly bitch. I do.
How dare you to actually be
matte black. Maybe. Dude,
I've caused the accidents
but people gawking I bet
that's it right there. Right?
Here we go.
He's going to cook the sausage.
Oh, that's a cool dad.
It's all digital. Yeah,
there we go. Wow. That's insane.
Okay.
I changed my mind. That's probably the
dopest thing I've ever seen. I'm a child.
If you show me flames coming out of
the car, you when dude the doors,
like it's like you roll up somewhere and
it's just like opening that thing and
get, now it's just like the, you
know, kill bill music plays down.
Do you like driving it though?
Is it a fun car to drive?
It's not as fun as the guy.
A LP five 60 cause you got a
nice like 75 degree Raleigh Day.
Put the top down in that thing and it was
just golden. And the thing is, you know,
you can I speed just in short bursts
very carefully. You know, like,
because knock on wood, never had a
ticket to any of my sports cars ever.
Well they're fun.
That's what people don't realize.
Like they're fun to just drive around
and necessarily even have to drive fast.
Just take it a corner of 35 miles an hour
in a car like that. It was really fun.
The best thing to do in a
car like, oh, what is that
Brian? It's one of those cars.
Yeah, but why is it all
fucking get weirded out now?
It's just [inaudible]. Oh,
they tried it out. It looks, she's like,
she's fucking terrible. It's, Oh my God.
It was a Chris Brown or white or men.
I think it looks pretty dope.
That out at me.
That looks like a Batmobile car.
If that was all the sudden matte
black, it's Phoenix Dillon's car. Yeah.
If I was a girl, I'd fuck you if
you had that car. All the, uh,
the charcoal matte gray ones.
Yeah, they're fucking gorgeous.
The charcoal mask gray is a dope.
That makes a lot of shapes look pretty
bad in America. You were raised,
you know like women are raised with the
sooner you're going to be a princess and
get married some day
program with that as a guy,
you know the Italian sports cars, you
know the, the posters on the wall, right?
Like it was always the, the Lambo and
the Ferrari and the Giardo getting,
when I first got that, it was wonderful
and I was fucking so appreciative.
But when I got the event door,
like it's the first night I just kind
of sat in there like when I, you know,
at the end of the night I just
went down and just sat in it.
My wife sitting there looking at me and
she's like, are you gonna fucking cry?
And I'm like, we ready to
cry. I was a little bit,
if a glimpse into the sensitive
part of cliffy Alma giant pussy,
you were about to cry cause
you achieve dreams. Yeah.
Did you cry in her arms and
just say babies maybe holding
be even worth anything?
I tell you what, dude, in
the grand scheme of things,
my Australian shepherd costs how much
lesson has given me so much more joy.
So then your car? Yeah. Okay.
Not then your wife. Okay.
We were in the middle of that. Yeah. I
was like, how dare you sir. How dare you.
Oh God, no. That's a fucking
expensive Goddamn Carson.
That's like a half $1 million and that's
supposed to be just driving around and
a half a million dollar house.
It only has two seats.
It goes zero to 60 in three seconds. See
though, you should see the, the trunk.
Oh, is he actually find the boot? It's
hilarious. Can you put your Dick in there?
It was a big trunks. I put my bike
in it. Whoa. Well, no, I've easy.
Clearly a big bike.
Do you have a big car like that?
You obviously have to have
a small cock, so no, that's,
that's the people who don't have
that car wanted even want to think.
They want to think that there's gotta
be some way that not having that car is
better than having that car.
I knew a dude in Raleigh,
he had this gorgeous Red Maserati and a,
and he would always take it out
to the clubs and real and a EA.
One time dude had a Sunday
fun day and cops tail them.
He wrapped it around tree
fighting died and his wife,
his fiance was pregnant at the time. Oh
Jesus guys. Fucking, that's my thing.
That kind of, those, that kind of
thing, man. It's my silver reminder.
Like first off, don't fucking take the
car out to the club and second off, uh,
just be careful man. Yeah.
Don't drive like an asshole.
You can enjoy your car and not drive like
an asshole thing to do those cars do.
Did you go underneath an
overpass is to downshift. Yeah.
It's like a make fucking fighter.
Roll the window down and listen to the
noise and any car with a nice engine.
Yeah. That's my fear about the future,
man. I just, you got connected,
you have touch screens, you
have electronic cars, the
Teslas. Gorgeous. Right.
But it's laying noise. You want that
feedback, that room, you know? Yeah. Well,
that's the thing about the Mclaren,
like we were looking at the car.
It's absolutely beautiful but the sound
it makes is very uninspiring cause it's
turbocharged. It's like
turbo charged cars. They just
don't have that same sound.
You Watch after Paul
Walker died, the uh, the,
the top gear of the Porsche Carrera,
I
saw the top gear a long time ago where
I took the stig all morning to get around
the fucking track once and that was a
gorgeous car to well it's
a very scary car. Yes.
It's not a car that's easy to handle that,
that mid engine design.
Extremely high horsepower,
very low weight.
There's a lot of room for
the tires to break loose.
Like one of the things that like about
a Porsche or a BMW is one of the things
that are really good about is they're
really good about engineering their cars
so that the,
the car doesn't overwhelm the suspension.
Like even when these incredible cars they
have today, like the new nine 11 turbo,
the turbo ass go zero to 60 in 2.7
seconds. Yeah, it's insane. Yeah.
Dual clutch. That's all
they make. They don't,
they don't make you a manual
and the turbo anymore.
And they're saying zero to 60 time
honestly instantaneously. But they,
they don't let you even buy a
manual anymore. Yeah. And the,
the suspension is fucking staggering.
The back wheel steer now they
have steering back wheels
and the Porsche nine 11
turbo in on the gt three and the braking
power and you get to a super car like
that. So it's, for me,
it's like as a guy who knows nothing about
technology other than what I've read,
like I have zero skill or knowledge
or education in technology.
So when,
when I see stuff like this,
to me it's just like a totally new world,
a world of,
of fascination and accomplishment.
And what we're looking at it right now is,
is the roadster for the Aventador.
And here's again,
the problem is taking these
into the fucking panels off and,
and you've got to put them somewhere.
The actually the,
they actually will fit in the boot of
the car. Uh, but this guy's not doing it.
This guy looks like he's about to die too.
And that's what you look like when
you can afford an event a door,
either cliffy B or some dude who's
been working some slave job for Lehman
brothers your whole life and you're ready
to die and that's when you finally say
to your wife, fuck you bitch, I'm
buying this fucking car and she's has
think about guys who have to have
a man cave. I'm like, really?
You get one room in the
house? Wow. It's okay.
I can ask for sometimes cliffy be not
everybody can be like you. I'm cries.
A lot of people that they, they have to
settle for what they got or maybe they,
they're fucking over their head.
That's also possible.
Like a guy who's like a not very good
looking guy has a really good look and
girlfriend, who knows? She's
really good looking. So this
poor bastard, he can't go.
I'll cliffy be style and drive
around in the event a door.
He's got to play things real close to
the chest to try to keep this fucking,
it's like he wants to make sure
that she hasn't run fair enough.
What she's gotta do and
didn't call up the uh,
the roadster Aventador roadster
and pay him like a pale baby blue.
That's the wonderful car man.
Yeah. Aventador roadster. Roadster.
But look up uh,
like blue cause there's this like
metallic kind of almost Carolina blue that
just looks like it belongs it like in
Miami. Just crushing it. Just gorgeous.
That's my next target.
Aventador roadster. Yeah.
Now do you ever drive a cars with a
manual transmission? My Viper was,
that's my favorite there to drive.
Stick on. I learned to drive.
Stick on Tim Sweeney's a Lamborghini.
Even if you're not driving fast,
it's just more fun.
And the,
the thing about the Lamborghinis and
the Ferrari's is that gated shifter boy
that's going to be, that's going to be
like, people are going to miss that.
It's a click, click, click, click thought
a lot about die hard gear heads doing.
But I'm not going to front and say like,
I know a lot about the car.
Like I'm not like that.
I just didn't know it goes right.
I just love it cause it's just gorgeous.
Jon Lovitz let me drive his car way
back in the day when we're on news radio
together and he had a Ferrari
three, five, five and it was, uh,
the gated shifter and I, it
was a convertible too. And
I was driving, I was like,
this might be the coolest fucking car
I've ever been in in my life because the
sound was incredible. I was
like, this sound like makes
me feel better. It's like,
it's intoxicating. It really
is. Click, click, click, click.
It wasn't even about driving. It's
super fast. That's a McLaren roadster.
That's fucking dead. That's the, that's
the Aventador is it? Really? Yeah,
but uh, it's all shaky video. Why
is it so shaky? I know, right?
State still bitch get a better phone.
But the start button on the event door
has a little like red cap over it.
Like a fighter jet. You have to lift
it up and press the fucking button.
I love it. Everything's in Italian
as far as like, but you don't have,
it doesn't say gas or fields has
been Zena. Ooh. And it's just that.
And when I bring friends in the car,
I'm like,
would you like to do the
honors of pressing the fighter
jet button and it just,
you have to start,
you have to start it like once a week
or the bad or the battery doesn't charge
or whatever.
It's the alternator I think so.
Like if you don't have a plug
in your garage and you go wait,
start at once a week. If you don't run
it on an average once a week, it happens.
All supercars dude. Really?
Yeah, like for ours as well.
They'll just bricked and you've
got to kind of get a jump.
That sounds ridiculous. Yeah. Biggie was
right. More money. More problems. Yeah.
Well you could always put a trickle
charger on. I can't yet. He could. Yeah.
That's just probably your electronic
system is draining because it's made by
Italians.
Silly pitches.
If you've got to fucking one of those
Lexus LFA supercars those a half a million
dollar Lexuses. Have you seen those? Oh,
that's their attempt to make the first
supercar right. Did an amazing cars.
It's not that good looking. Yeah, exactly.
The look is just not feeling it. Well,
it's kind of ironic because it,
it's similar performance wise
to the Nissan Gtr and like,
it's like you look at the numbers,
they're very commensurate. Yeah.
And then it's like the,
if you look at the,
looks like it's not much
better looking than Nissan Gtr,
but then you look at the price and
it's like, it's a half a million.
The Nissan Gtrs I still have to import
the gtrs cause those were only making
them here. Now I got a couple
of buddies, they swear by them.
They're just great cars.
They're amazing cars.
Nissan GTR is one of the greatest cars
that people have ever designed and
created for some friends whose logic
people love the NSX also. I had one,
I had two of those actually. Yeah,
I uh, I had one, I got rid of it,
I got the Porsche,
the Porsche broke down like five times.
And then I've got another NSX and
that put a supercharger on it.
When I had the Aventador delivered,
it was the first one in North Carolina
and they only had the trailers for the
other types of cars and it got stuck in
the trailer and they couldn't get it out.
And so the drivers didn't know what to do.
So I called my buddies a couple of big
boys and they basically got some dish
soap and were able to kind of pry the
car out by putting dish soap underneath
the tires after it pulled up and
pulled back cheese because it came from
Greensboro and it had like kind of
wedged itself in the trailer and that you
could, you couldn't do the Austin
Powers 15 point turn. Wow. They, yeah.
And actually won it with a couple
of little minor scratches on it,
which the dealers,
of course,
it's served me that when I
have it serviced I can put
it on a truck and ship it
to Greensboro. I had both of
them even need them surfaced.
The GTR is actually made at one factory
in Japan and they make them by hand.
And uh, apparently they lose money
on the car. Wow. Really? Yeah.
Well,
there's a how it's made for a Lamborghini
or dateline went behind the scenes and
how it was all made and it's all
dudes handmaking it the factory.
And for some reason all women doing this
dish of work and he just did the tour
of the factory.
That's how it should be.
They should be making sandwiches to cliff.
You'd be Joe that's misogynistic by
amine and he said by a blackbird instead
like a Yak. Blackbird. Yeah. Cause I
mean that's probably the same amount.
Like what are you talking
about? Those customers? Billion
Dollars. You knucklehead.
Those are like $1 billion at the
SR 71 yup. Yup. Deconditioned.
Yeah.
Yeah,
but you'd probably get a
used one transformers three
I think a Nissan GTR black
edition. $109,000 and it probably
feels just as fast as I fucking think.
Not really, but it's pretty goddamn
fast. Those cars are insanely fast.
I love sending my wife around town in
the white top down and people just lose
their shit. You love sending her
out there. She had cock holding.
So what's happening? What are you
saying? He likes sending her out there,
she's running errands. Just get all
that attention. He'll calm down.
You need to BRCA her up man. Keep her
up locked up in a castle somewhere.
Whatever.
What are the MMA fighters grabbed her
ass after the eyes when you were in
Charlotte.
That's shocking.
A cage fighter because I don't even
understand what you're saying and make it
sense man. Yeah, we're
willing to that bowling alley.
Lucky strike down there at the Charlotte.
Charlotte's a good towel man.
But it feels about his hip as the bankers
that built it really doesn't have a
lot of hard cause they built,
they've fucking destroyed it.
All the old buildings and
just rebuilt new shit.
So you feel like you're in the matrix.
So what is Raleigh as opposed
to Charlotte? Raleigh's
more down home or Ali's uh,
it's just,
you know,
a lot of the developers have embraced
the history and a lot of the restaurants,
you know, they leave the old brick.
They don't knock the whole thing down.
You know, we were talking about the,
uh, there's a bar right next to Charlie.
Good Nights, I guess. It's
actually downstairs from
Charlie goodnight's Rodeo bar.
They have like the fucking
mechanical bull and shaking, uh,
city limits and me and Ari and Brian,
were you there too?
I think in Eddie Bravo two we were there
doing standup and we went downstairs
and they were all singing along to this
song and we were all looking at each
other like, like, like
redneck woman or something.
It's like the scene in the dawn
of the dead where, um, you know,
like the guys in the
car and the zombies all,
all around and like he's the original
dawn of the dead and he's like, Holy Shit.
Like there's zombies everywhere
and they're just starting
to realize that that's
what it felt like when we're in this bar.
I guess we're,
we're by ourselves and then we hear the
song coming on and they don't know the
words at all, but everybody starts singing
along and they haven't got my pickup.
Why do you drink? Get
Drunk? No, no, no. It was,
it was not something that was popular. I
mean, it was popular for them, but it was,
these are people that I had no idea who
the fuck these people where they never,
we used to do bikini bull riding there.
They knew the summons though, man.
It was like, like top 10 country type
shit that they knew. And I was like, well,
this is like,
this is where the country audiences are.
A lot of the main countries. It's a
lot more rock than anything these days.
Like rascal Flatts, Keith urban
and it's, it's a little country,
but it's a lot of arena rock. Whereas
I'm saying just like Keith urban and uh,
and rascal Flatts and those kinds of
bands. Durban is like arena rock. Dude.
I went to a couple of his shows is
fucking fantastic. Yeah, look at that.
Brian Ebay. Oh, it's only a billion
dollars. That's just the tail rudder.
Oh my God. It's a tail rudder.
Yeah. That's all it is. And
it's sold for 1 million.
Oh, did it? Like was it from a plane that
crashed? Uh, let me get some historic,
yeah, it looks like a warehouse
in San Diego. I said the pride,
they didn't that day.
Oh my God.
Is some like Saudi prince is going to
buy that from making his coffee table.
He's going to jerk off on it every
day. That's what America, Jesus,
that's a weird thing to
buy for 1 million bucks.
I feel like you could do better
right by an oil platform.
Decommissioned one to start your
own country. That's not a bad move.
How much is an oil platform?
It doesn't work anymore. Um,
expensive but not as
expensive as you think.
I've read articles on it were really,
yeah.
People like you don't take the deep
mission and wanting to come to have their
own currency and make their own country.
There was an article on vice, uh,
it was a video. Yeah. Everything cool is,
there was a video on advice about,
um,
this woman who goes by the name
of neuro soup. Um, she was a,
she was a stripper and
then she got involved.
This guy who was an ecstasy dealer and
it's, it's a really crazy fucked up,
twisted tale involving murder and all
kinds of nutty shit and FBI and um,
she was living with this guy in a
fucking bomb shelter, not a bomb shelter,
but like a,
a missile silo.
They had converted a missile silo silo
into this like really beautiful high end
luxury house seats with it. Cause
it's multi tiered, right? Yeah. Yeah.
Something all underground. Yep. Missile
Silo here. I'll Google it. But um,
she uh,
you know,
she has this incredible story like the
got kidnapped her and like he was going
to kill them.
It's like the guy was just gacked out on
fucking drugs and he was selling drugs
and he was also like in cahoots with the
DEA or the FBI or something like that.
He was working under cover while he was
selling drugs. Yeah. Dude, if I have,
if I ever want to get anything done,
I don't go on a device like the Liberia
documentary they did about general buck
naked. Yeah. Cause you
remember he, that he made the,
the chemical sector and you pick a Mormon.
But he was a real fucking guy. Yeah,
he was. Yeah. That guy's
a scary fucking guy, man.
Now he's like a reformed and he's like
a preacher or something now. Well,
not only that,
he's killed thousands of people and
they absolve them of all of his murders
because he found Christ and he
was talking openly on vice
about eating babies. Yeah.
And eating hearts to cutting the hearts
of the innocent children and drinking
their blood to make them victorious
in battle and their strength and shit.
Like whoa. And then they went into
North Korea at one point on vice,
like it's just nonstop, like
crazy shit. Yeah. This is a video.
The vice video is available online.
It's a Hamilton Morris is a Pharmacopia
Hamilton who's been on the podcast
before.
He did a video about it,
but there's an actual article that may
have not been on vice. That's about it.
So you've just do a little googling,
you'll find it.
But the story is absolutely
incredible thing is you're, you're,
you're crowd sourcing interesting stuff
through your Twitter verse. Yeah. Well,
they get you in touch with stuff that you
probably wouldn't find on your own and
in turn you get them in touch. It's
sorta like a relationship that you know,
bees pollinate things and you know
seeds eat a grapefruit, you take a shit,
the seeds go into the ground and they
grow grapefruit. Symbiotic. Yeah. This,
this symbiotic relationship that we
have with people on the Internet now,
if you exploit it correctly or you utilize
it correctly is a better way of using
it. It's incredibly rewarding to tweet
up anywhere a tweetup what's it? Yeah,
we just tweet. You're going to be
at the fucking mall on Thursday.
Good way to get touched.
Yeah. Fair enough. Net Buddy.
I'm not into that kind of shit. I know
what you're saying. I think you think,
oh Hollywood people are like
that. I see, right? Yeah.
What is it that girl said last night,
she's like trying to get you to fix her
hair. The wash. It's a good way to say it.
And then she's like, oh
yeah, I know. It's weird.
Nobody does this la or something
and like, okay, fix my hair.
Like the California thing.
Joe, go to the fucking salon.
Seriously touching your fucking greasy
hair. Weird pitch, but your lights,
your head lice.
My favorite California thing is whenever
you know someone's come from California,
because in the first 30 seconds they
tell you something incredibly intimate,
intimate about their life. Like, Oh yes,
I used to be addicted to drugs or
like I was molested and I'm like,
that's why they're here. Dog Burden me
with this shit. I don't want to know that
sad, but that's why they're here. Yeah.
You know it's weird
because this is also the,
obviously people create all over
the world, no doubt about that.
But when you come to like creating
things that get attention,
this is like the hub of the universe,
creating things that get attention.
It's almost all in Hollywood. It's like
a big chunk of it. Whether it's movies,
TV shows, Blah, blah, blah,
blah. Well who needs attention?
People that didn't get enough or people
that got too much of the wrong con. Yeah.
And those are the ones that seek
out and seek out validation.
So they all come here. It's so
weird. Mathematical process.
Oh, always loved Angelina, I
believe. Uh, he always left her.
Now the whole blonde bombshell just put
up fucking billboards of herself and
became famous just for that.
I saw her the other day just picking her
nose and eating it and then you posted
something about,
you saw somebody picking your nose
and eating it like the day after.
And I'm like, what the
fuck? That's hilarious.
I love that pink corvette veteran lady in
a wig.
She was a on the PCH.
The Topanga to the PCH on the merge
were stopped at the light and I looked
behind and I watched this old
lady in a wig just dig, pull out,
I'll whopper and just start chewing.
I mean,
she was openly chewing mouth
open chewing and I was like, wow.
And all I could think
of course for the rest
of the day who that?
She probably came over here in 1955 and
she wanted it to be a star and she was
hot and it just didn't work out.
And now she's wearing a wig on the
PCH chewing or burgers and her,
her blue Saturn with fucking faded out
paint. It was very weird. Watch it.
I thought it was a touch. She always
drove a vet. Now that's Angelina. She did.
He saw Angelina. I saw some random
crazy lady with light blue Saturn.
I do that with people. I like try to piece
together what their story was. What's,
what's it. That fucking mind always
goes down to drugs and blow jobs.
The stories all of very
unoriginal. They always, you know,
somewhere along the line someone blew Burt
Reynolds. That's always in my stories.
What's that fucking water that they're
advertising all over la one 38 or
something.
They just like billboards.
It's just like hot hot chicks and some
bottled water. I didn't have enough.
It's like a banks I think
thing or something. Are you
serious? I haven't seen it.
And then the pop,
the bubble head renders on the bus
benches also with an la proper and it's
bottled water. Sexy water is the best
water. You don't even drink at Vons, bro.
Terrible for the environment,
but bottled water is,
somebody showed me a photo of a place in
La that just serves water like and like
you pick your water and they described
the spring that it's from. I'm like, oh,
those guys are assholes. Elling so
hard right now. That's not true.
That's gotta be a parody. Tim and
Eric Shit. Yeah. What's your color?
[inaudible] water. Clairvoyants
wait a minute. Cool. Blue Quill.
Clairvoyants what?
Why does it say clairvoyants you trying
to tell me that I could read minds with
your fucking, I think that's what it
is. It's the bottle is different colors.
So you just, what does it say? That's the
color of that. What does that one say?
Fuck. Vitamin water. Well
that one says clairvoyance to,
they all say clairvoyants look everyone
you click on and what does it say?
Also sexy something. What? Sexy.
What does it say in the middle?
She's as you scroll and Freak.
Hold it in place. Oh my God.
Where are you going up? The
actual thing, the logo itself,
it's like he's in a connect, bossy black
and what's below that? Clairvoyance.
But it was say it said sexy. One
of them was sexy. Something like,
that's one of the colors.
Placebo. Water. Come on,
you're telling me your water sexy.
You fuck that shit will drown you.
Sexy Sunshine,
yellow a waterboard you and find
out what you terrorist information.
The first fashion water,
we'll find out which one is sexy so I
can make sure I never fucking drink it
ever again. Sexy, sexy red. Fuck you.
How about that one 38 water.
Sexy read you.
You silly bitches are giving them a plug.
That's your name.
You come for the water. Sexy
red. Fuck you. How dare you.
I dare you treat me like I'm not stupid
plant man. I just wish I had some sex.
Can't get any sex, dude.
Nobody wants to give me no sex,
but it didn't go by some sexy red water.
Is She a part of this? She's drinking.
It's like I take it back. She was very
pretty. My Buddy's dating seems nice.
She's a sweetheart and don't
drop names on my podcast anymore.
It's making me uncomfortable.
Then your buddy. Okay.
I was trying to be what? It's Dana.
Really? Yeah. She's just fucking cool.
So have you seen them together?
Yes.
I'm sure he's not paying her because
if I was a girl like Adrian Currie,
what I would do is I would start a
service to make people look cool.
I would just hang out with them. So I'd
say I'm just dating dating this guy.
Now that doesn't make any sense a fair
enough. It doesn't make any sense.
It's not fair enough.
I'm just showing you.
I mentioned that cause
it's like if somebody had a
problem with her and be like,
well I knew her.
Just don't be mean.
Oh you were defending her without
her being attacked. That's beautiful.
I'm a white knight knighting.
Get advanced fucking Internet.
You're getting a white knight in advance.
That is one of the grossest
things about the internet.
Is it not the White Knight?
What's the White Knight?
The white knight is a chest movie
from the 80s it's the guy who's like,
oh guys are being misogynistic to you.
I'm going to come in and save you. Yeah.
They always want to assure you
that there are different to them.
All the other men, there's other men out
there are assholes. So here's just a,
an acquaintance of mine started a website
called fat ugly or slutty.com and so
the idea is if you're playing an online
video game and you're actually a female,
they assume you're either
fat, ugly or slutty. Well,
it's a weird thing where people like
want to profess the fact that they don't
hate women. Like they'll have it in
their Twitter handle. Don't hate women,
you know,
I don't hate women like Duh,
like how many people do like is it,
isn't it like more likely less people
hate women than more people hit women?
The fact that you have to actually say
that, it seems like what are, what are,
what numbers are we working
with? Like, I mean is it what,
what a percentage of people hate women?
Is it even won?
The thing about women in the video game
industry is having personally known many
of them. The stories I fucking hear
from them are fucking horrifying.
Like what do you mean? Like, as far
as like harass me, all that shit.
Of course they're working with men,
men, soc, but that's not my point.
My random dude's living presence on
their desk. Anonymous Lean Shit. Ooh,
that's creepy.
Especially you take that home and that
presence got a remote control camera.
Yeah, exactly. Oh, it's, hey, I need my
little nanny bear. You have the GPS. Yeah.
Well let's, that had
that, the hacking of, uh,
people's webcams and then
demanding that they, you know,
they find a couple of naked pictures
and they demand that the girl gives them
more. They recently posted a
guy for that. Oh, of course.
There's always going to be a guy that
fucks everything up for everybody else.
There's always going to be one douchey
dude does shitty things. And if,
especially if you could do it anonymously
and an office like that and just creep
her out. Yup. But they could find that
they could fight. They have cameras.
They could figure out who the fuck's
doing that. Yeah. It's, uh, I dunno.
I haven't had my feet in those shoes.
You have the same issue though.
If you a twink like yourself,
if you were a involved in a play,
I'm actually a puff a man.
I'm actually power bottom.
But if you were involved in a company
with a bunch of like really aggressive,
large gay men, it's like a big
bunch of linebackers who, you know,
just also were gay and they started a
company and they employed you. Yeah,
that'd be even more threatened.
I wouldn't fare well in prison.
I'd have koolaid and my lips and the
first spot. Great way of describing it.
I wouldn't fair, well,
I have a pretty mouth.
I wouldn't fair,
well that's not like pirate talk.
I wouldn't fare well and that's
scary to me. It would be acting up.
He would get me with the cooks need to
get to my citrus. What was that accent?
Yeah.
Being pursued is
not fun. Whether it's an unwanted,
whether you're a man or a woman,
but it's way creepier if you're a woman
because men are physically larger,
physically larger, usually, and more
violent and creepier. Yeah. You know,
like everybody wanted to get scared
because of the movie, like, um,
like fatal attraction. The bunny burner.
You know, she's boiling bunnies and shit.
He just wants to kill him.
He has to kill her at the end.
But for women that's like par
for the course, you know, that's,
it's way more common, but it just
doesn't manifest itself in movies.
It's fucking cat calls. That's the
thing. It just like, is that ever worked?
I saw that happen to my dad, my Stepdad
when I was a kid in San Francisco,
I saw some guy whistle at
him while he's with me. Man,
I was fucking seven and saw some
guy who was walking, he's whatever.
How did that get universal to buy the
right? That's like, okay, okay. Is Global.
Yeah, you can eat right. Most random
country and say, okay, okay, okay, okay.
And everyone fucking knows
it. Yeah. But it's like,
you see videos is most third world nation
and inevitably there's Coca Cola there.
I wonder who came up with check about bow,
uh,
came from the original, like it used
to be the classic porn style. Right.
But that sound though is like all you
have to do is go bounce when someone walks
by. And that very specific,
right? It's pretty much,
that maybe varies a little
bit like bowel wall mount,
but you could say that,
but you're a little bit more
sophisticated to the average person.
The average person
has midi keyboard.
The average person that saw like,
you know,
two people that are like holding hands,
they start making out and
you look at them, you go,
I'll watch a compound bow automatically
brown chicken cow. Cow. Yeah.
What is that and how did that one
make it through? It's cultural.
You can't map it,
but it's fascinating.
Everyone is saying literally
amazing about everything now.
I don't hang out with those people,
man. All right, fair enough. Checking.
You know what everybody is saying though,
you know,
and I do it too and a fucking hate it.
I was listening for it the other day in
an interview. I heard like a hundred,
you know, in one conversation
it's the new, uh, and I do it.
I'm trying to avoid doing it. It's hard
when you know you're trying to, you know,
trying to, you know, figure out what the
fuck you're going to say. Oh, he goes,
I hate listening to myself.
I hate fucking watching myself.
The problem with it though is once you're
aware of it, you can't not think of,
you knows, it's like you, you know,
it was just permeate your brain and you
can't listen to a conversation cause
he's like, you want to interrupt and say,
don't say you know, again, don't do it.
But they're gonna say it again. I'll call
people out on the literally thing. Oh,
if your friends, you'd be like, I'm
literally dying here. I'm like, really?
You actually fit? Do I need to get to the
fucking er? Like what's going on? Yeah.
The misuse of the word literary,
they actually changed.
Literally they changed the
definition of it. Yeah. Really? Yeah.
So it basically means that the
Oxford dictionary, whatever.
So that essentially means figuratively.
Sure. It's not the urban dictionary, Dude.
I don't if Ahca did. They really?
Dude, urban dictionary man.
90% that shit's made up. Well,
if you want to keep a job,
you will make up some urban expressions,
son. We got books to, Yup. We got
people that outfit.
Well that's like private prisons.
Once there's money involved in
it, it just goes, gets crazy.
You just bow chicka wow. Wow. A verbal
means referencing a sexual encounter,
act or deed. Also used to identify
someone or thing that is sexual. Hmm.
I got this girl at the club and
bounce your, wow. Wow. That guy.
That guy has sort of dazzled shirt.
Yeah.
He's probably got one of those ones
that has like Japanese writing in foil,
you know those affliction ones with
a tight v neck. Mike, Mike Posner,
the guy that wrote that song.
If I can write you a song like
he has a song called Bow Chico.
How well does he really? Yeah, it's
clever bastard and I saw him alive.
I like him recently. He was
good. Yeah. He's actually from a,
he was going to Duke when he started
his music career. Thank right graduate.
So he's having a call with a zero.
Yes.
Production values kind
of art music factory.
You got gas.
Shut this off immediately
do to America. Do you hate America?
Are you with the terrorists?
I'm opposing her fan. Uh, he opened
for what? Kesha, you can't really,
you can't really judge the
guy based on the 10 seconds.
A very stressful spraying and
nonsense to the air can match.
He just asked you to rent.
Yeah. Axe Body spray him buddy.
Chuck car or used car just went away on
its own. It's sort of like the plague.
How are I'm bringing it back
or are you bringing back?
I used to bathe in that shit
in high school. I bet you did.
Oh you son of a bitch will do it. Staring
at your poster of your Lamborghini.
Yeah. One day world. One of these
days. Show you all shallow. Yeah.
Going to
be a mega villain. Yeah. How did
you guys wind up in North Carolina?
Was that just where one
of the main epic guys, uh,
was working for IBM and he said,
hey, come check it out. And if,
if I was the person I am today
and I moved to Raleigh in 1998,
I'd be fucking miserable.
Why is that?
Because back then all I cared about was
that there was a fucking mall and at
Burger King and now you're more cultured,
your different guy.
Now I'm farm to table Joe Farm to table
all you organic. I it, no, fuck no.
We're not a free gluten free and organic.
No, it's a no. Just, you know, I don't,
I'm kind of over the big, big
chains and shit. Yeah. I'm like,
well this is nice when you go to places
like Seattle where you don't see too
many chains.
Yeah.
Seattle's a cool town in that
there's a lot of individual cities,
a lot of places that you know, are you
individual rather restaurants that are,
you know, locally owned, locally
operated like that pit place. Yeah.
Well that's a change. You
don't want to go, let's go,
let's go to fucking this place and
go to Chili's. Like what the fuck?
Those places have personality,
like places that are
individually owned and operated.
They have a certain personality that you
never going to get at a TGI Friday's.
Exactly. When the menus to let
laminated and just a little too slick.
You just think that there's anything wrong
with the Fridays, you know, or Chili's.
You want some baby back rings, wings,
whatever. Those fucking commercials,
baby back bad if you're on the road.
I had a buddy my visit from la a couple
months ago and I took him to my friends,
a establishment. He says, dude, what
do you think of Raleigh? And he goes,
it's great.
There's no chains.
I told you is what the terrorists
you here I was friends talk,
he's going to do think of Raleigh.
He's Raleigh.
You know he's Moroccan
and he uses the word dude.
All it is this Tila Tequila converts
and Nazi-ism Tila Tequila would suck
Satan's Dick if it got
her on TV. Tila, Tequila,
it converts. Hold on, pull down it
down, read it, converts the Nazis.
I'm calls herself,
hit Dilla and antisemetic
new song had Tila
fucking retard. Come on. It's that real.
She's trying so hard and she
still runs her heart. Hey man,
we're talking about her shit, right?
The Kardashians factor, right.
She trolled us.
Lawrence,
19 year old sister was talking about
watching that show and she had,
she didn't know that Kim
Kardashian had a sex tape. Oh,
well did it make her feel better about
the show or worse? She didn't really care.
A sex tape. Sex. That's something
like one of the best ones he liked.
Big Black Cock gets it. Be
Honest. She tunes into the beach,
she tunes into the BBC.
There will be a time when mark my
words in the future where like,
it's like you don't have a
sex tape. What's wrong with
you? Check mine out cliff.
He's saying this because he's about to
release a sex tape. I'm going to leak it.
You're going to accidentally leak
at accidentally leaking. Yeah.
She's one of the first that actually
got hugely famous though from it.
I mean Paris Hilton got sort of
famous from that boring, but yeah,
hers was annoying when she was blowing
that guy and kept answering the phone.
Fucking rude etiquette through terrible
blow job advocate can all learn from
that to your way of saying this,
my phone and my phone calls are
more important than your cock,
but she's basically like the
Floyd Mayweather reality stars.
You're tuning because you hate her.
You know?
She figured out how to market in that way,
become obnoxious in a way that
people will tune in just to hate her,
but they got tired of that after awhile.
She didn't fucking up big black guys
that show with Nicole Richie. That was
like, I just hate both of those girls now.
Where's in the call? Richie? You don't
really ever hear about her. She still is.
She's got it.
She's got millions of followers on
fucking Twitter thinks she's got kids now.
It's just out of the loop don with it all.
Oh,
you either stay in the party group
and die or become a family person.
That sounds like you should put that in
the beginning of a new video party or
die. This is a new video. You coop
and does all the rockers, right?
They're either die or they become
family men. Yeah. Or they become like,
I watched gene Simmons family jewels.
It's now it's on access TV.
It's not so crazy that miss
fakers show ever. It's weird.
You see the one where he,
I think we talked about where he uh,
got vibrators glued to his hands and he
had to go out and he couldn't take these
vibrators off cause somebody's super
glued them to his hands somehow.
It's weird because I was a huge kiss fan,
you know?
And so now I'm watching him
and he's just weird, you know,
older guy on a fake show. It's
like, but, but your gene Simmons,
you're like, you know your Gene
Simmons, what are you doing here?
What's going on here? You're
got a thunder. He probably
sees it as this marketing.
Yeah, I'm sure they came to town and
they still did a fucking good show.
Of course. Then I realized, fuck yeah,
half the members are like new dudes.
Two of them. Half of. Exactly. But my
wife had no idea what she was enforced.
She's like, what the fuck? Where the same
thing. And we just went and saw guar.
Oh my God.
I told her nothing.
What's the main dude goes?
Drink by bloody see made as his cuddle
for sprays into the crowd. She's like,
the fuck are you? That is rude. It's
bloody Sieman's crew open for kiss.
Really crude crude at crew wasn't doing
so good, man. They were. Vince was like,
he's the way that feeling. All right.
I got Mick Mars like propped up.
Oh Wow. Dude. That was like growing
up and listening to all that music.
The sunset strip was like
this fucking mythical place.
Right where giant girls
hair fucking aquanet.
You know comedians too,
man. Yeah. There's sunsets.
Trip has been a mythical place
for a long ass time. Yeah.
I still haven't seen that
documentary on the sunset strip.
It's supposed to be incredible.
We're trying to get it mattes.
Tags is trying to get a copy of it
for the, can you get it on iTunes?
The documentary, not the showtime
movie. Right? It's the same thing.
They showtime movie movies. The
documentary. Yup. Oh, I was confused.
I thought the showtime movie was,
had actors in it. It was a movie. No,
it's a documentary. Oh, I'm
an asshole. Okay. I was like,
when is this thing going to get released
and why is it I'm getting confused with
this other showtime documentary?
Right. Or show it to you.
Just move it aired on showtime,
but now they get, they have an,
I watched it on Itunes, I believe.
Okay. Cliffy be what's next for you?
I'm basically looking to
start a new studio looking,
you start a new studio to make some
ridiculous first person fast manly type
shooter. Aventador of shooters. Yeah.
Something that makes your Dick hard and
chewed flames. Flames out your ass. When,
when are you going to start doing this?
I'm talking to people about funding
right now. This isn't bitches get on it.
It's cliffy be you're talking to,
it's not some rank amateur through the
fucking cheese grinder since he was a
child. You know, when you're asking
for a certain amount of money,
there's certain strings
attached and there's due
diligence and all that Shit and
John Romero aside, you're a
different person than him. Okay.
You're not going to get their house.
Fair enough.
You're going to figure out how to keep
it together. My thing, Joe is, um, I,
I know my weaknesses and I joked that
if like I'm gonna make my Avengers,
I need my core like six leads,
like a Ninja art director and into
chief operating officer, like Ninja,
just those kinds of people.
And then like, you know,
we're all on the same page and,
and build the studio slowly
and intelligently build
the community while you
build a company while they build the game.
Do you have a timeline when
you'd like to get off the ground?
It depends on when the ink dries on
deals that are being negotiated. The,
my thing is I don't want to go with,
I'm scared of the old
guard cause you know,
the last thing I need is some
mid level executive going,
well traditionally this kind
of game doesn't do want,
therefore we're going to not market
it and therefore it doesn't do well.
So we told you so of a bitch.
Yeah, I don't like that at all.
How about that?
I mean the thing of the problem in
entertainment in general is the people who
usually are responsible for the
money or very rearward looking right.
And it's like Gretzky says,
go with a fucking puck's
going, not where the puck is.
You know like in the exact quote
and Gretzky. I love it. Yeah.
Executives go around e three and they're
like, oh, that's a World War II shooter.
We need one of that.
It's like it doesn't fucking work.
That wasn't that kind of
the problem with everything.
Now you get these mid level managers who
are trying to play the safe numbers and
trying to shoot things straight down
the middle and then the creative types.
So like why does it have to
be the way it's always been?
Why can't we do something weird?
Let's do something crazy and it's
due Buffy the vampire slayer,
but for fucking real shit. Yeah.
Scary. She had a complex two.
You got to fail early. Fail often. Dude,
we're out of time. Come back again.
Thanks for having me.
And if people want to file,
it's the real cliffy be on
Twitter. There's a bunch
of fake twitters for cliff.
Hi. Say last name Bill Zinsky Zinsky
you'd have known you for it. I know,
but I'm bad at Polish.
Bazinsky it's a hard one.
Joseph or Ghana bitch be alright.
Never go all the way.
Just the tip. The uh, um, the
twitters, the real cliffy B,
all the other cliff was
in skis are bullshit.
They're all just some weird probably
girls, girls pretending to be you guys.
Whatever you see Internet.
I don't know who it is,
but it's not the real cliffy bay.
So the real cliffy beads a real quick.
Anything else anybody needs to go to?
What Finland, that mansion on, you know,
just go to my Twitter on Twitter.
That's where I talk shit the most.
Beauteous Ladies and gentlemen,
uh, thanks to our sponsors.
Thanks to stamps.com go click on the
microphone. Enter in the code word J R e,
get your no risk Twila
and $110 bonus offer,
including a digital scale
and up to $55 a free postage.
And thanks also to carbonite.
Go to carbonite.com
and use the offer code,
J r e for a free trial.
No credit card required plus two free
bonus months with your subscription.
That's carbonite.com offer code j r h.
And thanks also to onnit.com that's,
Oh and and I t use the code name Rogan
and save 10% off any and all supplements.
Brian,
we got going on,
you've got some shit happened on a
Wednesday that San Jose improper having a
dirty show and it's Tiffany Haddish,
Sam Aaa and myself.
Tickets are only $10 and available online
at [inaudible] dot TV or improv.com
and also check out Joe,
you were just saying Thunderpussy a
Friday and it was one of the coolest shows
ever.
You did a pretty much an hour set of all
new material and people are loving it.
So that's an ad Lib show that we,
that is on that squad network where we
go onstage and the audience just yells
out shit. It's very similar to what I
used to do after shows. I used to do it,
but it's better to do it this way where
the whole show is that way. Right.
You know, I think doing a three person
show like this is the way to go.
Like have a real show
where you just have ad Lib.
I'm going to start doing more of them
cause I think it's a great way to develop
materials that it was so
funny Joe and it just,
and it shifts so amazing watching you at
like something that's designed for you
so perfectly that you just slayed.
You came in there and just destroyed.
It was so cool watching man.
It was drunk as fuck Sean gets.
That's the key though.
Hi. Drunk. Drunk and high.
Yeah, you got to do that.
You've got to do it like your skin
and you don't know how to stop and uh,
but it was a really supportive crowd too,
so thanks everybody that came out.
It was a, it's easy to do
those if the crowds are cool.
If the crowds are shit heads,
it's not that much fun. Right.
Comedy is the only art form ever where
we can't really create it on our own.
We need you guys there. All right,
thanks everybody. Wednesday night, uh,
at the ice house a, I'll be
there with Tony Hinchcliffe, uh,
Mat fold Tron, Ian Edwards, uh, and more.
I'm sure we'll have more people
sign up before we do them.
On Wednesday nights once every two
weeks or so. And there are a lot of fun.
All right. We will be back tomorrow with
the Great Tommy Bonds, Aka Tom Score, m.
And. A. That's it. All
right. We love you. Bye.