Natasha luxury rogue
drinking healthy green juice.
Oh,
I drink.
That's tough.
Is Yummy.
It's good for you.
Look at you all healthy and shit.
I mean,
doing yoga,
drinking juice.
I mean,
I also smoked pot and drank and
those are good things at all.
Yeah.
It's like who said that?
Oliver Wilde,
all things in moderation,
including moderation.
Oscar Wilde.
Was it?
Yes,
I was at right.
That's Oliver Wilde.
Did I say 1130 my brand is useless till
about 3:00 PM I made you come earlier.
Say overwhelmed.
Yeah.
Well I've been up.
I've been up.
I got up early today.
You got kids?
Yeah,
kids.
But I went to Yoga class.
Oh,
you went today?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Eight o'clock class.
They have like 5:00 AM classes.
I'm like,
who's taking a five amp crim class?
I know.
I kind of want to go.
Just fucking Weirdos
that I'm like,
who is getting up at 5:00 AM for an
90 minute class and where I live,
they pump up the heat too much.
They had this like,
they have this sort of vibe of
like they want to torture you.
You know,
it's an ordeal.
You're getting through an ordeal.
It's way more difficult
than anybody thinks it is.
Like you drive by these
little fucking boxes,
these rooms,
and nobody knows the kind of punishment
that's going on in those places.
Everybody thinks it's like
a bunch of housewives,
like stretching and
holding onto their toes.
Chowder is raping his students and they're
all getting $12 an hour to like teach
us
nothing to teach us.
And he's been,
I think accused of rape 17 times.
Well,
let's Google it.
It's more than one.
Certainly that's an issue,
right?
Whenever,
I mean,
if one person says,
hey,
Jamie,
the sexual encounter we
had was unpleasant for me.
I think you may be a rapist.
I'm calling the fucking cops.
That's,
you know,
there's some wiggle room there.
But when it's more the hotline numbers,
those are big numbers,
big numbers.
It's so hard to get 30
people to agree to law
unless they're working
for the CIA or something.
How many people has he
a new cases filed February 13th bringing
the total number of civil lawsuits,
civil lawsuits.
What does that mean?
What about criminal?
Uh,
okay.
It says claims he raped her during
the 2010 teacher training or
five other allegations
span over two years,
including another rape charge from,
it's always depressing when it's the
people who are like the spiritual leaders.
Super Common.
I know anytime you try to repress things,
but I mean I don't even,
I mean he's allowed to have sex,
right.
Allowed to like
use their dicks as weapons.
What about Pat Benatar?
What does she is as a weapon?
A weapon that I'd see.
I think it's different.
One woman when live on music,
I'm sorry.
I really do.
Because men have the upper body strength
and they had this thing specifically
have upper body strength.
Look at you and then you had this thing
that gets hard and then it inserts right
into the woman as an act of violence.
It's very rude and seemed
convenient and golfing,
golfing and penetrating are two
completely different things,
right?
Because the woman and Golfs,
but she can't,
she's not the aggressor.
She's receptive.
If someone grabs your finger
and starts sucking it,
come on,
man,
what are you doing on my finger?
It's not that big a deal,
but if someone grabs their finger
and stuffs it in your mouth,
you're like,
whoa,
that's kind of fucked up.
It's different.
Although there is female rape,
I watched a documentary on it.
Oh yeah,
there is
women.
You know what they do though?
They the rape other women and they get
on their face so a woman will sit on the
other woman's face so she
can't breathe and like get off.
Hmm.
And I think that's what
I saw it on Netflix.
Well female rape.
I think we would have to look at
each of those on an individual basis.
I mean I wouldn't want some woman
to force her pussy on my face.
That's what I'm saying.
That as one aggressive lesbian.
The problem is,
I think there's probably some
women that like a little of that,
probably some like,
look,
there's all sorts of sexual appetites
and I know there's guys I know guys don't
like to be smacked around and tied up.
I have a friend who likes
doing that fucking weird shit.
Oh yeah.
I used to work for a dominatrix.
I wasn't like working
for her as a Dominatrix,
but she,
I worked in her clothing store
and she was also a Dominatrix,
this German woman and she
would go piss on people.
She would just like,
it was so funny and she had this
crazy accent and she'd answer,
you know,
one line she was ordering,
fabric and then the other line she's like,
what are you into?
Do you want me to jog around the block?
You want my feet smelly?
She always like,
and then she had a guy
who had like his thing,
she would tell me about it all.
She had a guy who all he wanted to do,
she had to wear white underwear and he
just wanted to use a flashlight and look
up her skirt for like an hour.
She would get paid so much.
At one time I went over to her house to
get paid and she had a man blind folded
on the floor crawling and he was just
smelling her boots while she was writing
me a check.
I mean it was,
it never ended.
It was so funny.
But that's all voluntary.
So that's where it gets weird.
It's like they're paying,
they're paying and they want to do it.
It's like that's their thing.
It's like I just did a girl
who liked to get choked.
That was her thing.
She so I didn't,
I don't like doing that.
I don't want well cause
you're still strong.
It's one thing when you ask them emo
guide a chunk or some like scared dude.
But when you asked him guy who
like clearly could strangle you,
maybe it only with 10% of your strength.
I use good technique.
I know what I'm doing.
But
I didn't,
I don't,
I don't want to connect.
I never wanted to connect
those two things together.
Like I'm not in the sex violence,
but it's not.
And um,
I don't,
I think you could get into anything.
And when I was in high school,
I've talked about this before,
I had this girl that used to like rub my
dick where their feet and I had a foot
fetish for a little bit just for a
little bit like not nothing crazy,
but it lasted for a while cause I think
like I connected feet with sexuality for
a while because of this one girl.
I think if you start
choking people like that,
that could happen.
If you date someone who really likes that.
And this girl used to say
choked me like I can't,
I'm not going to choke you.
And I'm like,
I'm not going to do this.
I can't do it.
I'm not going to do it.
Do it a little.
She's like,
took me who I'm not going to do it.
You know,
in the wrestling match choker,
like,
you know,
just enough.
Just enough.
Just a little bit.
I don't need to teach you,
but I'm just saying
some girls like it too much.
But my point being is that if you got
into that and then you dated a girl who is
not into it at all,
he started choking her.
She'd be like,
I can't be comfortable with
you now because I'm thinking
you're going to fucking
choke me,
Ya know?
Right.
That's a good point.
Do you know that guy that's getting
accused of beating up women?
He was a host of the CBC radio show.
His name is John Ghomeshi.
Yes,
I read about it.
Yeah,
he's,
what's amazing is this
guy was like a feminist,
allegedly.
You know Mr Social Justice Warrior type
guy talked really calmly like this.
He was one of those guys who
would talk about women's issues.
Let's talk about women's issues and just
beat the fuck out of girls in his spare
time.
Like allegedly,
I should say allegedly,
but there's multiple counts.
Yeah.
You don't want to believe that Jimmy
Hendrix hit some girl with a telephone.
Listen,
we were talking about
that before the show.
She was telling me that Jimi
Hendrix had his wife and I see,
first of all,
never heard,
never married.
And the only time Mr.
Hendricks was ever in trouble,
listen,
God damn Canada,
and I told us fucking Canadians,
if you want the good music,
you got to let Jimmy bring the heroin end.
Can't be arrested him at the border.
Yeah.
I mean he's just so cool and unique.
There's never been anyone else like,
yeah.
Since then either.
There's been a few guys that have
kind of taken that vibe a little bit,
but
he was the motto.
Any crab that's,
I'm leaving
Oliver while I was going
to say Gary Clark Jr,
is that all right?
I don't know who that is.
Oh,
how dare you.
He's amazing.
He's actually really good,
but he doesn't have that.
He's got his own vibe,
but he's just a really good
guitarist and he happens to be black
since,
you know.
Wait,
so what was Jimmy's shelf life like?
Was he around for five years?
It wasn't around very long.
You died at 27 he was
one of those 27 guys.
Yeah.
You know,
there's a lot,
a lot of weird shit that's been going
on lately where people have come out and
said that he was killed.
His,
his girlfriend at the time,
who's with him when he died,
she jumped off of a building and Soho
and this guy who wrote this book who like
a bodyguard or worked for Jimi Hendrix
manager said that Jimmy Hendrix was
killed by his manager and so was the
girlfriend cause she knew too much and it
sounds like bullshit,
but he was actually kidnapped.
Jimi Hendrix was kidnapped for a couple
days and his manager is the one who got
him free and they said that what happened
was Jimmy was thinking about leaving
his manager.
So his manager had Jimmy kidnapped and
then made it look like he was rescuing
him.
Do you believe that?
Yeah.
I mean
I don't have,
I do killed.
Who was like such an industry
making you so much money.
If the guy was going to leave you and
you had a life insurance policy against
it,
have you?
I mean it is possible evil.
Well that's what everybody said.
That shook night.
Did.
I mean I don't think it's beyond the
realm of possibility that people who are
mean evil,
crazy fucks.
He'll make a lot of money off artists
like Jimi Hendrix manager allegedly did,
would be willing to do that.
I mean there's always been,
there's always been like organized crime
ties to music and and to artists is
just so much money involved and
having a guy like Hendrix with you if,
if he's going to leave you,
we got Phil Spector.
Remember that guy who
shot that fucking woman?
He was always in it like he was a guy
that like produce the Beatles songs and
that guy was apparently always into
putting guns in people's mouths.
Like that was his thing.
Right.
Feels like a power thing that maybe he
was like he just got too powerful as
opposed to being evil.
I think it's pretty evil
to shoot some of the mouth.
Yeah,
that's true.
I know,
I see your point.
I could see it both ways.
I could see it being a bullshit story
that someone wrote long after Jimi Hendrix
was dead.
This guy decides Cashin I'll just make
some ridiculous claims and I'll make some
money.
It's possible.
You know,
there's no one knows.
No one knows other than
the people involved.
Do you think people are evil?
I think some people are evil.
What do you think?
I Dunno.
I was just thinking like,
yeah,
I was thinking of like Tony Soprano.
He's someone who he is,
you've seen depicted like
he would kill someone.
Right.
And like,
but then he liked,
they justify it all cause they love their
family and they pay for their family.
So I'm just thinking like they must have,
they must defend their lives.
I wonder how evil people
defend their lives.
I don't think they have to.
I mean,
what about king
do themselves?
Yeah,
I know
he shot someone with an antiaircraft gun.
The story is that someone was,
um,
he was making a speech.
Some guy fell asleep during a speech.
So you shot him with an antiaircraft gun.
Really?
That was the story.
I mean,
obviously no one knows.
But he definitely killed his uncle.
He killed his uncle and his uncle's sons.
So,
uh,
that his son's couldn't avenge his uncle
because they were planning on some sort
of a cool,
so it's like a mobster vibe.
Like they're just like,
I'll kill people for my betterment.
Hmm.
Well,
I mean it's a dictator vibe.
It's some game of Thrones shit.
I mean,
that is exactly what's
going on over there.
Minus the dragons and the white walkers.
I can't watch that show.
I'm sorry.
I'm the only one.
There should be like a group for us.
What's the matter?
Uh,
like Howard Kramer,
he calls him,
make them ups and that's Kinda how I feel.
Like I'm not,
I can't,
I can't hold my,
what do you mean by make moves?
And it's just like fantasy,
right?
It's like,
it doesn't appeal to me.
What do you like?
I like documentaries.
I like things based in reality.
I like character driven dramas.
And I like funny comedies.
I don't like dragons and
people whose mission,
your hands become machine guns.
I just can't get into it.
It,
it speaks nothing to me of my life.
I can appreciate that.
Okay,
but you,
but you question whether
or not people are evil.
Oh,
well tell,
I mean,
yeah,
I guess I can't,
I'd like to question that
and things that I can un un,
you know,
things that I can get with.
I'm sure that game of Thrones
addresses these deeper issues.
If I were to be able to get
past all the names and the,
you know,
the fantasies and the,
the nonsense nonsense.
Winter lasts 10 years.
Don't know how many years.
Maybe it's because I
didn't have a childhood.
I can't get into fantasy childhood.
I mean I was just always like the,
the mom,
you know what I mean?
So maybe I can't like,
well I was the oldest,
oldest sisters,
so I like took care of my
brothers and my parents,
you know,
it was like not a fun childhood.
So maybe like I don't feel
like my imagination or my
ability to lose myself in
fantasy has been like,
it's been stunted or something where
your parents not paying attention or they
just needed your help.
I mean they were just working.
And so then I was like the,
the mom
siblings,
like five years old,
five years old.
So you were the one who's kind of
responsible for keeping them kind of,
I guess.
I mean,
it wasn't a terrible childhood,
but just wasn't fun.
I was just like looking at the clock,
like let's wrap this up.
Constant babysitter.
Yeah.
Like cooking and cleaning
and like getting in trouble.
Like,
you know,
well like not being,
yeah,
like being grounded.
I was grounded a lot,
climbing out the window,
trying to get some action.
And again,
I'd be juicing,
you know,
and need to get fucked.
Climb out a window.
Fuck some dude
climbed back in.
I mean,
I think everyone had a
bad childhood though.
Pretty much anyone funny.
Yeah.
Like I remember listening to some
Deepak Chopra thing and he was like,
imagine yourself as a child
by the beach with your family.
And it was just like one of the,
one of the good times in your life.
And I was like,
oh,
like to some people,
like their childhood was this dreamland
of like where they're safe and
beautiful.
And everything,
you know?
And I find that people like that,
that have these ideas of like childhood,
they're the rare ones.
Yeah,
it's a gift.
I mean,
I,
I'll help if I have a child,
I'm sure your children
have this experience.
I'm sure when your children grow up,
they're going to be like,
remember when they took us to
this amazing forest or that,
you know,
I'm sure you take your kids
to like beautiful places,
right?
Where they have experiences,
jog,
worry about that.
Well,
they're coming,
they're coming along great so far.
But I worry that that might like,
they're not encountering any adversity,
like really well.
I mean they are,
I guess socially at school
there's always like,
you know,
Debbie's a mean bitch and
she doesn't say bitch,
but you know,
there's,
there's that kind of shit.
No.
When we have trauma with kids,
two daughters.
Yeah.
My friend has two daughters and one is
really good at the piano and one can't
play it.
And she's,
and I was saying how good the one was.
She goes,
you need to say the
other one's just as good.
And I was like,
but she's not as,
I mean I didn't say this,
but it was like,
wait,
well one of them has talent
and one of them doesn't it.
We tell all the kids,
they all have the same amount of talent.
Like I specifically remember
an art teacher telling me
maybe art isn't my thing
and it made me try harder
and be more of an artist.
She'd get fired.
No,
I know.
But it helped.
It helped create like drive in me.
Well that's done a good way to do it.
Why I'm successful.
I've worked with you.
But it is an unusual set of circumstances.
You were independent,
you were already,
you had a lot of responsibility.
You realized you had to kind of
pull yourself up by your bootstraps.
So when presented with
criticism like that,
you kind of responded like,
Oh yeah,
I'll fucking show you bitch.
And then you went out and got good at art.
Whereas some people just
would get really discouraged.
Whereas someone could come along and say,
you could be good at art,
but this is what you're
going to have to do.
If you really want to be good at it.
And they could recognize that and then
move forward in a positive way that might
work on it would work on more people,
would work on more people.
But see it's like the things that work on.
Some people don't work on other people.
I had a shitty art teacher and a,
I was really good artist when I was a
kid and my art teacher in high school,
it's just so negative.
They're jealous sometimes or a lot
of them are jealous of youth and also
natural.
Yeah.
My guy was not very talented.
Like he,
he would draw,
he would draw things like in class,
you know,
like we would all work on stuff
and he would work on stuff.
And I remember looking at him,
there's this kid in my class,
I always wondered what happened to
him cause he was the most talented.
He was more talented than me as kidney.
I think his name was John Devor and I
always hope that he had gone to become a
famous artist,
but I'd never heard of him
should probably look them up.
But um,
it was him that I always
admired and it was this kid,
Kevin,
who's in this class was really good too.
And then I felt like it was
like the third most talented,
but we were all,
it wasn't bad,
but I was pretty good.
I drew,
I was like in the comic book stuff,
but we were all better than the teacher
and I'm not bullshitting.
I'm,
I'm being totally honest.
Public school teacher for art.
I mean,
that's like,
it seems like that'd be a pretty,
I think either of us could
go get that job right now.
Well,
I stopped when I was 15 or 16.
I think it was the last,
uh,
like my parents were really freaked out
by it too because I didn't want to take
art anymore.
I was like,
I don't want to do it anymore.
I kept drawing on my own,
but I completely stopped
taking art classes.
Like this guy,
just a fucking idiot.
It just,
the classes were just,
it was tedious and the energy was like,
he was just a really,
he was probably depressed,
you know?
I mean he had a pot belly.
I remember he had this like gut,
it was a depressing gut.
Like,
you know,
it's probably a drinking gut,
they like portrayed like they
don't belong on the person.
It says gross.
Yeah.
Well he just said no energy and no life.
And if you had life in you,
he wanted to squash it.
He wanted to throw a wet blankets on
whatever fire you had inside of you.
This is who is really weird.
Like I talked to the
other two guys about it.
I remember specifically like this guy and
the Guy John who was the most talented
guy.
I was like,
hmm.
That was his attitude
is like fuck this guy.
Who Cares?
He just,
you know,
kinda like raises,
eyebrows,
whatever.
So do you worry that your children will
encounter people like that at school?
Yeah,
I'm sure they will.
You know,
and I think that there's a,
I think as you're growing older you
run into like a database of people,
you know,
you run it,
you have like a whole gamut
of wide spectrum and along
that way you kind of get
to,
you learn lessons from
the negative ones too.
You learn like how never to talk
to other people because you,
you talked to someone talks to you
in a way that like affects you.
I can remember it like negative things
that people said to me when I was a
little kid that stuck with me that I
remember thinking I'll never talked to a
little kid like this.
I'll never say that kind
of shit to a little kid.
Yeah.
And even as an adult,
I remember I was,
I was in college and my friend,
I wanted to be an actress so bad and my
friends that me down this guy and he was
like,
I have to talk to you.
And I was like,
yeah,
this happened to me a
couple times with men.
He was like,
I just don't think you're going
to be as successful as you want.
And I think you need to think about that.
A guy sent out to the guy you were dating.
He,
no,
just a friend and then somewhat
another guy dating's a bit.
So I was like,
I would never tell someone that I
would never sit someone down and say,
I'm afraid of your dreams
aren't going to happen.
Can you imagine saying that to someone?
No,
I couldn't.
But I can imagine why a
guy would say that to you.
And the reason why probably is like
you're very independent and strong.
Like you're very smart.
And I think that's
intimidating to a lot of guys.
A lot of guys need a girl that needs them.
And if a guy is around a girl and the
girl seems like she could be fine without
you,
like,
you know,
like there's a little too much,
too much power in this one.
I must,
I'm a SAP it.
Oh,
interesting.
Yeah.
I think I even think of that men do that.
Other men too,
men do that to other men,
you know?
Uh,
you know,
in the open mic days,
I remember there was a lot of that,
there was a lot of guys telling other
guys they weren't gonna make it or tell
him.
And like David Taylor,
oh,
he's about,
he was always battle with that,
but it's just an,
you know,
it was Dave.
I think he's just,
you know,
he's shown work through his own stuff leg.
A lot of folks are,
you know,
it's like working through your own stuff
at the expense of other people is a
sport that's,
I can see if I could diminish this person,
but men do it a lot to women.
I think some women do it to men too.
You know,
some women will try to convince a
guy to get a regular job because,
uh,
it was never going to,
it's never going to make,
you know,
look,
I'm not going to make it.
Well,
that's,
you see,
you're,
you're independent.
You raised your sister,
your brothers,
you know,
you,
you had to do your own thing.
Childhood was a drag and you're like,
get me the fuck away
from all these people.
I got this right.
That's your attitude,
you know,
and you're like,
I'm going to be a fucking comedian.
And now they're like,
listen,
Natasha,
I think you need to come to grips with
reality that that might not happen.
Okay.
I take it,
I took an acting class once
and it was really gross.
I had to take it because a,
I got a development deal.
I had this crazy development deal with
Disney and they were writing a Sitcom and
I had zero acting experience.
I was 25.
Right.
So,
uh,
it's like all of a sudden I have this
whole fucking thing handed to me.
It's just completely ridiculous.
And they give me this acting
coach and this lady's so naked,
she's so negative and
she's fat and she's tired.
And,
and one of the things she
asked is if the show goes,
she,
she wants me to have
them pitch her as my mom.
She's like,
if this show,
if this show goes,
I want you to pitch them
that I could play your mom.
And I remember being like,
what?
Like she was terrible.
Like we would,
we would have read and when
we'd read she'd be like,
so fake,
you know,
like when you don't like,
you learn as a comic that if you're,
if you're saying something that
someone doesn't connect with,
the shit does,
it doesn't work.
You know?
So like when you're doing,
when you're reading something like you,
you've got to try to make that thing
as real as this conversation is.
And she was not like that.
She was like,
Natasha,
I'm telling you right now,
this is not going to work.
Like,
you know,
it was just like so corny and clunky.
And for the Disney channel it was free.
He was actually for Fox.
It was for Fox,
but it was,
Disney had the development deal.
So,
um,
she one day she said to me,
she like during the,
uh,
she goes,
I'm worried that you're going to go
out there and you're going to fail.
That's what she said to me.
And I go,
why are you worried about that?
Cause I'm not worried about that.
I go,
I'm not worried about that at all.
Let's just do this.
And like,
I like turned around the class,
you know,
I go,
look,
I'm not worried about this at all,
that much strength at 25 to say
that I would've started balling.
I came from a different world.
I came from the world of fighting,
you know,
so I had been competing in martial
arts tournaments my whole life.
So like this lady telling me
that I'm gonna fail at what?
Acting what?
I'm going to freak out
when they say action,
the fuck Outta here,
bitch.
The whole thing was so ridiculous to me,
but it was so obvious to me that she was
trying to intimidate me and it was that
she didn't like that it was too confident.
She didn't like that I was cocky.
It was bothering her.
It's like,
I'm worried you're going to go
out there and you're gonna fail.
I'm like,
acting
this shit that I'm already better at you.
Better at than you.
It's ridiculous and I'm not even good
at it and you're fucking teaching it.
I'm terrible at it and I'm better
than you and you teach it so fuck off.
But it was,
it was a clear feeling that
she was trying to diminish me.
And I remember thinking,
Oh this is scary.
I was scared if I had kids
that that was going to happen.
The champ,
what you,
it's like you would maybe be scared
because you didn't have a lot of time with
your parents.
We,
they were encouraging you and helping you.
I'm around my kids all the time.
You are.
Yeah.
I spend like I spend full days,
like every Tuesdays,
daddy daughter day we do.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Dunkin said ones and I
thought this was so smart.
He said the best Karma you can have
as being born into a good family.
Yeah.
And I thought that was like really
interesting cause it's like that is just a
lucky,
lucky person because you're
going to get all of the,
you know,
your kids are like my friend
Ricky and I figured this out.
It's like your kids are like
a second generation success.
Like you did it yourself and
now your kids are benefiting.
You know,
they're at the level that
like Lena Dunham's going to,
you know,
like her parents were successful
and got themselves out of it.
And you know,
like you see these people who like you're
the first generation of someone who,
who climbed out of the mud or
you're like the fourth generation,
like your grandma was working for
civil rights and then your parents were
successful artists and
then now you're an artist.
It's like it does a generation thing where
I think you'd benefit and you can get
success earlier.
Yeah,
maybe.
But I think it's also difficult
because they didn't earn it themselves.
Like I have a friend and his parents were
very successful and he worked for his
family business for awhile,
but he,
it always bothered him even
though he was doing well.
He's like,
I didn't earn any of this.
Like this is kind of freaks me out.
Yeah.
But look it,
I mean,
there's so many famous people who have
kids who are losers and it does take
something,
I mean,
well I think with them it's neglect,
but they just might not have the drive
or the ambition or a little bit of that.
But it's a lot of like,
if it's,
a lot of it happens with actors.
Yeah.
Because they're working and
they go away from more to the,
yes,
yes.
I think,
I think there's a lot of actors that are
like really fucking self obsessed and n
singers and it's celebrities
where they're just,
you know,
if you're going to be fucking
share or something like that,
like,
yeah,
good luck taking vacations.
Good luck having fun with your kids.
Like you're,
you're,
you're the CEO of an empire that is,
you know,
whoever the fuck you are,
fill in the blank with whatever superstar.
That dive requires everything you have.
No,
I knew someone who knew like Barbara
Streisand son and he wouldn't,
you know,
he had,
he had hit,
he'd have a play and she
would wouldn't show up.
And you know,
it's like how,
but I'm sure you can
make it happen somehow.
All
right.
Yeah.
I mean it's requires a
lot of communication.
You know,
I have a stepdaughter,
the 18.
Really?
Yeah.
I've been with her for
since she was little.
That's so funny.
You have all daughters.
It is funny because
you're so like masculine,
you know,
that happens a lot.
A lot of fighters have um,
uh,
daughters.
It's like really,
really common.
I liked that you consider
yourself a fighter.
My dog.
Do you feel like you're a
comedian more than a fighter?
No.
I'm a human being I think,
but I do a lot of different stuff,
but I'm just saying a lot of UFC fighters,
a lot of them have daughters.
Like it's like,
like they joke around about it,
let it,
it's like a fighter's curse that a lot
of them have daughters for some reason.
Your blessing,
they don't go into that bloody fields.
Wretched.
I think it's a balance thing.
I think the universe gives
you like this gift of,
of a different type of human being neurons
and also the different perspective.
Raising daughters to me has been very,
very educational because a,
raising them and being
around them all the time,
you kind of,
you understand first of all that you're
dealing with a completely different kind
of human being.
Whereas,
yeah,
we were so when I was a kid,
daughters or girls rather,
we're always like,
it was us and them.
It was like boys.
And then there was girls and
now I don't know what the fuck,
what are they wearing?
Makeup and shoes and weird shit.
I fucking gets it.
You know,
you didn't get it.
I mean,
I had a sister but I didn't,
I didn't understand them
the way I understand them.
Like having a wife and having daughters,
like I kind of,
I'm way a way more tuned in to that style
of human being than I was when I was a
young man.
That style of humor.
Well that's what it is.
It's a different kind of human being.
You know,
you're a different kind
of human being than me.
You know,
I don't like make 'em ups.
I don't like blood might come up unique
in your own feminine and an eight,
but a woman is a different kind of human.
It takes a long time to sort of figure
out the ins and the outs of that.
I think it's probably really difficult
for you to understand what goes on in a
man's mind.
Just like it's really difficult for
a man to understand what goes on in a
woman's mind.
And when you see it from
the time they're infants,
when the time when they
were little babies,
it gives you more insight than
growing up with your sister.
You know,
growing up with my sister,
I of I love my sister,
she's awesome and I love her to death,
but she's my sister,
you know,
she's not like a baby that I saw grow.
And so like raising daughters has
been insanely educational for me.
You know,
and you care about them so much.
It's a weird thing.
You care about them that
you don't care about them.
Like you love them,
you care about them like you love
them more than you love your own life.
It's real weird.
Love your two hours,
but if I did,
yes.
Yeah.
My,
my friend Eddie,
he had rabbits and I'm
different than it to Allah.
Well,
yes,
I guess,
but he had cats and he
loves these animals.
He loves the shit out of him.
And his wife was pregnant and I said,
listen dude,
once your baby's born,
you're going to want to kill
those fucking cats transfer.
We just shoot.
He's like,
no way,
man.
No Way.
I'm telling you,
you're not going to give a fuck
about those animals anymore.
You're going to love your kid so much.
You're going to laugh at the idea
of how much you love these animals.
I mean,
you're not really gonna kill the animals,
but is that true?
Yes.
Yeah.
You're the,
the dose shift is substantial.
The level of love.
Like you could leave your kid
in the Kennel for a weekend,
right?
Yeah.
I mean,
your dog,
you could leave your dog
in a Kennel for a weekend,
go somewhere.
You can't leave.
Your kid cannot.
You can't leave your kid for an hour.
You freak out.
It's weird.
It's a weird feeling,
consistent thing.
They give back,
you know,
like they're cute,
they lay with you,
but they don't really talk.
They don't grow.
It's just kind of like they just do their
thing for 12 years and then they die.
They don't have questions like,
uh,
my three year old,
well she's a,
she's five now,
but when she turned three,
she started crying and I go,
what's manner?
She goes,
I'm still litter.
And I go,
did you think that when you turn
three that you would be bigger?
She goes,
yeah,
I go,
no,
it's a gradual cause she's the
youngest is going to get tall talk.
Like all of a sudden she'd be bigger.
Oh,
I mean it's like that kind of
thinking like mind expanding too.
Yeah.
It's fascinating.
It's unbelievably fascinating.
It's,
it's like,
you know,
I really like,
it's not a chore.
Like if I had a babysit someone's kid,
it would be kind of a chore.
But hanging out with my
kids is not a chore at all.
It's like I love it.
It's really fun.
Like it doesn't seem like something like
a man would love to do is hang out with
little girls.
But I love how,
you know,
we play all kinds of silly
games and we played kitchen,
they have like little fake kitchen shit
and they make me fake food and pretend
to eat it.
And we joke around about stuff.
It's very a very different
way of living life.
You discipline them.
I don't discipline the
like I don't beat them.
Is that what you're asking me,
Bill?
I'm just wondering like how,
yeah,
like how do they get dive and when you
have to explain to them when they're
doing the wrong.
Yeah.
Well that's,
I mean that's sort of educational.
I mean,
when they do something wrong,
you have to explain
that they can't do that.
But you have to do it in one of the things
that I always do is I always let them
know that any,
any fuck up that they've had,
any mistake they make,
I've already done it.
I've already fucked up.
I fucked up way more than you.
Like if there's a fuck no,
I try not to.
I swear every now and then,
but most of the time now.
One time,
one time when my,
uh,
my daughter was three,
two,
I've been taking them skins.
It's a really little,
when she was three we were at the ski
place and she forgot to pack her helmet
and her suitcase and a,
you know,
we're,
we're getting ready to leave.
And uh,
I go,
oh,
we didn't pack her helmet
and she looks at her luggage.
She goes,
shit,
everyone laughs.
No,
my wife turned and looked at me like,
oh no,
like don't say anything.
Cause if you laughed and they think it's
right and then we'll keep doing it.
That's it.
Sarah Silverman said in her book that she,
she would get so much positive energy
when she would swear that does created a
comedian.
But see that created a
comedian in a lot of ways.
Yeah.
I mean,
so it's interesting
what's going to happen.
I mean I'm,
I'm sure you're doing an
amazing job with your kids,
but from what I've seen with my friends,
there's so much positive encouragement
happening in this generation where it's
like I was talking to my friends kids
and I was talking about New York.
She goes,
can you not,
can you not say anything
negative about New York?
I really want them to think of it as
a vibrant city and like every bar,
every single thing and like I was like
swimming with her and she's like make
sure she does the breast
stroke the right way.
I don't want her learning
the wrong way and it's just,
I mean this might be an extreme example,
but at the same time I think like wow,
like this is just,
and then those kids are going to
give birth to Cyborg or those people.
What is your kit?
What is your three year old or five
year olds child going to be like,
yeah,
they're going to have
implants in their brains.
Well I think that's
going to happen already.
Have you seen that implant
that they came out with?
They won't even know life though.
Like how we know that they won't,
I mean even kids that are teenagers today
don't know life the way we know live
because we grew up without the internet.
I mean I used to check my
internet at the video store,
my email at the video
store when I moved to La.
I like didn't want to get a cell phone.
I'd go to the video store.
How come you didn't want to,
well it was like 12 years ago.
Cause I've always been
kind of anti technology.
I've never wanted TVs around me.
Oops.
I'll make them up.
I like,
I mean I'm,
you know,
I,
I like,
uh,
I like re I used to like reading more and
they have this new lens that they're
going to insert into people's eyes.
It'll give you three
times the vision of 2020.
It's insane.
What does that seem at gym?
You can't see far away.
You're going to be able
to see in like way clear,
way further,
way more detail than any human being can,
right?
Way.
But what does that
do by the way?
Cause everyone's like HD.
It's so great.
And it makes women look like shit
or men.
But like,
what's it gonna do for our skin?
Is that going to make
us look less attractive?
That's what I wonder.
Yes.
We'll,
we'll,
we'll just tell him that.
We'll,
we'll only meet and then I'll
look at my husband's pores.
Are you scared of pores?
No,
but I just mean like,
you know what,
they're,
you know what there's going to be,
I bet like little cartoon
mascot or something that we
could put on our faces so
that you can't even age.
Right?
Like instead of,
uh,
instead of like makeup,
you'll just wear a mask.
Maybe while there was another study
recently that they've found a way to like
reverse aging in certain cells.
This is the,
uh,
optometrist claims to invent
Lens three times better than 20,
20 vision.
I wonder what it looks
like in that though.
Yeah.
Who the fuck knows devices called a
[inaudible] met ticks argument ex bionic
Lens.
He claimed it allows you to
see three times better than 20,
20 vision without wearing
contacts or glasses at all.
So they think that like macular
degeneration is a thing of the past.
In about 10 seconds,
a lens unravels over your eye and
your site is immediately corrected.
Well,
I understand that if
you've got bad eyesight,
just putting that
in to like try to be a super,
super hero.
This is what it's going to be implanted
in your honor during an eight minute
painless procedure similar
to Cadillac cataract surgery.
It's folded like a Taco and placed in the
eye using a syringe filled with céline
solution.
Wow.
But here's the thing
that's going to happen.
There's going to be an anti technology
movement and then there's going to be the
people who want to do this and then was
going to be the people who are like,
like,
already,
I see it in New York.
They're like advertising at
these like cool hipster bars.
Like no TV in here.
You know,
like it's like people want to go to these
havens of like just socializing with
people and,
and,
and eating farm to table and,
and you know,
like there's all these like farm movements
and I think there's going to be this
kind of,
uh,
hopefully like a new sixties that's like
another hippie movement against all of
this technology or a lot of that,
I'm going to start it,
you'll be a part of it,
but there's a lot of bars and restaurants
are into like metal and wood and it
makes it look like real
rustic click all the like,
like the tables like this table,
you know,
like brick walls,
like people into like real things as
opposed to like plastics and you know,
and,
and shiny like,
like different colored lights like
the inside of a virgin mobile plain,
you know?
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
It's like that,
but some people are super into that way.
Like people just want it like they want,
they cannot wait like someone
like red band or like someone,
you know,
it's like he probably like,
I feel like every technology he's like
absorbing and trying and I mean there's
like that extreme kind of person,
but looking at him it's a mess.
That's why I picked him.
No,
I'm just kidding.
But he's funny and silly.
Yeah,
no,
he's great.
He's at the cutting edge of technology
and there's a lot of people like that.
They get inspired by it,
whereas like,
well I'm on like that and a
lot of ways I love technology.
Yeah.
Most people around me are like that.
I just find human innovation fascinating.
I think the idea of human innovation,
I just think it's a,
it's a,
an unstoppable process I think.
I think unless we get wiped out,
unless something horrible
happens to the human race,
it's inevitable.
We're just going to continue to innovate.
And I,
you know,
I extrapolated,
I take it like really far.
I think about it all the time.
Like what exactly is happening?
I think we are giving birth
to a new type of life.
We are.
But here's the thing,
I was just reading this really interesting
article in the week and they were
saying innovation has stopped in the
sense of like they used to be like more
money put towards cancer research
and going to space and now everyone,
the only innovations that are
happening are with the phone.
It's all about the phone.
It's,
but it,
it is in a way like all we
care about is our phones and,
and how fast they're moving and what they
can get us in the gps and what they're
going to project into our
brains and into our lives.
And I feel like
it's an intimate attachment for sure.
But it's absolutely not true
that that's the only innovation.
Have you seen oculus rift?
It still has to do.
Yes,
I've had,
I've tried it.
It's amazing.
But it still has to do with like,
it's like a video game basically.
Right.
But that has nothing
to do with your phone.
Well,
it's,
it's a part,
it's part of that realm.
Well that's the realm
of artificial reality.
Simulated reality is the future.
But what about curing cancer?
And there's lots of
work being done on that.
A lot of innovation being
done on curing cancer,
a lot of innovation on
all sorts of diseases.
I mean medical innovation has
probably never been higher.
I think throughout the,
the,
the full range of things that
people are interested in,
innovation is accelerating.
I just don't agree with that at all.
And people are always looking to get
negative and poo poo and try to define
where things are growing and not growing
because it makes them look like they're
smart for pointing it out.
But I don't buy it.
I think it's a human characteristic of
a human trait that's inherent to the
monkey mind that they want
to figure things out and
they build on all the things
that have been figured out before them.
And it's inevitable.
It just continues and
goes and moves forward.
I mean,
um,
I have this guy in Aubrey
de Grey recently who uh,
is,
um,
is life extension,
guy from,
he was originally and where was he?
It's Columbia and now he's a,
now he runs this separate or Oxford
when one of his major university.
But now he runs this,
um,
this organization that is dedicated to
finding the best and brightest minds that
are involved in life extension
technologies and the way genes expressed
themselves.
I mean there's loser,
all sorts of crazy work
that's being done right now.
And artificial intelligence is
funding that different people.
I mean they're,
they're,
they're actively trying to recruit people,
um,
to,
to donate money.
I mean,
that's one of the reasons why I
came on this podcast to promote his,
uh,
his cause and try to get
people to donate money to this
warrant.
These things.
I and I,
you might know more about
this than I do warrant these,
didn't these things used to
be funded by institutions?
Like wasn't apple funded by
some college like college?
No,
apple was a private institution.
I mean,
I'm sure they've probably
gotten some money,
probably gotten some
money from some people,
but no,
it's a privately funded institution.
But you know what,
there's,
there's a lot of money
in the private sector.
Like that's one of the criticisms
about like the space program,
like space program has kind of fallen off
because the government doesn't want to
fund it.
So then Elon Musk comes wrong and this
space x thing and there's all sorts of,
there was something that just came out
today about a Elon Musk and space x space
x is,
I don't know.
Well they're trying to develop a
privately funded space exploration.
Whoa.
Yeah.
And the idea being is that you look at
all the innovation that's gone in this
country,
whether it's the invention of airplanes,
you know the,
that was another thing they mentioned.
They said airplanes.
He used to be able to go in three
hours and then what happened to that?
That was 25 years ago.
Why haven't we,
why haven't we built on that technology?
What do you mean like supersonic,
the Concorde did
not go to like in three hours you could
be in New York or rich people died.
People were dying from that.
Oh yeah.
That's one of the reasons it shutdown
and really rich people fucking gut got
toasted on the runway,
but they didn't continue.
The innovation.
I would love to get somewhere in two
hours and not have to have it take to get
to Rome.
It's like 18 hours.
It's fucking dangerous.
Really.
You're going fast as shit and you're
dealing with the same kind of metals.
I mean,
unless they innovate and come up with
different metals and make things much more
difficult.
Elon Musk,
space x is about to tap ship.
Huge march a new spaceship.
Does that go?
That guy is such a fucking freak.
Imagine being around him.
Who is he?
I don't even understand.
He's like some alien him.
So his is he,
does he come from some Mars?
Mostly Mars.
Like someone like that.
They must come from family money.
Why do you say that?
No,
because he was broke
just a few years back.
Yeah,
they were,
I mean,
he was trying to get funding for space
x at the same time he was working on
Tesla and he was trying to figure out
whether or not he should abandoned one of
the projects.
How,
but so he just did investments.
I don't know.
I'd be talking out my ass,
but uh,
he,
I don't,
I don't believe he came from money.
Did he come from how?
He's not that old.
I think he's like 40 or something.
And so he is so it didn't,
isn't Richard Branson trying to do that?
Yeah.
Virgin.
I mean he's funding a
lot of different things,
but they're,
one of their jets just blew up.
They had one that they were a,
this like prototype that
they were using and a,
it just crashed and people died.
AndW
would you go in one of those?
I'm not going to be an early adopter.
That's for fucking sure.
No,
I mean,
I read and getting to a,
you don't know who wouldn't?
He'll be for the first to try
on the virtual space helmet,
know he'll,
he'll be the first to
get one of the implants,
but I don't,
I don't have any desire
to leave this planet.
I just think that's foolhardy.
He made his money with paypal,
paypal.
Oh,
that's right.
Yeah.
He created paypal part of that.
Wow.
Yeah.
So he's just an innovator.
How old is he?
43.
Yeah.
Oh,
oh 71 71.
There you go.
He's is just a fucking genius.
He's iron man.
He's basically Tony Stark
but not quite as content.
Yeah,
I mean that's funny.
That desire to go to Mars,
they could socket.
Those people are ready.
That's going to happen up
there would be terrible.
I have a whole bit about it in my act.
I don't want to start
spewing out my jokes.
I do like your stuff about aliens and uh,
you know,
life on other planets.
I feel like you always kind of can connect
on these larger topics in a way that
I don't think I've ever
seen anyone do really.
I mean,
have you ever seen people captivate
an audience talking like we're,
you'll have silence for,
uh,
you know,
while you're explaining and everyone's
listening and then it'll end in laughs.
Yeah,
it's really cool.
Well,
thanks.
I mean,
I've never seen anyone do that.
Well,
it's just
things that I'm interested in.
If you're,
if,
if it's not something,
I think,
especially with standup,
you have to really care about
what you're talking about.
It's the number one thing.
And when you start going
through the motions,
like what is sadder,
if anything than an old comic that's been
doing the same material for 15 years.
You know those guys that you'll
occasionally see at the store,
you know they get that 1215 spot and
you'll watch that same act that you've
seen.
Like maybe you saw on MTV half hour
comedy hour 20 years ago or something.
I mean I'm not joking.
There's a lot of those guys,
they just,
and they don't care about
the material anymore.
There's no attachment to it anymore.
This is like
the state does care about
that $16 they're making it.
The companies too
keep doing it because they don't want
to admit they don't do it anymore.
But that happens to a lot of guys.
They just stop.
They just stop being relevant.
They stopped caring and
that's the worst aspect.
But the best aspect of comedy is when
someone is talking about some shit that
they really think about that
really means something to them.
And that's,
that's when the audience connects with it.
Cause I think stand up in some
weird form in some weird way.
It's kind of like a form of mass hypnosis
I think in the operates on the v very
similar level because you know this
like I've seen you on stage when you're
killing,
right?
And when you're killing,
When you're locked in and everyone's
laughing and you're hitting every pause,
right,
and you have air in your,
you're locked in,
everyone's respond.
Those people are thinking
the way you're thinking,
like you're guiding them.
Like,
I've watched you on stage
specifically do this.
Like where are you when
you're complimented.
No,
I'm telling you,
I saw you the other night.
You were at the store you were killing,
but,
but you know what I'm saying?
Like
when you're in that moment,
just thing idea that
they're in now with you.
Yeah.
They agree with you.
Are there in your mind,
well w okay.
The other night when you were at the
store and you were talking about the
Armenian genocide and that
fucking guy in the audience.
Oh right.
Yeah.
He was like,
you'll racist.
It was just an Uber joke.
Yeah.
It was a joke about learning about the
Armenian genocide because she got in an
Uber driver within Armenia and
he was fucking lecturing you.
Exactly.
Yes.
It was funny,
but it was the way he handled it,
the way eat like you led
the whole audience along,
like everybody was with you.
The reason why everybody's with you
is because you were locked in to this
subject who were locked into this idea.
And I knew it was true.
Yeah.
But so yeah,
but you know what I'm saying,
like this isn't,
this isn't anything casual.
This wasn't anything that you
really didn't give a fuck about.
Like in that moment I was with you who
the whole audience was with you or like
locked into your mind.
Like I think that's what,
when someone's killing on stage,
they might,
you might as well be getting
them to quit smoking.
You might as well be getting that audience
to lose weight or just stop beating
their dog or whatever the fuck
you're trying to get hypnotized.
Well,
how do you get into that?
Hit hypnos like how do you,
yeah,
how do you,
cause I didn't Chris rock say
you have to be like part preacher
[inaudible] a little bit.
Well his style is very much preacher.
You know,
Sam Kennison obviously was a
preacher he wasn't running with,
oh,
you didn't know no license plate on his
HBO special said x Rev on his corvette.
That's,
yeah.
And that was his,
you know,
that was his thing.
I wonder if there's tricks for sure.
Ooh,
to lock in to get into that much.
Well,
one thing I think you can
do is really try to feel it.
Like I've,
I've definitely felt how I can
turn around a set where I'm like,
this is going through the motions.
They're not connecting and
it's a long set on the road.
So I'm like,
I have 40 more minutes left.
Ooh.
You know,
so then it's like,
oh well maybe I can in the middle of this,
try to start feeling what I'm
saying for the first time.
I think that can maybe help a little
bit to really like almost like an acting
exercise.
Like,
because sometimes you'll say the words
and you're not even thinking about what
they mean.
You can't do that.
It happened.
I mean two shows on a Saturday,
two shows on a Friday.
It's like I don't even know what's coming
out of my mouth half the time and I
can't tell you how many times
on my second show I'm like,
I'm talking and while I'm
talking I'm looking at people.
I'm looking at people's faces to see if
I've done this joke already in this set
because I,
I'm all over the place and I
don't have an order sometimes.
Right.
So then how can you,
I just can't,
I can't keep track of it.
I always write set lists.
I need to start doing that.
Even if I don't use a set list,
at least I write it out so that,
you know,
if you've like in the board or
like this doesn't go up top,
what I'll fuck around sometimes and
I'll just decided to do my closing bit
first.
But then how do you know the club yet?
So you gotta be careful.
But I just,
I think that at least my style of comedy
is I like to just go with wherever my
brain wants to go.
And if my brain,
like if I'll start talking about something
and something comes up and then my
closing bit is appropriate at that moment.
Yeah.
I just go with it.
And then,
well how are you going to close the show?
I don't,
I close on another bit.
You know the idea is to get a bit that's
so get any bit that's so strong you can
close with it.
And if not all your bits
should be like that.
Yeah.
All your bits should be like to a point
where they aren't always like you got to
build them.
Like there's a lot of like I abandoned
my act in [inaudible] in November because
that's when my new comedy
central special came out.
So I passed November.
Yes.
So all this stuff from November
to now is all completely new.
So pick one of those things to close on a,
at a club,
they're dead.
They're dead to me.
Oh man was pressure.
So one,
one comedy special.
Your crystal.
He is on a second comedy
special this year.
It's too much.
It's too much for me to like keep up with,
well he's the,
he did his last one over a year ago
saying it's Ah,
I'm,
I'm filming mine in three weeks
and some of the jokes are like,
you know,
two years old,
but I'm like so sick of them now.
I'm like,
how am I going to avoid,
I know.
I'm like,
how am I going to find in one week,
nine days?
How am I going to find this energy
to make it feel fresh for my taping?
It's so hard.
No,
I'm not going to smoke pot then.
I'm definitely not going to
know if I've done it before.
That helps you.
Is that,
what are the tricks to
get into that hypnosis?
Yeah.
It gets you in the groove.
It makes me very sensitive,
like almost paranoid.
So you're,
you're of the mind of
doing it before you go,
you go to [inaudible]?
Not after both.
I like both.
I like pot.
I did too.
It works great for my personality.
Yeah.
That's what my therapist said,
cause I was like,
I think I might smoke.
You know,
maybe I shouldn't smoke pot.
And he was like,
no,
you're chill.
It makes you more chill.
It's totally fine.
Like you have the right vibe for it.
Um,
if you enjoy it though,
I just think it's,
it can be tricky.
You can definitely fuck with you.
And if you're one of those people that's
like really impulsive or a really,
uh,
you have addictive tendencies and you
like to do things a little bit too much.
Yeah,
it can be a,
it can be a problem.
Like I know people that do
smoke pot all day every day,
which I don't recommend.
I take big long breaks,
you know.
Can you say breaks?
You mean breaks in the day?
No,
I mean look,
weeks I like to take like a week off,
two weeks off,
and then when I go back to it,
I appreciate it more.
I don't like doing anything all the time.
Like I take,
I'll take breaks off working out,
I'll take breaks off of everything.
I think it's important to take.
I'll take bricks off,
stand up.
Like sometimes I'm like,
I need a fucking week off.
I'm just taking a week off.
I'm not doing shit this week.
I'm not calling in for spots,
I'm not doing shit.
I like to learn about your phone that
has the constant information coming
through.
We need you in this,
that respond emails.
It's just getting like more and more,
more.
I'm notoriously difficult to get ahold of.
Like my manager,
they're always laughing about I'm
the one client that will just,
I'll abandon my phone.
I like think like most people are
constantly calling constantly like,
what's going on with this?
What's going on with that?
I'm the total opposite.
Like they can't even find me.
Like I vanish.
I shut my phone off and I just don't,
I don't respond because I feel like if
you have fuck you money and you don't say
fuck you,
you don't deserve fuck you money.
What are you doing with that money?
Freaking out all the time.
Why don't you just say
fuck you just chill.
Just chill.
Got to get that money.
Yeah.
You got to enjoy the whole process and
part of enjoying the whole process is and
enjoying the whole,
the moment,
like all the moments
like I like doing like a,
we were talking about yoga.
I'm like doing yoga.
I like,
I like to an archery.
I like going and shooting
arrows at targets.
It's,
it's exciting.
It's fun.
I like doing different shit.
That's why I like doing Jujitsu.
That's why I like doing,
I like doing Moitai.
I like doing weird shit.
I like doing things and I think that you
get locked into one thing for too long.
I think it limits you in what limits your,
your point of references limits your mind.
Like there's certain people that
like all they give a fuck about it.
It's like say golf.
That's all they care about.
They're like,
you'll see them like fake golf,
swimming,
swinging during the day.
I don't think as an artist
especially,
I hate golf.
I think it's like a problem.
I think it's the worst aesthetic.
I think it ruins hotels.
I think it's ruins hotels.
It's just like whenever I go to
a hotel that is like golf scent,
like centered around golf,
I don't want to be there.
It's like old white
Republicans walking around.
They all at crusty and they're pastels
and they just seem like they drank too
much in a bad sense of humor.
I just think it's an ugly aesthetic and
it's terrible for the environment to
keep those golf courses green.
It is in California,
in Seattle.
It's really not that big a deal.
Right.
In California.
Yeah.
It's,
it's not cool.
There's still conservative.
I just hate it.
There's a lot of conservative
people that play golf.
It's,
it's a business thing.
A lot of guys who uh,
play golf,
they do a lot of business
meetings on the golf course.
I think it gets them away from women
because they get out there by themselves.
All a bunch of guys,
they drink beer and they talk
shit and they walk balls around.
Cause I think a lot of people are
like massively suppressed by office
environments and they just seek out
any possible way that they can be
themselves.
Yeah.
It's just,
it's a valve.
You know,
for a lot of men?
No,
I,
I was thinking about like,
because I'm so stressed
out about my special,
which I'm taping in a week and I'm like,
all I care about is it being over.
I just want it to be over.
I just want to get over it.
And then I'm like,
as soon as the special is done,
I'm gonna have something
else I have to focus on.
So if my whole life is like,
God,
I hope this is over soon.
It's like that's no way to live.
Yeah.
But the pressure is,
is overwhelming.
Like as a comic,
especially because you're the writer,
the producer,
the creator and the performer.
There's a lot of shit going on when you
get on that stage nine days from now and
do it,
just the weight of your world
is completely on your shoulders.
It's very different than any
other style of performing.
It's different than music
because you have a backup band.
It's different than a sitcom because
there's writers and directors,
there's a lot of shit going on.
You're,
you're responsible for it.
Totally.
And that wears on people.
And a lot of times,
well it wears on people is the way you
look at it and the way you approach it.
And I've been on both sides.
I've been where I felt great and I felt
like really loose and comfortable and
not worried about it at all.
And then I've also been in a place where
I was like really fucking stressed out
about it.
You know I've been,
I've been in both places and I think
a lot of it is my appreciation for the
process.
I think when I appreciate the process
am I look at it the right way,
which have kind of like cultivated over
the last decade or so of my life that
when I really,
really appreciate it then it's all fun.
And even though there's
like pressure and stress,
it's fun and I enjoy it.
Yeah.
When you say process,
what do you mean exactly?
Like just the fact that you've been able
to like think of these jokes and write
them and perform them
and people love them.
Well,
the whole process of creating set,
I mean creating a bit,
you know,
it is cool how it works cause it's
like you'll see this bit and it's like,
wait,
did this really happen to me?
You're like,
wait,
this did happen.
Like this,
this girl is a bitch.
And then I thought of this idea and then
it turned into this and then I added
this to it and then made
it connect with this bit.
It's like,
yeah.
So it is,
it is collaborative and you know,
you're collaborating with your
life to like make these things.
I had a freaky fucking nightmare last
night that I'm just now remembering.
Uh,
and in the nightmare I
woke up in the morning,
take a leak and as I woke
up I woke up like with it,
like I woke up at like five 30.
And what does nightmare in my head,
it was like,
Oh,
weird nightmare where I could not
remember whether or not I had committed a
crime and I was trying to remember
whether or not it was a dream or it was an
actual crime that I had committed
and that was the nightmare.
The nightmare was that I had like I had,
I was really confused.
Like,
did I do something fucked up or is
this bullshit or is this a dream?
And then I woke up and I was like,
wait a minute,
this is a dream that I dreamed that I did.
Something fucked up or I was confused.
It was really weird.
So scary.
Yeah,
it was really weird.
But
I dunno how it relates,
but the idea,
I think one of the ways it relates is
like when you're putting together a bit,
it's almost like it's
not even you doing it.
It's almost like when I'm on stage and um,
and I'm really in the
groove and the these long,
sometimes I'll line like a tag will
come on up fucking nowhere and it's the
perfect tag and then you go,
did I just write that?
Is that mine?
Yeah.
Out of nowhere.
And the only way that works is if you
allow yourself to go into these fucking
weird places while you're on stage.
And he'd go down dark alleys and sometimes
there's no fucking way out and it
doesn't work.
And you've got to,
you got to talk your
way out of that alley.
I'm gonna figure out how to
put it back together again.
That's what I'm talking
like that's the process.
The process is uncertainty.
It's confusion,
it's like,
and then finally a finished thing and
you can only hold on to that finish thing
for,
it's like a sand castle.
Like you build it,
it's beautiful.
But the fucking waters common bitch,
the harvest Carmen.
And you've got to accept that.
And people are like,
I want to turn it into summit and keep
it forever and I want to live in it.
You can't live in it,
you can't live in it,
but you shouldn't be afraid of like,
what if I bring a whole bunch of people
to see you and I loved one of your alien
bits.
And I'm like,
yeah,
wait,
he does this part and then
you're doing all new stuff.
It's like,
why can't you bring a few people?
Like that idea that like nobody wants
anything that has already been released or
recorded.
Everything must be new all the time.
Well,
I don't think everything
needs to be new all the time,
but my stuff has a cycle,
at least from me though.
I do my best work when it has a cycle
because I feel like if I'm working on a,
if I'm doing a an old
bit that's already done.
Um,
nothing wrong with that.
There's nothing wrong with it.
But I feel like at a certain point in
time that's taking away from creating a
new bid,
it's taking away from making a new bit
as good as those old bits and that energy
that I'll put into that old bit.
It's,
you know,
especially if I'm doing it all the
time or even adding new tags to it.
Like I could be adding
new stuff to a new bid.
I could make be making a new bit
as good as one of my old bits.
So that's just
the only way.
The way it's good for me is
if I'm constantly updating.
I give myself like a year
and a half and then I'm done.
I'm moving on like a year and a
half and then I have to film it.
How many specials have you done?
Let me see.
Um,
one,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven.
You're prolific energy.
Eight,
seven or eight.
I'm trying to figure out,
I was watching this documentary
on like folk music and it was,
but someone was saying,
don't laugh.
Fuck.
She's hilarious.
I mean hundreds isn't that far from folk?
Um,
yes he is.
I mean he's rock and roll,
but like he came from that
era of like hippies anyway.
Hmm.
Yeah,
he definitely came from the hippie.
Some like,
you know why?
Cause he likes white buzzy.
That's what was up with that.
There's only one way.
You got to find the hippies.
I mean,
he has like,
he has a whole album of like low key.
No,
he definitely will catch on the sand.
It's not all like electronic
or electric insanity.
No,
you're definitely right.
But anyway,
so I'm watching this documentary and it
was some folk artists was saying like,
your first albums,
you know,
easy,
but your second album,
that's how they can tell you're made
up because your first album is like 10
years of struggle.
This is what I've had to save for the
last decade and now it's finally coming
out.
Whereas like,
it's a hit your second album,
here's a year,
here's what I can come up with.
You know,
it's,
it's not as,
it's like it's,
it's just harder.
Yeah.
My first CD I did was in 1999
and I started comedy and 88.
Right.
So that's like a mall.
Yeah.
So much of you that you've been,
you know,
my next one a year later.
And that was kind of weird.
And it's also hard to
stay funny a year later.
Did,
was it just as good?
Yeah.
Um,
I don't know.
I'm not sure.
I think they all suck now,
you know,
and I go back and listen
to my old stuff like eight.
It really?
Yeah.
I can't listen to my old stuff
until about 2006 like shiny,
happy Jihad.
That was my 2006 comedy central
special or comedy central.
A CD.
I still like that.
Is that around the Rem
Shiny Happy People time?
Um,
no.
Our,
that was earlier than that shiny
happy Jihad was right around.
It was after September 11th.
There was a couple of years later there's
the suicide bomber talk and I had all
this Islamic radical material about
them blowing themselves up per pussy and
another dimension.
It was a political comedian.
Not really,
no,
not really political at all,
but I think it's a,
it's a bad hustle like to to,
to like,
like I have friends that are Democrats.
They'll talk about like,
we,
they'll say like,
you know,
we got to win this election
because we w w what?
What is this?
What the fuck are you talking about?
What does this we shit white man,
you know,
it doesn't make any sense to me.
Like,
I think the p the politics in
this country are so corrupt.
It's so stupid.
It's so unfixable.
Oh,
what about the uh,
oh,
you're going to claim
you have to play that.
We'll wait.
We'll do it right now.
I don't believe in pilot.
I mean I don't believe
in Republican Democrat.
I made it seem silly.
I would say that I,
I would rather vote for a female
criminal than a male criminal.
So I would probably vote for Hillary.
Really?
Was that it?
Just because I think that women,
uh,
I would like women have power.
Why is that?
Why?
Because I'm a woman and I feel like,
you know,
we still can't get abortions.
Like all these new abortion
restrictions have just been introduced,
are brand new that are
in effect in November.
And I just feel like this has already
been taken care of and the men are
bringing it back up and it's,
it's just a way to bringing that back
up to unfortunately really just thing.
Yeah,
there's a lot of,
I mean,
you go to this pro choice child,
I just don't even understand.
Well now Spartan Munich.
Okay,
well,
whatever,
like the embryo is the
second the sperm hits me,
it's like I just don't understand how
that is a life that we need to worry
about.
Well,
no,
I may mean I completely agree with you.
It does not make any sense.
And it's in my body.
Yeah.
So it's like if it was in a man's
body it would be totally different.
I think.
Yeah.
I have a joke about that.
You,
me,
uh,
if babies came out of dude's Dicks,
there'd be four people on the planet and
abortion would be an APP on your phone.
Right,
right.
Probably would be right.
I think that's political
without being like,
we don't really,
we republicans,
you know,
well,
it's just the nature of what it
is is people worried about babies.
Right.
And then like worried about life and
worried about like the religious idea of
procreating and
yeah.
But as soon as it comes out of our bodies,
they can like pay at minimum wage or take
away it's health insurance or send it
off to war.
It's like they just care
about it as an embryo.
It's,
it makes no sense.
And the fact that that women have to
wait 72 hours to have an abortion in
Oklahoma now and zero hours to buy a gun.
And the fact that like women have
to go to a across the state lines,
well there's a federal thing
for seven days for firearms.
All right,
can't just buy a gun.
It was a federal Sunday.
Seven days versus,
all right,
well that's actually longer,
but still I think there's a,
there's a real problem with anybody
telling someone what they can and can't do
it with their body.
But there's also a real problem
when abortions get later.
Like when you're talking about
like late term abortions,
things get really weird when you're
talking about like four or five,
six months.
Like I know a woman who got
an abortion at six months.
She had a chance to go
to like some secret.
It was in New York.
She had a,
there's very few doctors
that were willing to do it.
Her and her boyfriend
were fighting over it.
They were poor and she was pregnant.
She wanted to keep the baby and I mean
it was like more than five months.
So she wanted to keep it.
He didn't.
Yeah,
but see the thing is giving
birth to a child like that,
in that circumstance,
that is not the kind of child
that you're raising right now.
Right.
Your kid is being infused with love and
attention and positivity and it's like
they're,
they're already fighting
before the kid is like born.
It's like that is not going to be
a positive environment and we're
overpopulated.
No,
you,
you make some good points.
And I think the good point,
the counter to play devil's
advocate would be the,
or God's advocate would be that,
you know,
that kid could go to a happy family
that was looking to adopt and have a
wonderful life.
Maybe a wall or maybe it'll
end up addicted to drugs.
It's like it's not alive yet.
You're right.
Well it's just not,
but it can exist outside the womb
and that's when things get weird.
Late term abortions are really weird.
But she got it.
Yes,
she did.
And she didn't want to get it.
No,
she didn't.
They actually wound up having
kids after that is really weird.
And He loves his kids.
He didn't have kids before then
and then he loves his kids now.
It's very strange.
It's very dark.
It's very,
it's,
but that is the gray area that is life.
You know,
life is weird.
It's not as simple cut and dry.
When people argue one side or the other,
you know,
and especially if they ignore the,
the positives or the negatives
that the other side's presenting.
People love to have absolutes.
They love to have,
I'm right.
You're wrong.
They love to have,
this is the right way.
This is the wrong way.
This is what God wants.
I mean,
I guess that's what I'm
saying that I'm right,
but like I,
I feel like I'm right in the sense that
it's up to people to choose what they
want to do with their
bodies and themselves.
And if they want to get on drugs or
if they want to have an abortion,
like don't make people raise children,
which is probably one of
the hardest things to do.
I've never done it,
but it must be so challenging
and you have money.
I have money.
Like imagine doing it with no money.
It just seems like to force someone to
do that and make it almost impossible for
them to get rid of there when a man has
been the one who like did it to them
anyway,
it just seems crazy to me.
Well,
they did it together.
Hopefully.
No,
I know.
But anyway,
I would rather have a female in charge
because I feel right now if you do not
believe that women are equal to men,
which a lot of a lot of these Middle
Eastern countries don't believe that.
It's like that is,
you're part of the problem
of keeping people back.
Well,
there's certainly should be a
quality when it comes to laws.
Initiative certainly should be a quality
when it comes to the way we treat each
other.
But we also should accept the fact that
we're just fucking completely different,
you know?
And just leave people alone.
Let them do whatever the
fuck they want to do.
And anybody that thinks that a woman
who's pregnant for 40 hours or you find
out,
you know what I'm saying?
You just find out you're pregnant,
you've got pregnant two days ago,
and that you shouldn't
be able to stop that.
Oh,
what are you talking?
Are we talking about
like three cells take?
What are we talking about?
We're talking about a
cluster that fits in that.
The end of this stir mean,
I mean,
well,
there's a lot,
I don't know.
Everyone's specific beliefs.
I just know that a lot of new restrictions
in the New York Times last Sunday,
they had a map full of
all the new restrictions.
And like now in five states you have
to wait 72 hours and 10 more states.
There's two followup visits that
before you can get the abortion.
So you have to start doing counseling.
You know,
you have to go drive two hours
to do counseling appointments.
It's like if you know,
you don't want the baby,
why do you have to go do counseling?
It's just,
I think they're looking at it,
and this is obviously it's gotta be,
there's gotta be a religious perspective.
Yeah,
right.
It has to be,
but I think they're looking at it
and not looking at it like a person.
Like you didn't looking at it,
a person that is lost and confused and
they're going to give them guidance and
that's all the way.
A lot of like really
fundamental religious people,
especially Christians.
And that's the way a
lot of people feel like,
like this person just needs to be taken
in and we just take them into the Lord's
arms and show them what
they're doing is wrong.
You have a baby inside your body,
smells precious,
gift kill you and you were
just killing baby Kale.
What if you,
what if you went around to
everyone you saw and you were like,
you gotta smoke pot.
You got to do Jujitsu,
you got to do everything.
I do.
Just do it.
It'll make you feel better.
Do it,
do it.
You don't stand outside sports
locker or 14 million people a month,
but you don't like passionately feel
that everyone has to do what you know.
It's like it doesn't,
it's like do it for you.
But this the,
yeah.
Well I'm a big believer in let people
do whatever the fuck they want to do as
long as it doesn't hurt anybody else.
And I think you are too.
And I think that the real problem that
people have with abortion as they think
that there's another person involved,
and it's not as simple as like,
I should be able to smoke pot or I
should be able to that think who's,
who's standing up for that
little baby inside of you?
That's why do these people
care about people so much?
It's like that's where it gets weird.
That's compassion for a cluster of cells
that can fit on a fucking coffee star,
but you don't give a fuck about war
war or,
or,
or the minimum wage or making sure that,
that kids get great education.
It's are these people just like donating
all their time and money to help living
people?
It's,
it's,
it's so stupid
bid.
How many of these people
that are anti abortion,
uh,
are pro,
let's go to Baltimore
and clean up the city.
Exactly.
Let's help these people that are in like
really low income environments that are
filled with crime and
let's give them a way out.
Yeah.
It's like,
oh,
these people have such overactive empathy.
They just,
they just want to help everything.
Even the clusters of cells that are
living inside of poor strangers bodies.
It's,
it's,
it's such a stupid way to
direct their religious fervor.
But
isn't it fascinating because isn't
that part of what a person is?
We're just a bundle of contradictions
where it's so hard to be objective and
logical about every single aspect of
your life and that people will sometimes
think that they're doing good and at the
same time promote shit that's terrible
and awful.
You know,
there's a lot of people that are like,
I'm sure that we're like prolife an anti
abortion that didn't give a fuck about
that guy that got shot in Ferguson.
They'd,
right.
You know,
there's,
there's a lot of people that think
that you should execute prisoners,
you know,
for a variety of different things.
They believe in the three strikes law.
You know how easy it would be to commit
three felonies if you lived in Compton.
You know,
if you're born in Englewood
to a fat family filled with
violence and you want to
lock that person up for the rest of
their life by the time you're 18 because
they already have three felonies.
Yeah.
They didn't get the opportunities.
Oh,
that is so fucked up.
But I would love to see a
pro life movement that just
started like really trying
to help re lives that are
already like a functioning,
why not that be the pro life movement?
Yeah.
The real pro life.
Unborn babies in people
who don't want them.
Them's stomachs.
Doms yeah.
The real pro life
movement is like helping
the lives that are,
they're not turn into a murderers
are not turn to a disaster.
Yeah.
I mean we're fucked up.
Are All these republicans
that are running,
do they all believe in abortion
or they all believe that there's
Beano can't get through.
You can't get through
unless you're pro life.
There's no,
Oh really?
You can't get through the maze.
I've never even heard of of a successful
up republican that gets to the end of
the line.
Really the backing and
the religious right.
I mean there might be one that
people could prove me wrong,
but that's pretty much it.
Like Arnold Schwarzenegger or something.
But they'll probably like lip lip,
libertarian,
libertarian.
Yeah.
There's a probably a few rare,
like maybe a that Rand Paul
Guy believes in pro choice.
But yeah,
it's,
it's a religious thing for a lot.
I mean it's,
it,
it happened with Reagan.
I mean that's really,
Reagan was the first Republican to court.
Those like really radical religious
people because they realize back then that
there's a lot of power in that movement.
The political power that you get from
having the Christian right on your side.
You know,
there's so much does the organizing
and the song so much power behind that.
People that are just like,
I don't give a fuck.
Those people don't organize.
Those people don't get together.
The people that don't
like leave people alone,
let them do whatever the
fuck they want to do.
A lot of those folks don't have the,
the drive to get off the couch and go
out and organize and make sure that their
views are expressed
evenly across the board.
But like Pete,
when people get really religious and
they think that God's involved and their
choices,
there's a lot of people that,
especially Christianity,
there is this recruiting aspect to that
religion that you don't see in Buddhism.
You don't see in Judaism,
you don't see really anywhere
but Christianity or maybe
you'd see it in some of
the Middle Eastern religions.
I don't know.
Oh,
Islam doesn't recruit,
but they,
they promote the fact that there's,
they're the perfect religion.
They let people join,
but Judaism's fucking hard to join.
I know you kind of like ask three times,
you've got to like take like
my uncle did it.
Yeah.
My uncle married a Jewish woman and
he had to go through the whole deal.
He had to go to Hebrew school and the
whole animals like why are you doing man?
I liked Judaism.
Why?
Because it's more,
well I was raised Catholic and Judaism
is more open to like intellectual
discourse and asking questions and having
the questions thought about and talked
about and where it's not as like absolute
is like Adam and eve go sit in the
hall.
Like I was always just putting the hallway
for asking questions and this is how
it is.
And it's like,
how could that be how it is?
And then you just get in trouble.
Yeah.
But does it doesn't have to be a religion.
I mean,
isn't open discourse,
isn't that just part of being a curious
human being who's intelligent and I was,
doesn't have to be
attached to an ideology?
Well,
I think that the ideologies can
teach you things like tradition and,
and uh,
you know,
there's beautiful things
and probably all religions.
And I think that the future will be not
just like picking a religion and I'm the
religion that my dad was and
I'm the job that my dad was,
my dad was a cobbler,
Swami McCall blur.
My parents were Catholic,
so I'm a Catholic.
It's such an outmoded,
it's so outdated.
I think as an adult you use sample,
lots of religions and you,
you learn about as many as you can and
you form your own philosophies and pull
from there there for us to pull from,
you know,
they're,
they're all windows onto the same thing.
So it's like why not learn?
I mean I,
I'm,
I want to learn more about Judaism.
I'm dating a Jew,
I want to learn more about Buddhism.
I meditate and do Buddhist chants.
Like I love it all and I think it's like
definitely a positive thing for your
life.
I definitely think that looking into
the ancient traditions and philosophies,
there's the definitely
something to be learned from it.
What I have a problem with is attaching
yourself to any rigid ideology.
Yes.
I grew up Catholic too.
And for a very short period of time,
my parents like didn't,
they stopped me from doing
it when I was in first grade.
Oh really?
While I was in first grade,
I told them I would run away from home.
I'm like,
you send me back to the shit I'm going to,
I'm not doing that.
We're lapsed Catholic.
Oh so bad.
It was just rough.
I W but before that my
parents were getting divorced.
So before first grade I was like,
I was thinking that God was
like the answer to all of this.
Cause I was like really scared
and confused and you know,
there's like so much turmoil going on.
I really thought that
like that was the answer.
Like religion was the answer and uh,
cause I was just terrified.
But then going to Catholic
school cured me of that shit.
Oh,
there were so rude and mean
I had none and grabbed me.
I was,
you know,
what are you doing?
You think you're so cute.
Take those socks off.
Like anytime I try to like it,
like be individual.
Anytime I'd ask a question.
They were assholes.
God doesn't like your socks.
Yeah,
that's a dark.
Religion is a,
it's a very depressing religion,
you know?
Although I did go to the Vatican when
I was in Rome last week and I did
communion,
no,
not communion confession,
because they,
it was like through the rope.
They're like,
do you want to do confession?
I was like,
oh,
well,
yeah,
I'm at the Vatican.
What'd you talk about?
Well,
I just sat down and he asked
me if I believed in Jesus.
And I was like,
oh no.
First he goes,
have you ever made abortion?
Oh,
that's the first thing he asked you.
He goes,
do you have any sense?
And I was like,
well,
what did I say?
I was like,
Oh,
oh,
I,
I told him,
I was like,
not really,
you know,
um,
I don't really believe in this
religion or something like that.
And he's like,
have you ever made abortion?
And I was like,
no.
And he's like,
and I,
and I said,
well,
I do smoke pot and it helps
me with my creativity.
And he was like,
I go,
is that bad?
He's like against say,
I don't know,
like he was kind of seeing
more Jewish actually.
And then I told him I was,
I was going to get married
to a Jew and he's like,
what can you do?
And then he's,
it was pretty cool.
And then he was like,
can you go to,
can you go to mass once a year?
He's like,
I'm sure that,
and then you go to temple once a year.
He's like,
he goes,
what did he say?
He was like,
I think you can handle that.
Wow.
Sounds pretty progressive.
But I think they're trying
to be more like that.
You know,
this is coming from the Vatican.
Right.
And I think that that
was definitely an offset.
An offshoot of that new pope.
He's,
he's dope.
That new pope.
I mean I'm not a fan of popes,
but that guy is like the way
he speaks about gay people,
the way he abandoned
the giant throne love.
And I was Kinda like a regular
chair that he sits down.
He doesn't live in their apartment either.
They have like a gold plated
apartment or something.
He got rid of the pope.
Tmobile too.
He's like a second to shoot me.
They're going to fucking shoot me.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
Everything I read about him,
I'm so inspired.
Bulletproof pope mobile might
shoot me,
but don't shoot me now bitch.
I got shit to do.
I read that thing was so crazy.
This fucking aquarium,
you're driving this paper.
I have to look this up.
I've never seen the pope Moby.
Oh my God.
Oh,
this is what they told me
when I was enrolled in.
They're like,
oh my God,
that is a bulletproof Mercedes.
Funny.
The pope a driver on that thing,
so he didn't get JFK aid.
Well,
they told me when I was in cope
is doing a waving at 11 o'clock
never heard of that before.
I got to get a photo shoot and one of
those things drive around my hometown and
do a waving.
I could see you in there for
like Vanity Fair magazine
driven around La.
Oh my goodness.
God,
there's more than one.
I guess they've,
they've made a few of them over the years.
Always be Mercedes only
the best for pontiff.
Okay,
this is take America back from
Rick Santorum released today.
This is by the way,
this is just the beginning of
this wave of fucking stupid.
It's thinly veiled racism in a lot
of ways because it's taking it back,
taking America back in.
We'll take America back from
these liberals and there's Obama,
Barack Obama saying in a way they didn't
say when Clinton was in office when
they were trying to,
they were trying to elect
a Republican Post Clinton.
They didn't have this sort of
take it back sort of mentality.
This isn't,
and this is weird,
it will play this
unleash
the fried like the prides of pit bull.
This is him singing.
Yes.
I have to think so.
Oh my God.
These lyrics that we're not hearing,
it's like this is for the man work
in the factory making drive train.
This is for the farmer work in the
wheat fields grow in the long grain.
Seems like they're pandering.
It's just like when you get those ads,
like you start looking up a hotel and
then like Google starts giving you those
ads constantly.
It's like they've just done a
demographic search and they're like,
these are the only hope for these people
who are farmers and garbage drove a
garbage truck.
Drivers and like whoever that.
Yeah,
the laborers,
they're like,
this is no smart person will vote for us.
So we must hander in the in
the stupidest possible way.
This is for the preachers,
the teachers.
Here we go,
the blue collar warriors,
warriors,
they're blue collar and they're warrior.
I says,
not for the teachers.
Anyone who's gone to
college would not vote.
This is for believers whose
dreams are on the line.
Oh my God.
Now is this Santorum
actually singing Hampi.
Okay.
Boom.
Gun toting,
prolife homophobic,
former United States senator
will reportedly announced
his run for presidency
today after being edged out by Mitt Romney
in 2012 Rick Santorum is throwing his
hat in the ring.
Once again,
this time the campaign is on point.
Judging by this official Santorum
for president campaign song.
Okay.
Might not be his song.
Hello.
Find out the idea that well,
so the idea that there's like a Bush and
Clinton running again too is so insane.
It's mind boggling.
I mean,
I can't even believe it's a dynasty.
Their,
their,
their royalty that we don't,
we haven't figured,
I mean it's Kinda good that
there's other people trying,
well,
we tried with Obama had didn't
work out so good did it.
I don't even know if it did.
Nobody is a good fucking president.
There's no one has ever done
it where everybody loved them.
Not a single one ever because
the ambition involved,
it just excludes anyone.
Cool.
Especially today.
Right?
With the intrusion,
the amount of privacy,
the investigation into
your past and scrutiny.
I mean,
you can't be a human.
You can't be a human.
You can't have an ex
girlfriend or an ex boyfriend.
He can't have ever
puffed marijuana.
I mean,
I think we'd be great
with a gay president.
I think we need a gay guy or a gay girl.
How about a Lesbos?
Lesbophobic good.
Who would you go like Melissa Etheridge.
She would take this fucking
place in a good direction.
You don't think Hillary would.
A lot of people think
Hillary is in neo-con.
A lot of people think that Hillary,
someone who is in bed with the
military industrial complex,
someone who profits from war,
someone who is not like that.
Well he certainly is.
Uh,
he certainly is a guy who is not
what everybody was hoping for.
Like everybody hopes he's going
to close down Guantanamo Bay,
pull everybody out of the wars,
straighten up America's
inner cities and same ad,
the same brand of person,
aren't they?
Hillary and Obama.
I think everyone that gets into that
office has to be in bed with these
monsters.
Corporations that need to make
a massive amounts of money.
And the way they make massive amounts
of money is they bribe politicians.
They pay massive amounts of money.
Like when the Supreme Court
pass laws that say that the,
these corporations are
allowed to donate money,
like as if they were an individual entity.
Like if you're a person like save Natasha
Gera has $1 million in the bag and
you're like,
fuck it,
I'm donating my million
dollars to Hillary Clinton,
you can do that.
You can donate as much money as you want.
What you used to be
restrictions on corporations,
especially corporations that would
benefit from political influence.
And you know of those,
it's within the,
I think it was during
the Bush administration,
I think it was.
It was either Bush or Obama,
but it's fairly recent that they did that.
And as soon as you do that,
you,
you open the flood gates for corruption
and influence lobbyists like law,
that law,
the idea of,
I became educated about
lobbyists because of the UFC,
because of the UFC,
had to hire a bunch of lobbyists in order
to get mixed martial arts past and all
these different states.
Because when we first started,
it was only legal in a few
states and lot of states,
like right now it's legal in
every state except New York.
And the only reason why it's not legal
in New York is because of corruption.
And it's almost done.
Nope.
No.
And the one of the politicians that kept
it from being legal was just arrested
for corruption.
So it was hilarious when that
guy went down for corruption.
Everybody's like,
Duh.
Like it's the culinary
union is a big part of it,
but there's,
there's a lot of union influence
because long story short,
the UFC is owned by this company
that also owns station casinos.
They own 20 plus casinos and
they're non union casinos and they,
the culinary union wants them to be
union because if they were a union,
they would make some somewhere in the
neighborhood of $15 million a year.
Don't quote me on that.
Uh,
from the dues.
So they're,
they,
they've had this act of smear campaign
against the UFC and they spend a lot of
money.
They try to get the UFC to leverage them,
to get the UFC,
to turn those casinos
and to union casinos.
So there's a lot of fucking
bullshit involved in politics.
And that's the kind of things
they're involved in passing laws.
It's a lot of money,
a lot of influence,
a lot of people bribing people.
So to get to be president,
you'd have to play that fucking game.
And there's not gonna be any
white knights and that game,
there's going to be white or nights,
you know,
like there's going to be darker nights
and wider nights and it's this fine
balance between public acceptance and
public support and the support of the
corporation.
The corporate,
you can't have,
you can't have one without the other.
You got Kinda like walk this fine line.
That's why we keep getting close.
He makes no sense.
Friends.
I don't think it makes a difference.
I mean she's,
she's already been criticized
for being unduly influenced by,
I mean that whole thing with her email.
She deleted all her fucking emails and
she was getting emails from a private
server instead of the,
the way you're supposed
to do it where it's in,
they can easily investigate all of the,
uh,
the transactions that have gone back and
forth or the communications that have
gone back and forth.
I try not to look at it too deeply
because it's so frustrating.
So I can only give you like a cursory
understanding of how the whole system
works.
But at the end of the day it's,
it's money.
I mean it's all about money and
these huge fucking corporations.
The difference between having someone
in then supports them and having someone
in there that's against them as PR,
especially when it comes to environmental
regulations and how difficult they
make it to do things like fracking
and all that kind of shit.
It's billions.
You're talking about billions
and billions of dollars,
so I don't think anybody gets there
unless they play that fucking game.
Then that's why the commission for
presidential debates is a privately funded
institution.
When you see those people debating on TV,
like what does that,
you have to leave
but just you don't have to like
write it down on a piece of paper.
I wish I didn't have to go but I have to.
Let's do it again.
Listen,
you and I have been threatening to do a
podcast forever and we finally did it.
I got here because there
sometimes for hours,
no,
and I was like,
why have it til one does fine,
wine is good.
One is good.
Natasha,
you don't have to worry.
Listen,
let's do more often.
Come back.
I'm so depressed now.
Why?
Because you were thinking to,
Hillary's going to be the
the block Obama for women,
that country Western fuck.
You know what I mean?
How they're just like
purposely just dumbing it down,
dumbing it down for like,
well it's a hustle.
It's like a guy who wants a rape you,
but he shows up with flowers.
He's trying to get you
to think he's a good guy.
Who's the best person to be like,
do you think?
Like if you had to pick a
Bush or a Clinton for comedy,
it would be a Bush,
right?
Yes.
US like we'll have like a
glory day or glory period.
Right?
Comedian.
Yeah.
Like people.
Cause people would want to go out
to the clubs and talk about it.
You know?
I don't think we're,
we're supposed to think that way.
There's plenty of dumb shit going on
in the world without having it be.
Oh,
I'm not saying,
I know.
I'm just,
I'm just thinking.
Yeah.
Here's my hope.
I have a hope.
My hope is that the
Internet is so pervasive.
It's so deeply embedded in everyone's
life and the Internet is all about the
exchange of information and
information is being exchanged.
New Information.
Yes,
and it's
way words Noo
new and not just that,
but facts.
Knowing the reality of climate change of,
of a,
of war,
of profits.
The reality that we have when it comes
to like understanding what's going on in
the world is,
is,
is unprecedented.
It's instantaneous.
You have questions about that.
You can't be lied.
Like you know,
I remember Ronald Reagan on TV lying
about the new studies are coming out that
says that marijuana is one of the most
dangerous trucks ever known that was
going,
he was a liar.
He was lying to people and
because they were paying the lot,
if a politician tried to do that today,
the Internet would fucking explode.
Everyone would go nuts.
It was like,
we remember when Obama wanted to go into
Syria and Obama was saying that we've
got to go into Syria and literally the
entire Internet went fucking crazy.
The entire country was like,
fuck this.
We're involved in two fucking
wars and you want to go to Syria.
What's the big deal about Syria?
What exactly the fuck
is happening in Syria?
You think that what everybody's
done that is going to,
I think the Internet,
what the Internet represents
is the exchange of information.
I don't think the voice of the Internet,
I think it's human beings having the truth
where they've never had it before and
having the ability to express themselves
in a way that they've never had before
and all they would have to do to
change all this shit really change it,
is abandoned.
This fucking antiquated bullshit corrupt
system and have people vote online.
How you could help people.
You have people try make transactions.
You could fucking do your banking online.
I've got apple,
Pam,
I'd phone.
I could buy shit online.
Everyone's doing things online,
but you can't vote online.
That's ridiculous.
The reason being,
if you make it really easy to vote,
then really everybody has a say instead
of having the way they have it now where
it's this,
you know,
you have the electoral college
and you don't really vote.
You vote for a representative and that
representative represents your state or
your district.
It's all cocked bullshit.
It's nonsense.
What they need to do is revamp the system
and revamp the system in a way that
reflects the actual will of the people
and that will radically change the world
because the will of the people is
educated now in a way that it's never been
before.
How do we make that happen?
How do we raise money for a
revamping the electoral college?
I think slowly but surely
the system that's in place
is more and more ridiculous
every year
it seems to me.
Look at that song.
Yeah,
that is an actual not SNL sketch.
I mean that's an actual,
you and I are laughing.
Do you know any fucking people
were crying when they heard that?
We do need to take back
America for your portions.
By the way,
I'm not having a lot of abortions.
I'm just saying how many of you out?
Zero.
But I would love to have one if I had,
if I needed to.
I can't wait.
I'll relish.
I'll,
I'll periscope it.
Periscope,
that's another,
another new internet thing.
Getting people closer
and closer to each other.
We live in a weird time.
Natasha.
I'm going to
tweet.
I'm periscoping my abortion.
Intense.
I'm going to periscope you.
You ending this podcast right
now on periscope it right now.
How many more questions,
but we'll,
we'll,
we'll talk next time you have questions.
Well,
no,
I just wanted to get your thoughts on,
you know,
whatever.
There's a lot of things happening.
I'm now,
I'm all amped.
Let's do this again soon,
but we do this again more often.
Yes.
You should have your own podcast too,
by the way.
You Know Dunkin?
I had like the first podcast.
Yes you did.
But why?
It's hard.
What came over to our house and was like,
wait,
so you just like record into the
microphone and release it every week.
The first guest now he's got
a network we created Nerdist.
Yeah,
some sort of the way.
Who's your first guest?
That's hilarious.
That is really fucking hot.
Yeah.
You guys were doing one like one again,
just understood it.
I don't know,
like a long time ago,
maybe seven years ago or something.
It wasn't that long ago.
Six years ago.
It wasn't doing it before.
I was doing it probably.
Wow.
That's crazy.
I know that no one had one.
No one.
I mean,
Chris Hardwick did.
He did,
but he,
his was always more of a radio show,
you know?
Right.
It's still is Natasha [inaudible] raw
people can get you online to Taj Lucero on
Twitter.
What else?
Um,
oh,
uh,
our new show,
another period comes out on
comedy central June 23rd.
It's a,
it's like if the,
it takes place in 1902.
It's like,
imagine if the Kardashians
moved into Downton Abbey.
That's my new show.
And it's a reality show.
It is after Amy Schumer.
I'm so controlling like
a fake reality show.
Okay.
Don't be confused.
Yeah.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you so much.
Thank you for having me.
I love having you on.
Let's do it again.
Alright.
See you soon.
You fucks.
All right.
Are you
bye everyone.
Give me your mind bridge box.
Oh,
we live oh,
rich vos tomorrow.
It should be awesome.
Yeah.