Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Hello,
Jordan Peterson.
Hello.
Mr.
Rogen very spiffy today.
Thank you sir.
If this is a new look for you,
you're,
you've been rocking these,
a lot of these big,
gigantic,
uh,
what do you call those things?
These concerts that you guys are doing?
What do you speeches?
Well,
lectures.
Discussions is what I think of them as.
Yeah,
I'm discussing.
I mean,
you might think it's kind of perverse to
be discussing with a 3000 person
audience,
but it's not because if you pay
attention to the audience,
they're constantly in the individuals in
the audience.
They're constantly providing feedback.
So it's a discussion as far as I'm
concerned.
Feedback in applause.
Laughter.
Sometimes they shout things out to
shuffling.
Shuffling.
Yeah.
Well really what you want.
If you're on track,
if you're where you should be,
then it's dead silent and everyone's
focused and listening.
And so if that's not happening,
I mean,
you know,
there can be laughter and that kind of
thing,
but generally speaking,
you don't want to hear noise from the
audience.
So if you're,
if you're,
if you're pursuing a complicated topic
and you're paying attention and I'm
always looking at individual people in
the audience,
you know,
and the first few rows because that's
all I can see because of the lights and
trying to make sure that everyone's on
track with the talk and you know,
there's people just hear what their face
and they gestured with your eyes and
they shake their head and they nod and
there's lots of things to pick up and if
you're not speaking with notes,
you can really pay attention to the
audience.
And then you know,
if you're in the dialog and that's where
everyone wants to
to be.
Yeah.
It's an interesting thing you're doing
because you have experienced in doing
that with lectures and colleges and
universities.
But now it's the general public and
people just pay to see it and you fill
up these huge gigantic theaters.
I mean,
I've seen some of the places that you
guys are doing it.
Even Sam just got done doing one in
Vancouver and she huge places to,
to back to back.
And he asked.
It was about five hours of
intense discussion over two days and you
know,
we were supposed to talk for an hour
each night and then go to q and a,
but we asked the audience,
Bret Weinstein,
who was moderating,
ask the audience if they wanted to go to
q and a or continue the discussion and
you know,
the response from the crowd was
definitely continued that discussion and
so we ended up talking for about two and
a half hours each night and again it was
the audiences along for the ride,
you know,
and they were good discussions as far as
I'm concerned,
you know,
it was kind of marketed as a take down
in some sense Harris versus Peterson.
But the discussion itself was an attempt
on Sam's part and my part to further our
thinking about the topic and to bring
everyone along for the ride,
you know,
for the journey so to speak.
Yeah.
Well you guys had two podcasts that you
did over the phone,
so this,
these were the first meetings that you
guys hadn't person.
It was the first time I'd met Sam.
He said the first one that you two had
was marred by this discussion about what
is truth and it was a strange sort of a,
okay,
you got stuck.
You guys got kind of stuck in that first
conversation,
but I felt like the second one was much
better.
Yes.
He in both of you,
kind of recognize that there were some
errors made in the first podcast.
Yeah,
we agree on a definition in and let it
go and so that wasn't so good and I
wasn't in tip top shape for that first
discussion while over the second one for
that matter,
but they've been getting.
Each discussion I've had with Sam has
been getting better,
so as far as I'm concerned,
and I think he feels the same way and I
mean we're taught,
we're trying to sort something out
that's really,
really difficult and it's the
relationship between facts and values
which is parallel to the relationship
between say,
objective truth and narrative or
parallel to the distinction between
scientific fact and religious truth.
All of those things sort of are layered
on top of each other and it's an
extraordinarily difficult topic.
And so it's not surprising that it's
taking all of this discussion to even
vaguely get it straight.
It's been a central bone of contention
among philosophers for,
well probably forever,
but certainly since the time of,
of David Hume several hundred years.
Well,
one of the more fascinating things is
coming out of the realm of podcasting is
these kind of discussions,
these long form live discussions in
front of enormous groups of people where
you go over very complex issues.
It's a new thing.
I mean,
and it's a,
it's something that's greatly received
by the public,
which is really interesting.
I mean you guys are selling out all over
the place.
Yeah.
Well one one I've really been trying to
make sense of this say because I'm
thinking,
well,
what the Hell's going on?
Why?
Why am I selling out 3000 person
auditoriums and then,
and then,
but not just me.
Obviously Sam is doing it and you're
doing something on a larger scale,
but very similar with your long form
podcasts and,
and,
and then there's this whole rise of,
of what Barry Weiss described as the
intellectual dark web.
That's actually Eric Weinstein's coinage
and so there's a group of us that have
been sort of clump together for,
for reasons that aren't obvious,
but I've been trying to figure that out
as I do these lectures.
Another thing I'm doing with the
lectures or the discussions is trying to
continually further the development of
my ideas.
I use the,
the,
the stage I'd say as a,
as a,
uh,
opportunity in real time to think.
And I've been thinking,
well,
if you're surfing,
you don't confuse yourself with the
wave,
right?
That that's a real mistake.
He might be on top of the wave,
but you're not the wave.
And I think this long form discussion
and the public hunger for that as best
conceptualized like that,
there's a technological revolution.
It's a deep one.
The technological revolution is online,
video and audio immediately accessible
to everyone all over the world.
And so what that's done is it turned,
it's turned the spoken word into a tool
that has the same reach as the printed
word.
So it's a Gutenberg revolution in the
domain of video and audio and it might
be even deeper than the original
Gutenberg revolution because it isn't
obvious how many people can read,
but lots of people can listen and now it
turns out so he got a little bit of that
with TV,
right?
And you got a little bit of it with
radio,
but there was bandwidth limitations that
were really stringent,
especially in TV where you could get 30
seconds if you were lucky in six
minutes,
if you were stellar too,
to elucidate a complicated argument.
So you can't do that.
Everything gets compressed to,
to,
uh,
kind of oversimplified entertainment.
But now all of a sudden we have this
forum for long form discussion,
real long form discussion.
And it turns out that everyone is way
smarter than we thought,
right?
We can have these discussions publicly
and there's a great hunger for it.
And I see this parallel.
So,
and this would be,
what would you call it,
supporting evidence for this hypothesis?
The same thing's happened in the
entertainment world because you know,
tv made us think,
well,
we can handle a 20 minute sit,
calm,
or maybe we can handle an hour and a
half made for TV movie.
But then Netflix came along and Hbo as
well with the bandwidth restrictions
gone and all of a sudden it turned out
that no,
no,
we can handle 40.
Our complex multilayered narratives
where the characters shift,
where the complexity starts to reach the
same complexity as great literature and
there's a massive market for it.
And so it turns out that we're smarter
than our technology revealed to us and I
think those of us who've been placed in
this intellectual,
dark web group,
you know,
there's some things we have in common.
We more or less have independent voices
because we're not beholding to any
corporate masters except peripherally
and we've been operating in this long
form space and the technology has
facilitated that.
And so all of a sudden it turns out that
there's more to people than we thought.
And thank God for that.
I'm struggling with.
I want to.
I don't want to use the word hate,
uh,
there,
there seems to be a,
a non acceptance or a resistance to the
idea that anything of quality could come
out of this group of people.
It's really interesting to me and uh,
I'm wondering why when I listened to you
speak or Sam or Eric or any of these
people,
ben or Dave and I hear very interesting
points and I'm like,
why are people resisting that?
These are interesting points.
Why are they resisting this?
And I think there's a lot of people that
are beholden to mainstream
organizations,
whether it's newspapers or magazines or
television shows that feel trapped.
I think they feel trapped by this format
that they're stuck in.
It's a very limiting format and it's a
format that,
in my opinion is like,
I mean,
it might as well be smoke signals or ham
radio or something.
It's fucking,
it's dumb.
You know,
this,
this idea that we're going to go to
commercials every 15 minutes and you
know,
and in between you have 15 people
arguing.
I mean,
I watched a panel on CNN wants and I
think we counted 10 people that were
trying to talk during this five minute
segment.
I'm like,
who,
what genius thought that it would be a
good idea to get 10 people struggling
for air time barking over each other.
No one saying anything that makes any
sense because everybody's talking over
and trying to stand out and trying to
say the most outrageous things and I'm
seeing like some of the resistance to
this when we spend pretty far,
you know,
from Sam and I lean more left and Ben
Leans more right and your,
what you would call a classic liberal.
And Eric's very difficult to define.
And Brett is fiercely progressive.
I mean these are Brett Breton,
particularly very left wing guy,
but this desire to label and to have
this diminishing label is like,
all right,
or you know,
right wing or fascist.
It's,
it's very strange.
Yeah.
Well there's a couple of things going
on.
I think one of them is that the
technological transformation that I laid
out and then the other is that I do
believe that especially for the radical
leftist types,
the whole notion of free speech among
individuals is not only anathema but
also something that isn't possible
within their framework of reference.
I've been trying to think this through
very carefully because you know,
for free speech in some senses become
identified as a right wing issue and I
thought,
well,
how the hell did that happen?
And then I thought,
Oh yes.
Well if you're radically left and you're
playing the identity politics game,
there's actually no such thing as free
speech because you're only the
mouthpiece of your group whether you
know it or not.
So you don't get to talk.
As Joe Rogan.
You get to talk as like Joe Rogan,
Patriarchal White Guy.
Knots it and your audiences aren't a
reflection of your own opinions as an
individual,
but they're an attempt on your part
whether you know it or not,
to justify your position and the power
hierarchy.
And so everything right now,
and this is where the technology and the
death of the mainstream media and,
and this and this political polarization
all unite,
everything is turned into a political
conversation in the,
in the mainstream media and media,
and it has to be cast as left versus
right.
And if you're criticizing the left and
all of a sudden you're right and right
wing and it has to be about politics.
It's like,
well,
it doesn't have to be politics,
it could be about philosophy,
it doesn't have to be cast in political
terms.
And,
and then it's also subject to a form of,
of,
of well it,
it's made more stupid than it has to be
by these terrible bandwidth limitations.
Like,
I mean,
I've been on mainstream TV talk shows
and it's very strange experience because
you're definitely content.
You know,
Marshall Mcluhan said the medium is the
message,
right?
The medium shapes the dialogue and it
doesn't integrate,
integrate in,
in,
in a tremendous way,
powerful way.
You go on a TV talk show and maybe it's
an hour long,
something like that.
And there's five guests and you've got
your eight minutes,
something like that,
and you have to be bright and chipper
and entertaining and intelligent,
sort of glitzy,
and it puts that facade of momentary
charisma on you.
And if you don't play that out,
you actually fail,
right?
Because you can't start a long form
discussion when you've got six minutes.
And if you're trying to talk about
something that's deep and difficult,
well you want to talk about it because
you've got the access they had and the
opportunity,
but you've got your,
your six minutes,
you can't help but turn into sort of a
glitzy entertainer.
And so it cheapens everything.
And then the other thing that I think is
happening is that as the mainstream
media television in particular dies,
the quality people are starting to
desert like rats leaving a sinking ship.
I guess they're good routes if they're
quality people,
but um,
and then the,
the,
there's ever more enticement to use
clickbait journalism to attract a
diminishing portion of the remaining
audience.
You know,
it's like one of the things that's
happened.
So if you look at the five major indices
of violent crime in the United States
that they've declined by 50 percent in
25 years,
it's absolutely beyond comprehension.
It's so good.
This includes violent gun crime by the
way,
and yet the reports of violence in media
have gone up and up and up and up.
You think,
well,
what's going on?
It's like,
well,
it's.
It's,
it's click bait.
It's the.
It's the equivalent of clickbait.
And then to turn everything into a
polarized political discussion takes no
real intellectual energy,
but it's also driven by the death spiral
of the classic media,
I think,
and I think that's actually why the
polarization seems to be so acute.
Now.
Some of it is genuine,
but some of it is.
Some of it is the consequences of this
underlying technological transformation
and the death throes of the smoke
signals.
Fundamentally
what you're talking about when you're,
when you're saying people,
especially radical leftists,
have to concede certain points whenever
they discuss things that this is so true
and so important because you see that
play out over and over again.
There's very little variation from the
official narrative when they talk about
important subjects or controversial
subjects and whatever they are,
whether it's transgender rights or
whatever,
whatever's in the news.
It's big and it's very popular right
now.
There's these,
these certain things that you're not
allowed to deviate from and that that's
an insanely restrictive perspective and
it who's establishing these norms like
who's a staff question man?
Yeah.
Who is it?
I blame.
I blame the universities and large part
for this.
They act this disciplines,
but that's only a partial answer because
the universities are also responding to
legislation like title nine so and so
and so.
They've been driven into the and title
nine for people,
so title nine,
title nine.
Originally it was just a piece of
legislation that that ensured that women
would have equal access to sports events
and so forth at the universities.
That's what it was designed for,
but it's become this umbrella
legislation that pushes equality of
outcome essentially across every
possible dimension in the universities
and it's been used as a weapon by the
radical left,
but some of that's driven by legislative
necessity.
What's happening?
What was the reason that I think this is
coming from the universities is because
I don't think that this could.
Well,
there's all these activists disciplines
that are essentially subsidized by too
high to tuition fees and also by state
funding and they've produced an entire
substructure of,
of activists and those activists are
doing everything they can to lay out the
theoretical structure for the radical
left.
And that's a,
that's a structure that involves.
There's buzzwords,
right?
Diversity is one,
but that means diversity by race and
ethnicity and sexual preference,
for example,
as,
as if those have anything to do with
genuine diversity of idiation and they
don't.
And there's no evidence that they do
inclusivity.
I've never even sure what that means.
Um,
equity,
which is a marker for,
what would you call it?
It's a code word in some sense for
equality of outcome,
which is an absolutely deadly doctrine.
I think of all the mistakes that the
radical left are making and the moderate
left for not calling them out on it.
The equity doctrine is at the top of the
list.
And then there's other associated things
like white privilege.
That's a good one,
and systemic bias and which is a.
it's an absolute embarrassment from the
perspective of a of a reasonable
academic psychologist because
psychological tests have been used to
prove that there's this implicit bias
that that lurks everywhere and the tests
aren't reliable and valid enough to make
that claim.
That's even the people who've made the
test.
The implicit association test have
admitted except for Mazda and Banerji,
who's the chairman of the Department of
Psychology at Harvard.
They've admitted that the tests aren't
reliable and valid enough to be used for
the purposes there'll be using for,
and there's also no evidence at all that
these unconscious buying bias retraining
seminars have any effect whatsoever.
That's positive.
It's all nonsense pushed by this.
The,
the ideological.
What fulminations of the radical left.
Is there any benefit in having these
conversations?
Talking about implicit biases and
recognizing that there's an extreme
pushback against racism or sexism and
all these different things and that even
though these things,
these,
these ideas that they're pushing might
not be tested and proven.
The idea of putting it out there in the
mainstream that there's a shift in
consciousness in terms of like how
people will or won't accept racism or
sexism or homophobia or whatever else is
being discussed,
that maybe it's far left,
but maybe it's moving the needle towards
where it needs to be.
I think that,
well that I think that happens.
I mean,
I certainly believed that there's space
and necessity for a constant dialogue
between the left and the right.
This is also something that I've been
developing more particularly during
these lectures,
so.
So I'm going to lay out a couple of
propositions.
So imagine that you have to move forward
in the world.
You have to do things and the reason you
have to do things is because while if
you just sit there and don't do
anything,
then you suffer and die.
So that isn't an option.
You have to move forward and you have to
move forward towards valued things.
So you have to have the value hierarchy.
It has to be hierarchy because one thing
has to be more important than another,
or you can't do anything right.
You're,
you're to split with your choices,
so you have to do things,
you have to value,
you have to value some things more than
others.
Then you have to act out what you value
in the social environment because you're
a social creature and you're not going
to do things alone.
Then as soon as you start to act out
things of value in the social
environment,
you inevitably produce a hierarchy and
the reason you do that is because no
matter what,
you're acting out.
Some people are way better at it than
others and and it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter if it's basketball or
hockey or plumbing or law.
Doesn't matter.
As soon as there's something valuable
and you're doing it collectively,
there's a hierarchy.
Okay,
so then what happens?
Well,
the hierarchy can get corrupt and rigid
and then it stops rewarding competence
and it starts rewarding criminality and
power.
And so there's always the danger of the
hierarchy will become corrupt.
The right wingers say we really need the
hierarchies and we should abide by them.
That's sort of the Motif of patriotism
and,
and positive group identity.
And the left wingers say,
yeah,
but wait a second,
there's a problem here,
a,
your hierarchy can get corrupt and might
and be because some people are way
better at it than others.
You're going to produce a bunch of
dispossessed people at the bottom,
and that's not only good for not only
not good for the dispossessed people,
it actually threatens the whole
hierarchy.
So you have to be careful.
You have to attend to the widows and the
children,
let's say the widows and the orphans.
Okay?
So now and then,
now you can think about that as an
eternal problem.
You can't do without hierarchies,
but,
and that's the right wing claim in some
sense you can't do without hierarchies
and they're valuable,
but they're also prone to corruption and
they dispossessed people.
Okay?
So now that's an eternal problem.
The question is what you do about it.
And the answer to that is there's no
final answer to the problem.
So what you have to do is you have to
have a left wing and you have to have a
right wing and they have to talk all the
time about whether the hierarchy is
healthy and whether or not it's
dispossessing too many people.
And then the problem with that is is
that discussion can go too far because
the right wingers can say hierarchy,
Uber,
all right,
that,
that we've,
the state is correct and everything's
right.
And so that's the right wing.
Totalitarian types and the left can say,
will flatten everything so there's no
inequality.
And so both the left and the right can
go too far.
Now the problem is we don't know how to
define.
I think one of the problems is we know
how to define
when the right goes too far.
I think we learned that after World War
II.
I think if you're making claims of
ethnic or racial superiority,
you get to be put in a box and put off
the shelf,
right?
You're not in the dialogue anymore.
It's obvious that the left can go too
far even though they're necessary
participants in the discussion.
But we don't know when to,
we don't know how to define when they've
gone too far and have an obvious
example.
No.
And,
and,
and you might think,
well that's the moderate leftists
problem.
It's their moral responsibility to
dissociate themselves from the radicals
just as it's the moral responsibility of
reasonable conservatives to dissociate
themselves from the Birch John Birch
and,
and Ku Klux Klan types.
That's a very important point.
But,
but the problem,
but it isn't just the moderate left's
problem because even the people on the
right don't know what to point to when
they say no.
You've gone too far as a leftist.
Now I've tried to.
It's complicated because I think it's
it.
It might be more than one policy.
I think the really deadly left this
presumption is equality of outcome.
I think as soon as you start talking
about equality of outcome,
you should be put in a box and put off
the shelf.
That's the but.
But it isn't obvious why.
Like that doesn't sound like you know,
white people overall.
It doesn't have the same guttural punch
that the excess of the right has its
equality of outcome.
Why is that bad?
Well,
it's bad because when you play it out in
society and there's endless evidence for
this,
it's an instantaneously murderous
doctrine and I think it's because it
shifts so quickly into a victim.
Victimizer narrative.
I've had a great opportunity in the last
month and a half.
I got asked to write the preface to the
50th anniversary edition of [inaudible]
since Gulag archipelago,
and so I've been writing that and one of
the things sold units and did,
which was one of the things,
one of the things that made that book
arguably the greatest work of nonfiction
in the 20th century,
it's in the top 10 anyways,
was to point out very clearly that the
excesses of the Russian revolution
started right away.
It wasn't that Lennon was a pretty good
guy and then Stellan came in,
corrupted everything.
It was like Lennon was not a pretty good
guy.
The revolution got bloody really fast
and what seemed to happen,
so imagine you,
you're.
You're starting to divide the world up
into oppressor and oppressed,
right?
And you're going to do something about
the oppressors.
The problem is is that you can define
people multiple ways.
This is the intersectionality problem
and almost everybody can be defined in
terms of their group identity in some
way that makes them an oppressor.
So like if you're a black man,
well you could argue that you're
oppressed because you're black,
but what about the fact that you're a
man and so does that make you an
oppressor or someone who's oppressed?
And the answer is,
as the revolution progresses,
if there's any dimension along which you
can be categorized as an oppressor,
you end up dead.
And so that's part of the pathology of
the equality of you or that you ended
up.
Did you end up rounded up?
You ended up being put into the
oppressor camp,
right?
So there's only so far you can
go with that,
right?
I mean,
you can't put all men in the oppressor
camp.
There'll be no men left.
Like what do you all that.
But that is really sort of plays out
well,
it is how it plays out.
When we look for equality of outcome,
it is how it played out in the Soviet
Union.
And China,
I mean in the Soviet Union,
we don't know how many people died.
The reasonable estimates look like about
$25 million.
That's dad.
That's not just,
that's not in prison,
that isn't families destroyed,
that's just dead.
And in in Mao's China,
it might have approximated $100 million.
That's just internal repression.
And so what seems to happen as soon as
you decide that the hierarchy is unfair
because there are oppressors and the
oppressed,
then you can go after the oppressors
with moral virtue.
But the problem is is that there's
almost no limit to the number of ways
that you can categorize someone as an
oppressor.
The category just starts to expand.
Like the communists killed all the
socialists.
It killed all the religious people.
They killed most of the students.
They killed all the productive farmers
and they killed the productive farmers
because they owned land,
you know,
and maybe little house and a few cows.
To be a successful farmer in Russia at
that,
at the turn of the 20th century didn't
mean you were rich.
Right?
It just meant you weren't starving.
It's like they killed all those people
because they were oppressors because
they had more than someone else.
That's how they defined it in order to
get the people to rally against it.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
And the.
And the definition kept slipping because
we'll look,
look,
even now it's like,
well,
let's say we rally against the one
percent,
you know,
and,
and those will be the money owners,
let's say.
It's like,
okay,
who's in that group?
Well,
everybody in North America is in that
group worldwide.
Yeah.
Well,
but who sends the parameters,
right?
It's 34.
It's $34,000
a year sets you in the one percent
worldwide,
right?
Right.
So,
so does that make all of us will pay
basically everybody who lives above
poverty in America in the one percent of
the world.
Right?
Right.
And also by historical standards.
And so the problem is,
the problem with the oppressor,
we'll press narrative,
is that you can multiply the oppressors
endlessly and there's no end to going
after the.
As soon as you make a definition,
you can move the boundaries and then the
next person is the oppressor.
And then keep going.
Well,
and you also see the interesting thing
too is that this is complicated,
so I've been thinking about this
proclivity of the left to to destroy
members of the moderate left.
It's like there's the game part of the
game is being played as far as I can
tell,
the ideologically pathological game is,
I'm more virtuous than you.
Now look,
if you're on the on the radical left and
you say,
well,
you're more virtuous than a right
winger.
It's like,
well,
who cares that it's obvious because the
right wingers are are,
are,
are pathological,
so being more virtuous than them,
that's not much of an attainment,
but if I have my moderate leftist
compatriot standing right beside me and
he's pretty damn virtuous,
but I'm even more virtuous than him,
then that's a real.
That's a real attainment on my park.
It's a moral attainment with no effort
on my part.
If I can figure out some way of
classifying that previously virtuous
person as an oppressor along some
dimension,
then all of a sudden I get an increment,
my moral virtue and that happened all
the time in these leftist revolutions
run a muck.
That was just a constant feature,
so it's not good.
It's not good.
Why is it.
This is something that's always puzzled
me.
Why is it that the left is defined by.
There's like certain.
There's certain values and one of them
is when you look at the right you,
you automatically think of racism,
potential racism,
at least a dislike for gay people.
Homophobia.
There there's certain qualities that are
always attributed to conservatives and
then there's certain qualities are that
these are social things and that I'm not
quite sure I understand like why is it
that the left is always associated in
support of gay rights?
The left is always associated in support
of,
uh,
of all races and all genders.
I think it's the dispossessed issue
again.
So imagine,
okay,
imagine that we make these hierarchies
and there hierarchies that are devoted
towards the goal and that the sum total
of all those hierarchies is something
like the patriarchy,
even though I hate that word and use it,
I don't like that word at all,
but,
but that's where we're speaking within
the confines of that theory that's
defined in how you're using it.
What do you mean by the Patriarch?
Well,
the Patriarchy is,
is,
is the sum total of all Western
hierarchy.
So let's say it's or it's the left,
the radical leftist vision of the sum
total of all Western hierarchy.
It's always male.
Well that's the theory is that it's male
dominated and you know,
what is Patriarchy as well?
And it's a funny thing because of course
there's lots of elements.
There's lots of sub elements of the
patriarchy that aren't male dominated.
So Pr,
healthcare for example,
universities,
the education system in general.
There's lots of places where these,
these sub elements are female dominated
but so defined as the patriarchy and to
define healthcare.
Oh,
that's a good question Joe.
I don't know what happens if,
if,
if you have a sub element of the
patriarchy,
it's dominated by women.
Is that still the patriarchy?
It's like the structure is still intact.
It's still performing the same function.
Well now the women are running it.
Was that the patriarchy?
And the answer to that is,
well,
we're all vague about what the
definition is,
so we don't need to address that issue.
Here's the answers.
Here's some clear ones,
right?
Like a major corporations,
the vast majority of ceos are male.
Yeah.
We think of that as part of the
patriarchy.
Government never been a male.
Men never been a female president of
vast majority of senators,
congressmen,
etc.
Mail.
Yeah,
so I guess we could say,
well,
the patriarchy is all those eleMents of
hierarchical structure that are still
dominated by men,
law enforcement,
military mail,
mostly male,
right?
But it's a.
It's a peculiar definition because it
means You have to.
You have to a fraction,
hate the patriarchy into pieces.
You can't you,
you can no longer talk about it as
uniform structure.
If you're going to take out all those
pieces that are dominated by women say,
well,
that's not the patriarchy,
but the thing is is that the whole
concept is so we'll define that.
It's that it guards description,
but so is you howard though,
right?
I mean that's the other thing.
That's the claim.
The other claim is that all hierarchies
are predicated on power,
which is a claim that's absolutely
appalling.
It's like plumbers,
they part of the higher curry hierarchy.
You've got roaming bands of armed
aggressive,
tyrannical plumber's coming to your door
saying,
use our service or else if that's not
how it works.
You go look when you're going looking
for a plumber,
you go look for a massage therapist.
You look or a surgeon for that matter,
or a lawyer,
you go look for the person who's most
competent and one of the things the left
can't tolerate is the idea that
hierarchies are predicated in part,
even on competence,
which they clearly are.
The best predictors for success in
western hierarchies are intelligence and
conscientiousness.
Those are the best psychological
predictors of success.
They only account for about a third of
the variation in success.
maybe a third is probably about right,
so there's still lots of room for
randomness and and even for systemic
discrimination,
but the notion that our,
our systems aren't predicated in part on
competence is clearly wrong.
Now you asked a question about the left
is like,
well,
why are the left always on the side of
the people who don't fit in,
let's say,
or don't fit so easily at it,
and I think that is a matter of the
consequences of hierarchical structures
is that so imagine in every hierarchy
there's some people who don't do very
well in any given hierarchy.
Then imagine this,
then imagine across all the hierarchies
that there's this subset of people who
are very likely to not do well in any of
them.
So you might say,
well,
they're systemically discriminated
against.
The left would be on their side because
they're on the site.
Even temperamentally of the people who
are dispossessed.
And the thing about that is that it's
valid.
Look,
we need a.
We need a spokesperson politically for
the dispossessed.
That's what the democratic party used to
do when they work for the working class.
The working class needed to political
voice.
It's like,
okay,
that's the democrats.
Well,
why do they need a political voice?
Well to,
to,
to keep the hierarchy from degenerating
into rigid tyranny.
It's part of the political discussion,
but now the problem is is this is the
problem with the left is that,
well,
what's the hierarchy?
It's a tyrannical patriarchy.
It's like,
no,
it's not.
It's partly corrupt like every system,
but it's less corrupt than most systems
and there's a lot of elements of it that
are devoted towards self improvement and
self monitoring.
You have to be a little nuanced and
subtle about these sorts of things and
you can't throw the baby out with the
bathwater and the leftist rhetoric has
got so intense that the.
The idea is,
and people believe this,
well,
the world is going to hell in hand
basket.
Everything is getting worse in all
possible ways and there's systemic
racism everywhere and it's utterly
unfair and it should be torn down and
rebuilt.
so like,
no,
it's actually functioning unbelievably
well even though it still has its
problems,
you know,
and there's a big difference between
saying there's systemic racism
everywhere and the reason that there
isn't perfectly equal outcomes is
because of prejudice and saying,
no,
look,
the system is functioning now are let's
say at 75 percent.
It's doing all right.
It's got some problems including
systemic prejudice which hopefully will
work themselves out across time and,
and which show every bit of evidence of
doing so and so we don't need a radical
solution.
You know?
And,
and one of the things I've started to do
with my twitter account is to tweet out
good non naive news Because one of the
things that's happening in the world and
there's been half a dozen books on this
or more written in the last five years
by credible people is that the
distribution of the idea of individual
sovereignty and property rights and free
market economies,
etc out into the rest of the world is
making the non westworld is making the
non western world rich really,
really,
really fast.
So between 2000 and 2012,
the rate of absolute poverty in the
world fell by half,
half.
It was the fastest period of economic
development in human history.
We beat the un,
we beat the optimistic un target by
three years.
Staggering.
Um,
you know,
the,
the rates of child mortality in africa
are now lower than they were in europe
in 1950.
The fastest growing economies in the
world are in subsaharan africa.
Many millions of people,
millions of people a month are getting
access to this incredible technology
that's embodied in cell phones,
right?
People have access to fresh water like
they've never had access before.
The child,
uh,
the kids are kids are getting immunized
at a rate that's,
that's unfair,
that's unprecedented.
And,
and yet we have this idea that's become
rampant in the west,
that there's something ultimately
corrupt about the patriarchal tyranny
and that it has to be dismantled right
down to its core.
And a lot of that's being taught by the
activist disciplines in universities.
And I just don't get it.
It's not acceptable.
So they see these hierarchies and their
proposal to level everything off and to
take away the insane power at the very
top is equality of outcome,
is unproven,
unproven in terms of it's never been.
It's never been done successfully to a
utopian right,
right.
Well,
and I also don't even think you can do
it in principle because if you accept
the proposition that the propositions I
laid out,
which is you have to pursue things of
value and if you pursue things in a
value in,
in a social space,
so you do it cooperatively and
competitively,
you do it with other people,
then you're going to produce
differential outcome because people be
differently.
Good at it.
It was like,
okaY,
you don't believe that.
It's like,
okay,
do you listen to random selections of
music online or do you do what everyone
else does?
You go for the one 10th of one percent
of songwriters and you only listen to
them.
You only listen to the one.
You only read the productions of one
10th of one percent of writers.
You only listen to the podcasts of one
10th of one percent of podcasts.
Broadcasters,
right when you watch sports on tv,
you only watch the athletic
contributions of one 10th of one percent
of athletes,
so like where's the equality?
Exactly.
Where's that in your life?
You people who are pushing for equality
of outcome.
You manifest that in anything you do,
you don't.
You're unbelievably selective just like
everyone else and the reason you're
selective is because you.
There are things that are happening that
need to happen or that are entertaining
and interesting and you want the best in
all of those realms.
That's how it works and there is a best.
That's the other thing that's so painful
and that that actually is painful.
You know what?
Here's a problem of dispossession.
A real problem.
One waY to not do very well in any
hierarchy is to have a low iq and so iq
is normally distributed and if you have
an iq of less than 85,
it's hard for you to read well enough to
follow instructions.
That's about 10 percent of the
population might even be higher than
that.
Okay,
so given that lack,
how are you going to compete?
Announcer is you're not because low iq
is a good predictor of poverty.
Now these spiral,
because if you're,
if you,
if you're cognitively,
if you're on in the,
if you're,
if you're less cognitively gifted then
and you have children,
they're going to be in a less enriched
environment.
These things spiral,
but you still have the essential
problem.
that's the essential problem of the
dispossessed.
It's like hierarchies are complex tools
to obtain necessary goals,
but they dispossessed people.
What do we do with the people that they
dispossessed?
The answer is we don't know,
so we have to talk about it constantly
to figure out how to solve it because
it's an ongoing problem that transforms
and that's the reason that political
dialogue is necessary and then the
danger is is that the political dialogue
will polarize into the radical left,
no hierarchies whatsoever,
or the radical right?
Our hierarchy is 100 percent right at
all costs and so those are the.
We have the eternal problem and those
are the two poles that we have to
negotIate between.
It's interesting because the accusation
has always been that what the left is
trying to do with this equality of
outcome thing is sort of an infant's
stylization of the populous.
right?
And the best example of that,
a sports,
um,
when you look at sports,
clearly the best people when the fastest
runners,
when the race,
the people that have the best strategy
when the game,
the infant infant,
that's a weird
word in fun.
Thailand and I never get it right,
but of that is what we do with children
where you get participation trophies and
no one wins.
When my daughter was three years old,
she was in soccer and they didn't keep
score,
but everyone knew.
Everyone knew these kids scored and they
didn't.
At the end of the game,
they didn't announce a winner.
There was no,
you can't have a soccer game without
keeping score.
You're not a soccer game anymore.
It's something else.
But the score was kept.
Of course,
it just wasn't discussed was of course
it was the strangest thing,
but this is to treat these little kids
because they couldn't handle it.
she cried when the other team scored.
I'm like,
that's it feels bad when they score,
so it feels good when you score.
It's very difficult to say that to a
three year old.
Right,
so I'm going to run hills.
Is she going to practice drills so that
she feels that good feeling more and
then there's a point where that becomes
too far.
There's a point where you become an
obsessive over winter,
right?
And this is the people that want to
crush their enemies.
Then you become conan the barbarian.
Yeah,
this is.
This is the far end of it and this is
what the left is terrified up,
right?
Yeah.
The idea of the left is the demure,
the soft,
the,
the people that are kinder and gentler.
The idea of the right is the conqueror.
The people that work hard,
play hard,
go kick ass,
go America,
that kind of shit.
And so these are the type of people that
are going to be crueler.
They're going to do what it takes to win
and the people that you would consider
that would like equality of outcome or
the people that are trying to slow that
down.
Does this make sense?
yes,
absolutely,
and I think that's how it lays itself
out.
Temperamentally,
psychologically,
this is the motivation for all this.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
And it's.
And the radical left is his compassion
going mad,
although it's also envy.
Let's not forget about that as well.
Absolutely.
I mean,
one reason to stand up for the
dispossessed is because you're
empathetic and empathy is not an
automatic good.
This is something we make a big mistake
about.
We think,
well,
I'm feeling sorry for you,
therefore I'm good.
It's like,
no,
I might be feeling too sorry for you.
I might not be demanding enough of you.
So.
And that's the terrible devouring
mother,
you know,
from a psychoanalytic perspective,
everything you do dear is okay.
It's like,
no,
it's not right.
So.
So one of the things that john piaget,
the developmental psychologist,
he was very interested in figuring out a
way out of this and it's very much
relevant to your concept you're talking
about about athletics.
Okay.
So,
so imagine this because this is also
something that points the way to a
proper morality,
which was actually something that john
piaget was very concerned about.
he wanted to.
he wanted to reconcile that distinction
between religion and science.
That's actually what drove him,
even though he was.
people don't know that he was arguably
the world's greatest developmental
psychologist.
so.
So here's the idea.
You know,
how you tell your kid to be a good
sport.
You say don't.
It doesn't matter whether you win and
lose,
it matters how you play the game.
Okay?
So I've been unpacking that in my
lectures because it's really,
really complicated.
It's like you tell your kid that and
they look at you and they think,
well,
what do you mean by that?
Aren't I supposed to try to win?
It's a soccer game.
I'm trying to.
I'm supposed to win.
And you say,
well yeah,
you're supposed to win,
but it doesn't matter whether you win or
lose.
It matters how you play the game.
You know that that's right.
But you don't know how to explain it to
your kit.
You say,
well,
you want to be a good sport.
Okay,
so imagine this.
This is how it works and this is
crucially important.
So first of all,
life is not a game.
Even a game is not a game because a game
is most of the time the game is the
beginning of a series of games.
So let's say that you're on a soccer
team.
Well there's wInning the game,
but the game isn't the issue.
the game is the whole series of game.
So maybe the game is winning the
championship and winning the
championship and winning ad game are not
the same thing.
And the reason for that is,
well maybe if you want to win a game,
the best thing to do is to let your star
player make all the moves.
But if you want to win a championship,
maybe the best thing is for your star
player to do everything he or she
possibly can to develop all the other
team members.
That's a different strategy and the
reason it's different is because it
iterates across time.
Okay,
so I'll tell you a quick story.
So when my kid was playing hockey,
when,
when he was about 12 or so,
he was in the championship game just at
a local arena,
you know,
and uh,
it was really fun to watch.
The teams were pretty equal,
which is something that you want so that
everybody can expand their skills while
they're playing and it was like five
seconds to,
to the end of the game and the other
team made a breakaway and came down and
the guy came down nice and scored a
beautiful goal and it was for three and
that was the end of it,
right?
And all my kids team there is the kid
who is the star and he was a pretty good
hockey player.
He came off the ice and he was very
annoyed about wHat had happened.
He smashed his stick on the cement and
was complaining about the refereeing and
acting as if he'd been robbed.
And his father came up and instead of
saying,
get your act together,
kid,
that's no way to display yourself after
a loss.
He said,
oh yeah man,
you were robbed that the referees didn't
ref right.
And you played the best and you should
have one,
and I thought you had absolute son of a
bitch.
You're ruining your son.
And then the question is why?
Because hIs son was the star and was
trying to win.
Why was he running his son?
Well,
you're trying to train your son not to
win the game.
You're trying to train your son to win
the championship.
And so that's a series of games,
but then life isn't the championship.
Life is a whole bunch of championships.
It's a whole sequence of them.
And so what you're actually trying to
train your son to do is to be a
contender in the entire series.
And the way you do that is by helping
him develop his character and the
character is actually the strategy that
would enable him to win the largest
number of games across the largest
possible span of time.
And one way you do That if you're a kid
is like,
well,
what do you want to do with your kid?
You don't want to teach him to when you
want to teach him to play well with
others.
And that's to be reciprocal.
So that means to try to win,
but also to pay attention to the,
to to developing the other people around
him and not to put winning the game
above everything at all times.
So Then he's fun to play with and this
is absolutely crucial.
You get you can.
You can help your kid become fun to play
with between the ages of two and the age
of four.
If your kid is fun to play with,
then what happens?
Kids line up to play with him and adults
lined up to teach him and if kids line
up to play with him,
then he'll have friends his whole life
and he'll be socialized and can be
invited to many games,
some of which he'll win.
All of which will be able to participate
in.
And if he's fun to play within,
adults will teach him things.
and then he wins at life.
And so when you say to your kid,
it doesn't matter whether you win or
lose matters how you play the game.
What you're saying is don't forget kid
that what you're trying to do here is to
do well at life and you need to practice
the strategies that enable you to do
well at life while you're in any
specific game and you never want to
compromise your ability to do well at
life for the sake of winning a single
game,
and there's a deep ethic in that and
it's the ethic of reciprocity in games.
Part of the reason that we're so
obsessed with sports is because we like
to see that dramatized.
You know,
like the person we really admire as an
athlete isn't only the person who wins.
We don't like the narcissistic winners.
They're winners and that's a plus,
but if they're narcissistic,
they're not good team players.
they're only out for themselves than we
think.
Well,
you're a winner in the narrow sense,
but your character is suspect.
You're no role model even though you're
a winner,
and it's because we're looking for
something deeper.
We're looking for that.
The manifestation of character that
allows you to win across the set of
possible games,
and that's a real thing.
That's a real ethic.
It's a fundamental ethic.
I think what you're pointing out that's
very important is we're,
we're searching for the person who's got
it all nailed.
Someone who tries their hardest but is
also honest enough about the
circumstances to not cry foul when it's
gone the other person's way yet.
Well,
that's part of resIlience.
It's right.
You're not gonna win it.
You're not going to.
You're not going to score on every shot.
Right?
Doesn't mean you shouldn't take the
shots.
Doesn't mean you shouldn't try to to hit
the goal,
but part of part of being able to
continue to take shots is to have the
strength of character to tolerate the
fact that that in that instance you
weren't on top.
It's more trivial in games than it is in
fights and it's also the response is
much more negative to the from the fans.
If you lose a fight and complained about
it,
it is.
It's ruthless because they understand
that you've made a huge character error.
Yeah.
So why do you think it's more important
in fights than it is in games?
Why do you think it's because the
consequences are so grave?
Because you recognize that the high is
much higher and the lows are much lower
to lose.
A basketball game sucks,
but it's nothing like losing a fight.
There's no comparison.
It's not even close.
What do you think
it is?
The damages the fighter.
If he complains about losing,
why is that a mistake?
Why did the fans respond negatively to
that?
Because they know they know that you
lost.
They know that you're complaining for no
reason and you're not a hero.
They want you to be better than them.
They want you to be the person that has
the courage to step into a cage or a
ring or wherever,
wherever you were,
whatever the format is you're competing
and to do something that's extremely
difficult and when you do that,
they hold you to a higher standard to
lose with grace.
yes,
and when you fall,
especially if you were a champion,
that is one of the most disappointing
things ever want to champion complains
and it.
His response is horrific from the
audience.
Okay,
so that's a great example.
So let's imagine,
what does the person who loses something
important with grace?
Do announcers fairlY straightforward.
He accepts the defeat and thinks,
okay,
what?
What is it that I have left to improve
that will decrease the possibility of a
similar defeat in the future?
Right,
so so,
so what he's doing is because the great
athlete and the great person is not only
someone who's exceptionally skilled at
what they do,
but who's trying to expand their skills
at all at all times.
Yes,
and the attempt to expand their skills
at all times is even more important than
the fact that they're great to begin
with because the trajectory is so
important,
more important in particular to the
audience.
It's extremely important to the audience
because you are the person who's
competing.
You are expecting them to live out this
life in a perfect way or in a much more
powerful way than you're capable of,
and so part of that is the skill because
they put it into practice,
but part of that also is the willingness
to push the skill farther into new
domains of development with each action,
and that's really what people like to
watch,
right?
They don't like to watch a perfect
athletic performance.
They like to watch a perfect athletic
performance that's pushed into the
domain of new risk.
They want to see both at the same time.
You're really good at what you do and
you're getting better.
Okay,
so you lose a match which is not any
indication that you're not good at what
you do.
You might not be as good as the person
who beat you,
but if you lose the match and then wine,
what you've done is sacrificed the
higher order principle of constant
improvement,
of your own skills because you should be
analyzing the loss and saying,
I'm the reason I lost in so far as it's
relevant to this particular time and
place is the insufficiencies I
manifested that defeated me and I need
to track those insufficiency so that I
can rectify them in the future.
And if I'm blaming it on you or the
referees or the situation that I'm not
taking responsibility and I'm not
pushing myself forward.
And so then you also take the meaning
out of it.
but one of the things I've been doing on
my tour,
people are criticizing me to some degree
for saying things to people that are
obvious.
Well,
first of all,
it's not like I didn't bloody well no,
they were obvious when I wrote those
things.
You want my rules in my book.
For example,
stand up straight with your shoulders
back.
You know,
treat yourself like you're someone
responsible for helping.
It's like I know perfectly well that
those can be read as cliches.
The question is cliche,
let's say is something that's so true
that it's that it's become
that it's become widely accepted by
everyone.
Well,
but we don't know why it's true anymore.
And so this,
this issue,
the issue that we're talking about here
are the issue of being a good sport.
We need to figure out why that's true.
And the reason that it's true is that
you're trying to push your development
farther than you've already developed at
every point in time.
And that's the proper.
That's the proper moral attitude.
So
when you see an athletic performance
where someone is pushing themselves
beyond what they are,
you see someone dramatizing the process
of proper adaptation.
It isn't the skill itself,
it's the extension of the skill and when
you see someone acting like a bad sport
and they're sacrificing that and so
they're sacrificing the higher for the
lower and no one likes that in the
fights.
It's got to be.
See the question is,
that's the thing I can't quite figure
out is why that would be even
exaggerated in a fight situation.
And then you said it's because the
stakes are so high.
Yeah.
The consequences of victory or defeat
there.
There's just so much greater.
There's your.
Your health is on the lot.
it's one of the rare things that you do
where your health is on the line,
your physical health,
right?
So the more extreme victories and more
extreme defeats,
the morality that's associated with
defeat is more extreme.
Exactly.
Because there's more on the line.
Yeah,
exactly.
Makes sense.
And the way people treat the champions,
it's a very different thing.
It's the respect and adulation that a
champion receives is it's the pinnacle
of sports in terms of the love from the
audience.
when someone wins a great fight,
it's.
There's nothing like it and this is one
of the reasons why these people are
willing to put their health on the line
because that high,
the high of victory,
and it's not just a victory.
It's a.
Who was it who said victory is really
the victory over the lesser you.
It's a victory over as the victim.
Yes.
Yeah.
It's the victory is over you.
You've got to realize a guy like steve
bay chick who defends his heavyweight
title this weekend in the ufc.
He is,
he's the heavYweight champion of the
world,
but he's not undefeated.
He lost in his career.
He's lost a couple of times and he was,
I'm sure he's lost wrestling matches and
sparring sessions in the gym and he's a
product of improvement.
He's a product of discipline and hard
work and thinking and strategy and
constantly improving upon those skills.
And so because of that,
he's the baddest man.
So my in my book,
rule four is,
this is 12,
excuse me,
this is from 12 rules for life.
Rule four is compare yourself to who you
were yesterday,
not to who someone else's today.
Yes,
because you need to be.
You need to have a hierarchy of
improvement.
You need to be aiming for something and
that means you're going to be lesser
than people who've always already
attained along that dimension and that
can give rise to.
So
the question is who should you defeat in
the final analysis?
And the answer is you should defeat your
former self.
You should be constantly trying to do
that and you're the right control for
yourself too because you're the one
who's had all your advantages and
disadvantages.
And so if you want to compete fairly
with someone,
then you should be competing with you.
And it is the case in.
This is what we were talking about too
with regards to the self improvement of
the fighter is well if you're improving
yourself,
then what you are doing is competing
with your lesser self.
And then you might also ask,
well what is that lesser self?
And that lesser self would be resentful
and bitter and,
and I'm aggressive and vengeance seeking
and all of those things that go along
with having a negative moral character.
And those are things that interfere with
your ability to progress as you move
forward through life.
So it's very necessary to understand
that this is why,
you know,
I've been stressing this idea of
personal responsibility.
Personal responsibility is to compete
with yourself,
is to be slightly better than yourself
the next day and it better in some way
that you can actually manage.
And that's humility.
It's right,
like,
well,
I'm a flawed person and I've got all my
problems.
Could I be as good as person x?
It's like not right question.
The right question is could You be
slightly better tomorrow than you are
currently flawed self?
And now answer to that is if you have
enough humility to set the bar properly
low,
then you could be better tomorrow than
you are today.
Because what you also have to do is you
have to say,
well,
here's all my flaws and my
insufficiencies and the best that
someone that flawed and insufficient
could do to improve and actually do it
is this,
and that's not worth going out in the
street and celebrating with plaque
cards.
You know,
it's like,
well,
this is why I tell people to clean the
room.
It's not going to brag to someone that
you did that,
but someone is insufficient as you might
be able to manage it,
and that means you actually are on the
pathway to self improvement and you're
transcending your former self and you
might say,
well,
what's the right way of being in the
world if there is such a thing?
And it's not acting according to a set
of rules.
It's attempting continually to transcend
the flawed thing that you currently are.
And what's so interesting about that is
that the meaning and the meaning in life
is to be found in that pursuit.
So I've been laying that out in these
discussions too because it's say,
well,
the.
The fundamental issue is that life is
tragic and difficult.
Very tragic and difficult for everyone
and it's also tainted by malevolence
because no matter how things are tragic
and difficult,
but there's always some stupid thing
that you could do or someone else could
do that could make it even worse than it
has to be,
so that's life and you need an antidote
to that because that can embitter you
constant contact with that,
just the tragedy,
but the tragedy combined with betrayal
and malevolence,
that makes it even worse,
especially if it's self induced.
Okay,
so you need something to set against
that so you don't get bitter and
resentful.
Well,
what do you set against that?
Doing something worthwhile by her own
definition.
Say you need some reason to get the hell
out of bed on a terrible day because
you've got something good to do.
Well,
what's the best thing you can do?
Transcend your current wretched and
miserable self.
There's meaning to be found in that and
real risk and that's.
That's a meaning that's associated with
responsibility.
One of the things that I've been trying
to lay out clearly is that life is hard.
It's tainted by malevolence and be trail
that can make you bitter.
You need a meaning to offset that.
where's the meaning to be found?
Not in rights,
not an impulsive pleasure,
but in responsibility.
You take responsibility for yourself so
you take care of yourself.
If you're good at it,
you can have some excess leftover to
take care of your damn family.
If you're good at both of those,
then you have some excess leftover to
take care of your community.
Those are heavy burdens.
You pick up the burdens you find that's
meaningful.
the best way to pick up the burden is to
continually improve yourself and that's
where the meaning is to be found,
and so that meaning is in the continual
self transcendence.
That's letting your old self die and the
new self be reborn.
You did you watch when we were kings,
allie,
allie fraiser.
God,
that's an amazing,
amazing,
amazing movie right at the end of it.
So lee defeats frazier basically by
letting him defeat himself,
right?
Because frazier is angry and he's got a
chip on his shoulder and he doesn't
conduct the fight properly,
so we exhausts himself chasing ellie and
ellie is basically just trained himself
to take the dam blows.
Right?
And to where frazier out,
that's his plan.
then right at the end of the movie,
he knocks frazier down and it's pretty
much the end of the fight,
but frazier sort of struggled to his
feet,
you know,
he's just getting up off the mat and
alli's got his hand pulled back to just
nail them because he's completely laid
open and he puts his glove down and
turns away.
That's the end of the fight.
And frazier said,
and this is true,
as far as I know,
that that fight tamed him,
like frazier had a big chip on his
shoulder and he was kind of a dreadful
guy up until that fight it afterwards.
He was affable and he was.
He was civilized,
lee civilized and so,
but that,
that gesture that allie made was that
great gesture because he could have
flattened him.
Right.
And he had every reason to.
Man.
He got,
he got,
he got taken apart,
a lead,
took punches like mad in that fight and
then in the final analysis when he had
frazier down and he was struggling to
his feet,
he just let him go,
man.
Nobility of character right there.
Something impressive to behold.
So
when,
why are you defining people like when
you're saying this,
why you saying you're miserable?
Wretched life because there's a lot of
people that don't have miserable
wretched lives that also just want to
improve.
Like why does it have to be the worst
case scenario in order to.
cause it has to work,
it has to,
it has to work.
The theory has to work in the worst case
scenario.
Okay.
That's why you're using the worst case
scenario as an.
yeah.
Because do you think that that perhaps
may alienate someone who doesn't have
the worst case scenario just watched
improvement?
No,
I don't think so because.
Well it depends on how much time you
have outline the ideas,
but you know what I.
Because even if things are going really
well for you now,
there's going to be a time in the future
where things are rough,
you know,
you're going to be ill,
family members going to be
ill,
a dream is going to fall apart,
you're going to be,
you're going to be a,
uh,
uncertain about your employment status,
like the flood is coming,
right?
The apocalypse is coming,
it's always the case in life and you
have to be prepared for it.
And The question is how to prepare for
it.
And the answer to that is to find a way
of being that works even under the
diarist of circumstances.
That's the issue.
And so you outline,
and I mean I am pessimistic about this
in my approach in some sense because
when I'm talking to my audiences in,
the same thing happens in,
happened in my book maps of meaning and
in 12 rules for life,
I'm laying out the worst case scenario.
And that sort of like hell,
it's,
things are going really badly for you
and that there's just chance associated
with that sometimes.
And you and the people around you are
doing stupid things to make it worse.
It's like,
okay,
what have you got under those
circumstances?
You've got the possibility to slowly
raise yourself out of the mire.
You've got the possibility to do just
what the fighter does when he's
defeated,
which is to say,
well,
regardless of the circumstances that
might have led to my defeat,
and even if there were errors on the
part of the referee,
this is no time to whine about it.
This is a time to take stock of what I
did wrong so that I could improve it
into the future.
And that's the right attitude.
You know,
in the old testament,
one of the things that's really
interesting about the old testament
stories is in the old testament,
the jews keep getting walloped by god.
It's like they,
they struggle up and make an empire and
then they just get walloped and then
it's all crushed in there.
They're out of it for generations,
and then they struggle back up and make
an empire and then they get demolished
again.
And it happens over and over and over.
And the,
the attitude of the old testament
hebrews is we must have made a mistake.
It's never to shake their fist at the
sky and curse fate.
it's never that.
The presupposition is if things aren't
working out,
it's my fault and that's a hell of a
presupposition.
And you mighT say,
well,
of course you know,
it's that,
that underestimates the degree to which
there is systemic oppression,
et cetera,
and and the and the vagaries of fate.
It's like it doesn't over underestimate.
It's not the point.
The point is,
your best strategic position is how my
insufficient and how can I rectify that?
That's what you've got.
And the thing is you are insufficient
and you could rectify it.
Both of those are within your grasp.
if you aim low enough,
one of the things you see the you,
that's another thing you keep saying,
aim low enough,
have a low enough bar.
Why do you,
why do you mean that?
Well,
let's say you've got a kid and you want
the kid to improve.
You don't set them a bar that's so high
that it's impossible for them to attain
it.
You take a look at the kid and you
think,
okay,
this kid's got this range of skill,
here's a challenge we can throw at him
or her that exceeds their current level
of skill,
but gives them a reasonable probability
of success.
And so like I'm saying it tongue and
cheek to some degree,
you know,
it's like,
but if you're,
but I'm doing it as an aid to humility,
it's like,
well I don't know how to start improving
my life.
someone might say that,
and I would say,
well,
you're not aiming low enough.
There's something you could do that you
are regarding as trivial that,
that,
that you could do that you would do that
would result in an actual improvement,
but it's not a big enough improvement
for you.
So you won'T lower yourself enough to
take the opportunity.
Incremental steps.
Yes.
And so this is also what is achieved
through exercise.
It's one of the most important.
Yeah.
Well what do you do when you go and lift
weights?
You don't go on,
like if you have a bench press before
you don't put 400 pounds on the damn bar
and dropped and dropped the bar through
your skull.
You know,
you think,
look,
when I started working out,
when I was a kid,
I was,
I was weighed about 130 pounds and I was
six foot one.
It was a thin kid and I smoked a lot.
I wasn't in good shape.
I wasn't in good physical shape and I
went to the gym and it was bloody
embarrassing,
you know,
when people would come over and help me
with the goddamn weights,
here's how you're supposed to use this,
you know,
it was humiliating and maybe I was
pressing 65 pounds or something at that
point,
you know,
but what am I going to do?
I'm going to lift up 150 pounds and
injure myself right off the bat.
No.
I had to go in there and strip down and
put my skinny goddamn self in front of
the mirror and think son of a bitch.
There's all these monsters in the gym
who'd been lifting weights for 10 years
and I'm struggling to get 50 pounds off
the bar.
Tough luck for me,
but I could lift 50 pounds and it wasn't
very long until I could lift 75 and
well,
you know,
how it goes,
but,
and I never injured myself when I was
weightlifting and the reason for that
was I never pushed myself past where I
knew I could go and I pushed myself a
lot.
You know,
I gained 35 pounds of muscle in about
three years in university.
I kind of had to quit because I was
eating so god damn much.
I couldn't stand it.
SeeMing like six meals a day.
It was just taken up too much time.
but there's a humility in determining
what it is that the wretched creature
that you are can actually manage.
Aim low.
And I don't mean don't aim and I don't
mean don't aim up,
but you have to accept the fact that you
can set yourself a goal that you can
attain and there's not going to be much
glory and to begin with because if
you're not in very good shape,
the goal that you could,
they could attain tomorrow isn't very
glorious,
but it's a hell of a lot better than
nothing and it beats the hell out of
bitterness and it's way better than
blaming someone else.
It's way less dangerous and you could do
it.
And what's cool about it,
there's a statement in the new
testament,
it's called the matthew principle,
and economists use it to describe how
the economy in the world works to those
who have everything more will be given
from those who have nothing.
Everything will be taken.
So like what's very pessimistic in some
sense,
because it means that as you start to
fail,
you fail more and more rapidly.
But it also means that as you start to
succeed,
you succeed more and more rapidly.
And so you take an incremental step in,
well now you can lift 55 pounds instead
of 52 point five pounds.
You think,
well what the hell is that?
It's like it's one step on a very long
journey and so it's.
And it starts to compound on you.
So a small step today means puts you in
a position to take a slightly bigger
step the next day.
And then that puts you in a position to
take a slightly bigger step the next
day.
And you do that for two or three years,
man,
you're starting to stride.
You know,
when I have so many people coming up to
me now,
this is one of the things that's so
insanely fun about this tour,
which is so positive.
It's,
it brings me to tears regularly.
It's mind boggling because people come
up to me and this is happening wherever
I go now.
And they say they're very polite when
they come and talk to me,
you know,
and they're always apologetic for
interrupting.
And so it's never,
it's never narcissistic and it's never
annoying.
I'm really happy to see people and they
come up to me and they say,
well,
I know you've heard this lots of times
before,
but I've really,
I've really been putting my life
together since I've been watching your
lectures.
then they tell me a story about where
they were in some dark place,
too much alcohol,
too much drugs,
not getting along with her father,
not getting along with her mother,
not having a vision for their life,
being nihilistic,
playing too many video games,
you know,
like,
um,
being suicidal that,
that happens a lot.
Having posttraumatic stress disorder
sometimes as a consequences of combat,
whatever little slice of hell they were
occupied,
they say,
look,
I've been,
I've been listening to your lectures and
I've been developing a vision for my
life and I've been trying to take
responsibility and I've been trying to
tell the truth and things are way
better.
And so that's absolutely perfect.
it's,
it's the right way forward as far as I'm
concerned.
And those are people who,
they took stock of themselves.
They said,
I'm in a dark place and I'm a dark
person and here's some things that this
dark person in this dark place could do.
Little things that they could actually
do.
I'll clean up my damn room.
I'll make my bed.
I've had,
I don't know how many people have come
and told me.
It's so strange.
He said,
well,
I started making my bed and that made
all the difference.
It's like,
well,
yeah,
you decide a day mop man,
and the first concrete instantiation of
that was that you made your bed and you
think,
well,
that's nothing heroic.
It's like,
no,
but aiming up his heroic,
that something and then lowering
yourself to the point where you're not
above the mess in your room.
You know you're not super ordinate too,
that you lower yourself so that you
straighten up your grateful for what you
have right in front of you and you take
care of it and you put it in order.
It's like all of a sudden things start
to get better and so wonderful to be
doing this tour because see,
I see,
so that's what this tour has been about.
For me.
It's not political.
I never talked to people after the
talks.
For example,
I talked to about 150 people a night.
We never talk about anything political.
It's always this.
I wasn't doing very well.
I'm putting my life together.
I'm getting along better with my father.
I'm getting along better with my wife.
I'm getting along better with my kids.
I've got some meaning in my life.
Thanks a lot.
It's way better.
It's like,
yes,
that's.
That's the right thing and it's very
beneficial for people and they need to
hear that and there's something that
comes along with that that's critical
and what that is is an honest assessment
of yourself and honesty that that type
of honesty,
honesty with yourself.
It's very difficult for some people and
they don't have the tools for it and
they haven't been explained to do this.
Why you should.
Yeah.
One of the things that happens when you
go through school,
you're told what to do.
You're Never told how to think.
He never told that you're okay the way
you are.
That's self esteem.
You're okay the way you are.
It's like,
no,
you're not,
and this is another thing where you are
and you're not right.
You're okay as a human look,
if you want to be a black belt in
jujitsu and you just started your first
class,
you're okay as you are,
you are human,
but in the goal you're not okay,
and the greater goal,
the incremental improvement is
important.
You have to.
You have to honestly assess your
position and move forward.
Well,
that's it.
You're a position in the trajectory.
Yes.
Right,
and when you say to someone,
you're okay because of your position,
that's not good enough because you have
to say,
well,
wait a second.
You need a trajectory and maybe you're
okay if you're okay and your position
and your trajectory,
but you know the self esteem movement
and all of that will accept yourself the
way you are.
It's like,
no because you need a trajectory and one
of the things that that I think one of
the reasons that audiences are
responding to what I've been saying in
my lectures and what I've been writing
about is that I don't tell people that
they're okay the way they are now.
I say,
no,
you could be way more than you are,
and they're relieved about that.
You see,
because if you're in a dark and terrible
place and someone says you're okay the
way you are,
then you don't know what to do about
that.
It's like,
no,
I'm not.
I'm having to having a terrible time and
I'm hopeless.
You're okay the way you are.
Well then what?
What?
That's it.
That's where I am and what do you want
to tell a young person,
you're 17 year,
okay,
the way you are.
It's like,
no,
you're not.
You've got 60 years to be better and you
could be way better.
You could be in comparable,
better across multiple dimensions and in
pursuing that better.
That's where you'll find the meaning in
your life and that will give you the
antidote to the suffering.
The way I always describe it to
people's,
there are disciplines that you can
pursue.
Those disciplines are a vehicle for
developing your human potential,
and if you get better at these things,
you can get better at anything and if
you figure out what it takes to become
better at whatever sport it is or
whatever art it is,
or whatever,
you're pursuing the same principles you
can apply to the way you treat people,
you can apply to the way you educate
yourself.
You can apply to wait.
You keep your body in shape.
All those things are connected and
that's why you have to import impose
order.
People have asked me in my book why I
wrote it as an antidote to chaos.
You know,
because,
well,
there isn't anything technically wrong
with chaos.
Chaos is a place of great potential.
Well,
the question is what's the proper?
What's the proper balance between chaos
and order?
Chaos potential in order.
While the answer is,
look,
when you're a kid,
you're all potential.
It's chaotic potential.
It can manifest itself in any number of
ways and maybe you don't want to give
that up so you're like peter pan,
you want to be a kid forever because you
don't want to give up the potential and
you look out in the world and all you
see are captain hook's,
you know,
who've lost a hand who were chased by
death because that's the clock and the
crocodile.
It's already got a taste of them
terrified by death and he's a tyrant.
Well,
I don't want to grow up to be that,
so I won't be at all.
Well that's no good because the way the
potential transforms itself into
actuality is through discipline.
And so then you,
as you said,
this is the trick though.
You have to pick a path of discipline
whether what path of discipline you have
to pick as a different issue because
there couldn't be a rule.
The rule could be the rule might not be
followed.
This rule.
The rule might be you have to follow
some rules.
So it's a matter rule and the mega rule
is you have to discipline yourself and
the issue is,
well,
how that's not really the relevant
question.
You can pick a disciplinary path.
That's why I often tell my clients,
especially young people,
they say,
well,
I don't know what to do.
It's like,
that's okay.
nobody does go do something.
Do the best thing that you can think of.
Put the best plan you have into
practice.
It's not going to be perfect and it will
change along the way,
but it will change partly because you
become disciplined pursuing the path and
as you become disciplined,
you become wiser and as you become
wiser,
you become able to formulate better and
better plans so you can start vaguely
and confused and develop a plan that's
not so great and you start to implement
it and then you,
you.
You accrue incremental wisdom as you
implement your flawed plan and that
enables you to fix the plant.
And so that's part of that process of
incremental self improvement as well.
One of the more difficult aspects of
that is personal honesty,
like being honest with yourself,
being honest with yourself about what
you're doing.
Self assessment.
It's very difficult for people.
They don't.
They're never.
They're never taught it.
It's not something that's encouraged.
No one.
It's dismal.
I imagine you only got 100.
You only have $100,000
to go buy a house and so you go buy
gold,
look at this house and It's like,
jesus,
this house man.
It's like,
it needs a lot of work.
well,
that's all you've got,
or are you going to pretend that the
house is okay the way it is?
Are you going to look for where it's
rotten and where the plumbing doesn't
work and where the stove doesn't work.
You have to go and look and see where
everything needs to be fixed and that's
like,
that is harsh man.
But,
and then in order to do that properly,
someone has to have taught you.
It's,
look,
you aren't your problems.
Well,
you are your most fundamentally that
which if it confronts it's problems can
solve them,
and that's the hero myth in in a,
in a nutshell,
by the way,
the hero is the person who confronts
horrible,
chaotic potential and tames it and make
something of it right?
That's the fundamental human story,
but the problem is is that you have to
face what you don't want to face in
order to fix it.
Yeah,
and so you look at all the things about
yourself that needs to be burned off,
that needed to be dispensed with and
that man,
especially at the beginning,
especially if you're screwed up,
that might be like 95 percent of you
just has to go up in flames and it's
painful.
Even some of that stuff that you have to
burn off doesn't want to die and it will
scream in agony while you're burning it
off.
It's not pleasant,
but if you know that you're the thing
that can transcend your problems most
fundamentally,
if you know you're the thing that if it
faces the problems can transcend them,
then you have the faith that would
enable you to take stock of who you are.
Then you have to do that in small steps
because most people don't have
experience in their problems,
so they really don't know what it even
feels like.
It seems like an alien concept.
It seems like something other people can
do,
but if you do it incrementally,
you can show yourself that you can do
it.
I mean,
it's one of the reasons why they have a
belt systems and martial arts.
You start off slow,
oh my god,
I got a stripe on my white belt.
Oh my god,
I'm a blue belt and you,
you feel improvement.
Yeah,
and for some people it's the first real
improvement marked absolute improvement
in their life.
Yeah,
right.
Well,
that's an interesting thing too,
because right there you've got a bit of
a measurement system.
We have this system set up online called
the future authoring program and we've
employed last time we implemented it
because we've tested it three times.
We implemented at mohawk college in
Canada and we had people write about
their ideal future and also to put in
measurement strategies.
It's like,
okay,
here's your ideal future,
here's how you're going to break it into
goals,
here's how you're going to mark progress
towards those goals because you've got
to be playing a fair game with yourself,
right?
Because when you make progress,
you want to reward yourself,
so you have to identify what the
progress is and you have to reward it.
The consequence we had people write a
future plan for only an hour when they
came for their school orientation in the
summer before going to.
It's a,
it's a community college and they
dropped the dropout rate among young men
by 50 percent and is.
Yeah,
no kidding.
Fifty percent.
Yeah,
and what that meant was to me,
what that meant was just think about
that.
What that means is that these kids being
educated for 12 years and no one had
ever sat them down and said,
okay,
what the hell are you doing and why and
how are you going to get?
Like,
where do you want to go?
Why do you want to get there?
How are you going to get there?
How are you going to mark your progress?
I've never walked them through that
exercise.
You walk people through that exercise
just to get them to do that increases
the probability that they'll stay on
track by 50 percent does incredible.
Well,
it's one of the things I've always
complained about is that they know one
or two people teach you facts.
They don't teach you how to approach
life.
They don't teach you how to think.
They don't teach you how to confront
white insecurities and different traps
that your mind will set up for you.
Yeah,
well that's what partly what's so fun
about doing this lecture to her because
that's exactly what I'm talking to
people about.
One of the things I talk about is,
well,
why do you think?
Why bother thinking?
It's like,
think.
Well,
that's obvious.
It's like,
no,
actually it's not so obvious.
It's like the.
The.
The issue that I discussed with my
students at university a lot is,
well,
why write a good essay?
Why bother?
Well to get the grade.
It's like,
no,
that's not why,
and if you think that,
well that's better than not thinking
that there's any reason for writing,
but it's a bad reason why.
Right?
Well,
writing is a form of thinking.
It's actually the most demanding form of
thinking.
I would say.
there's other forms that are demanding,
so how do you write a good essay?
Pick a topic that matters to you because
if you're not writing about something
that matters to you,
it's like you're not living something
that's meaningful.
It's wrong.
You're not going to write a good essay
because you're wrong.
Right?
To begin with,
it has to matter to you.
Well,
why does it matter?
What?
What does it mean that it matters?
Well,
it means that it's going to affect how
you make decisions in your life.
Something that matters affects how you
make decisions in your life.
Well,
why does it matter how you make
decisions in your life?
Because if you make stupid decisions,
you're going to increase the sum total
of suffering a lot.
You're going to do stupid things to
yourself.
other people and you're not going to be
as good a person as you could be.
So not only will you do stupid and
terrible things,
but you won't have manifested the good
in the world that you could have
manifest.
So that's the luck.
So you write an essay so that you can
think and you think so that you can live
properly and so you're right damn
carefully.
You make sure that every single bloody
word is a word that you want to use and
you make sure the phrases that you put
the words in or as solid as they can be
and you make sure the sentences are well
constructed and that they're organized
into proper paragraphs and paragraphs
are sequenced and the content of the
thing matters and you put your soul into
it and you know when you've done that
because it's gripping.
When you write,
it's meaningfully engaging.
And this is another thing that I've been
sharing with my audiences,
meaning is actually an instinct like you
think,
okay,
so we already decided that incremental
self improvement is the proper route.
Okay?
So how do you know when you're
incrementally self improving properly?
And the answer is it's deeply engaging.
IT's deeply meaningful,
and the reason for that is you're
actually adapted neurologically to
identify the pathway of maximal
incremental improvement.
That was a discovery conceptually by guy
named vygotsky who was a russian
neuropsychologist who coined the term
zone of proximal development.
You here now and then people say they're
in the zone.
That's the zone of proximal development
and that's that place that you occupy.
When you're improving at the rate that's
optimal to you,
and your sense of intrinsic meaning
signifies that that's how you're bloody
brain is wired.
And so then you might say,
well,
what's the antidote to the tragedy and
malevolence of life?
And the answer is to put yourself in the
zone of proximal development because
that's where the maximum meaning is and
that actually does prepare you for life.
And so the question,
why think as well,
you think before you act and you act to
put yourself in the zone of proximal
development and you do that too as an
antidote to the catastrophe of life.
Well,
that's the.
that's the answer.
And the thing that's cool about that,
this is a thing,
part of what I've been telling people,
that sort of novel as well.
Where's the meaning?
the meaning is in responsibility.
You know,
because people avoid response.
That's peter pan again,
avoid responsibilities,
just a burden.
It's like no,
it's not.
It is a burden,
but voluntarily hoisted.
It's the place of maximum meaning and
the more responsibility you take,
the more meaning you have.
And that's the antidote to the
catastrophe of life.
And,
and everybody also knows this because
just look so simple.
When you are,
you sick of yourself.
Well,
that's when you're being useless and
irresponsible for yourself and for your
family and for your community.
You're not even taking care of yourself
well,
you sleep with a clean conscience unless
you're a psychopath,
like if you're not taking care of
yourself.
And then when can you,
when are you not awake in the morning,
at three in the morning,
tearing yourself apart with a guilty
conscience.
It's when you've done something useful,
at least for you,
you know when you can say,
oh well,
check one on my side.
You say,
okay,
so fine.
You talked a little responsibility for
yourself and you can sleep with a clean
conscience.
What happens if you adopted full
responsibility for yourself and then for
your family?
Lots of the people that are coming to
talk to me say now I've been really
trying to put my family together.
Like I've made that a goal.
I'm trying to heal my family and bring
it together and it's working.
So here's a story.
I love this story,
man.
It just killed me.
I was in la at the orpheum and you know,
it's rough downtown in la,
places around the orpheum to and tammy
and I,
my wife,
because she's traveling with me and is a
big help by the way.
We're wandering around downtown la that
morning after the talk and we're walking
down the street and we were on streets.
We probably Shouldn't have been on,
but in any case,
because what the hell do we know being
stupid canadians,
and so we're walking down the street and
this car pulled up beside.
It's this kid hopped out and it's good
looking latino kid,
20,
21,
something like that.
He jumped over and he said,
he's all excited.
He said,
are you dr?
Peterson said,
yeah,
yeah.
And he said,
I'm really,
really happy to meet you.
I've been watching your lectures for
like a year and a half and uh,
I've been trying to put my life together
and it's really working.
I'm really doing way better.
I really wanted to thank you.
And so it's lovely a when you're walking
down and kind of rough area and somebody
pulls up beside you and they jump out of
the car to tell you how much better
their life is.
That's a pretty good morning.
And so.
But then that is no,
that happened.
He ran back to his car.
He said,
wait a minute,
wait a minute.
We went back to his car and he got out
his dad and they came over together and
his dad was just smiling away,
like a real smile,
you know,
and so as the kid and they had their
arms around each other and they said,
look like we've really been working on
our relationship for the last year and a
half and it's cold and just create,
we want to thank you.
And the father said something like,
I'm really happy that you got my son
back to me.
It's like,
yes,
that's what this bloody tour has been
like.
It's great.
And everybody that's coming to these
talks,
that's what they're trying to do.
You know,
I goT 3000 people in each audience and
what they're trying to do is figure out
how can I take maximal responsibility
for my own life?
How can I am bw it with the meaning that
helps me with stan tragedy and
suffering.
How can I be a better person and
wouldn't it be great if that was of
optimal benefit to my family and the
community.
You get very emotional about that.
It's something joe jesus,
I've seen like 150,000
people in the last two months,
you know,
and this is what it's.
Well,
you'll have a chance to talk to reuben
about this too.
This is what it's been like.
It's so positive.
I can't believe it.
It's just one person after another
saying like,
look,
I was,
I was having a rough time.
I'm really happy that I've been
encountering what you've been talking
about.
I've really been trying to put things
together and it's really helping.
You havE.
Ruben was pretty blown away by it.
We had a long conversation about it,
about he just feels like there's some
crazy movement going on if something's
changing in the world
because of this,
this new avenue of learning and
development is opening up
for these people.
Well,
I know I've been thinking about that too
because you know,
you,
like I said at the beginning,
if you're surfing,
you don't want to take responsibility
for the wave.
And so,
you know,
I mean,
first of all,
a lot of what I've been telling people
are things that I've gleaned from the
clinical literature in the psychological
literature.
It's not like I'm coming up with this of
my own accord,
right?
I'm transmitting information that I've
learned from very,
very wise people.
And so there's that.
But also we don't want to underestimate
the utility of the technology,
right?
Because we have this long form
technology now and it's enabling us to
have this discussion and so we can get
deeper into things publicly and
socially.
Then we were able to before and I see
this,
I see this as a manifestation of that
and,
and as an.
And I'm hoping to that maybe maybe
what's happening because we were going
to have a lot of adaptation to do in the
next 20 years.
As things change so rapidly we can
hardly comprehend it.
And hopefully the way we're going to be
able to manage that is to think.
And hopefully these long form
discussions will provide the political
or provide the public forum for us to
actually think,
to actually engage at a deep enough
level.
So we built a master the transformations
and I think that's possible and part of
the reason that I wrote this book and
well,
part of the reason that I'd be doing
what I've been doing for the last 30
years is because I really have believed
since 1985,
something like that,
that the way out of political
polarization,
the way out of the excesses of the right
and the left is through the individual.
I think the west got that right.
The fundamentaL unit of measurement is
the individual and the fundamental task
of the individual is to engage in this
process of humble self improvement.
I believe that's the case and that's
where the meaning is and that's where
the responsibility is.
And I think and I'm hoping that if
enough people in the west and then and
then the rest of the world for that
matter,
but we're very polarized in the west
right now.
If enough people take responsibility for
getting their individual lives together,
then we'll get wise enough so we won't
let this process of political
polarization put us back to the same
places that we went so many times in the
20th century.
I don't see another antidote for it.
It's not political.
It's ethical.
This is the message that I alWays hear
from you and this is you as a friend.
This is the you that I understand,
but this is not how you're commonly
represented.
You are the most misrepresented person
I've ever met in my life.
I have never seen someone who has so
much positive that gets ignored and
where people are looking for any little
thing that they could possibly
misrepresent and switch up and change,
and I'm kind of stunned by it.
I'm really not sure what it is about you
that's so polarizing with all these
different people that are deciding that
you are some sexist,
transphobic,
evil person.
That's this right wing.
All right.
Figure.
you know,
even to the point where it's,
it's,
it's kind of humorous to me sometimes
when I read some of these,
these takes on you.
What do you think that's from?
Like what?
What is have you.
This is a new thing for you.
You mean it's only been the last few
years that you've gone from this
relatively unknown professor in a
university in toronto to being this
worldwide figure where people,
obviously your message is resonating
with people in a very huge way,
but the people that are opposing you
vehemently opposed.
WhaT do you think that is
collected?
Don't like me collectivists and what do
you mean by that?
People who think the probably proper
unit of analysis in the worlD is a
political and be group oriented.
The identity politics types don't like
me at all and they have every reason not
to because I'm not.
I'm not a fan of identity politics.
I think things are misrepresented
fundamentally.
There's other reasons.
I mean I came out against this bill in
Canada,
bill see 16 that that hyPothetically
purported to do nothing else but to
increase the domain of rights that were
applied to transsexual people,
but there was a.
There was plenty more to that.
Bail bad.
Let me tell you,
and I read the policy,
the policies that went along with it and
it was a compelled speech bill,
and so I opposed it on the grounds that
the politicians are not supposed to leap
out of their proper domain and start to
compel speech.
It's not the same as forbidding hate
speech.
I'm,
I think hate speech should be left the
hell alone personally for all sorts of
reasons,
but to compel the contents of speech is
a whole new thing.
It's never been done before in the
history of british common law,
english common law,
and it's actually the supreme court in
the 19 forties in the us said that that
was not to be allowed and so it was a
major transgression and they said,
well,
we're doing it for all the right
reasons.
It's like,
no,
you don't get it.
You don't get to compel speech.
I don't care what your reasons are and
why should I trust your damn reasons.
Anyways.
What makes you so st like so that you
can violate this fundamental principle
and I should assume that you're doing it
for nothing but compassion and that
you're wise enough to manage that
property.
It's like,
sorry.
No,
I read your policies.
I see what you're up to.
I don't like the collectivists.
I think they're unbelievably dangerous
and I have reason to believe that.
So I think that when push comes to
shove,
if your unit of analysis is the group
and your worldview is one group and it's
power claims against all other groups,
that,
that that's not acceptable.
IT's,
it's tribalism of the worst form and it
lead to nothing but mayhem and disaster
and part of the reason you're doing it
isn't because you're compassionate
because you're envious and you don't
want to take responsibility for your own
life and I'm calling you on it and so
you don't like me,
so I must be an outright figure.
I must be a nazi saying your house needs
a lot of man.
There's a lot of rot in the floorboards.
The plumbing is leaking,
the water's coming in.
You're not,
you're not the sage.
And st you think you are,
there's so much work you have to do on
yourself that it would damn near kill
you to take a look at it,
do everything want
that.
That's why people are responding to you
in a negative way,
that they only have their own personal
problems,
that they're avoiding the it can't
possibly be,
that you represent to them something
that is either cruel or something that
is not compassionate about people and
their differences and their flaws and
their,
their humanity.
[inaudible].
I think it's certainly the case that
their vision that's been generated of me
is gas.
That's what I'm getting at too.
But why is layers say there's.
Well,
part of it's the,
the political polarization,
you know,
at the moment we're viewing almost
everything that happens in the world
through a political lens,
at least the journalists at least.
FIrst of all.
First of all,
I got it.
I got to make this clear.
First of all,
I've been treated well by lots of
journalists really well,
like the best journalists in Canada have
been on my side since about two weeks
after the bill.
See 16 thing erupted and those would be
the journalist that have an independent
voice and that are,
that have created their own following
and they're in a number of different
media place.
It's mostly in print.
Okay.
And there's a.
There's a coalition of,
of newspapers in Canada,
the post media group,
200 newspapers.
They came out fully and supportive.
My stance on,
on bill 60,
and so there's lots of times that I've
been treateD properly by journalists.
There's a small number of journalists,
very noisy and a small number of
activists,
very well organized who have been on my
case right from the beginning.
And those are people who are generally
driven by a very radical leftist,
progressive agenda.
And I am not on their side.
I'm on their side as individuals.
I'm on their side is people Who could
struggle forward,
but the collectivist vision,
it's deadly,
but you seem to be the poster boy for
this very simple characterization.
Like almost a caricature of what,
uh,
the,
the right figurehead is,
it's,
it's to me as a person who knows you,
it's very strange to watch this take
place.
And then when they can find anything
that you say that could without further
explanation or definition be
misconstrued as appealing to this
definition of you.
Like for instance,
when all this,
uh,
when this.
Well I guess they call themselves in
cells,
involuntary celebrates when all this
stuff went down with his car,
drove his car into a group of people.
it's horrible tragedy.
One of the things that you talked about
within cells is that,
and this was a part of the role,
what was it?
It was a New York times piece.
Yeah.
You said one of the cures for this is
enforced monogamy.
People decided and you know,
I'd never heard that term before quite
honestly.
And I was like,
whoa,
what the fuck does that mean?
It's a psychological term.
And What it means is enforced by culture
that it is a good value monogamy.
Yeah.
Because polygamy,
polygamous societies tend to become
ultra violent.
Yeah.
That's been known in the anthropological
literature for a hundred years and
certainly leftist anthropologists were
among those who discovered it.
Like she knew the journalist knew
perfectly well what I meant by
enforcement origami,
she has stupid.
It's a,
you use it as if everybody would
understand it because you're an
intellectual and because you're a
professor and assault,
you do.
It was also two minutes out of a two day
conversation,
you know?
It's like,
so if that's how she glanced.
Oh,
well,
it's so funny.
That was funny in some sense because my
sense is if you want to pillory someone
you should attribute to them views that
someone somewhere has had and the
implication of that part of the New York
times article was that I wanted to take
new bile,
young women at the point of a gun
understate enforcement and deliver them
to useless men.
It's like no one has ever believed that
trinity sounds like that.
It's a real.
The optics of that statement,
a very bad,
but the question is why didn't.
Why wasn't their followup questions and
if there was follow up questions to get
you to define what you mean by
enforcement.
There were.
They just didn't make it into the piece.
That's a real problem.
Yeah.
It's a real problem.
That's a real problem because that's
that.
That is.
It's so ridiculous because inaccurate
definition of who you are,
one of the things I've said continually,
and this is on record in multiple
places,
it's like,
okay,
so you're a young man and all the women
are rejecting you.
Who's got the problem?
It's not all the women.
That's a bad road to go down if all the
women are rejecting you,
it's you.
We both agree on this,
but why is enforced monogamy the
solution for people that are involuntary
celibates?
Well,
it's the solution.
It's the solution to the relationship
between men and women.
Fundamentally is monogamous.
Social men are unattractive if these on
attraction to them,
but if these men are on attractive to
women,
I don't mean just physically
unattractive.
Women aren't just seeking them as mates.
They need to become men.
Yes,
they certainly do have the solution.
that's the solution.
Absolutely.
We both agree on this,
so they need to do that in a society
where monogamy is the social norm,
the social norm anyway.
Well,
that was partly my point,
although to the degree that we deviate
from that,
we tilt towards a more violent society.
I was making a very minor point.
I don't think they're related quite
honestly.
I don't think that involuntary celibates
I don't think that having enforced
monogamy as a part of our cultural norm
is going to help those people.
It does.
How's it going to help them?
Well,
because what happens is if a polygamous
society develops,
which is the alternative,
then a small minority of men get all the
women.
That's what happens.
That's the only point is make his theory
theoretical
goal world where polygamous societies
exist and mass and then you do have this
problem with is a small group of men
that are fucking all the women,
but that's not.
Or talking and also making the women
unhappy.
Right?
Because the women don't have any access
to a genuine intimate one to one
relationship over any long period of
time,
which doesn't work well.
It's the whole idea and what's best
women that.
Sure.
If you have children,
right,
but I still don't think that that is why
these men are involuntary celibates and
I don't think it's the solution to that.
I think the solution is that they need
to become attractive.
Yes.
That is the solution.
There's no doubt.
I don't.
I don't think the two are related.
Well,
the only.
I was making a minor point.
The minor point was that one of the ways
that societies around the world have
figured out that you keep young male
aggression under control is by enforcing
monogamous standards because it gives
everyone a chance in some sense.
That's the only point that out
meaning it clears more,
uh,
more women will be available for one on
one relationships rather than one guy
who is,
you know,
whatever,
for whatever reason,
so figure in society,
you see this happening in universities
where women outnumber men.
So the man hypothetically have more
sexual opportunity,
but that isn't what happens.
What happens is that a small minority of
men have all the sexual opportunity.
A fairly large minority of men don't.
The women are unhappy because they can't
find a committed relationship.
It's bad for most of the men and the men
who have all the sexual opportunity get
cynical,
but isn't this in some ways against your
whole idea of equality of outcome
because you're,
you're talking about equality of sexual
outcome.
Now,
if these men,
if a guy james that's dominant
basketball player that just kicks
everyone's ass,
this is the,
this,
this is a guy who succeeded at the
highest level,
right?
Well,
there's gonna be people like that
sexually,
there's going to be people that are
better at finding mates and this is what
they enjoy.
They enjoy having many mates.
They enjoy being yes,
but,
but if this is what they enjoy,
if it's a man who doesn't want a family
and enjoys dating multiple women,
why is that bad?
Well,
I think the fundamental reason it's bad
is because it's bad in the long run for
children,
it's bad for children if he chooses to
have children.
yeah,
well that makes sense.
But that's it.
That's the fundamental issue as far as
I'm concerned right now.
I think it's the answer.
Look to give the journalist credit.
That is the point she was making,
you know,
apart from pillaring me and,
and,
and caricatured my perspective.
That was the point she was making.
Well,
first of all,
I'm not in favor of unbridled
hierarchies.
Like I already said that,
you know,
the proclivity of a hierarchy is that
all the spoils go to the person at top
and that can
destabilize the whole structure,
so we have to have a dialogue about how
to rectify that,
but how
possibly rectified that if one man is,
but like say if we've got one six foot
five beautiful man who's got a perfect
body and the brilliant and he just wants
to date a bunch of women and all the
rest of the people or five foot one and
they're fat and they're lazy and like
this guy is gonna.
If this is the competition,
he's going to win.
Yeah,
gap.
There's no way around this and even if
you decide to have enforced monogamy and
blair becomes a popular thing,
the women are going to be more drawn to
him.
If he chooses to date them,
they might decide.
I would rather have him sometimes the
never actually what does happen,
but what is wrong with that?
Well,
what's wrong wIth it is that it
destabilized the society and it's bad
for children.
You said that would have to have
children,
but there's a lot of people that don't
want to have children.
There's a lot of people that choose to
go their entire life without having
children as men in their thirties and
some of my friends I've vasectomies they
don't want children,
so why?
Why would that help in any way?
These involuntary celibate?
Well,
I think you tilt the society so that it
serves the interests of.
Well,
that's a good question.
Do you see my point where I see your
point?
No doubt about it.
You're almost having.
You're almost forcing in inning in an
equality of outcome.
I know that was her point to to the
degree that she had a point that was her
point now and it's not.
It doesn't run contrary to my opinions
that the issue of outcome has to be
addressed.
Already saId there's needs to be a
reason for the left and the right,
and then the problem with hierarchies is
they can get to steep and destabilize
everything that does happen.
That particularly happens in the sexual
domain and there's plenty of
anthropological evidence for that,
but you still might say,
well,
who cares?
Because the man who are who are winning
should be allowed to win in the women
should be allowed to choose.
Yes,
except that there's the problem of
children and so society steps in on
behalf of the children and you can say,
well,
lots of people don't want to have
children.
Yes,
and that's truer now than it used to be.
Although many of those people end up
having children anyways,
you know the guys who snooping around
all the time,
so that doesn't circumvent the problem,
but the issue here for me isn't the man
or the women,
it's the children.
We're trying to set up societies where
the probability that children will be
raised in something approximating
optimal environment is optimized and
that's going to mean sacrifice of
opportunity and choice on the part of
the adults
necessary.
I agree with you,
but I think the what we're talking about
mirrors what we're talking about in
sports.
It mirrors what we're talking about in
business.
It's everything else.
There's going to be people that are
better at all different aspects of life
is going to be people that are talented
in terms of like getting women to.
Yes,
that's true,
but that's why also look,
you see this,
women are hypergo,
which means they made up and they meet
and up dominance hierarchies,
and so if you're a male who's successful
in a given hierarchy,
the probability that you're going to
have additional mating opportunities is
exceptionally high.
It's an unbelievably good predictor of
that.
That high is a very uncomfortable
discussion,
certainly.
Well,
there's plenty of uncomfortable
discussions too.
That's a big one though.
It is the idea that it defines women's
sexual choices by the fact that they
want beggar bigger,
better.
Someone who's more,
more successful than someone is so
higher on the social ladder than what
they're accustomed to or what they have.
What women do is like make choices is a
very difficult problem.
so how do you solve that?
Well,
here's how women solve it.
Throw them in a ring,
let them compete it.
Whatever they're competing at.
Assume that the man who wins is the best
man.
Marry him.
Yes,
it's a brilliant solution.
It's a market oriented solution.
It's actually the solution that appears
to have driven our evolutionary
departure from chimpanzees.
It's a biological solution solution
which has a cost.
What is the cost?
Well,
the cost is the cost is polygamy and so
we ran that in within forest monogamy
and we do that in order to provide
stable,
stable circumstances for children.
Is polyamorous,
polyamorous society just as unattainable
as this utopian marxist idea?
I think so because it looks like,
and this is another point I was making
that didn't get covered in the article,
I wrote about it somewhat extensively on
my blog,
is that society's tilt towards monogamy
across the world is human universal.
Now that doesn't mean that people don't
have polygamous or polyamorous
tendencies because they certainly do and
it certainly also the case that one of
the ways that women gerrymander this
system is that the number of women and
children who are in a say say you're
married and you have children with your
husband,
but you also have an affair,
so we have a child by another mat that's
more common than anyone suspected.
So part of their weight,
we weigh that women solve the problem
that you're just describing,
and I'm,
I'm not saying anything for this or
against this,
this is a purely factual biological
claim,
is they pick a monogamous marriage and
they cheat with high status guys.
Now you know,
obviously in the confines of the
marriage,
that's a terrible thing,
but that's a very uncomfortable subject
though for women and protecting her
uncomfortable subject for everyone.
But it's a terribly uncomfortable
subject.
They don't like the idea that this is a
common thing that women choose a safe
man that is willing to be monogamous
with them and perhaps maybe they're
above him in a social class or in a
sexually and then they'll cheat with
someone who was taught.
It's common,
but it's not the norm,
right?
It's still the norm not to do that.
The norm is fidelity,
but,
but there's plenty of exception.
This is enforced monogamy,
culturally the norm.
This is the very definition of monogamy
is this.
It's like,
okay.
So my son's married
in september and so,
so let's say he comes to me in a year
and he says,
hey dad,
guess what?
I've had three affairs in the last year
and they've all been successful.
I haven't got caught,
aren't I a good guy?
What am I going to say to that?
Know what the hell are you doing?
that's not what you're supposed to be
doing.
That's enforced monogamy
enforcement.
Origami meaning the people around you
try to guide them in a way that you
think is going to lose it's harmonious.
Yes,
it's built deep into the cultural norms
and if that starts to destabilize them,
there's trouble and that doesn't mean
that it's not prone to all the problems
that you laid out.
Look,
there isn't a bigger problem than
successful reproduction.
It is the big problem and all of the
solutions that we've generated for it
are full of flaws.
Like here's an example,
the gender paY gap,
okay?
There's no gender pay gap.
There's a mother gap.
There's other reasons too,
but women really take a hit when they
become mothers.
Okay,
that's unfair.
Fair enough,
man.
What the hell are you going to do
about?
It's not just that though,
right,
and this is what also,
I'm sorry to interrupt you here,
but this is what's one of the things
that I wanted to bring up but are kind
of lost track of it.
The misrepresentation of view mirrors
the misrepresentation of the gender pay
gap because it's a convenient
misrepresentation that upon further
inspection and understanding you realize
there is no gender pay gap,
the gender pay gap when people discuss
it that don't understand it and I've had
these conversations with really
intelligent people that just listened to
what's in the news or read some very
quick article talking about this problem
that we have and they assume that a man
and a woman are working the same job,
but the woman is unfairly paid seventy
nine cents to the man's dollar.
That's not the case.
It's not close to the case cases.
Women choose different professions that
don't pay as much.
They work less hours and they oftentimes
get married and have children and
because they have children,
they take paternity leave when they make
less money and they make less money
because that the reasons or 20 reasons
for the gender pay gap,
right?
One of them being motherhood,
but there's a whole slew of jobs meant
work outside.
Men are more likely to move,
but it's never discussed.
It's discussed.
Don't like multivariate problems.
It's not just that it's a.
It's a willful misrepresentation of
reality and I think it mirrors this
willful misrepresentation of where
you're,
where you stand,
and I think they're all tied in together
with people want bad and good.
They want a one and a zero.
They want things to be very binary.
Yeah.
They will not to be binary in the way
they already understand.
They want everything to fit their
ideological lens and things are more
complicated than that.
This is a complex discussion that you're
not going to get in a five minute
segment on a talk show.
Right?
Exactly.
Not going to get this on a radio show.
You're not going to get this in an
article that gets edited by someone with
a biased opinion,
and this is the problem with mainstream
media and this is the problem with
ideas,
period.
Warren farrell's book on,
he wrote a book called warren is the guy
who's
most,
what would you call it most pilloried
for?
Pointing out the real reasons for the
gender pay gap.
he wrote a book called why men make more
hoody rated for his daughters.
Why?
Because he wanted to help provide.
Now obviously he was doing it for public
consumption as well,
but one of the motivations was,
well,
men do make more.
Well why?
And if women want to make more,
what could they learn from the men who
make more how to make more?
And the answer is yes.
the question is whether or not they'll
do it and the book the probable answers
most women won't because how much you
make isn't the only hallmark of success
in your life.
You know,
iT's like it's one measure and it might
be a measure that really competitive men
compete for and they do.
and that's partly to provide access to,
to,
to increase mating opportunities because
that's built into the structure.
Something we never talk about either,
although we could.
So warren wrote this to lay out all the
reasons that men make more,
but it was so that his daughters,
at least in part so that his daughters
could figure out how to be
socioeconomically successful.
It's like,
yeah,
but that's not the only hallmark.
How much socioeconomic success are you
willing to sacrifice to spend time with
your kids before they're three years
old?
Well,
the answer to that shouldn't be none,
right?
Because what makes it look,
we already know this for,
for example,
once you make enough money to keep the
bill collectors at bay.
So that's kinda lower upper working
class.
Say something like,
even centrist working class.
Keep the bill collectors at bay.
Additional money doesn't improve your
quality of life.
Other things do.
So maybe it's a rational response when
you're like 30.
See the irrational men.
Here's the irrational man.
Maybe they drive the world,
but they're the irrational men.
More success is always better.
Along this unit,
dimensional axis of achievement wasn't
gecko.
Greed is good.
Well,
there's a tiny percentage of men who are
hyper competitive along those single
axis of,
of,
of competition,
and maybe they drive most things they
probably do,
but that doesn't make them right.
It also doesn't make them most people
and it doesn't make them happy.
Well,
happy is a whole different issue,
but that's what they're out of it
because everyone is well.
You are though in in pursuit of success,
it's implied that happiness goes with
that success.
Otherwise,
why the fuck are you doing?
Yeah,
well dominic domination,
power back actually,
but that's charisma.
Prestige while he applied it is success
and happiness or an extra bleak
connected in our perception.
Yeah.
Well,
there's often a flawed equation,
you know,
like what happens.
Look,
I workEd in law firms with law firms for
a very long period of time and I worked
for lots of high end women,
lots of and they were like,
they were usually extremely attractive.
They were extremely intelligent.
They were extremely driven.
They were very,
very conscientious.
They varied in how agreeable they were
somewhere.
Disagreeable litigator types in,
some were more agreeable.
They often had a harder time in the law
firms,
but the law firms lose all their women
in the thirties.
They all bail out at partner level.
a lot of them will say,
jesus,
yeah,
it's a good percentage.
It's a huge percentage and it isn't
because of the law firms don't want
them.
The law firms want them because you
can't find people like that.
They're really rare,
especially if they're also rainmakers,
if they can bring in money.
So the law firms bend themselves over
backwards trying to keep the women.
It can't keep them.
Why?
Well,
the women decide that,
oh,
I'm working 18 hours a day,
flat out all the time,
seven days a week.
My husband makes a fair bit of money.
If I made half as much money as I made,
we'd still have plenty of money.
Why am I working 18 hours a day?
Well,
that's not the question.
The question is why would anyone work 18
hours a day?
that's the mystery and the answer is a
small minority of men are driven to do
that and so they'll do that no matter
where you put these guys.
That's what they do.
Okay,
but that.
Does that mean it's correct?
I think there's something wrong with
these women.
They hit 30,
they've hit partner,
they've hit the pinnacle.
I mean they could keep going if they
want him to,
but they've accomplished their goal.
They've definitely shown man,
they're bloody well in the game and they
wake up at 30 and they think,
oh,
wait a minute,
I want to have a relationship and also I
want to have some time to put into that.
I'd like to have kids and I'd actually
like to see my kids.
It's like,
is that a rational?
This is another thing that you and I are
in agreement on,
but when I see people talk about the way
you discuss women,
they misrepresent what you're saying and
paint you in what I think willfully
paint you.
They do it on purpose.
They paint us a massage.
Ernest,
I don't understand why I don't
understand if it is because they
disagree with you on things,
so this is a convenient way to demonize
your position by demonizing you as a
human being.
Um,
but
well,
it's partly too,
because I've made the case that there
are differences between men and women.
Yes.
But like why that isn't a feminist case
is beyond me.
It's like,
no,
they're exactly the same.
they're not.
It's ridiculous.
It is.
And it's confusing.
It's confusing.
Purposefully.
Confusing thing is the data in so look
and people have accused me of pseudo
science,
you know,
which I already think is quite comical
because the studies that I'm reporting
aren't.
Who's accused you of pseudo,
oh god.
Journalists.
Journalists of all stripes.
Especially when I talk about differences
between men and women,
it's like,
oh,
that pseudo science.
It's like,
actually,
no,
it's not,
it's bloody mainstream science,
both biology and psychology,
but why do they like to do that?
Well,
because it seems to be there's a reason
that goes along with the radical leftist
agenda that if there are that a world of
equality of outcome could not be
achieved and that's the desirable world.
If there are actually differenceS
between people,
actual differences like that aren't just
socio culturally constructed so that you
can gerrymander.
There's also something as well,
if you're really power mad,
you want to believe that human beings
are infinitely malleable because then
you can mold them in whatever image you
want and if you say no,
they actually have a character,
right?
There's something built in then that
interferes with the totalitarian regime.
But here's happened is like,
look,
we've got a good personality model.
We've had it for about 40 years,
something like that.
The big five model,
five dimensions of personality,
and they were established statistically
a theoretically by left-leaning
psychologists.
Okay?
And I'm not saying that they're
ideological contaminated,
but what I am saying is there's no
evidence whatsoever that right wing
leaning psychologists produced the big
five because there are no right leading
psychologists.
So enough of that,
that isn't why the big five came up.
Okay.
So once you have a good personality
model,
you can say,
okay,
well we'll do men and women differ and
the answer is yeah,
it turns out they do.
There's quite a few differences,
but the biggest ones are women are more
agreeable because that's one of the
traits,
agreeableness and it's the compassion
politeness dimension and they're more
prone to negative emotion,
anxiety and emotional pain.
And that mirrors the psychiatric
literature that shows worldwide that
women are more likely to be diagnosed
with depression and anxiety,
just like men are more likely to be
imprisoned for antisocial behavior,
which is the reflection of low
agreeable.
This is true worldwide.
Okay?
So there's no evidence of any bias
unless you say everything is biased
everywhere in the world.
Fine could be.
But we've also controlled for that.
So now there are personality differences
between men and women.
Now the first thing we might point out
is they're not that big.
So if you draw a random woman and a
random man out of the population and you
had to bet on who was most aggressive,
least agreeable,
and you bet on the woman you'd be right
40 percent of the time,
which is actually quite a lot.
You'd be right quite a lot.
But if you take the one in a hundred
person who's most aggressive,
least agreeable,
there's an overwhelming probability that
there'll be mailed because the
differences get more extreme at the,
at the ends of the distribution,
people don't understand the statistics.
you can have two populations that are
quite similar and still have radically
dissimilar outcomes if only the extremes
matter.
So like who are the most powerful
physical fighters in the world?
Men,
all of them.
what does that mean?
That there are no women who can beat a
man in a fight?
No,
it also doesn't mean that there are.
There's plenty of women who are more
aggressive than men,
but if you take the most aggressive,
physically powerful people,
they're all men,
all of them because they're like one in
a thousand people or one in 10,000
people.
So you can have walloping differences at
the extremes,
despite most most similarity at the
middle.
People don't understand that,
but then the next thing is,
okay,
well there are differences between men
and women personality wise,
apart from the biological ones.
Are those caused by cultural
differences?
Hey,
turns out we can answer that.
How rank order countries by how
egalitarianism their social policies
are.
Does everyone agree?
Yeah.
The scandinavians are at the top.
Everyone agrees,
left,
right?
Doesn't matter.
Everyone agrees.
It's like,
okay,
so you stack up the cultures by how
egalitarianism social policies are,
and then you look to see how big the
differences are between men and women up
that hierarchy of egalitarianism.
And if as the societies become more
egalitarian,
the differences between men and women
disappear,
then it's sociocultural.
That isn't what happened.
What happened was is that as the has got
more egalitarian,
the differences between men and women
got bigger,
not smaller.
It means the sociocultural construct
people,
and I'm talking to you,
sociocultural construct people,
you're wrong.
You're wrong.
You make the society's more egalitarian.
Men and women get more different.
Who makes the argument in opposition of
this,
all the,
all of the social constructionist,
all the radical left wingers and what
are the uses fat.
They don't have facts,
but then they criticize the whole idea
of facts.
Then they go after the whole idea of
science as a,
as a,
as a western patriarchal construct.
What's their motivation?
The motivation is that if people are
different than the equality of outcome,
isn't,
is neither desirable nor achievable and
why do they want equality of outcome?
Why is this so?
That's a good question.
Well,
part of it is part of it is actual
compassion.
Look around.
It's not good that some people lose and
it's certainly not good that some losers
lose all the time.
Who wants that?
You happy when you walk down the street
and see homeless people.
It's like,
hey,
look,
the hierarchies working.
Look at these homeless people.
No one's happy about that.
right?
Right.
Okay.
So the fact of failure within a
hierarchy of value is painful.
And so to give the devil his due,
you give the left.
It's due just like you.
You do the right is like,
yeah,
it's painful.
That hierarchies produced dispossession.
Bloody right.
Okay.
What's the cure?
Get rid of the hierarchy.
Hey,
well wait a minute,
man.
You get rid of the hierarchy.
You get rid of the value structure.
You get rid of the tools that allow us
to generate absolute wealth and stop
people from starving.
It's a catastrophe.
Okay,
so.
So there's.
There's the problem.
You have to have the hierarchy,
but then also it isn't just compassion
on the left.
It's envy.
It's like,
okay,
if I'm.
So if I'm standing for the dispossessed,
what makes me so sure that I'm not just
standing against the successful and
maybe that's because I'm bitter and
jealous and envious and resentful and
certainly it's highly probable.
If you look at what happened in the
leftist societies that tried to pursue
utopia and you don't read envy and
resentment into that,
you're not.
You don't know the history because
that's clearly the why else did they
become murderous,
but this is the question like it's
clearly the case that the soviet union,
for example,
was motivated by the desire for equality
of outcome as a primary motivation.
What happened?
Twenty 5 million people were killed.
Why?
What was it all compassion and love for
the dispossessed or was it absolutely
bitter resentment and hatred for anyone
who had any shred of success whatsoever
on any possible dimension of evaluation.
so this compassion for people that
aren't doing well when utilized the
wrong way or when approached the wrong
way leads to attacking people that do
well.
The danger of compassion.
That's exactly.
Well,
look what happens if you get beat,
you think,
oh,
look at how isn't it lovely that the
mother,
grizzly bear takes care of her cubs?
Yeah,
it's lovely bad until you get between
her and her cubs and it's not so damn
lovely,
and that's the flip side of that
affiliate of agreeableness.
It's like if you,
if you're on my side,
you know,
if you're the infant who's sheltering
under my wings,
it's like I am.
I'm the absolute epitome of of maternal
love and care,
but if I have identified you as a
predator,
you better look the hell out and that's
playing out in our political landscape
at a very,
very rapid rate.
That's the female side of
totalitarianism as far as I can tell,
the feminine side of totalitarianism.
It's not just that.
It's not just that agreeableness
motivates aggression because it
certainly does.
it's also that it's that the envious and
the resentful can use compassion as a,
as a camouflage for their true intent,
which is to tear down anyone who has
more than them.
That's the why you noticed like when
there's discussions about the one
percent we already talked about this.
Well,
who's the one percent?
While it's.
I'm a,
I'm a.
I'm in.
I'm in the,
in the park in New York,
demonstrating against wall street down
with the one percent.
It's like,
wait a second,
you're in the one percent.
They are mr.
Protester.
No,
no.
You don't understand the rich are those
who have more money than me guess,
right?
That's the definition.
Who's rich?
Someone who has more than me,
not me.
It's like,
well,
why?
Why isn't the one percent north America?
Why not?
Because it's inconvenient.
That's an inconvenient fact,
so that's part of it,
but there's the.
The envy and resentment.
This is the real pathological end of the
full compassion that motivates the
radical left.
It's like,
yeah,
you liked the poor.
Do you?
What makes you think you just don't hate
the successful?
Now it's a question.
It's like because you're not perfect,
man.
There's hatred in you and the
probability that it's more powerful than
love is pretty damn high.
So,
so look to your own,
look to your own viewpoint before you go
out there and try to fix the hierarchies
of the world,
just exactly what it is and it's worse
like look in the russian revolution,
for example,
let's say just for the sake of argument,
that the first rung of revolutionaries
were only driven by compassion.
Maybe they were.
They all got killed.
they got killed by the people who came
after and they weren't so interested in
compassionate at all.
They were interested in ferreting out
everyone who had a modicum of success on
any dimension and doing them in and that
happened in wave after bloody wave.
They killed all the successful farmers.
Those were the kulaks.
It killed all of the running up,
killed him,
rape them,
stolen property,
sent the remnants to siberia,
froze them to death 10 years later,
6 million ukrainians dot because they
couldn't raise crops.
Why do you think that people are so
opposed to discussing these things or to
challenging cultural norms?
Because one of the things that I've
seen,
especially in terms of the differences
between men and women,
this,
this reaction to some of the things that
you've said has been very.
It's very strange to me.
It's very strange that people aren't
recognizing that these are unbalanced
approaches and that there's.
Well,
some of it's just complicated joe.
It's like,
well,
let's say there are differences between
men and women.
Just for the sake of argument.
The biggest differences seem to be an
interest by the way,
and so what's going to happen is that if
we let men and women's sort themselves
out,
there aren't going to be very many
female engineers and tech types and
there's going to be a lot of female
nurses.
There's not going to be many male nurses
and healthcare types.
There's not going to be met very many
male elementary school teachers.
But Is this bad?
Well,
that's the question.
Who knows?
do we know?
I don't know.
Well,
the idea of having
unequal society where gender inequality
is completely knocked down,
gender pay gap is nonexistent.
Yeah.
Well that's a problem because that's
quality of outcome.
It's also,
it's the quality of outcome thing is a
nonstarter.
Whether it's okay with like if men and
women sort themselves into different
occupations,
which looks highly probable.
I don't know if that's okay.
And then it's also like,
okay,
compared to to what alternative?
Like you should every elementary school
teacher be female,
should every psychologist be female?
Because that's what's happening.
And the answer to that is,
well I don't know but.
But there's another answer,
which is,
well,
what do you propose as an alternative to
free choice that isn't going to cause
more trouble than free choice?
Because I would say,
well,
okay,
let's say I'm a feminist for the sake of
argument,
right?
So I think while there are differences
between men and women,
there are actual differences and so some
of those are biological,
some of them are,
are,
are strategic in some sense because
women pay a bigger price for
reproduction and so that's going to lead
them to make different choices.
That's just rational based on
rationality,
based on biological differences.
So it's like a second order.
Biological difference.
There's differences in temperament and
interest.
They're going,
it's going to lead them to make
different choices.
Is that a pro feminist stance or an anti
feminist stance?
It's only antifeminist if you assume
everyone has to be exactly the same and
the outcomes have to be exactly the
same.
if the.
If your goal is no,
leave people the hell alone as much as
possible.
Let them make their own informed and
free choices.
Then you let the differences manifest
themselves in the world.
And you take your,
you take your knocks because of that.
The problem with that is this narrative
of equality,
the equality of outcome.
Yeah.
It's just equality of human beings.
Just looking at people as we're all
equal,
we're not just.
Some people are different.
Things were equal in terms of our rights
or equal in terms of the way we should
treat each other.
metaphysically equal,
yes,
right?
But on every other dimension,
we're radically unequal and there's pain
in that.
That's the.
That's the problem is the pain in that
is real.
The only thing that's worse than the
pain of inequality is the pain of forced
equality.
And I'm not being fascinated about that.
It's like,
look,
I see the.
The iq issue is,
is the killer one.
For me,
it's like,
look,
if you have an iq of less than 83,
you can't be inducted into the american
military by law.
Why?
Because there isn't a damn thing you can
do that isn't counterproductive despite
the fact that the army wants you because
they can't get enough manpower.
That's what they decided.
It's like,
okay,
so you're on the low end of the
cognitive distribution,
what are you going to do?
Not much,
and it's going to get worse.
Is that good?
It's not good.
It's horrible.
Do we know what to do about it?
No.
Right.
And we can have equality of outcome
amongst people with lower than 83 iq.
No one's,
no one's advocating for that.
No one's asking for that.
Well,
people will say,
well,
the iq tests aren't valid.
It's like,
well,
yeah,
one of the conversations that you have
that I found to be shocking and it
started a trend of misquoting and
misrepresenting you was uh,
you did an article,
an interview with vice and they use a
snippet of one of the things you said
and tried to pretend that you had made
these very curt statements.
And one of them while he was,
he was annoying.
So I got kind of curt and that was
probably my strategic error makeup.
Is that the one you're talking about?
Makeup and the way people dress,
you know,
while I was trying to draw a lot,
first of all,
how is he annoying?
He knew everything,
he knew everything well.
It was just in his attitude,
you know,
it was challenging you.
He wanted.
he wanted this from the very beginning.
This was him.
Arms crossed,
eyes up.
It's like a,
I know more than you and be your
probably that reprehensible person that
I've thought about and this side job to
reveal you.
He was signaling he's left leaning.
He was deciding that what you were doing
was representing the patriarchy or you
were representing male dominant
structures that he was saying that are
not correct.
Yeah.
Well it wasn't accurate assessment,
but it wasn't even that it was left
leaning.
I've talked to reasonable left leaning
people.
It was built right into his attitude.
So it made me a little test here that I
might have been,
which was my strategic error and you
know,
you asked earlier,
well why do I get pilloried with some
regular?
And some of it is probably my own
inadequacy.
You know,
it's not,
it isn't that I've handled all the
opportunities that I've had perfectly,
you know,
and I can get hot under the collar.
It's a mistake.
It's a mistake because the right
approach in these situations is to use
minimal necessary force and to allow
myself to get irritated,
let's say even minorly when I'm faced
with someone who's doing this is not
productive,
it doesn't work well,
and so I really need to keep that under
control and when I do keep it under
control,
it works better.
The makeup one was particularly annoying
to me because I think it's a valid
conversation.
It's an interesting conversation.
I said,
and they didn't put this in their
initial cut.
I said,
I'm not saying that women shouldn't be
allowed to wear makeup in the workplace.
I said that explicitly.
Well,
that was why people were so angry when
they saw the full version of it.
I mean the full version was released.
Someone leaked it,
right.
Someone who felt like you were being
misrepresented and that the editing was
unjust,
decided to release it and people were
absolutely furious.
Yeah.
Well,
I think the.
I think the vice people actually
released it,
but other people took the full release
and clipped it with the clip release and
showed how it was being misrepresented,
but so okay,
so the the makeup thing,
it's like,
all right,
look,
here's the.
first of all,
I make a mistake sometimes in treating
journalists like I would treat my
graduate students,
so when I'm having a conversation with
my students and we say,
well,
here's the problem.
It's an intellectual exercise,
sexual,
sexual behavior.
How do we regulate?
What are the norms around sexual
behavior in the workplace?
It's not the question.
It's a question we don't know.
Okay.
Here's a bunch of possibilities.
Possible rules,
right?
No flirting,
no hugging,
no eye contact for more than five
seconds.
That's netflix,
right?
No hugging,
no damn right.
They have no eye contact for more than
five seconds.
That's holy shit.
Nbc,
no hugging.
That's real.
It's real.
Fuck.
What if you're having a conversation
with a woman who's your boss and she's
asking you questions about things.
Can You look down every five seconds?
Fucking christ.
Is that real?
Yes.
It's real.
So bad.
That's such a terrible idea.
Yes,
it's.
Yeah,
it's a terrible idea,
but there's a lot of women that I'm
friends with that I've never had any
sexual interest at all,
and we looked at each other in the eye.
That's what you say,
but you're a potential rapist.
Manifestation.
Yes.
Picture,
yes.
You get the whole picture.
So.
So if you have a discussion,
you say,
well look,
what are the rules governing sexual
behavior in the workplace?
OkAy.
Can you come to work at a negligee no.
How about boxers?
If you're a mat?
No.
Okay.
So there's some short skirt.
Well that.
This is the thing,
the devil's in the bloody details,
right?
It's like,
okay,
we can't come to work naked.
You can't come to work in boxer shorts.
You can come to work in a suit.
Okay,
so the line is somewhere between boxers
and suit.
Where exactly is the line?
Exactly.
Can wear shorts while that can't.
Why can a woman wear a dress?
The way that men in professional
organizations,
the way that men solve this problem was
that everyone wore a uniform and a
uniform makes you uniform.
That's why you wear it and the uniform
is the suit and it's a derivation of a
military military garb,
and so the Idea was,
well,
we want to get rid of excess diversity,
right?
In clothing where your damn suit.
Then we know you're playing the game and
we don't have to be distracted by what
you're wearing.
Okay,
so what men did.
so now women come into the workspace.
It's like,
hmm,
what do they do while there's business
professional dress.
Right?
And there's some rules around that,
but.
But what are the rules?
Exactly.
And I was thinking,
well,
we're worried about sexual misbehavior
in the workplace.
You can't look at someone for more than
five seconds.
You can't give them a hug.
Okay,
what about makeup?
Do we have a discussion about makeup?
oh,
well no,
we can't have a discussion about that.
It's like,
well,
let's make up sexual signaling.
It's like,
well,
if you're an fear,
an evolutionary biologist,
the question is makeup sexual signaling,
that's not even a question.
It's like awful.
Obviously that's what it is.
That's why the conversation was
frustrating because he was saying
because they want to do it,
they want to wear it,
they want to look good while and maybe
does that even mean well?
That's right.
What does that mean?
Well,
everyone knows what that means.
He has to say that.
No,
he has to say that because in his tribe
you have to communicate that way.
He,
oh wait,
women wear makeup because they want to
look good,
but what do you mean do that?
Because that's his take or because he's
trying to rile you up,
but you're getting riled up right now.
Both as a journalist.
It's kind of his idea or his job to
challenge you in some way and it it the
very least offer the devil's advocate
opinion.
Sure.
Explain yourself better.
Why shouldn't they wear makeup?
They just want to look good.
You need to explain yourself better.
Why you saying he did it was like,
oh,
Dr.
Peterson.
It's obvious what it means for them to
look good.
Like everyone knows that.
Do you think that.
Why don't know it like perhaps like he
was intellectually sparring with you and
he was being aggressive about it.
I think he felt.
I think he felt that.
I think he felt that it was necessary to
challenge me that that was his role as a
journalist,
but fundamentally he was smug.
He thought he came at the entire
conversation with an air of intellectual
condescension.
It was built right into the discussion
right from the beginning and he never
dropped it at all.
It's like,
well,
I know what you're doing and I know
what's up and I know how to take you
apart and I know that whatever you're
talking about is just an attempt to
defend your how long indians?
Oh god.
About an hour.
Something like that.
How much did they use owing the clips?
Hardly any of it.
I don't even know.
a couple of minutes.
So yeah.
Yeah.
So your tendency to get riled up can be
exploited?
Yes,
of course.
And it's,
it's,
it's the problem of deviating from the
doctrine of minimal necessary force,
like the best times.
The best interactions I've had with
contentious journalists is where I've
absolutely kept my cool,
you know,
but kathy newman.
Yes,
exactly.
Exactly.
So what you're saying is,
well that's what he was like,
yeah.
It's like I know who you are and I know
you're covering it up.
It's like,
well,
it's these con,
these concepts.
These are complex situations.
When you find men and women who are
sexually attracted to each other and
they're working in confined environments
for long periods of time and they
essentially spend more time with the
people they work with and do what their
lovers and their wives and their
husbands and it's weird,
you know,
men and women interact with each other
and closed in boxes is weird.
That's what an office is.
Closed inbox.
They're all together and if they find
each other attractive and they're
interacting with each other socially,
especially if there's any interaction
that deviates outside of work
discussion,
they start talking about different
things.
You also don't want them to find each
other unattractive take.
If you're taking someone out for dinner
on a business dinner,
it's like even if it's guys going out
together,
let's say,
it's not like they're working to find
each other unattractive and I don't mean
sexually.
There's you want to manifest yourself as
wine,
enjoy each other's company and you want
to be charismatic and you want to be
witty and all of those things and that
shade.
Especially when you,
when you add,
assuming a heterosexual environment,
you add a heterosexual component to
that.
The borders become fuzzy.
And so I was talking about border
conditions.
So if we're going to have a conversation
about this,
let's talk about the border conditions.
Oh no,
we can't do that.
It's like black on the discussion you
guys wanted.
Why do you continue to agree to have
these conversations that are going to be
edited?
Oh,
well that's a good question.
The jim jefferies one was another one.
Jim's a friend of mine,
but I mean he gave you a good question
and you actually gave a good answer.
You said,
actually,
I'm probably wrong about that.
You were talking about whether or not
gay people,
uh,
should,
whether someone should be forced to bake
a cake for cake for gay people.
And you said forced to probably not.
And they said,
well,
what if they don't want to bake a cake
for black people?
And he said,
well actually,
probably they probably should be forced
to.
Yeah.
Well probably wrong.
Well I was probably wrong in everything
I did in that,
in that part of the discussion because I
hadn't thought that issue through enough
to actually give a good answer.
You didn't expect that issue because
this is not something you talk about
commonly know.
And it's,
it's actually complicated,
right?
I mean obviously the whole I won't serve
you because you're black thing is not
good.
But then again you have,
you also have the right to choose who
you're going to affiliate with,
but then that's complicated because it's
a commercial circumstance and then if
you're making a cake,
is that the same as serving or is that
compelled speech?
It's like,
oh my god,
these are border cases that caused a lot
of controversy.
I don't mean serving black people.
Obviously that's not a border case,
but these cases that caused a lot of
controversy is where two principals are
at odds and it isn't exactly clear where
to draw the line and I'm not happy with,
you know,
I'm not happy with my answer to that,
but I hadn't spent the week would take
to think through the issue and really
have a comprehensive perspective and
expect that to be a subject anyway.
No,
no.
What.
How long did you talk to jim for?
Oh,
I think about 45 minutes.
Maybe an hour.
Quite a long time.
Oh,
two minutes.
Yeah.
Well my daughter has told me and and my
wife as well,
my son as well.
in these discussions we've been thinking
about how to handle the media,
which has got a very complicated
question and one hypothesis being don't
do interviews that will be edited and
I've thought about
that and and been thinking about it and
that might be the right answer.
It might be the right answer going
faster and get his as well.
It could.
It could easily be,
although snow
way you can't be misrepresented.
Trust all of the problems that I've seen
with you,
all of them come from you being edited.
Yes.
I mean there's complex subjects that
people would disagree with you on,
but when you look at complete miss
characterizations of your point,
these have been established because of
editing?
Yes.
Well I guess the only counter argument
is this,
and I mean a lot of these,
a lot of these opportunities come.
I've had opportunities that are coming
at me,
a rate at a rate that doesn't allow me
to think them through as much as I could
optimally,
but,
but then there's another thing which is
it isn't necessarily a mistake to lay
yourself open to attack because
sometimes it reveals the motives of the
attackers.
Like that's what happened in the kathy
newman interview now that could have
gone really sideways.
Like I was lucky there to some degree
because she interviewed me for 40
minutes or whatever and something like
that.
And then they did chop it down to seven
minutes or three minutes and it was
exactly what you'd expect and that is
what I expected.
After I walked away from the interview,
I thought,
oh my god,
they're just going to chop this into
reprehensible segments and pillory me,
but I walked away from it because there
was 50 other things to do,
but then it was so funny because they
did do that and then they put up the
whole interview and the reason they put
up the whole interview was because they
thought the interview went fine.
It isn't that they knew that that was
going to cause commotion.
Not at all,
not a bit,
and I know this for a fact,
so they put up the whole interview and
then,
well,
what happened was what was actually
happening revealed itself,
and that was very,
very effective.
Now that having that happen meant that I
had exposed myself to substantial stress
and risk because that was stressful.
I mean,
first of all,
there was the interview second
afterwards I thought,
oh my god,
I'm going to get pilloried for that.
Then they did release the cut.
Then they released the whole thing.
Then there was all this response to it
and then then the newman people who were
absolutely flabbergasted by the negative
response said,
peterson is unleashed his army of trolls
and poor kathy had to go into hiding.
It's like there's no evidence of any
credible threats.
They said they called in the police,
but you can do that Without there being
reason.
You can just say that which is what they
said.
They played a victim narrative
instantly.
Although one thing kathy newman is not,
even though she might play it at the
behest of her employers is a victim.
She's one of the most powerful people in
britain.
She's no victim,
so to play the victim card and a
situation like that is absolutely
reprehensible,
but that's what they did and then like a
dozen newspapers did it and said,
well,
peterson's trolls are attacking poor
kathy,
and I thought,
oh,
well now I'm screwed.
You don't own your fans.
Did the idea that people that are
interested in the things that you have
to say that you have control over them,
like you can give them marching orders
person that does that well,
and how many million,
how many million people did there have
to be before?
They're not all trolls.
yeah,
because that was the real issue there.
It's like,
okay,
10,000
people commented on the video trolls.
Okay.
What about 150,000?
Well,
what about 10 million?
Well now if you look at the video,
which is about 10 million plus all the
clips,
it's like $50 million.
And the commentS,
the pro,
the comments that are critical with
regards to kathy newman's conduct are
running about 50 to one.
So that's all trolls.
Is it?
I don't think so.
It's preposterous that narratives you
see,
that was,
that was a good example of taking the,
taking the risk and I'm not saying it's
justified and I think that it's very,
very stressful,
you know,
but you know,
you take the good,
you take the bad with the good and maybe
maybe it's time for me,
it might be time for me just to
disappear to some degree altogether.
You worry about being overexposed.
Oh definitely.
I'd be worried about that for a long
time.
Yeah.
And is there any benefit in that?
Is there any benefit in more exposure?
Are we talking about the same thing we
were talking about earlier with regards
to men working insane hours?
I mean have you as your message out
enough that you don't have to do these
ridiculous interviews maybe instantly,
maybe,
maybe.
Yeah.
Well,
and I don't want to turn it into a
parody of myself and all of that.
I mean,
I think and I am trying to handle this
and I've got people who are advising.
We were trying to figure it out.
I think that this tour is a good thing.
Yes.
And but that's,
that's very controlled.
I think we'll so completely unedited.
Yes,
exactly.
It is long form conversations.
Yes,
and I think that coming on your podcast
and talking to ruben on his shows and so
forth,
I think that's good.
The,
the,
the interaction with the journalist.
I'm certainly not taking anywhere near
the number of opportunities that I have
in front of me.
Right?
We are trying to be very careful in
picking and choosing,
but that doesn't always go well and it
it like.
It could be that,
it could be that I shouldn't do anything
that is edited at all.
That's certainly possible.
So.
Well this is the problem.
You,
you speak in these,
you speak in these long form podcasts
and interviews and you get a chance to
extrapolate and unpack some pretty
complicated issues and compare them to
other complicated issues and try to find
meaning in middle ground and try to try
to eliminate certain positions.
when you expose yourself to editing,
you expose yourself to someone's idea of
what the narrative should be and how to
frame your positions in it in and
dishonest way.
You're seeing it time and time again and
it exposes the problem with medium look.
I went to the aspen ideas festival last
week,
which is a whole story in and of itself,
but I was interviewed there by a
journalist from the atlantic monthly and
it was a relatively long form interview.
I think we talked for 40 minutes,
something like that,
and it's going to be edited now.
I trusted her.
I trust her now.
Whether that'll be how that will play
out in the final edit.
I don't know because she won't be the
only one making the decision.
Well,
the question is,
should have I done it?
Well,
look,
it was the aspen ideas festival to
different audience.
It's left leaning.
I thought,
well maybe I'll go talk to a left
leading audience.
People are always criticizing me for not
doing that.
I usually don't do it because I don't
get invited,
but so I went and talked to them.
It's like barry weiss interviewed me in
front of the aspen ideas festival and
that was long form uncut and put it on
the web and so maybe that was useful.
The atlantic thing.
Well,
it might be good.
We'll see.
It does expose me to the risk though
because it will be edited so it was wise
to do it.
Look,
I've been fortunate so far,
despite the fact that I've been taken
out of context at times and fairly
significant proportion of times,
but not the overwhelming majority of
times.
The net consequence of all of that has
been to engage more and more people into
complex dialogue as far as I can tell,
so that's the good.
That's the good.
It doesn't mean that the strategy that
I've implemented so far is the only
strategy that will work into the future.
We can also clearly establish it.
You didn't plan any of this to happen,
this,
this whole thing that happened from you
opposing that bill and then going to
where you are.
How many years later now?
Two years.
Two years almost.
That's fucking crazy.
Yeah.
I mean you think about the
transformation of your life and your.
Your public image.
I mean it's unprecedented.
I don't.
I can't think of a single public
intellectual that has gone from being a
universal university professor to being
essentially a household name.
I mean,
you get brought up With at least my
circle of friends all the time and
people that I run into all the time.
I can't tell you how many people have
run into after comedy shows or in an
airport that they talk to me about you.
So this is a mainstream thing and not
just no precedent.
No.
Well,
it's partly,
you know,
that's also part of it,
the conseqUeNces of this technology.
It's like,
yes,
you know,
like in 2013,
I thought,
huh,
I wonder what will happen if I put my
lectures up on youtube.
It's like beware man.
And that's what I thought when I made
the bill see 16 videos.
I got up at like two in the morning.
I thought this is bloody well driving me
crazy.
that damn university is going to force a
UNconscious bias retraining,
which is not a validated process by any
stretch of the imagination on its
employees.
And I worked for the university and I'm
a psychologist.
So
what is the what's,
why are they doing that?
Why would they do that?
They did do that to silence that are
protesting.
Are they doing that because they want to
enforce a certain type of behavior,
why they think there's two reasons.
I think that there's some genuine
concern for the dispossessed and then
there's some hatred for the successful
and some envy and some resentment.
It's like everything that people do,
it's complicated,
you know,
but the pathology is well that the hr
types,
for example at the university think it's
okay for them to read train other people
about their hypothetical views on the
off chance that they might be racist and
and forcing them to admit that they're
racist by making them agree to
participate in the training.
I don't think that,
but for me that waSn't even the.
The issue,
although it was an issue.
The issue is we can't measure
unconscious bias reliably and validly.
I'm a psychologist and a research
psychologist.
I know the literature,
that's a misuse of it.
It's a misuse of it.
And the damn university was doing it.
They were hiring consUltants who didn't
know what the hell they were talking
about.
Let me ask you this.
If they are,
this is a universities,
this is a,
an establishment for higher learning.
How can they possibly act on something
when there's no clear evidence that it's
real,
that it works,
that it's effective and they're doing it
just to make people happy or just to
make themselves happy or just to
reinforce an idea that they want
to be told.
That's the thing.
It's part of.
For me,
it was part of the head gemini of the
radical left.
It's like,
no,
you're not going to do that at the
university.
I work out without me telling people
that there's no warrant for that from
the psychological community.
So anyways,
I got up at two in the morning and made
these videos.
I thought,
well,
let's see what happens if I make these
videos.
It's like,
well,
this is back to the technology issue.
It's like I didn't know what youtube was
when I put my videos on it.
You didn't know what youtube was.
Well,
you know what I.
No one knows what youtube is.
Now the thing,
we'll look at what happened to you.
You have a million,
billion and a half downloads a year.
It's like you're definitely riding a
giant wave.
like what have you predicted this 15
yeArs ago?
No,
so.
So you know you're in the right place
and the right time and you're a very
interesting interview because while,
especially for long form because you're
very,
very curious,
but also very,
very tough.
Like it's interesting watching you
because if you don't understand
something you will go after the person
and you're not doing it in a vindictive
way,
but you're quite a formidable interview
and I've been trying to figure out why
you're so successful and like you're a
lot smarter than anyone might think,
which is quite interesting.
So you're a weird combination because
you know your persona doesn't shout
intEllectual but you're damn smart and
you're tough as a bloody boot and you
ask rudy pop provocative questions and
not because you're provocative and so
your personality in this long form seem
to suit each other really well.
You're also really good at pursuing
things you don't understand instead of
assuming that you know what you're
talking about,
so you take the listeners on a journey,
right?
It's an exploratory journey,
but fundamentally what's propelled you
to superstardom in some sense is not
just your ability,
which is non trivial,
but the fact that you're on this giant
technological wave and you're one of the
first adopters and I'm in the same
situation where first adopters of
technology,
that's as revolutionary as the gutenberg
printing press,
and so that's all unfolding in real
time.
IT's like,
look at what's happening.
Yeah,
well,
the spoken word is now as powerful as
the written word that's never happened
before in human history and we're on the
cutting edge of that.
For better or worse.
That's a very good way to put it.
The spoken word is power.
Yeah,
and maybe even more so.
Well,
he's so accessible to people that don't
have the time to read well or stuck in
traffic or or.
And here's another possibility may be 10
times as many people can listen to
complex information as can read complex
information in terms of their ability to
process it.
Sure could easily.
We don't know.
Maybe it's maybe it's the same.
Certainly easier to listen to a book on
tape for me than it is to read a book.
Yeah.
Well,
so,
so the question is for how many people
is that true?
And I would say it might be true for
the,
for the majority of people.
And then people are doing hybrids,
you know,
so because you can sync your book with
audible.
Right?
So they read when they have the time,
but then when they have found time,
which is also a major component of this,
that that's the time when you're driving
or the time when you're doing dishes is
now all of a sudden you can educate
yourself during that found time.
ThiS is a big revolution.
And the blowing out the bandwidth makes
a huge difference.
Because while we talked about that at
the beginning,
looks like people are more intelligent
than we thought And you and I are both
in the rest of this intellectual,
dark web.
That's kind of what unites us.
Hey is everybody has an independent
platform.
Virtually everybody,
they have an idiosyncratic view point.
They,
they're interested in having discussions
and pursuing the furtherance of their
knowledge even though they Might have a
priority ideological commitments.
Sam does and I suppose I do and and ben
shapiro certainly does,
but they're still interested in having
the discussion,
but more importantly they're
capitalizing on the long form and the
fact that that's possible is a
reflection of this technological
transformation and the technological
transfer information might be utterly
profound.
It looks like it.
And so that's,
you know,
I've been trying to sort this out
because I keep thinking,
why the hell are these people coming to
listen to what I'm saying?
It's like,
well,
I'm a guru.
You know,
I'm a sage.
It's something like that.
It's like,
don't be thinking that first.
Think if there's situational
determinants first.
Take your damn personality out of it.
Okay.
What's going on?
Oh yes,
this is all fostered by youtube and
fostered by podcasts.
What's so new about that?
No bandwidth restrictions,
no barrier to entrance,
possibility of dialogue because people
cut up the youtube videos into chunks
and make their own comments on it.
It's a whole new communication
technology.
Also a lack of interference by
executives and producers and all these
different people that have their own
bias unmediated.
Yes.
Unmediated as giant.
Yeah.
Well,
and that's all part of.
Part of the reason you're so popular too
is like you just put this on like so
you've got exactly the right of
a competent production because there's
nothing access about it.
Like it's competent,
but no more than that.
I know that's by design,
but you also don't edit it.
It's like what you see is what you get.
It's like everyone is relieved by that.
We can make our own damn decisions.
do I think that's very important?
If you're going to have a conversation
with someone is honest,
you can't decide what to leave in,
what to take out and it's just,
well,
that's partly also why I deal with the
press the way I do.
Like if I'm going to have a full
conversation,
it's like I'm willing to take the hits
and I understand what you're saying,
but that's one of the reasons why it
frustrates me so much is that I see what
they're doing and I'm like,
what you're doing is ancient.
What you're doing is it's,
it's.
This is what people did 20 years ago,
30 years ago for.
you can't really do that anymore.
He can't misrepresent.
People used to be able to.
If you were in the press,
you can take people quoted out of
context,
do whatever the fuck you wanted to put
an article about them and they couldn't
do a god damn thing about it.
It happened to me in 19 boy.
It was like 99.
I did a comedy cd that came out and this
woman wrote an article about it and it
just.
She just lied.
She lied about my perspective.
She lied about the bits,
she misquoted the bits.
She didn't just paraphrase them,
she changed what the bits were to make
them know misogynist or hateful or
whatever it was.
And in doing so I,
there was no recourse.
There was nothing that I could do about
that.
I'm like,
wow,
I'd never experienced that before.
I was like,
this is stunning.
And then I found out this person did
that a lot and this is what she did and
there's ultimate power that comes with
being the person that has the pen being
the person that has the typewriter and
you,
you're the person who works for the
boston globe or whatever the publication
is,
that that is something that existed
forever,
you know,
and that you had to be either a friend
of the press,
you had to play ball,
you had to,
you had a bend to their will,
you have to do what they wanted you to
do and they could misrepresent you and
choose to paint you in any way they
like.
And it's one of the reasons why I don't
do anything anymore.
We don't do any interviews anymore.
I don't do anything,
I don't want to do anything.
Just I do enough,
man.
You want to know about me?
Fucking there's a thousand Podcasts,
there's more than a thousand years.
I think there's,
there's 1100 and there's a bunch of
other ones too.
Let's just doesn't make any sense.
It so well that,
that's,
that,
that it may also be the position that I
increasingly find myself yet I think
it's the right position because then the
misrepresentations don't exist anymore.
So then the only problem is the dispute
over the actual ideological
conversations or the,
uh,
the actual concept.
But you know,
the thing is,
you know,
you made a point there that's quite
interesting is like we are in a new
media landscape.
So now if someone comes out as a,
as a media figure with some
institutional credibility and
misrepresents,
it's exposed.
And so then the question is how much
risk should you shoulder to expose the
proclivity for misrepresentation
and answer to that might be some now it
might be moving,
you know,
maybe I've done enough of that.
I mean,
it would be easier for me in many ways
if I just stopped doing it,
but,
but there is some utility in having it
play out and so while,
so I'm trying to.
I'm trying to only take those
opportunities that appear to have more
benefit than risk and when I'm defining
benefit,
well the question is then what
constitutes benefit and I guess what
constitutes benefit is while that would
further the attempts that I making to
bring information to a vast number of
people that could conceivably help them
stabilize and improve their individual
lives,
that's worth a certain amount of risk.
Well,
it certainly increases your profile,
increases your profile and even if you
have 60 percent of these people are
gonna get a bad perception of you.
Forty percent of these people that never
heard of you,
now we're going to understand who you
are because they do further
investigation.
So there's some benefit in that.
But the,
the negative.
I mean I've,
I get text messages from random people
that I was friends with years ago.
Let's say there's Jordan Peterson has
just such a lying sack of shit and he's
like,
I don't even know who the fuck you are.
And then second of all like,
why are you contacting me?
You're not even saying hi.
You're saying Jordan Peterson is a mrs.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well there's an emergency at hand.
He's a scam artist.
He's a fraud.
He's and I'm like,
wow.
And so they'll see an interview,
you know like the,
the jim jefferies clip,
which is a minute long or whatever it
is,
or the vice piece or the initial kathy
newman piece and they just formed this
determined position on you and then read
hit pieces on you.
And then this is where they take their
opinion out.
This is where it's from.
It's and it's,
I,
I feel like these are the last gasps of
a dying medium.
I really do.
I just,
I think too,
I don't,
I don't think that people appreciate it.
I think the people that are listening to
this that do appreciate long form
conversations and with all warts and
all,
all the ugliness and the mistakes and
the critical errors and the people that
appreciate that,
they,
they have a real hate for being lied to
because it's it.
It changed when
when you're being treated as if they're
stupid,
which they aren't.
Yeah,
that's both.
It's just,
it's,
it's deceptive when you,
when you edit someone and take their
words out of context and change them
around,
you're being deceptive.
Did The New York times did that again
this week?
They had some philosophy.
Professor from Hong Kong university
wrote a piece on me and he.
He took,
they quoted me a was a sentence.
The first phrase was in quotes and then
there were some joining words and then
the second phrase was in quotes and
the third phrase was in quotes and the
three quotes added up to a statement
that bore no resemblance whatsoever to
what I was saying.
How can they do that in the New York
times?
That seems to me to be something should
be the the
synthesis of what they think they can
do.
I think they're killing their brand so
fast that they can't put it.
It's so disturbing to me as a person
who's been a fan of the New York times
forever.
I just don't understand how they could
allow that to happen.
How could you allow your.
What is the gold standard for
journalism?
How could you allow it to become
something that willfully misrepresent
someone but they never did to push an
ideology or did put my book on the New
York times bestseller list?
It's quite comical.
How's that possible?
Oh,
they have rules which they don't
disclose,
but one of them apparently is.
Well,
if the book is published in Canada and
distributed in the United States,
then it doesn't count.
Even though they've had books like that
on the New York times best seller list
before and I think,
okay,
well is this bad or good?
It's like,
well,
it's bad because to the degree that I
might want to be on the New York times
best seller list,
although I haven't been losing any sleep
over it,
but you're selling.
I know how many books are selling.
Yeah,
it's basically been the best selling
book in the world since january know
it's gone up and down to some degree,
but fundamentally it should be the
number one New York times best selling
book.
So they,
they,
they have their reasons and.
But I look at that and I think,
oh well you can only do that 10 times
until you're done.
Like because it's a fatal error.
You have the gold standard for
measurement.
You're not measuring properly.
You're burning up your brand.
You think,
well we're the New York times so we can
burn up our brand.
It's like,
no,
you can't.
Newsweek is gone.
Time magazine is a shallow is a shell of
its former self.
Like the big things disappear and they
disappeared when they get crooked and
ideologically rigid.
And so that's what's happening at the
New York times.
Not with everyone there,
but with plenty of them.
and it'll die faster than people think,
but it's so confusing to me that it
didn't use to be that.
Yup.
And now it is.
And they just responding to this new
world where you have to have click bait
journalism and some people are
struggling to find people to actually
buy physical newspapers,
which is two different things.
It's hard to say like because maybe see,
it's weird because you don't have to
resort to click bait because these long
form discussions are the antithesis of
clickbait,
but are they struggling in terms of like
how many people buy their newspaper?
Oh,
absolutely.
Every newspaper,
the newspapers in Canada went cap in
hand to the federal government for
subsidies about six months ago because
they're dying so fast and so some of it
is they're being supplanted by
technology.
ThAt's a huge part of it,
but as they are supplanted,
they get more desperate.
They publish more polarizing stories
that works in the short term to garner
more views,
but it alienates people from the brand
and speeds their demise.
Classic death spiral of a big of a big
organization and that's going to clean
things out like mad.
I mean I don't know where cnn is in the
cable news rankings now,
a cable show rankings,
but it keeps falling but it's falling in
the rankings as cable itself
disintegrates and dies.
Why do you need cable tv?
No one needs cable
t the only people who have cable tv or
the people who figure haven't figured
out yet that you can replace it entirely
online for like one 10th the price with,
with
less hassle.
But the irony is people want a location
they can go to to find out what's going
on in the world and this is the one
thing that they use to represent and you
know,
I mean I don't think fox news is any
better.
I think you,
you just have these ideological extremes
left and right.
And I remember very clearly watching the
election coverage before the election,
like leading up to the election,
I would go fox news and then I go see an
ent.
I just would go back and forth with them
on my cable and I would just be
laughing.
I'll be like,
what is really happening in the world?
Because I'm getting two different
stories.
I'm getting Russia and I'm getting
hillary's emails.
This is,
I don't know what the fuck is,
what?
What is happening?
I'm getting pussy grabbing and I'm
getting,
you know,
a bengazi yup.
this is what I'm getting and I don't
understand like why this is obviously
ideological.
This is not just.
It might be that as the technology is
supplanted,
the ideological polarization increases
as the thing dies,
right?
They're struggling for anyone to pay
attention and this is the way they have
to do it to ensure.
And I think what's happening on the
other side which is decide you occupy,
say is that a new technology that's long
form that deals with many of those
problems is emerging and it's going to
emerge.
It's going to be victorious,
but in the main might already be
victorious in the meantime.
Bad stuff still exists in the digital
world.
you know,
and then you're getting a lot of the
articles that are written about you.
People are absorbing these articles,
not from a physical form.
You're getting it from.
From digital.
Yeah.
Well okay.
So then the sense is,
well do you have fundamental trust in
the judgment of your fellow man,
let's say in my answer to that is yes,
because although I've been pilloried to
a great degree by the radical types in
the commentary in the classic
journalists,
the comments with regards to me on
youtube are 50 to one in my favor and
that's even the case when the ideologues
put up videos about me,
they're designed to discredit me and
I've sold a million and a half books.
It's going to be published in 40
countries and thousands of people are
coming to my lectures and so I would say
the attempts to discredit me aren't
working so and now I think that's
because that even like even if you go to
youtube,
you can see Jordan Peterson smashes
leftist journalist,
you know as a clickbait thing.
Someone's taken a two minute clip from a
video and they put it out in there using
that clickbait headlines to attract
attention.
It's like it does attract attention and
that probably even further as
polarization,
but I think that most people,
enough people,
that's the prayer.
Enough people are going for the long
form thorough discussion so that the
sensible will will triumph.
That's what I'm hoping for.
the sensible.
We'll try them.
No,
I agree and I think that is what's
happening and I think that's why this 50
to one number exists is that there,
but the number one in that 50,
the $50 versus the 50 people that are
actually understanding what's going on
and agreeing with you versus the number
one that are trying to willfully
misrepresent you.
They still exist and they're loud and
they're fighting to be right and this is
one of the things that people love to
do.
They love to fight to be right.
Instead of examining their position and
wondering whether or not they are taking
you out of context and misrepresenting
your positions to the world willfully
and doing so in order to paint a
negative picture of you that does not
act accurately represent who you are,
what you stand for that,
but by doing this,
they're destroying virtue without any of
the work.
They're Also destroying their own
credibility.
That's the thing.
This is what's devastating in there
trying to win.
They're killing themselves,
right?
Well,
and that's a good.
that's a good motif for the entire
conversation.
It's like try hard to.
Hard to when you kill yourself.
You were talking last night when we
were,
when we were over dinner,
you said that one of the most deadly
things for a fighter to do is to
overestimate his his own position.
Underestimate your abilities.
if you overestimate your abilities,
you,
you're,
you're in deep,
deep trouble because you're going to get
a wake up call and objectivity is one of
the most critical aspects of
development.
You have to be.
You have to be objectively assessing
your strengths and weaknesses at every
step of the way.
Now it's bravo bravado,
right?
I'm trying to prove how am so powerful,
so powerful.
It's an ego shield and that's why I was
saying that the ego is the enemy we're
talking about.
Right.
So,
you know,
I want to get into this because this is
a.
I think this is a fascinating thing with
you personally that your diet,
you're on this carnival.
Yeah.
Now.
Okay.
So I want to preface that with
something.
I am not a dietary expert,
so I've now speaking as an uninformed
citizen.
Yes.
Well this is anecdotal evidence from a
human being is dealt with autoimmune
issues their whole life.
Yes.
You have done this for how long now?
I've been on a pure carnivore diet for
about two months and a pretty,
a very,
very low carb greens only modified
carnivore diet for about a year.
so in the year
and,
and the low carb diet for two years
years.
So from the time that I've known you,
I've known you for what,
two and a half years now.
Something like that.
Yeah.
When I first met you,
you had much more weight on your body.
You look different.
And you were back then you're eating
like standard diet,
normal people guess pasta,
bread,
chicken,
whatever.
You shifted over to only meet and
greens.
I saw you on.
I'm like,
you look fantastic.
whAt are you doing?
And you're lIke,
I changed my diet.
I only meet and greens.
And I was like,
wow,
that's fascinating.
Well,
I felt like,
okay,
what you're doing is cutting out refined
sugars and all these different things
that are problematic.
Preservatives,
all the bullshit process foods and
you're having this extreme health
benefit.
And I was like,
wow,
that's really excellent.
You're showing great discipline.
Then you
decided to take it to another place and
cut out the greens.
What was the motivation for cutting out
the greens?
All of the motivation for this has been
my experience with my daughter because
she has an unbelievably serious
autoimmune disease.
I just talked to her this,
what is it called?
Well,
it's arthritis,
but it there's.
There's way more to it than that,
but the arthritis was the major set of
symptoms.
She had 40 affected joints and she had
to have her hip replaced and our ankle
replaced.
When she was 15 and 16,
and so she basically hobbled around on
two broken legs for two years in extreme
agony and that was just a tiny fraction
of the,
of the whole set of problems.
I just talked to her this morning.
She's in chicago,
looks like she has to have her ankle
replacement replaced,
so that's next on the horizon,
but.
But apart from that she is doing so well
now.
It is absolutely beyond comprehension.
So she's.
She's,
she's very trIm.
She had a baby,
but she's very trim.
She's down to about 100,
18 pounds.
She's about five foot six.
She's just glowing with health.
All of her autoimmune system symptoms
are gone,
all of them.
And she was also seriously depressed,
severely depressed,
way worse than you think.
She couldn't stay awake for more than
about six hours without taking ritalin.
And she was dying and I had a cousin,
my cousin's daughter,
she died when she was 30 from an
associated autoimmune condition.
So there's a fair bit of this in our
family.
It was bloody bleak.
I'll tell you and my wife always had a
suspicion that this was dietary related,
you know,
and well,
we did notice that when makayla was
young,
if she ate oranges or strawberries,
that she'd get a rash like there were
there were there,
and then when she developed arthritis,
if she ate oranges in particular,
that would definitely cause a flare.
It waS the only thing we could see.
The problem is is that in order to
identify a dietary component,
the response has to be pretty quick
after you eat the thing,
like if it's two days later,
how the hell are you going to figure
that out?
A lot of these responses appear to be
delayed for four days and last a month,
so good luck figuring that out.
Anyways,
mckayla noticed about three years ago
now,
more than that now,
five years ago,
she was at concordia university and
struggling with her with her illness and
all the associations associated
problems.
She noticed that around exam time she
was starting to develop real skin
problems and my cousin's daughter,
who I mentioned had really bad skin
problems and wounds that wouldn't heal
and that was partly part of the process
that eventually killed her and she
thought,
oh,
it must be stress,
and then she thought,
wait a second,
I really changed my diet when I'm
studying.
All I do is eat bagels.
All I do is eat bread sandwiches.
She thought maybe it's the bread,
so she cut out gluten first and it had a
remarkable effect,
like really remarkable effect.
And then she,
she went on a radical elimination diet
all the way down to nothing but chicken
and broccoli and then her symptoms
started to drop off one by one like and
and like one of the things that happened
is she started to wake up in the
morning.
She started to be able to stay awake all
day when you're only staying for six
hours with ritalin,
stay awake all day.
That's like having a life.
And so a whole bunch of things improved.
Their depression went away and I've had
depression since I was 13.
Probably and very severe and I've
treated it a variety of ways.
Some of them quite successfully,
but it's been a constant battle and my
father had it and his father had it and
it's all just rife in my family and my
wife has autoimmune problems and hurt.
You say depression?
Define it.
Oh,
would you define it?
Because that's a word that's a blanket
term.
Yeah.
Well,
imagine.
Imagine that you wake up and that you
remember that all your family was killed
in a horrible accident yesterday.
The you would feel that even if nothing
was wrong.
Yes.
Just just worse than that because.
Well,
one of the things mckayla told me what
she thought,
well,
what's it like to be depressed?
We imagine you have a dog and you really
love the dog and then the dog dies and
then about two,
three years ago our dog died and that
was mckayla's dog and she really liked
that dog and she said that was bad,
but it's nowhere near as bad as being
depressed.
And I asked her to,
at one point when she was about 15 or
16,
I said,
look,
you've got a choice kid.
Here's the choice.
You can either have depression or
arthritis,
which,
what I'll take the arthritis.
Well that was after she'd lost two
joints.
So it was no joke.
It's no joke,
man.
It,
there isn't any.
No,
I wouldn't say that.
I wouldn't say there's nothing worse,
cause worse is a very deep hole.
But it's bad that people will prove you
wrong,
right?
Oh yes.
Definitely.
Worse squares is a deep hole.
Anyways,
her depression went away.
All of these symptoms went away and like
radically.
So what changed her from chicken and
broccoli to carnivore?
Well,
she,
she kept experimenting and she got very
sensitive to all sorts of foods in the
aftermath of that too.
So this is why I wouldn't recommend that
anybody does this casually because we
don't understand much about it.
But the upshot was that,
well,
she kept,
she kept experimenting and she started
to add things back and take them away.
And sometimes when she added things,
the results were devastating.
She was like done for a month.
She eat the wrong thing,
done for a month.
All the symptoms came back.
The depression came back.
She thought that her whole dietary
theory was wrong because it lasted so
long,
so extreme and it's like,
it took her two years to figure out that
really what she could eat was beef and
greens and then she figured out that she
could only eat beef.
So greens themselves.
Well,
look.
So what happened?
Happened.
Okay.
So two years ago she said,
dad,
you have tried this diet because you
have a lot of the same symptoms as me.
now I didn't have arthritis,
but I had a lot of the other symptoms
and I thought,
oh christ,
okay mckayla,
I can try anything for a month.
She said,
try it for a month.
I thought,
okay,
whatever.
I can hang by my fingernails from the
window sill for a month.
It's like,
it's just not that big a deal.
And so I,
I eliminated.
I went on really low carb diet.
Okay,
so this is what happened.
I had gastric reflux disorder and I was
snoring quite a lot.
I stopped snoring the first week.
I thought,
what the hell that supposed to be
associated with weight loss because I
had gained some weight.
I weighed about 212 pounds and I'm what?
six?
One and a half,
so that was my maximum weight,
stopped snoring,
which was a great relief to tammy that
just quit and that's a big deal,
right?
Because if you snore,
you have sleep apnea and then you don't
sleep.
right.
It's like not a good thing.
Okay.
Next I started waking up in the
mornings.
I'd never been able to wake up in the
mornings my whole life.
I always had to stumble to the shower
and then maybe I could wake up and took
me an hour and I felt terrible and so
all of a sudden I woke up,
but it was like,
oh,
look at that.
I'm awake in the morning and I'm
clearheaded and things aren't gloomy and
horrible.
It's like,
well,
isn't that weird?
Then I lost seven pounds the first month
I thought seven pounds.
That's a lot in a month and I'd already
gone for a whole year on a sugar free
diet and I didn't lose any weight and
I'd been exercised sugar free,
but did you cut out bread?
no.
No.
It was just no desserts,
no sugar,
no,
and I thought that might do.
It didn't make any difference at all.
Seven pounds.
Well then then I lost seven pounds in
the next month.
Then I lost seven pounds.
The next month I lost seven pounds every
month for seven months.
Like I'd throw away all my clothes.
I went back to the same weight that I
was when I was 26 and my psoriasis
disappeared and I had floaters in my
right eye and they cleared up and then
the last thing that went away from me,
I was still having a bitch of a time
with mood regulation and that sucked
because when I changed my diet,
I didn't respond to antidepressants
properly anymore.
They weren't working and so although I
was getting better physically on a
variety of ways,
like radical ways,
I was really having a bitch of a time
regulating my mood and I was having
sporadic,
really negative reactions to food when I
ate something I shouldn't.
So that took about a year and a half to
clear up and I was still really anxious
in the morning up to three months ago,
like horribly,
and then it would get better all day.
People said,
well,
you're under a lot of stress.
And I thought,
yeah,
yeah.
I've been under a lot of stress for like
10 years.
It's like it's a lot,
but it Wasn't any more stressful than
helping my daughter deal with her
illness.
That's for sure that no,
this is something different.
and she saId to me quit eating greens
and I thought,
oh really?
Jesus mckayla,
meeting cucumbers,
lettuce,
broccoli and chicken and beef.
It's like I have to cut out the god damn
greens,
just like try it for a month.
Okay.
Within a week I was 25 percent less
anxious in the morning,
within two weeks,
75 percent.
And I've been better every single day.
I'm better now probably than I've ever
been in my life and I haven't been
taking antidepressants for a whole year,
so I don't know what.
And I weighed 162 pounds like I have.
No,
I'm,
I'm and I've actually gained
musculature.
I've been doing some working out,
but not a lot.
And so I can sleep six hours a night.
no problem.
I wake up in the morning,
I'm awake.
If I take a 15 minute nap.
That used to take me an hour to recover
from,
that's gone.
Here's the coolest thing.
I've had gum disease since I was 25.
That's been serious enough to have.
I've had to have minor surgical
intervention scraping and that sort of
thing to keep it at bay.
It's gone.
I checked with my dentist before this
last tour,
no inflammation.
And that's associated with heart disease
by the way,
gum inflammation and ginger vidas.
It's a good risk factor for heart
disease.
It means the systemic inflammation is
gone and it's not supposed to happen.
You're not supposed to recover from
ginger bitus have my gums are in perfect
shape.
It's like,
what the hell?
So here's what happened.
I lost 50 pounds.
That's a lot,
right?
I'm nowhere near as hungry as I used to
be.
My appetite's probably fallen by 70
percent.
I don't get blood sugar dysregulation.
Problems.
I need way less sleep.
I get up in the morning and I'm fine.
I'm not anxious.
I'm not depressed.
I don't have psoriasis.
My legs were numb on the sides.
That's gone.
I'm certainly intellectually at my best
at the moment,
which is a great relief.
Especially doing this tour.
Depression is gone.
I'm stronger,
I can swim better
and my gum disease is gone.
It's like,
what the hell?
And you've done.
You've done no blood work so you don't
know what your lippert lipid profile is.
No.
I'll get that done again when I go back.
Take any vitamins.
Nope.
No,
I eat beef and salt and water.
That's it.
And I never cheat ever.
Not even a little bit.
No soda,
no wine drink club soda.
Well that's done.
It's still water.
Well,
you know when you're down to that level
though,
it's not joe joe.
There's there's club soda which is
really bubbly.
There's perrier,
which is sort of bubbly.
There's flatwater and there's hot water.
Those distinctions start to become
important.
It's crazy where we ate last night and I
ate what you ate.
Just a.
We both had that giant tomahawk.
I had wine though.
Yeah.
I'm.
I'm curious about thIs.
I'm very curious to try it,
but I eat a lot of vegetables,
but I don't have any problems like
health.
Hey man.
Like I'm not a disclaimer.
Number two,
I am not recommending this to anyone.
However,
I have had,
however,
I have had many,
many people come up to me on the tour
and say,
look,
I've been following your daughter's blog
and I've lost 100 pounds.
I think what?
you lost a hundred pounds.
I lost a hundred pounds in six months.
I talked to a woman yesterday.
She lost 15 pounds in one month.
She was 70.
It's like,
this is.
Here's a question.
Why is everyone fat and stupid?
That's a question,
man,
because it's new.
Is it?
Yes,
it is.
It's new and it's not sedentary
lifestyle that that hypothesis doesn't
seem to hold water.
There's something wrong with the way
we're eating and the.
What's wrong is that we're eating way
too many carbohydrates.
I think
no expat shift,
the elimination of most carbohydrates
lives made a big shift in my life and I
do cheat occasionally with bread and
occasionally with pasta I will.
I will go off with ice cream and things
along those lines,
but most of the time I'm just eating
meat and vegetables most of the time and
then I'll have a cheat day,
like once a week or something like that.
Especially if I go to dinner,
I'll have a little pasta and it doesn't
seem to mess me up too bad,
but I do feel shitty after I do it.
It's like for simple mouth pleasure.
I'm allowing myself to feel tired
afterwards.
Yeah,
that's a big one man.
Yeah.
But like I.
Well really I.
And it's so interesting too,
like I can't believe I can wake up in
the morning.
I get that's never happened to me in my
whole life in when I was a kid.
13,
12,
had a bitch of a time waking up in the
morning.
It was just brutal.
I just thought that's how it was.
This is what
I mean.
Again,
I'm not a nutritionist either,
but what's fascinating to me is I
haven't heard any negative stories about
people doing this.
Have a negative story.
Okay.
One of the things that both mckayla and
I noticed was that when we restricted
our diet and then eat something,
we weren't supposed to,
the reaction to eating what we weren't
supposed to was absolutely catastrophic.
Would it show?
What did you switch to or what did you
eat rather?
Um,
well,
the worst response I think we're
allergic to or allergic,
whatever the hell this is.
Having an inflammatory response to
something called sulfites and we had
some apple cider that had sulfites in it
and that was really not good.
Like I was done for a month.
That was the first time I talked to sam
harris.
You were done for a month.
Oh yeah.
It took me out for a month.
It was awful.
Really?
Yeah.
So and so this is right before this
whole truth conversation with sam harris
had dirt and the mud
during the day I talked to sam was like
the worst day of my life,
not because of talking to sam,
but it was just physical.
Oh jesus,
I was so dead,
but I didn't want to not do it.
Because cider like,
well,
what was it fights in?
What was it doing to you?
Oh it,
it.
It produced an overwhelming sense of
impending doom and I seriously been
overwhelming,
like there's no way I could've lived
like that if that would have lasted for
seeding.
Mckayla knew by that point that it would
probably only last a month and I was
like a month to month fucking cider or I
didn't sleep that month.
I didn't sleep for 25 days.
I didn't sleep at all.
I didn't sleep at all for 25 days.
How that possible?
The all county,
how it's possible you lay in bed frozen
in something approximating terror for
eight hours and then you get up.
Oh my god.
Yeah.
This is some fucking cider from sites.
What we thought,
yeah,
I mean look again,
I don't know what the hell I'm talking
about.
Okay.
This is all a mystery to me.
The fact that my daughter was so sick.
See,
the one thing that I did know,
because I scoured the literature on
arthritis when she was a kid,
the scientific literature and because we
were interested in the dietary
connection and the only thing I could
find that was reliable was that if
people with arthritis fasted,
their symptoms reliably went away.
Now it's actually a well documented
finding,
but then if they started to eat again
and there was symptoms came back,
I thought,
well,
what the hell does it not matter what
they eat?
They can't be reactive to everything.
It's like,
no,
but they can be reactive to almost
everything and the difference between
everything and almost everything.
That's a big difference and so mckayla
seems to be maybe me too and tammy's on
the same diet because she has autoimmune
problems on her side of the family and
so mckayla seemed to inherit all of
them.
Your skin looks better.
Oh jesus.
Joe,
I'm waiting you.
You look like more vibrant.
It's very strange.
You're welcome,
but my point is you're saying that there
is a.
There is problems with his diet,
but that doesn't seem to be a problem
with the dyads.
He was a problem with deviating from the
diet that your body becomes accustomed
with.
well,
one of the hypothesis that we've been
pursuing,
and there's some justification for this
in the scientific literature,
is that the reason that you lay on
layers of fat because the fat acts as a
buffer between you and the toxic things
that you're eating because fat is
actually an organ.
It has functions other than merely the
storage of of of calories,
and maybe when you strip out that
protective layer,
then you're more sensitive to what you
shouldn't be eating.
This is all speculative hypotheses,
right?
Or maybe you sensitize yourself by
removing it from your constant diet.
I don't bloody well know.
Well,
I would think it would be much more
likely that because you think about
people who are alcoholics,
they develop a tolerance to alcohol.
You get off of that and then you have a
drink and your tolerances are shot,
and then you immediately have a adverse
reaction to the alcohol.
Same thing with marijuana.
When people do it all the time,
your body becomes tolerant.
Well,
I think,
I think that the layering of fat on
might be part of the tolerance
mechanism,
so it's not merely a matter of caloric
intake.
It's a matter of of toxic caloric
intake,
buffered by whatever it is that fat is
doing as a neuroendocrin Oregon.
But again,
like I said,
I said I'm out of my depth here,
but you know,
the whole,
everyone's out of their depth that god
damn food pyramid was made by the
department of agriculture,
not the department of health.
It wasn't predicated on any scientific
studies whatsoever.
We should have,
we shouldn't be eating massive
quantities of corn syrup.
We eat,
we eat way too many carbohydrates with
mckayla posted a paper the other day,
a doctor,
uh,
successfully treated type one diabetes
with a carnivore diet type one,
not type two.
So that's bloody impressive.
Yeah,
it's,
it's very curious to me because you're
talking about one adverse reaction,
which is when you deviated from the
diet.
What I'm talking about is when I read
people's accounts of trying this diet,
it's almost universally positive,
but again,
that's a problem.
Well,
it's probably anecdote,
right?
I mean,
I'm not sure and it's the same with all
these stories that I'm collecting as I'm
touring people.
Lots of people have come up to me and
said,
look,
I lost 45 pounds in the last three
months.
I think.
Yeah,
I think it's shocking to me.
I think,
well,
what do you make of that?
And say,
well,
I can't believe it.
Well,
who can all couldn't believe it?
50 pounds.
It's like,
first of all,
I didn't know I had 50 pounds to lose,
you know,
I thought I was maybe 20 pounds heavier
than I should have been.
Should have been won 85,
something like that.
I Guess that's 25 to 30 pounds.
That was the maximum I thought.
No,
no,
I lost.
I met one 62 and I was at 2:12.
So what's that?
50 50 balance.
Has a lot of weight.
Jesus.
I threw all my clothes away.
It's.
I can't believe it.
When I was nine,
I was like,
you're so slim.
Like your.
Your stomach is completely flat and
it's.
And this is not a lean,
mean fighting man in.
you're not a an exercise fanatic.
It's not like you're starving yourself.
It's not like you're going,
I'm not having fun.
That's another thing I should say to
people.
If you want to try a diet like this,
you eat enough meat and fat so you are
not hungry.
Okay?
You can't get hungry.
You're not eating enough.
If you're hungry,
if you're hungry,
you're going to cheat and it's gonna
drive you stark raving mad.
The other thing that was really cool is
like,
I really liked sweets,
like I've kind of lived on peanut butter
sandwiches and chocolate milk.
Not,
not really,
but that was my go to food,
you know,
both of which were terrible for me,
but after I stopped eating carbohydrates
for a month,
the carbohydrate cravings went away.
You know,
last night when we were out for dinner,
somebody ordered bread pudding and I
bloody love bread pudding with caramel
and ice cream,
so it was sitting there and I could
smell it and I thought I could go all
fantastic Mr.
Fox on that bread pudding and just tear
it down in about 15 seconds,
but it wasn't,
it wasn't as intense as a craving for a
cigarette if you're next ex smoker.
It was like be really nice to eat that.
But like my appetite declined by about
75 percent.
That's been permanent.
That's been.
So there's a perverse thing for you.
I eat way less and now I'm not as
hungry.
Okay.
Well how does that make sense?
Well,
you're not eating way less eating way
less thing because you had a 30 ounce
steak last night.
yes,
yes.
I'm,
I'm doing my best not to be hungry.
Although it didn't look like it was $30.
No,
no,
no.
It was a small 30 state.
Well,
I think it starts out 30 ounces before
they cook.
It loses a considerable.
Right.
Very fatty.
But that's the other thing to you.
You must have to get a lot of fat.
I eat fatty cuts of steak and mckayla is
buying directly from the butcher store
and we cook that up,
cut it into small pieces and fried up
until it's crispy.
Wow.
It's actually quite delicious.
It's not bread pudding with ice cream,
but it's funny.
You mean daniel?
It's so ridiculous.
I want to.
I want your blood profile.
I want to find out what's going on with
you because one of the big myths,
misconceptions when it comes to
cholesterol and saturated fat and food
is that if you eat dietary cholesterol
that it affects your blood cholesterol
levels.
It's not super common.
Misconceptions.
Well those.
So the thing about clinical studies with
diet are virtually impossible to conduct
because you just can't.
you can't conduct a proper randomly
distributed controlled experiment is too
hard,
so a lot of what we're trying to do is
pull out information from correlations,
right?
He can't do it,
which is one of the real problems with
correlating meet with cancer and
diabetes and all these different
diseases is because people are eating a
bunch of shit with that.
They have different lifestyle profile,
like there's just endless numbers of
confounding variables and you only need
one confounding variable that's,
that's relevant to screw up the study.
You can't get that information with
correlational studies.
We try because it's impossible to do the
studies,
but how many people were incredulous?
We went,
how manY people when they're hearing
about this,
everybody,
while you are not,
but you know you're interested in this
sort of thing,
but they should be incredulous.
Like when people make absurd claims,
it's like,
oh well I had 50 health problems and I
stopped eating everything but meat and
they went away.
It's like,
oh sure.
yeah,
well it wasn't you dying so and I see
the results and I know it's an anecdote.
I bloody will understand that and I'm
highly skeptical about all of this,
but I'm telling you so that's why I'm
telling you what happened to me and what
happened to my daughter and also what
happened to my wife because she's.
Tammy was always in good shape and she's
exercised a lot and she reduced to the,
to the pure carnivore died about a month
ago.
She lost like 12 pounds and she was
already slim.
She's back to the same way she was when
she was 21.
She's,
she's like 58,
you know,
and she doesn't look 58.
I can tell you that.
So it's really fascinating.
It's really fascinating because I just,
I,
as a person who studied diet for many
years,
I would assume that you need fido
nutrients.
I would assume that you need vitamin
supplements like vitamin c for example.
It turns out if you don't eat
carbohydrates,
you don't need vitamin c.
Huh?
Who would have guessed?
How's that work?
I don't.
I don't remember mckayla outline to
paper.
For me vitamin c is necessary for
carbohydrate metabolism,
but if you don't,
if again,
remember everyone listening.
I am not an expert in this field,
so,
um,
but,
but I want you to get your blood tested
because I think,
yeah,
if be pretty funny.
If it was in good shape,
Yeah,
it would be.
I'd like to find out what your nutrient
levels are and where they're coming.
Yeah,
I mean,
what,
how much?
I'm getting a little getting a little
cramping in my toes from time to time,
so I'm not sure about potassium or
magnesium.
That's a possibility.
That's how the supplement.
It's very easy,
which is why I'm concerned about.
And also minerals and certain minerals
You're getting from vegetables that
you're probably not getting.
Yup.
Well this is all like,
look,
it seems hard to supplement that stuff
though.
Colloidal minerals,
you know,
there's some mineral pills you can take
plenty of.
Well there are people,
there are people who basically lived on
meat.
You know,
the inuit did was.
I basically did some supplementation,
but not a lot.
Yeah.
And apparently if you do a carnivore
diet,
you're supposed to eat more organ meat
and I do some of that,
but not a lot.
But I can tell you like I'm,
I'm in.
Well look,
I wouldn't be doing this if it wasn't
producing positive results.
It's not like it's fun for a while.
Well,
it makes you a social pariah.
Let's invite the peterson's over.
Oh yeah.
they don't eat anything.
Oh,
we have other friends.
Was like,
well that's how it works.
It's not malevolence right.
It's just a fear,
a pain,
no one invites you out and so.
So I'm a social pain in an ideological
pain and now I'm a nutritional paints.
No friends.
How difficult is it when you're trying
to get breakfast?
Like what do you do when you.
Well,
lots of times when we traveling we cook,
so we usually stay in places where you
can cook,
but most places you can get a steak and
so that's mostly what we do when
traveling in a motor home and so we've
been cooking in the motorhome and so
carrie beef jerky with me,
which we make,
so yeah,
it's crazy.
You make your own beef jerky.
We have a dehydrator and you just
basically put salt on it,
throw it in the dehydrator.
so that works pretty well.
You anticipate continuing this?
Well,
I remember god forever is a long time.
I'd like to be able to eat more things,
but I'm going to experiment with that
very,
very cautiously.
I'm going to add mushrooms next because
maybe I could eat them well.
This is why I'm asking.
There's
positive benefits that a lot of people
achieve and experience when they
switched to a vegan diet,
things it is as you get off of the
standard american diet with lots of
refined sugars and preservatives and
bullshit,
and then you find positive benefits.
chris kresser has gone into depth about
this,
but then over time to nutritional
deficiencies in that start to wear on
your health.
And I'm wondering,
certainly possible while,
uh,
certainly eventually this diet will kill
me.
No life will well near right.
Biology will,
yes.
And less so in science.
Intervenes might be for some people have
a vegan diet or vegan diet.
Is it preferable to a standard american
diet?
For sure,
to a standard american diet.
But also there's so much biological
variability,
you know,
the things that bothers some people
don't bother.
And that's,
that's something that we got to take
into consideration.
Yeah.
Well that's why I don't want to
universalize for my experience,
but,
but this is what's happened to me and
this is what's happened to my wife and
my daughter.
So.
And all of it's been well with mckayla
lights.
It's miraculous.
I cannot believe that the last time I
saw it made me cry.
I've never seen her look like that.
She looked so good.
She's so healthy and over.
Other joints are not experiencing any
problems.
And she's taking no immunomodulators at
all.
No medication.
And she was on them for jesus.
Yes.
More medication than you can shake a
stick at methotrexate,
which is basically a,
they use it to treat cancer.
It's uh,
it's uh,
what's,
what's the cancer treating drugs called?
Whatever.
I don't remember at the moment she was
on enbrel,
which really,
really helped,
but,
but later open to bacterial infection.
so she always had pneumonia in The fall,
but enbril really helped.
And then heaVy doses of antidepressants
and ritalin and jesus was.
How long has she been on this carnivore
diet?
Oh god,
she's only been eating meat.
It's got to be at least six to eight
months now.
Wow.
And does she get blood work done?
uh,
yep.
And her blood work.
I won't comment on that.
I don't know the details of her blood
work.
Um,
so I don't know the answer.
That is fascinating.
I'm curious,
I'm,
I'm considering trying it for awhile.
The problem is I ate so much game meat.
There's not a lot of.
Get some fat.
That's the trick there.
Tried for a month.
See what happens.
You,
what the hell?
A month,
you know,
just a month now amongst.
Not hard.
Yeah.
Interesting.
All right,
let's wrap this up.
Already.
Did three hours.
It's already 2:20,
believe it or not.
Hey,
crazy.
Listen,
it's always a pleasure and I want to
bring up.
How weird is this a whole association to
you?
Because it's weird to me.
The idw dew.
That of course intellectual dark web.
The hell it is.
It's like I've been trying to puzzle it
out.
I mean I think what it is is a loose
collection of early adopters of a
revolutionary technology.
that's what it looks like to me.
And we found each other because we're
all doing the same thing,
but it's also a bunch of people that are
honest intellectually honest about their
and maybe don't even don't even agree on
full.
Yeah,
well definitely but honest about
perception.
Well,
and also I think interested in long form
discussion,
right,
and able to engage in it because
otherwise we wouldn't be having the
relative success that we're having in
the,
in the,
in the middle,
you know,
and it got a name and that's kind of
interesting.
And that's eric though.
Yeah,
that's right.
That's eric.
He loves it.
Oh yeah.
He certainly does versus spies
definitely,
definitely denies it.
He loves it.
Which is what's most interesting about
it.
I love to rib him.
Yeah.
One,
it's got this funny conspiratorial
element there that's sort of true in
sort of mostly dramatic.
And as a mathematician he's always
looking for patterns and codes.
I don't know what to make of it.
I mean things get a name and then you
think,
well why did that get named and well
someone named it,
but yeah,
but the name stuck.
So it seemed apropos to some degree and
well,
what do we have in common?
Most of us are entrepreneurial.
Most of us have our own platform so we
can speak independently.
Most of us are interested in long form
philosophical discussions.
Primarily,
not political but,
but bordering on political,
well bands,
more political office.
He's the most.
Yeah,
but he's also very sophisticated
political commentator,
so he borders on both the philosophical
and the religious.
Um,
and then we're,
we're,
we're all the newly new adopters of this
new technology,
so that's enough to put us in a group.
And then,
well,
it turns out that we've all been talking
to each other,
but part of the reason for that is while
we're all doing the same thing on the
net,
so it's not surprising that we're
talking to each other.
So I always go for the simple
explanations first,
you know,
it's not a movement exactly what it is.
It's the manifestation of a new
technology.
And then while do we have anything in
common that's worth discussing that
would make this a viable group,
let's say?
And the answer to that is out of.
No,
you know,
I've been touring with ruben.
That's been good.
It's been good to have a comedian along
and he's also a good interviewer.
He does the q and a's with me and it's
nice to have some levity in the mix
because the conversations or discussions
with the audience are very serious,
although I can crack a joke and uh,
I can't tell a joke,
but if something funny occurs to be,
I can say it and sometimes it's funny.
So that's something,
um,
you know,
and we've been,
we've been discussing a fair bit and I
had good conversations with shapiro and
harris for that matter.
So there is lots of interplay between
us,
but I think that's more because we,
we inhabit the same technological space
more than the same ideological space
apart from the fact that we are actually
interested in dialogue fundamentally.
So we'll see.
I mean,
I'm,
I'm watching it with curiosity.
Are you
propensive do you think that there's any
potential downside?
So thEre's lots of downsides to it.
Sure.
There's lots of downsides.
I mean,
first of all,
you know,
most of us are on an individual
individualistic path.
I'm not,
I'm not really much of a group guy,
you know,
so am I in this group?
It's like,
well,
I'm pleased to be associated with you
guys,
that's for sure,
but I don't really know what it would
mean or if it should mean anything or if
it'll screw up what I'm doing or if
it's,
I don't know anything about it,
but mostly I'm curious.
It's like,
huh,
this is a group.
I thought this is the rat pack.
I thought when I walked into the
restaurant with us,
because we were out last night was ben
shapiro,
sam harris,
eric weinstein,
dave rubin,
joe rogan,
and me and my wife tammy.
And so we're all walking in there and I
thought,
well this is kinda like being in the rat
pack in the 19 fifties.
I thought,
well,
I know,
maybe it isn't,
but that's what came to mind.
So I thought that's funny and it's,
it's,
it's kind of cool and it's interesting
and it's edgy and all of that.
But I'm not,
I'm not taking it seriously.
I'm not,
I'm not also not,
you know,
I'm not taking it.
Not seriously either,
but I'm just watching.
I'm watching everybody interact because
it is a very motley crew of people.
It is so,
and they're very different and so,
but it was very enjoyable.
Thank you.
Okay,
so why did you think it was enjoyable?
Good conversation.
I mean,
everyone that was in that group has been
on my podcast or I've been on there and
you know,
it's a fun group of really honest,
interesting people that truly are very
peculiar people.
Especially eric.
He's listening right now.
That's what I'm fucking with them.
I love that guy,
but I mean they're all,
they're all,
everyone's different but everyone's also
unique and they all bring a lot to the
table and that's what's interesting
about it.
The weird collection,
you know,
I don't know what to think of it.
Like when eric called me up about the
whole New York times thing,
I'm like,
what are you talking about?
Like we're all together in this and you
did that.
Why did you do that?
What do I do?
What?
What did you be part of the New York
times article?
A barely was.
I just answered a couple of questions
because you got a picture.
Yeah.
They asked me to take a picture.
I picture of you right.
They didn't,
they should have taken a picture of me.
I was dressed like I was going on stage
at the comedy store.
I didn't wear anything any differently.
They were trying to make a big deal of
it.
I'm like,
look,
I don't have any time.
You want to take a picture.
This is what I'm wearing.
Yeah.
And,
and we,
we did it on the parking lot above the
comedy store and it started to rain.
I go,
we're done.
I gotta go,
I gotta go on stage.
I can't be soaking wet,
you know,
and then go on stage and that was it,
it was just.
Okay.
So your take on it is that it's.
Well,
it's intro your take on it.
Is that it's interest?
Yes.
Well this is the,
this is probably another thing that
unites that group of people.
Everyone in that group of people is
likely to get in trouble because they
find too many things.
Interesting.
Trait,
openness.
That's another thing that unites all of
us and you know,
curiosity killed the cat and so did,
but we're not cats.
True curiosity also built the pyramids.
It did,
it did,
and it saved a lot of caps too.
Let's end with that.
Alright.
Alright Jordan.
Pleasure my friend joe.
Always good to see you again.
See you always.
Yeah,
that's it folks.
See you soon.