Yes.
Wayne Fetterman.
How are you sir?
I'm swell.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Well,
swell.
Yeah,
first time anyone's ever said that real
on this podcast when I asked him how you
doing swell either the first Guy Matt,
and what number podcasts is this?
Eight 800 and something 829 829 so
you're the first guy to ever say swell.
What's the usual response?
It's just standard noises,
you know?
Great.
Awesome.
Ah,
Eh,
you know,
standard stuff.
The way people normally talk.
This is,
you're going to learn something about me
not standard swell.
Yeah,
it's definitely Janie.
Sketchy.
So,
uh,
I am talking before this podcast about
someone stealing your twitter handle.
Man,
I inadvertently posted,
uh,
at Wayne Fetterman and I thought it was
you because when you go to it,
it had that,
it looks like they had it.
So how'd this guy steal it?
I don't know.
So he stole your password somehow.
Somehow.
That's,
that's the scariest part.
So how does twitter not respond to that?
And I don't know.
I tried to go through twitter and he
wrote me,
he was like,
oh don't you remember we?
And then he just told a story that
didn't happen about a,
I can't remember.
I mean I have it on here if you want to
look it up.
But uh,
and it was just like I don't want
anything to do with this guy.
This guy's a liar.
So,
but now this is the first time I ever
talked about it cause I'm more,
cause he has obviously access to my best
word,
you know,
so,
so your past what?
I had two accounts I had at Fetterman,
which is my main one.
Am I talking too loud?
No.
Okay.
I had a,
I get excited.
Okay,
well that's something to be excited
about.
I mean that's your fucking name and
someone stole it.
I had a fetterman and I had at Wayne,
Wayne Fetterman had them both and one
was just going to be to put people to
add fetterman cause I liked that one a
little better.
Why do you like that one better?
That's a good question.
These are already good.
All right.
Let me think.
I didn't know what was going to get this
intense.
It's early crazy.
These conversations or I don't know.
I just like,
I liked the simplicity of it more than
Wayne Fetterman.
Well,
it's a,
it's an unusual last name isn't a lot of
Fetterman's so you could,
you could hang onto it like that,
you know?
So let me turn it back on you.
Am I allowed to do that or just to
answer?
We're friends.
Okay.
Sophie to the for 22 years at Rogen,
um,
I don't think so.
You don't want that?
I mean,
Joe Rogan is small name Joe.
It's quick.
Yeah.
Gin.
It's not hard.
I don't like the name Wayne.
So it,
anyway,
but I bought Joe Rogan.
There was another guy named Joe Rogan.
His identity.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It was his real name.
I had a,
I think I had originally Joe Rogan
experience,
like the same as the podcast name.
I think that's what originally what I
had.
Right.
And uh,
this guy had Joe Rogan.
So I contacted him and a,
I said,
hey man,
can I buy it from you?
And he said,
sure.
And he sold to me.
Am I allowed to ask?
I don't remember.
I don't know.
Get a number.
I don't remember.
Wait a minute,
now that I'm thinking about this,
this might not totally be true.
That might be my space.
I think my space I bought,
I think I bought Joe Rogan on my space.
When was the last time you were on my
space?
Oh,
it's been never,
it wasn't even me.
I think every seven years you're a new
person.
They say that your cells completely
swapped out of that.
As a kid,
it's not really me.
So seven years.
It's been more than seven years for
sure.
It's weird,
right?
It's weird how like some people just
decide,
like everybody was saying,
but my space is dead and then
everybody's like,
Shit.
Mindspace is dead time to get the fuck
out of there.
And I'm still,
I'm still on there.
Are you?
Come on.
I never check it or anything,
but it's use it.
No,
no,
but does it,
I still feel like I'm on there and there
was a girl.
Can I make a recommendation about a girl
on my space now?
She's on Youtube,
she's on youtube,
but she wrote a song years ago on the
Ukulele,
which is one of the many instruments I
play,
you know,
and it was called,
my hope is in the name of the song.
It's my recommend and it's about parents
forgetting their password to shut down
their myspace account and their kids as
teenagers.
Reading that in the future.
I tried to shut my mind space down.
There wasn't no good.
It couldn't shut it down.
Yeah.
I don't think they want anybody to shut
it out.
They don't.
I think they think somehow or another
it's going to come back,
but then it just gets sold again.
Yeah,
but that's what I'm saying.
I think like they keep trying to move it
around and sell eight if I'm not
mistaken.
And I know,
I don't know if you're into bands,
we're going to find out to find out a
lot about you,
but like I feel like bands still have a
presence on my space.
Jamie,
not bands you want to see.
I don't think anyone's on there.
I think it's a dead zone.
Okay.
All right.
Did you ever see that movie?
Yes,
I did.
A Cronenberg.
That's a good one.
A good movie.
Yeah.
I read the book too.
Why would book,
do you read a lot of those times?
I can't read fiction really just gets
wet.
We're learning about Wayne fetterman
today.
I read both.
I prefer fiction though,
I think for reading,
but a,
I like reading nonfiction too.
I'm reading a book about coyotes right
now.
Obviously fiction.
No.
Well,
you can have a nonfiction talking,
like why would you say what's kind of
the title even sounds like fiction.
It's like a spiritual and supernatural
history of God,
you know,
and give me one fact.
I need to know about a coyote or wolves.
The same family.
Same.
All of them.
Exactly the same animal.
They're like a dog is exactly that.
Like,
you know,
a dog can breed with dogs.
Coyotes are wolves.
There are small wolf,
and they were originally called prairie
wolves.
Here's,
yeah,
I remember that.
Here's the history of the name Coyote.
They used to call the people that landed
here.
He used to call them,
you know,
the,
the early settlers called them prairie
wolves.
When they first encountered him,
like Lewis and Clark there,
the first shot one,
and they thought it was a fox.
They wanted to see what it was.
They shot it,
they examined it and they said,
that's not a wall fox,
it's a small wolf,
classic light guy.
Let's examine this shoot and kill it,
kill it,
and let's take a look a little.
We got here.
So,
um,
they used to call him prairie wolves and
then the trappers in counted a native
Americans who,
uh,
called them,
Co call you cause that was the Aztec
word for them.
The Aztec word was coit.
And then the trappers,
um,
encountered,
uh,
or the,
native Americans encountered Spanish,
uh,
people from Spain.
They called it [inaudible] because they,
they had the Spanish pronunciation of
the word coil.
And then the trappers could not say
[inaudible].
So they started calling them coyotes,
coyotes,
coyote and prairie wolf.
Those are the original names.
And of course [inaudible],
which was the yet as technique.
And you still have 420 more pages to go.
The books.
Fascinating.
It's really fascinating.
What's really fascinating.
It's by this guy,
Dan Flores.
What's really fascinating,
that name,
there's the book right there.
You see it up on the screen and natural
and supernatural history.
Oh,
why you would,
um,
what's interesting is the,
the more like the reason why coyotes are
all over the country now,
they're in every single state.
Every single city.
Even in Hawaii.
No,
they're not in Hawaii as a state.
It's not really,
so it's a country we stole.
We still an island from a bunch of Brown
people.
It's fucked up,
Wayne.
It's called a state.
It's bullshit.
The last date,
it's their own country.
1959 it came,
she gave me,
I don't buy it.
It's going down.
Leave him alone.
He's very,
and I feel like anybody,
I think they should,
you know,
probably protected by us,
but that's their own country.
I feel like that give it back.
Like,
yeah,
we'll make a deal hung.
Yay.
What was 10?
It was a matter Australia,
but yeah,
it was about the aborigines.
Yeah.
How do we stay here?
Give it back.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's right.
They would drive around that time has
come to say,
hey,
hey.
Oh Shit.
Wow.
What is that band now that I think they
were a one hit wonder,
but I remember the like the lead singer
was like bald guy.
Yeah.
Very intense.
Very intense something.
Boy,
I'll think of it.
I think.
Not Remember,
but I remember that.
You give it back.
Yeah man.
What about Alaska?
Give it back.
Nope,
that's ours.
We own that shit even though it's not
part of the,
who else did you ask?
Who else owns it?
Who Canada?
Give it to Canada.
Fought it down.
Give it to Russia.
So give it back to Russia and then that
connected to Canada,
which is connected to us.
I'm just saying that for giving up a
why.
Well,
I'm just talking about the last two
states that became,
if that Alaska was its own country,
couldn't defend itself.
Plus there's a lot of military in
Alaska.
US military.
I say we keep Alaska.
Okay,
so we're back to 49 states to help the
flag because then you can do the seven
by seven right?
Well,
that's the other thing.
Hawaii has their own flag like they
does,
but they have,
they really have their own flag.
Carry it around with them.
Like they,
they express it.
Every state has a flag.
But when was the last time you saw
somebody driving around with a
California flag hanging off the car?
True.
Can they speak in a flag or something
crazy?
You might have spoken about it on the
show.
You've done 200 829 so I don't know.
I haven't listened to all of them.
I assume you have,
but six flags.
Great adventure.
You're familiar with it?
Yes.
Do you know the six flags?
No.
You curious?
Sure.
There the six flags that have flown over
the state of Texas.
Whoa.
If we can go through them.
Yeah,
let's do it.
Oh,
there's more than that's Texas is that,
it's not a state,
right?
It's a republic.
It's a stage.
It's like they can kind of bail.
They kicked their estate.
There's,
it's not about bailing before.
There's people that always talk about
the seeding is the word that he is going
to bail.
We're gonna bail.
You got to map out to this liberal
bullshit.
Okay.
So obviously United States,
right?
Texas state of Texas flag,
Spain Spanish flag flew in Texas.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But yeah,
cause it was Spanish territory.
Yeah.
Um,
Mexico,
I believe Mexico,
we here it goes late.
Don't,
there's one crazy one.
This is the crazy one.
There's a French,
because it was obviously the French
hounded did for awhile as a part of the
Louisiana purchase.
Right?
Oh,
that's right.
Um,
but here's the craziest one.
Confederate.
You know,
so when you say go to six flags,
the sixth flag is the confederate flag.
That's not cool.
I actually think it is Kinda cool.
It's Kinda like,
if you think about it,
you're like it at this meme,
muse by park.
You're like,
oh,
that is the French part.
That's the heat confederate part.
That's the,
it's weird that it was not that far long
ago that the confederate flag was on a
car that was on television every day.
Right.
You're talking about?
Uh,
the generally,
yeah,
a daisy dukes.
I remember that.
Yeah.
The flag was on TV.
First of all,
the flag is
still part of the state of Georgia state
flag if I'm not mistaken.
Yeah.
Oh,
that's ugly.
That's especially why,
I feel like in the last 15 years it's
taken a turn.
But before that,
Leonard skinner,
if you ever went to one of their shows,
did you know,
but they,
they used to failure with demand there
from Florida.
Leonard skinner.
Yeah.
They're from Florida.
I'm a huge Leonard Skinner Fan.
Where in Florida?
I Dunno.
Somewhere that sucks.
Cause I know Tom Petty from Gainsville.
Yeah.
Did you know I grew up in Florida?
Olson?
I used to live in Gainesville.
I lived in Gainesville for three years.
I was a little kid.
Oh,
from the time I was 11,
12,
13.
Let's see what we got here.
There's the,
uh,
there's the flag to 2001.
Yeah,
up until 2001.
because I remember when Jimmy Carter
accepted the nomination in [inaudible]
76 there was like a big,
it looked like a confederate flag
because they had the Georgia delegation
right down front.
That's crazy.
Up Til 2001 they had a fucking,
or is it 2006 yeah,
that's what I'm saying.
In the last 15 yet.
No,
you nailed it.
That was their state flag.
That's insane,
dude.
Same Dukes of hazzard style.
Yeah.
But dukes of Hazzard at least has a TV
show about a bunch of rednecks that are,
you know,
they run from the law and some moonshine
or they used to sell moonshine.
I guess I didn't watch that.
Share that all there was a show.
Yeah,
no,
I know.
I've seen the picture of the guy.
I find,
I guess maybe because I grew up in the
south,
like the confederate flag.
Not Crazy offensive,
but now it's like the Nazi flag,
right?
Yeah.
But it's amazing how it was accepted.
It was accepted.
The London scattered things.
A perfect example.
The fact that learns skinner had that
flag flying everywhere.
Yeah.
And now you could never do that.
You could just can't do that in a less
specifically.
That was what you were trying to be
provocative.
Oh Man.
But here there's linen skins flight
that,
yeah,
that was the logo.
What?
That never flies there.
Now Leonard Skinner without,
with the surviving members.
Uh,
you know,
[inaudible] it's not really Leonard
Skinner,
but you know the,
what they're calling Leonard skinner
skinner.
It's Leonardo's very close.
They don't,
they don't try to rock that any more.
They gave,
I'd like to know,
and I,
Jamie's over here doing it.
I don't know what year they did give up
on it,
but it within the last 15 years that
they were like,
it's now a symbol of hate as opposed to
a cultural situation.
Yeah.
Was a little,
it's about the culture of the south.
It's about the culture.
Yeah.
It was kind of,
the culture is kind of connected to
something fucked up.
You're talking about slavery.
You got to let it go.
Is that what you mean?
Yes.
You got to let it go.
That's what I thought.
So we got to,
we went through the Securitas route
to this coyote thing.
Uh,
by killing coyotes,
you,
you forced the females to have more
babies.
The females litters increase.
There are very strange animal.
Like if they call,
like when you hear coyotes call in the
middle of the [inaudible],
do it again.
Do it again.
It's a weird sound.
The first time I heard it for some,
I moved to California.
I was like,
what the fuck is that?
But when I moved here,
he's a perfect example.
In 94,
uh,
when I was living in New York,
there's no fucking coyotes where I was
living like I was living in men.
No,
I was in new Rochelle.
There's,
but there's coyotes near now.
There's coyotes in Westchester.
There's coyotes in New York City.
They've actually gone into the city.
There's a bunch of B.
Dot.
At one.
They are the opposite of a danger.
They are everywhere.
They are one of the most prevalent large
animals in North America.
They are everywhere.
They're in every single state.
Just million questions.
What is the population increased since
the Lewis and Clark?
Hundred percent.
Yes.
Not only that,
the range,
the range is increased when they're
there.
What's interesting about them is when
they're persecuted,
they spread out.
They expand their range when they're
persecuted,
just like Jews.
Wow.
I'm kidding.
I'm Jill.
You're allowed to say that.
You could say that.
I can't,
you couldn't say that.
I don't want to get in trouble.
Okay.
Especially I was wearing a confederate
flag after,
sorry.
Anyway,
um,
cody books.
Awesome.
How do we get to that?
We're talking about books.
Nonfiction.
Yeah.
We were tiny.
We were asking you about,
you were talking about some book now.
I was,
we were just talking about,
I was saying that I don't read fiction.
What,
and you just said,
that's the last thing I'm reading.
I read only fig.
I can't get into it.
Really?
Yeah.
I could get into a coyote book,
you know,
a nonfiction,
but,
but I like a,
uh,
like a Jack London story.
Has It always been that way?
Well,
I,
you know,
you had to in school read those books.
Yeah.
You were forced to.
We never got into books like they were
never like fascinating.
My brother was,
but I was not,
he had Robert Heinlein and all that
science fiction books and I know that,
I mean,
I've read a few and uh,
I just get,
I love movies.
Like that's how I get my fiction.
Well,
movies are better if they're done right.
What's really better is television
shows.
The long form TV show.
But you'd like thrones.
Yeah,
because it's,
they can go so much more like a novel,
a novel.
It's like a novel.
But you're seeing it and you're seeing,
I'm using amazing acting and music.
Exposed breasts.
Right.
That's what's happening.
Yeah.
Because the one time I don't watch game
of thrones,
but they both times I tuned in,
I've seen negative breasts.
Is it every week they try.
That's just to get ratings.
How does that work?
Well,
no,
because I think people back then to show
their tits lot what?
Yeah,
it's not real.
It's not back then,
it's not even a real play in the future.
It could be absolutely like star wars.
Yeah.
Long time ago in a galaxy far,
far away.
Like you would think star wars is in the
future,
but it's actually in the past.
He would think game of thrones in the
past,
but it might actually be in the future.
Speaking of Star Wars,
I just stumped a star wars and that.
How'd you do that?
It was about that song done.
Don Don,
Don Antenna,
the antenna,
you know,
that's the darth vader's theme.
There's actually a,
that's not the actual name of that song,
but it's,
um,
but that song was not in the original
star wars,
but yeah,
it wasn't.
No.
Oh my God.
I've talked to a guy,
he's like,
you're wrong.
I was like,
well you're wrong.
And because I happened to be a nice guy.
I know when I'm know I'm right.
I know.
I'll never bet somebody,
oh,
what a nice guy.
Yeah,
cause she was laid out.
I know.
I know how much you think you could've
gotten out of them.
I don't know.
Maybe 10,
10,000
maybe 10 to I'm alone dollars.
I think it could have easily got,
he was convinced because you're a rich
guy.
He was a guy at the bar or we're just
talking about star wars.
I've seen him all the thing.
He had a shirt should have went in,
um,
March of the,
what is it called?
March of the called the imperial March.
March.
Thank you Tom.
Thumb down.
Oh,
John Williams.
He's unbelievable.
Um,
is that from the second one?
First strikes back?
Yes.
Wow.
Yeah.
Interesting.
I know you wouldn't think so,
right?
A little bit of trimming.
Not Surprise.
Now that you said it,
I'm not surprised.
They all kind of blend in probably the
perfect age to see star wars as a kid.
I saw star wars a bunch of times as a
kid.
It was one of those things where I think
I might've saw it 13 times or something
crazy because it's one of those things
where kids in school with how many times
you seen star wars?
I've seen the 20,
you know,
there was always listens.
You're from Jersey?
No,
I was born in New Jersey,
but I only lived there until I was six.
I spent my seventh birthday in a car on
the way to San Francisco.
I lived in San Francisco from seven to
11,
lived in Gainesville,
Florida from 11 to 13 Boston from 13 to
2124,
24,
I guess.
And then,
uh,
somewhere 23,
I guess.
And then New York for a couple of years
and then here,
then here.
Here.
Wow.
Yeah.
Are you facebook friends?
Are you on facebook like per night?
Very.
I use facebook only in that instagram is
connected to facebook.
Okay.
I don't go there and I just,
are you friends from any of you have any
friends from your San Francisco years
you're still in touch with?
No.
So only on Warfarin,
only Boston.
Boston in New York.
No.
What,
you've never gone to a show and
someone's come up to you and go,
no.
You know,
when you're a little kid,
it's hard to stay friends
with people for that long,
you know,
like that you don't,
if you don't stay in the neighborhood
and stay in the area.
Yeah.
And uh,
I just didn't stay there that long.
I only lived there.
We moved around a lot,
man,
which obviously not good for you.
I moved around as a kid.
I mean maybe not as much as you,
but similar,
similar,
similar to that.
Yeah.
It,
it's,
I don't think it's that healthy for
kids.
I don't think it,
I thought it was good.
I thought I learned a lot of great
skills.
We definitely do.
You learn people skills and learn how to
communicate with people,
but you also don't,
I feel like that's a pretty important
thing in life.
It is.
But I also think that some people,
they gain something by being secure and
having friends and a community
confidence.
Yeah.
Are you saying you're not implying
you're not confident guy?
Um,
I think I got my confidence from martial
arts and I went to martial arts because
it didn't have any confidence.
Oh my God,
I'm going to start crying because it's
sad.
Just the most sensitive I've ever seen
you in my life.
What is happening?
I think that sensitive is that
sensitive?
Yeah.
You're less like,
I was just,
now all of a sudden I see this kid,
you know,
eyes darting around,
no friends all of a sudden like it was
Maine really?
Oh yeah,
for sure.
Oh my God.
And then you were like,
I need something.
And so you started taking steroids and
doing martial arts economy?
They were,
and I didn't take steroids.
I'm kidding.
What I did in high school,
take some when I was older.
You did?
Yeah.
Oh,
I had no,
yeah,
no.
Most of this stuff I took was stuff that
you could buy at Gnc,
but uh,
they used to sell stuff at Gnc that's
now totally alive when,
what do you call which doing?
Mcguire was hitting him.
He was stinking real steroids.
I would,
you know,
he was lying.
Yeah,
100%.
But there was something that's now with
legal at g and C.
Yeah.
A bunch of those things.
But the,
there's stuff that you take now,
like there's an issue that's going on
constantly with UFC fighters where they
go to some sort of a vitamin store and
buy some stuff.
And it turns out that these supplements
that they're buying have steroids in
them.
Steroids.
Wow.
Yes.
You okay?
When you till you said you did take?
Yes,
I took the strong strongest shit ever
took was a stuff that's totally illegal.
Now it's called Mag 10 and when you
just,
cause I've never taken anything like
that.
Can you,
can you feel it like when you take it
like what?
What's the real body recovers?
Better recovers.
Yeah.
That's really neat.
Better?
No,
not on the stuff that I took.
How many hours do some stuff I try to
sleep a solid eight.
I think it's super important.
It's one of the most important things as
far as a relaxation recovery.
You know,
if you work out a lot and you did,
did you work at earlier today?
Yeah,
it worked out today.
Wow.
That's impressive.
Why is it impressive?
You don't work out?
I play basketball and tennis.
Those are workouts.
Dyno,
I know,
but I,
I don't,
don't really do them in the morning that
often.
When you do them like in the afternoon,
so you'll ease into your day.
He's so to do that kind of comedian.
Yeah.
Well that's most of us.
Most of us ease into the day I would
assume.
I get up and I attack that motherfucker.
I like to work out hard first thing in
the morning like this.
Do you do these lifting weights?
Do these,
he's doing the,
he's,
he's doing the pressing motion and do
some of those,
these,
the curls.
Well,
most of the weightlifting than I do is
with kettle bells.
Oh yeah.
I know that those things behind you on
the ground.
Those are kettlebells.
Yeah.
Those were the one when I said yes,
I knew what they were and I didn't
really have to turn around and look,
I don't know exactly what the right,
do you want me to try to lift it?
No.
Maybe later.
Maybe.
I don't want you to get hurt.
Okay.
Can I flash forward?
I have more workout questions.
When does this,
how did,
how do we know this is over?
We decided we'd say it's over right here
and say it.
We can pull the plug right now.
Now we want to do it.
No,
no.
I'm enjoying it.
I just want to know because if I run out
of steam,
go like,
I'm going to,
I'm going to do this.
Just go.
Don't,
I'm going to do,
I'm going to tap out.
But definitely you don't want to think
about that.
That's all I'm thinking about.
You can't think like that.
Oh yeah.
Well that's the same thing with working
out.
If you,
if you work on your man,
when am I going to get tired?
You'll start getting tired.
Do you have to think about what you're
doing?
You gotta be getting is I'm getting some
life in the moment mean like it's very
important.
Of course,
we do almost everything in life.
Right?
Did you ever,
do you ever read the right in the middle
of sex going on when this is going to be
over and then it's over?
All right,
well that's,
I can't think like that.
Hey,
you understand?
I understand.
I don't really have a problem with that.
Okay.
But now it seems like you might think
you have a problem.
Now all of a sudden that's,
it creeps into your head and that's it.
Did you ever read the book the power of
now?
You know what I have is that's Eckhart.
Totally.
Yeah,
it is.
I have that book on audio tape.
I have not finished it.
I hope to God it's not him reading it.
I do not know who got the worst.
I don't think speaking voice it,
it's horrible.
But his book is pretty good.
Yeah.
I remember thinking this is kind of
cool,
but this is a lot of stuff that I
already kind of practice and kind of
know into it.
I was,
it was quite a few years ago that it was
listening to it.
The worst guy ever to read his books on.
Let me,
let me hear Stephen King.
Oh really?
Oh God.
He's awful.
I mean,
he's one of my favorite authors.
I love him.
Did you ever a fan of his read his
writing?
Right,
but oh my God,
when he reads it,
it's death.
Like you literally want to fucking just,
I used to listen to him back when it was
cassettes and uh,
I,
one time I fucking pulled the string
that the tape out of the cassette.
Right.
So I could never listen to it again.
I'm like,
this is fucking terrible.
And I threw it in the garbage can.
You couldn't just throw it in.
You had a hell's mad,
obviously so boring.
His rate,
his reading is so awful.
I remember the book.
Was it Ku?
You remember what I've listened to a
bunch of his stuff on audio tape and
Actually Duncan was talking about it
yesterday.
Yeah.
I didn't realize it was Frank Mueller.
That was one of the best guys at reading
it.
He did the dark tower series.
He read the dark tower series.
Stephen King Book.
But uh,
yeah.
Stephen King,
one of my favorite offers.
My least favorite ever reader of his
work.
That's great.
Favorite author?
Least favorite reader?
Yeah,
that's my Dave King.
He,
I don't think is my favorite author.
Um,
he might be though.
He's fun.
Did you know he's really good too?
His son,
Ernie King.
Joe Hill,
I don't know.
His son's name is Joe Hill.
Joe.
Hell wait a minute.
Yeah,
it changed his name so he didn't have to
ride his dad's pony coattails.
Ponytails.
Putney tells Joe Hill a famous character
and uh,
I'm going to say,
let's say his name right.
I'm not blanking.
Emma.
It's Joe Hill.
Heart shaped box.
Yeah,
he's really good.
You don't really know.
You don't have the song Joe Hill and
about the worker who died to jolene.
Jolene,
jolene.
There is still fresh.
Looks like Stephen King.
That's crazy.
That's him.
Joe Hill writer.
Can you,
can you do me a favor and look up Joe
Hill Union activist because I think
there's a,
did you ever see the movie woodstock?
MMM.
Shot in 1969 it was about a music
festival.
Here's the guy upstate New York.
Well,
I know about the music festival,
but I don't think I saw Joe Hill ain't
dead.
Don't mourn.
Organize.
Yeah.
It's about a unit if I,
he like died and some kind of maybe
union act accident or something like
that.
Or Osha.
And when Joan Baez sang in,
in Woodstock,
that's one of the songs she's saying,
which Joe Hill.
Oh Wow.
I'm wondering if that's why I'm making
this connection.
Well,
he might changed his name to that on
purpose.
That's what I'm asking.
Yeah.
Okay.
It could be,
so that is it.
I got the name right.
Good.
Sometimes I'm think it's right and it's
like,
oh no,
that was Ernie Hill and messed up.
Yeah.
You know,
not sometimes,
like you'll say a word and you're like,
that's not the right word,
but it is the right it is.
Yeah.
Cool.
Especially like the way it's spelled.
You look,
look at the way something's spelled like
that can't be right.
I wonder if there's a word for it.
I'm looking at it for the hell.
I'm looking at the pictures.
Mind.
Yeah.
These all mugshots.
Well,
sort of.
They're not.
That's the Elvis Presley's shit.
Two of them.
Bullshit.
It's Elvis.
One is bullshit because he was a at the
White House and he wasn't accidental
yesterday.
No,
I think he took it as a joke and when
might it be a security thing?
But I think you'd take him.
Do you like how he's that way it's
behind you.
I am a fan of what Elvis kind of is.
You know?
He's like this iconic,
crazy Americana figure.
I became a drug addict and got all fat
and sweaty and died on the toilet.
I think there's less than later.
Remember there's lessons in Elvis.
I mean I think he certainly was a
talented singer,
but a,
I'm a,
I'm a fan of him.
More of a cultural icon than I am.
Even as a musician.
Jimmy Hendrix.
Yeah.
That's not real.
See that is the real writing.
But the actual image is from,
uh,
one of the Jimi Hendrix experience,
which is where I stole the name for this
podcast.
I love it.
Um,
the name of the band?
Yeah.
Made me,
made me feel experiment.
What?
Mitch Mitchell there.
That's the real one.
So you up on the screen,
that is the actual image.
That's the real image.
He got arrested for heroin in Toronto,
but this picture that I,
and I bought this at a fucking nice
gallery.
Two of these cons and then Rosa parks.
Yes.
But the Rosa Park one is real.
That's 100% real.
Is that when she,
that's when she got arrested.
You know,
she was,
a lot of people get that story wrong,
but a lot of people think like,
she sat in the front of the bus and then
was asked to move to the back of the
bus.
Somebody else had done it before her.
Of course,
of course.
Of course.
But even the front of the bus part is
incorrect.
What part,
what is it?
It's Kinda,
it's a very mean minute thing,
but I'm like a history dude.
There was a white section in the front,
right?
African American in the book,
in the back.
Uh,
at the time they call black or colored
section.
Uh,
she was in the colored section.
But what happened was if the white
section filled up and a white person
went back to the color texture and sit
down,
you still had to stand up and give them
your seat.
Really?
Yeah.
And then she wouldn't do it.
And that's,
that was the start of it.
Wow.
I did not know that.
They know it's a small,
you know,
but everyone says,
oh,
she wouldn't go to the back of the book.
It's like,
well,
that's even grosser.
I agree.
It is.
Grocer just like literally just sitting
there and then just some guy just got
to,
yeah,
she's complying with your racist rules
and then you're like not racist enough.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
so then that's when she got arrested.
Parks original seat.
Wow.
You were totally right.
Am I correct?
Yeah.
Look at that.
What happened?
Ever seen?
I've never seen this picture.
There's a diagram like the Kennedy
assassination.
It looks like the fucking magic bullet.
Rosa parks boarded the bus and sat in an
aisle seat in the designated colored sex
colleagues stops later the driver told
parks and three other blacks in her row
to move to the back to make room for a
white man.
The three blacks moved to the back
parks,
slid to an adjacent window seat,
refuse to move.
Wait til it was even.
It was like,
okay,
just so I'm clear on this,
now that I'm learning something,
I almost feel like now,
like they didn't even want him to have
to sit next to exactly what it was like.
That was an empty seat.
Yup.
That's exactly that.
Right?
Am
I reading that right?
You're absolutely reading it right.
It's interesting,
right?
That is,
it's awful.
That's awful.
That's another thing that's not that
long ago.
All these things that are not that long
ago.
The colored flag being on,
I mean the confederate,
the colored flag,
the confederate flag being on the state.
Right.
Flag of Georgia.
This,
what year was this?
I want to say this is 16
d
what year was it?
I want to say like 61 does that make
sense?
56 in the late fifties right.
Oh Wow.
I'm totally wrong.
Montgomery Alabama system was Lego in
the graded.
Wow.
So good.
We learned,
I learned a little something.
Yeah.
That's fascinating.
It's silly.
It's a stage photo.
Then her right there.
Yeah.
Like how if there was a full bus and
there's a white guy behind her.
What?
Like houses?
What's this photo from?
Oh,
I see.
So wikipedia photo,
they might've done that after the fact.
Right?
What's in the upper right hand corner?
What does that,
is that the actual,
is that like no upper right hand corner,
upper right hand corner that,
yeah.
Mine never seen you yell at somebody
like,
Yo,
this is the bus where it's at.
And so like you can actually go there
and sit in an extra of Obama there.
Oh Wow.
So they took the actual bus and put it
in a museum.
Well that's it.
Up in the above.
Someone should make a tour bus out of
that,
I think outkast or something.
You're talking about the band outcast.
Yeah.
I think it might be better in a museum.
Yeah,
I guess.
But it's not a thing to have in a
museum,
I guess it is.
Right.
It's like when do you decide what,
have you ever gone to one of those old
West museums?
I went to an old West Museum in Montana.
It's pretty interesting where with city?
Uh,
Bozeman.
Yeah,
I know Bozeman beaut.
Billings.
Yeah.
I know the whole tour up there.
Pretty awesome.
A museum.
But one of the interesting things about
it was they had these old stage coaches
and just have to imagine taking one of
those fucking goofy things.
Cross the country.
Not that long ago.
That was long ago.
That's the thing.
I think that's tricky.
My horses.
That's the theme of this podcast.
Yeah.
Not that long ago.
Well,
it's really not that long ago.
When you eat,
you get older and you realize,
oh,
I'm almost 50 right.
It's half a hundred years.
The wild west,
shit that was 200 years ago,
200 years ago,
less than two wild west is less than 200
years ago.
Sure.
It's post civil war,
so it's like,
okay.
Yeah,
150 years.
Yeah.
Well I mean when people first started
coming,
like what year was it?
I think the wild west is like the 18th
seventies 1865 is when slavery was
abolished.
That's,
is that the end of the wild west gun?
That's the start of it.
No,
1865 when,
well before that there were still
traveling across the country like,
well,
yeah,
the milestone,
they delete the [inaudible] and all that
jazz.
I still feel like that's a all of that,
but I might be wrong.
I might be wrong because the 40 niners
that's 1849 they're searching for gold
in California.
So people are obviously trekking across
the country looking for gold in 1849 we
know that nine or 49 ers.
Yeah.
Right.
And you know that we know.
So maybe,
maybe 1850s and when would they be?
1850s what was the donner party?
How is that the family,
each other.
Oh,
they got stuck in the mountain and that
pass.
Whew.
That was that.
That is a,
that's intense.
Trying to get over the fucking rocky
mountain in the winter.
Not Good.
Yeah.
It's even,
it's like,
it would be like trying to do it with
the hybrid.
Right?
Because those things don't have a lot.
Yeah.
Test.
The Donner party was a,
what does that say?
1846 yeah.
Okay.
So we got them right here.
I was wrong about the wild west.
I guess it's 1840s still again.
Lewis and Clark was around 1804 so
around 1820s is 1820s okay.
All right.
I'm wrong.
So it's essentially almost exactly 280
right.
You were right.
So fucking recent though,
that's so damn reason to think that 200
years ago there was no Chicago,
like as we know it,
giant buildings and airplanes.
No,
San Francisco as we know it.
No New York City as we know it,
when New York City was kind of like
pretty much cosmopolitan,
but they,
they definitely had like buildings and
stuff cause there's some buildings from
the 18 hundreds in a lot of spots,
but this,
this entire country go back 200 years
and it's not much here.
That's a,
that's strange.
Really.
Yeah.
I,
I'm more think it's beautiful and
fascinate that too.
Yeah.
I just think it's incredible.
They're not mutually exclusive.
Wayne Fetterman.
Oh,
correct.
Correct.
It's not the opposite.
Could be both things.
Right.
It's all the above.
Yeah.
There is that.
Now this country is,
you know,
I'm a big 4th of July is my favorite
holiday,
by the way.
Are you a big patriot or are you just
like fireworks?
I love fireworks.
I even got him one of my favorite
fireworks.
It's just the one that flashes and makes
the sound.
Yeah.
You know that one.
Yeah,
I know.
That way.
I don't really let their call to go to
Disneyland and stayed to the very end.
I would.
Yeah.
I just,
I love the whole thing.
I love the idea of this country who
liked me too,
like what we went through.
I don't know.
Patriot is the word,
but I get mad.
I just,
I would say I'm very appreciative of
being lucky enough to live here.
Yeah.
Me Too.
We're lucky as fuck.
I especially think that when I travel,
whenever we go to other countries,
yeah.
And Go,
hmm.
You know,
I was talking to this gentleman in
Italy.
I was in Italy a couple of weeks ago,
right.
And it was talking to this guy about he
wants to move to northern California.
He wants,
he wanted to move to a San Jose and he
has this idea,
this is dream to take his kids and moved
to San Jose.
And uh,
you know,
it was kind of interesting talking to
him about it and then it got kind of sad
because he was talking about his
children.
He's like,
there's where he lives.
There's no hope,
there's no future,
there's,
there's nothing to plan for,
there's no opportunities.
And he's like,
I really feel like my children would
have an opportunity to succeed if they
could go,
go to America.
And I was like,
wow.
That,
I mean that is what led my grandparents
to come here.
Yeah.
Why did they come from Italy?
Wow.
So that's your most of them.
My grandfather,
my father's side came from Ireland.
Everybody else,
my grandmother and my father saw,
and my grandmother and grandfather on my
mother's side came from Italy.
All of them.
And not easy for the Italians and the
Irish when they got here.
No,
no,
no news.
It one of those stories where they pass
down to you or were you just saying,
oh yeah,
absolutely.
Yeah.
And they were there and they were all
circus performers,
right?
No,
no,
they were,
they were a wild pasta hunters.
My grandfather grew up road farm was
rogue.
Yeah,
same thing.
Same thing.
Now I feel very,
very,
very fortunate and love it.
Yeah.
We're well,
when you go to other countries then you
really kind of get a sense of,
first of all how recent this experiment
in self government really is.
Cause a,
you know,
when we were in Italy we were,
I took some photos at the Vatican and I
posted them up on my instagram the other
day and one of them that was probably
not maybe the most impressive but the
most put things into perspective.
There's a floor of the Vatican where
they have the statue of Hercules and
this tile mosaic floor is 1700 years old
and people walk on it.
Thousands of people walk in this mosaic
tile and it's 1700 years old and it's
just a tile for,
I mean it's just one thing of in this
insane there.
That's the floor right there that at
1700 years old,
and that's one tiny aspect of the
Vatican.
The Vatican is so monstrously huge and
incredible.
It is one of the most breathtaking
things I've ever seen in my life.
And the accomplishment of people from
hundreds and hundreds of years ago.
They put together this building,
I even called them artisans.
He,
you know,
I guess humans.
Humans.
Yeah.
With the human beings can do is pain.
I'd be just along design,
it's not quite as breathtaking is that,
but just this morning someone posted
Steve Jobs announcement of the Imac when
that came out in the nineties late
nineties and just,
and then all the comments from the kids
who were just like,
oh,
it would blow their minds if they knew
the computer.
I'm looking at this demonstration on
you,
like just,
that's how fast,
you know,
everything changed.
Yeah.
There it is.
Look at jobs.
A big fat face.
And what is interesting,
no room looking like that.
This is before,
this is pre a tee shirt and jeans or
turtleneck and jeans.
Yeah.
This is jobs with a button up shirt all
the way up to the neck and a blazer and
office.
Ma'Am.
Yeah.
Hair.
He's got hair.
But look how chubbies phases that poor
guy worked himself to death,
if I like that early.
Yeah.
I feel like you read it.
Crushed his immune system with is an
intense pursuit of excellence.
I really,
I really think that,
I think that was a big part of it.
Did you read William Isaacson's?
Isaac?
No.
I've read many accounts of people that
worked with them,
but I've never read any biographies on
him.
But uh,
you know,
I,
I'm fascinated to it like that to
cautionary tale.
Yes,
you do.
Yeah,
I do.
I mean,
I think there's,
um,
there's a balance to be achieved and in
life and I don't,
I don't necessarily think he achieved
balance.
I think he burned it.
I think he went crazy and did the best
to make an incredible stuff and an
amazing company.
That's probably one of the most
innovative and influential companies in
the history of technology.
No question,
if not the right.
Probably the,
and it's a big part of it was his
vision.
Right?
What the,
to me the most amazing of all the things
he did were,
what is those stores like Tim,
in my mind,
I can't even imagine at a time.
And everyone was like,
brick and mortar is gone.
Everything is online.
Our Co,
our liberty,
our company is about online.
It gets I is Internet.
That's what I phone I Mac.
Right.
That's what it's about.
And that he had the vision to go,
you know,
I think it needs a store.
Yeah.
A store like,
well,
you pay rent and you have insurance and
all of these other overhead costs that
Amazon doesn't deal with.
Well here's this.
Even better windows tend to copy them
and they don't sell computers.
Oh,
the,
the Michael's stores.
Microsoft stores.
You mean?
I think they call them window stores,
don't they?
Well anyway,
you go to them.
Yeah.
They don't sell computers.
They sell,
they're just the software computers out
there and you go,
oh,
can I buy this?
Nope.
Like what the fuck are you selling next
level,
next level marketing go.
And like you can go and like this
laptop,
you can go to an apple store and you
could say,
hey,
I want a retina 15 inch and blah,
blah,
blah.
And they'll go,
okay,
let me see if we have it in stock.
Yes,
we do.
Come on over here.
Credit card.
Would you like your receipt emailed to
you?
Yes,
I would.
Whoa.
Do I have to stand in line?
No,
we just didn't rate him.
Then he'd get out of there and you walk
and you got a computer.
There's no other store like that other
than like you go to best buy and you can
buy an oh an apple or windows computer.
Microsoft stores will have giveaways,
special events,
and no computers.
They have anything.
They're like showcases for what they
sell,
which is the windows.
I mean,
maybe they sell windows.
Let's find out.
Jamie,
what the fuck do they sell?
I just went in one the other day.
Well,
let me guess the one you went into.
Century city.
I was in Ohio,
actually.
Jesus,
way off.
Give a fuck it a lot stuff was a lot of
the stuff,
they're selling cars.
They sell x boxes is a product Mike.
Oh,
okay.
So they sell games,
the,
a lot of games and things like that.
Now what about word Microsoft word?
Isn't that,
isn't that a program?
There's,
yes.
What's this spreadsheet?
What's a,
what's that called?
Power Point.
Power,
right.
They did have a little office suite and
a section of a smaller day,
but they sell a lot of those.
They sell a lot of it.
So he sell some software.
Yeah.
But it's just a little card to download
it.
Yeah.
Everything gets downloaded now.
Interesting.
No,
I mean obviously they just panicked and
we're like,
okay,
I guess we have to have some presence in
these malls.
We have these apple stores are,
well,
windows computers are pretty fucking
good now.
And they had our touchscreen.
A lot of them have touchscreen,
right?
Like I was at a a one of those best buys
or whatever the fuck it was the other
day.
And I was checking out the windows
computers.
I was like,
it's Kinda interesting.
Like you could touch the screen,
would you jump?
Give a fuck?
But windows have many more,
um,
problems with viruses.
They're,
they're way more vulnerable.
Right.
And there's also compatibility issues
because,
excuse me,
one of the things that,
um,
apple's done brilliantly is integrate
all the parts.
So the fact that you have the exact same
video card is everybody else,
you have the exact same motherboard.
Everything works together.
Everything works seamlessly.
The,
the problem with windows is what
[inaudible] is going to do is going to
be different than with,
you know,
Dell's going to do,
which is going to be different than
what,
and then you have to have all the
drivers in order.
And then I see different companies put
their own proprietary stuff on there.
And then there's also,
there's a,
there's more ways,
and obviously I'm not a computer expert,
but there's more ways to explore the
windows operating system apparently than
there is to exploit apple.
As far as like innovating or no,
no,
it's fine.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
I mean,
how many viruses have been,
the number of computer viruses alone.
Oh,
that's a thing I was watching the other
day.
I was watching a documentary around
stuxnet and on how they,
they concocted this,
a computer virus to attack the Iranian
news.
Oh,
I know all about this.
Ooh,
do you?
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean obviously I didn't recognize that
name,
but there's,
that documentary is out now.
Yes.
Where did you see it?
In the hotel room?
Hotel Room in Atlanta.
Yeah.
Cause there's a book,
there's a book about it now when it's
just like,
that's scary because now you can ruin
machines with computer virus.
Yeah,
correct.
Yes.
You can or launch a missile or do a,
we'll shut down the power grid or do a
lot of different things.
Yeah.
It was,
it's crazy what they did.
And they relate to the United States and
Israel if I'm not mistaken.
Yup.
Apparently.
Um,
I delwin stalking about it.
Yeah.
How did they get people to talk?
But how did they do it?
Well,
the people in the documentary,
they were not real people.
They were,
uh,
like a sort of a CGI version of a
person.
They used to talk and their voice was
all scrambled and,
but they were talking about the
developmental process and all the
people,
which is interesting.
They were saying that all the people
that work at the NSA.
Yup.
Um,
there,
there's two types of people.
Uh,
there's like military type people and
then there's like super nerds.
There's like people with like one guy
had,
they were saying had a death star that
he built out of Legos that sat on his
desk and like they had verizon.
Yeah,
I'm very a mark and they had various
like superhero dolls,
like laying around stuff.
They were like comicon type folks.
And um,
it was uh,
interesting that there were sort of
describing the environment of working
there that is these sort of a computer
folks and super nerds,
super a computer geeked out wizards who
are working together with these military
characters and the military characters
are sort of guiding them to try to
create these viruses to attack these,
um,
various facilities that I ran had.
Okay.
So let's say again,
Delwin goes on the record about this
thing.
Let's say this actually happened.
Let's assume it did.
Um,
that was built at the NSA.
I thought that was just about
eavesdropping.
Stuxnet.
Yeah,
the computer virus was built there.
Someone can cocked it.
I don't think,
I don't think they ever admitted or know
for sure where right now find out jamie
put up,
see what I,
yeah,
cause I know I understood that it was
Israel and the United States and that's
how they shut down.
They grinded that centrifuge.
They,
yes.
They undermine the centrifuge and in
Iran and I think even that is a little
bit speculation.
I don't think that's been 100%
documented.
We actually did it or where that Israel
was involved or both.
I don't,
I don't know if it's 100% documented.
Yeah,
we,
yeah.
No one goes on the record.
I don't know.
That's why I was asking who was talking
in this document.
Yeah.
I didn't watch the whole documentary
either.
I've watched the about 40 minutes.
I'm like I get get the point here.
And then you went back to game of
thrones with the,
I don't think those breaths.
I don't know what I did.
I think I was leaving.
I think it was just watching it before I
had to leave.
I'm a documentary nut.
Hmm.
Love Him.
What have you seen recently?
That's awesome.
Tickled.
Oh,
you into that,
huh?
Jamie tried to get me to watch that,
so I'll take off.
There's a lot of people that were
thinking that it was fake.
Yeah.
It looks vague.
At the beginning I was like,
I didn't.
Yeah,
no,
it's for real ties.
Saw tickled.
I saw the Brian Depalma documentary.
I saw wiener.
Did you see that?
What's that?
It's about Anthony Wiener,
the congressmen.
What does that incredible.
Really,
Joe highly recommended.
I'm not highly recommending Ted Gold.
I'm highly recommending this.
What's so good about wiener?
Okay.
You know what happened?
He had a sex scandal.
He was,
you know,
site or things that steam,
correct.
Yeah.
It's all behind me.
I'm back with my wife,
Huma.
I'm running.
I've,
I've resigned from Congress.
I'm running for mayor of New York.
I'm a New Yorker.
That thing.
Hmm.
His acts,
let me get this right.
One of his top campaign aides wants to
be a documentary filmmaker.
It's like,
do you mind if I cover your campaign?
sure.
You know me,
I've worked with you before.
You're loyal ix,
you know,
assistant during all these horrible
scandal in Congress and all of that.
I trust you.
So we ate,
brings this guy in Joe,
you know what's happening.
And then in the mid and he's winning,
he's actually a head in one poll,
the the mayor to win the mayorship if I
don't know if maybe shipped the right
word.
And then second sexting scandal breaks
while full access to him as it's
happening inside Jesus.
And at one point I'm not going to spoil
anything.
Well obviously you know what happened?
Oil The shit out of it.
At one point he,
you hear the camera guy,
his buddy just go,
why are you letting me film this?
Great.
Oh my God.
You know,
off cameras is,
why are you letting me film this?
I assume he got a piece of it,
right?
What does it say?
Hilarious.
Like a spinal tap of politics.
It's the full package mind blowing.
One of the most,
one of the best documentaries ever made
about a political scandal.
Fast,
funny,
insightful and outrageous politics that
it's insane.
Best.
And,
and he's a smart guy.
Wieners a super smart guy and his great
advocated,
great liberal advocate.
Then problem is like a lot of great
people.
Yeah.
He has a bizarre sexual drive and you're
not allowed to express that if you're in
politics.
It's the one,
I mean,
if he was an actor or if he was a
musician or a comic,
if he was one of us,
right,
you would have no problem.
He'd be like,
sorry,
I fucked up.
I freak.
And they're like that add that if weird,
pulling his dick out.
Wow.
Right.
Be psyched for his next Netflix special
where he would talk about it.
But unfortunately for him,
he's in this bullshit world where you
have to pretend you have to not
resetting sanctimonious about marriage.
Yeah.
Well,
it's not just that.
Yeah.
Sanctimonious,
say sacred.
Right?
Yeah.
Um,
you will,
you,
it's not just that it's also secret
sent.
Yes.
That's it.
Right.
I think so.
Sanctimonious is like you're talking
down to people who are not doing what
you're doing.
Right,
right.
I think there's also the issue that we
want someone who is a leader who
we have very unrealistic expectations of
them as human beings.
We want them to be completely different
than everyone we've ever met in our
lives and lead us and lead us and also
have the desire to be that one person
that Alpha who,
and those guys like fucking Kennedy and
many,
many other ones that I'm sure we don't
know who was cheating on who or who is
doing those guys are always freaks.
Bill Clinton.
They are always freaks.
Oh my God.
That you know,
Steven crowder,
Steven crowder made this,
uh,
this video about Hillary and the in and
part of the video.
It was like all reasons why you
shouldn't vote for Hillary Clinton.
Um,
it's the different things that she's
done to cover up the,
the different sexual scandals that her
husband was involved in.
When you see the list of sexual scandals
and he was involved in,
it's like,
oh my God,
and this is only the women that
complained.
Of course.
I mean,
it had to be a gang of gals that were
paid off,
ride or die.
They kept their mouth shut.
They knew how to hang.
Oh,
I see.
I see what your land with that.
Of course it's gotta be one of those
gals that you know wanted to out him for
all the dirtiness.
That's the kind of guy that wants to be
president.
That's the kind of guy there.
They're always Dick slingers wa.
Yeah,
and Anthony does kind of address that a
little bit.
Jenny,
a little bit.
He talks about at once,
once it broke,
God,
there's Joe,
there's a scene in there where he's,
you can see he's in the car and his
assistant is like,
what do we say?
Did this happen just once?
Did this just happen?
And he's like trying to figure out,
you know her,
he,
his press secretary or,
and he's,
you can hear in his head replaying
interviews he's given before where he
lied and I'm like,
oh,
I shouldn't have said that to the New
Yorker Guy.
It just,
yeah,
it's just all crump camera.
Right.
What does that guy do now?
He's,
he's the husband of whom hill?
Yeah.
Hillary's one of her top advisors.
He's going to be very close to the White
House if trends continue.
I'm at,
I'm not a predictor.
I'm not,
do you think Hillary?
Hillary probably comforted Houma cause
she's used to this shit.
She was like,
listen,
you can tell you about dudes.
She probably went down on her,
but that I don't that comfort that I
don't know.
But that's what I heard.
If you go really?
Okay.
I heard them on fortune.
Um,
yeah,
so that's a documentary I would
recommend of the ones I've seen
recently.
MMM.
But I love them all down.
I don't love them all,
but I,
I really liked the genre.
Yeah.
I'm a big fan of documentaries to give
me a couple of your favorite,
um,
merchants of doubt and I've seen that.
Oh yes.
That is about the cigarette companies
and then the will,
the same guys are now global warming.
Yeah.
Well explain
to folks at home what we're talking
about.
The same.
The the cigarette companies hire these
folks to go on all these different talk
shows like those talking head split
screen shows and like cnn where someone
would say cigarettes have been shown to
cause cancer.
This is a lie.
This is a patented lie.
Cigarettes are not addictive.
They don't cause cancer.
It still just don't to white guy and
these guys would go on all these
different shows and they would throw
doubt into the whatever the narrative
was that the FDA or whoever was trying
to say that cigarettes were bad for you.
The same exact guys,
not the same tactics but the same human
beings.
Same dudes.
Same exact guys.
It wasn't from the 50s it was from the
70s the seventh same exact guys went on.
A wows actually wouldn't when the
lawsuits were going on,
it might've been the 80s anyway,
same exact guys were then shilling for
global warming a couple decades later I
anti global warming,
anti global warning.
They were doing the exact same thing as
documentary.
It's great.
Yeah,
it's stunning.
So wiener level,
I don't know.
I haven't seen wiener.
I'd have to see wiener wiener would make
me cringe.
Yeah,
it is.
I mean it's,
it's so human is the word I would use.
Yeah.
Well,
Human Houma,
you can't be human in that world.
That's a world that doesn't allow human
behavior.
He was John Stewart roommate.
Waze.
Yeah,
one of the like in college or something
or right after.
But he's a great speaker.
He,
and he did some speeches before the
first scandal.
He had some speeches on the,
uh,
the floor of the Senate.
And uh,
I remember listening to him going,
wow,
this guy is going to be a force in
politics.
He's passionate,
he's intelligent and he knows how to
write.
She's good at framing.
Yeah.
He's righteous.
That's what I was saying of unbelievable
advocate.
There's also another scene in the movie
where Kinda can't think of the guy on
that.
Do you follow Msnbc at all?
No.
All right.
One of their talking heads has him on,
and it's this,
it's almost like a meltdown interview,
but it's,
you see the interview on television,
but also the video crew is there.
Like,
just seeing him alone.
You know what I mean?
When someone's doing a remote interview
just alone and he kinda has this look
like I'm crushing this,
so he's not really aware of how bad it's
going.
Wow.
It's,
yeah.
All right.
If you're into that at all,
I'll see it.
Yeah.
You know what's interesting to me is
that the same time what he was
experiencing,
his meltdown,
Charlie Sheen was rising like a phoenix
from the ashes talking about doing blow
and bang and hookers and saying,
you don't pay them for sex.
He pay him to leave.
And everybody's like,
go charlie,
tiger blood.
It's your point and your point you're
making exactly like there's that'll the
latitude of that kind of stuff.
What's interesting to me
is that we've sort of crossed the
divide.
Donald Trump and Donald Trump is allowed
to kind of do whatever the fuck you
want.
You know?
And especially when he's competing
against Hillary Clinton who's been shown
time and time again to be a fucking
complete liar.
She's just an absolute liar,
right?
On a grand scale,
like not just little lies,
but lies about all sorts of things,
like the origins of her name,
who she was named after.
Like she's,
she's a crazy person and she's a
politician and like in an,
in,
in a sober way re bizarre character.
So when a guy like Donald Trump is
competing against her,
like,
and you know,
it starts naming her crooked hillary,
like someone,
someone tried to get some traction by
calling Donald Trump a womanizer and
saying that,
you know,
he's a,
and people don't care who cames a fuck.
Of course he is looking at me.
He's a billionaire with a super hot wife
who did lesbian porn,
by the way.
Do you see that?
I don't lack a lot of porn.
Tell me about it.
In New York,
Daily News took a,
that some cover,
uh,
the,
some photos that they put on the cover
yesterday and uh,
it was,
was the say Melania,
how'd he say it?
Well on it with a bow.
Okay.
Yeah.
Chuck Pal's a Wowza like,
come on,
that is not just the hottest first lady,
potential first lady ever.
But off the charts.
It's like the difference Chine,
like who's the toughest fourth grader
and Mike Tyson,
right?
I mean fucking crazy.
I mean this,
this guy is going to be the fucking
president.
It's super pop.
It's super possible.
It's not just 50 50 in my hand because I
think that as time goes on she looks
worse and worse and the only thing that
that saves her,
his,
his outrageousness and I think he hired
that guy who has that political
strategist that he hired that is um,
I don't,
I do not remember his name.
Paul Manafort.
Is that his name?
Chief chief of his campaign.
The most recent I that he hired about
three months ago,
four months ago.
But the idea was that this guy is going
to shape the new,
like the idea is like he's going to God,
he got the nomination now that he's got
the nomination nomination secure.
Now you go after Hillary and you bring
in all the people that are on the fence.
How do you do that?
You become more moderate.
You become more,
less outrageous with your statements and
you try to point out the benefits of you
versus the,
the problems with her.
Of course,
if he does that successfully,
do you think he has a chance?
Yes,
100%.
He has a chance.
He's the fucking Republican.
Again,
he has a chance.
There's a lot of people that are just
not going to vote for Hillary because
they do not want more Democrats in
office.
They're like,
he fucking nuts.
Like this,
eight years of Clinton and then the
eight years of Bush and then you've got
eight years of Obama.
It's just stands to reason that you're
going to want to have eight years of
some Republican now
you ma,
I don't know.
I mean,
I looked at the polls,
you know,
I try not to follow because I just feel
like it's so overwhelming at this point.
But,
um,
I don't know.
I feel like she's in pretty good shape.
Do you think so?
That's again,
I'm a comedian.
I'm like,
like just what's today?
What's today?
The 2nd of August.
Yeah.
So this is what I'm saying.
There's one sec.
We voted in November.
We got along way to go.
We've got a hot 99 days.
Gary Johnson is going to be on your
show.
Yeah,
well he was supposed to be on the phone
with him.
Where am I?
We're on a tweet with them.
When you mean,
well you tweeted something with my name
and isn't it?
Oh,
that's the first time I've ever,
most likely he's going to have to pull
out on Thursday,
but he'll be back again.
We've already had them on once before.
It was,
he was great.
Great.
He's great.
He's a good guy.
He's,
he's seat mean.
I don't know if I agree with him about
everything,
but I agree with them about most things.
Uh,
you know,
he's got some interesting ideas,
but he's a reasonable person,
like an actual reasonable person,
meaning guy.
And the more he talks in,
the more he,
the more he speaks.
If someone is going to get hurt by him
being around the question,
is,
is going to be trump or is it going to
be Clinton,
someone's gonna get hurt by this
reasonable alternative.
And this,
this is attitude that everybody has
about who are you throwing your vote or
if you're voted for him.
Not everybody does this is,
this is,
this is a stupid attitude and the only
thing that could possibly potentially
fuck a third party candidate is the
electoral college.
Like that's where things get really
weird.
The Electoral College,
the idea of the representatives,
you know like you don't necessarily vote
for,
you know,
the state picks a representative.
The representative is the one who kind
of puts in the vote.
Yeah.
So it's that could fuck them,
but,
and also the idea that you're going to
throw your vote away if you vote for a
third party candidate,
that kind of fucks him.
But we're going to have to come at,
there's gonna come a time where we
realized how ridiculous to pay two
barter system.
I'm with you on that.
Everybody is,
who thinks it's great,
it's ending.
I find me the person who thinks it's
great.
I think the DNC and the RNC think it's
great that they get to participate in
the debates and get money and all of
that and it gets a really good,
what they did it their way.
Ernie never had a chore burned.
He didn't have a chance.
Chance they rigged it and then she
immediately goes to Hillary's campaign.
We get a nice juicy reward.
Come on over.
We'll get just some speech.
Oh,
you're talking about Wasserman
Wasserman.
Yeah.
Ah,
whatever.
I don't like talking politics.
I feel like it's like talking about a
magic trick.
Well,
what I really liked is when he made her
11th grade,
he didn't really megger levitate,
man.
You know that.
Right.
All right.
Let me ask you about this then.
Please do talk about Michael Page.
Oh,
okay.
Michael Venom page.
I let him.
That's his middle name.
Yes.
Or just stage.
You're talking about the fighter?
Yeah.
Okay.
Cause they just,
again,
I,
you know so much more about this than I
did,
but I saw
the highlights of that fight and then
you tubed his other fights.
Yeah.
And I've never seen anyone fight like
this.
Have you watched his other fights
because there's one in particular seeing
all of his fights.
Okay.
There was one in particular where he's
fighting this guy and they get down to
the ground and they're grappling around
and all of a sudden he gets it.
The guy caught him in a leg lock.
Yeah.
Gets the guy's foot and he looks at the
guy and he started smiling as he's
turning his foot and then the guy
eventually at a,
yeah,
and I was like,
this is like the,
he's hands down.
Is that a style we don't fight hands
down.
Well you can.
The thing about it is he has a very
unusual set of skills.
What he is is a,
a sport karate champion and what sport?
Karate is.
Point fighting is a style of fighting
where you dive in and you were
[inaudible] point card at karate
tournaments.
Just tell me just quickly,
I don't know what point.
Okay.
Point karate is.
The way it works is like there's a judge
on one side,
there's a judge on the other side and
there's two.
There's,
well there oftentimes just several
judges and there's two fighters.
And they stand the outside and the idea
is they blitz at each other,
they dive in and the idea is to try to
hit a guy once and if you tag them,
if you do tag and they stopped the
action,
the referee steps in and then the
referees will point.
Like oftentimes there's an exchange of
blows and the referees will say,
I got him with the straight punch,
I got him with the round kick.
And if there's no consensus,
they continue to fight and no one gets a
point.
But if there is a consensus,
if one guy one the exchange,
they will give like there's a great
point.
Karate fight,
um,
between Michael Venom page and uh,
this guy who's a fighting and glory
right now,
Raymond Daniels,
who's a,
also,
he was originally a point karate
champion who went over to kickboxing.
Glory is a big kickboxing organization,
whereas Michael Page fights for
Bellatore.
So he's fighting MMA.
Whereas this other guy who was a
champion is like this is them fighting
right now.
Right.
Is that page and I'm Daniel's.
Yeah.
All right,
I see it.
See how they fight.
They wear these helmets on and the idea
is to just score to dive in and hit each
other and then get out.
And if they can hit each other and score
cleanly,
like watch what happens when they score,
you'll see it.
So they're bouncing around,
they move very fast.
And the idea behind this is the blitz.
So they noticed beeping in and
attacking,
see how they bolt of their hands down.
Well,
I didn't feel like the other guy has his
hands up a little more than Michael
Page.
Michael White?
No.
Yes,
he is the bulk of the notes down.
They both have their hands down and the
other guy lifts his hands up
occasionally,
but no,
they both have their hands completely
down.
The Orthodox method of holding your
hands up,
your hands would be at your cheekbones.
These guys are not fighting and remotely
like that.
They're both very similar in their
style.
Okay,
I understand.
But this style,
I know Sandy,
like 80 people in the crowd who goes to
this,
mostly karate students most,
it's mostly people that are either their
students,
their fellow students are competing and
they're sitting there watching or
they're going to compete and they watch,
or the families of the people competing.
But it never really became much of a
spectator sport.
I could understand that,
but it's a very unique talent.
The ability to leap in and perform those
techniques very quickly.
And most fighters don't have that timing
and they don't know how to avoid it and
they don't have the ability to avoid
that.
Crazy bummer.
How's good to see you?
Very good.
Well he was a world champion and a sport
karate.
Okay,
okay.
That stuff.
He's a world champion and so what he had
to do is you just had to learn,
take down defense,
and then he had to learn some
submissions and some grappling.
It takes a long time to learn those
things.
But if you are the type of person that
could become a champion in one aspect of
martial arts,
that type of intense dedication and
focus,
you could transfer that potentially to
other martial arts if you have the time
and you have an inclination.
Well,
I read something that you said that was
the worst injury you ever,
so yeah.
Is that hyperbole or no?
No.
So worst mma.
I'm never seen anybody get their skull
crushed.
That's the worst injury I've ever seen.
I've seen broken orbital bones.
That's fairly common.
All right.
The uh,
the bones around your eyeball or are
fairly fragile,
but the forehead,
I've never seen anybody's forehead get
crushed,
but as a perfect storm [inaudible] he
charged in,
tried to shoot for a take down and page,
caught him with a knee.
He leaped in.
Elite caught him.
Yeah.
What's the name of that jumping knee?
Say it again.
Jumping knee.
You just jumped up and hit him with a
knee pain.
Jumping knee.
That sounds like a,
like an Indian who didn't need yeah,
and jumping.
I said,
hey,
wow.
It is intense to see Joe.
Yeah,
it was intense.
Yeah.
I mean,
I'm not kidding.
It was,
I was like,
whoa.
Well I've been involved in martial arts
for more than since you were scared
little child.
Yeah.
More than 30 years.
And I've never seen that injury and
never seen it that bad.
Well,
I saw also your buddy,
I don't know if he's your buddy.
Um,
Silva.
What's his first Anderson Silva.
Anderson Silva break his own leg.
I've seen that before.
I've seen that a couple of times.
You ever done that?
No,
I've never your own leg?
but I did get my leg broken before I
broke the,
um,
not the,
with the Tibia as the large shin bone.
I broke the fibula.
Somebody we collided.
It was actually a sparring session.
A friend of mine,
a threw a kick and I have through kick
at the same time and his heel hit my
fibula and I've got a hairline fracture
in my fibula but not broken.
Like it didn't break like that,
but it could have seen.
Had you seen that before?
Yes.
See what happened to Anderson is he
broke it earlier and then he broke it
all the way through,
so he cracked it.
Oh,
one kick that he threw in the same
height.
Yup.
Oh crap.
Hey.
He really cracked it before that because
he,
it was,
it was hurting,
and then he threw that kick and hit the
exact same spot and just snap like a
twig.
That's according to his manager.
His manager feels like he broke it
before that and then broke it again.
It's very unusual to see someone's legs
snap like that,
but it happens.
There it is right there.
I've seen it happen three times.
Person giving,
kicking.
It's always the person kicking the
person kicking price their own legs.
Yeah.
Occasionally it's the person on the
other side,
but it's a,
what the difference is,
is where you're kicking,
you're kicking with the middle or the
bottom of your Shin,
which is a thinner bone.
Oh.
Then you're colliding with the top of
the knee where the,
the the Tibia,
the knee.
It didn't seem possible.
It just didn't seem there.
You could see it as snapping.
Yeah.
Do you remember Joe Theismann?
Remember that Monday night game?
Yeah.
I'm broken legs or particularly
disturbing for people.
There's a guy named tyrone spong.
But you're saying not for you like,
yeah,
I mean it bothers me,
but you're looking at me like you people
that,
that probably about it.
You Wayne.
I have seen for sure I've seen way too
many people get injured.
Right.
So you're a little more immune to little
immune.
I've told the story before,
but this is,
my wife was there,
her leg.
She had the uh,
card,
uh,
hatch,
you know,
like the back of the hatch and she had a
package and she lifted her head up and
hit the corner of the hatch and cut her
for it and blood pouring down her head.
She was freaking out because she was
bleeding and I looked at it,
I was like snuffin,
it's like mica stitch like one stitch.
It's nothing.
Don't worry about it.
Like to me,
I was like,
walk it off.
Like,
this is nothing like I'm so used to
seeing people just caught open,
smashed,
broken nose,
swollen eyes,
cuts all over their face,
head kick,
knockouts,
arm's broken,
snapped legs,
torn apart,
knees.
I'm so used to it.
And that's just in the comedy clubs
Janam hell and try to win.
So you've seen it all.
I've just seen thousands of fights.
I mean I've seen,
I've called professionally at least
probably 1500 funds.
So I've seen so many knockouts and so
many injuries.
I'm so used to seeing trauma almost too
used to it.
Like it doesn't bother me.
How can people get injured?
And that was paid 100% a hundred percent
the worst.
Definitely the worst.
Never seen that.
That's your fucking brain.
That's the protection that your brain
has to the outside world.
It's basically gone.
And if he got hit again,
that same spot,
he's probably dead.
Dead.
Yeah.
I mean,
how's he doing?
How's,
he said look,
you know,
we can see how he's doing.
That's the surgery.
The pictures on the ride or post
surgery?
Yeah.
Is that what they put in there and those
little metal look in there,
you can see it.
It's a,
those are plates that they've,
uh,
most likely titanium that they've
screwed in place to,
uh,
sort of reconstruct his scholar on of
his skull.
Yeah,
they've pulled it up and he wheeling
ever wrestle again.
Fight.
You mean fight?
Yeah,
me starts,
I could wrestle again.
The,
the,
the question remains is if any
psychosocial psychological,
it's not what I would be worried about.
I'd be worried about the actual
physiological damage is more than
psychology.
Yeah.
Expanding.
Well,
he had to get his fucking skin pulled
back.
I mean if you look at what they did,
they literally made a scar around the
top of his head.
Look at what it needed.
His hairline is essentially a giant scar
now.
They pulled his face forward and they
rebuilt his forehead with these fucking
bolt there.
He buys knows too.
Apparently his nose a shatter too,
but you know,
it's like a very,
very significant injury and I just think
psychologically you could never maybe
get used to it.
Get used to getting hurt.
Guys get used to getting knocked down.
Guys get used to getting punched.
You get used to it.
It's,
you know,
it's a part of who you are,
if that's what you choose to do for a
living.
But I mean his [inaudible] have you been
knocked out like out nick unconscious?
No,
I've never been mugged out.
Yeah,
I've,
I've been dropped.
I got [inaudible],
I got hit and my legs went out.
Like you get hit in the jaw and you seem
like stop working and you just collapse.
And then I got back up and I got dropped
again and the referee stopped the fight.
But I was conscious that was the last
fight I ever had.
That was a kickboxing fight.
That was it.
Yeah.
Well I was already,
did you ever have a nickname?
Never had a nickname.
If you could tell it was this guy's
nick.
Nick,
could both these guys have one with his
nickname was cyborg.
Cyborg and venom and venom.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's say you could go back,
pick a nickname,
sweetie pie.
You'll go to the ADC,
this two guys and kissed each other.
Who were they?
What are you talking about?
Some like face and watching porn.
No,
Ella MMA thing.
Oh,
long time ago.
Herring and this Japanese gentleman,
I knew he wouldn't eat herring.
Knocked him out.
Oh,
he can't stay.
I looked at the guy.
No,
I mean maybe it's a different one.
Maybe talking about different one.
You're talking about Anderson Silva and
Chris Weidman.
Anderson Silva like touched faces with
Weidman.
Weidman's just wouldn't move.
There's possible this it right here.
Is that the one?
No,
no.
I know,
I know.
The guys listening on the podcast can't
see,
but the is like two guys faces rate up
again.
Here's the silver and Chris Weidman
Silva is were like nose to nose and then
one guy kind of kissed his stem and then
the other guy kissed him back and then
they kind of,
I haven't seen that.
I saw that one.
Well I probably have,
I just forgot.
But the,
the really funny one was Anderson,
not Anderson Silva.
Heath herring was doing a face off with
this Japanese gentlemen.
I don't remember the guy's name,
but the guy kissed him on the lips and
he tearing,
knocked him out cold as they were like
doing the stare down.
He hit him with a right hook and kit.
Wash it right here.
This is a heat herring,
Texas.
Crazy horse.
Bad motherfucker.
So they get face to face watch.
Okay,
there's standing face to face.
He kisses him,
boom.
Kaos him out cold and you lose the fight
automatically if you hit before the
you're,
it's supposed to kiss people.
So wait.
So I don't know if he lost,
I think Japanese look at things entirely
differently.
The Japanese people might've rewarded
him for this because it's part of the
spectacle.
It's a spectacle of look at.
He's like,
what the fuck man,
don't kiss me.
And he said he right.
So I was like,
I'm sorry the guy.
Yes ma'am.
Don't fucking desk.
Hey tearing.
Now you know the next guy won't kiss
them.
Do not.
He's pointing down on the ground.
Look,
he said he kissed and I fucking hit him.
Well,
what do you want me to do?
I'm sorry.
All right,
I thought I saw another one more guy
kissed the guy.
I think you did.
All right.
I now remember the guy kissed and the
other guy kissed and they laughed.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I'm just getting that one.
It was though Mike Bernardo might've
been a k one bout.
Maybe it's,
you know these guys more than I do.
Talk to me about the stare down a little
bit.
What about it?
Cause I saw one,
your buddy Anderson Silva one cause at
one time it didn't look at the guy.
A lot of times guys don't look at him
like bobby witness strategy is on that
boss.
Rutan didn't look at guys a fade or a
million ankle was probably one of the
greatest of all time.
Not Probably.
Definitely one of the greatest days.
Name again fade or a million inco.
He's absolutely,
he's a Russian gentleman.
His name is he the,
in Russia they don't even say Fado.
They say fuel door,
fuel door,
a million ankle.
But it's,
it's spelled in,
you know,
obviously it's English as version.
The version of the way we spell it.
It's different than the way they spell
it because they use different,
when did he,
when did he fight?
Well,
he's still fighting.
He just started a fighting again
recently.
He just fought and won but looked really
bad.
Right.
This is a different fight.
This is a different stare down.
These guys are going to kiss too now I,
oh,
he kissed him and the other guy got mad.
Ooh.
I don't really,
don't have to keep watching guys get
suddenly.
I don't want to be known as Wayne
Fetterman just loves guys kissing.
That's not,
and we'd just so he wouldn't look at
them.
He looked down a cause.
This is a waste of energy.
Did you?
Oh,
waste of energy.
Yeah,
you can.
You,
if you get anxious,
you get anxious about it.
It's a waste of energy.
Not a,
uh,
what's the word for like,
like intimidation.
Nonsense.
Honestly,
it's nonsense because you're going to
fight.
It's raw.
It's already wrapped and then she
already happening.
So you don't have some guys who are
really good at it.
Some guys,
like some guy and also some guys would
get angry if other guys were doing it,
so they would out stare them down.
Like,
here's the best stare down of all time
in MMA.
I'll show you the best steer down.
Right.
Mirko Cro cop versus vandelay Silva.
This is the best stare down ever because
Vander Ley was,
they used,
his nickname is the ax murderer.
He's a fucking savage.
He was a pride middleweight champion.
Bad motherfucker.
Just a bad mother.
But he was fighting Mirko Cro cop who
was the head of an antiterrorist
squadron in Croatia and he's a real
murder.
This is you talking about a different
kind of fucking straight up killer and
an elite high level kickboxer so look at
cro cop on the left.
Yeah,
I sam C.
Dot.
That's the eyes of the guy who's killed
someone with a knife.
See is a fucking completely different
stare down here.
Cro gobs looking at him and he's not
budging.
This is the first time we're vandelay
lost a stare down.
A vandelay was used to staring guys down
and they would be intimidated.
And the Cro cop looked at him like he
was dinner and Cro.
Cop wound up head kicking him like
video,
um,
pull up,
uh,
Mirko Cro,
Cop k o vandelay Silva.
Can I say on a side note,
one of the greatest head kick knockouts
ever?
Yeah,
I want to see it.
But on a side note,
it's impressive that you know all these
guys names.
Well,
it's part of my job.
I understand,
but it's still like,
I feel like they're like friends.
It's only impressive because you don't
know their names.
If you were like another mma fan,
you blink.
Yeah.
Rogan knows those guys names.
It's as he supposed to know those well
fellow comedian.
I'm just saying it's a break.
You've gotta be the only comedian that
knows all these guys names.
Maybe Adam Hunter.
He probably would know it.
He's,
he's a big fan anyway.
Just probably wouldn't know.
Maybe as many,
I don't know.
Maybe it does.
It's impressive.
Well,
I just,
I don't,
I don't know a lot of sports.
Like you guys were talking about
basketball before the show started.
I don't know Jack Shit about basketball.
I,
there's a limited amount of data that a
man keeping his head or a woman I'm
assuming.
Right.
And I just don't,
you know,
I only have so many stats.
Of course.
My,
my stats are filled up with I before we
get to this spice.
This,
all right.
This is Mirko Cro cop.
Well,
this is a slow motion version of it.
Watch this.
Ooh.
That's those two guys that were staring
each other down.
Oh,
I see.
Yeah.
With a stare down is actually from their
first fight.
The head kick was from their second
fight.
Anyway.
Um,
stats head kicks.
No,
no,
no.
I know.
No,
I was going to ask you of the sports
that you don't follow,
what are your favorites?
What are your least favorites?
I don't really care about any of them.
They can get them all illegal.
I wouldn't give a fuck baseball,
nothing.
Waste of time.
Okay.
Can you just say you're name
right,
but he forgot to touch the bag that was
on the ground so it didn't,
is it because you think that this is the
ultimate sport?
Because it's,
it's not,
it's not the oil down that it's the
ultimate sport because it is boiled
down.
It is unquestionably the most exciting
thing.
The two human beings can engage in it
because it's not a game.
It's a game,
right.
Consequence.
It's high level problem solving with
dire physical consequences.
That's interest.
That's really,
did you come up with that?
Yes.
That's mine.
That's pretty good.
Yeah.
Say it again.
High level problem solving with dire
physical consequences.
Right.
Okay.
All
right.
So,
um,
so well I don't even have to get through
baseball,
soccer,
the soccer when he is interested.
It's bunker impression about all of
them.
I've been watching soccer recently
because I'm friends with Ian Edwards and
he's a giant soccer fan and he actually
has a soccer podcast and uh,
he's been trying to get me into soccer,
so we watched a bunch of soccer games
together.
Matches.
It's fun,
it's fun,
but when they get smacked accidentally
and they go down like bitches,
oh,
I can't,
I can't.
It's the worst thing.
I agree with you.
I looked at him,
I looked over at Ian and I'm like,
I can't support this kind of fucking
pussy behavior.
This is horrible.
I that I agree with you 100%.
Yeah.
That's hard to watch.
That is hard to watch because it's like
you're a competitor.
You're a competitor.
Like it's pathetic.
It's pathetic.
You agree with everything.
Someone knows when someone's smacks him
on,
you know,
everyone knows you could see it.
They have replaced,
you don't have to go down like a bitch.
You have to hold your face and roll
around the ground and agony.
Especially when you've seen what I've
seen.
You seen guys get right kneed in the
face,
like Cyborg,
you know,
like,
or any event venoms knee into Cyborg
skull.
Yeah,
I know these guys names now.
Now you do.
Well,
just their nicknames.
It's um,
but it's an interesting sport.
It's an interesting sport in that,
you know,
it's,
there's some pretty complex strategy
going on.
There's a lot of move.
Now.
I remember I talked to you about this
long time ago.
There was a great episode of either CNN
sports or espn when they brought you on
to talk about how horrible mma was
compared to boxing and then you in a
very skilled manner,
took apart the interviewer and the other
guy with a,
your knowledge boxing and then be
explaining why you thought mma or I
don't even know if that's the right
transport term,
uh,
was,
the APP,
the natural evolution of what was going
on.
Well,
people remember that.
Yes.
Do you talk to,
I'm assuming you're talking about that a
lot on this podcast are now to talk
about the difference.
No,
that moment,
no.
What was it?
There was a,
there was espn,
espn you,
but it was the early days of the UFC
where people didn't accept the UFC and
there's,
that guy has actually become a ufc fan
and,
but I think they had to realize that
there's room for everybody.
Look,
I'm a boxing fan.
I've always been a boxing fan.
All of this.
Oh yeah.
My whole,
my whole life I've always been a boxing
fan.
Can I say something about maxine?
Sure.
Whenever I hear the term pound for
pound,
that term,
right?
All I think of,
no.
Okay.
That's a little guy.
I don't know.
Well,
whatever we're talking about,
see it's,
most people think it's Jon Jones and
he's 205 pounds.
Oh,
he is?
Okay.
Well he's around two 20 whenever.
Whenever I hear that term it's always
like,
well,
they're dying little doll because most
of the time during Roy Jones Jr day was
him and he was a one 75 and he'd won the
heavyweight title.
He beat John Ruiz at heavyweight.
Roy Jones Jr.
Yes.
Yeah.
Anyways,
yeah.
I thought
super middleweight,
which is one 68 he won the light
heavyweight title.
He fought as divisions in mma.
Of course.
Same One,
same number.
No,
not the silos.
Different numbers.
Same names.
It's very confusing.
Like welterweight welterweight and
boxing is one 47 welterweight and mma
it's one 70 yeah.
So those guys are just bigger.
It's just a different name because we
have a one 45 weight class.
What's it called?
A featherweight.
Oh,
did they have an ultra featherweight?
No,
they have a bantamweight that mini
federal.
Yeah.
Well,
they have a lightweight,
which is one 55 which is the small one.
55 in boxing would be super,
super lightweight or junior middleweight
or super welterweight or junior
middleweight rather.
Interesting.
Yeah.
It doesn't have weight classes in Bach,
in mma rather.
There's maybe people think there's too
many and boxing,
which I don't have a problem with it.
I like the fact there's a lot of weight
classes cause it gives you a lot of guys
options and it gives guys options for
championship and counters.
But I think that the UFC could use more
weight classes.
I think there should be a way class
minimum every 10 pounds cause 10 pounds
is that there's a big difference between
a one 70 pound guy on one 80 pound guy.
As far as strengths,
it's a big difference in what they can
do.
How long before from the way in to the
fight did they have to put on weight?
But it used to be 24 hours,
but now it's quite a bit more because
now that you usually let them start
early in the morning as early as a,
I believe 8:00
AM sometimes 10:00
AM so they have from 10 to noon to make
weight now and the way in,
um,
now when we do the Wayne's,
I announced the winds Friday.
I've always done that.
Yeah.
And I'm now,
it's the official weight.
It's not the actual way and they don't
actually get on the scale.
And then the way in the they,
they get on the scale.
It's more for show.
It's kind of stupid.
Did they get on a scale at all because
they're hurting.
File already weighed in.
They've already waited.
They already waiting.
Yeah.
We probably shouldn't have them stand on
a scale and do this a nonsense.
It's really kind of foolish and I'm
actually going to talk to them about
maybe coming up with a better solution.
You need me to send an angry email?
What do you need me tweet off the
fetterman account at federal people
won't know it's you.
Yeah.
They're looking for Wayne Fetterman.
Who was this angry fetterman fetterman
who was furious at the,
sure.
Rod.
That is the way in which is like a
charade when you're drunk off.
Shiraz.
This is a total,
sure rod.
God Damn sure Rod.
What's going on here?
You could be indignant.
You'd be furious.
Failed Way it all the time.
All the time.
What happens to that fight?
They either lose 20% of their purse to
their opponent and the fight goes on or
they cancel the fight.
And it depends entirely upon their
opponent's choice.
Like it doesn't like,
there's a perfect example.
This past weekend is a guy named Ian
Mccall and he knows his name fighting.
You're good,
Justin.
Scoggins we're
kidding.
I'm kidding.
This is my thing.
And get it.
Oh my God thing.
You're so silly.
Um,
and scoggins was supposed to get down to
one 25 is a flyweight fight.
This is the lightest weight class in the
UFC.
Flies.
The lighter,
the lightest.
Well,
there's a straw weight for women,
which would,
we just won 15 but there's not assuming
strawweight division.
Millie.
Well,
women one 15 is not even the small size.
The name Straw,
like literally your pizza Straw.
I guess he never thought about it flies
better than being strong.
Is it better to be a fly then straw?
Alecia,
you have some this.
You're an insect.
He'd at least you have some fallout
today are not moving.
Some farmer daughters Chilean on
flirting with the guy from the gas
stations.
I think about it.
That's how I think it's strong.
What do you think of that?
I think that is wheat Ra.
What is straws?
Straws,
like grass that's been,
no,
that's,
hey,
right.
Hey is when they take grass and they
chop it down.
They roll it up and they feed it to
cows,
right?
That's,
Hey,
like Hay Bales Charlotte.
It is straw struggle with like there's
little the same.
Are they the same?
We're going to find out,
well,
you always see like wheat in someone's
teeth.
I always think of wheat more is like a
stock that has little flowers on it and
that little,
I mean straws,
a stock,
usually a waste product of wheat.
Oh,
okay.
It's the same thing I guess that's used
as a bedding for barnyard animals.
It's the waste product.
Interesting.
So the straws,
the part that you don't use hay is
typically Alfalfa or grass that is used
as animal feed.
Interesting.
Okay.
Now I know cause I strawn.
Hey,
I said would you rather be again,
let's go back to your question that you
pose.
Fuck about names,
Bro.
I don't care.
Straw fly gives a shit.
Honestly,
I think no names.
I think one or two numbers.
Yeah,
I agree with that.
He's the 155 pound champion.
That's what I think.
Very clear.
Everyone will know.
I don't like the welter weight.
I'm going to fire up a navy senator.
Wait,
come on.
Crude heavyweight.
You know,
here's another interesting thing.
Heavyweight has a weight limit.
You can't be heavier than 265 pounds in
boxing in the UFC because we don't have
a super heavyweight division.
We have a heavyweight division,
he goes up to two 65 and that's what's
sanctioned.
And then from to 65 on up is super
heavyweight,
but the UFC does not have and has never
had a super heavyweight division.
They didn't want to see those guys that
are not,
just never had it.
Well,
it doesn't,
they don't have to be like fat.
You made the fat gesture and I did.
They could easily be just giant like
brock lesnar.
Yeah.
As to suck.
Wait,
he has to dehydrate himself to make the
265 pound weight limit.
My how much did a little,
well,
you know Lebron,
this is basketball.
The sport.
You don't know.
He's an athlete,
right?
That I've seen him anything.
He has sneakers.
Jamie,
how many do you think he weighs?
300 pounds.
Weight ever to 70 to 70 75 huge.
All right.
I guess
he could have somebody that says,
yeah,
I'm super heavyweight.
Yeah,
I do fat guys.
but remember that Guy Butterball is that
him let her being,
what was his thing?
He just died,
right?
No,
he's alive.
He is.
He's fat as fuck,
but it's like a bouncer or something
that became a,
um,
well I don't know what his deal was.
I know he's a cook.
They'll eat like supposed to be really
good at cooking pork chops.
No,
in mma for awhile while boxing,
kickboxing,
Hudson,
some kickboxing fights.
So can I go back to your last fight?
Yeah,
sure.
Cause I'm really curious,
but just as somebody who's like afraid
of fighting,
so,
and we'll just curious about it like you
get hit,
did you think you are winning at the
time was definitely winning?
Yeah.
Oh No,
you're winning like a short story.
I fought three times that day.
That was part of the problem.
But there was two problems.
One of the problems was that you know
the exact date?
No,
I don't.
Okay.
One of the problems was that I was doing
comedy at the time and I was working
full time and in Boston and it was
trying to figure out what I was doing
with my life and I was not nearly as
dedicated as I was to fighting just a
few years before that.
And I was 21 on my way to 22.
I might've been 22 at the time or maybe
a month or two before it turned 22 and
that's when I decided I was done because
I was,
I knew I was half assing it.
And uh,
I just wasn't training as hard as I was
just a couple of years ago when I was
fighting and competing and I was
throwing Massachusetts state champion
and I was competing in national
tournaments and traveling all over the
country,
I'd realize that it was a dead end.
And then I had put an incredible amount
of time and effort into something,
even at its best case scenario.
There was no money in it.
And then I'd go,
I'd also had a problem in that I started
competing in taekwondo,
which was a mostly a kicking art and
very little hand techniques.
And then I went from taekwondo.
I started training at a boxing gym and I
realized that I really needed a massive
amount of work on my hands.
And so I started boxing and I was
getting beat up a lot.
Like I was,
I was having wars in the gym and I
wasn't always winning.
And uh,
I was kidding.
We just slid down in these wars you're
having and you're getting beat up,
just beat up.
You're getting beat.
Okay.
You get punched in the face,
you're getting punched in the face.
And we all know that great Tyson thing.
Everyone has a plan until someone
punching in the face.
Uh,
like what's going through your head?
Is it just like,
keep moving,
Throw Your Jab,
move your head,
don't get hit as much.
Move your feet,
use your foot work.
Don't stand in the pocket.
Tees up all technique.
Yeah,
I mean,
you're sparring.
You know,
what I was doing was I was,
there was a guy named Joe Lake who was
my boxing coach who was a,
this is what happened.
I was working at this place called
Nautilus plus in revere,
Massachusetts.
They had this section of this gym that
we had rented out,
right?
This big room that we had rented out.
And I had started teaching taekwondo
classes there.
And so I would go out and put out flyers
and I would teach classes and I also
taught at Boston University.
I had my own classes at bu and flyered.
Yeah,
put flyers up.
Did you ever do flyers for comedy?
No.
Never did flies for comedy.
Did you ever stand outside of Chlamydia
club?
No,
never did that.
I needed it.
But I know that's a New York thing.
That's a New York thing.
Yeah,
they stand down.
They kept,
there's so much foot traffic trying to
get people to go to the seller.
It's just funny.
It's just like if all the Comedians I've
known that are like or band,
you know,
you would hear about these bands in the
eighties starting out and I had to put
up flyers,
flyers and then you are doing it for a
Tae Kwon.
Dell?
Yeah,
I was doing it for lessons or lesson or
like,
uh,
I think there was like a photo of
someone throwing a side kick or
something like that.
And it would be,
you know,
the name of the gym and the phone number
for the school where you could go call.
And,
and did it have your name?
Yeah,
my name,
no nickname.
Rogan.
No,
no nickname.
It just had my credentials and my,
you know,
black belt and all that jazz for time.
Massachusetts state taekwondo champion
and won the US Open and all this and
stuff.
Yeah,
I've got a bunch of that shit today.
Metals in my closet.
Everything is in the class.
Just hanging around,
you know,
what am I going to do with them?
I've never want to,
you know,
a boxing or a taekwondo.
Everyone.
All right.
And he's anger is starting to hurt me.
I don't know why you're attacking me.
We were having a pretty good time here,
weren't we?
I don't think I'm attacking me.
I think you're super sensitive.
I am.
I am a sensitive guy.
Uh,
um,
yeah.
I have a couple of sports stroke,
football trophies from when I was a kid.
Yeah.
Okay.
On a team,
but not an individual like this.
I,
that's what I didn't like about teams.
Again,
I didn't like the idea that we all one
together.
I was very selfish.
I wanted to win and I didn't also like
the idea that we lost,
cause bobby dropped the ball and now I'm
a loser because bobby's a fucking Klutz.
I'm a loser like that.
Okay.
So why?
Anyway,
I went from,
I'm teaching,
I was teaching at this class and this
guy,
Joe Lake was a friend of mine who was a
boxer.
He was a professional boxer and his
boxing coach,
he taught a lot of pro boxers in the
area.
He came in and was watching me work out
and he wanted to learn some kicks and
we,
we started talking and found out I was a
boxing fan.
We started talking about boxing and he
told me what he does and he said,
uh,
you know,
hey,
how about we make a deal,
you know,
teach you some boxing,
you teach me some kicking and I'm
sending it,
love it.
So when I started learning from him,
he's a great coach and teach me boxing
techniques and stuff like that.
I started realizing how little I knew
about combining boxing and kicking
together and also how little I knew
about really like getting hit and
rolling with punches and I just was
missing that aspect of,
of,
of fighting.
So I started doing it and as I started
doing it,
um,
and I competed and I started doing a lot
of sparring,
I started realizing that what I
dedicated all my time to taekwondo was
limited in a lot of ways.
Like without learning how to throw
punches,
it was like a real problem with it.
So I kind of knew that I was not going
to compete in taekwondo anymore.
I kind of knew like,
wow,
this is sort of opened up my eyes to the
fact that taekwondo is very limited and
there was no mma back then.
So like taekwondo you see in mma a lot.
There was no,
I'm not very happy with everything
turned the way,
everything,
but I'm just like,
no,
no to tiff tested yourself and that kind
of,
I would have for sure 100%,
but like I would have definitely done
it.
I mean,
I did kickboxing because I wanted to
find out about that.
I did taekwondo because I wanted to find
out about that.
I fought in karate tournaments.
I did a lot of different stuff because I
just wanted to see what it was like.
Um,
but if mma was around,
I would have realized that,
well,
all this stuff is all fine and dandy,
all this kicking and punching.
But if somebody takes you down and then
when are you going to do,
I would've realized then,
and that's one of the reasons why when I
came to La,
I immediately got into Jujitsu.
So I started taking Jujitsu in 1996 and
the reason why I started taking it was
because of watching the UFC and seeing
guys take guys the ground,
seeing hoists,
gracie dominate guys and try to come and
tap them.
And I realized,
Oh,
okay,
I got to learn this stuff.
This is some totally different stuff.
And I kind of caught the wave,
like I got into it as a traditional
martial artists as a taekwondo
practitioner and then went from that
into all these other martial arts that I
had kind of like sort of assimilated and
plus I was a big Bruce Lee fan and that
was one of the things that Bruce Lee
subscribed to [inaudible].
He was the,
he was the first proponent of mixing and
integrating different styles together
and his g coon dos style was that it was
entirely the philosophy as a style
absorb what's useful,
take all the useful aspects of different
martial arts and apply them.
I saw like that could almost apply to
bigger things in life.
Oh for sure.
Of course.
Yeah,
and also the limitations of not doing
that apply the limitations of being very
rigid idea in your life.
Definitely.
Yeah,
for sure.
Because this is a lot of people that
want to think that,
you know,
what they do is the only way,
like people that are on like windows for
instance,
some people are just like,
I'll never use it back.
You know?
Or there's,
there's people that are,
I'm a Democrat till I die,
Bro.
Oh fuck.
A registered Democrat.
You know,
there's a lot of people that will get
real rigid with their,
I don't know what the evidence,
no matter exactly,
information comes their way,
not interested.
Yeah.
Dan to that applies because there was a
lot of blowback or a lot of push back
when I was doing taekwondo and then I
started boxing when I started really
getting involved in boxing.
Wait,
there were people that didn't want you
to do it?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
They've felt like it was an argument.
I didn't need to,
I was wasting my time.
I was taking away time from my taekwondo
training.
It was a waste.
And a,
one of the things that helped me is that
I started opening up my own school and
when I opened up my own school in
revere,
um,
I was away from my instructors.
So I got a chance to train on my own
and I'd got a chance to bring in other
people.
And that's when I really started to
expand my ideas about what I needed to
do.
What,
what was and what wasn't effective.
And I had a good buddy of mine who would
also,
my friend Mike [inaudible] who had had a
some pro boxing fights and we did some
sparring together and he beat me up too.
And so I kind of realized like,
Oh man,
I got to,
there's some stuff I need,
I need to figure out how to incorporate.
Now that's the,
well first of all brings up a million
questions.
But back to my original question about
getting beat up,
like just as someone who has the flight
reflex right when someone's coming at me
like that's my reflex as opposed to oh
brush it off,
move lane fleet and stuff like that.
I'm always does that,
did that ever appear where you're just
like fuck,
I got a,
I'm getting pummeled while I was never
getting pumped.
Like I'm to just talking them.
I like emotionally wasn't no,
cause it wasn't like I didn't have a
chance.
It was like I was just losing,
it wasn't winning.
Okay.
I know,
but I was getting shots in like there
was guys that were pro boxers that I
knocked out in the gym.
So it wasn't that I was,
I gadget 100% losing,
but I definitely wasn't winning like I
was winning and taekwondo tournament's
in taekwondo.
Was that a real national class level?
I must like I was beating.
Yeah,
but that's the problem.
When you're really good at something,
you want to stick to.
Only that.
We don't want to test the waters with
things that you're not good at.
You don't know in a weird way.
Horrible.
Can I draw a parallel to stand up?
Sure.
Cause a lot of times like you get really
good,
you develop a bit,
you want to do,
it kills you feel good.
People are flirting with you after the
show.
It's a whole Ms.
Flirt with you.
What's going on?
Chicks coming up to you.
[inaudible] a lot of action.
Fetterman.
Yeah,
that's my moves.
Nice.
So,
uh,
but then again,
hypothetical,
totally hypothetical.
Uh,
but then if you want to expand your act,
you have to try out new stuff and that
undercut this invincible standup
comedian imaged it.
It's so popular.
It was so wonderful.
Oh yeah.
So I feel like there,
do you think that's a valid parallel?
Yeah,
for sure.
Definitely.
Yeah.
Yeah,
definitely.
Well,
I think that's also other things in
life.
I love doing things that I'm not good
at.
Like one of the things I'm really into
casting.
Yeah.
Perfect example.
Thinks a mid to lately is yoga.
I'm not good at it.
I've been doing it for a year,
like really solid.
Uh,
what time do you do it in the mornings?
You just said you worked out hard in the
morning.
Yeah.
And then he goes,
I do yoga today.
I did kickboxing.
Yeah.
Tomorrow I'm going to do yoga.
I do yoga.
Different days.
Your best moves pose.
Bestfest I'm going to guess,
I'm going to guess it's,
I'm laughing what?
You're making those,
the laughing princess.
Do you do that one?
Fuck.
Is that,
that's,
that's the hardest one.
I don't even know what you're talking.
I don't want it.
He made it up.
Yeah.
You knew that since they started.
I don't know.
It might be laughing.
Prince House.
There's a lot of moves.
I don't know,
but it's difficult.
It's basically hot,
hot yoga.
I really like.
Oh,
cause it's brutal and it's also requires
and a mental toughness.
Same as big room.
Yeah.
Same thing.
Okay.
Yeah.
How hot.
That's where I didn't it 104 degrees.
Do you do it any justice in this?
If this is too personal,
just say Wayne back off.
Just say,
Wayne,
this is overlying.
Okay.
Do you do this over the line?
I know it.
No,
I'm very probing.
We'll move onto another thing.
It's part of the hot yoga to lose
weight.
No,
as well.
none of it.
No.
None of them.
It's all just for the just exercise.
All right.
Yeah.
I mean you definitely will lose weight
if you do it.
It's 90 minutes of exertion is a lot of
calories being burned for sure.
How hot is it in there?
104 degrees,
but it's also 104 degrees and then
you're exercising and there's 50 other
people in the room and they're all
sweating like pigs smell good.
It's fucking hot.
Nuts.
Smells terrible sometimes.
Is that the hardest part?
No smell?
No.
The hardest part is mental.
Well,
here's the hardest part.
You,
it never is going to be easy.
You will always put a hundred percent
effort into each and every individual
posts so it will never know less.
It will never be less than a hundred
percent effort.
So it will always be difficult.
You will get better and maintaining
those poses,
you will get better at your range of
motion.
You'll get better at your ability to
hold positions,
but it will never be easy.
It's always going to be hard.
90 minutes.
Yup.
90 minutes sweating like a fucking like
how does it end?
How does it analyze their ldl?
Is there a bell and they just go,
that's end.
They say Namaz Day.
What'd you say?
Newmont stay back non ironically.
And you're fine with that.
That's a comedian.
Yeah,
you do it.
You do that?
No you don't.
I don't do that with my hands,
but I would if I had to it.
Why not if I meant it.
Uh,
I hate yoga.
That's the president.
Yeah.
But I'm not good at it.
That's why one of the reasons why I like
it,
I like doing things that I need to get
better at and like you see your
progress.
I know I'm better at it now than it was
a year ago.
And if I continue to do it,
I'll get better at it.
It's just a challenge.
Gel.
We've known each other long time.
We're not long time.
We're not close friends.
We could be.
Thank you.
Very smart guy.
That's nice.
Uh,
yeah,
but I am also on a lifetime self
improvement program.
Yeah.
No question.
What kind of stuff are you into?
Well,
one cold yoga.
Have you tried that deep due to the
snow,
now we do it naked and ice cube.
A lot of people don't know it.
I do call it yoga.
I do,
uh,
I,
while I try to,
you know,
I'm always teaching myself,
reading a lot,
teaching myself instruments all the
time.
I like that you're really into musical
ones,
really into music.
Many different musical instruments.
You know how to do well.
Play is the word,
but it's um,
how many do you saying,
how many of those things do you sing?
Yeah,
I know it's the,
you know,
a few.
Just mainly how many gay ones if that
half,
but out piano,
Guitar,
Bass,
getting back into drums.
Are you one of the reasons why there's a
piano on stage at the Improv that I need
to take that fucking thing down?
No,
we need to do,
we needed another one dueling pianos.
Like they could have another room maybe
with a piano,
but the piano just gets in the way.
The stage,
it's not used for 9.9%
of the time.
And you and Owen,
Benjamin,
Jimmy,
it's this tradition.
It's just took the fuck that tradition.
It's in the way those people to the
right of the stage,
they get fucked.
You get sit down.
All we're going to be front is getting
good now.
Staring at the God damn piano.
It's bullshit,
right?
Isn't a bullshit.
Knew how the Improv started.
Oh,
I do.
You do.
I'm friends with Bud Freeman.
How do you like that?
Yeah.
Huh?
So how did it start?
So Nike's people made a piano and they
put it on a stage and a microphone there
and the comics were constantly annoyed
by that fucking piano.
Not True.
She started out as Broadway singers
coming in and doing show tunes after
their shows and people would hang out.
And guess what?
We'll you know how the south started
slavery.
Should we go back to that?
Jesus went quading a piano.
Yes.
Slavery.
Fucking confederate flag in a musical
instrument form.
What if it only plays Leonard scanners
on the piano?
Just free bird.
Give me three steps.
Could you do free bird and the piano?
Here's me at the Improv,
being annoyed by the piano.
It's right there.
Here's some me off.
That fucking thing is huge and it's in
the way.
It's not the best thing.
It's the best.
Little is the best thing about it.
They should chop off the side.
You've ever seen him?
Do you ever,
oh wait,
let me hear what the chop off the sides
of that stage.
Take some date.
Yeah,
you can take a few feet off of each side
and uh,
add some more seats.
Get rid of the fucking piano thing.
Stupid said.
I look fat in that picture.
Yeah.
It's not real.
If it was real,
I'd be pissed at myself.
Fuck,
I gotta do.
So how do I do I do yoga in there?
Yeah.
So lenox hill anyway,
till I teach myself musical,
I call it that.
And Youtube has been phenomenal for
that.
When you talk about standup and writing
jokes and how many special have you ever
done?
Oh,
this is weird.
I'm,
let me,
I'm going to can do this.
This is,
that came out last year.
Let's go the chronicles of Fetterman.
You can open it up if you want that on
the cover.
I'll tell you right there.
Thank you.
Now I feel like you're hitting on me.
No.
How old were you in that picture?
How long does it,
what was that picture?
That is 19.
I mean 2009 the photo.
Yeah.
So the picture is like,
so the picture was many years before the
actual albums released?
Yes.
Why is that?
Yeah.
That's picture.
And
because it was one,
I don't take good pictures.
It's like you fuck got one fucking run
with a marriage.
That one looks at it goes it this.
Why would you ask that?
I just look different in that picture.
Yeah.
It's what I'm from eight years ago or
seven years ago.
Um,
so anyway,
uh,
I have one,
I just did the comedy central spray.
I've never had a special outside of half
hour,
a half hour thing,
but,
and I've never had a comedy album in my
life until five months ago.
Hmm.
So that's what that is.
That is a triple comedy album.
Compilation of all my stand up through
the years.
First bit is from 1984.
Oh yeah.
Recording on here from [inaudible] 84.
Yeah.
Wow.
So 84 80 yard.
Those started to at the comic strip in
New York.
I said we started in New York.
Where are you from originally?
It Florida is shelley was,
I built this crazy because I took,
I don't know.
Oh,
I'm not allowed to say Canoga Park.
Well,
I don't want to say where we are.
Crazy fans.
Um,
uh,
but I was actually born in California
and then,
uh,
moved back East when my dad got sick and
then he died and then we moved to
Maryland.
My mom remarried and then we moved to
Florida and then I started my career in
New York.
Oh,
that's intense.
Yeah.
How old were you when your dad died?
Like a little over one.
I have no memory of him.
Wow.
Yeah.
So,
so,
uh,
yeah,
so,
but I started my,
as soon as I graduated high school.
And it's interesting,
we have a Florida connection.
As soon as I graduated high school,
I got the fuck out of dodge.
I can't have a good move.
Do you know,
speaking of sports,
you know where I graduated?
Where in a sports arena,
do you want to guess it's a gambling
arena.
Las Vegas?
No,
in Florida there's gambling arena and in
Florida it's called high lie.
Oh,
one of those things.
You ever heard of it?
Yeah,
I seen that shit.
Did they still have that?
I think that little tube to like when
people are walking their dogs and they
throw the ball,
that's what it looks like.
No.
Yeah,
they have like a highlight stick.
They throw the ball for dog.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
People that have bad rotator cuffs and
they can't really throw a ball.
That's sad.
Right?
I can't throw a ball.
It's looks just like that.
Yeah.
It's one of the few sports in the world
where you can't be lefthanded and play.
Really?
Yeah.
Cause there's a wall.
Good.
They throw it against the wall.
You can only be writing one of the few.
And they used to call it the fastest
sport in the world.
And then guess who made them take that
moniker away?
That was one of those.
The kid was like the fast cars,
they would,
you know who whipped that thing?
Golf.
What's the golfers say?
The ball travels faster when you hit her
off fatigue and it's true.
So they made him take you down.
He made them.
They like,
first of all on a sports course.
Of course.
I want to use weird.
So I graduated high school.
This is
an I,
I talk about this on stage south
plantation.
Hi.
Let's watch some of this or this.
Oh,
so it bounces off the wall and then they
throw it and they catch it.
Right.
So if you were left handed,
the wall would be in the way?
Yeah.
Why would the wall be in the way?
Cause you would smash her arm at Beth
can against the wall.
Um,
but they're on the right side.
It's only one wall or on the right side.
Right there is where I'm going in a way
that's dumb as fuck.
You could have a left hand in one.
Okay.
These guys are idiots.
Rogan takes down the,
I go to the left and the right.
If you can go to the left and the right,
it makes no sense.
There's a net on the right where the
audience is and then the the wall on the
left.
Right.
Okay.
It doesn't matter.
I don't want to,
but I might be wrong about this.
Again,
I've been wrong about a lot of things in
life as you know.
As you know,
I grew up hearing that that was fixed.
That highlight was fixed.
Yeah.
Wait,
wait,
wait.
You're saying like a fixed like fake,
like they cheat.
I would assume it would be the easiest
of all the sports to fix because we get
that wire left in.
It's forbidden to play.
Highlight.
Wow.
How many walls are there in highligh?
Lefthanders can play highlight as long
as are willing to use their right hand.
Your right stay correct.
I'm just reading this man.
The rules and traditions specifically
forbid playing lefthand did.
The reason for that is that the court
only has three walls and one at each
end.
One the sidewall and one the left
against which the ball can be rebounded
spectators it behind a chain link fence
and the fourth side because of the side
wall on the left.
It would be dangerous and almost
impossible for players to throw and
catch with their left hands.
Hmm.
Okay.
Makes Sense.
I love that fucking game though.
I agree.
But is it,
is it the only reason I'm bringing it?
Of course.
I'm sure.
I'm sure at least one of the eight
matches that happen or the 10 matches is
fixed,
which is why it's a gambling sport.
Like as soon as you get gambling
involved,
I would assume it would be the easiest.
Literally you look at the Guy and wink
and he drops the ball and they lose
that.
It would be the easiest as opposed to a
horse might be a little more difficult.
But the reason I bring it up,
not be telling you my knowledge of
highline.
I graduated in a highlife,
Ron Taiwan,
it's called a Fontan.
Say it again.
[inaudible] you got it right.
You're nailing it.
What was that like is saying Florida is
insane.
That's my boy.
That's why he got out of there three
days.
A audience and this day,
yeah,
the whole thing.
Parents,
families.
And then he goes down in the arena.
We're on the floor on the full on the
thing,
the three,
the three walls around you.
And literally there's like the bedding
boards are on both sides.
So it's like the Quinoa,
the tribe,
you know,
that's like the worst possible.
Classic Florida.
That was Florida and that was Florida.
So I got out of there and then went to
New York and went to Nyu drama and just
the boring kind of like normal.
Wow.
Yeah.
And then started my stand at catching
the comic strip or my two clubs.
I remember those places.
Yeah.
So I have recordings from those all the
way up to 2015 was the last one on here.
So that's bad ass dude.
So it's a whole thing.
Yeah.
And so,
yeah,
I've never had a comedy album before,
so not that I want this whole thing to
be about the comedy.
I'm,
but that's Wayne and I,
who should tell everybody we met on the
set of a pilot that never happened.
Remember that thing I have to say we met
before then.
Well,
we met before then,
but we became friends on the side of
that.
Right.
That thing that,
uh,
overseas,
do you remember they did an episode of
your television show?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
News radio.
Yeah.
One.
And I remember something he said to me,
Joe Rogan,
he said,
you said you were talking about news
radio and you go,
you know what,
we were doing the pilot and you're like,
you know there's a certain kind of like
special quality that happens amongst
people that creates a sitcom as much as
of the writing and I just hope we can
capture that.
Is that what I said?
Yeah you weren't,
you were saying,
you said that it was more than a Sitcom,
like a successful Sitcom is more than
just funny jokes.
Yeah,
it definitely is.
Do you agree with that?
Yeah,
for sure.
Do you agree with your younger self?
Yes,
I do.
Yeah.
Well I was super lucky in that I got
cast on news radio and we got along like
the cast got along on a pretty
incredible way,
like the way we jive together.
Like there was a,
yeah,
there was a,
I mean even like guys that I didn't
necessarily get along with that well
like Andy Dick,
right.
Who was just like so much work.
It was hard to get along with Andy.
But when we did get along like well
unset,
we had amazing chemistry.
Yeah.
You know,
because our,
our,
our characters,
you know,
the way we would interact with each
other like in scenes was great.
But then there was also,
you know,
everybody on it was so good.
It was just,
that was just a super fortunate place to
be.
But there's been good actors and bad,
you know,
and tickets.
It don't work.
I had writing too.
You got to have good writing.
You know?
Newsradio was like,
in a lot of ways it was a perfect storm.
It was also perfect storm in that it
wasn't successful.
How many years was zone five?
But it was never really successful.
Like at one point in time we were number
88 in the ratings.
Did you think you were going to get
canceled?
Yeah,
every year.
Every year.
The only year we didn't think we were
going to get cancer was the year we got
canceled.
Yeah.
That was after Phil died a life.
Cause we did and he came back and did a
a season with Jon Lovitz.
Right.
That's the season I did.
Yeah.
Yeah,
we did.
Um,
that last season would love it.
And that was also
same time when we were doing overseas.
It was during the same creator,
right.
Paul Simms.
Yeah.
And uh,
it just,
it just wasn't the same without Phil for
sure.
But the,
the,
the show wasn't owned by the right
people,
so it never got that juicy after friends
time slot that there was so many shows
that were horrible,
that went on for a long time and did
really well in the ratings.
It's like,
do you remember sex in the city or like
we used to call sex in the shitty.
Did you ever see that it's not on NBC,
not sex and the city,
Carolina in the shitty caroline in the
city,
that's the one.
They're the same thing to me.
It's a fucking chick show.
I have them in like a box in my brain,
a category.
And then there was another one that was
way worse.
The single guy.
Do you remember the single guy?
Actually I don't.
Oh,
Jonathan Silverman.
It was like someone had,
they got prime spots that you guys,
amazing spots.
There was like number two,
number three in the ratings,
there were the post friends,
there was friends Seinfeld,
there was that,
that sort of a Thursday night right
group.
And uh,
that used to be what you needed to get
on.
You need to get on that Thursday night
lineup in order to have a successful
must see tv.
Yeah.
But there was a different time then
because when they moved you,
no one knew where the fuck you where we
got moved nine,
eight or nine times over the past five
years.
Oh,
that's horrible.
So we were on like Monday night and
Sunday night and Tuesday night and we
were all over the fucking place and one
time we were on Thursday and we were
like,
number two.
Do you have a favorite episode that you
did?
Yeah,
the one we did in space,
we just space episode.
It was ridiculous.
We did,
uh,
the fucking,
the writers were so goddamn good.
It really spoiled me.
Like,
that's probably one of the reasons why I
never did a sitcom after that because
they were so good.
Did you ever guest on a sec?
Yeah,
I guested on um,
you did something right?
Yeah,
I did a what was the David spade one
where they,
oh,
the music,
shoot me.
Just shoot me.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I did an episode of that.
I did an episode,
a couple of ones.
What was the difference between being on
the show cast regular and guest starring
cause you're liking?
Ah,
well,
you know,
obviously the comfort level,
and you're on a set and you're there all
the time and you know,
a little makeup lady and the sound guys
and the bill,
the camera man are all the same folks
and you become friends with them.
You know,
there's a comfort comfort level there.
But uh,
just shoot me with all due respect
wasn't as good.
It wasn't as funny,
you know,
for you.
For me.
Yeah.
But there was something about news radio
that was just really special.
It was all a lot of it.
It was day fold.
He was a big part of it too,
because Dave fold,
that's the space episode.
We did a whole episode,
Steven,
we were in space.
It was amazing.
Dave Foley was like a,
almost like the secret producer of that
show because he,
they gave him,
the writers were so smart that they gave
him a pretty much
everybody artistic license to try out
new ideas.
And because of the fact that Dave was
one of the guys from kids in the hall
was such a,
a brilliant writer.
Just a brilliant guy.
Very fucking smart guy.
Um,
he always,
has he been on your illusion?
Yeah.
He's been on.
He told some of the most depressing I
know about his doors in life about
divorce.
Good Lord.
To talk about a man who's been fucking
need Paula over and over again through
divorce.
It is horrible,
man.
Horrible what they did to him.
I know.
It's really sad,
but he sees finally I think coming
through it.
Well,
he's,
he's on a sex successful,
successful show now that with doctor
Ken.
Yeah.
What does that show called?
Doc.
Doctor Ken.
Doctor.
Yeah.
But it's uh,
it's doing well,
right?
Isn't that [inaudible] doing well?
I think it's,
I think,
I think it's holding on totally on their
own ticket cancelled and no renewed
renewed.
Yeah.
Well good cause he owes about a half
million bucks or it can't get to Canada
if Dave doesn't go to Canada.
I mean if Dave doesn't pay up,
he,
his um,
his alimony and child support are off
the charts because it was based on the
money that he was making during news
radio.
Right.
And then that was the most money I'd
ever made in his life and never came
close to it ever since.
And it didn't matter.
The doctor said to him is one of the
most depressing things about the
podcast.
Your ability to pay has no relation to
your obligation to pay.
So the doctor was like,
look,
you,
you establish a lifestyle.
Your same doctor.
The doctor said,
doc,
did he say doctor?
I did the judge just having that.
It's a judge.
Some,
some soup character,
some official,
no,
I mean,
did you just have a brain aneurism?
No,
just forgot what I was talking about.
You already and we need to take a break.
He trying to just sit down.
I'm trying to say for no reason
whatsoever other than to get your own
rocks off the,
the judge told him that and he was just
devastated.
And in a lot of ways,
I don't think he ever recovered from
that.
You know,
like when you find out that a doctor,
I mean a judge is doing and the system
is so bad and so poorly constructed got
lives.
I mean,
we're already laughing.
Have you been married now?
Would you be willing to doing yeah,
he would definitely not signal out there
to the ladies.
Let them know who we are.
Ready?
Yeah.
Lead time.
It's time passed.
I feel like I'm a,
you know that shit.
Yeah.
I'm having a family.
I don't know.
Yeah,
hold on,
hold on.
It we don't cramp in my leg.
Yeah,
it's over.
Don't marriage gives you a cramp.
Just talking about it.
Talking about making a commitment with a
woman.
And I was like,
well,
it's also the Canadian system is pretty
brutal.
Can Canada's very different than the
United States.
And,
uh,
they just,
Oh,
I'll keep talking.
I'll ask you about something.
Okay.
Just hit me.
Do you want to keep talking about Foley
weekend?
No.
Okay.
There's this girl I was trying to date
or should nine interest in May but,
but has gone to the Amazon and done
Iowasca.
And who she said that you,
I don't know if she learned about it
from you or you were advocating for it,
but uh,
she,
yeah,
she went down there a couple times and
then did it not in the Amazon.
How many times have you done it?
I haven't done Iowasca.
What I've done is Dmt,
which is the active compound in Iowa
still.
Okay.
What I ask it is,
here's,
here's what I want us to is the Amazon
indigenous people figured out a way to
make dmt orally active DMT is broken
down in your gut by something called
monoamine oxidase and all of this makes
sense.
So when you eat it,
that's why when you eat a lot of grasses
and different plants,
you don't get high off the DMT in it
because it gets broken down in your gut.
Well,
so what they figured out as a way to
combine the leaves of one plant,
which contained the DMT and the source
of the leaves,
email and Hibbert.
No,
it's an Mao inhibitor.
And so this combination of the two
plants,
one that contains DMT and one that
suppresses model aiming oxidase and your
gut allows you to experience dimethyl
trip to me orally.
So it's a long dmt trip.
What I've done is smoke it,
which is way more intense,
but way shorter.
Last,
have you?
When was the last time he did something?
Cause I think a year ago.
A year ago?
Yeah.
What?
All right.
Because I,
you know me,
we've known each other 20 some years.
I'm not like a pot smoker.
Don't really drink at all.
Uh,
but I'm a drug experimenter.
Like I've done mushrooms,
gas,
that's my favorite truck.
It's a great drug.
It's very similar.
They are in,
in their reaction,
especially at high doses to dmt.
And in fact they're there.
They're very similar.
Um,
as far as the compound themselves,
I think there's,
where the way it's expressed in the
body.
A DMT is n n dimethyltryptamine and when
Psilocybin is broken down in the body,
it produces something called for Fox
four.
See and Hen Diane [inaudible],
I'm kind of like glazing manner,
which is,
I'm just saying they're really closely
related with the most potent psychedelic
drugs are very closely related to basic
human neurochemistry.
And DMT is human neurochemistry is,
is actually the most potent psychedelic
drug known to man.
And it's actually produced by your body.
It's produced in your liver,
it's produced in your lungs and it's
produced pineal gland.
Okay.
Let me ask you a question.
When you smoke the DMT,
how many times have you done it?
Nine Times.
Nine?
Yeah.
Will there be a 10?
Yes.
Today with Wayne,
uh,
well I don't have it here,
but if I did,
if really wanted to go,
we could do it.
What would live with them?
Ready to do it again.
I need,
I think I usually need some time after I
do it to sit back and think about it and
absorb it and taken in.
But do you feel like it helped your
standup at all?
100%.
It helps everything in my life.
It helps me or any downside.
Yeah.
You get the,
there's a real anxiety that happened to
me once after it was over.
I did one,
one trip where it was incredibly intense
and um,
wouldn't say overdose.
You don't overdose because it's a
natural part of your brain.
Your brain knows how to bring it back to
baseline very quickly.
It's like one of the most transient
drugs ever observed in the body.
You go from being blasted out of your
fucking mind to completely sober in 20
minutes.
All right.
Yeah.
How would you then you just dive back
in.
The last time I did it,
we did it like four or five times,
so it was,
I was pretty Gonzo for about an hour and
a half or so.
Somewhere around there just go.
We would go in,
come out,
go back in again.
Meantime,
the whole time this is going on,
we're playing this a South American
music,
these ICAROS,
which these shamans have created to sort
of coax the experience.
I need a showman.
No,
you don't need a showman.
If you're going to do DMT,
there's,
there's Wayne Fetterman.
Just wait again.
You know me,
I'm kind of a straight,
you know,
I'm not,
I'm not an edgy guy.
Really?
Okay.
Um,
what would you recommend?
How would you recommend they do?
Have you ever smoked crack?
No.
Would you know with Wayne?
But if I did this face,
no,
I didn't know.
I'm no interested in,
in crack.
I don't have any interest in even
cocaine.
I've never done cocaine.
No.
Oh No,
I don't.
I don't have any interest in stimulants.
I'm not interested in anything that
gives me confidence.
I'm not interested in any false sense of
bravado and getting boosted up.
I'm not interested in that.
Okay.
If it feels like amphetamines and speed,
what they do is they,
they remove inhibitions in a way that
gets you in a lot of trouble.
What about,
you know,
drinking?
I like drinking,
even though that's a barbiturate right.
Bar barbiturate it drinking is a downer,
right?
That's not a barbiturate though.
Like isn't a barbiturate a specific
class of drugs is alcohol.
Barbiturates.
And I think Erbitux,
it is a very specific class of Downer
isn't it?
We're gonna find out that was when I
was,
I not asked.
I don't drink really.
But as there's a rule,
say barbiturates overdose,
Bababababa central nervous system,
depressants,
alcohol,
opiates.
Okay.
So that's what they're saying is an
overdose.
No,
I'm not talking about,
so I'm just saying that Picchu,
it's in overdose with other central
nervous system depression.
It's,
no,
that's not what it's saying.
So it's not saying,
so it's different.
They're saying something different.
You're saying,
I'm just saying is alcohol or
barbiturates?
That's no,
no.
It said you shouldn't be mixed with
alcohol.
Barbiturates should not be mixed with
So edition is alcohol a drug or
antidepressant or barbiturate or all the
above?
What the fuck kind of question is that?
Um,
yeah.
It's not the same thing.
It's a depressant.
It's a depressed,
it's not a stimulant.
No,
But it does loosen inhibitions.
Yeah.
For me,
social lubricant.
Me With the layman when I'm drinking.
Oh yeah.
What happens?
Um,
but way more,
um,
better.
Better is fun.
I would,
I hopefully I'm fun no matter what,
no matter what the scenario,
but I will fail.
I feel like I'm a little more sexually
aggressive when I'm on a whoa.
Jesus settled down.
I know you a little random men to get a
little rapey wouldn't use the word.
We can use that descriptor,
but um,
yeah,
I feel you.
What do you drink?
Beer,
right?
I drink.
Yeah.
I like,
I like to drink.
I only drink to get drunk.
Really?
That's my style.
Yeah.
So I don't ever casual,
you never see me.
You don't drink a glass of wine with
dinner?
No.
Never.
Oh really?
That's what I enjoy the most.
Never meet.
I'm going to have the red.
What is this a piece of fish?
The white of,
that's the way the other one.
Yeah.
No,
I um,
drink way more.
One drink with dinner than anything
else.
What do you get from it?
I like glass of wine.
I enjoy the taste dictate.
If there was no alcohol in it.
You think you enjoyed the taste?
I have.
I have like really low alcohol wine.
That doesn't do anything for me.
Well,
okay,
so you like,
do you like doing this Paleo wine?
No,
no,
not a freak about it.
I don't know enough.
I liked the way it smells though.
I liked the way it tastes.
I like to sip it with dinner.
I like a nice wine with dinner,
but I like a little buzz too.
I'll go like a couple of glasses of nice
and I don't,
yeah,
I again,
it's far from judging as possible.
Just curious.
No,
not,
not defensive.
Yeah.
Um,
but uh,
so alcohol is a depressant.
That's what I just meant.
It's like a barbiturate it said,
not a steaming up,
but it does allow me to get what your
word confident race,
say.
Well,
you might meet,
might have confidence issues a little
bit and I'm chillers really comedian,
comedian asking for approval from
strangers might have competence.
What I'm saying,
that's an interesting insight.
Let me think about that.
I go on deepen.
I take one chances go on a whim.
Um,
so that's probably why you like it,
because it alleviates some of that
anxiety.
Well,
there's things that happen in
psychedelic drugs that make you more
vulnerable.
Oh.
You know,
they make you aware.
Have you done molly?
Yes.
What do you think of that thing?
Um,
well Mtma which is molly,
you know,
same thing.
Uh,
the,
the after effects were way too brutal
for me.
The Post Post trip,
the trip was wonderful.
Trip was amazing and I got some pretty
deep insight about the nature of
insecurities and how they manifest
itself in social security.
May need the conversations.
Yeah.
But the next day,
um,
I couldn't read.
I remember I was at a coffee shop and I
was trying to read a magazine and I was
like,
I can't even fucking read.
Couldn't kind of constant trail.
Yeah.
And then I found out about,
that's before I had found out about htp,
five htp,
which converts to Serotonin.
One of the things that serotonin
depletion because of,
uh,
when you do,
Mtma,
what's happening is you get this massive
blast of Serotonin and you feel amazing.
Right.
Well,
after it's over,
that shit crashes and your,
your body body's depleted.
You feel like a dry sponge.
Like you don't feel good.
To me,
at least I,
I dry sponge that can't read.
Yeah.
I just,
my brain wasn't firing.
It just wasn't working well and I didn't
like,
it didn't like the feeling and it took
at least a day or so from fruit to
rebound and I was like,
not,
you're probably not going to do that
again.
No,
no,
I don't think so.
Not Worth it.
The next day is just not worth it to me.
Okay.
Now,
and I've heard from some people that,
oh,
I have to get the pure stuff that it
doesn't do it,
but the people that have heard that from
her all in poor health,
there's not,
yeah.
They don't,
the people that have talked to their
healthy saying there's always a price
you pay from the modeling.
Yeah.
There's not a price you pay for
mushrooms.
I don't,
I've never felt a physical price for
mushrooms.
There's zero physical price you pay from
dmt.
None.
Zero.
Some people have an issue with Iowasca
because you purge and you'll do a lot of
throwing up and a lot of diarrhea.
That's why I'm not doing it.
That's it.
Well that's one of the reason I will,
I mean again,
I'm a drug experimenter.
I know everyone says that it's like a
euphemism for,
I'm a drug user,
but I'm actually just like on the right
circumstances.
I deal with drug even though it's not
part of my life in any way.
So I don't like throwing up.
Yeah,
no.
What do you think?
He understands psychological now the
stuff is disgusting.
Everybody that tells me they've tried
Iowasca says it's fucking disgusting.
I don't want to go to the jungle.
And I mean I'm sure I could do it around
here,
but not in the bugs and snakes and
Jaguars and all that shit.
You can go fuck yourself.
I'm not going to fucking rain forest.
No.
But people have had these amazing
experiences cause they do it in the rain
forest and that's where it's from.
And See,
I'm also,
I hate to say this and this is going to
sound prejudiced,
but I'm kind of an on people that what's
down that good Sam prejudice.
I'm sort of Anti Sharman.
Well,
there's a good reason to be because
schamens are a lot like Yogis,
like a,
there's a lot of yogis that are really
just douche bags that are trying to fuck
women that are in their classes.
Right.
And there's a lot of sham and that are
like that.
And I feel like I have a pretty good
radar about people.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
Thank type of people that want to be a
showman boy who knows,
who knows what you're going to get
there.
And Jen,
he was a friend of mine that was a sham
and they used to do these rituals on his
resume.
Writers on his resume.
No,
but he was a,
he would guide them and these people
through,
uh,
these I wasco rituals and he wanted to
do it with me.
He died.
I would,
I would definitely do IOWASCA.
And what Iowasca is,
is just a less intense,
longer lasting version of a DMT trip.
But the DM tree trip,
the Dow,
I'm more interested in DMT.
DMT is Iowasca Iowasca so you don't
throw up the act.
No,
you don't throw up.
Yes,
you're smoking it and it goes directly
to your bloodstream because what happens
instantaneously?
How many does he take?
Omni pump?
Three big hits,
a hit,
not even a puff.
Three is like number,
you'll hold it in now you take big hits.
Okay,
hit it again.
And then at the second one,
reality starts getting real fragile.
You start seeing things pixelate around
you and,
but you gotta go one more time.
One more time,
one more time.
You put the pipe down,
lay down.
Oh,
okay.
And then it just overcomes you.
You go through the flower of life and
enter into this massive,
infinite geometric pattern that's made
out of love and understanding and you
communicate with God.
And that's your definition of a good
trip.
It's pretty intense.
It can be terrifying to some people.
It definitely is terrifying if you try
to control it and manipulate it because
then you're going to be in a wrestling
match with your emotions and your mind.
You have to be able to let go.
It's one of the most difficult things
with any really intense at breaks.
And you're saying psychedelic
experience,
you gotta be willing to let go.
How would you compare it to,
because I've only done mushrooms.
How many?
Well,
you say you've done mushrooms when you
saved,
done mushrooms.
Well,
what kind of dose are you talking about?
aid.
I hate the taste of it,
so I put it in a big Mac and I get him.
Oh God.
That might be the worst way to take
mushrooms I've ever heard.
No.
I kind of big Mac,
kind of like fucking big Mac.
Yeah.
Have you ever had one of those?
No.
Mcdonald's?
Yeah,
but why would you do that?
Why would you delete mushrooms in a big
Mac?
Because I love big MACs.
What are you judging?
Big macs now.
It's so bad for you.
It's factory farmed.
This bucket.
Tortured cow.
Taking them in with the mother Gaia.
Wow.
Maybe it was just that was my
experience.
What if I said times I said dug in and
out Burger,
we'd deputy better.
Not really.
We still,
they're much more delicious.
What about from the counter?
What if I got our cheeseburger from the
counter,
the bride at home?
Because what I did,
I kind of spinning.
Even supposed to eat meat for days
before you do mushrooms.
That's not true.
It is.
Yeah.
The rule is that people that get the
most out of the experience recommend
that you,
you have a vegetable only diet for at
least 24 hours before you do any
question.
Let's say meeting just salads
and my lead up thousand island dressing.
Cause that's a question.
That's my favorite dressing sugar in
that I avoid sugar.
I would say avoid sugar.
So just like a vinegarette,
avoid toxins.
Avoid Nasty Shit.
Oil and vinegar.
You know what I'm drinking.
You see what I'm drink coca cola.
It's not good for the greatest thing
ever,
man.
Ever meant to mix it with Jack Daniels.
Some ice,
I'll suddenly nuts,
but I want to know what kind of dose
you're you're taking.
I don't know that you kind of mushrooms
like put it,
open your hand up and show me how many
mushrooms you're talking about.
I would say fit like in here.
Oh,
you're not doing anything.
You,
you,
you have a baby doses so you're not even
experiencing the dissolving of reality.
No,
I was just trying to have a good time.
Yeah,
the real that was my goal is they have
mushroom chips.
The real mushroom trips only get a few
drinks.
They get again,
what do you mean dissolve the solving of
reality?
That's the goal of being on mushrooms.
Not like,
oh,
I'm going to see aerosmith at the
Hollywood bowl and you could do that.
That's the way I do that.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Okay,
so tell what I'm saying.
If you want something that's
commensurate with a dmt experience,
you're going to have to take five grams.
You're going to have to take a large
dose,
but it seemed like it was part of the
mushroom that was like potent and other
was just like little short,
five grams of the potent stuff you need.
You need the real deal.
Okay.
I didn't wait it out.
I mean,
you look,
you could,
depending upon the,
can you see?
How do you eat the mushrooms?
Just fucking eat a man like chill.
Yeah,
you eat them.
You're saying this like this is so
alien.
Well,
I just found the taste so horrific.
That's why I hit it into a delicious big
Mac and the other next time I did it I,
this is what I did.
Tasteless.
They don't taste horrible at all.
You got to be kidding me.
No,
like literally.
If we go on the Internet right now and
put up the taste of mushrooms,
everyone was going to say it's
tasteless.
Go to [inaudible] dot com that's my
website.
Driving traffic to my website.
[inaudible] had a problem with the tape.
No one's ever,
wait a minute.
I'm sure some people don't like the
taste.
I've never heard you say about me
earlier today.
I'm sensitive.
You're a little bit sensitive.
I'm a little bit sensitive,
so maybe she's our us.
Does that hurt?
Does that hurt you?
No,
not at all.
Great.
I it's,
it's,
it's branded.
I branded well,
what has happened if you go to pussies?
RFCS got to be a porn site.
Right?
It's probably just like gaping fucking
people throwing quarters down their
whole,
so,
all right.
All right.
Um,
okay.
So,
um,
hand believe because everyone I've ever
spoken to,
with the exception of a guy named Joe
Rogan as talked about how horrible
mushrooms days,
they don't care.
Well,
I understand that.
I believe you,
but uh,
I've never found them to taste bad.
They just taste,
they kind tastes like cardboard or
something or plasticky they don't taste
like much.
I mean,
they
got,
I hadn't mushrooms three or four months
ago.
They didn't taste that bad.
Okay.
We're gonna lose to me too.
It's okay.
I mean,
it's not something I would look forward
to.
Like,
it's not like pistachios.
I go,
Ooh,
let me take some of these,
but not that bad.
Okay.
All right.
Let me pick a deal.
We'll let that,
we'll let that lie below.
Kind of like,
I do think you're wrong about that.
I just want to get this word wrong
thing.
There's probably some things that you
enjoy that I don't like obviously.
Right.
How you feel about gefilte fish.
Okay.
Of all the things that we're going to
come out of your mouth.
That was when the last things I can eat
it.
It's not great.
Okay.
I can agree with that.
I can eat it,
but there's a fermented,
the least favorite part is the jelly
part.
I get rid of that.
But the actual fish I can deal with,
there's a fermented shark that people
eat in Iceland that is supposed to be
fucking horrific for anyone else other
than the people that live in Iceland.
It was one of the few things that,
uh,
Anthony Bordain told me that like was
like truly disgusting that uh,
he eight on his show,
you know,
when he used to travel and go to these
different places and try their local
cuisine,
um,
fermented shark supposed to be fucking
awful.
But uh,
they,
they enjoy it.
You know,
so it regional,
you're saying there's regionalisms when
it comes to taste?
Yeah,
for sure.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now I'm not going to talk about my diet
cause you're going to hate it.
You're going to die.
What do you do?
What do you,
what do you think?
Big macs.
It's all big MACs.
It's not all big macs,
but I think a lot of shit you would
consider shitty food.
Right?
Think you're overreacting to it.
You think I'm overreacting?
Well what is shitty food then?
If that's not shitty food.
I feel like,
I feel like if people during the
depression could get a 99 cent
cheeseburger when people were so poor
that they couldn't even afford meat,
like big it maybe meet once a month.
Right.
And that was the worst of it.
Some risks get thing that people would
be like,
they would have thought it was the
greatest thing on earth.
And I think they,
these cheeseburgers that we get be at
the quarter pounder with cheese,
be it the double,
double it in and out,
be at the uh,
like a pretty good,
I think they're pretty good food.
I know the factory farmed,
I get it.
I get it there that it seems horrible.
I'll re,
I'll re ask the question,
what is bad then if that's what is bad
food?
What is bad food?
Yeah.
What's bad food for you?
I would say food that is uh,
has gone rotten just has to be boiled
milk.
It has to be like literally poisonous
and rotting.
Yeah.
For you to think it's bad for the yes.
Yes.
That's a good question.
No one's asked me that necessarily.
What I would consider a health
conscious.
I am super health conscious.
I just believe the negative,
uh,
what's the word for it?
The negativity actions that are
overblown known
by people that by people,
the negative repercussions of eating
cheeseburgers,
eating cheeseburgers or pizza or
something like that.
Having a pizza or going to,
and I getting a,
okay,
forget about the rotten stuff.
That is what you're talking about is
literally the worst aspects of the
American diet other than sugar.
I know I've read that you're drinking
sugar.
I don't know what book you're talking
about,
but you're drinking a can of sugar that
has,
I want to say let's 40 grams of sugar
per can.
How many grams?
Not even close.
39 again,
exaggerating.
This is the point I'm trying to make joe
not even close.
That's a lot of fucking sugar,
man.
Yeah.
You're only supposed to eat 25 a day.
A day.
Yeah.
25 gram.
Who?
Who says that?
Yeah.
That's on there.
The lambs a protein though.
That's how much fat in here.
How much fan in here isn't have Tony's
back towards to fat zero.
It doesn't matter.
Protean it's going to go right to your
gut.
I'll let sugar.
Well,
insulin spike from what you understand
is that we,
you're going to want to understand that
when you gain weight,
it doesn't go to one place.
It goes all over that way.
That way you can't spot reduce.
I think I'm correct on that.
Uh,
yeah,
but some people have an inclination to
gain more gut fat where some will gain
it and unfortunate areas,
I do like their ass.
Right.
Some people go to the girls worth their
ass.
Yeah.
I mean this is no a consensus,
right?
Yeah.
No,
no.
I believe me.
You're not the only one that is not
happy with my diet.
Who else isn't happy with you.
Dot.
You know,
people who are well read,
people understand diet people are
Dietitians.
So back to her solid,
the you.
So all this stuff when you're talking
about like pizza and cheeseburgers and
sugar,
that's,
that's the kind of things that people
had ever had.
Chinese food,
I like that.
It's delicious.
There's the reason why it's popular.
Right?
Right.
I like delicious things.
Just basic tick.
Yeah,
me too.
I just don't allow myself to have them
very often as it's not more disciplined
than I am.
Maybe.
Yeah,
probably.
I think that's been sort of the theme,
the theme of my life as far as like
getting things done has always been
about forcing myself to work.
You know,
that's uh,
I,
I think especially Comedians,
one of the things about what we do is
that it's so open ended.
Like no one can tell us what to do.
Like,
I don't know how your schedule works,
but me,
I call into the comedy store on Monday
and I can decide how many days I want to
put in for,
I can say,
oh,
I'll do Tuesday and Friday,
Saturday.
So I'll take Wednesday and Thursday off.
It's,
it's totally up to me.
Right.
And I think that's how we all are.
We can decide like when to work and when
not to work.
But there's a big,
there's a direct connection between
forcing yourself to write more and
perform more and your act getting better
and you're getting more work and your,
your,
your comedy career progressing.
And so for me,
the discipline that I applied to s two
fighting and martial arts and other
things and to continue to stay fit and
work out,
I applied to comedy too.
I just make yourself go do the thing.
But the,
the natural inclination of really funny
people is often to fuck off is often to
be lazy.
But I don't think that they're mutually
exclusive.
I think you can be disciplined but still
have the same sort of comedic instincts.
You just have to know when to turn it
out and when to turn it off and when it
benefits you.
I think you'd done,
yeah.
Like then you go off on this things.
Uh,
I agree with the,
I agree with you 100%.
I admire your discipline.
I feel like I'm not as disciplined to do
you want a little more discipline.
Although people who look at me are
always like,
you accomplish more because of the Dayak
they did things that go on the road.
I just stand up.
I write books,
I write articles.
Um,
but I,
I know I'm not disciplined,
but you're more disciplined than a lot
of other comics.
I know,
I just know me,
but we all know comics like especially
are just getting high all day.
I know that's not only that we all know
the tragic stories of the guys who wrote
an hour in like 1996 or,
and never fucking adjusted it.
And they had real promise.
There's guys that are doing the same
fucking jokes that you and I both know,
they've been doing the same jokes for 20
years and they still are.
And you can go and catch them at the
fucking laugh factory tomorrow night and
they'll tell a joke from the late
nineties.
Right?
I mean,
there's those guys,
they exist and a lot of those guys had
massive potential.
Like they were really good.
But I think,
I know you're blaming,
some of it is obviously discipline and
the,
but I think it goes back to what we said
earlier about the risk of doing new
material for sure.
But he's just part of disciplines when
you understand.
But there's a pain involved with it.
And maybe with your,
just,
I'm just hypothesizing here that if
you're a comedian and you love the
attention and the approval,
that that overwhelms your desire to
write new material and go through that
pain process.
Yeah,
that's right.
There's definitely some excuses that you
can make for why people don't.
Right.
I think that's why Eddie Murphy doesn't
do stand up by the way.
Well I think he's the,
the thing where he got caught with those
transvestite prostitutes.
That's not wet.
I think it is at all.
I think that's 100% where it is.
Cause that's when he stopped.
No,
we get stopped before then.
It's stopped doing standup before then,
honey.
Yeah.
You know,
he's had been caught a few times.
Okay.
This idol,
this is not a mat out he,
Nettie Murphy and doubting anything.
This is all,
this is all news.
It happened.
I thought that happened just once.
I have a friend who's a cop and I know
some things.
Yeah,
that you know what they call them?
Dragons.
Your police officer friends,
they'd call it the drag queens to call
them dragons.
That you see them picking up dragons.
See that movie tangerine by any chance?
No.
What's that?
It's about dragons.
Really?
Yeah.
No.
Did
she does it good?
[inaudible] Dragon Hyphen Shat on an
iphone.
What's that?
Edwards is in her best friend,
Ian Edwards,
who you go see soccer matches.
The width is in that movie and is
excellent in it.
He did you see and is excellent and
everything.
Yeah.
He's a townsie comic.
Funny too talented comics.
Oh Sweetie.
He's eats really healthy.
He does sort of more than you is Vegan,
but he's really,
no,
but he's very disciplined with it,
but he doesn't supplement.
Like if you are going to go Vegan,
you really have to take be 12 and d
three is,
it's very hard to get m and D for ever.
[inaudible] no.
Yeah,
that's the good one.
No,
I don't even know if that's it that I
don't think it's,
I don't take stuff.
Mine might be a thing.
I take d three d three.
Yeah.
But uh,
he doesn't,
uh,
doesn't supplement and I just really
tried to get them to do that cause he's
always tired.
So he's napping,
warn the cars on the way to gigs is
fucking falling asleep and shit cause
that him in the movie.
Hmm.
Anyway.
Shot on an iphone.
Those are,
yeah.
That's a couple of dragons as you'd like
to call.
I've never heard that expression before.
And it's interesting little low budget
movie.
Well at least fucking phones are way
better than the film cameras that they
use 20 years ago.
I mean we,
you can get off of a phone now.
The images and the crystal clear images
off of just a regular iphone six,
they're fucking phenomenal.
I mean,
no question.
No,
but I don't know if they're better than
a good camera with the,
it's the lenses that were amazing on
those cameras.
But I guarantee you you could get a
video camera from a video camera.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Oh,
you mean like a film camera?
Like the camera?
Yeah,
no,
I meant like something nice video.
Well,
it's interesting because when nobody was
one of the whole thing on this.
Yeah.
But you could do that pretty well.
But I actually think the five,
what's interesting about,
um,
like phones and digital is that it shows
you the entire image as opposed to
focusing on the center or the for the
front.
And then everything in the background is
blurry,
which is what a lot of people like about
film,
about doing movies with film is that you
would have the shallow focus field
yelling.
Yeah.
And it's kind of,
it really keeps your,
it's almost like the way you think.
You see things in real life.
Like if I'm looking at you in real life,
I,
I note that there's background behind
you,
but I'm not really seeing it very
clearly.
I see you.
And then I see Elvis Presley,
right.
Visiting President Nixon.
Right.
Did you ever see Presley perform?
No.
Not Live.
But I was just,
do you know,
they just released that movie.
They digitally rerelease the film,
a concert film of his comeback and a in
Vegas.
Wait there,
I'm gonna be talking about the film from
1970 yeah,
digitally remastered it and that was at
the movies recently and they had a
trail.
A view.
But yeah,
look fucking crazy.
They did.
They want you to do one of those nights
in the theater with yeah,
and he was dancing.
What was really crazy.
It's watching women react to him to
still just scream.
No,
no,
not to women today.
The women back then screaming and
falling down.
They didn't even,
they didn't even like you think about
like how much bigger a star he was then
anybody could ever be a star.
Today is cause like people are used to
social media and video and snapchat and
this and that and there's a million
different stars and there's a million
different movies and there's a fucking
hundred thousand television shows and
you have 290 channels.
They're constantly running and this all,
all this information data,
it's not special anymore.
Back then there was two fucking
television channels.
There was these movies that he would
come on and you know,
he would sing through the fucking movie.
There was only one elvis.
He was arguably one of the first ever
singing movie stars.
Right?
Singing slash.
Superstars.
No,
he's still one of the first ones.
I mean,
how many of them there were,
what are you shaking your head because
you're wrong.
I mean,
just a great Kelly.
There's a few guys who around saying
being crazy.
Right,
but how many of them were talking about
Al Jolson?
Okay.
Al Jolson.
The first,
the first movie,
the first talkie talk.
He was in the first talkie.
I mean,
it's not,
it's officially known as the first
target.
There was some sense it's called the
jazz playing being point being,
there's not that many back then.
I mean,
it's a very small pool beings.
Yeah,
but Frank Sinatra didn't sing in movies.
Okay,
okay.
Joe Did he chai.
This is getting sad now.
Why Sang?
Did he say it was like that?
A part of the movies like Elvis would
go,
we gotta go down to the beach.
We own it all down to the beach.
She on the town or any of the beach?
Kate's I like,
yes.
I mean he would sing,
but my point is,
even at oakey include Sinatra,
we're still only talking about like 20
people.
Okay.
There's so few hundreds now.
I agree with you cause huge star.
My point is,
yeah,
it was a new thing.
It wasn't,
it wasn't,
it wasn't that it was,
it was not much history to it.
I mean,
television had only been around for a
few decades when in the 1950s I mean
it's super new.
And then movies before that,
you know,
we,
before you know,
the silent movies and then you're only
talking about like a hundred years
maximum,
right?
So this is all a completely new
experience that these girls are seeing
this superstar,
this guy,
this Elvis Presley was perfect hair and
his singing and his fucking jumpsuit and
the whole deal.
And the reaction to them,
it's almost like their brains can't
process it and they're screaming and
they're fainting and is one of the most
bizarre things about watching elvis is
watching the reaction to Elvis that
these people have the audience.
Yeah,
no question.
Yeah.
Like that,
that power.
Can I talk about Elvis for another
second?
You don't have to ask me if you can talk
about,
Oh,
I'm not allowed to just talk.
Just talk.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You know the book,
I'm silly.
I'm sorry.
She knows the book.
What is it?
It's,
it's written by the guy about 10,000
hours.
You need to do 10,000
hours to be good at something.
It was that Malcolm Gladwell.
Malcolm Gladwell.
Yeah.
And it's the one after blank.
Know that.
Right.
So Elvis is the opposite of the 10,000
hours.
The opposite.
Because if you go back and like,
it was like,
what was,
how did Elvis like,
whoa.
Was He sang in high school?
A little bit,
but not in a band.
Not in a band around Memphis,
Tennessee gigging or anything.
Recorded it thing for his mom.
A song for his mom at Sun Records said,
oh,
I want to sing here.
The girl,
the girl liked it,
you know,
the secretary,
she gave it to the boss.
He was like,
Oh,
I think you to getting the police.
Let me bring in some local guys and they
cut these unbelievable rockabilly
albums.
He had never sung with the band.
Wow.
This thing around his home or anything,
who knows?
But even it wasn't 10,000
hours,
like the Beatles in Hamburg or something
like that where you're like,
oh,
I'm going to learn how to sing and get
around it.
Or do you know billy Joel playing around
for a long time and then finally
breaking through.
You know,
he was in a rock band of and became
billy Joel and it's the craziest,
yeah,
I just feel like his story is like the,
he's the opposite of that 10,000
hour.
We should also at the gate.
Great.
And he was the biggest superstar ever.
Like there was no roadmap for him to
follow.
There had never been anybody before him.
Plus he was also the first guy to
experience pills.
Oh,
you know,
I mean the Fars like superstars,
like that's when the whole pill craze
was coming on.
It was like during the 50s in the 60s
you know,
there was that,
I mean,
how many fucking pills were there?
there were opiates,
they could give you opium and you know,
milk of the poppy.
There was a bunch of different things
that they would give people dilauded
member that they used to give those a
women dilauded and those old wild west
movies,
that was it.
Basically,
uh,
an opiod.
They would give them certain drugs,
but
he was one of the first guys that really
got into like pills.
Yeah.
He had some,
he was kind of an addict,
right?
Oh fuck.
Yeah.
It was,
yeah.
Yeah.
I mean,
that's one of the reasons why he died so
young.
I mean,
for sure.
Yeah.
I never saw,
I never saw him perform,
but I did see,
I know you were talking about,
uh,
Freddie Mercury.
I saw those guys,
Huh?
Yeah.
And you'd liked him,
right?
Oh fuck.
Yeah.
Huge Freddie Mercury fan do.
Right.
I went to,
I've only saw him in concert once and
I'm still laughing at it.
Really?
Oh,
they do the most ridiculous thing in
concert.
First of all,
he started getting,
oh,
he's in a white suit and then by the end
he just didn't like white underwear.
You know,
he's just great.
He was like a slowly shoes are off the
shirts off.
It's great.
But you know the Song Bohemian rhapsody?
Yeah.
Do you know how they do it in concert?
No.
Oh,
it's classic.
So I'm like,
okay,
I can't wait to see this Bahamian
rhapsody like are they going to go
around a Mike,
hold their aunt or their ears and do
the,
is this the,
you know the harmonies?
None of it.
They skip the beginning part.
The skip it.
Skip it completely.
Start with a doon.
Doon Doon Doon Doon doon the piano part.
Real Mama.
Yeah.
They don't do the,
is this the reela is,
it's just fantasy.
Call it in Atlanta.
All in escape.
All of that gone.
Really?
Yeah.
So they start with the song,
wait Joe,
this gets better.
Yeah.
They smiling.
I just killed a man.
People are going,
Nah.
Then they played the first guitar solo
and then they got dunked in den.
I'm just,
you know that part,
the opera part,
guess what happens at that part?
What they run offstage?
Queen leaves the stage.
They play the record.
I'm just at the end and then the whole
opera park figure [inaudible] I'm just
up a boy if I'm up over all of that.
And then when they come back for the
guitar so damned and an end,
they don't learn and then they come back
on stage and sing the rest of the show.
The song.
Huh?
It's the craziest thing I'd ever seen
Madison Square.
I'm like,
I turn to the person that I was like,
you realize there's no one on stage
right now?
No one on stage.
And they're just playing that opera
part.
Hmm.
Like a song of it.
Wonder why they do that.
Cause it vocally,
I assume we would just be impossible to
come near what's on that record,
right?
Yeah.
Gas.
You liked that song,
right?
Yeah.
But I would imagine they would want to
replicate,
I mean opera singers can replicate
opera.
Yeah.
But it's so multitrack.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
That's did it in it.
I will not.
But you,
which you would think that they would
like at least perform part of it.
What they do,
they do the the easy.
Know what I mean?
While they're doing it while all the
hallways at least participate.
Run offstage.
Huh?
Maybe like a cigarette break for little
girls.
It's just like,
we can't do this.
We're out of here.
And then they come back and he was
pretty good singer.
Yeah.
That guy was a good singer.
Hmm.
Um,
what's the best counselor you've seen or
your favorite favorite.
Do you leave and go to concerts?
No,
very rarely now cause I can,
all right.
This is going to sound insulting.
It's going to send him.
So I said okay.
But I,
when I look at,
you know,
your act,
I think if you like it,
a slayer concert.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
A Danzig counseling,
any of that shit.
You don't know?
No.
Tell me what you like.
Ah,
I'm totally,
I apologize if I judged you on,
you're kind of an aggressive act right
now.
I'm like a slayer aggressive act.
You don't even watch,
he doesn't watch the,
Oh,
I would like to do it the other night.
Doing your,
uh,
a bit about Bruce,
the new Bruce Jenner or whatever.
What's her name?
Caitlyn.
Caitlyn Jenner.
Yeah.
How do you feel about that Caitlyn
Jenner thing?
Wow.
First of all,
I'm afraid
to talk about it cause I'm going to get
frick to tug.
You're way braver than I am.
Way Braver.
And I,
although there was a comedian last
night,
I had a great joke.
God,
what was his name?
Kyle.
Kyle Kinane.
No,
not kyle.
Kinane.
Um,
I'll think of his name.
It,
this is not my dog,
but he said he don't say his joke.
Don't say your joke without his name.
No,
they're going to give his joke or it was
just a throw away.
Don't say don't say anything ever.
Uh,
he's doing now.
He's doing the tonight show on Wednesday
and he's not doing that joke.
He told a joke before.
He does it on this and I just not doing
it on the tonight.
Show what I'm saying it all right.
Nevermind.
Uh,
but it's a weird subject right where it
is all the sudden you're not supposed to
make fun of something that's obviously
ridiculous,
unprecedented,
unprecedented.
I don't buy it and I'm not going to buy
it and I don't care.
I just get any blow back at all.
You do?
Sure.
People get upset.
Yeah.
And do zen out on it.
Do you think it's funny?
I listen,
were we,
this is a really easily defensible one.
First of all,
you're talking about a ridiculous human
being.
Okay.
Not just ridiculous,
but patently ridiculous.
Right?
A guy who is a transsexual jeff dye was
the comedian.
Oh,
okay.
I'm going to do each joke later.
Transsexual comedian who comedian
transsexual man became a woman and
doesn't believe in gay marriage.
So he's ridiculous person right there.
And when on Ellen,
when Ellen confronted him,
did you ever watch that?
No.
It's pretty fucking awkward because you
realize,
first of all,
how stupid he really is.
He's a dumb man.
He's not smart as a woman,
as a man,
whatever.
But when Ellen's talk knew about gay
rights and about gay marriage about,
wouldn't you think that you as a person
who's been marginalized your whole life,
you would support his argument was or
her argument whenever you want to call
while voice from tron for short of a
traditionalist like no,
you're not a traditional,
you're a fucking man with nail Polish on
and address who's now a woman and you
had your jaw shave down to be a woman.
You have fake tits,
you're not fucking traditional at all.
And that's a shitty,
stupid excuse for being a bigot.
Like you can't say that you don't
support gay marriage because you're a
traditional woman cause you're not a
traditional woman.
All right.
And then I know it says a bunch of
things about him.
He doesn't hold that position.
You feel gives you more latitude.
It drives me nuts.
The only thing that we're supposed to be
paying attention to when you're looking
at someone who's doing something that's
obviously odd,
right?
Right.
You're not supposed to make fun of it
because it's a thing about gender.
Why is gender all of a sudden the only
that,
like this is the only category that
precludes you from humor.
Like you're,
you're supposed to be,
you're,
you're unsafe space,
right?
You've,
you've,
you're holding on to base.
Like I'm touching base.
You can't get me,
I'm touching base.
This is gender that I reject that.
And I think that over time we're going
to realize how ridiculous we were acting
with this preposterous person who's
essentially a male cardiac,
an
older male card.
I mean that's what the fuck he is.
No.
Right.
And on top of that,
everybody forgets.
He killed a woman.
He fucking slammed into some lady cause
he wasn't paying attention,
knocked her into oncoming traffic and
she died.
And everybody's just sort of whisked
that away.
And then he wins an Sba award and he's
walking around with fucking drapes
flowing the curtains and the breeze and
there's a helicopter flying over.
And when he's walking around his house
and his heels,
it's preposterous.
This is a preposterous person.
This is not his standard subject of
transsexuals who,
you know,
need to be respected for the choices.
Of course you should respect people for
their choices.
Of course,
people should be able to express
themselves in any way they want.
You could be a heterosexual man who is
completely into women but likes dressing
up like a woman and I support that too.
You can say you're a woman.
He was a woman when he was on the Diane
Sawyer show or he was a man.
He said he wants to be him.
He wants to be called [inaudible].
And then immediately after the attention
that he got from that,
he gets massive surgery and changes his
name to Caitlyn.
This is a ridiculous person,
right?
This is a person that's infatuated with
attention for no reason,
not attention for their art,
not attention for their philosophies or
for their thoughts or for their work.
No,
this is a person who's a infatuated with
attention for no reason.
That's why I think you're supposed to be
able to make fun of this person.
I think my feeling is that,
and again,
I am,
you know my act not edgy at all.
Dot.
Not Edge.
React.
Well
you,
you go after some stuff.
I loved your bit about actors.
I fucking love that because I've always
felt the same way.
You did a bit that I was clapping and
laughing out about actors being able to
cry on cue and you were like,
yeah,
that's because they're fucking crazy.
Like these are massively damaged people.
Like trust me,
I know them.
I work with them.
You did this really cool.
Thank you.
Right.
All right.
But that's his,
that's his like his head.
Yes,
but you went in the,
I did.
I knew when all it does is completely
benign,
but you have to work with them all the
time.
I know,
I know.
I know what it was just about because I
went to acting school,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
And patently the most ridiculous people
and all of show business.
The actor without a doubt.
Yeah.
We're here.
Well,
I want,
hey,
Seinfeld does a great,
just a great takedown actors all the
time.
He says like,
what are they?
Why are we giving them awards?
I was like,
they're told what to say,
where to stand,
but they don't have to do Anik,
why are they getting an award?
It's great.
Um,
yeah,
no,
I learned that in acting school.
Then it'll be like the more emotional
leeward,
the better actor you were like it's
true.
Yeah,
it's true.
The more emotionally imbalanced,
the more the whole thing,
the less grounded you are in reality.
You're creating this whole thing that
you can really become a great actor.
Um,
I knew that my point was it,
even if Katelyn wasn't all of it,
even if she was pro gay marriage or not
part of the Kardashians,
I still feel like it's part of life and
can be made fun of.
Sure.
I don't,
this is a thing I have a problem with
and which is this thing about punching
down.
Do you have any idea what I'm talking
about?
Yeah.
But this is all nonsense.
It's all nonsense to make fun of things.
You're allowed to make fun of
everything.
More fun of myself as my main thing,
but like you're letting me find,
I think it's great.
Of course that's a Gibson,
this hole punching down thing is a
symptom.
It's all coming out of social media.
It's a consequence of people being able
to criticize and get upset about things
and become recreationally outraged and
yeah.
Well there's some punching down.
It's really fucking mean of course.
But then there's Kennison talking about
the starving people in Ethiopia.
That's fucking hilarious.
It's a total punching down bit and it's
one of the greatest bits of all time
you,
but it's funny and you cannot define
what's funny and what's not funny.
Some people,
well we have seen some mean common who
bully be able with their comedy.
Right.
Doesn't work though.
Right,
right.
It's not good.
Nobody likes it.
I know.
I've seen it.
I've seen it work sometimes.
So it's,
I'm not saying there's nothing to it.
I'm saying the idea that like some
things are off limits or what did your
great analogy years and of I'm on base
and this,
you can't touch this crazy,
right?
It's nothing off limits but,
but people will decide that there's
something off limits.
And then the way they reinforce that
they gang up on people like bullies.
Like Daniel Tosh got in trouble.
Remember when Daniel Tosh made that
joke,
which was a,
uh,
we're dealing with the handler,
right?
He's dealing with a heckler and
[inaudible] he was also not even
supposed to be on stage,
so he didn't have any material prepared.
And Dom irrera forced him to go on
stage.
The client go on stage.
So he,
he said,
all right,
okay.
So we went on stage and he didn't have
any materials cause what do you guys
want to talk?
I don't have any material.
What do you guys want to talk about?
And some guy yells out rape.
And so he goes,
well,
what's funny about rape?
The humiliation,
the violence.
Like what's sorry,
what's funny about rape,
right?
And some woman yells at,
actually nothing's funny about rape.
This is like someone who took the
opportunity to be sanctimonious and
obviously nothing's funny.
Rape.
And he goes,
well wouldn't it be funny if five guys
just raped her right now?
Which is something that a comedian would
say,
right?
And so this woman goes and writes a blog
and then it becomes this big issue.
Did he crossed the line?
She's a fucking heckler.
I know he's a heckler.
Not only that,
she's the worst kind of hackler.
Someone is trying to take the high
ground and you know,
and be sanctimonious and stand up and
admonish anyone for saying like,
look,
you'll enjoy the show or don't enjoy the
show.
Leave,
do whatever the fuck you want.
But if you want to jump in and decide
that you're going to be the moral voice
of the crowd,
you're going to get chopped up.
And that's how comedy works.
That's your,
you're dealing with live comedy.
And when someone has to make comedy out
of what you just,
you just come all over these people and
you used your emotions and you used your
morality and you decided you're going to
enforce it on these people in the middle
of a comedy show,
you can't do that.
You know what he's doing?
He's trying to make comedy out of
something.
And also just his reaction to be the,
yeah,
it was perfect.
Just do that kind of like,
okay,
what is the worst offensive thing
say to somebody who just said nothing
about rapes fun.
Yeah.
Would it be funny if five guys raped her
right now and then,
hey,
by the way,
the audience,
how old laughing,
right?
Timing was perfect and she's decided
this is a fucking wonderful opportunity
to be recreationally outraged.
Yeah.
It's,
look,
I hate fuck them.
I understand.
I understand,
but I do.
What about,
let me,
let me take the side of like,
look,
now that I have a twitter account and
I'm not talking about me,
I'm talking about in our audience member
now,
who was outraged that somebody made fun
of something that now comedians can't
hear.
Like I don't have free speech.
I can't yell at me and my friends can
gang up on a comedian yell at them on
twitter.
You certainly again.
Right,
but you're a cunt.
Oh,
okay.
Well it depends.
It depends on whether or not you have a
point,
right.
It's like all kinds of opinions and you
can have an argument with someone,
like say if you have an argument,
someone publicly and somebody stands and
walks by and they maybe didn't get the
entire full argument but they watch you
say something mean to that person.
They're allowed to have an opinion on
that.
It might not be the most informed
opinion,
it might not be correct.
And then maybe you can choose to engage
them and have a discussion about their,
their opinion or you can choose to not
and let it,
let it exist in a vacuum and let them
just fucking Yap about it.
Yeah.
Let me ask you another question.
Okay.
And I know you don't like it ha like me
asking about asking questions.
Right.
That's not the question though.
Okay.
That's not the question.
Is there anything you've done in your
act through the years and you've
released many albums,
had five specials,
right?
At least.
Yeah.
At least candy we count.
Uh,
is there anything you've looked back and
gone?
I don't think I would have worded that
today the way I did back then.
Not In terms of it being offensive,
but in terms of it being solid man on
the economy of words was incorrect or it
wasn't the best bit or I should have
worked on it more before I did it.
Or maybe I got a little lazy and my,
which is more about tightening,
making a bit better.
Yeah.
But that's just like looking at it now,
standing back and being completely done
with the material and then going over it
now and then being able to critique it
honestly and openly.
But at the time,
no is my points.
I'm,
I'm saying looking back,
would you go,
ah,
I wish I hadn't said
no,
not really.
No.
I think that's,
no,
I mean I think pretty much everything
I've ever said I've thought about before
I said it enough to point where I had to
have a reason for wanting to joke about
it and then I had to have a,
a perspective,
I'm betting matches more as a evolution
is someone who's always,
as you said earlier,
learning,
trying new things.
Yeah.
I mean here was,
have an evolution of my own thought
process.
Right.
But I think when I look at old comedy,
what gets me is how it links to what
words.
Yeah.
An extra words.
Economy of words.
So critical and also,
you know,
the being in the moment and the timing
and you know,
and just,
it's why it's hard to watch yourself.
It's hard,
but it's critical because that,
that watching and listening to yourself,
do you tape yourself?
Reset every set.
Wow.
Yeah.
That is discipline.
Got It.
That is hot.
Yeah.
That the only way you're ever going to
understand where you ad libbed and
figuring out what those have lives are
and whether or not they're valid.
When do you listen to it?
On the car?
On the way home.
Yeah.
That's the best way.
Or the next day on the car.
On the way to a,
the show again.
I'll listen to it because it's so nice
because your phone just boost juice.
Yeah.
Up to the stereo.
It's great.
It's easy to do and sometimes it's
painful.
Oh yeah.
Fuck Yeah Dude.
I just got done editing my special and
you know,
sitting down there and listen in San
Francisco.
Yeah.
You get it at the fillmore and dope and
then go on the legion.
Thank you.
And then going and watching it.
It's like,
oh,
I hate myself.
I don't want to watch it.
That's gross.
You know?
Did you do it?
We just did three hours.
Okay,
we're done.
We're done.
We did it.
You gonna walk away.
Hold on.
He actually left.
Fetterman has left,
but I've got his phone.
It's a fake leaving.
You left your phone.
Did the bit.
That's wrap this up.
Let's do a wrap up.
Let's wrap this up.
How do we wrap up?
We don't,
we just,
it is no usual this.
The beautiful thing about podcasts,
man.
How many times you done podcast?
Manny,
manny,
come on up to the microphone so people
can hear you.
Oh,
is that how you do it?
Yeah,
that,
there you go.
You gotta be up there.
You've done a bunch of them.
Yeah.
I've never done,
this is the longest I've ever known.
Have you ever thought about doing your
own?
I did do one with the girl does.
It didn't work out because you fell in
love.
Now here's interesting.
Choose 25 years younger than I am
married and I'm single,
so we had this great back and forth.
Little bit of a tension.
Sexual tension,
I think,
unfortunately.
Yeah.
A little bit on your side or her side or
both.
Just leave it there.
Let's just leave it in nicely with this
silly.
The hat.
Fetterman on twitter.
Yeah.
Whoever.
You are the guy who still awaiting
fetterman.
Fuck you.
Fuck
you buddy.
Tried to get money from you,
right?
I think he wants some money.
Yeah.
Let's get twitter to get that back.
Jamie.
Contact them.
Get on that.
Get Chandra on it.
Thank you for inviting more.
Allowing me on your show.
I only invited you and number 200 820
and 29 two 829 it hundred 20 how many of
those have you heard?
Completely back again?
At least five.
I would think it would be less than five
is more than the five.
Five.
I probably heard 12 it's pretty good.
I listen to very many.
I I how could you?
No time and I don't want to,
man.
It's out there.
Yeah,
but are you,
but it's again,
it's the same kind of thing like
standup.
You learn,
you know,
when you talk too much or if you talk
over people listen.
Yeah,
I know.
I feel like I interrupted you too much,
but,
oh,
you were great.
Thank you.
But I did have the,
uh,
I really appreciate the compliment,
the a,
that album,
the Jimi Hendrix experience.
My,
it was my older brother's,
but I remember Mitch Mitchell Aqui.
She could remember the name of the Bass
player.
Do you remember his name?
No,
but those are replaceable white dudes.
No.
I feel like they were never as good.
No reading is my guest.
That's off the top.
I'm not looking at,
you can tell them right now.
Am I looking at a computer and not
looking at the computer?
Going to say no.
Ready.
Mitch Mitchell and then Jim Hendrix.
That's the way I used to call him.
All right.
When fedderman ladies and gentlemen
later.
Good bye.
See You tomorrow.
We'll be back tomorrow with Neal
Brennan.
All right.
That was easy.