Four,
three,
two.
Hello,
Dale.
Hey,
how you doing?
Thanks for doing this man.
I appreciate it.
Yeah,
I'm glad to be here.
Nice to meet you,
man.
Nice to found out that not only you're a
car driver,
you also a bowhunter yeah,
yeah.
They'd be like,
I saw your,
your archery equipment and all that
stuff,
but me and a buddy of mine owned some
land and,
and I try to get out there and at least
go twice a year.
I just love being in the stands,
sitting in the woods,
just thinking about what's going on and
brain cleanse everything before the shot
really is what it's all about.
Yeah,
that's a lot of it,
right?
Hanging out with your,
being with your friends and family,
you know,
you need one of those technical wants in
your life.
It's pretty impressive.
Yeah.
That thing is all my friends would come
over here.
Just go,
whoa.
Yeah.
That's a,
that's a life changer.
Yeah,
absolutely.
But it's also a giant time waster.
I know.
I don't know.
I've got a golf sim at the house,
so I got to figure out where I can put
that.
Golf is the one I've always avoided.
I've always avoided golf because I just
saw it suck away people's time.
I don't go.
That's the thing,
like I don't have the time and the
patience to really block that whole day
off to go play outdoors,
but to go over there and just hit the
driver for 30 minutes on the simulators.
So fun.
Well,
I would imagine with what you do for a
living with.
I think what you do is one of the
craziest,
wildest,
most demanding things a person could do
for an occupation where,
I dunno,
it's,
it's right up there,
you know?
No,
other than being a soldier or a
firefighter or a cop or a fighter
fighter and bullfighting and bull
riding,
those types of things are those people
boxing.
That's some bull riders that's on
another level.
That's another level of crazy as hung
out with those guys and they are on
another day or crazy people.
You know,
it takes a certain mentality to,
to be able to climb onto a bull.
Yeah,
they have a certain energy about them
that they got that I don't give a fuck
energy.
It's cranked up the tab.
Yeah.
Have you ever been in Vegas when they
have the finals?
I haven't actually,
but they're everywhere and they're all
crazy.
I know that they are really,
I know a lot of those guys and uh,
um,
our car,
our paths have crossed several times and
every time you're around them you're
like,
are we going to end up in jail tonight?
That's a real possibility.
Yeah.
I mean there are throwbacks real
throwback.
They are legit wildman.
I agree.
Yeah.
I mean,
but what,
but driving,
driving a race car,
I mean you have a giant engine,
you're strapped into a seat,
you're and down the road at extreme
speeds right next to other cars doing
the same thing.
Just the intensity and the,
just the everything.
Being on nine at all times like that is
a wild way to make a living,
sir.
Yeah,
thanks.
I mean,
I,
um,
when I was a little,
when I was little thinking about,
you know,
what the hell am I going to grow up and
be a,
I was,
my father was really successful in the
sport so I would go to
the races and I would watch him race and
see him win and watch him go through
victory lane and,
and celebrate and all those things.
And I thought,
man,
this is what I gotta do.
I gotta do this,
this is,
this looks fun.
This looks exciting.
People are,
you know,
people are in all of the drivers,
the race,
my father,
the,
the personalities and I just wanted to
do it real badly.
But I knew that the odds of making it or
tufts,
so there's only 40 guys in the field
every weekend.
So there's 40 guys in this in the whole
country that are going to get the shot
to do it,
you know?
And may the odds of me even with my dad
being a successful,
his,
he was,
I'd have a lot of doors open to me.
But the odds of me actually getting
there and being able to stay,
have the staying power and the success
and talent I just knew were tough.
So I didn't know if I'd ever get that
chance.
Um,
but it is.
I don't know.
I remember the first time I went to a
two and a half mile track.
It's Talladega and you hold it wide
open.
I was uh,
working at my dad's dealership,
changing oil.
He owned a Chevy store in Newton,
North Carolina.
And uh,
the phone rang and he said,
my dad,
my dad was on the van and he was in
Talladega for a test and he said,
get your helmet and your suit and meet
me at the race track the next day you're
gonna fly the king air to the,
to the track.
Don't know,
don't ask questions,
just do it.
And so I got there and I knew I was
going to Talladega and I thought,
man,
I must be driving this.
This is gonna be crazy.
I'm going to go around this two and a
half mile to track full speed at 190
miles an hour.
I'd never done,
I never went faster than 90 or 95 on a
race track before.
Never drove anything bigger than a half
mile.
And uh,
I pulled out,
he's got there,
he's like,
you're gonna test this car,
get in,
get ready.
He puts me in there and he's like,
you got a hold of wide open if you don't
hold a lot up and the motor's not going
to work it,
it'll hurt the motor.
You got to hold it the way they tune the
motor to run wide open.
It has to run it,
it has to run at full throttle if you
tried to go around there and half
throttle to burn the Pistons that a run
to lean all those things.
So he,
he was saying that and I thought to
myself,
is he just telling me that just to make
sure I hold a lot open because he
thought I would,
I would,
I would be opposed to not do it.
And so I was like,
man,
I,
I'm a little nervous,
uh,
to hold it wide open.
But I pulled out on the track and mash
the gas full throttle and I'm going down
the back straightaway and I was like,
I'm looking down the back straightaway
into the next corner,
this long corner.
And I'm like,
how's it going to stick?
You know,
how's the car going to,
how's the car not going to flat of the
racetrack like it.
I'm going so fast,
I don't,
it doesn't feel like it's going to stay
in the track.
And uh,
and I kept running,
kept running through my head about my
dad's saying,
I got to hold it wide open.
I'm like,
well that's it.
It'll,
it'll,
it'll go wide open around here.
So I don't think he would,
you know,
I believe everything he says and you go
in the corner and you turn a into the
corner and there is more grit than you
can imagine.
Like the,
it,
there's so much grit.
The truck of the car is stuck to the
track with such grip that you've never
felt this before in your life.
This grip,
like you can't slide across that track.
That or the tires and the car,
a hold of the track,
so tough and tight that nothing going to
make it.
It just goes around there like it's the
craziest thing.
And so now today when I tell people,
uh,
when I got,
we got this two seater car and we take
people for rides and they get in there
and I'm like,
man,
what am I going to do?
What are you going to do to explain to
somebody what this is going to feel
like?
Whether I will tell you things to pay
attention,
to pay attention to the grip.
You're not going to believe how much
grip this car has.
Like it's,
you're,
you're just not going to believe that
it'll stick to the track the way it
does.
So pay attention to that and pay
attention.
Now,
bumpy and violent,
it is,
you know,
you drive a cadillac or a any car down
the street,
well,
it's six,
eight inches off the ground.
These big old inflated tires and big,
giant sidewalls.
And it's going to feel nice.
You know,
when it hits a little bumps,
our cars are rigid and stuck to the
ground and don't have much travel in the
suspension and you know,
it's just,
it's,
it's built to hand to go fast,
not to feel good,
you know,
and it's gonna it's rough as hell and
shakes,
shakes the hell out of you.
And um,
that's what I remember about that.
And as soon as I got over that initial
fear,
I think that was the only time I ever
had any real fear of driving a car.
As soon as I was like,
well,
alright,
what do you know?
Anything,
nothing else is going to be as scary as
that was.
Right.
Driving a car.
And I've been flipping and when I
flipped for the first time and our,
you know,
the car's tumbling and flying parts
flying off the air,
my eye,
I thought to myself that I wasn't scared
or I never was scared of flipping.
My thought was I just did something.
A lot of people never get to experience,
you know,
I did something that,
uh,
that only a few people know what that's
like.
And,
and I feel safe,
I've always felt incredibly safe inside
the car,
you know,
with,
especially with the,
I mean,
in the last 20 years,
this safety stuff has really been
focused on and improved and better and
better and better.
But I'll look at the interior of our
cars today versus 20 years ago.
And it said,
I can't believe some of the stuff that
we used to climb into that.
So you felt calm while it was flipping?
Oh yeah.
I always will have seen cars flipped,
right?
I've seen it for years.
Right.
And so I know it's possible.
So I get in there and I got turned
around at a race in 1998.
I was racing at Daytona and uh,
I got turned around and the car,
so I'm flipping for the first time in my
life and this car is like over 3000,
3000 pounds.
So it's.
But it flies up in the air.
Like it's paper,
man.
It's the craziest thing in the world.
It's so weightless,
you know,
and what it felt like to me [inaudible].
So the car rolled on its side and came
down kind of on its side.
It felt like somebody wrote a prop wall
of grass up against the car,
you know what I'm saying?
When I was on my side and I could see
the ground,
I felt like I was right side up because
as you're flipping,
the force pushes you down in the seat.
So you feel internally you feel gravity
all the time.
Like you're,
you know,
as a cars flipping your.
You're pushed into the seat so you feel
great.
You feel weight of yourself in the seat.
That never changes.
You never kind of come up out of the
city like that,
you know?
And so it was like somebody wrote a prop
Walla grass up against the side of the
car and then against the roof and then
against that side and then this,
you know,
it kept doing that and I'm like,
it's just the weirdest feeling and you
feel completely safe and you feel like,
you know,
nothing's going to harm me,
but this,
any,
you know,
just,
you.
Just.
One of the things we always talk about,
it's like get your hands on to something
because the spinning makes your arms and
you just go like this and if you watch a
lot of old wrecks from the sixties and
seventies,
you'll see the guy's arms come flying
out the window and they're just kind of
flopping around.
They can't pull it spinning so fast.
You can't pull it in and uh,
your arms go like that.
So as soon as you know you're going
upside down,
you grabbed the bottom of the steering
wheel and just Kinda,
you know,
watch.
But um,
I flip my pickup truck one time on
Christmas Day and I wasn't holding on
the steering wheel and my arm went out
the window,
you know,
for like a split second.
It banged around in the,
in the,
in the window seal.
And I was like,
man,
you know,
I got it back in and grabbed a hold the
steering wheel with both my hands.
And so ever since then I've like,
you know,
now I know like anytime I'm in a crash,
you gotta have your hands a hold of
something because that's the one thing
that you can't control.
You're strapped in with your seat belt
and everything,
but your arms are,
you know,
can go anywhere.
And in that moment when the car's
rolling or barrel rolling or flipping
you,
it's so fast.
Like you can't,
your arms just go this way.
It's the craziest thing in the world.
That's the only fear I guess is that
your arm could get outside the window
and get crushed or something because you
guys have had that happen.
Yeah,
I would imagine.
Yeah.
How'd you flip when you were on
Christmas?
On Christmas Day?
My sister,
uh,
she knows this,
she just won't be news to her,
but um,
uh,
it,
it's probably not fun for her to hear
every time I tell it.
But we,
I had a pickup truck with a tape deck in
it and I had,
she got me the Walkman cd with the
adapter for the tape tape deck that you
stick into you,
you know,
you said adapter.
And she bought me the Walkman extended
after.
And I'm in my,
I'm in,
I'm in my truck.
I got an extended cab as 10.
I'm driving from my house to my memos
house where a farmer union is.
My Dad's there.
Everybody's,
their whole family's there.
I'm a little late,
um,
and I'm driving down the road and I got
to mess around with that Walkman.
And I drove off into the ditch and I hit
a driveway,
covert pipe drainage pipe in a driveway
and went like seven flips and destroyed
this truck in the middle of the flip.
And I remember that happening and
everything.
All my change jacket,
anything that was loose in the car,
ended up down in one corner,
like flow board.
Everything sort of collects into that.
One corner is spinning and it crushed
the windshield down.
The mirror was down into the radio,
you know,
we was,
it crushed the roof down real bad.
I was really lucky.
I had my hands on top of the steering
wheel and the windshield kept slapping
my knuckles and knocked on,
busted all my knuckles real bad.
And so then I let go and my hands went
this way and then I finally got him back
in and grabbed the bottom of the
steering wheel.
The tires were broken and busted off the
truck and this I got out of the truck
and I was fine.
Didn't have any injuries other than just
the knuckles kind of being scraped up
this,
this newly married couple.
They just are either got engaged or just
got married.
We're driving the other way and saw the
whole thing and they stopped and uh,
they were like,
yeah,
right.
I'm like,
yeah.
And uh,
of course there's this line of cars
behind me stopped on the road and this
one lady pulls up and I was like,
I need to borrow your cell phone to call
my dad.
She's like,
you're in shock.
You need to sit down.
I was like,
no,
I'm not in shock.
I just needed to borrow my cell phone.
So she walked to the next car and I got
a cell phone from this person.
I called my dad and I was like,
Dad.
I was like,
man,
I flipped my truck.
I had pe,
I had got,
I'd financed this thing for five years.
I was paying $100 a month is perfect.
I was working at dealership changing
oil,
probably making $130 a week and I just
got this truck for probably two,
three months and I'm used truck,
but it was,
it was good.
It's junk.
Uh,
I called dad and I'm like,
man,
he's gonna be mad,
can't be too mad because I'm paying for
the truck,
but he's gonna be mad at me because I'm
screwing up family reunion.
And Christmas he comes to get me a,
I'd flip this truck real close to where
our farm was.
So he ran over to the farm and got this
flat bed truck.
And uh,
he pulls out there with the flatbed
truck and he pulls up and as soon as he
pulls up,
state trooper pulls up in the State
Trooper Guy and dad talked for a minute
and to get state troopers,
like,
you know,
one single car accident.
You okay?
Yeah,
everybody's Okay Dad,
you,
Daddy,
you going to put this on flatbed?
Take it home.
Yeah.
Okay.
Um,
you know,
I ain't gonna I ain't gonna investigate
or anything.
Everything's cool.
Y'All just go about your business.
So he left because he did a solid there
and didn't give me any kind of traffic
ticket.
And so me and dad put the truck on the
flatbed and we're driving back and he
started laughing and I was like,
man,
I expected you to be really mad because
he was a fiery kind of dad,
you know,
and,
uh,
pull the belt out and go to town,
you know,
he,
he was a rough,
strict,
tough,
tough dude.
And so I thought I was going to get,
um,
a good customer at least.
But he started laughing and I said,
man,
what's the funny?
And he goes,
I was 18 when this happened.
He goes,
when I was 18 years old,
I've flipped my car.
He's like,
I can't get mad.
I'm just glad you ain't got hurt.
I'm like,
well,
that's nice.
So we drove back.
I took pictures of it and uh,
got me,
got any insurance for it.
Got like 11,
12 gram for the insurance to be able to
buy another truck.
So it all worked out.
So that was the first time you ever flip
something or did you,
were you the first time?
That was not the race car was next.
So the race car is like,
Oh,
I've been here before.
Yeah.
And there's nothing in the race car.
It's,
it's not as bad as a passenger car.
You only got that strap,
you know,
you're moving around and banging around
in there.
And then the race car,
you're in there pretty tight.
Yeah.
Do you feel weird when you're in a
passenger car to is for the lack of
support,
lack of support and safety?
Uh,
you know,
I,
I do because compared to the way our cup
cars are now or the race cars are now,
man were cocooned in their,
the seat and everything.
The headrests,
you got six slash seven point harness.
I mean in a street car,
you really just got the strap.
I mean it's um,
I certainly,
uh,
you know,
I'm more,
I'm much more cautious as I get older on
the highway and people were like,
hey man,
how do you do it?
How do you drive on how you drive a race
car and then go 45,
55 on the road.
And it's really easy actually,
you know,
just kinda chill out all your fast
driving out of the way.
When I was younger I was getting
speeding tickets all the time,
but when as I got older I just didn't
care to be in a hurry anymore.
Yeah,
I would figure the way you drive for a
living,
you just get it out of your system.
Yeah,
I get plenty of.
I had plenty and plenty of high speed
action and hi jinks on the race track.
I don't,
I calmed down the road.
What kind of car do you drive in real
life?
Well,
it's funny.
I,
um,
I just bought a brand new Silverado.
I hadn't bought a truck and a long time
I had,
I still have my old Silverado bald is
about,
oh,
four.
Oh six.
But this new one a,
I like a lot of new ones are bad.
I didn't like the old ones that much.
They just look kind of basic,
like the new ones are really sweet,
look under character lines and the body
lines.
It's just a good looking truck.
So about that.
Um,
but my,
what I was driving before that,
I got a 48,
a pickup truck and a,
it's all rough as hell on the outside
and I'm original,
faded all messy and ugly looking.
But it's got a vortac motor and good
drive train in.
It drives good,
but it's easy to work on and I just love
fooling with it.
I took the original banks bench seat out
and put these old bucket seats in from
an 80 a chevy blazer and some made it
comfortable and just the way I wanted
it.
So I drove.
I drove that a lot this summer until I
got this new truck and I got a 76 Chevy
Laguna that I love to drive.
That thing just kind of floats,
floats down the road man,
and it's a dark midnight blue tinted
windows and just a really cool because I
love the seventies in the style of the
cars in the seventies even though kind
of the bigger ones,
like in the late seventies,
like the 4:42
oldsmobile cutlass,
it was big,
big,
big cars.
There's something about those guys that
I really dig.
Is that your car?
That's my car right there.
Yeah.
I love that thing man.
I had a 19,
73 Chevelle.
Yeah.
That reminds me of that kind of body
style.
That's it.
I got it for 42.
That's sort of the sister that also bill
for 42.
That's red and I'm Kinda the same.
Tenant went same.
I did the same wheels,
same tire,
same tent,
same.
I put a spoiler like a nascar style
spoiler on the back and the front and
kind of look because those cars were big
in Nascar.
Uh,
so those,
those cars don't get as much love as a
60 slash muscle cars.
Well,
we'll get there.
I think as we get older.
The what's cool gets older.
Roommate.
Yeah.
Like,
I mean nothing.
I mean this car,
the [inaudible] 67 Camaro.
Those cards.
Yeah.
I got a 67.
I thought I had a 69,
but uh,
like the 55 share,
all those things will always hold their
rightful place in history.
But these cars like that car right
there,
that wasn't very cool.
Ten,
15,
20 years ago.
No.
But as we get older that car becomes
cool,
you know?
And,
and,
and one day we'll be driving around in
like a 85 pickup trucks.
Go on man listening.
So,
so awesome.
So really think so.
I mean know about that.
I just think that the car might just be
cool because you own it.
I don't know.
I think that it's got these old
character lines,
man,
like it does have old.
You know what's interesting?
I was,
I was just talking to a friend of mine
about this one in 1970.
My mom bought a barracuda.
Yeah.
And when I was in high school in 1981,
I was a freshman in high school and she
had this bear coat and it was like a
classic car and it was like a classic
muscle car.
Right.
But that's the only 11 years old.
Yeah.
Like if you had a car today from 2007,
whether.
Yeah,
you wouldn't be a class.
So yeah,
you're right.
It's weird.
It is weird.
Like a 1969 when I was in high school in
1969,
which is only an 11 year old car was
amazing.
Like whoa.
People would stop and stare at it.
Do look at that 69 Camaro.
Yeah.
I got an 88 s 10.
That was the first pickup truck.
Uh,
I owned or had,
that was like the car I got when I was
16 years old and I got one and restored
it and uh,
which was a terrible investment,
but um,
it makes sense for me because it,
you know,
because it was my first truck boat and I
didn't think anybody would give a shit
about it.
Right.
Because it's an Stn,
it's like the,
the bottom of the barrel and pickup
trucks for Chevrolet in 1988 and,
and,
but I drive that thing around and people
were like,
wow,
that's the cleanest as 10 I've seen in
20 years.
That's it right there.
Oh,
that's nice.
Yeah.
And so what's something about seeing one
of those,
it's in great shape.
I like that it made it through.
Yeah,
there's not many of them left.
I mean for,
for good reason.
But what was your first car?
My first car was a 73 Chevelle.
Yeah,
that one.
But I got it out on anyone.
Good car man.
Oh,
I love.
She's.
So would you buy,
would you get a 73 and restore it to get
a 70?
So that's my favorite year.
Sixty nine and 70 are my favorite years.
I go back and forth between six slash
nine slash 70 with Chevelles.
Both amazing years.
Yeah.
I liked those cars.
They're,
they're uh,
they're a big muscle car.
It's a big.
It's bigger than the Camaro.
Yeah.
I have a 19,
69 Nova.
Really?
Yeah.
I would just like a smaller.
Yeah,
like that right there.
Daddy looking car that is as classic and
American muscle cars you get.
That's a 1970 with silver with black
stripes come out.
They used to race Novas my dad raced a
Nova.
Yeah.
Nope.
I liked Novas because their light is a
light car and because you know,
you put a big engine in it and new
suspension and you know,
I have a,
a Nova,
a lagging,
but I just bought a 66.
Oh Wow.
That's my next project.
I'm about it from a buddy for five grand
and um,
it's in,
it's,
it's pretty bad shape,
but I'm going to,
that's my next project.
Soon as I get some time I had this
little girl,
Allah and she's six months.
Um,
so it's kind of made it tough.
Do any kind of proxy.
Thanks.
It's awesome.
But it does,
uh,
it does eat up.
Everything is on the side right now and
it will be forever until they move out
and then it's still a little bit on the
side because you got to call and check
on them.
Yeah.
So it's awesome though.
It is,
it's amazing.
I can't,
I couldn't.
It's like getting married and having a
kid and all that stuff is not nothing
like I thought it'd be.
It's no one can explain it to you.
Especially a kid part.
Yeah,
they can explain it to you.
I've had friends that have kids.
They just go,
we'll,
we'll talk after the kids bright.
There's no way you're going to be able
to figure this out until it actually
happens.
Yeah.
I've had people,
everybody tries to tell you this is what
it's going to be like,
man.
You Ain't gonna believe that greatest
thing ever.
Boy,
you just don't even know.
And it still does.
It doesn't help.
It doesn't,
don't sink in till you go through the
experience.
When you go through that experience,
you're like,
damn,
they were right here.
This is the greatest thing ever.
It's a different kind of love.
It is just to,
it's just,
it's hard to explain.
It doesn't,
doesn't make,
you know,
when my,
if I come home,
my daughter's run up to me and jumped in
my arms and I catch him and they give me
a kiss and I'm hugging them and there's
a kind of love that doesn't exist in any
other.
Nothing in my life.
Nothing you could have ever felt before
with anything or anybody else.
It is,
it's just different.
Yeah.
I can't wait.
I can't wait for that.
She's six months and uh,
everybody's like,
man,
and you'll,
you'll probably agree there like it goes
fast.
It goes fast,
it goes fast.
We're sort of in that moment wherever,
like come home,
like can't wait for her to talk.
I can't wait to hear her voice.
Like,
what is her voice going to sound like?
You know,
what kind of voice is she going to have
and what is she going to like and what
are we going to want me to do with her
and those kind of things.
Yeah.
It's awesome.
Yeah,
it's awesome.
But yeah,
it does put your projects on the side is
my projects are on the side golf.
Sam's on the side.
Hunting's on the side.
I ain't going to go hunting this year.
I was,
I was going to go.
I usually go in October or November
first.
November when you guys have a spot in
Ohio.
Yeah.
Me and one of the best white tail spots
in the country.
Man,
Buddy Martin,
Martin truex Jr.
He races too.
And uH,
we just been buddies a long time and
he's hard core.
He's heavy duty into the hunting and so,
uh,
we got,
I wanted to hunt but not,
you know,
I'm not going to be going every week,
uh,
but I knew he was probably interested in
probably buying some land and us
managing it together and learn and how
that process goes.
So we bought this land and we've put the
crop,
we've put,
we've put the food plots in,
not per,
not ourselves,
but we've managed the land on how you
want to change it and I'm sort of
managing the hurt and you know,
it's been a really educational
experience.
Uh,
And I got a lot of people don't hunt,
don't even understand what we're talking
about,
you know,
the whole process.
Yeah.
Like if you buy a nice piece of land,
people who are,
especially if you look at like there's a
bunch of organizations that uh,
you know,
teach classes in how to manage a giant
piece of property,
but laying out food plots and,
and people buy these big chunks of
property specifically for whitetail
hunting.
Yeah.
So we have about a thousand acres and
that's awesome.
All we do is bow hunt for white tail.
That's it.
Will,
it will go in there twice a year maybe
or what at least once a year for Turkey.
And we eat what we kill it.
We ate,
we killed a,
we got to Turkey last year and was
eating it that night.
I mean,
that's,
that's amazing,
isn't it?
It's crazy.
Yeah.
When you can eat it and it doesn't even
ever touched the freezer never goes in
the frigerator just straight from the
harvest,
right to the grill.
Yeah,
it's great.
It's incredible.
I love deer.
Deer jerky is probably my favorite and
we fry a Turkey nuggets and stuff like
that.
I mean it's pretty cool.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
So that's a cool little getaway for you
to write a thousand acre.
A little slice of heaven.
Yeah,
it's driving distance.
So because I love a road trip,
I'm,
I mean if I wanted to I could fly out
there,
but I like the road trip.
The whole thing for me really is
everything before the shot that you take
into,
you know,
on the deer or it's the drive up there
with your buddies talking about what are
you going to do,
what he can't wait to do,
what's been going on with everybody
getting up there and getting everything
laid out.
Looking at the map on the wall,
you know,
it.
Get that big laminated map on the wall
and be like,
man,
this big good stan.
Which ways of limbo,
and let's talk about the win.
What's weighing going to be doing
tomorrow morning?
We're going to go tomorrow morning,
you know,
and then you know,
everybody has,
you know,
everybody gets their hands into cooking
dinner that night.
So you know,
everybody gets a sad or something
they're dealing with and managing and
it's just fun,
you know,
just,
just spending time with your buddies
because you don't never know.
We don't take tHat time anymore.
We don't really make time anymore and
it's kinda,
you go,
you're gonna go do that for two days,
you know,
so you're gonna make time to be with
each other and enjoy it.
I like taking my buddies and like taking
friends of mine that don't hunt or
haven't ever hunted and letting them
sort of understand what that experience
was like.
And it's pretty cool.
It is cool.
But it's tough to get someone who's
never hunted before.
Who is an enough sit in the stand?
yeah.
I can't get my wife to go.
I wanted amy to go.
She's,
she knows what hunting is about.
She's into it,
but um,
she don't want to go.
We got to,
we even got the redneck blinds,
you know,
the real clinical deals and you sitting
there in the chair and move all you
won't and you ain't got to worry about
your scent too bad or anything like
that.
And she won't even go sit in that.
I'm hoping in a little olive oil
want to go.
So we'll see.
Yeah,
maybe it's better that she doesn't go
break.
Yeah,
you're,
I need a little place where like if you
get like,
if she wanted to go every time you were
going that.
Oh,
come on.
what do you lIke it too much?
Yeah.
well I would imagine like again,
so what you do for living,
having something that's peaceful and
quiet now,
nature would be very important to kind
of balance out the just the wild hectic
nature of race car drivers.
Yeah.
I mean for me that's,
I'm getting when I get in the stand and
I sat down and I look out across the
field and look at the land and
everything.
Um,
man,
you ain't got to worry about and you
know,
answer no email or,
or getting back to this guy or setting
up this appointment or answering this
question or,
you know,
It's just,
it's even better.
It's better than going on vacation.
Like we go on vacation with my wife or
with my buddies or whatever.
You still can't really ever really
young,
you know,
disconnect from everything you're doing.
It seems like though,
when I go hunting I can completely get
rid of technology,
you know,
if I want.
And you know,
it's just a and sitting in the woods,
it's peaceful,
you know,
there's still good for you.
It is good.
It is.
It's therapeutic even though nothing's
happening.
It's kind of cleansing in a way.
Weird way.
In a weird way.
Just I think human beings have a certain
amount of requirement for time in
nature.
Yeah,
I think.
And you don't realize you have that
requirement until you're out.
You wouldn't.
Yeah.
You wouldn't know it until you go sit in
the stand.
You're like,
wow,
I needed a little bit of this.
I think even a park,
you know,
and even people that go to central park
in New York city that go to that park
and sit down,
but that tree and they just feel better.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
That's exactly what it is.
I mean,
in your,
your work environment is a concrete
slab.
You know that you're drIving how fat,
what's the fastest?
You go to 15 when that,
when that passes,
you realize how fast to 15 really is
cheese.
Sit in that car and do it long enough.
You forget.
Do you have apprehension about the
horsepower wars with just modern
consumer cars?
Because I look at some of these cars
that they're putting out that are
amazing.
Like the new core of that [inaudible]
700 plus horsepower right from the
factory that dodge demons,
like 800 horsepower.
Like they are putting out these insane
race cars right from the factory that
any dummy like me,
I could just go to a stiff.
I have the cash.
I go to a corvette dealership and pick
one up and all of a sudden I'm on the
highway.
Yeah.
I don't.
I don't have a problem with it now until
it becomes a common occurrence where
people don't know how to control,
you know,
or know how to manage what they're doing
behind the wheel of something like that.
But until,
until that's like a common issue.
I don't know that it'll need regulation.
yeah.
Yeah.
I don't necessarily think of.
I wouldn't be surprised though that one
day maybe you know,
regulated because everything gets,
you know,
governance.
Yeah.
Maybe too much.
Maybe we should just appreciate that you
can do that.
I know.
I mean I want to be able to build
whatever I want to build.
Right.
you know,
if I want that in production,
ought to be able to produce whatever
they want.
I agree.
But I feel like I feel at the same way I
feel about guns,
like I'm very pro second amendment.
I feel like,
uh,
I am a responsible gun owner.
I have a lot of friends that are
responsible gun owners.
I've used guns for hunting.
I think you should have a gun for
protection.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with that,
but I don't think it would be a bad idea
to have some sort of course that you
have to go through.
So you understand all the aspects of
safety and precautions that you should
take and how to correctly loaded gUn and
clean and gun.
AbSolutely.
Yeah,
but this is not really the case right
now,
you know,
and it's not necessarily.
I'm not talking about gun control as
much as I'm talking about gun safety and
gun responsibility.
I feel like the same way about a car.
Yeah.
I feel like if you're going to go out
and buy a corvette z r one,
I mean the kind of body mashing
acceleration that g forces you can get
from something like that right from the
factory,
zero to 60 in under three seconds.
That's an insane automobile.
Like maybe someone should like take you
around a track a little bit and that's a
great idea.
I guess that would be the case if you
were going to buy something like that or
getting a car like that,
you would need some kind of a trainer
course.
They had to pass her three hours on a
track.
If you're.
If you have to have particular licensed
to drive 18 wheelers down the
interstate,
you know there should be a style or a
type of license that you need to achieve
to have a certain type of,
you know,
you want to go buy a viper acr and take
it on the road.
Those crazy race car vipers.
You could juSt drive.
She'd probably know how to drive hyper.
Yeah.
Those things are a little bit a handful.
They're a little too happy.
They're pre dealer.
They're so crazy too that the race car
one with all the vents and all the arrow
all around it.
That was just an insane thing that you
can just go buy that and take that on
the road.
No.
Yeah,
the giant as v 10 in it.
It's pretty crazy.
It's awesome.
Yeah.
Do you.
So do you drive like fast cars on the
road ever,
or do you?
Mostly are you just like,
just mostly driving normal relaxed on
the road.
So I,
um,
I got a lot of speeding tickets when I
was younger.
Uh,
that was a shocker.
Yeah.
And I,
and it seemed like it would just never
failed.
Anytime I got behind the wheel of a
corvette or anything like that,
I'll be getting pulled over for rolling
through.
Lights are rolling through a stop sign
or reckless driving or whatever.
And I kept,
I mean,
it happened as recently as two or three
years ago.
I got pulled over for a rolling through
a stop sign and speed and uh,
and the guy's like,
man,
you don't need these tickets,
like,
what are you doing?
And I was like,
you're right.
I don't know what the hell I'm doing.
I don't need to be driving this damn car
is what's up.
I need to get out of stupid car.
I don't need to a corvette with all this
power.
And so,
uh,
and I've,
I've got this original,
um,
I got this original,
a 65 impala that's been in my family
since it was brand new and it's kind of
been the community car.
It was passed around and got banged up
on the corner corner,
right front corner,
couple of crashes here,
a couple of crisis area.
You just gotta needed a car because his
broke down so that he used it for awhile
and such.
And it was just pat and I finally got
it.
I bought it for two grand from my dad
and I've fixed it up.
It's got a two barrel to 83.
Wow.
It doesn't go anywhere,
right.
And I just as much rather drive that car
is a little low powers it has.
Um,
no,
and I won't get myself into any stupid
trouble,
you know,
being in a hurry or being impatient.
And so that's,
you know,
that's,
that's what I,
that's what I try to do.
I actually,
I don't care about as much what kind of
power the car has as much.
I like a driver,
I want to,
I like nice cars.
I liked know,
frame off restorations,
but I'd rather have a driver that's
reliable and easy to work on and I think
that's why I liked that 48 pickup truck.
It's got the vortec motor,
which is just a,
you know,
it's,
it's not a powerhouse is just dropped in
and out of a job out of,
out of a junkyard crash and it's a,
it's easy to work on,
like a me and a buddy of mine put
electric wiper motor in it the other day
because it had the little vacuum on it
and it just didn't,
didn't work.
And uh,
and it's easy to.
It's easy to work on.
I put,
we put these seats in it and we put a,
we got old ammo box for a console and
shit like that.
Do you just enjoy,
because it's also,
it's,
it's something that's sort of related to
what you do for a living,
but then again,
not in kind of just a project.
Automobile.
Yeah.
Um,
I uh,
I think the reason why I like to work on
cars is because it,
I don't know,
that makes you a,
it puts,
it,
makes you a little invested in the car
and there was a,
there was a pin,
there was a point of time where I was
just kinda like,
that's cool,
I want to buy that,
I'll get that,
I'll drive that a year now.
I don't like that anymore.
Well that's cool.
I want to buy that.
I'll get rid of this one,
get this one.
And that got old real fast for me.
And so I started to,
that's when I stopped.
That's when I put a little more time in
that 65 and palette and fixed it up.
And,
and I'm like,
that's,
I've never let,
I've never seen that car.
Never gonna sell it.
I'm that 48 truck.
I'll never sell it just because of the
work I put into the,
you know,
the time,
the time that I've spent with it.
Um,
I've had,
I mean,
you know,
and I,
I've got,
there's people that are helping me work
on these cars.
I got a buddy of mine that,
that actually helps me work on these
cars,
but um,
when I finished that novel wagon,
I'll probably never sell it even though
it's probably nothing special if someone
else were to look at it,
but it's what I,
you know,
it's what I put into it.
Yeah.
You've got sweat equity and the more you
work on these cars,
the more confidence you get and trying
to do more,
getting into the jobs that you didn't
think you were capable of doIng.
Have you ever thought about a buildup
straight from scratch?
That's probably this little a nova
wagons going to be.
Yeah.
I wanted a nomad.
so my dad had a nomad and uh,
it was uh,
this thing had polished aluminum on the,
on the underneath floor pan and mirror.
He parked it on a mirror in the shop so
you can look underneath it,
you know,
and look how good the damn thing was.
It was a boat.
It was frame off,
hardly ever seen the road.
I mean,
just clean as it could be from indian.
And I love road trips,
the nova wagon.
I mean,
uh,
the,
the nomad is the perfect road trip car,
but I,
I just don't want to spend the money on
a black on the nova.
I mean,
a nomad chassis and body is,
they're just ridiculous to buy and I
want to build the car.
I'm not a expert mater.
So this nova wagons,
perfect.
It's a wagon.
It's not a nomad,
but it's a little smaller,
which I liked and if I screw it up it's
okay.
If I screwed up a nomad build,
I'd be pissed.
Why are nomad so expensive?
I don't know.
They're just rare and it's like the,
you know,
it's like the old.
It's like the old 55 chevy wagon.
It's just put into my head what a nomad
looks like.
What year?
Like at 55.
Fifty six.
Fifty seven.
Pull up while you're 55.
Nomad.
Oh yeah.
Say that to me is my ultimate car.
Uh wow.
But damn man,
I mean they're just so high.
That's a beautiful car.
That's a different era.
You know,
when you look at the muscle cars of the
19 sixties and then you go to something
like this,
like that's a whole different world.
Yeah.
That's a different kind of thing.
I'd like to get.
Um,
there was this one nomad,
this guy chopped up and narrowed up and
they made a,
one of those things.
Um,
it's like a rat rod.
Yeah.
Um,
that was,
that was an idea for this nova wagon.
but I think I'm on.
I don't think I'm gonna chop it up and
then we'll keep it as it is.
When I was in high school,
there was a man in the neighborhood when
I was a kid that had a 55 chevy and it
was the greatest thing anybody has ever
seen in their lives.
And we would all wait while this guy
drove by and his 55 chevy,
we just couldn't believe it was a real
car that someone could own this.
It was black and meant it was a
beautiful car,
manual transmission.
He would dress drive by and that thing.
And we would all just have our jaws
hanging out.
When I was a little boy had hot wheels,
my favorite hot wheel was the 55
[inaudible],
55 chevy that had to flip hood diff.
The flames on the front.
It was like an original hot wheel.
And ever since then,
you know,
that's kinda,
that's kinda been my car.
But I went from the regular sedan to the
wagon.
I think that,
no,
that nomads pretty awesome.
Do you have like a full garage set up
where you can do repairs on things?
It's kind of a farm shop.
So it's,
it's dirty.
We fix lawnmowers,
we do some modeling on our cars.
Whatever needs to be done in there.
I parked my uh,
apart my bus in there,
I got a busted would take the racetrack.
And so,
I mean it's kind of kind of just a big
building.
We got a sandblaster in there,
we got a big ole,
we get a sheer in there.
We can do anything to manage vendor.
Yeah.
Whatever man shop.
Yes.
So tell me aboUt your book from you.
Well,
one of the things that was surprising
that I had heard was you,
your experience with concussions,
you know,
um,
tell me about that.
So when I've had concussIons in that
flip,
I was talking about 1998.
They tell him I got a concussion from
that crash.
Uh,
I'd had concussions throughout my career
at many different points and didn't
think anything of them.
I thought when you,
you know,
when you got a concussion,
you joked about it with your buddies
about how it made you feel and you just
rested until it was gone and you race
through it,
uh,
and eventually go away and you were
fine,
you know,
it was just something that would go
away.
And you never thought anything about
steve never thought about seeing a
doctor.
You never thought about getting
treatment.
You didn't know there was even treatment
available for concussion.
You just thought it was something like a
bruise.
You know?
So this is going on throughout my whole
career.
I was racing it.
I was testing at Kansas,
a motor speedway in 2012 blue right
front tire hit at 185 miles an hour and
it screwed me up.
And so that was a really not,
you know,
that wasn't a typical crash,
not something that drivers deal with
usually in their career.
This was something that was unique to
me,
uh,
and it was just a terrible impact at a
bad angle,
at a very,
very fast rate of speed.
And I got out of the car and I knew
something was wrong with me and I
couldn't,
I couldn't,
I felt,
you know,
just like I'd been hit in the head with
a bat,
a shocked and shell shocked in a way or
just couldn't.
I couldn't,
uh,
shake it off,
you know,
you just kind of wanted to shake your
head and get it out,
whatever it was and you couldn't.
Um,
that's why I failed immediately.
Immediately after that crash,
we went,
dark test was done because the car was
killed.
So we went over to this place to get
some lunch and we're sitting there and I
started getting sick,
nauseous before we ever,
you know,
wouldn't eat and uh,
we just ordered,
just sat down and I started,
I'm sitting with my team,
all my guys and I'm,
uh,
starting to,
I think phil,
I'm gonna throw up right there in front
of them and I'm getting nervous and I
don't,
haven't said to them that I feel this
way,
you know,
so I don't want to tell them I feel this
way,
but my crew chief evil,
it's like my,
like a brother.
Um,
I was like,
steve,
I am getting sick and something's wrong
with me.
I don't know what's wrong with me,
but I got to get out of this room is a
business lunch hour full of full of
people,
noises,
talk and chatter,
a shit going on.
And I got to get the hell out of there.
Um,
and as I was getting up to leave my wife
come walking in,
they were,
she was coming to get me.
We were going to Washington redskins
monday night game and uh,
sitting on a box with dance,
not or whoever else there.
So we had them plans to go.
I said,
amy,
I'm a good lay down in the car.
I just got to lay down in a car for a
minute and I laid down all the way in
the car all the way to the airport.
I'm thinking,
this is,
this is bad,
this is worse than I've ever failed
anything,
but hopefully it's going to go away.
And so we get the game we get.
We went and the redskins game,
we watched the game,
uh,
did that whole thing and I went about
four weeks of feeling bad and sick for
about four weeks and it finally went
away.
And I was,
I knew that was unusual for it to be
that long,
but in my mind I wasn't thinking doctor.
I wouldn't think in treatment.
I wasn't thinking anything like that.
It ain't cross my mind to tell anybody
or that I really needed.
I thought,
you know,
I thought that I had been dishonest and
not a,
you know,
I hadn't,
I hadn't been honest with everybody
about the way I was feeling,
but I didn't ever think that it was
going to cost me anything.
So I thought,
alright,
I'm feeling better.
I'm good.
Go to this race.
I've been racing the whole time.
Right?
Finally four weeks later I'm great.
I go to another race,
I'm racing,
I crashed and it all came right back,
like as bad as it was,
if not worse.
And that's when I said I gotta go to the
doctor.
This is bad.
I can't,
you know,
I can't even,
I can't keep crashing like this.
Just putting these concussions so close
together is a bad deal is dangerous and
my,
I couldn't bite my tongue,
like my attitude and my emotions and
shit was out of whack.
Like I couldn't control mY anger and I
was like,
anybody would anybody say something I
didn't like?
I'm like,
you know,
I want to tell him to fuck off,
you know?
And that was just not like me.
I couLdn't,
I couldn't keep myself calm and uh,
everything that I heard like made me
angry.
It was the craziest thing.
Even people just talking about stuff
would just get under my skin.
I'm like,
er,
real impatient.
Um,
and there were some new symptoms.
But,
uh,
finally,
I went to the doctor and,
and uh,
got to,
I went to this neurosurgeon in
charlotte,
dr petit.
He's like,
I want you to meet this guy in
pittsburgh.
His name's mickey collins.
He works with the pittsburgh steelers
and the penguins.
And uh,
I'm like,
I,
I go up there and I'm thinking I'm going
to meet this guy that works,
works with the penguins and the steelers
and he sees,
know players,
but he's a,
he's a doctor that sees anybody and
everybody,
like there's kids in there,
you know,
they got hurt playing on the playground.
There's workers a con,
you know,
carpenters,
housewives,
everybody's in that damn waiting room to
see this man.
He sees about 25 people a day and um,
he's an expert on head injuries and he's
got,
you know,
he's just,
he's on the cutting edge of whatever the
hell the new shit is.
He knows and he's,
you know,
his team and his people are
investigating it.
And so there he fixed me.
So I go there and I'm like,
this is what happened.
This is how it happened.
I crashed,
I hid it.
I didn't tell anybody about it.
I was sick for four weeks.
I got better.
I crashed in this race and I feel sick
again.
And he was like,
well,
these are two different injuries of,
to two different parts of your brain.
The first injury you bruised this,
uh,
right front edge of your brain when you
hit the wall.
He said this,
the second crash,
you twisted the base of your brain and
injured some things in the back of your
brain and that's why you're having the
emotional and different things like
that.
So,
uh,
but we,
he went deeper into it than that.
He was like,
you know,
we did all these tests and um,
digital
tests and all kinds of stuff for,
for,
and I'd go back,
I mean,
we did this thing,
we went through the gamut for a whole
day of doing tests and then I went back
every week before I,
you know,
and in two weeks I was back racing again
as clear and uh,
so he,
he took an injury that I hid and took
four weeks to heal and healed it in two
weeks.
What did he do to him?
Um,
he gave me.
I never took any medication on this
particular issue.
He gave me a home exercises and eye
exercises.
There was a,
I had problems with focusing and making
my eyes work,
tracking in an object,
like a bird flying across the sky or
anything like that.
I couldn't,
my eyes couldn't stay on it.
If I looked at you,
um,
eyes would bounce off of you and they
just wouldn't stay,
you know,
if you said,
hey man,
I'm gonna,
take a picture and you held up a camera
and I tried to look at the lens and
smile.
My eyes would want to jump off of that
object they would want,
they didn't want to look at what I
wanted them to look at and track
anything going anywhere.
And this was the cause of that.
Um,
the,
the brain has the ocular stuff.
I mean,
you can have injury to that part of your
brain or you can have an injury to the
vestibular parts of your brain that,
that,
uh,
that may have,
like if you have bad balance then that
your ads in your balance work together.
And so if you have a vestibular issues
that can create ocular issues and um,
that can create that,
that can affect your anxiety and
depression and things like,
so all these,
you can have an injury to one part of
your brain that affects for other areas.
And so,
and we talk about that in the book.
Mickey comes into the book and I'm,
I'll talk,
you know,
I'll say this is what I was feeling.
This is what I did.
And mickey will come in behind me and
say this is the medical science behind
that.
And this was how we treated it and why.
But I would have an injury to one
singular area,
my brain,
but I would have four different symptoms
affecting for different parts of my
brain for different senses and um,
you know,
he would have to hone in on the one that
was broken and then know to fix it.
And when he started fixing it,
all the other ones would start
communicating together.
The brain would start working again.
Balance and visual and all those things
would start to work again.
And anxiety and all those things.
You begin to come back in tune.
No.
When you said he fixed it,
like what is he doing?
He.
Well,
so he gave me physical exercises to do.
I had some balance issues.
Basically if I was,
if I turned my head a or looked up and
down,
I would get dizzy and sick.
Like my stomach would turn if I turn my
head left it right.
If I looked up and down,
just sitting there,
like the best thing for me was to sit on
the couch and not move.
And so like literally not move and not
felt fine then.
But if I moved an inch man,
it was like my,
it'd make your stomach nauseous.
And so I did a lot of,
I did a lot of exercises that created a
ton of motion with my head.
I'm lifting heavy balls up and passing
them over my shoulder this way or that
way,
taking a ball and turning around and
heading this way,
taking the ball and turn around and
that,
just doing that for,
for hours and hours and hours.
And so I would train basically,
uh,
I was training myself to,
to balance again,
you know,
training my training,
my,
my body to balance itself again.
And in my,
if I couldn't see a horizon or a flat
surface,
uh,
I couldn't tell which way was up and
yeah,
it was so bad.
And um,
the visual stuff,
there was these,
uh,
I had a string with these balls on it
and I would hold the string on my nose
and hold it out here.
and I had to look at all those balls and
it would.
My,
my,
my eyes are focusing.
Just all it's doing is really just
making my eyes change.
Focus from one to the next to the next
and back onto the next,
next and back.
And there was this add chart on the wall
and it had all these letters and all
these numbers on it.
And I had to,
I had to look at that.
I chart and turned my head back and
forth this way.
But look at that.
I chart and count and count do from a to
z but backwards knew the alphabet.
So I'd have to look for the letters.
Where's the,
you know,
and go backwards or one,
one to 20,
you know,
all are you shaking your head too three
standing up and walking backwards and
walking forward.
And what is this doing to your mind?
Like how does,
how does this fix your mind?
What is the process?
You know,
I don't know what the real.
I don't know what it's the I've had the
problem with me was my vestibular
system.
So my ability to understand balance and
understand horizons.
And so I was putting my mind in a
perplex,
uh,
in a complex environment or making my
mind do complex things that you don't do
every day.
And it's just firing your brain.
It's kind of like stretching this
muscle,
you know,
it's like,
it's like they used to say when you
would get hurt to go into a dark room
and hide and er,
you know,
no,
no electronics,
no tv,
just sit in a dark room and wait and
what they're,
what they believe today is that exposure
is what helps pushing yourself into
these complex environments and doing
things that are really challenging for
yourself.
Even doing that,
if I put you in front of that,
I chart made you turn your head back and
forth and walk walking two steps
forward,
two steps back and doing it would be,
it'd been difficult for you.
Um,
uh,
so,
but for an injured person,
it's super difficult.
It has to be really challenging,
but it just sort of tunes to mind are
retrains the brain to do balance,
to balance it retrains the eyes to,
to track on objects and to lock on
objects and stay on them.
And what's crazy is,
it sounds like physical rehab,
what if you had a knee?
It is a physical.
Yes.
There's a lot of physical rehab to it.
Yeah,
there's a ton of it and don't think
about that when it comes to the mind
though,
I'm usually think of the mind is
something that needs to be healed with
medicine.
Yeah,
I agree.
um,
the probably 85 percent of the work that
I did was physical therapy doesn't
change your diet or anything like that
because they see inflammatory causing
foods or inflammation causing foods.
I did not.
I did not change our drank strictly
drank water.
I didn't drink anything other than water
and uh,
I incorporated and bananas and things
like that into my diet that I never ate
before it of potassium.
Yeah.
What would affect his potassium have on
just recovering?
I just hear that it's good for your
brain.
It's good for your brain is her.
Yeah,
I did not.
My doctor didn't say start eating this
stuff.
So it was just,
you know,
you got,
you get tidbits,
like when you go and get injured like
that,
you're going to get people texting you
and giving you the information here and
there and you kind of take what you
want.
And go and,
you know,
I don't know about that but um,
did you ever mess with cbd at all?
Cbd?
You don't know what that is?
No.
Interesting.
Um,
cbd is a non-psychoactive form of hemp.
Yeah.
And uh,
it's a radical inflammation fighter and
a lot of people that have some pretty
significant injuries to the brain.
A lot of fighters take it like right
after fights.
It used to be,
um,
it's still questionable federally.
Yeah.
Like they're trying to,
there's some pushes to try to make it
illegal just because of pharmaceutical
drug companies kind of putting pressure
on that doesn't do anything in terms of
like get you high or anything?
No,
I've actually inflammation.
I actually read a little bit about that.
I'm just a couple of weeks ago because
it controls anxiety and,
and,
and it's helped a lot of people with
that.
One of my biggest,
one of the problems that I faced just on
a,
on a regular everyday is,
is where my anxiety is like,
is that because of being famous?
I don't know.
I think it comes from like your
childhood and just things that you
experienced in life and what are you
anxious about?
Just general social situations?
Yeah.
I mean I,
I would avoid.
I would,
I've gotten a lot better.
Like I go,
I can't,
I,
I would avoid concerts.
Even if I love the band,
I would,
uh,
just because there's too manY people
there,
but there's a ton of people that are
going to bother you.
No,
no.
Um,
I don't think So.
And I like being bothered.
I don't mind people coming up to me and
saying,
man,
that's cool.
I know who you are.
I mean that shit's feels great.
But it was more about like,
am I going to be accepted it?
My
scene is.
I don't know,
man.
I just always had a lot of anxiety over.
Okay.
So anxiety about whether or not you're
going to fit in,
fit in?
Yeah.
Okay.
So you felt like an hour
when you're younger.
Yeah.
so that anxiety,
I don't know,
I still feel,
um,
I,
I don't,
you know,
so that shit goes away hard,
takes a long time for that to go away.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Like my wife,
um,
she uh,
likes ashwagandha.
You ever heard the officer brown?
Yes.
Yeah.
So she,
she likes that and I take that every
once in a while and I think that shit
works pretty good.
It kind of keeps you calm and.
Yeah.
So,
but I've never tried the.
I've read about when I was reading about
ashwagandha is when I read about that
stuff you're talking about.
I'll get you some.
It'll help cbds.
Amazing.
And you know,
it's really good.
There's some muscle balms that work
really good on sore joints and stuff.
I mean,
but like nothing I've ever used before.
Better than anything.
Cbd just gets right into the muscles and
just relaxes all the inflammation.
And the best part about it is it's 100
percent natural and no side effects.
There's nothing right?
But in terms of like,
there's a bunch of different cbd oils
you can take,
they chill you out,
but they don't get you high or anything.
You're not weirded out.
But they just just calm me down and I
wonder how much that calming down is
because of inflammation.
Just reducing inflammation and just.
It just,
it seems to.
Your body has a,
your body knows what to do with it.
everybody's like,
oh,
I know what this is.
Is good.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean I got ted nugent into it.
Really?
Man,
ted nugent.
Before he came down here,
he was Telling me how he's anti
marijuana and this and that,
and we had this conversation about it
but makes people lazy.
I'm like,
I don't think it does,
man.
I think people are just lazy.
And I told him because I knoW he's got
some serious knee problems,
had all these knee surgeries.
He's,
you know,
he's a madman.
He used to jump off the top of the
fucking stage and land on the ground and
blues meniscus out.
I got them on the cbd bomb now.
No,
he texted me the other day.
So there's not a thing I've ever used to
telling me like this before.
Really?
Yeah.
So now I'm having cases sent to them
like every week night.
Yeah.
He loves the shit.
I mean,
he's,
he wants to endorse it,
which is hilarious.
Like the motor city madman,
ted nugent,
super anti marijuana,
wants to enjoy an endorser,
a cannabis product that's helped us.
Yeah.
But it doesn't do anything to you
psychologically.
It doesn't affect me.
Do you know,
calm me down.
yeah,
that's what I read about.
It doesn't have that part of the
part of the drug that's my friend's son
has.
It's a type of epilepsy brendan shop.
And he started giving his kid cbd oil
and it stopped the epilepsy and the
tracks.
Yeah.
I think I read where they are.
Um,
it's been used for that for years.
Yes,
yes.
Yeah,
yeah.
To hail,
uh,
for um,
god seizures and stuff.
Yeah.
For seizures.
It's just a radical inflammation
decrease.
Just figures out a way it does as some
sort of interaction with your body,
which reduces inflammaTion.
But it's like I said,
it also calms people down,
alleviates anxiety,
and no side effects.
That's the most important one.
Some people,
it gives them a weird stomach.
They don't like the way,
but I think they'll probably take it too
much or maybe it's expired or something
like that.
YeAh.
I've never had those issues.
But I'll get you something to look into
that too.
Right?
Yeah.
So what else did they do with you?
Did you do any cryotherapy or anything
like that that also would reduce
information?
No,
no.
Basically I went and um,
in this,
in 2012 we did basic basic,
uh,
physical therapy and I therapy,
I eye tests and different eye exercises.
Um,
and in two weeks I was back in the race
car raced for,
that was in 2012.
I raced all the way to 2016 to weeks.
You felt 100 percent.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
So With all these crazy exercises you're
doing,
when did you feel like it had settled
in?
Like,
wow,
this is really working?
Uh,
pretty.
I mean,
and if it was a two week period it
wouldn't,
you know,
it was a day or two,
I guess,
you know what I mean?
I can't even remember.
I can't remember that far back a day or
two.
Yeah.
I mean,
I imagine it was feeling pretty good
after a couple of days.
I'd have to.
I don't know.
I mean,
I don't know if that affected me right
away or,
but I know I was by the time we have,
I take an impact test,
which is basic kind of measures,
memory and Things like that,
all kinds of different stuff.
And my,
um,
measurements had come back to my norm,
you know,
my basic,
uh,
you're,
you know,
they kind of make you take the impact
test beforehand so that gets your
blueprint of how you are and uh,
and then whenever you get injured you
take it again and they align that up
against,
against that and say,
okay,
yeah,
you're deficient here.
This is a problem.
Maybe it's not diagnosing a concussion,
but it wants it.
It's asking us to look in this area.
And um,
so you have a baseline and then you have
whatever post,
you know,
your injury or post crash a baseline is.
Um,
so I was matching all my normals on that
impact test and that was kind of the
trigger for them to go,
man,
if you feel good,
you look good here.
All the thIngs are saying that your
back,
you know,
and uh,
I wanted to go race.
So I felt pretty good.
Is it a strange feeling knowing that you
can't see what the damages,
like a brain injury is a strange one,
right?
Because it's affecting everything in
your body,
but you don't,
you don't see it.
Like if you have a broken arm,
you're looking at it,
you know,
it's in a cast that gets fixed,
you,
you're,
you're aware of it,
you're doing rehab on it,
you're looking at it while you're doing
it.
There's something about the brain where
it's all like you can kind of mind fuck
yourself and say,
hey,
I think I,
I'm okay.
So in the book I talk about these notes,
I started taking after that crash in
2012 when I would wreck after that I
would get sick and I wouldn't tell
anybody and so I started writing these
notes in my journal,
in my phone and from 2013 all the way to
2016 I had this long journal of crashes
and how I felt and I would crash on
sunday and I'd ride in the journal and
sunday night,
monday morning,
monday at lunch,
money at night,
you know,
every three times a day every day until
whenever I felt good,
which is usually either wednesday or
thursday of that week.
And I was writing these notes because I
couldn't tell if I was getting better
than the brain injury or any type of
head injury.
I mean if you said how's it feel monday
and then you asked me again tuesday,
I'd be.
I really don't fucking know man.
It just,
it's there.
I don't know if it's better,
I just feel bad.
And so I would try to write as detailed
as I could on a day,
on a monday.
And then try to write as detailed as I
could on tuesday and reread monday and
see is this better?
I can see in the comments or you know,
I can't really remember exactly what I
was feeling monday,
but in the comments it seems better and
I would write these notes right.
And so I kept doing this and I thought I
was treating myself and eventually it
caught up with me like I had about a
dozen concussions in a period of about
two and a half years.
And I got to where I couldn't walk and I
called my owner and I was like,
man,
I need to talk to you.
I can't race this weekend.
I can't hardly walk.
And my balance is so bad that I can't
get up off the couch without holding on
to something and walking across the room
without grabbing stuff as I go.
And jesus,
he,
he was like,
we gotta go back to the doctor,
what are you doing?
He was mad.
He was lIke,
you know,
what do you fucking do?
And getting to the doctor,
why aren't you at the doctor?
And I was like,
you're right,
I need to go to a doctor.
I mean a concussed person doesn't have
good judgment and self awareness,
you know,
you're just,
you're just in a brick and you're in a.
It's like being hung over the worst
hangover,
you can't make decisions.
And so I went back to pittsburgh and saw
mickey again and I had to stay out the
entire whole half of the year in 2016 to
get better.
It took me five months to get,
well instead of two weeks.
Wow.
And that time I was on,
they put me on medication that will drop
my anxiety levels so the anxiety levels
would stay down so that I could
concentrate on the injury and what
medications I'm on.
I don't know exactly the names,
but um,
it was uh,
it was very,
very small doses and it would take about
three weeks for just kind of kick in.
I'd have to take it for awhile before it
started working.
But it just made me real chill and it
made me not analyzing myself every
single day when I got up,
when I got up,
I wouldn't go,
hmm,
is it still there?
Is it as bad as it was?
Let me walk across the room and see how
I feel.
Let me go do this and test this and trY
this and try this and try this all day
long and see how I feel.
It made me stop doing that because I was
driving myself crazy.
And um,
he gave me a lot more physical therapy,
basketball movements,
anything that got my head moving.
Um,
I do those exercises for about tWo
weeks.
Some of them would stop triggering
symptoms.
I'd go back to this place in pittsburgh,
we'd go through about 30 more exercises
and I'd take home about 15 that made the
symptoms trigger.
And I do them for about two,
three weeks and some of them would stop
working.
I'd go back to him,
we'd go through more physical exercises
to kept doing that process over and over
and over.
I took the medication for about a year
and a half.
Um,
and I had a lot of,
they gave me this,
a computer program for my eyes and I was
wearing these,
I would wear these three d glasses and
uh,
this computer program would try to take
these three d objects and go to two d
and three d and my eyes would literally
try.
It would've felt like it was trying to
rip my eyes apart.
It hurt,
like physically hurt when this object
would try to go from,
from a three d to two d and it was going
very,
very slowly and it felt like it was
trying to rip my eyes apart and imagine
your ads are tethered together.
So when you look left,
they both go there,
right?
And they both go wherever you look,
they go together like they're supposed
to.
And mine didn't want to do that.
Mine.
You couldn't physically see my eyes
towed out or going the wrong way.
You couldn't see that.
But when I try to look over here,
they both didn't go to the same place.
And that was that action or that,
that computer program was strengthening
that activity of my eyes,
trying to do something together and I
would walk.
So if I,
I've got these buffalo on my property
and they're across the field,
wait,
you know,
200,
300 yards out across the field,
out the back window of my living room.
And if I walked across the floor,
every step I took would knock my eyes
off of the buffalo,
like they're way out there and I could
look at them.
But if I took a step,
my eyes would shake and I couldn't,
I'd have to find them again,
you know.
And so that was,
that computer program would strengthen
my ability.
It's called gaze stabilization.
It would make it to where when I walk,
I don't know if I'm walking or bouncing
across the room,
um,
I could still look at you in the eyes
and,
you know,
like a normal person.
And if I,
when I was in my,
at my worst,
I couldn't do that.
And so,
uh,
but that took a long time to fix.
And,
uh,
the book basically is me admitting
making those mistakes.
Uh,
I should have went to him as soon as I
got sick again the first time instead of
trying to document it myself and,
and hide it and manage it myself and
trying to get to whatever the end of my
career was.
Whenever that moment was in retire,
thinking I was going to walk away
without anybody ever knowing.
Um,
and,
and I had to retire after that.
After that 2016,
you're missing half a season and going
through all that,
I didn't want to go through it again.
I had one more year on my contract in
2017,
so I'll finish that season.
And that was that.
Were you apprehensive while you're
finishing that sense?
Yeah,
I didn't want to get hurt.
I didn't want to go back through that
whole process again.
It goes through that rehab again.
I didn't want to get sick again.
Me and my wife just got married on new
years of 2016,
17.
So we're newlyweds were getting,
she's pregnant.
Uh,
we're going to have a baby.
Um,
you know,
I didn't want to go through any of that
stuff sick.
You know what I told my doctor you'll
like this since now we know each other
so well.
Um,
when I was ill in the hospital or when I
was with mickey in pittsburgh as my
wedding was a on new years and I was
probably around october or right.
No,
this was probably in august.
I said I need two things.
I was like,
I need to be able to,
uh,
go through my wedding on my wedding day
and my wedding night and that whole
experience.
I want to do it with a completely clear
headed and I want to be able to remember
everything.
I don't want to be on any drugs.
I don't want to have any symptoms.
I don't want to even be thinking about
my head.
Reminded about it and one in a moment
during that night,
I want my wedding to be perfect and I
want to be able to climb up in my deer
stand without feeling like I'm gonna
fall out of it.
And he said he'd fix it.
And I was hunting that I was hunting
that october or november
you,
um,
in,
in doing these exercises and then fixing
the issues that you were facing.
Were you,
were you concerned though about longterm
effects?
You know,
I wrote a absolutely over the last five
years.
It's,
it's,
it's been hard for me to turn,
turn mY back on articles,
um,
uh,
stories about nfl players and their
history and these guys,
you know,
the,
the whole lawsuit brought up so many
stories about what these guys have went
through,
what their families have went through.
It's been impossible not to read that
stuff and fear that is that,
you know,
is that something that's going to happen
to me?
Uh,
if I do,
I need to be worried about my,
you know,
a longterm health and what,
I,
I would,
it took me the longest time to watch
that concussion movie because I just
didn't want to know what he had to tell
me,
you know?
And I,
uh,
eventually I got to a place where I
thought I'm after.
I talked to mickey,
you know,
when I was in hurting 2016,
I said,
mickey,
why aren't you shutting me down?
Like he,
he shut down some player,
I don't know the guy's name,
I don't know who,
whether he was a hockey player,
a football player,
but guy was making millions of dollars
and he was in his mid twenties and
mickey had to say,
you can't play anymore and I want to
make you to tell me that I didn't want
to have to go out,
go out the room and say,
y'all,
I'm retired.
I don't want to do this anymore.
I want to say y'all.
Mickey said I got to retire.
I don't know,
but he wouldn't.
And he said,
you know,
you're not where that guy is and I don't
see what's going on.
I don't see anything going on with you
that tells me you can't race if you want
to race.
I said,
well,
what if I get hurt again?
He,
he's good.
He said,
if you get hurt again,
if I can fix it,
if you,
it's up to you.
If you want to go through that.
He said,
you're just as likely to get hurt as you
were before the injury.
You're going to race and racing and
racing is dangerous.
Uh,
you gotta make up your mind whether you
want to go out there and risk getting
hurt again and if you do I'll fix it,
can come right back here and we'll fix
it all over again and us like.
And I was like,
all right,
if you're not shutting me down then you
must not be worried about my longterm
health.
AnD he's like,
oh,
I'm not worried about your long term
hill.
There's nothing going on here that I see
that would make me concerned about your
longterm health.
And so with all that said,
I got married,
I had a little girl.
I'm sitting there on them days at home
with them and I'm thinking to myself,
what if I'm sitting here worried about
cte or my mind,
you know,
going away and it never happens.
You know,
am I gonna wait,
am I going to sit here and worry about
that at 44 all the way through my
fifties and sixties and seventies?
And then one day wake up at 80 and go,
damn,
I lived pretty good life.
Why did I worry about all that?
Um,
why didn't I enJoy what was in front of
me?
And so the other.
So I'm going to enjoy what's in front of
me,
not going to worry about cte,
not going to worry about my longterm
health.
And there's another thing too,
the,
the conversation about concussions is
really just skyrocketed into,
you know,
into warp speed over the last five or
six years.
And the,
the way they treated me in 2012 to the
way they treated me in 2016 was
completely 180 degrees because they know
so much more and they're so,
you know,
they understand so much more about
treating the injury.
And so if I do have any problems
whenever that is,
I'm confident that there'll be something
there for me that there'll be something
there to give me a good quality of life.
I've had a hell of a run.
I had a lot of fun.
I raised hell.
I partied,
I won,
I lost.
And if it all ended now,
I wouldn't be,
I wouldn't have missed out on anything
other than my wife and my little girl.
And so I'm content with where I'm
content with where I am.
All I want to be able to do is just,
you know,
be a good father and be a good husband.
And I think,
you know,
I think I'm going to have that
opportunity.
But if anything does happen to me,
I think that there'll be some,
some information,
some medicine,
something that would give me a good
enough quality of life that I would be
able to enjoy those things.
I think you made the wise choice in
retiring.
Oh yeah.
And I Think that I'm,
look,
I'm very familiar with head injuries.
I'm around people that have had them all
the time and I think it's um,
it's something that we are understanding
now more than ever before,
but someone like you writing a book
about this and your experience with it I
think is really important for people.
I think it's going to help a lot of
people.
It's gonna help a lot of people
understand it and the more we talk about
this more,
this gets out there in the public,
the more it helps just regular folks
that have had concussions.
Understand what a significant thing this
is.
Yeah.
This,
there's,
this book is to not discourage you from
doing what you want to do.
If you want to race,
race,
if you own a fight,
fight,
if you want to do whatever it is,
play football.
I'm not discouraging anybody from doing
that.
I'm encouraging you.
I'm just saying that when ever you are
hurt,
wherever you,
if you ever do find yourself with a
injury,
don't make the bad choices that I made.
That's really all I'm doing here is to,
uh,
share with people the mistakes that I
made.
I never would have known about mickey
had somebody not taking me to him.
I would've never even considered the
fact that there was treatment for head
injury had I not met mickey.
I mean,
there's people out there today that
don't know there's treatment that
they're living with these injuries are
veterans,
um,
that don't think that they can be
healed.
A,
there's people in my timeline all the
time saying,
man,
I'm glad you're talking about
concussions.
I had one and I'm dealing wiTh it all
the time.
Boy,
it's just nagging me every day,
and the truth is that you don't have to
even live that way.
There's better.
There's a better quality of life with
the information that they know today,
even if this injury was 10 years ago or
15 years ago.
There's stuff todaY that can help give
you a better quality of life.
And so that's what the book's about.
It'S an amazing time.
And when you think about the fact that
2012 you had an injury and they treat
you one way to thousand 16,
they had already advanced their
techniques and I'm sure they've advanced
even more now in 2018.
It's.
It's amazing.
Yeah,
and we're live.
We're living in this.
We're living in this big learning
experience right now.
Yeah,
I know.
They're starting to do some stuff with
stem cells as well and you know,
there's a guy named dr neil riordan that
I've had on the podcast before that he
did wonders for mel gibson's dad and so
mel gibson came on and went to talk
about this.
They have to do treatment and Panama
because they can't do a lot of the
treatments here in the United States
because they're not legal yet,
but the effects that they're having on
people that are,
they're bringing down to Panama,
it's just mind blowing,
you know,
and I'm hoping that's gonna also help
people with traumatic brain injuries and
cte and some other things as well.
Yeah.
I'm excited for them to find a way to,
um,
to take cte in living human being.
They already have figured out ways.
They've figured out a way to do that
now.
It's very,
very recently started to do that.
But you know,
it's a,
it's a major concern obviously for
fighters,
but I would imagine that someone in your
line of work,
it's not thought about the same way.
Look,
if people think About it with football,
they don't think about in terms of they
don't directly associate boxing with
head injury.
They don't directly associate race card
now.
Yeah.
And,
and I'm,
I'm hopeful that there aren't a lot of
drivers that have experienced what I've
experienced and crash the way I've
crashed and there there's drivers that
will raise their lives without it,
you know,
uh,
without ever having that experience.
And I'm glad for that.
But for the guys that have,
I've got,
I've had veterans retired guys call me,
say,
man,
I've,
I've given him my doctor's number to so
many damn people ever since I've,
I've spoken up about this in 2012 to now
and this book a mickey says there's,
there's at least three people a week
that come in his office talking about me
and that's why they're there.
And so that's the whole mission,
man,
is because mickeY gave me my life back
twice.
I'm telling you man,
at 16 I was in bad shape and I was,
I was without what?
Without my wife and without mickey.
I don't know,
that automated it out till the end.
And this book or anything else and this
podcast,
anything,
any ever,
any opportunity to talk about this is
only to push more people to mickey,
uh,
so that he can do the same thing for
them.
He did for me.
That's amazing.
Um,
there's a guy named Dr.
Mark Gordon that's also been on this
podcast before that it does a lot of
work with tbi and soldiers and football
players and stuff like that.
So there's,
there's a lot of other doctors out there
that are specializing in this.
We realize that this is a significant
issue.
Just so happy that those people are out.
Yeah,
well they're getting some good,
you know,
they're getting some opportunities to
actually,
you know,
get up,
get up there and speak up about it and
make it known.
And I know there's got the mic,
I have mickey,
there's a bunch of makers out there and
there,
you know,
and there's a lot getting learned right
now.
Well there's just so many people that
are silently suffering that don't want
to open their mouth because they don't
want to appear weak.
Well that'S part of it too.
Yeah,
a lot.
A lot of people don't want to.
There's people,
there's some people that just don't know
where to go,
you know,
I don't think that they can afford it or
don't think that they're going to get
that out.
You know,
like when I,
when I first went to mickey I thought I
was going to go in there and see just
steelers in nhl players.
Right.
That's how ignorant I was about it.
And you know,
he sees every man.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
Now do you,
me being a race car driver is such a
wild,
exciting,
powerful way to make a living.
Do you ever get the itch now?
Yeah,
sure.
I,
um,
I ran a race and uh,
about a month or a month,
two months ago at richmond,
Virginia and it's a,
uh,
we haven't finity level.
We haven't extended the series that's
sponsored by xfinity and basically our
college
level,
they race on saturdays before the big
show on sunday at the same track and
it's a,
uh,
abbreviated race.
Um,
and I got a couple on a couple of cars
that race in that every week.
And so I ran in a race at richmond to
scratch the itch a little bit and had a
blast.
We ran great lead a lot of laps,
had fun competItion,
everything we wanted to accomplish.
Um,
I'll probably run one more next year at
another track and probably do that every
year until I just don't feel like doing
it anymore.
Just for fun.
Yeah,
just for fun.
But no more than that.
And I never go back to the cup series,
the six.
So the cups that people talk about it
like,
man,
you can just go back.
It's like you can't just go back.
it's like,
it'd be like,
um,
when it,
it'd be like one of the fIghters,
you know,
just taking a couple of years off and
then jumping back in for the
championship match,
you know,
you,
you just,
it's too elite.
You know what I'm saying?
Well,
that's just happened.
Conor mcgregor just came back after two
years off and fought khabIb normal.
So it's good point.
Yeah.
I mean he probably would've lost anyway
to be.
Yeah.
It could be just a monster.
But who knows,
he might not have.
If I would go back,
I wouldn't,
it would take me six months just to get
up to speed,
not even really even get competitive,
just to get up to speed physically and,
and mentally bring yourself to your
agent and it ain't something you just
get out of and go back in.
I mean,
the people on the outside looking like,
wow,
you steering,
you're just shifting.
Yeah,
it's a big deal.
Yeah.
Hit the gas.
Go.
It's such a man.
If you take a week off,
you just get so behInd.
What is it that you get behind what?
Um.
Well,
there are.
So our sport,
we were,
I was telling him about this with a
friend today and he made a good point.
He said there was a guy that he says our
sport is the only one where the,
where the ball is governed and the
bottle is inspected,
like the race car,
the car,
right.
The physical card itself.
Uh,
so technology is one of the things that
is like what's fast today will be
obsolete and slow six months from now.
You wouldn't even think about running it
and six months really?
Yeah.
Wow.
Um,
yeah,
I mean it's,
it's,
it's constantly evolving and somebody
next door,
the guy next to you and the guy next to
him and the guy next town's always
constantly trying to build a better
mouse trap and,
and everybody's in what's new and bad
ass today is going to be okay and not
very good six months from now and
they're constantly,
uh,
so the teams are constantly working and
if you're not in those cars and current
and in that flow,
in that changing,
in that cycle,
in that we'll um,
then you can't,
you're,
you're behind.
Like when you geT in the car and you get
around a team,
like you're behind on,
on what's,
what,
what's in the car,
what's happening with the car.
And I don't know,
it's just not something you just jump in
and out of cars.
You're not the,
you're not really the,
the key component like your body is,
your body is a fighter,
you know your body and your body is the
tool.
I'm a football player,
same thing,
quarterback his arms,
the tool right in racing.
It's the car.
And so if you're not in it and around
it,
every day,
you will be behind
on technology,
understanding what's happening and what
teams are doing,
what you're,
what you need to be doing.
The damn dash is full of switches with
all kinds of shit going on.
And this needs to be on.
This needs to be off and this needs to
be back on and off and own.
And there's a levers,
there's brake levers,
some drivers have for fucking brake
levers,
or you can shut off the left front,
the right rear,
the right front,
you can put all the breaks from the back
to the front,
from the back,
from the left of the right.
I mean,
that's just the breaks and yeah,
I mean there's just so many.
There's,
there's just a lot going on
that it would take you awhile to get
back up to speed if you were to take
some time off.
It's not,
it's just not as easy as it used to be.
I had no idea there were that many
options.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
I mean,
you could have as many as you own or as
little as you want.
Some guys really think that that stuff's
a good tool for them to be able to
adjust the brakes and change how the
brakes work on all four corners of the
car and some of them do,
they move them during the race while
they're racing,
you know,
they're changing them,
fooling with them,
you know,
in an indy car,
you can adjust the roll bars and all the
wings and all that stuff and you know,
in those cars and stuff like that.
So I mean there's a race car driver,
there's,
there's a ton
of stuff going on in that car that
people don't even know about.
yeah.
So.
So it would just take you a while to get
all that stuff.
Automatic mind.
Yeah.
I would get into,
I would get in the car and forget about
those tools and forget that I had those
adjustments and knowledge and be getting
beat by guys that are using it everyday.
Now.
How,
what,
how much time are you in a car in a
race?
three hours.
Probably three and a half hours.
Do you do anything or do you,
do you take anything to keep you
concentrating at your full potential
during that time?
Vitamins or.
I never did.
I just mixed water and orange gatorade.
I'm your electrolytes.
Yeah.
50 slash 50.
Uh,
jimmy johnson,
several of those guys do energy,
choose different things.
A lot of gatorade oriented stuff.
Gatorade's a sponsor for jimmy,
so he's going to have the gatorade chews
or whatever.
You must be sweating like a pig in those
things,
right?
You sweat a ton.
As you lose,
you lose anywhere from six to eight
pounds race.
Um,
it's all just water weight and he just
put it right back on in a day or two.
Is it really hot in the car?
Is that what it is?
Yeah.
So.
And I'm in
chicago this year.
It was a hundred and 50 degrees in the
car.
Whoa.
So it's a sauna?
Yeah,
we had a template.
We had these temperature gauges in the
car,
so we're seeing them on from the
broadcast booth.
We can see you're in the,
in car camera.
It'll be pointed at a temperature gauge
and all of the guys cars were 150
degrees inside all the drivers and it
was miserable.
That's insane.
So is there any fear of people blacking
out from,
you know,
that's something that I've always kind
been concerned with.
I think that we don't have that concern
today,
but it is coming and we need to like if
we had 150 degree incar temperatures,
I think that we need to think about how
to try not to have that,
you know,
try to do something to where man,
is that really necessary that we put the
drivers through that.
Is it because the engines in front of
you as you're driving the heat from the
engine just blows in danvers compartment
that in the brakes,
everything.
The breaks spring,
the breaks are going to be a thousand
degrees on,
on the calipers and that heat radiating
into the car.
The drivers can open up these knack,
naca ducks,
uh,
to,
to allow air into the car.
But that,
that's going down.
Well,
yeah,
it's going to slow you down.
It's going to hurt the performance of
the car and so,
um,
the drivers try to trim the cars out so
much that there's not a lot of air
moving around in the car and it's so low
to the ground,
there's no air moving around under the
car either.
So that air under the cars just got a
baking in there and just sitting in
there.
Um,
so they're miserable.
They're miserable,
miserable,
miserable car.
That's when I watched races and I'm
like,
you know,
I'd love to get out there and do that
for a few minutes,
but damn,
running three hours,
150 degree race car,
it's miserable.
It is the worst experience.
I can't imagine being in a sauna just
sitting there for three hours.
never mind driving her car around a
bunch of heavy focus on something.
Yeah,
everyone's going 200 miles an hour.
the worst part is when you slow down,
like the caution comes out cause that it
gets hotter.
Like it just when the car,
when the coach comes out and you have to
come in and change tires and you're
sitting there and you go about eight or
10 pace laps at 50 miles an hour,
you're just,
that's when you get to think about it,
you know,
that's when you're sitting there going,
damn,
this is hot while you're racing.
You're almost so hyperfocused on what
you're doing.
It can.
It kinda doesn't bother you as bad
distracts you.
Is there anything they can do to cool
you off with your suit?
Does your suit.
There's these new vests that we were
that has a jail in it and it's a you
plug into a little machine that pumps it
in so you unplug it to get out of the
car and those work really well.
Actually we use the usable in the last
year of my career and it was very
comfortable.
So there's some,
there's some innovative stuff out there.
They have a helmet,
a cooler,
a.
There's a hose that plugs in top of your
helmet and it blow some air in there.
It's a little bit cooler,
but it draws those two things,
draw much amps that the teams don't want
to use them.
The drivers want to use them,
but the crew chiefs don't want you to
draw on that many amps off the rate off
the alternator.
They want to use amps for other things
that are gonna.
Make the car go faster.
Yeah.
No,
make you comfortable.
That's why there's no ac.
Yeah,
I would imagine.
man.
Now when you think back of on doing all
that stuff that you did do and think
about those kinds of races and think
about all the endurance and all the
different aspects of it,
does it ever seem kind of crazy that you
did it?
Yeah.
Like that I,
that I raised.
Yeah.
I mean now that you're not racing,
like whoa,
what a wild way to make a living.
Yeah.
Like I can't believe it happened to me.
No shit.
Like,
um,
my dad was a sort of this
invincible.
He wrote and I wanted to do what he did.
I didn't think I was going to get to do
that.
When I started doing it,
I was thinking to myself,
I can't believe this is happening to me.
When I started to,
when I won a few races,
I never,
man,
I never.
So when I was in,
when I was 20 years old,
I wasn't thinking,
man,
don't be a champion.
I'm a win 20 races.
I'm a win 50 races.
I'm going to kick some ass.
I was thinking,
I sure would love to do this and pay my
bills.
I w I would love to do this just for a
living,
not have to work.
I'm changing oil.
It wasn't the best,
you know,
it wasn't where I wanted to be.
A workinG in a service department was
fun,
but damn,
I wanted to be a race car driver and so
when I made it,
I didn't really.
I wanted to win,
but damn,
I just want to be able to make money to
afford to do it for a living in him.
That's all I ever wanted.
So the winds,
they turn 500 words and all that shit
was a bonus and when I look back on it
now,
I'm like,
man,
I,
I was so lucky.
Holy cow.
Was I lucky to do what we did and do
what I did and when,
what I did and
very lucky.
Do you think you had such great success?
Not just because obviously your dad is
one of the greatest of all time,
but also because your love for it was
what propelled you.
It wasn't trying to seek fame or
fortune,
it just,
you just truly love racing.
And that's why you became so great at
it.
Yeah.
My dad's a,
the link to my father opened up a shit
ton of doors for me.
Opened up so many opportunities for me.
I'll even today,
um,
it made my path much easier than some
other fellows that I know.
Um,
but I think that my,
my passion for it and my,
uh,
yeah,
my love for it,
my love for its history,
my wanting for it to be healthy,
the sport,
uh,
all those things is what probably made
me make good decisions as I went along,
you know,
and when I would talk or get in a
position to make a comment or say
something,
I always tried to think about how that
would represent the sport.
Um,
I didn't understand what building a
brand meant until way too late in my
career.
Good.
Yeah.
Concentrating on that.
It's always a mess.
No,
I mean I wished I'd known a little bit
about trying to bring my brand and I
wouldn't have been such a hard ass and
hard to work with a lot of times like
there's been,
there were some sponsors I loved and I
did everything they wanted and there
were some that I just weren't,
I wasn't as good as I should have been,
you know,
I wasn't,
uh,
you know,
I have regrets,
but I'm just saying like I did as I was
going through this career.
I wasn't thinking about me,
me,
me.
I didn't even know how to build my own
brand.
I didn't know what that meant.
I waS thinking about a man that I love
this.
This is great.
I can't believe I get to do this.
I can't believe I'm here.
I can't believe I'm racing here racing
this person doing,
driving this car,
got this sponsor shit.
You knoW,
this,
everything.
Everything was the best of the best.
You know,
I had had great sponsors,
awesome,
awesome equipment.
Um,
everybody always nice,
you know.
hey,
how you doing?
Everybody's so nice.
My wife just hates that because
everywhere I go I'm like,
everybody's so nice.
How has this?
But they were so nice.
She goes,
everybody's nice to you.
You know,
she,
it so bent out of shape.
She get mad at that college.
She says she's,
I don't know,
she just says you're normal people.
We don't get everybody nice.
Yeah.
You live in a different world.
That is interesting.
Yeah.
He live in this world where everybody's
happened to me.
Like a hot chick.
Yeah.
Kinda.
Write me like you're a hot chick.
Yeah.
Where you go.
It's kind of similar,
I suppose.
I guess what the world's like.
Everywhere they go.
Everybody loves him.
Yeah.
People are super,
super excited to see him.
Yeah.
They know there's danger out there and
some of these men,
but everybody's very friendly to the
right.
Yeah,
very similar,
but a large lady with the unfortunate
looks so has a different view of that.
Yes.
Yeah.
Um,
how much did you learn about racing from
your dad?
Hardly nothing,
man.
I mean we uh,
obligate asked all the time what your
dad taught you about x,
y and z and we never talked about race
and I'm really never.
Wow.
Yeah.
We never talked about reason mind you
started racing professionally?
Yeah.
Wow.
Yeah,
we never did.
Um,
he was always a don't,
you know,
finished.
He was so worried that me and kelly
wouldn't finish school that we would
give up on school.
He gave up on school is an eighth grader
at 16 years old when he was 16 in eighth
grade and quit and never finished high
school.
Never got no ged,
nothing.
And people would come to him and say,
are people would talk about him,
um,
even while he was alive and ever since.
And uh,
say,
look what this guy made of himself
having quit the eighth grade.
That's awesome.
And he always hated that.
That was embarrassing,
uh,
for people to,
you know,
he was embarrassed that he quit.
He knoWed how bad it disappointed his
own father.
So he was always like worried about
where I was,
who I was hanging out with,
were there,
I was doing my homework.
And then even when I started racing,
it was who I was hanging out with,
what I was doing with my free time,
what I was focusing on,
whether I was,
you know,
thinking about,
what I was,
whether I was on time for sponsor
appearances and never is it drive this
corner.
This is,
I get around this racetrack.
He never talked about this stuff.
It was always the person not being a
man,
being bright,
being good to people,
being on time,
being ready to work,
a looking your best.
Um,
general,
you know,
morals and values.
He didn't,
we never sit down and talked about
racing like I'm going to show you how to
get around this corner and this is how
you shift and shit like that.
Well,
in that respect it was probably
brilliant of them because look,
the championships came and you also
turned out to be a great man.
Thanks.
I appreciate you saying that.
I uh,
I don't know.
I always felt like that when I was
younger I kind of let my father down
because there was this one time I was
probably 12 years old and there was
this,
me and my buddy,
we were going to play,
man,
we're here.
We're outside.
We're going to play outside.
My dad's standing over there and there
was a bucket full of shit and he's like,
hey,
come here.
And pope junior pick that bucket up,
move it over here.
And I went over there and tried to pick
it up and I was like,
I can't lift it.
And he got so pissed off at me because
they knew I didn't try.
And he got,
he said to my buddy ryan,
he was ryan,
come here,
pick the bucket up and take it over
there.
And he turned around and gave me this
look of pure fricking disappointment.
And I felt like that set the tone for
our relationship.
Wow.
For one bucket.
I know,
I feel like that that was the,
uh,
that was our relationship in a nutshell
for most of my teenage years.
You know,
he looked at me as,
you know,
I don't know what he's going to mount
to.
I don't know what this gives you to do.
I don't know what,
what,
you know,
what skills he has or what is it you
don't ever get his act together or
whether he's ever going to figure
himself out,
you know.
And I probably didn't give him much
reason to think different.
Um,
but then when we got,
when I started racing,
um,
when I started racing late models,
I ran 159 races and he never came to one
a through 94,
95,
96,
97.
I raced at myrtle beach,
South Carolina every weekend and he
never once came down there to watch me
and so he didn't know whether I was a
good race car driver or a bad race car
driver.
He didn't know whether I was,
you know,
working on my car or understanding how
they,
you know,
what,
how,
how to build the car,
fix the car.
And when I would do good I'd come home
and I'd have a trophy and I'd say,
hey man,
I want.
And he'd go,
well,
who wasn't there?
And I'm like,
shit.
He really did the first.
I remember coming home With the trophy
and I could not wait until he,
he would walk.
I kept my car in this,
uh,
in this building that was his.
And he put all his deer head up there
and call it a deer hit shop.
I'm talking 35,
40 minutes in this place,
a couple of elk.
And uh,
he'd come in here every monday morning
before lunch.
And I had that trophy sitting up.
We'd brought it home and it was right in
view.
Soon as he walks in,
I got the car working on my car and he
comes in there and I'm like,
I'm like,
he's like,
so you want,
huh?
He's a trophy.
I was like,
yeah,
we did.
And he's like such and such,
must have not been there because there
was this one guy and then robert,
pat used to beat us all the time and he
goes,
robert bus not been there.
I was like,
no,
he wasn't,
he wasn't there.
I was so pissed off,
man.
I finally won a damn race.
I thought that he was going to come in
there and slap me on the back and man,
when,
you know,
give me an,
give me a good talk and give you more
motivation that he didn't do that.
I don't think so.
I don't think it did.
I think it made me want to.
It did not make me want to win more.
Um,
but then one day,
so right around the end of 1997,
I was out of money.
He was like,
hey,
you know,
you're out of money and race.
I was like,
shit,
my life is coming to an end.
As far as I know it.
I'm not going to,
I guess my racing career,
this is,
it is.
It's coming to an end in 1997.
Um,
he was sitting down and talking to a.
He had a car that races in the xfinity
series that I told you about on
saturdays and he,
his driver was leaving to go to a cup
car and he was talking to his best
friend.
Tony senior is the guy's name that
actually crew chiefs that car.
And he's like,
who we're going to get to drive this
thing.
Who should we get?
We got to hire a driver.
And tommy senior said,
why don't you put dale junior and there
he goes,
what are you serious?
You really think so?
He's like,
you're going to spend a little money on
this car.
why don't you spend it on your own kid?
You know,
why don't you just put may,
I can,
I can probably make a driver out of him.
Tony senior says so and so.
They made the decision to put me in this
car,
in the xfinity series.
You'd think that dad would come tell me
or we would have press conference.
Not be a press release.
At least I walked into.
This is the month before the season
starts.
I think I'm out of or I think I'm out of
racing.
Right?
I ain't been,
I ain't even talked to anybody about
what I'm racing or if I'm racing in a
couple months.
I think that it's dried up.
Opportunities are gone.
I'll walk into the shop to get something
where tony and seniors car tony seniors
race car was and my name was on the roof
and I was like,
I thought it was a joke,
like a mean joke or a prank.
And they were laughing tony senior and,
and uh,
some of the guys in shop laughing and
I'm like,
man,
that's messed up man.
Y'all are dicks for putting that name on
there to say no.
It's funny in there.
And they were like,
it's true,
man.
I was like,
you mean I'm a race car?
I'm racing this car.
And they were like,
yeah.
I was like,
really?
And uh,
I mean obviously I was thrilled,
like,
man,
I couldn't believe it,
but this is the way I found out,
not from my own dad.
And I'm like,
dad,
I'm racing the car.
Yep.
I mean like days later when I see him,
I'm like,
so I'm going to race the car.
And he's like,
yep,
sure.
Birgit get ready and said yeah.
And I mean it waS,
it.
He was the strangest dude when it came.
He didn't,
he didn't really.
But once,
so I started racing that car and I had
had great success.
We won six or seven races the first year
we won another six or seven races the
second year of championships in both
seasons.
So,
I mean,
the choice to put me in that car worked
out better than he probably ever
imagined,
ever in 159 and late model races that I
ran from 94 to 97 and one slash four in
159 late model races I won for.
So he put me in this car on a whim and a
prayer and we ended up winning the
championship two in a row.
So he is thinking,
damn,
this little shit can drive a car.
And that's when our relationship
completely changed.
That's when I hit his arm around me.
We were doing shit together.
We were doing,
we were doing,
we had sponsored deals and promotions
together.
We were doing photo shoots together.
I saw him all the time and we talked
about all kinds of,
you know,
we talked about life girls and,
and everything,
but racing,
you know,
we didn't talk about race in much but
just fine.
But um,
it was awesome.
And so not eight 99 and in 2000 I went
to cup.
He,
he,
he built a team around me.
We had budweiser come in for $10,000,000
a year,
which was the biggest sponsorship
anybody had and at that time,
um,
and uh,
so.
And then he got killed in 2000.
One and two.
Started the season in daytona 500.
So those three years,
98,
99,
2000 were as good as it could get.
Wow.
Yeah.
That must have been amazing.
It must have been amazing for you to
turn that corner.
Yeah.
It was like a light switch he went from.
He went from not really engaging with
me.
Me not a comfortable around him feeling
ashamed.
I'm not.
May not measuring up.
He's because he's 10 foot tall,
cowboy boots,
black hat,
tougher and shit.
Not gonna.
Intimidate her.
That was his nickname and I was blonde.
Pale short as hell.
Not a muscle on me and had accomplished
nothing,
you know?
And so it.
But it overnight.
It was like completely changed when we
started running great and people were
coming up to me,
I'm like,
dude,
you're freaking.
You're doing awesome.
And you know,
and he's.
And he was a.
He was really happy with that.
He was pretty proud.
It's crazy that he never talked to you
about race.
No.
That's just so strange.
Him.
I can't imagine that was one.
It was only one time that he did that.
We were at a track called bristol,
Tennessee.
We were,
we were at a track in bristol,
Tennessee,
uh,
it's a half mile high banked racetrack
and we run 15 second laps around there.
It's really fast and it's,
it's kind of technical and tough to get
around.
Um,
and I had been raised.
I'm out there practicing and I wasn't,
I wasn't doing it right.
And he got up on the uh,
he got up on one of the haulers and got
on the radio and started talking to me
and he was like,
hey man,
I'm going to tell you how to drive it.
And so this one day,
one time in this one practice for about
five minutes,
he's like,
I'm gonna tell you how to drive his
track.
So I'm out there driving and um,
when he's like lift right here and I
lift and he getting the gas,
okay,
I'm turning the area and he's just
telling me how to drive the track.
And that was the only time he ever did
that to just think of how much it would
improve.
I know it really helped me there that
day.
I mean like his,
like when he told me how to do it,
I'm like,
holy shit,
this is what I would have never thought
of doing it this way and this is way
better.
So yeah,
maybe you could have given me a few more
tips on some things.
I mean,
come on man.
That's how that has to be so crazy
because that's your profession or your
dad is a superhero.
Well,
I think that I finally made it a cup and
I think had he lived,
he would have been in my ear all those
years,
you know,
do this,
don't do this.
This is the best decision today.
So maybe he just didn't,
wasn't in a hurry to do it because he
didn't know that he wasn't going to be
around for it,
you know,
how hard was it to race after he was
gone?
I thought about whether I should quit or
not.
Um,
you know,
I probably,
if it hadn't paid a lot of money and I
didn't have partners and people that
were depending on me are counting on me,
I probably could have easily walked away
from it.
But we had a great partner in budweiser
that was incredibly supportive.
Um,
I had a lucrative opportunity in front
of me personally to be a be a race car
driver for as long as I wanted to,
which I wanted and I just had to go
through missing him really bad for a few
months.
You know,
I had to,
I had to go to the race track and
everywhere I looked,
you know,
there's dad,
there were fans morning,
uh,
there were signs and paintings and
things,
you know,
there was just markings and
acknowledgements and just shit
everywhere for like a year.
Uh,
and I appreciated it.
I knew why it was like that.
Um,
but it took awhile for me to sort of get
to where I didn't.
Um,
I was,
I went,
there was a little period of me,
the period of time where I was real self
destructive and just like a mad,
you know,
everything.
And um,
you know,
took me awhile to calm down and get to
work,
you know,
for,
for awhile there,
it was just sort of going through the
motions,
the,
you know,
I mean,
it must have always known mean everyone
knows there's dangers involved in racing
cars.
but when it hit someone so close as your
own father that had to change what
racing felt like to you.
Yeah,
I'm sure.
I'm sure it would have completely been a
different experience.
I'm emotionally had that not happened.
Had racing for me would have meant
something completely different.
Um,
you know,
I just was,
he was in,
he was this,
he was this invincible god that wasn't
supposed to get hurt,
wasn't supposed to.
I mean,
he was,
he was supposed to get hurt and drive
hurt and be tough.
And um,
he wasn't supposed to get killed and
leave us all,
you know,
he left the whole sport,
and,
and no one knew what to do.
Like that was like,
the whole sport was sitting there going,
oh shit,
what do we do?
You know,
he was the guy for everyone.
And even in even the competitors,
you know,
looked up to him like he was the,
yeah,
like that,
that's the man.
And uh,
so it was tough on the whole sport to
big giant void for the whole sport.
Um,
but I,
you know,
we just uh,
huddled together,
me and my team in our company,
we are rice for my dad's company,
so that whole company kinda just kinda
held,
held itself together and everybody kinda
pulled,
pulled together and worked our way
through it that first year and
[inaudible] just that year,
you know,
that he was killed now that was just a
kind of a tough year.
I don't even really remember anything
much about What happened that year.
Um,
won a couple races,
uh,
but it was,
otherwise,
you know,
the races where we didn't win.
I can't even,
I don't even remember much about them,
you know,
just retaining too much from.
It was just kind of a daze,
you know?
Oh,
four was a great year.
I think we kind of finally,
we're coming out of the funk,
you know,
around 2004 kind of coming out of the
cloud of that.
I would imagine that being a race car
driver and having your dad be who he was
always carried a lot of weight.
But did it carry more weight after he
was gone with her more eyes on you?
Yeah,
I thought so.
Um,
you knoW,
I thought he,
he was tough.
He knew who he was to the sport and he
knew,
he knew that he carried,
he carried a big massive fan base and he
knew that people listen to when he spoke
and all those things.
And so when he was gone,
I think some people are,
some people kind of looked at me to try
to carry that same load and even be that
same person and I just wasn't going to
do it.
Um,
I was like,
man,
I'm going to be me.
I'm going to be the pr,
you know,
like I said he was,
he's this template,
tall black hat and I'm,
I'm this short scrawny pail kid.
You know,
I was,
I couldn't be who he was,
I'd have been faking it and I couldn't
be the intimidator,
you know,
so I just have always,
ever since then been me and if that's
good,
if you'd like that.
Um,
great.
Uh,
I think I've been relatable,
honest,
genuine,
and the fan base that I gained when,
when he passed away,
I thought we nurtured that and grew that
and I think we did a lot of great
things,
uh,
and,
and outside the sport to,
uh,
to do that.
Um,
so I'm kind of proud of all those
things.
I thought I handled that well.
I'm considering there are a lot of
different avenues to go at that time and
I think I chose some good ones and
certainly probably could have made some
different decisions and have regrets.
But for the most part I was able to,
you know,
add to his legacy a little bit.
That was something that was important to
me.
I didn't go out there and win 90 day.
I'm racist.
I didn't win seven championships,
but I didn't hurt his legacy.
I added to it,
uh,
made a lot of people happy.
Uh,
there was an on the tracK,
you know,
that was good for a lot of people.
Deal.
You got a great perspective.
Thanks.
Really do any book.
It's called racing to the finish.
It's out now.
Go get it folks.
Thanks.
Thank you,
dale.
yes sir.
Man,
I appreciate you having me.
Appreciate you being here.
Great to meet you.
Great to meet you too.
Thank you.
We should do a hunt.
Nice.
Let's do it.
You name it.