I was listening to some old timey music
the other day and it was making me think
of how depressing it would be if that
was the only music that you could hear.
La La La la La la La David Lynch movie
that David Lynch in his movies,
he always has those,
those songs.
Like there's a woman dead in a hotel and
there's just this
oh
mansion.
The days where that Tuba with a needle
at the bottom of my grandfather had one
of those in my home in Pelham.
And his Colin Powell in New York,
they had an old chronic graft.
They,
it is called right phonograph and they
would play,
uh,
you know,
classical.
My grandparents never listened to.
They were Sicilian.
They never listened to music.
Did your parents or your grandparents
have the TV and a cabinet?
Ah Ha.
And they certainly did.
And then with the TV would die.
A lot of times folks who put the new TV
on top of the cabinet,
they would keep the tea,
the cabinet with the blown out TV.
Yeah,
dude,
everybody did that.
Well,
I had a family that never threw anything
away.
No my night.
Never ever.
I'm talking about road cones.
We got to my attic,
we find crazy.
She had her phone.
Yes.
Phonograph.
Not a chronic,
that's a chronograph,
but they always had a chronograph.
Oh,
watch.
right,
right.
Yeah.
Cause I have a chronology,
goddammit.
Yeah.
Those things were crazy.
Like that was how they used to listen to
music.
A Tuba attached to a needle bolts right
here and the speaker must have sounded
like dog shit.
My Dad used to have a dust cover for his
turntable and he would,
he had,
there was a ritual to how you clean your
Lp.
Oh,
there's a ritual.
You got to dust it off.
You have a special cloth and all the
shit thing.
Yup.
That's what we take a peek at that
fucker.
Look at that.
That's nuts.
I think for people at home,
it looks like it does a really traffic
cone.
Right?
It does.
Right.
Like a big old brass traffic.
A little needles.
I read the Ted Williams,
the great,
uh,
this might've been a myth,
but the great baseball player,
Ted Williams,
who could hit a fast ball,
hit any kind of ball,
and he apparently could read the label
of a record as it was going around.
His eyes could slow shit down.
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
I wonder if that's true.
I wonder.
Well,
yeah,
you know,
is this is one of those three things you
hear,
right?
Like Joe Frazier was in a hotel room.
There were four flies in the room there,
the way it was started with the flies
and he went and caught them all and he
goes,
here,
you flies the fuck out outta here.
Andy Griffin was telling us that Bruce
Lee's story once it was one of those,
yeah,
I heard he killed him.
Bruce Lee was in a fight with 30 men and
he stood in the center of all of them.
And you're like,
wait,
wait.
Where'd you hear this?
He never,
I heard he never wasn't harangue
already.
He would never,
he never sparred once.
I don't think Bruce Lee ever.
Did you ever fight competitive?
Was rumored.
No,
but he did one thing once where you
sparred at like this a karate festival.
One sparring session.
Cool.
Yeah.
All right.
Well
good luck.
Yeah.
You could see good luck against the guys
to be able to read the label on the no.
Good luck to everybody against a guy
like Darren till that's luck.
Good luck.
I mean,
yeah.
Vinny,
vinny shoreman who is,
he does,
um,
a color commentary for a lot of big
Moitai events.
Yeah.
And super knowledgeable like as a
striker and he's also a hypnotist.
I got hypnotized by them a couple of
times.
I,
I kept my pants on,
but he got,
sorry.
Yeah,
you hypnotize me.
Fascinating.
V Hypnotism is feet.
You get hypnotized cause you're 100%
really?
Yeah.
Give into it.
Just let it,
let,
let yourself achieve the state.
But you realize what it is.
It's like,
Oh,
you've got this idea where like someone
can like turn you into Manchurian
candidate if they hypnotize you and you
wouldn't have to troll your brain
anymore.
No,
no,
no.
You're relaxing.
Yeah.
You're relaxing and you're open to
suggestion in an interesting state of
mind that you can achieve.
Right?
See like I think just think there's a
larger spectrum of the way the mind
works then we give it credit for.
And I think what I've been thinking
about this a lot that that's one of the
things that happens with standup.
I think if you're onstage and you're
killing and stand up,
if I'm in the audience,
it's like you've got me hypnotized.
I'm locked up into your line of thinking
and like your act is a very silly,
so like when I'm watching you,
like I start thinking in silly ways and
then you'll keep getting sillier and
sillier and then like I'm locked into
your head.
It's like it's a form of hypnosis,
100% and I think that so is like being
in a good place.
Thank you.
Young.
Jamie said though.
So it'd be in a good place mentally.
So it was being in a bad place.
But I think there's like,
there's a large spectrum in the mind of
all these different chairs.
Where are you going fucker?
He can't.
What kind of staggered was fantastic.
Cheers dude.
It's all right.
It's a solid white on the juice guys,
gentlemen.
I like them because it's a good juice.
It's a good juice and those guys are
gross.
Hey you guys who say it's a good juice
and you're talking about wine.
It's a sexy juice stopped.
Honestly,
it's sexy.
Just kind of feels like talk to you.
It's like taking a big bite.
On one hand
it's like having a wet dog to great
juice shake itself out.
You have,
have you ever gone into like a real wine
tasting with a bunch of nerds?
Sure.
Have different cause.
Amazing.
Those nerves.
Nerves I ever got to a wine taste
tasting where you graded a wine and you
stood up and said it has woody after
tones and there's a s I was invited,
I was invited by a guy a long time ago,
20 years ago.
And he said,
um,
I'm going to invite you to a wine
tasting where we all bring our own
wines.
And he said,
he's a good guy.
Goes,
he said,
I said,
well,
what do I bring?
And he said,
I don't want to insult you,
but you can't afford the kind of wines
that we're bringing,
so I'm going to bring you a bottle from
my seller so it doesn't make you look.
That's how,
that's how big these wines were.
And I was there with the guy from like
Zach,
he's or whatever the different
southerby's they did the guys that set
the standard and write the thing and I
was watching him taste it and write down
notes.
It was really wild.
Nutmeg to leather,
mushrooms,
earth,
you know,
all kinds of weird tasting those.
It's still subject.
My buddy matt is a huge wine head.
Like he's got his own cellar in his
house.
It's all temperature controlled.
And if I'm out at a restaurant,
I'll call Matt [inaudible],
Matt Lichtenberg.
I'll call him up and I'll,
I'll,
I'll go,
hey,
okay,
let me tell you what I got.
Yeah,
tell me what to get.
And he'll just like,
oh,
the reason why this is this one socks
and stay away from this one and this is,
this is what you want.
That's your groove right there.
Grab that one.
And I'm like,
okay,
well he's always right.
Yeah.
The brand has been known as a new wine.
Kai Kai has a ridiculous,
a good one.
I've had that at 97.
Ron is a wine head.
Yeah.
He has some up quite a few bottles of
opus one apparently.
Which is this one is not,
that's as it guys.
Way better than opus one.
Look at what you wrote here last night
was mad real fresh out of advil.
Jesus.
Grab the wheel.
Sheesh.
Vegan fucked up a Lebron James.
I think I brought that wine to the one
with the yellow.
Uh,
I think you did.
I think I brought that here.
Yeah,
it looks very familiar.
Yeah.
That's some good ass fucking wine.
Schatz home old cliche.
Good ass.
Why Mr. Super Athlete and there you go.
That's a real one.
Why?
There's some real super athletes.
We go,
listen,
he's an Avatar.
Fuck what kind of steroids you take.
Never going to look like that.
Never.
Like there's,
there's human beings that have just the
most unfathomable physical advantages.
It's ridiculous.
Like Lebron James would have like an
unfathomable physical advantage over
someone who had have an unfathomable
physical advantage over you.
Yeah.
Well I think I asked the guy who follows
this,
Jimmy Burke about Lebron James and
called them up and I just,
I left.
I left him one message.
I go,
I said,
Jim,
and I want you to be honest and don't
insult me.
At what age did Lebron James Surpass me
as an athlete and be careful with your
fucking answer.
He said,
because I'm a proud man that man and
I'll kick your fucking ass.
I hung up the phone,
I got a very thoughtful,
very thoughtful,
this station and I just got this 12
years old and there's no question about
that 12 by the time he was 14 six four
two 35 best player in the country.
You were not that.
You're not even close to that.
He was 14 and he was six four,
yeah,
he's a freak and there you go.
Oh six,
nine two 65.
And I sat next to Carlos Boozer who
played with him and they're the same
size.
And he goes,
he's just a step faster.
And everybody as well as as and just
ridiculously strong.
We'll see a guy like that.
If he was fighting,
everybody would be fucked.
Of course the,
they're lucky.
They are God damn lucky.
There's that much money at basketball.
Right?
He's incredible.
And then people go,
well,
you know what man,
some things that make great looking at
basketball player wouldn't necessarily
make you a great fighter.
Um,
listen,
listen to me.
Save it.
That guy's going to beat your fucking
ass.
This he's a winner.
There's,
there's just a certain
level of winners.
They like,
he do whatever the fuck you want.
Bo Jackson could have done ever.
I worked with Bo Jackson for a week.
Did you?
Yes,
I did.
And he was,
um,
and I said,
oh,
what do you,
what do you weigh?
He was in a white t shirt and I was
looking at the thickness of his fingers.
You know me,
I have sas because I'm basically a gay
man.
So I was,
I was looking at his hands,
I grabbed his hands.
It was just this giant me and I said,
what do you,
he goes,
um,
he said,
I remember in her,
he was so weird.
It's so specific.
He said,
I'm 61 and a half,
240 pounds to 245 pounds.
And he was the same size when he played
and he never has lifted weights in his
life ever.
And he didn't lift weights.
When he play,
he would just,
as in his words,
I just strap it on and I'd hear the
other team go on posing the game,
posing in the game.
But you have to also understand at Bo
Jackson,
not only did whatever you want it to you
on the football field faster and
everybody at two 45 and stronger.
He was also a,
was he,
was he not an MVP in baseball star?
At least start that.
That's unheard of.
Deion sanders play both ways,
but there's no one like Bo Jackson free.
That's crazy.
Throwing Bibi's,
throwing fucking ropes from center
field.
I mean he,
the whole different,
a whole different kinds of one tackle
one hip injury that's changed all that
shit.
Well it was his hip started to die or
have some kind of in a crisis in this
bone or something.
Let's from getting hit,
there was a very famous hit that he got
tackled.
You could see like the impact that has
on his hips when he goes down.
At least I am I remembering that
correctly.
There was a video,
right?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You can see the injury and it's just a
ridiculous half.
And we still came back and was smashing
home runs with a fake hip,
came back and played baseball.
Just couldn't really run anymore,
you know,
just a different kind of,
just a different kind of wonder if they
could fix that hip.
Now you know,
you think about what his hip was then
and what does hip is now?
Well,
I think you'd have to read,
you have to generate their tissue.
So I don't know if we're there yet,
but we're getting close.
What I mean is like the artificial hips.
I wonder if there,
those are better now.
I don't know it did you read a book
called Sapiens?
I sent you a,
probably not,
but Yuval Harari.
Everybody should read it.
It's an amazing book and it's a brief
history of mankind,
but it brings us to present day and he
also wrote another book called Homo
Deus,
I think.
When should you send this to me?
I sent you a screenshot.
I said,
you've got to read this book,
but Oh,
but he,
he talks about where we're headed
technologically.
He's really done the research.
I mean really looking honestly at what
medical research,
what to expect in the next 30 years.
You say,
well,
I mean,
you know,
not only are we going to live much
longer if you have the money,
but the real question he ends the book
with in a way is we have to decide as
human beings,
for the first time in our history,
we can control our own evolution.
So we have to ask ourselves what we want
to become.
That's a really big responsibility.
What do you want to become?
What do we want to become?
Because that question can be answered.
We will have the technology to answer
that question and,
and it can get silly where you can say,
we could splice our genes with Elian or
with a gorilla.
But,
but
more importantly,
we'll be able to splice our genes with
synthetic biology and become what it,
but it's a very heavy question.
What do you if so if you want to live
forever,
if you become what he called,
I think it was a moral,
uh,
or a different word for it.
But we're going to get mad at you for
fucking 50 year olds.
Like they don't know anything yet.
God,
how could you fuck a 50 year old?
You'd be like a thousand years old.
I know you'll,
you'll be so smart.
And so,
so why is people go,
you know how gross you are.
You're fucking someone who's 50 years
old as a human.
We figured,
look,
we only think of ourselves as like,
Oh,
you should have your shit together by 50
because we know we only lived to be a
hundred.
But the reality is most people don't get
their shit together.
Period.
Yeah.
Like that.
It's a race that nobody's winning.
Yes,
but we all know that if we just,
if we had an infinite amount of time,
we would keep getting better at getting
our shit together.
You would not be who you were yesterday
and hopefully you'd be much better than
you were a year ago.
But I think about something different.
Like I,
that's the case though.
But if you get to 900 years old,
are you still allowed to bang 50 year
olds?
Like live?
Like if she's a fucking kid,
bro.
I mean when is it?
Okay.
I mean if she's super hot and vampires,
vampires,
fuck like 30 year olds,
but we're talking about people,
Bro.
I'll talking about like,
you're apparently not if you can live,
if they figure out medical science and
this is not outside the realm of
possibility,
they can regenerate tissue and you stem
cells to rejuvenate your body and you
live 900 fucking years old.
Are you allowed to bank 50 year olds or
are you gross?
Well,
it takes to actually have what I think
the answer is,
it takes time and it,
and it flips it on its head.
I mean time no longer has a consequence
because there's not,
you have very,
you don't really have limitations.
We had the biggest thing about human
beings,
right,
is that we have limitation.
We know we're going to die.
That's the fundamental difference
between sort of a,
the idea of a a robot being just like a
human,
we are defined by our limitations.
Right.
But you know why they bring the,
the draft around and try to get young
people to get drafted.
I didn't want to go out to their 40 year
olds and 50 year olds would think cause
it won't work like a wonder if it gets
to a certain age.
I wonder if you live to a certain age
and like cults just don't work anymore.
I wonder if it only works up until
you're like 50 or 60 or 70 but if people
live forever it would be just like
telling Santa Claus to like a little
kid.
Like it tell Santa Claus to your five
year olds.
They're like Whoa,
Santa Claus is real.
Yeah.
He tells the Santa Claus to a 15 year
old.
They're like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
The same kid,
it'd be like,
Dad,
you're retarded.
Like stop.
This is the sense that it depends on
how,
whether you or not,
you've brought your understanding.
There are a lot of old coal,
but if you're a cult leader and you're
900 years old and you just bang and all
these 50 year old ladies,
you're an asshole.
They're like little kids still.
Maybe,
maybe,
well,
50 year olds are not gonna look like 50
year olds.
Now they're going to look.
It got really hot.
But my point is like there was still
beating me naive.
They still put the holy water on
themselves.
They still do.
You know there's going to be awake,
weird shit,
but there'll be attracted to that 900
year old cars full of wisdom
possibility.
A sorcerer.
Yeah.
It was kind of power you to have your
nine years old.
As you get older,
that of life breaks
down.
You're out when you're younger and you'd
see somebody who's really good at
something,
you're like,
God,
they're a genius.
And then you kind of get,
you start,
you know,
you get to a certain days where you get
good at something or you just start to
do it enough and you go,
there's a certain formula to success.
Like sometimes like it to be really good
at something.
There's a,
there's a,
there's a mindset for competition.
But to be really good at something also
just requires a shitload of repetition
and good toodle edge.
There's a lot of touching,
a lot of focus.
And one of the things that you recognize
in people when you,
you see another enough people that are
like really truly awesome at something,
you see enough of them,
you start to recognize this like thing.
Like,
I especially can see it in musicians
because I have zero talent cause I have
zero musical talent whatsoever.
Zero.
Have you ever tried to actually hold a
tune?
You're trying to just try this,
try to sing all serious.
Don't laugh.
No.
Try to sync.
Just look at me.
It's embarrassing,
but do it.
Okay.
Try to sing.
I want to sing silent night.
Holy night.
Try to hit it.
Don't do it right and then I'm going to
try it.
It's so hard.
So nervous.
It's so vulnerable.
I'm asking this in two verses,
but isn't it funny that like making
noises with your mouth?
It's vulnerable.
Nah.
Oh,
lean.
That's not bad.
Oh,
this copy.
That was spring.
Can you get a little power?
Oh,
is Bra.
Ciao.
What's the rest of,
I don't know.
Something in heavenly peas.
Holy infant.
So tender and mild.
Oh,
so
already please
then leave
pe.
I went immediately to the douche singer
voice that whispery.
I know you did,
but you,
but you know what you had to do.
I think you were.
He was tuned was me.
Jamie entering key.
Don't you tell her anybody who talks to
you like that?
Listen to me ladies.
That's my joke about,
that's my joke.
Where I do I,
I talk about that guy.
You can say nice dressed.
Just don't whisper it.
That's where it's creeping.
That's funny.
That's what am,
I was like,
there's just some things you can't
whisper in life.
Like you can be like,
your daughter is so cute.
If you're like,
It's creepy.
The creepy voice is recognized,
but you know,
you know what?
It's a fucking confusing ass voice is
the scary voice.
You know the scary voice like next on
twilight zone,
like anybody taught like any scary
monster like and then they went down
that dark dark row.
Yeah,
like are those people who have that kind
of a scary voice this summer?
And here's
another one that doesn't work.
Hell just got a hot is girls all the
hottest dancing like that.
Kind of like hot and sexy.
There's old commercials,
remember and I would just like a weird
rhythm to the way they're talking.
They're establishing very clear
parameters for vocabulary.
Oh,
the hottest girls.
There's not going to be some soliloquy
fees on your interpretation of
consciousness as you know it versus this
objective view of the universe now.
Now it's,
Oh,
the hobby,
all that.
It's dancing.
It's like you have these like really
short sentences.
Well,
so we're,
we're,
we're in tune,
we're in tune with those rhythms.
Those girls are saying,
look,
to cut the bullshit.
We're down to fuck.
We've got fake tits and we're drunk.
That's what they're saying with that
voice.
Like that's what that voice is.
Did you ever,
did you ever hear the experiment they
did where they played?
Um,
doctors?
So they took,
they took different doctors and some had
been sued a lot and then they just took
the doctors at bedside.
They recorded them speaking and they
took out the words so you could only
hear the tone of their voice.
And people said,
I don't like that guy.
And they didn't even know what they were
saying.
They say,
I don't like that guy.
And without,
almost like most of them chose the
doctors that had been sued.
And it turned out that they had a
dominant tone so that their tone and the
sound of their voice was what people
objected to.
And because their bedside manner was a
saddle,
Malcolm Gladwell's book,
their bedside manner was,
was dominant.
They weren't,
they weren't sort of understanding and
listening.
They were rather telling the patient
something.
Those were the doctors regardless of
their,
their errors and what they did,
um,
that had nothing to do with their
degrees.
Didn't even have do with it what they
did.
Um,
those were the ones that got sued for
malpractice.
Don't remember.
That's from blink,
right?
Yes.
I think it's from blank blinks are great
book.
Yeah,
it is.
It's great.
And it's a great audio book too.
I got that one on audio book.
I listened to it on audio.
It's a very,
I always listen to shit on audio.
I listened to Sapiens on audio.
It's very good drive.
Yeah,
it's very good way to uh,
you know,
I like podcasts but I like to mix it up
and it's like,
I don't want to only watch
documentaries.
I like watching fiction too.
Oh,
work watching.
I like,
I like to mix things up with,
with would I take in and what have you.
But I think that like audio books in
particular,
it's a great way to utilize like wasted
time.
Yeah.
100%.
Instead of listening to music.
I always listened to,
I listen to a whole course on Nietzsche
would,
how crazy was that story and blink about
the artwork where they found this good
statue and this art expert looked at it
for a second and went,
it's fake.
How much would you be or what came to
his mind back?
Remember the word that came to what he
says?
Nay.
He knew it was fake because new,
nope,
close when it was supposed to be up.
Statute was buried for 3000 years.
A Kudos,
right?
Like a fully formed Kudos is young boy
in Greek,
so it's a fully formed like statute,
which is near a thessaloniki or
something.
And they tested the,
the marble
came from Macquarie near there.
They even tested the mold,
which actually turned out to be somebody
put it on potatoes,
but they,
but the mold seemed legit and all that
stuff and,
but he,
the minute he saw it,
he said,
can you get your money back?
This is a fake.
And he didn't know why,
but the first word that came to mind was
fresh,
kind of crazy,
right?
Yeah.
Mason something you're supposed to here,
but isn't it crazy?
And he was right.
Yeah.
Then you could just see like for you and
I would be like,
wow,
crazy statue.
You know what I mean?
We wouldn't have,
but there's certain things that I'm sure
you could see.
You know,
like there's certain things like here's
one that I see all the time.
Um,
I see when people are about to spin from
all my years of taekwondo.
Oh yeah.
Like a little simple dip that people go,
I was getting,
he's looking at her.
Did you call that a lot?
All the time.
Because you see,
once you learn it when you're a little
kid,
cause he'd been kicked in the head a few
times,
like it becomes a part of your life.
How does recognition see this little
thing always kind of spin he's trying to
spend,
you know,
and you see it.
And as a regular person,
I was like,
how the fuck are you seeing that?
Well,
I've seen it cause people would hit me.
Yeah,
don't get hit by that.
Yeah.
Like when you see that,
like,
oh,
get out of there.
Yeah.
Well one of the wealthiest guys,
my friend who made $1 billion more,
his buddy is worth some crazy amount of
money.
And uh,
so what's your secret?
And he said,
uh,
mirrors and windows.
So what do you mean?
He said,
I can tell if somebody is going to pay
me back.
I can tell if somebody is a good
investment or not.
And he said,
well how?
And he goes,
you had to got windows,
you've got mirrors for eyes and if you
got married,
surprise,
you can go fuck yourself.
You've got windows.
I'm a lending money and that's an
instinct he would just pick up on.
He got [inaudible] Saturday and he could
pick up on whether or not you were a
phone.
You know that's a real problem with
communicating with people in nonverbal
ways in non purse non-face-to-face ways.
Yeah,
it's a real problem with like texting
and stuff like that.
You're not looking into the person.
Like I think it changes the way we talk
to each other.
It changes interactions.
And I think most of the problem that
people have most of the time with each
other,
there's not talking like today and
especially not talking enough,
looking at each other in the eyes.
That's exactly figuring out like if
maybe someone's,
someone's right,
maybe you're wrong about something.
You got to talk to them and you go,
okay,
well when did you think I was supposed
to do?
And I did that.
Okay.
And what time were you supposed to be
there?
What time did we say?
I thought we said this and you can try
to figure it out while you're looking at
each other.
Right.
You know when someone gets say,
look man,
I was really bummed out.
You know it was a really important
thing.
He was supposed to pick me up and then
you could work it out and look at each
other and work with that.
But when you go through these series of
text messages,
I've had text messaged discussions with
people are like,
hey man,
I can't do this.
Like let's just talk.
Can we just talk,
cause this is crazy cause I don't know
what your face is making when you're
making the statement,
you're saying something and it's not
entirely accurate and I'm trying to
figure out what the fuck your face looks
like.
We are you laughing?
Is this lol right.
We look at each other cause I bet we
could work this shit out.
You know that that's,
that is the problem with reading
sometimes about something and thinking
you're getting the whole picture.
What I like about Thaddeus Russell is
that he,
his book or renegade history of the
United States,
I think it's called,
he actually takes a look at
things that I've never heard.
I was a history major and historians
tend to be pretty conservative,
stodgy people,
right?
They,
they're not,
you know,
but your average college professor is a
pretty conservative guy.
Even though he might be very left wing,
they're conservative people.
They're,
they're not,
they're not young.
I'm not going to find them at an orgy or
you know,
usually or various things.
And especially with historians and when
they write history,
they always write it from this really
stodgy kind of,
you hear about the events,
you actually don't hear about what it
was like in the brothels.
You don't hear about what it smelled
like in the bars.
You don't hear about the noise.
You don't hear about things that
actually have an effect on people.
Who are the criminals,
how safe are the streets?
Where were the prostitutes who was
actually getting laid?
Was there a lot of black and white sex
that went on in during the revolutionary
where,
which apparently there was a,
what about dancing on a dirty white
ladies?
It got some dark Dick.
I only,
I can only hope I co it's the ultimate
fuck you to your dad.
Yes it is.
How many chicks just fucking couldn't
wait.
I know as soon as it was,
the veil was lifted,
you know,
as they say,
my dad is fighting to keep you asleep.
I'm fine to suck your Dick Dave.
It sounds like a title little hot dirty
white girl with freckles.
Apparently there was a lot of that
because what they would do is the Irish
who come in,
they were indentured servants.
Then you have this black slaves and they
danced.
They would go,
there'd be like these,
these speakeasies and everybody would
mingle.
It'd be late at night,
black but beautiful black women and you
know,
the black and white dudes be like,
dude,
these girls are hot.
You know,
and there was mixing and everything else
and there was all kinds of shit like
that.
Remember slavery was being talked about
is I'm great moral evil.
Really back when this country was
founded,
what really kind of,
one of the things they say that kept
slavery going another hundred years was
the cotton gin,
was the fact that Eli Whitney invented a
machine that made it fucking really,
really easy to separate the seed from
the cotton.
And as a result,
this guy comes up with a great invention
and it's rough.
They were like,
Whoa,
we got all this free labor down here.
I'm not free and slaves.
This shit is white gold.
I can send it over,
I can send it to Europe,
and there's an insatiable demand for my
cotton fuck that I'm not going to have.
My whole economy is built on the fact
that I've got all this free labor and
I'm making a fortune.
So a lot of historians kind of talk
about how Eli Whitney invented a machine
that was really efficient but might've
been responsible for keeping an entire
group of people in slavery for.
That is so crazy to think about.
Well,
you came up with an idea.
He came up with a cotton gin,
most of the clothes that were made out
of hemp,
hemp fiber for everything,
and apparently it's way better than
cotton.
It's stronger for sure.
I stronger todd mccormick.
Do remember my friend Tom Mccormick,
he had this stock of hemp in his house
and it was like from a hemp tree and
it's like,
it's from another planet.
It doesn't seem like it's a real thing,
so really
hard,
but it's really light.
It's light like,
like Balsa wood,
but it's hard.
Like,
oh cool.
Like it's weird.
It's cool.
And he was explaining to me,
and he knows way more about me than I
do,
but he was like,
dude,
it's an alien planet and it's an error
on the alien planet.
It's very hearty.
We'd write an alien plant.
It's like no other plant.
It has all the essential amino acids.
You,
you get essential oils from it.
It has protein in it,
a very high protein content.
Like you can eat hemp seeds are great
for you,
Huh?
They're really healthy and you can make
clothing out of it.
You can make fuel out of it.
Hemp fuel.
Henry Ford made the first fenders on the
first model t out of Ham.
Fiber's really an,
there's a video of him hitting them with
a hammer and the hammer bounces off.
These hemp vendors,
they're far more durable than steel.
That's crazy.
It's an insane fiber man.
It doesn't make any sense.
It literally is like no other fiber on
the planet.
It's a really complex fiber and it's
illegal and it's illegal.
You can go home,
can't you grow hemp.
You just can't grow the female plant and
the government is doing their best to
make cbds being regulated by the FDA.
They're all trying to stop CB.
There's people that are trying to stop
cbd.
It doesn't even have a psychoactive
effect on you.
Well,
the guy who invented that,
I mean,
I don't know if he had vetted the dark
web,
but the the Silk Road Guy.
Oh,
brexit.
Yeah.
I got to point this out.
This is really important though.
Before I forget,
the CBD oil folks,
there's a,
I'm reading a lot of reports online of
people testing cbd and it tests positive
for thc.
Greg Fitzsimmons talked about this.
He said that he tried cbd oil and he got
him high.
I don't know what he used,
which company he used,
but the,
the,
the studies that I've read where people
have actually got them tested,
there's,
there's thc in some of them,
so you've gotta be careful,
especially if you have some ups job or
somewhere that,
I don't know if ups tests where they
test your piss.
If you,
if you take cbd oil for pain and
inflammation,
you've got to really make sure you trust
the sources because I guess apparently
it can,
it can have thc in it.
When you didn't you point that out.
I don't know if I did,
but I've seen that same thing for two
weeks.
I think you're the one who told me about
it first.
Yeah.
It's not just cause we were talking
about Greg,
like Greg,
it's high off CBD oil.
Mike.
Like maybe it's just like a super
lightweight,
but I don't think so.
Maybe.
I think there's some weed and some of
them I think might just be super
sensitive.
I love the weed.
Yeah.
I think if you just give him a regular
cbd oil,
Betty be fine.
It might not even just be the CBD oil.
I have noticed a something like head
shops and some states that it's not
recreationally available.
They're selling it in the same form as
like dabs and concentrates and you smoke
the CBD the same way you would smoke
that heavy concentrated shit.
Whoa.
And that crazy like dab rig with a hot
torch.
So you smoke cbd oil that doesn't get
you high and the Dab rig and that,
I don't know what it is to sleep better.
It didn't work.
It didn't.
I'll tell you what works.
Smoking weed,
you a a hard time sleeping.
Yeah.
What?
Uh,
anymore so much.
But you know,
I always worry,
yeah,
that'll do it.
Yeah.
I worry that I,
you know,
he's just go,
it's interesting sometimes it just,
I feel guilty about being so lucky.
I get into my really soft bed and I do
what I love and I'm like,
what does the other foot gonna drop
here?
If you really stop and think about how
lucky you are in comparison to the vast
majority of human doings are,
it's ridiculous.
What you know.
Well,
I'm what?
You know,
it's,
I have zero tolerance for people that
talk about how hard things are today.
Like they're complicated today.
Yeah.
They're not hard.
It's complicated.
Yeah.
Way More complicated.
Of course there are hard moments.
No one's,
no one's denying your,
your pain and your hard moments.
If you get a cut on your hand,
you're not going to get gang green.
Yeah.
It's just way easier.
A little thing.
You don't have to worry about the,
the pox.
There's so much more today.
It's a,
this is a fucking crazy time and
there's,
it's still,
the thing about this time is,
the good thing about it is,
yeah,
we're overpopulated.
Yeah.
We're crazy.
This is the system we were operating on.
Doesn't make a whole lot of sense,
but you could still go into the woods at
any moment.
Like there's a place where you can go
right now,
we can go in the woods.
Like you could go,
you can go to big bear and you just go
for a hike.
Also in you're in the forest like,
oh,
this shit's still real.
It's still,
this is still here too.
Right.
You know?
Yay.
Yeah,
life is crazy and life's bizarre,
but we haven't completely turned the
whole world into a city.
That's true.
Guess what bitch that's coming.
We looked out big Los Angeles is,
it's much of it is covered in concrete
and streets and then the streets go off
everywhere,
like veins and,
oh by the way,
200 years ago,
no streets aren't there,
but are in town.
We'll admins is expanding in this
country.
Is that wrong?
I do not think that wildernesses are
expand.
There's more grazing land and stuff.
I,
I don't know.
I mean we're definitely suffering from
urban sprawl,
but I was surprised to see how little,
like the percentage of of the
continental United States has actually
inhabited that actually has houses and
on,
it was really small.
It surprised me that she had added me.
Yeah,
it's pretty small.
Super.
It's crazy how 6% or something.
Yeah,
and these little areas,
but yeah,
I'm like these people that live in these
small towns all across the country does
a big reason.
Also why trump won.
They just felt totally unrepresented by
all the people that live on the sides.
I also think it's because they had,
I think 50% of Americans have what,
$500 in their bank account?
Something crazy.
Yeah.
She might be less than that.
$400 it's $400 think about that.
So that's why I get mad when people
character.
I don't like trump,
but I never liked when people
characterized all trump supporters as
racist,
et Cetera.
I thought it was unfair because I think
the majority of people want to live in
some dignity,
and they had Obama,
eight years of Obama say,
but you will.
But their lives didn't change for a lot
of reasons.
I don't think Obama's to blame.
There's a lot of reasons.
And then along comes hilary's speaking
the same exact language.
So if you're going to blame people for
saying,
wait,
under eight years,
I still
only have $400 in my pocket.
Here comes a woman who's speaking the
same language.
Oh,
and by the way,
there's a lot of rumors about being or
being corrupt.
I have nothing to lose.
I'm going to try that other guy.
Did you see what Donna Brazil rope?
One of the reasons why she came out with
their book is after seth rich got
murdered and she called him a patriot.
Wow.
I didn't have seth rich got,
oh,
that,
that's right.
That was the guy worked for the DNC.
There was a Bernie Sanders supporter
that wikileaks has alluded to the fact
that he them information and got shot in
front of his house and it became this
big conspiracy theory where people would
mock you for saying it was a conspiracy
and then hannity ran with it and so it
became clearly there for a lot of people
that seth rich conspiracy theory that it
was nonsense.
Nobody knows what happened to that guy
though he was murdered,
his watch on his phone with him.
He had his wallet on him.
Nobody took anything from,
they shot him at four o'clock in the
morning.
Who knows what happened.
But when wikileaks starts saying that
you gave them information and that
there's consequences,
do you give them information?
One of two things is happening.
Either wikileaks has decided,
all of a sudden you start lying right
and making things up about people or
two,
they were misinformed and someone was
pretending to be this guy and sending
them information.
It's always possible if they can meet
face to face or three,
they're telling you something you didn't
know that this guy who was just shot and
murdered was leaking information about
the DNC and other DNC was corrupted by
the Hillary Clinton group,
which is what Donna Brazil is saying in
her book and that this guy released that
and showed how the primaries were rigged
against Bernie Sanders and that Hillary
Ari was sending me excerpts from it the
other day.
He's like,
dude,
she was Donna.
Brazil was saying that Hillary was in
control at DNC before the primaries,
so,
so is the implication that Hillary might
have had something to do with his
murder.
That's the implication.
The information was already out.
I like maybe add more and maybe they
were punishing him to stop other people
from doing the same thing.
Maybe other people had more information,
you know,
I don't know if it's true,
but there was another guy that
disappeared reasonably.
It was a guy who,
uh,
had dirt on the Clintons.
Some,
some guy vanished.
This is like really,
really recent.
Like,
see if you could find that one.
Some guy just read,
just type in Google Clinton dirt.
And this is like from Newsweek.
So there's,
people have vanished and I dunno how
many of them had been murdered.
People suicide themselves.
I don't know how many of them actually
suicide themselves,
but it could,
let's just say one out of 10,
just one out of 10.
It was an actual murder,
right?
This guy academic at the heart of
Clinton dirt campaign vanishes.
What leaving trail of questions.
It's really recently.
See that figured out when you kill
people.
It's my piece way hearts to maybe
usually heal people.
Um,
it's like God damn,
how does body get here?
But when people just vanish,
tamp,
they just vanish.
Oof.
That's crazy.
They just disappeared.
What does that do when I need him?
Whereas Mr Bravo and I made him crazy.
He be going crazy about that one.
Yeah,
but Eddie's,
Eddie's
conspiracies turn in on themselves
because he'd be like,
he's disappeared,
but he's not really.
What if he's not really dead?
Eddie?
Um,
he loves himself a conspiracy.
He gets so excited.
Yeah,
I know.
It's like watching the clock in the
community towards like a dude is super
into sports.
You know?
Like he'll,
he fucking,
you want to talk to me about you?
All I'm saying is it's a little weird.
Well,
you know what I tried to see someone was
like,
well,
why does he enjoy conspiracies?
I said,
well,
first of all,
enjoy them.
Enjoy what you like.
But also Eddie's always been really good
at like shutting down people not
believing in his ideas with Jujitsu is
Eddie has like revolutionary Jujitsu.
Jujitsu is rubber guard setups and all
the different things.
The paths that he,
he fixed a lot of paths in traditional
Jujitsu,
changed a lot of things and did some
things his way.
And when he would describe it to me,
I was like,
oh,
this is a guy like has an idea how to do
things and when people are opposing.
And he's like,
no,
no.
I'm going to shut that down and move
over here.
So That's interesting.
So it's brainworks hour.
So when someone comes at him with an
idea,
he has an idea and he's going to try to
get that idea through.
And when you come at him with some weak
attacks on that idea and just expect
that he's going to relinquish his hold
on the idea,
he's like,
no,
no bitch.
This don't make no sense.
No,
you don't.
You don't have any information.
It's going to take someone giving him
real honest to goodness,
impossible to deny information that he's
going to believe in any of the
conspiracies that he believes in war
being false.
Or it's going to take somebody to
explain him that his feelings control
his thinking.
That is true.
But there have been conspiracies that
have successfully been executed,
which makes this whole thing way more
confusing.
It's like,
which one of these were real to say that
all conspiracies are bullshit.
You are a victim of like some reverse
racism.
Yeah,
no,
I,
I'm usually skeptical of conspiracies,
especially government conspiracies
because government has no tourists so
completely out of sync and not efficient
enough and certainly there are so many
different competing interests within
government.
Within an administration.
Yeah.
Everybody's trying to undermine each
other and that's the history and it was
set up that way and even if you talk
about faking the moonlight,
you'd have to have about a thousand,
maybe 2000 people to keep a secret.
That's not necessarily the case.
If you just had people thinking on a
need to know bates basis with everything
compartmentalized,
like this guy's responsible for making
the o rings.
This guy's responsible for,
I don't know how it works.
I've known,
I don't know how it works either,
but I do know that you're talking about
if you were trying to fake the moon
landing,
one of the things that would be much
easier is your d during the Nixon
administration there were getting used
to fake and things.
Watergate was going on,
you know,
found out though,
cause somebody drops.
You just starting to develop the kind of
special effects abilities where you can
sort of recreate spacings like 2001 that
was the big conspiracy theorist dream.
Was that somehow or another like there'd
be like some irrefutable proof that
Stanley Kubrick was the one who worked
in the moon landing.
That was like,
if I'd found that I'd be like common in
my pants.
Like Eddie never acknowledges that the
same impulse that drives him,
which is really to find the truth and to
be skeptical of of people's claims and
even evidence that's been written down.
Human beings have always,
always,
for the most part,
unless there's something wrong with you
want it to be in the know.
I don't know anyone who doesn't want to
know the truth.
I don't know anybody who doesn't want to
know,
who likes being deceived and so,
so it it,
that's why it's almost impossible to
keep a secret longterm in government
because somebody's always talking on the
other side of it.
Here's one of the reasons why the whole
conspiracy thing is so attractive to
people because there's a reward chain
built into the human psyche of solving a
problem that's presented in front of you
that could potentially be dangerous.
It's a reward chain and deserves more
chain gets acted upon.
Even if you're talking about nonsense,
even if this is like some area 51 you
know,
Ufo body,
fucking whatever it is,
Roswell,
New Mexico,
the guy who was there,
the gut,
the general talk to my grandma.
Yeah.
He told me about the coffins,
four foot tall coffin.
There were little alien babies.
I took him to the back of the hearse.
They had embalmed and Mike.
My aunt saw it and they killed her in
the forest.
Like stop,
stop.
I know I can't,
but when you have an explanation you
don't feel as unsafe.
Yeah.
If you,
if I tell you that there are random
things that happen.
For example,
the shooter in Las Vegas,
he was 64 and there are no signs.
He was very controlling.
If you look at these good bit of a
sociopath,
he had,
we had this obsession with control.
But,
uh,
if I just tell you that sometimes people
wig the fuck out and they just want to
shoot a bunch of people,
that's not appropriate because then
what's going to happen?
It's anxiety medication.
Sure.
But I'm sure,
but there's also like,
when you say that stuff,
it's like,
now what you're saying is I have no real
way to protect myself.
Even if I carry a gun and take all my
vitamins,
wear my seatbelt.
There's always some crazy shit I didn't
think about.
It's called faith.
The people I've talked to,
um,
that,
that understand,
um,
psych medicines that I've talked to,
some psychiatrists I've had on the
podcast,
listen to Kelly Brogan.
Kelly Brogan talked about it quite
extensively.
One of the things that she went,
her and many other psychiatrists brought
up is the disassociative properties have
a lot of these psych medicines that
someone might have a horrible idea in
their head,
but the repercussions of it are real.
Like acting on it feels real.
But as soon as you have some sort of
heavy disassociative psych medicine
that's not even real,
like you don't care anymore.
You're like,
you're like,
wow,
like watching yourself in a movie or
something.
You're,
you're,
you're Ron.
Something that Dole's all the highs and
the lows.
It puts you in this weird state where
it's okay,
it's okay.
It's okay to just kill these people.
Like I don't know whether or not you
could,
the leap from being a person who could
never kill somebody to be in a person
doesn't have a problem with killing
somebody.
I don't know if that's true.
I mean,
maybe that's a,
that's a Chaz.
I'm too far to cross.
But I guarantee you if you're the type
of person that is having some horrible
thoughts about like being aggressive to
people and then someone puts you on
something that makes you like,
I don't give a fuck.
Like it's gonna.
It's gonna.
If you are Ha,
who knows what the right chemical is
too,
right?
Like if they give you the wrong one,
maybe it'll switch you one way or the
right one.
We'll turn the other way.
Or maybe we should add some abilify into
the mix.
Just throw some of this in there.
This is an antipsychotic to help you all
even out.
Do you know you can have a lesion on
your brain?
The size of the head of a pen.
You can have a lesion and if it's in the
right,
there's a specific area of the brain
where it can be a tiny lesion that you
can't see really barely with the naked
eye and it can render you a homicidal
maniac.
Doesn't my problem fighting off the
leash?
I got lesions in my brain.
Is that true?
Yeah.
What is it called?
What's the leaves?
Don't know.
I could look it up for you,
but it's by eye.
But you can use where I heard it was in
a lecture by Daniel Robinson who is a
professor at Oxford and Georgetown and
the smartest man on the planet.
That's why you have to really be careful
when you're punching people in the head,
right?
Yeah.
Yes sir.
That's why it causes,
well,
so the guy who,
who does that make sense?
Neuroscience.
Who captured the 13 year old girl?
Not Elizabeth.
SMART,
but the other one had two children with
her,
kept her for 18 years and she escaped.
Finally.
Yes.
That was the guy that was,
were were,
were to he and his wife.
It was somewhere in like,
I think Seattle is basement.
Right.
You got him in the backyard,
in a shed for an a in a,
in a sealed about shedding and they
lived in the backyard with the daughters
until,
I mean literally she was 18 then they
would go out once in a while.
It was real Stockholm Syndrome shit.
Oh my God.
Then she,
oh,
crazy.
Yeah.
And,
and she,
but she got,
he got her pregnant at 13 and it was
just a terrible story I was going to
tell you about earlier.
Did you,
did you see the footage where they have
their selling slaves in Libya?
Is it Libya or is it Iraq?
It's Libya.
There was,
maybe it's in Iraq too.
Yeah.
But it was Libya and they were,
you know,
there was a,
I forget who the title it was usa today
that had an editorial that said,
thanks Hilary Clinton because Hilary
Clinton,
apparently they're blaming her decisions
on the reason why we went into Libya and
dethrone Mo Market Aafia who knows?
Yeah.
You would know maybe more than most,
but video of migrants,
soul and apparent slave auction in Libya
provokes outrage worldwide.
It's disturbing,
man.
When you watch it,
they got guns to these dudes heads those
photos.
I retweeted it.
If you want to go to my instagram,
you can see some of the pictures of it.
But they have like Libya is a failed
state now.
Yes.
And it's God damn terrifying in,
um,
2017.
Look at that in,
in 1970 and my father just told a story
at,
uh,
at Thanksgiving and he was talking how
Dubai
and Abu Dhabi have become these
incredible countries.
And when he was first there in 1970 and
1971,
I don't know what it was.
Um,
somebody said,
you see that woman over there and she
was a black woman.
She was from Africa somewhere and uh,
I supply,
I said yes,
he goes,
that's a slave.
And that was in Dubai,
I believe back in the day.
I'm sorry to anybody from Dubai.
I know you guys have come a very long
way,
but slavery was the,
was order of the day for in a lot of
countries.
I'm not just picking on you in a lot of
countries and a lot of countries,
it was,
it was the order of the day.
I mean the idea that slavery would no
longer be a case.
The idea that this would be outrageous
to the world,
um,
in 1940 would be certainly in 1910 or
something,
it would have been like what now it will
always go on.
Slavery's is,
uh,
is,
is in order,
is the way of life.
I mean,
you know,
I think though today with the ability to
film slave auctions when your cell phone
and then stream that shit I [inaudible]
dot com or whatever this is,
the more you learn about people and how,
how similar we all are and how,
you know,
Sam Harris had a really interesting ted
talk about this,
about the idea that you,
you have to be able to have a
conversation about what is the most
optimal way to live for a human being.
What is the most optimal?
Is it,
is it true that women are at their best
when having to wear a full Burka in 120
degree heat?
That's a good question.
Is,
is,
and by the way,
are all opinions are welcome at the
table.
Are you interested,
I'm quoting Sam here,
but are you interested in the Taliban's
point of view on physics?
No.
And,
and does,
there's someone who does,
does for that matter and he talks about
himself is his point of view on string
theory,
which he knows nothing about.
Uh,
as valid as somebody who studies string
theory.
No,
no,
but we get it.
There's a tendency to kind of go,
well,
you know,
that's your culture and I'm not going to
get involved in it,
even though it's might seem brutal by my
standards.
You hear this a lot with like the aztecs
and human sacrifice,
and it's very taboo to talk about how it
was Barbara,
cause you know,
that was them.
You and me and Steven Rinella had a
conversation about that.
Rinella literally didn't believe me when
I told them they sacrificed 80,000.
Was it?
Is that the number was a number when
they'd sacrificed the,
the,
um,
the people who are not a huge sign of
ICAN,
temple of [inaudible].
Is that how you say it too?
Alcon,
but apparently they'd sacrificed some
fucking insane number of slaves.
So it's so crazy that if you tell a
rational personally,
Steve Rinelli,
he's like,
why I can't,
I can't be true until you go and read
about it.
And he'd go,
how,
how horrible where people then,
yeah,
they could sacrifice.
I really want to say it was 80,000
people then.
That was the number,
the numbers,
I don't know.
I mean,
that's a crazy,
it's like in a couple of days,
they,
all the people that worked on the temple
apparently after it was over,
they just sacrificed them.
Wow.
Just a minute.
The aztecs,
they,
one of the things they say is Cortez to
able to conquer the aztecs much,
easily over a lot more easily because
the aztecs had neighbors that fucking
hated them because they aspects would go
in and basically if you weren't,
you know,
an Aztec,
which means you a person of the son,
you'd get sacrificed.
So their neighbors were like,
are you Spanish guys?
500 guys really will help you.
100% of those.
Fuck,
we hate him.
You know?
So have you been to cheech and Eatsa?
No,
dude,
there's a fucking platform and cheech
needs,
so with the Mayans used to behead
people,
they have the sacrifice.
There was this,
there's this like thing,
it's like a demon.
It's lying on its back.
And they would sacrifice the people and
the stomach area where they sacrificed
people.
It was kind of grooved out from all the
bodies had been slicing on it day on.
Well,
that's why.
That's why,
oh my God,
I'm wrong.
It's way more is high.
It's estimates.
The number of persons sacrifice and
central Mexico in the 15th century was
as high as 250,000 per year.
But um,
go to the construction of temple a t I
don't know how to say this.
He,
I contentious number by the way.
Of course it is.
And people,
like people,
a lot of people were like bullshit.
And there's a lot of historians that had
did the,
and publishing my book,
Bro,
I'm jacking it up 100,000.
If I was,
if I was a a historian,
I was like,
yeah,
40 million people died on the shores.
Although the whole male population was
trying to be warriors.
It was,
uh,
you know,
what is the,
uh,
c just google 80,000 aztecs sacrificed
temple of tea.
I don't know how to say the word icon to
a con.
I forget out.
How'd he say it?
But I believe what they did was they
built this fucking spectacular struck,
spectacular structure and then killed
everybody worked on it.
They just killed the union.
Kind of like El Chapo when you'd build a
tunnel for him and he's like,
can know where it is.
Sorry,
could,
could you talk apparently to have a
party for him and then you guys,
thanks for working on the tunnel.
They have a party to toast champagne and
here's some lead poisoning as well.
Super,
super hammered when hookers and then
shoot him in the head while they're
sleeping and can't have people know.
They said that the Soviets would do
that.
Like when,
when you would build a tunnel,
did you ever hear that story about how
we figured out that implementer,
what does this,
this is it I say that will make that
larger please.
Uh,
tiene no tiene,
no Chit [inaudible].
Hmm.
Um,
I don't think that's the same one.
I 80,000 came up with it because that's
the number of people.
Okay.
Maybe I've seen it said,
well,
I think also when one of the things you
have to deal with when you're dealing
with a,
an English deciphering of really ancient
Aztec and Mayan code is that it's
phonetic.
So like there's sounds that they made
that they're trying to replicate with
English words,
but they weren't really designed for
English lettering,
you know?
I mean,
they're designed,
they're hieroglyphs,
they have the,
they,
the way they wrote and spoke.
It's very,
very different than the way we do.
You know,
they had a,
um,
like some of the Mayan writing in
particular.
What does it say there,
Jamie?
He troward thousands of,
um,
some of the,
the um,
God,
some of the Mayan languages were like
images that like,
like the tenants,
we kind of described it this way.
He was like,
you have a,
like an eyeball and a picture and then
you'd have a saw and you'd have a,
the bug,
the ant,
an ant,
and then you'd have the flower,
the rose.
And that's how you would say I saw aunt
rose.
That's a weird,
yeah,
yeah.
Because we just assume that everyone
should,
what is like,
what is writing?
Writing is some symbols that you make
that correspond to certain sounds that
we've all agreed in our own personal
definitions that we have.
And in societies,
we've all agreed that this sound means a
certain thing.
We argue the parameters of what that
means.
Right?
And that's why people get super offended
when someone says it like,
uh,
like words are violence.
Okay,
okay.
Like you're,
you're fucking with the real.
Exactly.
Don't know if violence and never been
punched in the face.
You haven't seen somebody like get sold
by all the silos.
Say it's so important for young people
to understand that the difference
between things and,
and there's a real tendency to equate,
equate.
For example,
you wrote a memo at Google and it made
an unsafe work environment for women and
your healer.
Now you're Hitler,
Hitler.
And by the way,
you know,
crab boats,
coal mines and Navy Seals,
they have a pretty dangerous work
environment as well.
So let's,
let's,
let's talk about the fucking difference
because it's very,
it's,
it gets very weird and dangerous and
meaningless.
And in fact,
in my opinion,
when you equate everything,
when you basically say,
you know,
you,
you shouted at me,
that's assault versus breaking my nose.
And we have lots of different examples
of that.
It does a disservice to people that have
suffered real,
you know,
violence.
You know what I think is going on man,
and I could sum it up in Warren word
tribalism.
There's a natural inclination that we
have to form likeminded groups and
defend our position to the death.
And this is what people are doing.
And it's not that you're wrong,
he's right or he's right or wrong.
It's that all of us are acting like
people trying to protect our team.
That's right.
And that is a,
it's an incorrect way of behaving.
So if you say that like words are
violence,
like guess what?
And
no,
they're not.
Go Fuck yourself too.
Was that violent?
This is what I say.
I'm talking about this in my standup,
but it,
and,
and you know,
it's much easier to be full against
something.
It's really easy to be against that.
We joined a team.
What happens is you don't have to do the
thinking.
He let the,
let the leader do all the thinking.
You've got the bullet points.
Now what your job as a soldier is to put
down the other team.
It's much more difficult.
And think about this for young people
listening,
it's way harder to define what your,
for defining what you're actually for.
Like so if you're a revolutionary,
you want to burn down the whole,
the whole,
you know the whole house.
What are you going to replace it with
men,
that's really important and
revolutionary.
They did
with Libya.
Revolutionaries.
Forget that shit all the time about like
when they came,
they saw and he died.
Right?
You've got really good,
bad guy.
Cool.
Now what?
Now?
What are you replacing it with?
Yes.
Well welcome to the power of vacuum.
You hope you're going to be dead before
this fucking becomes a disaster and a
failed state.
Well you're not.
That's,
that's my problem when when people,
and we have a lot of people in our
government that look at a problem and
go,
oh,
it's isis.
What we need to do is get authorization
to kill more of them in other places.
So what you're talking about is groups
that identify as isis and that's going
to solve the problem.
My problem with that typically is that
it goes back to that,
one of my favorite sayings is it's not
what you think.
What you think is way less important
than how you think.
Because a lot of times if you pay
attention to your thinking exactly the
way your enemies snaking,
I'm not so sure that that's how you do
it.
I'm not so sure that bombing and
shooting your way out of that problem is
the way to go.
It might be in some cases I think you
need seal team six,
et Cetera for certain shitheads but we
can't see the Line of defense.
Everyone has to know that they're real.
Yeah.
That's like one of the most important
things about the elite forces of the
government or of our military.
He said people need to know the real.
You need to know that's real cause like
there's 100,000 whatever the fuck.
There are people right now that are just
ready to go.
All you have to do is press a button
launch.
Thank God.
Thank God for Tim Kennedy,
etc. Exactly.
Cause remember this,
you need walls,
you need strong walls.
Those walls.
You haven't seen enough bad people.
That's right.
You don't cause there aren't,
the Mongols are out there.
They're out there.
Yeah.
Look at Libya.
It's,
you're out there.
That's right.
And these people,
by the way,
that are in the military that the only
ones that are experiencing it,
you're,
you're back here.
You're passing judgment on there saying,
hey,
there's zombies.
Like,
Hey,
we'll let the fucking world's gone
crazy.
Hey,
they're selling slaves in the streets.
Like we need to all know that there are
people that are in some really horrible
parts of the world right now that can
give you valuable information.
It doesn't mean we should kill those
people.
It doesn't mean we should fucking nation
build.
But we need to be aware of the landscape
and keep this in mind though too,
is it's not.
That would be hard strength.
You need men like,
you know,
Tim Kennedy,
et Cetera.
Those guys who are,
who are our protectors,
who we can push a button go,
hey those fucking guys want.
And there are people out there that want
to kill us for sure.
But I always think that it's also
important to remember that those guys
are doing that to protect the softer
strengths in our community.
The people that are creative,
people that are inventing,
you can't have a doctor working on a
cure for cancer and had the Mongols come
over and smash all his fucking beakers.
Exactly.
That's why you need those.
So you need both.
Problem is you knew you do need both.
And the people on one side don't want to
recognize the people and the other side
cause they wished they didn't have to
exist.
Exactly what they do have to exist.
Of course they do.
There's a balance to this fucking thing.
You know,
and here's the thing,
people in Libya,
if Kevin Spacey had a TV show in Libya,
we fucked all the grips right in the
mouth before every episode they would
go.
That's what he does.
He's the fucking store.
You would just talk with this stuff.
Kevin's business,
this,
this bombs going off of the streets with
your mouth open.
Your mouth is fucking ied at every
fucking dead dog on the side of the
road.
Kick them over.
You lose your leg?
Yeah.
Okay.
He fucked your mouth.
What's the appointment?
He's Kevin Spacey is Kevin's has to guys
to present as you fucked your mom.
Come on.
You went to work or not to start off,
what do you want to do?
What you went to do,
you went to live that isn't offensive.
Accents,
personable.
I don't even know why you do it because
it doesn't sound like anyone that's ever
lived.
It's so offensive.
No ones.
It's not a bad accent.
It's exactly what someone who doesn't
know how to speak English with Sally.
I would wish that I could speak Arabic
so I could realize how fucking shitty my
fee bad Arabic would be if I learned
Arabic for a couple of years and tried
to talk to those people.
Make Fun of me.
Go ahead.
I give you full permission to make fun
of an American pretending to be or
trying to speak Arabic.
Arabic is a very difficult language to
learn.
Too hard for me to hide my friend,
my friend.
It's so hard.
It's such a rich language compared to
like French Haley.
Give Kevin Spacey a race if he was in
Libya.
If you had a show in Livia,
Netflix,
Libya would give them a raise
would go,
this is method duct.
This is our president would do fuck them
out of everyone.
He can.
Fuck.
This is what I like.
How you are behaving as a president all
the time.
Go Frank Underwood is a fucking grade.
Just pull out a machine gun.
Shoot through the fucking ceiling just
in the room.
Kiss him on the mouth and Lee's not a
bad fucking that's,
that's a good,
you play a good Arab desk pot dude.
Who's a pervert.
This,
this is what you'd do.
You'll fuck every once a month.
Do you have the president will have to
it.
There's nothing I can do it.
They just get drunk as fuck on,
on booze made out of camel pice.
I take camel piss and they mixed wheat.
Hear about how the president of the
longtime dictator of Yemen got power.
He was a major in the army.
Oh,
I'm scared.
He just showed up at uh,
like he was there.
He was just going to be one of the
majors.
And the president was having a cabinet
meeting and apparently you can look this
up,
Jamie.
Apparently he basically put a briefcase
down or a suitcase down and just pull
out two guns and went,
well cln or Kush,
Kush,
and wild.
The entire decapitated.
The government goes,
I'm in charge now.
Uh Huh.
Well you was it.
It's in the 70s you ever see what a
Pistol Grip Uzi looks like?
See you later.
And then he rolled the nation with
what's called an iron fist for about 30
years.
I'm sure you watched Narcos,
right?
I certainly have.
How about that fucking show?
How about Pablo Escobar?
Amazing.
You know what's crazy is apparently
Columbia's bounced back tremendously and
Columbia is like a really cool place to
visit.
I've heard,
I've had friends who've been there,
I want to go badly,
and that they're most,
they saved the most beautiful people
voice,
certainly the most beautiful women on
the planet where the famed,
it's just amazing that they bounced back
so quickly from being under control of a
drug,
Lord.
Yeah.
You know that the Pablo Escobar story is
so goddamn crazy.
It is crazy.
Ladies and gentlemen,
you do not live forever.
Listen to me,
make coke legal.
It'll solve 80% of our problems.
Just make coke,
legal,
Agri,
just make coke legal.
I agree.
Are we really pretending that whiskey is
any better than coke?
We really pretending that.
I don't know coke.
I don't do coke.
Coke is even better cause it's
devastating quickly.
So you do a lot of cooked.
You can drink for 40 years and before
you realize you're like,
holy fuck,
I don't have a house or anything else.
Yeah you fucking do below duplo everyday
for three years and come talk to me and
see how your life works at night.
I think that less people would be
inclined to do it if you made it legal
and then let everybody see the
consequences of its use in a realistic
way.
I think probably part of the problem
with things being illegal is that people
can't choose for themselves.
And if people can't choose themselves,
it's forbidden and forbidden things
just like that blank deck back during
the revolutionary war come more tasty.
They become more test day duck or a
barrier to switching.
I mean that's all forbidden and stuff,
but you can't,
human beings should not be able to tell
it.
This is the bottom line.
Yeah.
Human beings should not be able to tell
other human beings what they can or
can't do with their own bodies where it
doesn't make sense.
It doesn't make sense.
If you have some things that are illegal
like cigarettes and some things that are
legal like whiskey that I don't have a
problem with.
Cigarettes being legal and I don't have
a problem with whiskey being legal and
you should be able do whatever you want,
but I think it should be with all of the
things like why,
how come these things right?
Why can't,
you know,
do you telling me that whiskeys legal,
but mushrooms aren't like that's what
year is this?
What are we doing?
Are we pretending?
We pretending there's no science.
I we in wishcraft days or no?
Yeah.
Let me know when the witchcraft days are
over because I would say witchcraft
should be over now.
Yeah.
So if it's over now we have to look at
science.
Right?
Right.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well you can't let me by oxytocin from
or Oxycontin from the fucking pharmacy.
You can't let go scissor control because
I stubbed my fucking toe.
Yeah.
What do you think would happen if we,
we made cocaine legal would win with
consumption.
Go Up.
Yes.
For a little bit.
Yeah.
A lot of girls would show their inner ho
did let it out.
A lot of dudes and business debt that
they'll never fucking complete.
That's that Joe was that joke.
Cause like when you do cocaine,
you want to start a business together.
The joke,
funny.
Great Joke.
It's so true.
So true.
I mean open a doughnut shop.
What the fuck we doing to talk to you
about their passion?
Yeah.
Passion.
It's a weird drug to be around.
I was in Jamaica and I,
I don't,
I'm not a big truck guy,
but I did,
I did a bag of coke,
a whole bag.
A guy sold it to me.
I was smoking weed and this guy was
willing,
we're hanging.
He goes,
do you ever do blow
was like,
I'm not a big cotton,
not a drug guy.
I don't even smoke weed much.
And he goes,
try this.
And I did one line of cocaine,
Jamaican cocaine,
and I was like,
this must have fallen off a boat because
this shit's got a yellow little thing to
it.
And I was like,
first of all,
I'm the coolest motherfucker on the
planet.
Second of all,
we're going to play ping pong for good
three hours.
Third of all,
they're going to go to my fucking hotel
room and I'm going to wake my girlfriend
up and tell her that I'm a genius and
then wait for it.
I'm going to write for three,
four hours,
keep doing cocaine,
and I'm going to change my career
because I'm gonna write a three hour a
bit on how God is a roster foreign.
How funny is that?
And I wrote stand up and God has Ross
foreign kept waking my girlfriend,
I'm going,
I'm writing the funniest shit.
You're not completed.
She was like,
you wait all this.
And I looked at it,
then I passed out.
I have to before my heart could give
out.
And I looked at the shit I wrote about
eight hours later and it was just,
it was basically God's a roster and he
speaks like a Jamaican.
And that was the joke.
And I thought it was brilliant when I
was fucking doing the blow in the right
state of mind.
If you captured that idea,
like if you gave that bit to Dave
Chappelle.
Sure.
He maybe he could make something.
Not Brian Calvin.
He's high on cocaine in Jamaica.
It's like you would need to to figure
out what the fuck you were trying to
say.
Like I've written things down on
marijuana and I,
oh,
I'll figure it out when I'm sober.
But then you try to read it when you're
sober and you're like,
tell the fuck was my point.
Yeah.
What is the point here?
Yeah,
but they did studies on people on drugs.
I think cocaine and had them play music
musicians and stuff,
and they were like,
I thought I was amazing.
And then they listen to what they're
planning.
Like,
Oh,
what the fuck?
Well,
the Arctic was made.
What killed the music after 1968 it was,
you know,
the Monterey Music,
I mean rock and roll festival with John
Hendricks and the Mamas and Papas.
So what,
what,
what gave birth?
That renaissance was marijuana and
psychedelics.
That that was it.
That enhance the music.
Oh,
for sure.
Cocaine and heroin came in.
You've got this fucking killed.
It killed it.
People die.
Yes.
Literally Boogie man.
Well,
that was last year.
Some of that shit is good.
Yeah,
there's a lot of good stuff,
but it's the idea behind that music.
Like how about showgirls?
Showgirls,
that movie would not exist if it wasn't
for cocaine.
That movie is a Goddamn cocaine movie
that movie's a move where you could see
the blood coming out of their nose while
they were watching the edit.
It's like,
keep that in.
No,
fucking keep that.
Can you make it longer or flopping in
the pool?
Oh,
it's a terrible movie.
Duff fucking sex scene between the girl
from saved by the bell.
What is her name?
Elizabeth something.
Berkeley Berkeley.
Who was the dude?
Kyle mcglaughlin clank.
That guy,
she was on naked who?
She's a very beautiful,
but there's a scene when they were in
the pool where they're making love Brian
Cowen.
Yep.
And if a girl was doing that,
if you are having sex with a girl that
you were having sex with a girl and she
started doing that,
you would immediate and I know you,
you're a pervert.
He would still immediately call a
doctor.
You,
you is perverted as you are,
as much as you love ladies.
So I got sentenced to be that Kyle
mclachlan golf,
Elizabeth Berkley,
and she's wrapped around and she's
flopping around in the pool.
You would call the police,
call the police.
This is only part of it.
So this is okay,
I can handle this.
This pitch is getting crazy.
Woo them titties are flopping.
First of all,
if you're calm,
mclachlan,
walk one couple shoots all over your own
face.
Here's the problem.
His problem,
she starts flailing.
Oh cool.
It's like throwing herself back.
Got a call,
the doctor not,
and by the way,
he blew out both his rotator cuffs in
the scene.
He had to get both of his shoulders
completely reconstructed.
I only hope you're telling me shut up.
Fuck that.
He tore his Labor.
Him.
He tore the bicep tendon from the bone.
Goddammit.
She's flopping around like she's dying.
Go.
You gotta let me know if you're going to
do that.
You can't just them because if you just
die for like girls just lit.
She's crazy.
Yeah.
You might pray.
Let you a break my dick too,
but foot if I let her die.
What have you let her die like you
asshole.
She was having a seizure.
You kept,
you came inside of her.
She was having us
seizure and you came inside of her dude.
What the fuck?
I thought I thought you was just freaky.
You didn't see we have a video of it.
You didn't see there was something wrong
with her.
You fucking selfish all you care to
problems coming.
Yeah,
she was dying,
man.
She's flipping around.
She can't breathe.
She hasn't seen anymore.
Oh,
oh,
I gotta take it easy.
How can you raping her here?
You're holding onto her.
You keeping her inside of you.
Just let her go.
There's no way she's trying to just go
on for,
can you get
a whiff of it?
It's just on repeat.
Oh,
sorry.
Get away.
She's trying to get away.
All right,
well,
congratulations on all that.
There's nothing funny about rape,
ladies and gentlemen,
but this isn't rape and that's why I
made a joke.
Okay.
I'm holding my,
I'm,
I'm like,
it's a joke about something you
absolutely know is definitely not rape
and I'm being ridiculous joke.
Yeah.
Everybody.
It's funny how you to that nowadays in
today's call.
I know,
I know.
You're ready.
You ready to get mad at me.
Don't get mad at me.
Everybody.
We need to stop doing this.
We need,
we need to figure out what to be so
literal.
Yeah.
Being so literal.
Start start realizing this with,
we had real problems in the world and
they've Kevin space things about
example.
I was just trying to be funny about the
Libyan.
Yeah.
Don't let Chapman's basic grab your
deck.
I get it.
I'm not saying that that's not what I'm
saying.
What I'm saying is we just need to be
super cognizant of the fact that there
is a real highly likelihood that we have
achieved the highest level of
civilization the world has ever known.
It's right now,
and we need to be aware of that.
We made progress.
In other words,
in any massive.
Yeah,
and any seemingly important thing that
you want to go off on.
You're taking energy away from
recognizing the fact that we need to,
the crucial elements of this amazing
thing that we have right now,
and one of the things that we have to do
is we've got to avoid this weird
tribalism that I keep talking about
tribe I thinking because it's not just
sexual,
it's political,
it's socioeconomic.
It's fucking blue collar guy.
And I'm like,
no,
you're a fucking person.
Yeah.
We're all just,
well,
you're in a trap.
Human beings are,
were,
were genetically predisposed to be
tribal.
It's US versus them.
Pass that.
If we're a tribe,
okay,
we should be tried.
Planet Earth.
There's famous Ronald Reagan's speech.
Remember that Ronald Reagan's speech,
he gave a speech,
I'd want to say it's in front of
Congress,
but he gave a speech where he was
talking about how quickly we would set
aside our differences if we were
attacked by an alien force from another
world.
Right.
And all of us would realize,
yeah,
just heat or the Cold War.
I mean this is like look very scary
times.
Do you remember growing up were the same
age worried about nuclear war?
We were always worried.
A real threat of nuclear annihilation
was actually something we all thought
about every day.
Yes.
And the,
the further we're away from that,
the more we forgot.
And,
but if you just pay attention to Libya,
just pay attention to Afghanistan,
pay attention to Iraq,
pay attention to all sorts of parts of
the world where North Korea things are
not fucking stable at all.
We are assuming the thing's going to
stay stable because they're stable right
here,
but we're all on the same God damn
planet.
Yeah.
And that's a real problem.
It's a real problem.
And I think we're better at figuring
this out than we have ever been before.
But there's a lot of hiccups and bumps
along the way.
But one of the things it's going to
eliminate a good percentage of them is
if we can isolate tribalism and see it
when it's happening and call it for what
it is and avoid it.
And it's very,
it's very tough now the tough,
and I'll tell you why,
because they used to be one of the great
people always was talking about how
religion was responsible for so much
violence,
but they always forget.
Religion was also responsible for a
great deal of unification.
So there was a national narrative in
this country,
right?
We were a Christian nation for a long
time in this country.
And there was a national narrative.
There were just certain things that
people collectively agreed upon.
And usually it started in the church,
or at least it had its values in the
church.
I would argue that,
you know,
even our constitution has been greatly
influenced by the Judeo Christian ethic.
Uh,
all men are created equal,
for example,
as a Christian idea.
Did you,
there's no way to prove it biologically
are mathematically,
but it's something we all kind of,
it's a nice starting point.
It's literally what our justice system
is predicated on.
All men are created equal.
Even though Lebron James and I have
totally different genomes and he's an
Avatar and we're not equal.
If you kill me,
you kill Lebron.
You do the same amount of time in jail.
Theoretically,
that would be the idea behind our thing.
He should be worth more.
He shouldn't be worth a little bit more
than that.
I would agree.
And,
and what's really interesting is how
different we are,
how we like all strive not to be equal,
right?
I want to be better than everybody else,
but we believe in it.
It's a really nice starting point.
You know,
something that I read that's like really
important.
I always bring it up.
It's
people that free will or the ability to
do whatever you want.
The uh,
like,
uh,
a freedom of expression of freedom of
pursuits breeds inequality.
Because if you give people true total
freedom,
some people are going to try harder than
others.
Some people are going to be a bad thing.
Some people want to be Tyler Perry and
have a fucking island.
Yeah.
Did the big,
they remembered.
There's a fundamental difference,
right?
Well Simmons,
between being American and a communist
and American believes in equality of
opportunity.
I'm not saying we have that,
but that would be the goal.
Then there's equality of outcome.
The only way to have equality of outcome
is to keep down the people that work
harder at,
they're smarter and more talented.
Yeah.
You got to make everybody equal.
That's to me a fundamental evil.
That is,
that's my problem with Marxism.
What the fuck you,
the only way to do this with force,
it's the problem is it's never worked.
No.
I sent everyone worked and it almost
always leads to like mass murder.
Right,
exactly,
but nobody wants to think that because
the idea behind is beautiful.
Okay,
so need to compete.
We should just share money and Sharewell
Pol Pot,
Mao Tse Tung Hitler and Stalin
dictatorships.
Hitler was more of a fascist.
Yeah.
People also don't realize that the Nazis
were the national socialists.
That's right.
The real problem with the idea in
execution,
but the idea in the most romantic view
possible is that we don't need to
compete with each other.
We don't need to be greedy.
And then we could all share resources
and wealth and we all get along and have
income equality.
But I see this,
I think it's important to recognize the
thought behind the best version of that.
Right?
The thought behind the best version of
that is someone that just really wants
to be an amazing person.
Right.
And they really want other people to be
amazing people as well.
I want everybody to be fine.
They strive for everybody to get along.
So let's just like combine our wealth.
We don't have to get rich,
delicious,
like provide for the poor.
It's super important.
Let's like give healthcare to everybody
before anything.
Hey man,
we don't need the military.
Let's just relax.
Okay.
You're going to get invaded,
right?
As a matter of time before the Russian
shows borders.
Yes.
And they're going to fuck your mouth.
But on that,
let me pick it back up and doing that
forever.
Remember that the idea of Adam Smith's
idea and the idea behind making money
was also that when you are rich and when
you were an Aristocrat,
you have a responsibility to give back
to your community.
That's very,
that was,
that was very much ingrained in the
British sensibility and even in the
American aristocracy,
like the Kennedy's in this country,
rich and you have a responsibility.
Correct.
Bill Gates,
one of the boys,
it'll cases in gendered himself with a
lot of us is that if he does an amazing
amount of charity,
amazing,
creative with it too.
And by the way still lives like a
fucking gangster.
It's not even like it's putting a dent
in his lifestyle.
I mean he's,
he's helping so many people out with the
Bill Gates Foundation.
That's the same thing.
Warren Buffet gave his kids up,
now it's up to $7 billion.
He was like,
go make the world a better place.
And,
and,
and he's got all kinds of charities.
But that is by all accounts a super
sweet guy.
Yes,
they're really humble.
But went back to what you were talking
about about how we're breaking into
tribes.
I think that we have lost any kind of
national narrative,
and what I mean by
that is that people don't even trust
their own institutions with the
crumbling of any kind of like religious
institution.
It seems that now people are looking
for,
they don't trust main sources of
information so they don't trust most of
the mainstream media has earned their
shitty reputation.
Cause now it's about clickbait.
Now it's about kind of creating some
that you want to be first.
Not True.
Being true is not as important as being
the first one with the story and Blah,
blah,
blah.
I think that there's certainly our
agendas with liberal media,
conservative media,
they both have their own agendas of shit
that people do.
Exactly.
So what happens is people,
I think media's favor abilities and the
single fucking digits or something like
that though among most Americans.
Let me give you an example of how this
works.
Sometimes.
I'm somebody who wrote a good article
about the debate that Eddie Bravo and I
had about the world being flat,
but the art,
the,
the title of the article was Joe Rogan
argues with someone about the world
being flat.
So it seems like you saying that the
world is flat,
so you immediately click it,
but right away the first sentence has,
God bless Joe Rogan,
and then he was in a conversation with
his friend who was arguing with the
possibility and then like,
but like,
okay,
I see what you did.
Yeah,
I kind of let you hooked him.
You got it.
You did it.
You did it right.
It's okay.
But because of that,
it,
even though it's very insignificant,
a bunch of people have said to me,
bro,
you used to believe the fucking earth
was flat.
I saw that.
I was like,
no.
Yeah,
I bet you didn't.
They didn't see CNN and Huffington post
both.
Do they all do that?
I can't stand either one of those.
I think CNN,
Huffington post started terrible,
but both of them do that.
They,
they'll,
they'll hit you with this.
Like Donald Trump just said one word to
change the entire presidency.
Let me see what the fuck you fuck.
Yeah,
Dude.
Keith Olbermann is signed off is one of
my favorite things to watch.
I like him.
He's a,
he's a a spicy character,
super liberal,
but I liked him anyway.
We're liberal.
But I think you have to have that look.
I'm a,
at least who I am right now.
I'm an open minded,
friendly person that allows for all
ideas.
Yes.
Keith Olbermann is as far left as you're
going to get.
And I liked the fact that he was out
there.
I think having a wacky dude out there
standing in front of a cable access show
background with red on one side and blue
on the other.
And he's got his notes in front of them
and he's wearing a tie and delivers
these super eloquent like dissertations.
But he's decided he's going to step
away.
And uh,
he said he's retiring from politics
because he thinks that donald trump's
done.
He'd done it.
He thinks Donald Trump,
he lists a series of things.
Keith Overman,
it says he's retiring from political
Calamari.
Yeah.
And he lists a series of things.
Oh,
you're no good for him.
He's a fucking formative.
He knows his shit.
I would not want to debate that guy.
You know what to say.
She did one dude.
He did one thing though.
That was pretty fucking stupid.
What was that you knew when that Tomi
Lahren girl,
um,
she,
she's like a conservative hot chick,
hot white girl with blonde hair.
No,
she put a flag on like,
she was like holding up a flag and a
photo and he wrote something about not,
you shouldn't use the flag that way.
And then Donald Trump Jr tweeted a photo
of the two of them together with her,
with the flag and keep opening,
then wrapped in a flag and said,
you know something about him being
stupid.
Some,
some funny thing that's also caddy to
say that it stopped being catty with
this fucking tall ships.
And I understand you don't like her
because she's a hot girl that's a
conservative and she says ridiculous
shit sometimes and she does.
But like you gotta save your attacks.
You can't throw rocks at every target.
You can't stop for every dog that barks
on the way home or you never get home.
This is why George Washington talked
about the importance of civility.
You need civility if you start attacking
each other.
If I start,
you know I heard a rumor that Donald
Trump in meetings when he was
negotiating somebody car,
he go,
oh Jesus,
your breath,
holy fuck.
You get the worst breath and the age
just gets you on your heels.
He'd be like,
what does it do that?
Yeah,
he apparently,
that was some of the tactics.
He would just insult you and get you off
your pins.
You're emotional and you're insecure
about your breath.
Now.
You can't talk as much.
You know the little techniques.
I think Donald Trump would be super fun
if he was like your uncle that you were
going to take your girlfriend to when
you first started dating.
Like say if you dated a girl and it's
like three months in and you're in love
and you're,
you're parked outside your uncle's house
and like,
listen,
we're going to spark,
sparked this joint and we're going to go
meet my fucking crazy uncle.
He's beautiful,
he's flawed,
but he's crazy and don't look at his
hair and we're just going to leave.
And then like
when he talks about himself,
just seem fascinated and you passed the,
you guys are lucky.
I'm here and you'd go in there so high
that you're barely alive.
So you got like 180 beats per minute.
Your Heart's going.
What are we doing dude?
I,
I golfed with his caddie,
Obama's caddy.
George W's caddy and Cameron.
I know you golf three times.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
Three times.
Those guys at the same guy.
The same guy.
Same Guy.
Oh caddy for all the one number makes it
sound like there's three camps.
No,
I wish.
no.
And he said,
he said Best Golfer in the group,
hands down by far.
Donald Trump,
he said,
and t they didn't,
doesn't like trump but,
but basically said he's very nice,
very funny and crack them as they looked
at me,
he,
I didn't think I'm doing.
And Cameron was like,
I think it got to be a lot on your
plate.
And then apparently he drove by there.
I just club and key largo whenever Mar
Largo and these people were there and he
just bought as they were driving by in
the car,
he goes,
you guys have any idea how lucky you
are,
you're in the best club in the world.
And he just kept driving.
He's,
he's a very entertaining dude.
I'm,
I'm a little bummed out at myself that I
didn't do celebrity apprentice.
Really?
Yeah.
Because uh,
the celebrity apprentice was available
when we were doing the second run,
a fear factor and they asked me to do it
and I was one of the,
were on NBC.
I was like,
God,
I want to move my family to New York for
a few months and like maybe,
and you know,
Mrs Rogan was down for it,
but I was like,
I don't know if that's a smart move.
It seems like a lot of work for
something that's not really my thing.
I don't,
I don't really want it do it that kind
of wish I did it.
He has no trump.
Yeah.
I don't know how well you get to know
them.
Get to know him.
If you let me hang onto them.
Yeah,
I'm sure he's letting me be close to
smell you.
I'm sure he'd be a blast.
I'm sure he'd be a lot of fun because
it's one of those lives.
Maybe I could talk to them to fix
things.
Maybe we could just tell him to just
take it down a notch.
It would be okay.
He's not interested in,
the problem with him is that he's not
interested in what he doesn't know.
I,
that's how I feel.
Maybe I feel like we could have a sit in
with homeboy.
Yeah.
Just to just him.
You get him on his podcast,
come out.
It's wearing him out.
Just relax.
Relax.
He never drinks.
It doesn't course that's the problem.
It's part of the problem.
Like you need a separation from the
normal states of consciousness.
Otherwise you're acting on momentum your
entire life,
so you like a child.
They did it.
They did a psychological profile that I
thought it was interesting on him,
which was that he's always been on the
outside.
So his dad wasn't allowed to be part of
the developers in New York.
He had to go elsewhere and he was always
kind of like kept out.
And he is now in the media.
So his way of,
uh,
and I think Roy Cohn,
the infamous lawyer,
um,
was his mentor and said,
attack,
always attack to meet any threat with an
attack.
He listened to the reason why he's
president is because Obama mocked him at
the press corps conference.
Remember that?
Remember that press corps dinner meeting
thing?
And Obama mocked him and said,
I'm one thing that you're never going to
be.
And that's the president.
And he's go,
oh,
for real?
Yeah,
I'm fucking older than you knew.
Can I lock?
I'm ridiculous.
Look at my hair and I'm still going to
be the president.
How about you go fuck yourself?
How about you don't know what you're
dealing with here?
How about he was amazing.
He was so amazing.
And the debates,
he was so entertaining.
It was funny.
And even George.
Jeff Bush said,
you can't insult your way to the White
House,
my friend.
Yeah,
you can't change.
You can,
you definitely can.
When you're fighting.
Look,
it's like what's,
what's really ironic is one of the
things that's come out to over turn your
notes things both punters I don't,
but I do know about is talking shit,
I'm good at talking shit and I
understand the strategies behind talking
shit.
And one of the strategies behind talking
shit was that Hillary felt very
confident that if she could get donald
into a position of being the primary
candidate against her,
she would have an easy path to the White
House because she felt like Donald was
so ridiculous that there the other
candidates by even being associated with
him in the same party,
there would be revolt.
It would be chaos.
And if he won he'd be an easy target.
And there's all this like written banter
back and forth where she was trying to
connect him with the most ridiculous
people.
Like,
of course,
you know,
there was a,
there's just all this like strategy with
Ted Cruz where they had this idea of how
they would make them all look,
marginalize,
easy path,
the White House,
and he just threw a monkey ridge
right into that theory.
It's like stupid.
I'm the worst person for you to argue.
I'm going to say,
I'm going to say you should be in jail.
Lock her up,
lock her up,
and I'll make shit up to make up my own
facts.
If I have to,
I'll do whatever I want and I'll get
caught on tape talking about how girls
just let you grab him.
The Pussy.
Yeah,
just a few weeks out.
no problem.
It was locker room talk.
Not a problem.
Let's talk about uranium.
Dude,
I thought he was done when I heard that.
I thought,
oh,
he's definitely done no precedent.
By the way.
What's really shocking?
What was it?
44% of the white women voted for him
because they want that Dick.
Well,
they weren't that.
They weren't that offended by it,
I guess.
Right.
This is a lot of women right now that
just shut off this podcast.
You fucking asshole.
Right when I was starting to think you
weren't an asshole.
It's just comedy.
I don't really think that 44%.
I think people didn't like Hillary.
They didn't trust her.
I think if you looked at what it is in
terms of like,
um,
like good versus evil,
it's known evil versus unknown,
you know,
it was,
I think it's unknown.
He's known evil or known corruption
versus a sideshow.
Like sort of a guy who's going to be
really entertaining for the next four
years but probably won't bring the
republic down.
But what if he decides to really look
out for the American people?
What if he decides to make America great
again?
What if he decides to bring back
engineering and bring back production of
goods and fucking what if he decides
that?
What if you really decided that then is
it better to take a chance?
And I think a lot of people did that.
I agree.
And then I also think we were realizing,
and we should,
this is something we need to all come to
grips with.
It is irrational,
illogical,
nonsensical,
an antiquated to have one person have
that much power in the United States of
America.
It is nonsense.
It's not something we need.
It is a,
it's a,
it's a value system and a ruler
leadership system that's designed for
small groups of people and it works very
well,
works very well for groups of hundred
and 50 people at leaves over their
dicks.
But as soon as you get to 320 million
people all trapped together on a
landmass,
you cannot have one dip shit that's good
at insulting people and standing in
front of a camera.
I don't care if it's him or the next guy
or the,
it's on a assault on Donald Trump.
It's like one person who figures out a
way to fucking manipulate and dance and
do his best.
America's got talent,
fucking preppers,
a presentation,
presentation,
representation.
One of those things to get to the point
where people go,
ah,
the other lady's boring and she keeps
fainting.
Boom and they kill.
They hit the switch for trump.
I mean,
one of the things that president always
talks about and governors talk about is
how little power they have.
You say that,
but there's real problems right now with
the environmental protection agency
being defunded.
There's real problems right now with
them deciding to start drilling in
places in Alaska that people have been
fighting for them for decades
because they're worried that in
extracting minerals from the ground,
they're going to ruin these salmon
waterways.
Well,
he can eat,
he can hit mine judges and he can,
he can appoint judges.
You do a lot of things and obviously
that cost is a big stir in political
discourse and people being active and
it's,
you're seeing like some trans woman
going to a got elected somewhere and gay
people are getting elected papers and so
you're seeing a a rebound,
which is what?
How does that work?
That's right.
He's,
he's created a lot of civic unrest and a
lot of civic organization on the other
side.
On the other side.
Yeah.
David from us talking about that.
He is.
Yeah,
he just sent me his book.
We just have to be really careful,
like really careful of getting tribal
with this.
Again,
I can't,
can't,
I hate to reiterate this,
but I think that in looking at the group
of humans as a whole,
there's a real problem that on the left
and on the right,
people have with getting attached to
their particular ideology they've
adopted and fighting against anything
that's any different and not coming to
some sort of a common understanding of
what we really need to get by in this
plant.
It's called,
it's called a couple of things.
One is there are different psychological
profiles and I've heard Jordan Peterson
talk about sort of like the left is
rooted in compassion and the right is
rooted in respect for the strong.
And then what happens is the way things
move forward is you have an idea.
I have an idea and remember something,
it's very important.
Human beings,
uh,
usually are weighing two values and
their head at one time.
Let me give you an example.
I don't believe in illegal immigration,
but I have a lot of compassion for
people who are dying to get over the
board.
If I was a border control agent,
I would probably be the guy who was
like,
come on and cause I have no,
I'm emotional,
right?
Doesn't mean that's right.
What it means is that I can sometimes
you way to values in your head,
right?
Mercy and compassion versus justice and
fair play.
Okay,
let me propose something to you.
Now,
this is gonna sound crazy for a lot of
people that were you.
A full could call me at one point in
time.
I believe in the future we will not have
boundaries in terms of places you're
allowed to travel,
not to travel,
right?
One point in time people would truly be
thought of as equal and when that point
in time happens,
you'll allow people to freely travel all
over the world.
Why can't we do that now?
First of all,
you won't even have to travel.
I think what's going to happen is when
you can interface with another brain and
that's,
that's possible,
you're going to have an experience about
what it's exactly what it's like to be a
woman.
Exactly what it's like.
By the way.
It can be a woman.
I'm going to take it.
I want to be a woman so I can see what
it's like to have sexual Lebron James,
but here's the thing,
what if she would you complain,
which you put your hands on her hips.
I will.
I'm only going to,
I'm going to be able to experience it so
then if I could interface with another
brain,
now we got a real problem because what
the fuck does that mean about my
identity?
What if they can't?
Like you can't pick what brand new
interface with like you're going to be a
girl out sex with a little broad james,
but you're a 100 pound Irish girl like
shit.
Oh boy.
You Ain't get your uterus blown.
You know?
Yeah.
Like you want like 178 pound chick from
Ecuador that can really take it.
I don't think any of that's going to
happen.
I think what's going to happen.
So you can have guys like Lebron James
who had these fantastic lives who have
sex and dunk basketballs and they're
gonna sell their experience.
You want to interface with my brain,
it's going to cost you this much money
and that is going to be the new drug.
Oh my God,
the new drug is going to be,
I want to see what it's like to be
either,
you know,
whoever it is,
the Brian James and will rise again.
Correct.
Dennis Robin will rise from the flames
like a fucking phoenix.
Be the number one superstar again in the
world.
And when you watch porn,
you're going to be able to tap into the
guy's brain and you're gonna be,
I'll have sex with anybody you want.
So that's how you thinking about Dick.
Just like he is.
Imagine that unless you pay your head
your favorite over to Dick and like,
hey,
he's thinking about Dick.
This is a confusing,
why am I coming on?
I'm thinking about God,
but ah,
Shit.
Dammit.
People get mad at your yoga and money.
Dick by that Brian Calla video.
All the fucking homeboys got a giant
Dick.
But he's thinking about dudes bugs all
the time the way,
but he folks a little hubs,
girls,
doesn't matter man.
While he's fucking all the hottest girls
digging about dude's butts.
Hold on.
Dope,
Bro.
Did you come or not?
Came immediately.
Immediately I came like a terrorist
wearing a wig in my mind.
I came like a dude strap with dynamite,
getting his dick sucked for the last
time.
Ooh.
It could give me and I took the
headphones off like,
fuck you Brian Cowen.
Dammit.
He's fucking the hottest girls.
But took it about dude's butts.
If friends and be like,
man,
I don't even know if he's telling the
truth.
I've been holding out for the Bryan
count,
virtual reality sex video.
But now god,
he's so medium and white.
I don't want to think about Duke,
right?
I know.
Oh,
I told you I had a dream.
I was gay,
right a couple of times.
Sorry about that.
On a podcast before or after you had gay
sex,
uh,
this was during,
so I don't know if that makes sense.
Dream I was game of gay in my dream.
I was like,
I can't believe I'm gay.
This is so not what I'm into.
And then I knew I was going to have to
have sex with my boyfriend who may or
may not have been Brendan Shop.
I can't remember.
It was a big guy,
a gate.
You can't really bounce back and forth
from,
I don't know man.
I've actually never really had a gay,
we didn't talk to fattiest Russell,
cause he'll tell you you're a liar.
And then all men have some sort of gay
fantasy somewhere deep in their head or
35 years,
daddy has had a conversation about truth
and versus like plural truths versus one
fixed truth.
That's a huge debate.
You know what I mean by that?
So like Nicha,
what would be the guy to talk about?
Plural truth.
So if you look up at a painting,
that painting,
is there different truths,
right?
One is that painting's beautiful and
that's all I know.
It's a beautiful item.
It,
it affects me emotionally.
That's the truth.
Right?
Then a chemist would look at that
painting and say,
well,
you're not really seeing yellow.
What you're seeing is you know your eyes
are,
are at light and then reflect.
There's a chemical in there and he'd
break down a chemical.
That's a different layer to truth.
You're saying different kinds of true
love,
right?
So true love.
I don't know what the,
that's still a really an interesting
mystery to me because I wonder if that's
a relationship with yourself.
So sometimes you're obsessed with
somebody,
right?
You love them.
You might be obsessed with the idea of
being the one that can break them.
That can be the one that,
that,
that tames them,
the one that owns them,
the one that you know gets them to
forget about all of the Dick and just
yours.
That's,
that's what a lot of relationships are
predicated on.
This terror doesn't notion of
territoriality,
right?
But does that true love,
is that what we're talking about?
Does it matter?
But,
but does,
what really matter is the moments where
you are together.
We truly care about each other,
where the intensity is almost
overwhelming and the love.
And the happiness to be with each other.
It's almost overwhelming.
That is really true.
Love all the other set of state though.
And how long does it last?
That's a good question.
And whether or not you're committed to
that person as a love,
not just a love interest,
but like as a,
uh,
an inhabitant in your,
your realm of truly loved ones.
Like what is your,
your village of Trans Cynical answer for
you on that.
So,
so I know what the Greek says.
So why do you love your children?
Why?
What is it about your children that you
love?
And this is what socrates said.
There's kind of an interesting way of
looking at it.
So he said love,
difficult to define.
You have to define it as love of
something.
Right?
And what is the one thing man loves more
than anything else?
Think about it.
Post it,
not close pussies.
Part of it was these may be a
manifestation of what you're trying to
Ken from it.
What is it?
Come on attention.
Why would you breed a,
you want to get rid of Jews,
goddammit.
Goddammit,
keep going.
You got to think deeper bro.
Like I needed to think the next level.
Why?
What is it the man loves more than
anything else?
What does he want more than anything
else?
I don't know.
What does he want you to tell me?
In mortality,
you want to live forever.
Exactly.
What puts you at the gateway wherever
with no plus
kids and your kids are your genetic
expression.
Anybody worth a fuck do you,
do you want to live forever with no
pussy forever or live for a hundred
years and just live like Jay z on a
yacht and gold underwear with is
dangerously.
I want to live dangerously.
You want to live dangerously?
Not Safely.
Fuck,
fuck.
A thousand years old.
100 years.
I'm excited.
So what you're saying about any
mortality is horse shit cause the
mortality without pussy is nonsense.
Immortality is represented in different
things.
Wash legacy.
Listen to me sweetie.
Yeah.
If someone is in my circle of friends
and somebody offers you in mortality
with no pussy or a hundred years and
pussy,
if you don't take choice number two,
lose my number.
But hold on,
hold on,
stop.
Stop texting her.
I can't work with you.
I would argue that your love of pussy
might be genetically like you've evolved
to
that.
Your love was he is.
Is your love of Pussy because you
ultimately want to spread and further
your DNA?
Well,
first of all,
I think it would be very disrespectful.
You as particularly,
oh,
of course.
Giant.
I met Vagina.
I'm talking about sexual relationships.
What about the gay folk?
Gay Folk wouldn't want to be and then
assess to actually instead of sex.
Yeah.
Instead of calling it pussy because the
gay folk would be like,
hey man,
I'm with you,
but you're excluding me.
I'm one 10th of the population.
Allegedly not one 38% corn.
Sandy.
Yes.
Russell Thaddeus.
It's what he says.
He's head of dudes get hard and they see
dudes getting the good stuff.
Fucking do that.
That's not true.
He didn't say that.
He didn't say it.
I like that.
Yes.
Yeah,
me too.
But I think that the idea of not being
in a sexually pleasurable relationship
with someone for all of eternity,
that sounds stupid.
First of all this he had said they do
with men and women in longterm
relationships.
You know what the secret was?
The long term,
the West and there were C,
they fucked.
They had a deep sexual connection.
Get the talk out of here that talked to
me.
I'm just friends with you.
We have a deep friendship.
You want to,
you should want to fuck the person you
should want to.
Fuck I heard,
but successful marriages are like that.
Yeah.
Why you make it?
This is noise.
This is what you do and your fuck right?
Fingers and noises.
That's all.
Fuck no,
I don't do that.
I go,
I go and I do a lot of slicking back
here.
Ooh,
Ooh.
That's an idea.
That's what I do.
That's what she does on.
In all honesty,
if you had a choice between living like
a hermit,
like all bullshit aside,
no jokes,
living like a hermit,
living like someone who occasionally
interacts with people but doesn't have
any real deep connection with them or
living like you're in like a wonderful
community of people that you care about
and drinking and carrying on.
And hugging each other and laughing and
joking around and waking up,
hung over and getting breakfast
together,
and you live for a hundred
you want me to get an intellectual?
Want you to know you're talking about
that right now?
You know the question.
Now you know you're,
you're,
you know,
you know what this distinction you're
drawing my friend.
What can I get philosophical on you?
The distinction between socrates and
Nichi,
socrates said,
a man should have quiet contempt for his
body and ultimately learn to be a
complete template of human being.
Just be a brain and your body is
nothing.
As he was dying,
he drank the hemlock.
He said,
why are you guys crying?
I'm living in a shitty shell and it's
all gross and I'm going onto a better,
I'm going to be in the sky with all the
great philosophers and neat.
She goes,
yes,
socrates.
You said that because you are ugly,
you never got laid.
So of course you want to negate and you
turn reason into a tyrant.
And he said,
all those seven deadly sins of the
Christians talk about like,
like pride.
There's another words,
right?
It's called self esteem.
Self esteem is a good thing and lost.
Yeah.
Sex is a lot of fun.
Even though he never had sex,
but literally he never had basically
never got laid.
They even think,
yeah,
he might,
they think he either got syphilis and
that's why I died and went crazy.
Or he was gay.
Either way.
He never got laid.
He had a giant mustache.
Bring up Nietzsche and take a look at
his mustache.
He's talking
about masks.
He had a crazy mustache or code if if
need.
She was gay.
Brilliant motherfucker.
But he talked about there'll be able to
make your life a circus and a work of
art and joy,
everything and live dangerously.
Don't be fucking in a mountain when
you're in a mountain meditating.
It's awesome.
But guess what?
You're not really engaged in the world.
I wish she was gay.
Well,
look at that because there's so many
statutes.
There's so many dudes that are like,
like real aggro sort of Wall Street type
guys that are pro Nietzsche.
Yeah,
it'd be awesome if Nietzsche was just
like the whole time we was talking,
hey,
you're ugly.
I'm thinking,
well,
good looking guys.
Cox.
Hopefully that's not the only
conventional ways.
This is the noise.
I want you to think about him making
behind the spectacles and with this
beautiful mustache with a suit on.
He's doing this.
As soon as they stopped the camera,
thinking about Dick,
don't get,
you're being stereotypical.
He's not licking his lips slurping.
You don't know.
Look at them,
but look at that face I,
that would be a Dick slurp and type face
things whistle through his mustache when
he says fuck,
maybe that's why he has that mustache in
the first place,
so dude's can just really grab it and
get all four fingers
like this problem.
Nippy late his lips,
small discussion.
Those are lip handles.
He could grab a hold of them and wrap
them handled Zinger and then use it to
just like push down on the shaft.
Lady.
Man,
I don't want to apologize.
I want to pause.
Check those unique.
Why else would you grow mustache in your
face?
He was basically sick his whole life.
He was sick and told like that many
dicks.
You suck a lot of Dixie lose weight.
I don't know if that's true.
Cough a lot,
sir.
I don't know Dick Handle on his upper
lip.
A lot of girls have that.
Why else would you grow a Dick Handle on
your upper lip?
Because he's hiding behind his mustache.
Oh,
so sensitive.
What about a full beard?
Like fucking animal?
It's interesting.
Some dude in special forces,
it's kind of a neck handkerchief on
those necker shifts.
That was part of his,
that was his scars.
uh,
special forces for mask.
Why do so many of those don't look real?
Badass ass guys have those crazy,
uh,
like things around their neck.
Oh,
uh,
you mean?
Um,
eh,
those ropes are how those uh,
Bandana type thing.
Do you want to know?
They're like scarves.
I gotta I have to answer why.
Okay.
Ready.
Go ahead.
I know this from my buddy Rudy Raz,
who was a recon guy and saw a lot of
action.
They did generation kill.
So why do you wear those things?
Why?
Why do you wear a scarf?
Here's why.
Ready,
Dude,
I'm ready for this.
And Hey,
all you operators out there,
please forgive me.
I had never done any but just but just
indulge me and all due respect as I'm,
if I'm here and I'm shooting,
okay,
boop,
up,
and you're next to me.
Where am I?
Shells gone.
They're fucking hot.
They're spitting out.
And when nutshell lands in your neck and
gets under your shirt.
It burns like a motherfucker and Avu
buzzy.
No.
So you cover your neck.
When you're in a firefight month,
you cover your neck.
Oh,
so you were that you open mother fucker
up getting Marchenko style.
You're talking now you're [inaudible]
burn marks all over your body.
All over.
I'm like little fucking rain.
Teardrops rolling down your chest.
How about me?
And I've got to stop.
When I went to Afghanistan,
when I went to do standup at
Afghanistan,
oh,
I've got to say I wore one of those and
the,
and the special forces guy,
we're in the truck,
he goes,
take that off.
I go,
why?
Because if we hit with an IED or face is
going to catch fire,
her mother
cotuit used to wear one of those and I
was like [inaudible].
Yeah,
that's a sign of what a bad
motherfucker.
Randy Cooke tourists.
He thinks he's going to walk around with
a scarf on.
He's a ranger too,
wasn't he?
Wasn't he in the military is definitely
in the army.
He learned to box in the army,
look at them
things all over the place.
He says shit about it to action.
He could wear addition on his head and
still he signs a new five scarf deal.
Oh,
what years this scarf deal sounds like
it's,
it might be click on it and it real.
He really,
he's a handsome magazine.
I guarantee this ain't a joke.
What year is this?
We use,
this article's from January of this
year.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Oh that old.
Less than a year.
Do you remember?
You and I,
we were like 28 years old.
Do you remember?
You and I.
When we first saw him,
Joe and I first saw him,
we were at the UFC and he was standing
there and we were like,
wait,
let me snuck up.
When we were looking at him and he had a
big bond,
his knee was like,
he has a weird knee and then we like,
his legs are skinny compared to his
body.
We were like assessing.
We were taking him down.
We were looking at his whole body,
but we were like two teenage girls
looking at a rock star.
I never forgot.
That really is days,
dude.
You and I went to one of the earliest
ever UFC is when I was like,
dude,
I can't work for these people anymore.
I was like,
what am I doing?
It was like,
it was just calm.
Are you calling me saying you were going
to announce it?
UFC?
I remember you saying,
dude,
get this.
I was like,
what?
The fucking people that worked for news
radio,
like the production people really like
what?
I was like,
yeah,
I'm going to go to Alabama to do this
UFC thing.
It's a cage fighting.
They looked at me like I was going to
watch like animal porn.
That's right.
I was going to watch some chicks sucks
and donkey,
Dick's and bunch of dudes get fucked by
mules and like that's like literally,
I know.
They were like,
oh my God,
you're ruining your life.
And I was like,
I'm not gonna fight you.
And I were asked.
I remember that.
Yeah,
they have to figure out who's the best
can I have to fight?
I remember meeting or looking at
Bustamante and you said,
what's his first name or low morale
boost Manta and he's just,
he's six,
four and he was at a food,
there was like a food laid out and I and
and you just,
you were like,
that guy's one of the best Jiu Jitsu
guys in the world.
And I looked at him,
he had that jaw and I was just like,
God,
I remember go as Alan Gomes,
I call this done fucking style pizza.
That's me.
1997 adults it alibi.
Lord,
look at me a little pipsqueak beautiful
young man.
He was sweet,
beautiful skin,
or we used to train across my full head
of hair.
He sure does.
He's starting to go though.
You sure do.
My best to hang on.
Yeah.
Sharp,
sharp.
Your nose.
Your nose is my had a sharp does banner
called me up.
I was the same way.
I just,
I did Artie Lang's radio show and
rounded off as you get older.
I had a sharp nose.
Skinny fucking neck.
Yeah.
It's weird.
Like I'm a thick guy now.
When we first met,
we were both skinny.
We're both like a 27 maybe.
I had breakfast with Brendan shop this
morning and I came fresh,
fresh,
my Olympic lifting class,
you know I Olympic lift now,
right.
And my testosterone.
Look how,
look at Hackett.
You
see if you get me and Brian Count
together.
When Brian was the pool boy.
Dude.
You know what's really sad about that
picture?
I thought I was kind of tough back then.
You're always a sweet guy.
No,
but I mean,
in my mind I was like,
I'm a black belt in taekwondo.
I wrestled in high school.
A sad story.
I remember when we first met man,
we immediately had so much in common.
We started talking about martial arts.
Like what?
You didn't take one doe?
What?
You're a comedian.
Yup.
What happened to that check?
What was her name?
Well,
when you said [inaudible] box and you do
Jujitsu and you have to,
cause you'd be in jail.
Otherwise I went.
All that guy speaks to my life.
We're both retards.
Both the pit bulls.
There you go.
There's Brian.
Look at you.
It's you fucking look at the dancing.
Look at that.
I was doing pushups to where's her?
Uh,
she,
what is her name again?
Mary.
Um,
oh my God.
I can't believe I'm forgetting her name.
She's so,
she's the most talented woman I've all
fucking funny.
I'll tell you that.
She's incredible.
Fuck's her name,
man.
I really can't believe I'm forgetting
Mary's name.
Jamie.
Find finding me so lucky.
You like a baby.
Look at you.
How weird is that dude that this thing,
someone captured time?
I,
this actually really happened with us.
I know.
We were actually there at us in 94 dixie
westward to find out what her name is.
Manoj feel disrespect Mary Mary,
I'm so sorry.
I'm,
we're going to find it.
I'm 50 and I'm senile.
Oh my God.
If you smoked weed,
that's what it is.
That's what it is.
You bastard.
Terracing myself.
We're doing a wonderful job of
entertaining people.
She's incredible.
She's one of them.
She was,
I was always in awe of her talent.
She's an awesomely funny Mary masterson.
No,
but that's patriarchy.
Son asked her woman,
we have to smash the city.
Park is here.
Back.
Last name,
master woman.
How can we get up masterson can even at
masterman.
Yeah.
Masterman yeah.
Dammit.
Eris Scheer.
I'm so back to Mary.
She was very funny.
She's incredible.
That was a great character.
She had to I,
she was one of those people that was so
talented like I could,
she write shit and,
and she would figure out what was wrong
with a sketch and I would be sewing all
I did,
but then she was a groundling forever.
I didn't know.
I was like,
Oh,
you've been doing this forever.
Like I did.
Never done scratch specific type of
comedy.
Yes.
You know,
it's very different doing sketches.
Very.
It's very different animal than doing
stand up.
She,
she was ridiculously funny.
Yeah.
It's weird form of comedy,
you know those sketch little short
things,
writing them every week.
You know,
that's the craziest thing about Saturday
night live.
But yeah,
like the Chappelle show and a lot of
these other shows,
they had time to develop these sketches
and they weren't doing them all in front
of a live audience like night live does.
I have friends who've gotten Saturday
night live and that is grueling
schedule.
They're up all night,
man.
Kind of an idea.
It seems like,
well at least coming from Phil Hartman's
explanation of it,
he said it was very like competitive.
Oh yeah.
The point where people got real hostile
with each other.
It's just,
it was never like a relaxed,
fun environment.
Like,
in fact when he first came from Saturday
night live and came over to news radio,
one of the things what he was like a
little standoffish at first and then
eventually he like realizes like,
oh these people aren't competing with
me,
we're not competing.
Right.
It took a while though really?
But yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There was like an environment of snl
that was like super like hyper
competitive and Michael's wants it to be
that way.
You have to compete to get your sketch
on and if you don't,
you you go away.
And so it's a very competitive
atmosphere.
You could see it and felt like fit.
And Phil just relaxed after a while he
relaxed and I'm like,
no,
we're not competing like you're Phil
Hartman.
I'm some fucking dude that nobody even
knows.
Yeah.
Okay.
And were both on a show together.
Hey,
what's up?
Yeah.
And he's like,
Oh okay,
okay,
okay.
And then he like,
I got deeper and deeper to know him.
You know,
this is back in my non weed smoking
days.
Unfortunately.
I wish I smoked weed cause he used to
love to smoke weed and yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He would,
he would smoke weed after shows and wind
down and play music and go to strip
clubs and shit.
He does impossibly funny.
He was a really interesting guy.
But you're not like any guy I've ever
met.
Like legitimately not like any guy I've
ever met.
Like he had an incredibly unique way of
viewing opportunities and things.
One of the things that happened is he
didn't really make it until he was quite
old,
you know,
in terms of grounding.
Right.
Or is the second city,
I think it was brown.
I think he was cracking city.
He might've been groundling too.
I think you might be right.
But I know he was also an artist and he
did peewee's playhouse.
He did something with peewees play,
uh,
you know,
pee wee herman or an artist like a
painter.
Yeah,
no,
he needs to make album covers and stuff.
Yeah.
It was like a,
like a legit graphic artist.
Wow.
Yeah.
He's a fascinating guy.
Like when we first did a news radio
together,
he just decided that he wanted to get
his pilot's license,
so every time I talked to him,
homeboy and have his pilots book out and
be going over his fucking pilots book
and going like he was constantly have it
on the set,
like in between scenes.
He would do a scene and they would open
up as pilots book and just as obsessed
with learning how to fly a plane.
My Dad?
Yeah,
my father,
my father was obsessed with that.
He got his pilot's license.
I never got it.
I was like,
I don't know why you care that much.
Well,
you know what it is,
man.
It's freedom.
It's like,
especially a guy,
obviously I can say this now since his
wife killed him,
he had a bad relationship.
When you have a bad relationship,
you just want to fly these kids too and
I want to,
I don't even know.
I don't know.
Horrible store.
That was a worst.
I remember talking to you right after
it.
Again,
this is another thing where it was a
disassociative.
It was a psych psych medicine.
It was zoloft mixed with cocaine.
Not saying that she wouldn't have done
that without anything.
Not saying that the drugs are
responsible,
but I'm saying it's,
it's eerie.
How many different violent episodes are
connected to psych medication.
God,
yeah.
We are fucking with the very way that
your brain interfaces with reality.
To think that that doesn't have
consequences is absurd.
It's absurd.
And to think that you can sort of poo
poo those consequences,
like correlation is not causation.
Okay,
you're right,
you're right.
But have you done a study to find out
what's what,
or have you really dug into it?
Have you looked into these people?
If you find out what they were like,
is there a way to even back engineer
their personality before you start
adding drugs?
Is there a wet,
like,
do you know what the difference between
depression and psychotic madness's?
I don't know.
I'm not.
And I think obviously the people like
the guy,
the vegas shooter,
nobody knew,
right?
If nobody knew and he just did that.
So there's a,
there's a line that he can cross.
Well,
he's capable of doing that.
You don't know what that line killed
himself.
Point is.
We're not dealing with an exact science.
Yeah.
We're dealing with something that vary
so widely.
This for anyone has suggested dosages,
depending on how you react to it.
Only reason why people are saying it's
fine cause they make money from it.
That's it.
They didn't make money from it.
They'd be like,
well blah,
blah,
blah.
How many people are being prescribed?
What?
Yeah,
why?
How did you try exercise?
You didn't,
okay,
so you just took a pill.
You're eating sugar all day and you just
took a pill.
Now everything's supposed to go check
your hormones.
Did you do,
did you do anything other than that?
Yeah.
The thyroid medications.
Try Meditation.
Did you try exercise?
Did you try jogging?
I want you to try jogging for six
months.
It will give you the pills.
Yeah,
but can you,
but then again,
is that hypocritical?
Shouldn't,
if I think coach should be legal,
should I shouldn't,
I think that people should be able to
take a pill.
Well,
I think your,
your objection to that is that there's
an entire industry making lots of money
and making claims about those psychotic
drugs,
those drugs,
psychosomatic,
whatever the word is,
drugs that may be in many cases are not
true.
I'm sure that things like PROZAC and
Zoloft have their place.
I'm sure they work for some people.
I know.
In fact I have family members that
really do well with Xanax.
I do as well.
And I know,
I know it's just like weed is good for
some people and other people can't
function.
I can't really function on marijuana
talk a pretty good right now.
Thank you.
But I yes I am but,
but for the most part,
it depends on your chemistry in your
body.
But I think what you're objecting to is
that there is people who get there,
people are getting very,
very wealthy.
Certainly companies on,
on,
uh,
claims that are not measurable and not
always true.
There's that.
Right.
But there's also the same reason why I
don't think a 900 year old dude should
be able to fuck a 50 year old lady cause
it thinks she's basically like a phobia.
This is what I think.
I think that people are goddamn
vulnerable
and gullible and when you have these
commercials where there's people walking
down the street and art cartoon
butterflies are flying around and
they're all jolly and you're selling
antidepressants and then you start
listing off be explosive,
anal bleeding,
heart blown out of your fucking chest,
like the alien movie,
Your Dick Falls off,
your feet go numb,
you start reading off this thing while
you're showing the same cheerful
environment and crazy music.
I think that alone shows you that
there's a problem.
Just those commercials alone,
the fact that they exist,
the way they're structured,
the fact that they have to say all these
horrific side effects for like a minute,
two minutes of the commercial,
it's a horrific side effect.
A giant like if you have like
legitimately have and what is commercial
30 seconds.
It's entirely possible that 15 of those
30 seconds are going to be the
consequences of you taking this drug
while you're looking at cartoon bunny
rabbits and week flying through the air
and everybody's smiling and there's a
bunch of whistles and fucking piano and
it seems like everybody's having a grand
old time.
Yeah.
And they're talking about death and
suicidal thoughts.
It's psychotic episodes and come on.
Do you want a really good insight into
how big Pharma works?
Read Ben Goldacre is but pig farmer,
fucking bad farm.
I think it's called just money.
And it's the same thing as all of it.
It's tribalism because if you could look
at your team,
your pharmaceutical team as being you
against everybody else,
you could figure out a way to sell fuck
up drugs to people that you really
shouldn't be selling it.
I just have to say you want to make
money cause we're doing this podcast
that my entire act right now,
my new hour is all about this and
everybody who's seen me that knows that
this is true.
That's what I want to say this.
Cause you're talking about teens and
tribalism.
The theme of my fucking next hour is,
is exactly this,
how we break up into teams.
So I just don't want anybody to think
that my next hour has been influenced by
this fucking podcast cause I love that
you're thinking about the same thing.
I am.
I think a lot of people were thinking
about this now because as we were
running into this weird situation where
we realized that,
you know,
our democracy is in some weird way,
uh,
being examined that's being fractured
isn't happening.
Sure.
There's a lot,
but it's been examined by people.
Yeah.
They're looking at it from all sorts of
different angles in an unprecedented
manner.
Right.
And we're looking at the influence that
Russia might have had and all this
Bernie Sanders was going to run in 2020.
There's,
there's so much going on right now
that's this intense,
incredibly high level that we're all
sort of like caught up in this thing
trying to figure out what's,
what's going to happen next.
Also,
it's also we're having really trouble
trouble knowing what to believe.
Right?
I mean,
we don't know what to believe and what
to believe in.
I mean,
is this a Bot?
And,
and what,
what is twitter?
I mean,
if six people are saying you did
something and that's it in the why,
what,
how true is this?
And if the stories are all remarkably
similar now some consistencies,
I he,
Charlie rose,
but what,
what do we do?
It's very interesting time because trans
privacy privacy is dead yet we still
don't really know what to believe.
I mean,
I,
I'm getting information from six
different sources.
So who's actually telling me the truth
about that person or that event?
Um,
that's the biggest.
That's to me.
And that was one of the biggest shit.
And when you add that to click baiting
as it gets real,
it gets to be a real create cynicism and
it creates paranoia and it creates the
idea that I can't rely on any,
the institutions I used to be able to
rely,
rely on.
And there's also been an observed
strategy of really,
um,
inflated headlines that get altered
later.
Yeah.
You know,
they say something completely
ridiculous.
It's not really represented by the
facts.
And then they tone it down when people
complain,
but they got all the initial hits.
That's when I first novus notice doing
that.
You can sway a vote by saint floating
things anonymously and then by the time
it comes out that it's bullshit.
Well you,
you've lost what's also dirty to name
stuff after important values like the
Patriot Act.
Of course.
Fuck.
How do you vote against the Patriot and
patriot?
Patriot.
Exactly.
Like that's rude.
Of course.
That's rude.
That's a root,
dirty trick.
Somebody should have pointed that out.
Someone David from,
they had any balls like there was on the
Senate floor.
David from editing and in a book called
don't think of an elephant,
I think it was called.
What year was this?
When did I read that?
A long time ago.
But he basically talks about how
language,
if you learn,
if you learn how to manipulate language,
it is very beneficial,
man.
You,
you will.
It's really interesting.
I read a um,
it's fun,
interesting things about like our
population.
Do you know that 80,
I think it's 82% of Americans can't name
one living scientist yet.
If you ask 82% of Americans will say
that politicians should be talking to
scientists even though they don't,
they can't name one living scientists
like Neil degrasse Tyson or Stephen
hawkings or Lawrence Krauss.
At the same time,
there is a deep,
not only mistrust but also respect for
science.
In other words,
hey,
you politicians listen to the fucking
size.
If there's,
if there's a weapon out there that can,
if there's a technology that can reduce
this all the dust,
listen to those fucking guys.
At the same time,
I find it very interesting that science
is still being questioned.
Like there's real questions on the right
about the science behind climate change.
Did you see what happened recently and
it was in Texas,
the recent rash of earthquakes.
I tweeted about it today directly
connected to fracking.
I'm sure 100% but it's also interesting
is that both sides of the left and
right.
Speaking of tribalism,
the left doesn't want to hear anything
about the difference,
the scientific difference between men
and women.
That would be an issue,
especially when you start talking about
trans women,
but the difference between male and
female brains because what happens if
your James Dannemora is that what you're
is
that women are a victim to their biology
and ultimately are not able to overcome
certain things that men have inherently.
James [inaudible] from the Google knows.
Yes.
I just want to as the Google memo guy.
Yeah and I read that Google and I'm
about twice and what's interesting is a
lot of evolutionary psychologists and
biologists basically said,
well what he was saying was just drawing
on on empirical evidence based on how,
for example,
a 48 year old,
a 48 month old infant female and a 48
month old male we'll look at too.
If you give them a choice between
looking at something moving and a human
face,
typically the female to 48 hour old
female,
we'll look at the face,
the human face,
the boy will look at the moving object.
What about lesbians?
I definitely kid is running out of the
room like leather Tuscadero that's a
different story with a Mohawk on the
days that I don't [inaudible] haircut.
Do you remember when Pinky Tuscadero
came to town?
There was out of town.
Remember this?
Yeah,
they did that thing when you got to
learn it.
How do you remember me that I don't
remember that we're the same age.
We had to learn it in high school.
Who tested their out?
They keep Tuscadero
got to learn it and once you learn it,
you only learn how to do it.
One side of we 50 or what was that?
Who was that show now?
No,
that's a new chick.
Oh,
that's her.
That's what she looks like now.
That's good.
Wow.
That's what she looked like.
Leather Tuscadero hm.
That's leather.
Tuscadero and then there was pinky.
Pinky.
Pinky was like a little tougher.
She wore like a pink leather jacket.
She sure it did.
She is there.
She said she had her shirt like this
high.
That she was hot and like a dirty mom
away.
Damn right.
She was fucking dancer.
Ooh.
We could hurt with Fonzie.
You want to talk about nicest guy in the
planet.
It might be Henry Winkler.
I've met him.
He's such a sweetie.
He's a sweetie.
He's a beautiful man.
He's a really,
really nice guy.
I did it Kevin James movie with him.
You did?
Yeah.
I could not have been nicer.
You know,
I was supposed to do.
Kevin can wait.
They offered me apart,
but I was in New York and I couldn't do
it cause I was,
I was doing a one off your fucking
excuses.
Well,
I'm glad to that cause I feel bad.
I Miss Kevin.
I would really love him.
And he's a great guy.
You talked to him lately.
No,
I haven't,
but I love that car.
I love and Leah revenues on that show,
right?
Yeah,
she's back.
She's a new wife.
They damn,
I don't know what happened.
Scientology,
when you mentioned Phil Hartman did some
album covers.
I found this.
Oh,
Asia Dude.
Have you heard?
Have you heard Charles Manson Song?
He did Asia Fuck Outta him.
Steely Dan.
What?
Yeah,
whatever.
What else do you have eight album cover
is designed by listening.
Can Be America.
Yeah,
that's right.
And POCO.
Which fucking kitten now.
He was awesome,
man.
Did you hear that?
Wow.
The firesign theater fighting clowns.
Damn.
I want to get a print of that.
Go back to that,
see if we could find a print of that
fire sign theater.
Fine.
Yeah,
I'll look it up,
but yeah,
let's get a print of that and put it up
in the studio that did you hear Charles
Manson's song to I hear about it.
Jerked off to it.
It's amazing,
sir.
Sarah,
please.
Sorry,
five to ten five foot two Charlie.
Matthew.
Hi.
You're your garbage man.
He legally,
I played him on Mad TV and me and that's
why baby without the,
what do we do?
You believe?
What do you do is amazing that that guy
got so many people to follow him,
but that's a thing like 900 year old
people would not fall.
Charles Manson,
man,
I'm talking about the 900 year old
people.
That's a long way,
but that's the whole reason why we are
infants were just infants with a very
short lifetime as quick.
Let me ask you this.
Imagine if people look like you ever
look at a person from like the 18
hundreds when they first started
inventing photographs.
You see a 25 year old like,
oh my God,
he's almost dead.
They look so old.
They look so weathered.
They looked like they were just dirt,
had been he Gary Fisher when they would
take pictures of with their dead
relatives.
Oh,
you ever seen that?
This is my kid.
They all died.
I have pictures.
I'll take pictures with them.
Oh yeah,
those people,
they died quicker.
They looked like shit.
What if you lived 800 years?
This is what I think about.
I don't think about developing that much
understanding.
I feel like I'd be like,
all right,
well I guess I'll start the drums and
then the guitar and then the piano and
I'll master those as well.
And I would just figure out all the skin
skills I've master.
Let me tell you what you would be at 80
or 800 years old.
You'd be living in a castle and you
would basically be having young ladies
come to the council and give them
seminars.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I enjoy.
Well,
older woman because your 800 they're
going to look hot as fuck and they're
still going to be like kind of spiritual
but not really religious.
Yup,
I do that too.
Why?
I don't know why.
It's just top being awesome.
The sex DAPI and awesome.
I think that's a crock of shit designed
by people don't want to fuck me too.
Me Too.
When do you know can to look to
look Dixon molds wound.
It's going to be boring.
Well,
okay,
maybe,
but I don't see any evidence.
I'm not seeing any evidence that that's
real.
I think you're making things up and I'm
not really interested in talking to you
about this,
so I find your,
your,
your fucking opinions are exhausting and
they boring,
so you hang onto them.
Your opinions are exhausting and they're
boring.
Yeah.
So you hang onto them,
you run with them,
but I go,
Nah,
I'm good.
The base living,
here's the thing.
It's like there's this idea that there's
like some higher level of thinking and
then there's like base physical
pleasures that's not real.
You have a hundred years and then you're
dead.
So you're supposed to have,
if you're lucky,
you've got a hundred beers.
Just because you enjoy some very
intellectual pursuits.
It does not mean you should enjoy
getting your drink on every now and then
or doing something stupid,
being silly or
sacks or anything.
What would you say herself a friend,
what would you say to yourself right
now?
If I put your 25 year old or your 20
year old body right there,
what would you say to yourself right
now?
Figured out pitch.
Really?
That's what I'd say.
Yeah.
You got to figure it out.
You gotta make your mistakes.
You're you,
what you're going to learn from someone.
You're never going to learn from them
sitting down saying,
listen,
you got to learn from me.
Well,
you're going to learn from someone as by
example.
We're going to learn for someone as by
someone out there like following a lead
that you know is difficult and achieving
teams that you think are very hard to
achieve and you watch that and you go,
okay,
well you got to do is you got to get
comfortable with being uncomfortable.
You got to grit your teeth.
You've got to bear down.
You got to work hard.
You gotta be honest.
You can't go to be honest with yourself
about how hard you're working.
And that's what a lot of people are not
doing.
That's what you learned.
You never know how to,
how to slip a jab until you get punched
in the face of much going to show you
how to do it.
But to really learn it to the point
where it's a part of your normal
patterns,
there's certain things that happen to
people where you,
you see them like slide their hips back
there.
Oh,
that's the guy who's been kicked in the
stomach.
Yes.
Like he,
he's been times where everything you do
as a reaction,
you don't have to think about it,
but it gets you same thing for sure.
Yeah,
yeah.
Those pathways get carved in and by the
way,
those pathways can be really shitty too.
You're going to have a bunch of shitty
pathways carved into your head that
ensure your failure.
It didn't sure your failure,
they didn't show you're,
you're questioning yourself and also
blaming a bunch of other people.
You got to like,
you know how like people are supposed to
edit.
You're supposed to edit.
Like when you make a document he's
supposed to edit.
When you write a book,
you should also add thoughts.
You can't just let them all run wild.
Right?
You can't because some of them are
really like impulsive and they're,
they're not well fabricated.
Right.
And if you try to defend those fucking
stupid thoughts,
you're going to be like what we were
talking about with conspiracies and you
learn what not to listen to.
That's the other thing.
Not all,
not all fucking ideas are on the same
plane.
There are a lot of people you shouldn't
be listening to and if you want to be
really good at something,
find the right tutor.
There's big differences in how file
Codero and you know,
if you want to learn how to kickbox or
whatever,
and that dude over there,
right?
Yeah.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
If you can,
well,
yeah,
if you have the,
I mean,
they'd be be a good,
good guidance and tutelage is really
important.
It is.
You know,
it's interesting now is that people that
don't have access to good guns and
tutor,
which still have access to online,
say Thomas because you got,
you got,
you got the Gracie University,
you've got,
and you've got youtube,
you've got Hansel,
gracie giving you a little thing.
I mean,
could he,
Bravo has this whole system,
10th planet Jiu Jitsu System.
It's all available online.
You can learn all the moves and if
you're in a small town,
Eddie has over a want to say go to 10th
planet,
Jiu jitsu.com 10 planet j j.com.
I want to say he has more than 80
students,
or excuse me,
more than 80 studios worldwide.
Yeah,
I think he has more than 80 schools,
so,
wow.
And they put up a lot of the data of
like the stuff they're doing and stuff.
They're working on drills and things.
A lot of it's online.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
How many,
what does it say?
Look at the fucking,
that's incredible success.
10th Planet that the city says he's
charging a lot of license,
that he's making money.
Trust me.
We'll talk later.
Look at this though.
Look at this.
This is,
I mean,
this is insane.
That's amazing.
He's,
he's got a huge accomplishments.
Z,
a crazy number of people that follow his
Jujitsu.
He is right about his conspiracy
theories,
but he's definitely right about Jujitsu.
You know the chemistry of things.
Another one,
like he,
he claimed that for a long time.
He still,
he'll put something up on his instagram
page.
I know why he believes that because he
doesn't believe in the government,
but my position is I get that and I
don't,
I don't trust a lot of people either,
but you have to trust the people that
are scientists that are all agreeing
that if a fucking jet engine that's
heated up goes through condensation and
a certain atmosphere that creates
artificial cloud being responsive to
evidence.
It is.
And it's also like you,
you,
you can't,
you can't mock that.
Like it's very important if you're going
to get anywhere with any of their stance
on your wrist and in your hand,
and you're going to have,
when you're listening to it like this,
this is their science,
that measurable science that works,
right?
So the science that goes into your
earphones that goes into the vaccines
and antibiotics,
I push you beyond your black biology,
the science that gets food,
fresh food in front of you.
All that shit is,
is you're benefiting from that.
And usually the science that you don't
believe in is the same science you're
actually using to speak into.
Well that's,
yeah,
that's the argument we were having
yesterday that it's,
it's so ridiculous that anybody would
have an issue with the highest minds in
the world deciding whether or not things
are real and things are not real and
what is and what isn't.
Well,
he thinks that's really weird.
I don't know what he believes we could
sit him down and talk to them about it,
but my point about all of it was that
the very genius that allows him to like
shut down Jujitsu attacks,
like he doesn't recognize Jujitsu
attacks.
It's like,
well this is valid too.
No,
he's like,
shut that shit down and move forward.
It's one of the reasons why he's so good
at Jujitsu.
He's so good at Jujitsu cause he doesn't
like recognize your attack is valid.
Gosh,
shut shit down and it moves.
It's really interesting as well because
he's an undeniable,
Eddie Bravo is an undeniable jujitsu
genius.
I haven't sound to die.
I know.
I've been salivary.
Sure.
Yeah,
he's great salivary.
I'm sorry,
have some reason to shout out to Ivan.
He,
I went and he gave me a lesson and if so
awesome.
It was fun.
I went to Seattle and the school,
you know,
he's the only guy in the UFC that has a
submission.
I think maybe one of the person might
have it now,
but for the longest time he was the only
guy that had a body triangle rear mount
submission where he got a guide.
He got Tony Fryklund in the,
he got his back.
And when you flatten somebody out and
you have someone in a body triangle,
yeah,
it's so fucking brutally painful.
Yeah.
That um,
Tony frequent tapped.
He was the first guy ever to tap from a
body triangle.
And I remember I've watched him do that
and I was like,
oh wow.
Cause I knew that that hurt,
but I didn't know if someone would tap
from it in a UFC fight as well.
Whoa.
For a guy like me,
he's probably 43 44 now.
And he said he invited me to school.
I was just so excited and he's going to
teach me tricks and just like in close
fighting,
Bach,
dirty boxing.
And He,
we put,
he put vaseline on me.
I was like,
what's going on here?
Yeah.
See he gets a body triangle last cross.
It's tap and fucking the pocock.
He's awesome.
It's so painful.
He's such a great guy.
Look at him.
He's from Chile.
Yeah,
he's a bad motherfucker.
And he's got a rooster tattooed on his
wrist.
He does it.
And it was funny because he came to my
show and then I,
the next day I,
I was,
I got an a ring with him and he had,
he put greets salmon and we're just
doing little things with gloves.
And when you,
it's for a man like me,
for a man like me who's basically 170
pounds and nothing come back.
And when you feel that a man who's been
thrown bodies around his whole life and
punching,
and it's been his life and he's,
oh,
he's probably about to 20 maybe to 30
and he acts a little heavier than when
he used to fight.
But the strength and the,
just the density of his body as you're
fucking trying to do anything and he
just moves you.
He kind of shocks you around with a
script writer.
It's so humbling and he's super
technical to Oh fuck.
He so to Ivan was like super,
super.
That's it.
Did I take a picture of him and was
like,
it was a picture of him and Maury Smith
being held court and meet with Charlie
Murphy.
Charlie Murphy is explaining something
called the Chicago Ridge hand.
That's like a,
a technique karate technique that people
aren't using enough in mma.
He's kind of right.
It's a rich hand is where you had hit
someone with a side of your hand.
Do you ever know rich hand?
They were practicing karate move.
You'll know about chet shot.
I don't know shit.
Karate move is a rich hand.
It's like this.
This is Eddie Murphy.
That's Ivan salivary to the right of the
table and the black bald headed dude is
Maury Smith.
Come on.
Yup.
You got two bad mother,
two killers at the table and then I'm,
I'm back behind this,
all this stuff.
I'm on this side of it,
but uh,
it was a charlie murphy explaining,
I don't know shit about the Chicago look
at his hand and so quotable Charlie was
holding court.
Charlie was so funny.
Like I don't think people that never got
to hang out with Charlie ever.
Really good to understand how funny
Charlie was.
I heard is a great storyteller is
amazing storyteller,
but he just would hold court and you
would let them,
you would fall to the ground laughing.
He was just a great,
he was great at like being the guy who
told the story the best and it had the,
but it didn't translate in a stand up as
much as it should have been.
This is what I think happened.
I think he jumped into standup like way
too quick.
It was headlining like really early.
Like he didn't do like the whole thing
like we all did like do the open mic
night and then start doing no dude,
he was headlining like that.
He was charlie my from the Chappelle
show him done standard before that he
had never done standup,
can't do it.
So he figured out how to weight it.
I mean,
he did it and he figured out,
but I don't think he ever,
I think if you had allowed Charlie
Murphy develop the way we all did.
Yes.
From Open Miker to Middle Act,
a headliner to holt,
he would have been a world class
assassin.
And he know he died.
It's still a very funny comedian and he
was headlining all over the world.
Did you know he was sick when you were
hanging up?
No,
he was in sick when I was hanging out
with leukemia or some kind of a stretch.
But that all happened after,
um,
after I'd seen him,
I hadn't seen him in a while.
He did my podcast in like 2000,
I want to say in 12,
somewhere around there,
maybe 13.
Um,
him and my friend freeze love.
Did you ever meet Eddie Murphy?
Yeah.
Met Eddie and uh,
Hawaii once,
just randomly.
It was funny.
It was the craziest thing ever.
Really.
It's like he knows who I am with.
This is so cool,
dude.
He goes,
you're a funny motherfucker.
What the fuck happened?
He reached down and grabbed my hand.
He gripped it.
Bobby funny mother Fabi had,
who's married to Whitney Houston.
Bobby Brown came up to me the other day
and the comedy store and told me some
crazy.
Bobby Brown came up to me.
I was,
I was getting my ticket and I was
flying.
I was flying from,
I can't remember where.
And he came up and he goes,
you're funny dude,
man,
you make me laugh a lot and you're
shaking my head.
I didn't realize who it was until
somebody came up and said,
you know,
that was right.
I go,
I don't,
and he goes,
that was Bobby Brown.
I go,
fuck that.
He looked familiar and then we sat.
I sat next to him singing the songs to
him and everyone else to have bad tech
camp.
Did you know he was the first dude to
Dirac the microphone on the side of his
face.
Really headset son who had a headset for
Bob.
You're fucking Brian.
And he was dancing.
Who the fuck had a headset before Bobby
Brown.
He was like pushing the technology.
Yep.
Right.
And then Christopher Titus started doing
it on stage,
but healy and I said,
hell no,
no.
Titus does it still.
I think he has like a little microphone.
Hmm?
Does the whole thing walks and talks
like this?
Have you?
You've done like letterman.
There he is.
Look at him Brown.
A couple of full on headsets on.
I mean if you sit,
realize how rich he was because he's
still super rich.
Must be,
oh what am I as accountant?
Look at that picture of him with the
headset on.
They'll go,
dude,
this is like a guy.
If you were trying to get your Imac
fixed and you had to call India to
please look at please let ain't got it.
I'm mad right there.
You kidding me with that tank top you
tank,
you tuck that tank top on and you guess
that you get the jacket off your
shoulders a little big.
By the way,
that's what it's a gay porn.
If I ever seen in worries and look at
those offering wristbands,
why else did you have wrist wristbands
on it?
Unless you were there to stop hands.
Don't get all sweaty when you know when
you have lube all over your hands,
it doesn't get into your elbows.
Damn right.
Can't have blue double hell,
but I'm so proud.
Don't be mad.
We're just joking around.
I'm a big fan.
My prerogative bitch.
He's awesome.
Right?
That was a great fucking song.
He had some amazing shit.
It's about motherfucker,
but that does look,
yeah,
the way I like,
but not like when anybody,
anybody recognizes me.
I love it.
So not to do anything wrong with it.
I'm not a cool celebrity.
I'm not a,
come on buddy,
I'm tardy saying this.
You're hurting my feelings.
What?
You're cool celebrity.
Thanks buddy.
If I wasn't friends with you,
I'd be psyched to be friends with you.
I care attitude.
I'm looking for a young man like he's
silly.
Damn right.
Good done.
That's what I'm,
I'm serious.
I'd be looking forward to hanging out
with you.
Thanks buddy.
My pleasure.
I appreciate it.
What's something about your dates on
travel?
How to calm me down.
It's going up.
I'll be at cobb's December seven,
eight,
nine then at the Schomburg Improv the
weekend after that.
December of what?
14,
15,
16 something like that.
This history.
Oh,
and you guys please go see Brendan Shop.
My brother at the wiltern theater the
night of Wilbur,
Wilbur,
Boston and Boston.
Uh,
the night of January 19th,
January 19th,
apprentice shop,
uh,
the Wilbur theater.
[inaudible] UFC.
Don't miss it.
He's doing good stuff and he's very,
he's,
he's writing all kinds of functions.
So people asking me if I'm doing stand
up the night before that UFC no,
but I will be there for that UFC,
but maybe it will be hanging out with
Brendan.
There you go.
I'll be heckling.
Maybe you'll open forum if you do a
little fucking little time.
Maybe do it with 15 minutes.
Don't talk about jokes.
He does do a couple of jokes.
We'll do a couple of jokes.
I don't even know who I'm playing right
now.
Um,
you're playing a guy like an old,
I've always,
what does,
how does might army.
Yeah,
we're hanging out.
We hanging out.
Yeah,
the party continue else's there.
Kristalina me,
you shop,
shop and someone else.
Someone else.
Really funny to
know.
Quite a few.
It's like a good lineup.
That's a,
it's the same Tripoli show comedy
castle.
Excellent.
Yeah,
he's got a,
he's got a very good line up.
I think one or two other comedians on
that show.
Russell Peters in the house.
My main man.
Someone else.
Oh Shit.
Please face coming.
He's amazing.
He's hilarious.
Those are the other two are those really
good lineup right there.
Great God damn lineup.
I think the stitches for your sides.
You Eleanor,
Eleanor Kerrigan.
Ah,
very funny.
I love Alan Moore is one of the funniest
people alive and used to be a waitress.
She was a waitress at the comedy store
for years and she was the girl that I
would go to when they would tell me
someone to tell me that this guy is
really funny.
I'd go,
eleanor,
is that guy really funny?
She'd go,
fucking hack.
Eleanor is a wonderful human being and
reminds me of the women in my family,
so I have a very soft spot for her
because she's Italian,
I think is a softball.
I don't know if she has time,
but by the way,
I love her.
Oh,
that's beautiful.
I love her too.
She's Irish names Kerrigan.
It's true.
Actually she's married.
Isn't it her married name though?
No,
I feel like she's telling it.
Okay.
Nope,
that's it.
Eleanor Kerrigan starting.
She's from the,
she's from the Italian side of our,
what?
This is not real.
You don't know how real the eleanor is
an Italian man.
Nobody appreciates Dama rare.
More than the Irish
dominant.
I said one time we were talking to this
man depth,
we're talking to this young,
very pretty girls at the upstairs in the
laugh factory and he's taking a piss
next to dove.
And he goes,
oh,
those,
uh,
those girls good looking.
And Doug goes,
yeah,
you couldn't tell.
And he goes,
I have no,
I mean,
at that age,
you know,
when they're that young,
they gotta have a goat head.
I'm still attracted to
dom.
Irrera is a god that's still swinging.
Like,
you know,
like we all have this idea that a
certain comedian age,
like when you get into your sixties
you're not going to write new material
anymore.
He's always writing and killing.
He's always killing and he's killing it.
He sits next to you.
He'll pull over and sit next to you and
go,
oh,
look at you queers like this.
Just find a way to automate things.
But what it tells me,
it goes on and she goes,
I did a set really well whenever he
goes,
bro,
Bro,
come over.
I was like,
oh,
this is what,
I didn't know him that well.
I go,
what?
What?
What's up done?
He goes,
you know what I like about you as a
comedian?
I was like,
what so exciting is you don't really go
for the laughs.
I was like,
fuck.
That's where he lives.
He lives in the joking with other
comedians.
It's like dom,
my rare,
in my opinion,
is the best guest ever on killed Tony.
It was seeing him until to now.
I'm sure he's great.
He's magical.
Like I've done it with him.
He's magical cause he's still
professionally funny.
He's so professional.
He funny.
But also there's a bunch of comedians
that he's making laugh.
Like that's what Dama rocks like best
at.
So it's,
you know,
me and him and red band and a Tony and
then the comedian who does the sat and
then the audience who are comedy nerds.
So it's like dom irrera.
It's just coming in there fucking with
six guns loaded.
Yup.
Yeah.
That's his,
his,
he's like,
I just got an arsenal.
Yeah.
If I,
if I was Tony Hinchcliffe,
I would fire everybody else.
And I would say the talk show is dom
irrera is there.
And then another guest,
like it's always dom irrera have him on
the fighter and the kid,
I don't,
we haven't had him.
Never on time.
No long time ago.
He couldn't make it.
I can't remember what it was.
I got to get them on.
I fucking love them.
Who's your least favorite guest?
Awesome fighter.
And the kid on the fighter and the kid.
Yeah.
My least favorite guests.
Don't tell me,
let's just keep this shit.
I don't even,
I can't remember.
If you ask someone a question,
you hope they don't answer this one.
Will some people just kind of like,
just don't come to play.
Oh like they don't know what they're
doing.
They just don't come that they might
have be having an off day.
If I don't pay right now,
I'm going to die.
How do you not have to pay?
God,
you're impressive.
Huge bladder.
Go ahead and do my huge deck and I'll be
right back.
Jamie and I'll talk about Lebron James.
All right.
Don't
tell me.
Tell me things.
Jamie,
is there a new sneaker?
He does have a new seeker out.
Well,
did they have one every season yet?
He's got two different pairs.
He also has his own imprint label on
Nike,
which is a,
that's a ball or may he sponsors Ohio
state.
That's like conor mcgregor starts cope
promoting with the UFC like it takes it
to the next level.
Right.
Did you hear anything about conner
yesterday?
Don't know if it's rumors or not.
Well,
he got into a fight and in a pub or
something and I know terrible random
shit about,
I don't know if it was even accurate.
That's the problem with keeping it real.
Yeah.
You know,
if you want to keep it real and hanging
with the people,
eventually someone's going to test you.
Someone like you were when you were 20
you know,
maybe.
Sure.
I Dunno if conner was into that.
I assume he wasn't because he's a
winner,
but man,
that absolutely can happen if you want
to be out there.
Again,
Hashtag keep it real balling to,
yeah,
Hashtag balling.
I mean he's,
he's walking around with expensive
watches,
these beautiful David August suits on.
He wears,
he's tailored suits everywhere.
Here's the super expensive shoes and
watches and many of their lambos are
driving around Ireland to a lot.
That's great point.
No,
that's a good point.
That's a good point.
Yeah.
He's balling out of control.
I wonder what it would take him.
I mean now that he had that big crazy
fight at the fight and when he jumped
over the fence and pushed referee Mark
Goddard,
I wonder what it would take to get him
back in the cage now.
Like one of it's going to be fines and
suspensions.
I wonder what the fuck is going to
happen.
It's quite fascinating,
but I'll tell you one thing.
He makes things fun.
He does.
It makes things fun.
With Oscar de la Hoya is hitting the
heavy bag on.
He should say that he'll fight Oscar de
la Hoya,
but only if Oscar agrees to wear a
skirt.
You got to wear a skirt and you've got
to wear fishnet stockings and I'll
fucking fight.
You think there's anything still too.
I've heard Roy Jones is still trying to
fight Silva,
which I don't know.
Is there any kind of,
not that it's going to happen,
but the undersigned does not take that
bait.
Yeah,
you have.
Roy Jones is,
I mean,
you see what happened when floyd fought
connor and connor is in his prime.
You know,
and I'm not saying that Roy Johnson his
prime,
but he's still very active.
He still fights.
Roy works out all the time and he
knocked out some uh,
amateur boxer MMA fighter last year.
He had some,
some fight.
Remember that like there was like a
contest to see who gets to fight him.
Yeah.
He Kao that guy with one punch a dinners
and get suspended for his,
uh,
yeah.
Yeah.
Anderson's going to be suspended for
quite a while.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Once,
if,
if he indeed is guilty.
Let me just preface that.
If he indeed is guilty and uh,
they,
they don't have any reason to believe
he's not.
What's your,
um,
what do you think is the move for conor
mcgregor?
Sure.
The fight Manny Pacquiao or tiny tube
made of gold can feel it with diamonds.
Haband trash.
Wow.
Oh,
till I get tired of doing it every day.
Crap.
Image oxide.
We fucking drank and had we,
during constraint the Tardis whiskey,
I drink a fucking gun barrel full of
Viagra,
gone barrel,
make my way to the pool and just started
shooting rounds off.
That's not a bad or good,
it's not a good time,
uh,
iconic mcgregor accent.
But is it good or lucky charms?
I would hire the most beautiful,
huge volleyball player,
women to just carry me everywhere.
Hmm.
Yeah.
Just to get giant super athlete women
and just carry you everywhere.
Do you think he fights Tony Ferguson or
does he fight?
That's the Moon Manny Pacquiao.
He used to be,
not the move,
but I think Tony Ferguson,
like I think Eddie Bravo had a real good
point about it when he and me and
Brendan talked about it.
I think Tony Ferguson,
uh,
is the right move as far as for the
fans.
I think,
uh,
over many.
Yeah.
I don't think that's smart.
I think if he wants to do a,
um,
a boxing match,
the real smart move,
be fun an mma fight and then fight a
boxing match in a year.
Uh,
but I think that,
um,
uh,
the Habib Nambucca madoff fight,
you've really got to see he'll be fight
somebody else first and the nate diaz
fight,
although it could be huge.
Nate's not really fighting anybody right
now.
I would,
what I would like right now,
this is my thought,
I think nate,
if nate comes back at fight,
someone who wins conor fight someone and
wins.
Connor is a boxing match.
They have a huge mma fight after that
fucking huge,
goddammit.
I mean 3 million pay per view buys huge,
gigantic.
He's got a ton of conor mcgregor.
Yes.
That's the fight.
It's going to get through it.
Yeah,
but that's a big fight.
He might not even have to get through
that if he can lose but lose in a
respectable manner,
like lose a very close five round
decision where it's like a nail biter
where at the end of the rank and,
Ooh,
and then Tony Ferguson drops the ground
and was like fuck.
And then there's like controversy.
I thought conor won and the people that
the pundents we'll debate it online if
he can lose a fight like that.
Yes.
But if Tony Lights him up,
crack some darce choke some puts them
out in the first round and then spits on
his dick.
Yeah.
Then the nate diaz fight isn't worth a
lot.
But yeah,
if he can do that,
he's like,
he's so loved by Ireland that he could
almost do anything.
You know,
like Daniel Cormier,
you said this to me,
we were at a fight.
It was in between while we're doing the
standup thing where like,
you know,
they set you up at the microphones and
you give your analysis about the
upcoming main event,
that kind of Shit.
And we're looking at each other and he
goes,
he doesn't lose anything when he loses.
He goes,
that's what's crazy.
Yeah.
He goes,
he loses a fight and the support is
exactly where it is,
if not more.
That's right.
He's like,
yeah,
I'd never seen anything like it.
They applied as courage.
He's just so brave.
Like he just puts on the line.
There's definitely that.
There's definitely,
except what he says is definitely that
crazy.
The fact that he came back and beat Ne,
cause I said that Brendan,
after I saw him lose a person that I go,
nate's just too big for him.
Big came back,
beat him.
Yeah.
And then and then and then knocks out in
the first round.
Knockout Eddie Alvarez second.
The second rounds aren't lit him up.
Sorry.
Unbelievable.
Like I was like,
what was the second round?
Wasn't it?
I want to say a second round.
I want to say made it to the,
I want to say they were coaching them.
It's fascinating man.
It's like to see him kind of back it up.
That's what they applaud.
Just his courage and his spirit.
It's also,
he's,
he's a great shit talker.
Yes.
That's a big part of this.
He's fun to listen to.
Great dresses.
Look at the way you dress to doing
second round.
Yeah.
Khabib needs to fight at one 70 there.
I said,
well you say that,
but he's got a new nutritionist and
Corina was telling me that he's having a
way less problems with his weight now.
He's 25 no,
no,
no.
He's not eating.
Okay.
No,
that he's in the one seven he's now.
Really?
Yeah.
That he's like way lighter now than he's
ever been.
Any time close to a fight and that he'll
have way less problem making weight for
this fight and they've got them on a
very strict nutrition schedule now
because he's fighting his team.
Yeah.
My coworker Tammy,
for me,
I tells me I'm sure much rockhold luke
walks around at two 15 you know,
I've listened to him.
It doesn't make near megabit off bigger.
You understand how that works,
right?
Right.
No,
it never like he looks at Luke posted a
picture of him training with Khabib and
I was like,
who's the giant?
And it was done.
Like he's one of the most impressive
grapplers I've ever seen in MMA.
Yeah.
It's ability to take guys who are very
good,
you know,
like Javiel dos Anjos and just sorta
ragdoll of wow.
He's his wrestling is.
It is.
It's,
it's stunning.
It's a different kind of Russ because I
think dos Anjos is better now than he
was during that fight,
but it doesn't matter.
It's like,
well,
the way he did it to him,
it's like,
man,
if there's levels where it's hard to
tell with them,
it may because strikings and fault when
strikings involved the,
you don't get to see the pure grappling
level.
But what I was seeing when I was seeing
just pure,
just pure grappling,
I would see in strength endurance
technique there.
It was just like 30% like they're
stacked up on number grammatical.
She gets a hold of you.
Yeah.
You're not getting him off.
He got Mowgli Javery yeah.
Nobody gets him off.
Look at the size of it could be a
breath.
Yeah.
But now I might be the camera angled,
but it could be,
but he's,
you know,
he's in front and,
but he's,
you know,
he's not cutting weight right there or
he's,
if he is,
you know,
halfway into the game.
Yeah.
He's a monster man.
He does.
I think he does really well at 72 that's
what I'm saying.
He posted something on his instagram.
This is a show you,
why motherfuckers so hard and why all
those people from Dagestan so hard.
He posted something on his instagram,
one of his friends who had been
tortured,
no posted photos of his friend who had
his stomach cut open.
Yeah.
He put posted on his,
in his,
uh,
instagram.
This,
this guy,
there's two photos,
there's this photo and then there's the
next one.
And this guy had his stomach cut open.
They were tortured him about something.
And there's a translation,
you can translate all of it,
but it has something you,
him saying that someone was wrongly
accused,
they were trying to get him to confess.
But the point is this is a UFC number
one contender,
or at least number two in the
lightweight division,
one of the most towns fact divisions in
the world.
And he's posting stuff on his page about
how hard his environment is that people
are being tortured.
Yeah.
He's,
when he gets in there,
his mind,
I mean you're,
you're fighting,
literally fighting.
He calls himself the Eagle.
He's like a fucking eagle.
Yes.
I mean he's fucking for Roche's when he
gets in there and he's at a level of
grappling,
like,
man,
he's been doing it his whole like crazy.
And at an intense super primal level,
you know,
so intense,
real technical,
super knowledgeable about wrestling and
Jujitsu and submissions.
I think Daniel said that they liked,
they basically tussled for 15 minutes.
Damn Daniel the Olympian.
Yeah,
he said it was hand fighting with them.
He like Whoa Shit.
It's like he's a beast,
never coming off as a beast.
And when you see him get a guy like
Michael Johnson down in the ground and
just own him,
he owned and he was saying,
look,
I'm sorry I gotta do this to you man,
but you gotta tap
like,
um,
I need my title shot.
Nobody saying guys beating the fuck out
of him,
man.
He was just holding him down and
pounding on him.
Yeah,
it was really hard for me to watch cause
one thing I'm like,
I'm impressed with Michael Johnson's
complete unwillingness to tap just,
he just like beat me up,
keep beating me up cause we're fighting
through it.
And then he eventually got Kimora but it
was just ruthless man.
Yeah,
it was ruthless and the control that he
had on him,
just his arm tied up and just beating
the shit out of all.
I was like,
wow,
this guys,
there's,
there's certain positions where you see
a guy so much better at a god that he's
not done and then a guy that,
the guy who's holding down just not
going to get up.
It's not going to get up.
So matter of time before he gets beaten
into unconsciousness,
right.
Jacques are raised the same way and when
[inaudible] gets on top of you or get
you down,
you,
you know,
unless you're a little Yoel Romero your,
we'll see you later.
Yeah.
See how he's got his right arm tied up.
He just clamps down on his wrist and his
right arm became,
he became a one arm defensive guys.
Just the guys been fighting and his
whole like wrestling his whole life.
So fine details.
It's fucking details though.
It's where his hips are.
It's all the minutia,
the micro movements that any,
any ways.
He probably feels like he weighs 300
pounds.
I'm sure like those wrestlers like that,
like,
you know,
the,
when you,
when you tussle with a guy who's been
doing it his whole life,
he can make him,
he can,
he can tap you.
If you're a regular guy by putting his
weight on you.
After a while,
you'll just,
you'll just tap and which ben her and
it's going to be on the podcast.
Oh,
I'm working it out with Ben astron going
to get them out here.
Finally,
I've been a ben ask a ball rider the
killer for several years.
Not Technically a Dick Rider Paul rider
or have a ball.
Right?
The Dick is so deep in it.
Now you're riding his girls over there.
I write,
I hold on the balls.
I look up at the day.
How much does he weigh?
Well,
what is he fights at one 70.
Uh,
okay,
so he's one seven athletic.
If I was 30,
50 or something,
cuts some weight for sure,
but I don't think he cuts a lot of
weight.
I mean,
it's not one of the bigger guys in the
division and he's just super technical.
This wrestling.
He was his,
uh,
where do you learn?
Well,
he is a fucking serious world class
amateur wrestler.
I mean,
do you know?
Yeah.
Before I thought he was just Jujitsu
tits.
No.
Ben Asker and pull up Ben aspirins
record.
You could see his collegic wrestling
He was a fucking monster at that hair.
Powerful Missouri.
Look at that.
Uh,
if you,
uh,
pull up his record,
those wikipedia record and he does a lot
of work with a lot of Duke roufus.
This guy's too.
Yeah.
Um,
he's has always been a corner man.
I've always seen him at the UFC.
He's,
yeah,
he just had,
he had some sort of an issue with the
post Olympic career.
So like what is the Olympic Games?
He was in Beijing.
Well,
what did he win in the Olympics?
He lost one.
Any one one.
Is that what it says?
Wow.
You know,
phenomenal wrestler.
I mean,
just phenomenal.
And he's retiring undefeated as a mixed
martial artist.
He just a,
I think he just beat Aoki.
I think that was his main,
his a retirement fight.
Wow.
One on another contest
after the Olympics.
To Dave Schultz Memorial International.
He Won.
MMM,
probably,
yeah,
probably over middle or defeated a
silver medalist in another tournaments.
Interesting.
Um,
go to his MMA career because I want to
see who he just beat for his retirement
fight cause he just had,
it was retirement fight.
Yeah.
Shinya Aoki who at one point in time was
one of the most,
uh,
exciting submission guys in the world.
And he was
right.
Uh,
did she tapped out by Nick Diaz?
He used to wear tights.
That's what I'm still fighting though.
You seen that was recent?
Yeah.
Aoki just fought Ben Aspirin.
I didn't know basketball was still
fighting.
Yeah,
this was his retirement fight.
He just had like,
just had it like last week.
Wow.
Yeah.
I sent him a congratulations and I said,
let's do a podcast.
He had a twin brother or am I thinking
of Matt Hughes?
You're thinking of Matt Hughes.
Are you sure to have a twin brother too?
Might as well.
I don't know.
And,
and but uh,
let me ask you,
this.
Does,
why was Matt Hughes Doing,
do you know?
He's doing better?
Apparently they're really excited about
his progress.
You know,
he was in a coma for quite a while from
the,
apparently what they're saying is that
he thought that he could make it across
the tracks and then if you waited,
the train takes like 10 minutes to go or
tearing or attendance,
fucking giant ass train.
So he took a chance and he hit some
gravel and he was able to sell.
I worked with them on warrior and you
know what he said to me?
Well he goes,
I just hope I can put my shoes on,
put my own shoes.
I when I'm 70,
I can like he cause he,
he worked,
we were talking about head,
head trauma.
He worries about it.
He says about all should he should,
you know,
and towards the end of his career he
developed a,
um,
a compromise chin.
It's the best way to put it.
Like you could see like everybody,
j pen,
brain shut down.
Does everybody,
does chuck the Dal who had the,
probably one of the greatest chins of
all time,
he exhibited it later in his career.
He just couldn't take shots anymore
because your body goes,
oh,
I've been here before.
I see a letter and shuts down.
Yup.
It makes sense.
A guy who is just rock solid for Rosha
says Chuck Liddell,
he just a walkthrough bombs.
Guys are just throw bombs on him.
He'd walk through them at the end of his
career,
he could not do that anymore.
So interesting.
How your,
how a lactone of fighting makes you more
fragile,
you know?
Yeah.
I mean your body's just not designed for
that.
He did an x ray of his face and he has a
micro fractures all through his face and
he said,
and the doctor said it's very common
with fighters and football players
choose corona.
Just micro just cracks all through your
math.
Oh my God.
Of course.
Yeah.
You think about Brendan Spar and Shane
car when all the times getting mugged.
How about getting punched full on and
having his nose shattered by Cro cop?
It was an elbow,
in fact.
Yeah.
And still coming back.
Lamb.
Yeah.
Took shots.
Took some good shots from a big country
before he got hit behind the ear.
He watched that fight.
Well,
boom.
Ben Rothwell caled him
Big Ben.
He's another guy.
Like what happened with him?
He got caught with something,
right?
Yeah,
man.
Ask him,
does not have a twin brother.
I know.
He's got a brother.
Oh,
there it is.
There you go.
That's her brothers.
I think
one of the things that,
um,
I mean when you're talking about in
these,
the fucking athletes that we're dealing
with today,
you know,
he talking with like what they're
experiencing.
I think with medical science,
I bet like in 50 60 years we're going to
be looking back and they're going to be
going,
God damn,
man,
these people couldn't even take blah,
blah,
blah to fix their problem.
They couldn't even go to the blah,
blah,
blah machine to fix their brain and they
just had to have bad brains.
Right?
Remember what Robert Sapolsky said in
your podcast last time?
He said,
I thought it was amazing.
He says,
we learn more.
What do you think's going to happen?
He said,
I think in like 20,
30,
40 years,
we're going to go,
my God,
look at the way we treated people who
killed and who did things that were
impulsive.
They,
their brains were just fucked up and we
didn't know how to fix him well,
just that he,
um,
he was not just talking about their
brains being fucked up.
He was saying that the idea of free will
is a ridiculous concept that's ingrained
in the psyche of the American people in
particular.
And that's a Christian idea.
Yeah.
But it's also that you as a scientist,
the way he looks at things,
I mean,
he's boiling things down to the fucking,
the,
the very atomic level.
And he's essentially saying that your
behavior has been determined by your
environment,
by your genes,
by year.
The experiences that you've had by all
of this,
things that you've left frontal cortex
may not be as developed because you grew
up poor and under a lot of stress.
So you make impulsive decisions,
lack of nutrition.
They got the guy who kidnapped bent girl
I was talking about.
The young girl had two kids with her
when she was 13 years.
His father said that he had a motor
cycle accident.
He was a normal kid,
and then he had a motorcycle accident.
He was never the same.
He,
his whole personality,
just the kinison story,
the kit and got hit by a truck.
Oh Wow.
Kinison was one kid,
Sam kinison got hit by a truck and then
he's like,
wow,
wow.
That gut kicking over.
If you know what else changed your
personality,
they say sometimes,
which is fascinating.
Jerking off in your own mouth,
almost almost.
That would be traumatic.
Changes your personality.
It would be traumatic for a little bit.
It does a little until you end up liking
it.
But here's what really changes.
You're having a heart,
uh,
operation.
Oh,
that makes sense.
Now what was so weird though,
we'll see for an operation on your heart
and it changes your whole personality.
Well,
there's one thing about that that Dr.
Mark Gordon,
you know,
he actually did a paper on um,
post traumatic surgeries like open heart
surgeries and the effect it has on
depression and perhaps suppression of
your body's ability to produce hormones.
There's something about being under
anesthesia for long periods of time with
very complicated operations.
It leaves people uniquely depressed
afterwards.
Wow.
Yeah.
And he was,
he was telling me about this after the
whole Robin Williams,
things happen because Robin Williams got
sick,
he got a heart condition,
he had heart surgery,
and then he eventually one of committing
suicide.
And he's like,
I'm not saying it's the core,
it's the reason Robin Williams
did that,
but there is absolutely some connection
between this compromised hormonal system
and depression and between a compromised
hormonal system and long operations
while under anesthesia.
And I was like,
wow.
Have you had a lot of guys on about the
Gut biome?
Oh yeah.
And how that affects your mood from
having people on,
from having Chris Kresser on the last
time he was on,
I changed,
I'm eating like four cans of Kimchi a
week.
Oh really big ass cans,
man.
I mean fermented cabbage and of course
cause you're an extremist.
Do you have to eat that much?
I know,
but listen to me.
Look at me right now.
Who are you the just because fucking
Kim,
she's good for you.
Doesn't mean you have to eat that much
proud.
All the,
you're the,
you're the extreme.
Can you have a little bit like the way
the Koreans do feel pretty good.
I know,
but why the fuck he get his weapon?
He gets bay a piece of information and
he'll just eat bowls of Kimchi.
Yeah,
I played this video game.
Fainted.
I fainted.
I never do that.
But I have bone broth and Kim,
she of course you do.
Of course you do.
And I put Habanero sauce in the bone
broth.
A surprise.
I sweat beads of sweat coming off my
bald head.
His pouring down of course.
And I'm eating Spicy Kimchi and I'm
drinking spicy bonus.
Did you need stream?
Yeah.
Well want to live forever?
No,
no,
no.
And he's in love with mortality.
I told you I any mortality fuck out
until the lights go off.
This mother fucker is going good.
I'm going to be dead.
So this engine is perin.
I'm corner in,
everything's listen man.
If you don't think,
if you think I didn't have a long
conversation with Mister Justin Ds,
who is Phil Heath's trainer was and he's
a Mister Olympia guy.
He like trains all those guys.
I talked to him for a lot.
I cut to the chase.
I go phil,
Justin,
Knoxville,
Justin days.
I go justin right now,
Ken and my Sean Salt like I go and his,
his,
his beautiful wife,
heather ds is number four in the
Olympia.
She and I will kill you.
She looks amazing.
And I went,
I went,
hey bro,
let's cut to the chase.
You know everything about nutrition and
everything about weightlifting.
There's no doubt about how to build
muscle.
He's a fucking genius.
Talk to him about trt cause I'm 50 and
it's getting to a point where I'm going
to have to start shooting myself up.
What?
He said,
we had a long talk.
Don't worry about it.
The point is,
I'll be seeing the doctor for the sound.
Look,
if you guys see me,
really want to start?
No.
Uh,
she'd say no,
you don't mention it.
I'm not afraid.
Not Afraid.
You don't have that stuff.
First of all,
she's got a girl for a boyfriend or
other excuse.
She's got a husband.
Yes.
I wouldn't even talk about giant man.
He's a,
he's a very thick rabbet.
All right.
Sorry.
Sorry man.
Jamie's pulling up pictures of her.
Hey Bro.
I wasn't looking.
I was just looking at her back,
her back.
I'm looking at the basket.
Someone else by slaves doesn't mean you
have to.
You son of a bitch,
son of a bitch,
probably into orchids to [inaudible] is
the real problem with the social justice
warrior movement as they eat their own
to try to take away any sort of blame on
themselves.
I just think the left,
the liberal left is not,
that is lost.
Their sense of
humor.
You can't even be funny.
You can't say anything.
I predict that this is the inevitable
demise of a vast majority of the
colleges in this country and the people
are eventually going to learn how to
form communities and learn online.
Why Jonathan?
You know Jonathan Heit these creating
the Heterodox Academy,
you know about this?
No.
So John [inaudible] is a fucking giant.
Jonathan Heit,
I can't believe you haven't had much
podcast.
He's a giant.
He wrote the happiness hypothesis.
Lily fit in this room.
Ah Yes.
He,
his brain might not though.
And he basically is a Columbia
University and he was like this place
you got fucking students that can report
you blindly and then you get called up
in front of a whatever and he
[inaudible] appropriation of all,
it's 17 to one,
usually like 1717 to hardcore liberal
sort of leftists and one conservative to
ever do these colleges like Brown and
Columbia.
And he's,
he said this is orthodox thinking.
It's so bad that they've created safe
spaces where you're not even allowed to
hear the other side cause it might be
violent too much.
So he said,
I'm creating the Jonathan Heit,
h a.
I.
D.
T.
You have to have my various,
he's a fucking,
he's a genius and he's awesome in every
way and he's so important as a thinker,
he's been,
he's one of the more influential
thinkers in the past 30 years.
Really?
Yes.
Basically proving that intuition and
that your,
your feelings control so much of your
thinking.
He's a fucking genius social scientist.
Anyway,
that's my shout out to Jonathan.
Hi,
I'm glad I had a chance to talk about
them,
but powerful shout out to Jonathan Heit.
Yeah,
but he created the Heterodox Academy.
He's like,
this orthodox thinking is fucking,
you know,
is not good for anybody.
What we talked about earlier,
it's people being tribal idea sex.
We need idea sex.
Do you remember that thing at University
of Missouri Without Mama and that guy
was an Asian young student photographer
and this woman came over and she was
yelling at him to stop taking
photographs because they had created a
safe space.
And then she said,
can I get some muscle over here to take
this photographer out?
He's like,
this is like the first amendment.
Wow.
He's like,
I need freedom of speech.
Freedom of the press.
I was taking photographs like there's an
event that's happening on public
property here.
Like what do you,
I'm a part of the school.
I'm being hired to do this because she's
so,
she comes over and totalizing them.
She is,
she's a woman.
She's contacting them.
She's not even a child.
I mean that's her child.
She is a professor in training or
something like that.
Anybody who disagrees,
anybody comes to grace?
Look at her.
She looks like a fanatic.
You're need to get out.
I actually don't.
All right.
Wow.
So crazy.
She's not very smart.
Well,
she got caught up in the moment.
You know what I mean?
That's really what it is.
More than anything.
She probably thought she could get away
with doing that.
She didn't realize how crazy it would
seem on camera saying,
I've got some I want,
I need to get some muscle over here.
She her up.
So she's
chill.
She's thinking the same way.
Those that are intolerant I thinking,
right.
She's same methodology or brain works
the same way you're,
you're in the way.
I'm going to get you out of the way.
Well,
Isis goes,
you're not a believer.
No point in trying to convert you.
I'm going to shoot your,
cut your head off because it's the same
one mentality.
You were totally right.
You're totally right.
Same methodology.
Yeah.
And it's also like she's in a heightened
state,
right?
She's in the combat state.
She's immediately argumentative.
The guy's got a camera on her because
you got anybody,
anybody who disagrees where there's
region evil and false.
The enemy.
Why racist,
sexist,
homophobic.
And when you said when you hit somebody
with racism and you go,
you're a racist or sexist,
what you do is you shut down the whole
debate because you just,
you just labeled as very complex human
being with all kinds of emotions.
Right?
Who goes through it?
Some days I'm having a moment.
I fucking hate everybody.
But other days I love everybody and
everybody.
Then you hate black people,
then you're racing them all.
But if I'm listening,
I'm listening or day I care about
terrorists and their mothers and
everything.
And you know,
it depends.
We all have moments,
but when you brand somebody,
what we do is we go,
you're a racist.
You said one thing,
so you're racist.
Now I'm going to inflate that.
I'm going to blow that up like a big
balloon and fucking strap it to your
face and you are out of the conversation
wherever you've done ever brill cause
you're my competition.
That's right.
And your ideas,
your ideas might be threatening to me.
More important.
They're actually,
they create violence towards me,
therefore I need to save space.
Oh,
and by the way,
I have all the answers.
My side is rooted in the truth and love
plus crabs in a bucket.
I'm trying to push those other clubs
down so I can make my way to the tip of
the tip.
I love crab metaphors.
God,
goddammit.
Best Way to do it is to call other
people racist.
That's it.
Everybody's like,
what?
Me?
What?
You immediately get people on their
heel.
Who blood.
We're not racist.
Sexist tool.
Yup.
Oh Yo,
what am I saying?
We're not racing this actually with
tribal,
right?
That's the thing.
There's a smile,
logical basis to sex,
and that is patriarchal in and of
itself.
There's no biological basis for sex,
not hormones,
not x,
Y,
chromosome.
There's no uterus are saying that on
ironically in 2017 I they're saying it
on a regular basis.
Really?
Yup.
It's one of the Jordan Peterson
discussions that he had with some,
I don't know if it was a man who became
a woman or a woman and became a man,
but she was a professor.
He's a professor of medicine.
No professor at University of Toronto
professor in like transgender studies.
I saw the debate.
Yeah.
It was hilarious.
Debate.
I know she's saying there's no sexual or
bile.
What is it?
There's no difference between the
popular misconception to think that
there is a difference between a male and
female.
This doesn't exist and there was no
biological,
biological basis for Jenny.
Like,
well,
okay,
but if you go to the puppy door and you
see,
oh,
I want a boy puppy and they'll give you
a girl puppy,
would you say you say,
well,
there's no biological basis.
How about the power lifter?
The power lifter that
became a woman and was a competitive
power lifter as a man,
I just stop you right there because she
is a woman.
She's always been a woman.
Sorry.
Don't be a piece of shit.
No,
she's a woman now.
no,
no.
She's always been a woman just now.
She gets to express herself in the most
unique way.
I see it when she was,
even though she had an xy chromosome in
a dick and she was competing in men's
division,
she was told him she was a woman.
This is so transphobic.
I can barely handle this.
That's a question,
man.
She is her authentic self,
so you get a lot of shit for your,
when you talk this way from I'm only by
people that are retarded.
Yeah,
exactly.
I feel like most trans gender people
would be very reasonable and not be
inside a bunch of transgender people
come to see me at the Ice House the
other day.
They'll give me hugs.
They were super sweet.
I love that.
They said with the Trans community loves
you.
I love you guys.
Like there's a lot of trans people,
by the way,
that we're upset at the whole Bruce
Jenner,
Caitlyn Jenner fiasco.
They were like,
look,
this is not who we are.
Like you're,
you just want more attention.
Hey,
your Kardashians.
Exactly.
Big Old male cardiac issue became a
chick settled out.
Right.
You know,
and there's a lot of people that felt
sort of like also when they found out
that Bruce Jenner then became Caitlyn
Jenner,
and then after that didn't believe in
gay marriage.
So fucking weird
gave you just crazy.
You can,
you can be a boy who wants to be a girl
or a girl wants to be a boy.
Doesn't mean you're smart,
but doesn't mean you're smart and that's
a problem,
right?
That's a problem.
And if you are an intelligent person who
is in the transgender community,
you don't want that as your ultimate
representation.
You just don't.
You don't want someone who's got that
much of a contradiction where they look
and they asked him about it.
One of the most crazy things he said is
like,
well,
oh,
forwards.
It's been the traditional work.
Like what?
Why not traditionalist?
You're a man who became a woman that's
not traditional.
You don't believe in gay marriage
because that's even dumber because
you're talking about and you're changing
biology and you're saying that some
manmade bullshit fucking thing called
marriage.
That guy shouldn't be able to do it if
they love each other.
But you should be able to be a girl.
Right.
Shut the fuck up.
That makes me angry.
So making me angry,
I can't even,
I ended up rubbing my eyes cause I don't
know how to,
I don't know how to respond to insanity
is the only time I've ever seen ellen go
after somebody.
Really?
Ellen had Caitlyn Jenner on her show and
she actually went after and just notice
how I said her not mis-gendering cause
I'm a good person.
Yeah you are.
And I'll vote.
I'll vote Democrat if it works.
It's strange.
Remember I stepped out on the podcast.
You were like pull shit.
I was like,
I've heard it.
Yeah.
You called it way before anybody knew it
was called.
I got.
That's cause I heard it from a reliable
source and you called it like I'm on a
same a year and a half early.
Yes.
Cause I knew it.
He was already starting to feminize
Feminine Eyes Look,
looks also it's kids go to a school and
he would show him bracelets and they
were like,
what's going on?
It's hair would be in a burette.
You and I need to get press credentials.
What does this feminism site?
Medusa magazine shuts down after founder
admits it was pure satire.
Oh my God.
Don't gender your pets.
It was pure satire the whole time.
Oh you beautiful people.
Thank you on a tweet,
that podcast.
So
thank you for being you.
Thank you for fighting the good fight.
Resist.
That's the real resist.
Keith Olbermann.
I get what you're doing,
but the real resist is to fight the
nonsense nonsense with humor.
We know what Michelangelo said,
my favorite,
their quote,
criticize by creating,
I got a new show for you and me.
What you owe me.
Yeah.
We go to places we get high as fuck.
Okay.
We become journalists.
We get high as fuck.
And I don't say anything.
I forget if,
I don't know,
we'll be doing just like this.
You just,
okay,
you don't get high as fuck.
I get high as fuck.
I can take one hit.
We go to places as journalists and we
interview people,
whether it's we go to like a Republican
correspondence dinner or Democratic
convention or we go and you just,
you and I just,
but drunk and high and we interviewed
these people and we mocked this whole
thing.
We get it.
We get a view of how crazy the frenzy
is.
The center of the Hive for control of
the Queen
and watch those fucking crazy assholes
just to call him.
He called the center of the Hive Freak
party worldwide.
That's what we call it free party
worldwide.
We're not,
Democrats were never publicly
freak party worldwide.
And we'd go,
Oh man,
we act as I'm dead serious about this.
I say,
we get Netflix to do this.
Alright.
And we just fucking travel.
I'll do it in a heartbeat.
Yeah.
We get one dude to film must.
He can keep his mouth shut and we never
see each other.
I always complain about on the podcast,
I'm like,
I never see rose.
I sulk about it.
I'm like,
I see it twice.
I,
let's go.
Let's go hunting.
I know,
but you're,
you're,
you're deer hunting.
I have a fucking bowl,
bro.
I know.
I get a PR.
I'm out.
I've got a problem though.
I've got a hunting problem.
What?
Oh,
really?
Kimchi and fucking hunting.
You mean you were an extreme of both?
Yep.
I'd never seen that before from,
you know,
well,
this is,
you know,
I'm out there every day shooting out of
rubber dear.
Are you?
Yeah.
It's a real problem.
I kept fucking,
I got gold
in my arm to pull my bow back.
Too much ad against stem cell shots.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I'm going crazy.
Yeah.
I have a good time though.
Fucking wonderful time.
He fucking boxing shop gets mad at me
for sparring,
but I just love it so much that it rod
bitch that it,
right.
I'm with you,
but it rod.
Yeah.
Did you see that?
That where Luke rockhold punched me in
the fucking nose.
Yeah.
Don't want to do that.
And then,
and then I had to go get makeup to my
nose was so black and blue.
I had to go.
I'm at the fucking San Jose Improv.
That's how I kind of take pictures of,
this is ridiculous.
I couldn't cover it.
It was black and blue.
Why'd you let him punch you?
I didn't.
It wasn't like,
hey look.
I was like,
well obviously he threw me headgear and
I go,
hey,
look,
listen to me right now.
I'm a gazelle right now.
And they're a bunch of lines out there.
Let those people know like all those
guys training that I'm,
I'm a bitch that I'm an actor 50 and I
dance around a gym.
How bad did it hit?
I spar because I do it with people who
aren't athletic.
Yeah,
but it was way worse than that.
What's that?
What did he hit you with?
Oh,
he punched me with his fucking glove
right in the nose.
That's when it was.
It wasn't even,
it got purple.
Okay.
Well,
why do you think it's cute to fight
professionals?
Domo,
first of all,
I didn't want to,
I thought it was going to hit mitts and
he throws me headgear and I go,
I don't want to do this.
And Daniel Cormier goes,
I got him first and core mate double
legs me and look at it,
look at that.
Stupid knows are going to take pictures
with ridiculous what didn't work.
You should just stick to just straight
boxing where you could school them with
your skills.
Oh yeah.
You know me.
I'll fucking slip those jazz pop,
pop,
pop about.
That's the one of the worst things.
Like why don't you get involved in
Jujitsu that way you don't have to get
hit.
I'm going to.
Yeah,
because this wrestling I miss.
I Miss Mat work.
I really do.
When you first started doing Jiu Jitsu,
way back when we were at Carlson
Gracie's malaise.
You took to it right away because I was
a wrestler and it was like,
oh,
this is,
I got trained with hence over here for a
year.
I love Jujitsu.
I love it.
Love it.
I like boxing though.
I really like.
It's fun.
It's such a challenge to me like,
like,
um,
obviously Jujitsu is a whole world and
it's really difficult,
but there's something about boxing at my
age I guess I like because it's,
it's,
I guess it's just such a mystery.
It's such a mystery tenant.
Well,
you're learning a skill and pattern in
the,
yeah.
And then on top of that you're also
working out.
Yes.
That's one of the fun thing.
Like you've used to find a sport,
like here's a good one.
Soccer,
I'll give you play soccer.
You're going to fucking run around a
lot,
a lot.
But you're also going to fuck your knees
up you to fucking,
and I'm tool.
But boxing,
you actually stay pretty injury free,
believe it or not.
And you can get to the point where
you're not going to,
yeah,
but you wear headgear,
you don't go crazy on each other.
I'm not fucking fighting,
you know?
Do you know where you get hurt when you
spar dudes who don't box and they swim
for the fences and they catch you and
you fight.
Dudes like that are really good.
[inaudible] the Great Wayne Mcculloch
out spar with him.
Sometimes I get in there,
Wayne's fucking Wayne.
Wayne at 44 is going to do whatever he
wants even though he's 135 pounds,
but it's,
we're moving around.
He'll hit me,
but it's not,
he's not going crazy.
Exactly.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's,
that's the best in Jujitsu to you get
less hurt when you spar with someone
who's really good.
Correct.
You don't win.
You're going to get tapped a lot,
but you won't get hurt.
Right.
He'll just control you and you learn
patterns and then pretty soon you learn
these patterns,
you start practicing.
Then you go against the guy who doesn't
box a lot and you look good.
Like you know what you're doing.
Yeah.
And he goes,
dude,
you've been doing it a long time ago.
A opprobrium I look good.
Just see my left.
What's funny is you can find,
somebody can learn how to hit myths.
It's where you punching from and we'll
kind of like,
how are you setting that up?
That's how are you not getting hit.
Yeah.
And what happens when you hit to the
body and like
that's the worst.
That is the fucking worst.
That's why it kickboxing.
He's so much more terrifying.
And Molly,
ty wants to,
is getting need in the body.
And I was watching John Wayne Parts.
He had a video up on his instagram of
him fighting when he was 17.
The first title that he won.
Wayne parts like 44 note John Wayne
Carson,
my boyfriend,
and talking about 40,
41.
And he's 41.
And uh,
still going after it,
but like watching a video of him from
when he was 17 years old knee and some
dude in the body body's like,
oh,
punches.
I don't have time to condition my shin.
This is him.
17 men net crazy.
1993.
[inaudible] crazy.
Look at those needs of the body son.
Is that him and the Red John Wayne
Parts.
Fucking savage.
Boom,
boom,
boom is a real fighter man.
Yeah.
It's um,
it's a crazy way to express yourself,
you know,
but you really get to see a person's
character in a fight.
That's the thing that makes it so crazy.
It's just,
it's this wild may lay of bones and
flesh and you get to see how bright your
star shines.
It's also really awesome to learn
defense and learn how to get out of the
way.
Learn how to block your eyes open when
somebody kicking and stuff.
Yeah,
problem solving.
How to figure out what to do when.
Yeah.
When the issues are what poon that's it
by the way.
I shouldn't,
but just so everybody knows I didn't
spar with Luke.
Rockhold games just punched you in the
face.
I got to move around and they were
really nice to me and they,
they,
they move me around at will so let's
not,
I hate when people like me say,
I sparred with so and said,
no you didn't spar.
You didn't spar with them cause they'd
beat the fuck that.
Fuck him.
Yes.
You moved around with them and they were
being cool and you've got to throw some
shit and do some stuff that you've
learned and giggles.
Yeah.
Relax.
If I'd opened up with my taekwondo,
they'd be sued.
What if you did like with him?
Bruce Lee movies did my wheel kick.
You want to know fucking shit.
I've seen it like sorta like when that
not in the air.
You have caution and Regan air.
You know ty cobb could read the letters
on the,
I can see your kick coming a mile away,
but you can read.
You can read.
You can read the label on my underwear.
Well,
Brian Callan,
it's 5:00 PM I say we wrap this pitch
up,
brings him pleasure my brother.
We need to do this more often.
I love we've said this before.
I miss you too.
I never see it.
I don't see you enough.
It hurts my feelings.
My feelings are a little hurt.
Hey,
we're hanging out in a couple of hours,
but I'm the record store tonight for the
record.
My feelings are hurt.
My knee not hurt too.
All right,
so my fault.
Shit,
you're busy too,
bitch.
We're both of them are busy.
Really Fun though.
It was awesome.
Brian.
Count,
but it's jumping me.
Call him cops,
cops and cops.
December seven eight nine 10 then the
following weekend,
shot Schomburg in December,
they called 60 whatever plan ahead.
Yup.
And by the way,
go see Brennan shop at the Wilbur
Theater.
Please.
January 19th so that bitch out December
19th no genuine,
authentic January 19th January,
19th day before the UFC.
I'll be there hanging out with them.
All right.
You fucks.
We love you.
Bye.
That's awesome.