The joe rogan experience.
That's a guy thing like guys want to see
like yoga pants on it's schick.
Like a girl can walk down the street
with yoga pants and a camel toe.
Totally acceptable.
If a guy walked down the street with
fucking ballet tights on and no shirt,
Jesus Christ is Hugh Jackman.
That's not real.
Yeah,
no it's not.
Come on.
That's not real.
That guy's face faces.
Photoshop.
You're so full of shit.
Look at that guy in the left.
The lighting,
the lighting is totally,
it's not real.
They're,
they have their shadows are in the wrong
direction.
Hugh Jackman Shadow's coming towards us.
This guy's shadow is going towards his
left shoulder on real.
Get the fuck out of here.
How dare you think that Dude's hgh in?
Uh,
probably.
Yeah,
if he's smart.
Shred it out,
Bro.
We were,
for whatever reason,
Brian was obsessed with the fact that
Hugh Jackman was Kay.
He wouldn't stop talking about it.
It's fucking hands were moving.
He kept puffing on the glass.
Dick.
He was like,
I hear you.
Jacqueline's gay.
There's multiple pictures of him holding
hands with guys.
Come on,
son.
Is Multiple pictures of me with big
black dicks in my mouth.
But I did
hold on a second back that up because
one of those look real.
Go ahead.
Go piss you weak bladder at son of a
bitch.
Who's the guy with the beard is a
Wolverine Fan.
He's telling them how I'm watching that
movie made them cure cancer.
That's what it is.
So Hugh Jackman's guy in the right,
let me see,
is he really holding that guy's hand or
is that a perspective that night?
Like a perspective thing.
Who cares if he's gay?
But it's a weird thing like a chicken.
Be Gay like a Jodie foster and everyone
knows she's gay.
She's out,
it's all good.
And she could play okay.
That is super gay.
God,
but sexy Frawley he looks so these look
so big.
But you know,
if a woman like Jodie foster be decides
to come out and you know,
proclaims that she's gay,
that's not real either.
Stop it.
Just stop.
Stop.
Now.
It's a woo hoo.
Awesome opinions.
What's this guy doing?
It's fucking my kg.
I didn't plan this.
Um,
tell you a funny story and some of your
listeners know I had the first Jujitsu
Academy and the eastern seaboard and
these guys and a exercise.
And um,
at one point we had a guy by the name of
Jeff,
Tom Watson,
who was a Philadelphia Eagle football
player.
This guy was probably about six foot
five to 75 at the time,
if I remember correctly.
Unbelievably strong and lean and slim.
He was the darling of the super bowl the
year that the eagles went to the
superbowl in Jacksonville.
He was called up.
He had actually been released from the
team,
but they had a couple of injuries and
they called him in and went in there,
caught a couple of touchdown passes.
Wow.
So,
uh,
he,
he's,
he comes to my Jujitsu class and it's
like,
Whoa,
wait a minute.
[inaudible] was designed to protect us
for guys like you,
man.
You know,
what do you do with a guy?
I mean just ungodly strong.
Yeah.
He came to my kettlebell class.
It's the first time I ever had to break
out like a 48 kilogram kettlebell just
to teach these guys swings cause he was
based kilogram.
What is that about a hundred pounds?
That's a hundred.
I mean he was just like doing front
uprisings,
w you know,
front front raises with his shoulders.
He was just so ridiculously strong.
So he gets a go on with one of my brown
butter,
the time a fellow by the name of Ron
Hawkins who lives in Hawaii.
He teaches in the why now.
But at that time Ronnie was a brown belt
and ron gets him of course,
you know,
and then our block right from the mouth
and the guy literally does a Turkish get
up with Ronnie,
the fcm op.
How much does Ronnie way?
Probably about 148 pounds at the time.
Under 50 and the,
you know,
this guy's like two seven fa.
He literally does a Turkey.
Turkey's got up and just putting rhymes
head through the ceiling.
I remember screaming cause I,
you know,
this guy was like really an important
part of our team.
Don't hurt.
Don't break Friday.
Don't break rati put him down.
Put him down.
It was insane.
It's just insane.
Just how strong some people can be.
I mean,
you mean once you came to America and
what I was trying to get at was like,
what is it?
What's the opinion of America when
you're living over in England?
Does it look like when you see people
were invading Afghanistan,
fucking blowing up Iraq and some
missiles into Pakistan from robots that
fly in the sky or sucking up all the oil
all over the world.
Didn't bug us at all.
You're fucking awesome neighbors.
No,
I didn't know the craziest fucking
phrase.
A really fucking pissed us off guys.
Serious is when you come into our pubs
that your shitty rain jackets.
You know who is this weekend?
What the Fuck Matt Farah?
We didn't do nothing.
I don't own a single north face.
I know
over here with this bull shit shit.
Yeah.
So don't be surprised when you know you
get beaten up or when I'm in the UK.
Wait a minute.
Wait.
Don't be surprised.
We get beaten up.
I'm always prize when I get beaten up.
Right.
You're getting beaten up so often.
The Not surprised I'd be like,
God damn,
man,
you got fucking on some road,
different places.
You got to talk to people nicer.
Just fucking getting beaten up left and
right.
That's not surprising.
You fucking make it some critical
errors,
basically.
Everywhere you go.
I'm a fucking constantly shocked and I'm
beaten up every time it's ever happened
to be like,
what the fuck did I do that led to this?
Let's break this all down and never
repeat this problem again.
He's like,
well,
they were wearing the wrong jacket,
so we had a Kona them for the queen.
Okay.
You can see the wrong colors on
northface inquisition and he was born on
the wrong Patchett.
We signed the Patagonia Charter in 2014
Naco Sandwich coming your way,
mate.
Oh,
we do all weather gear.
Okay.
You know what we do like what?
You're afraid of her little mate.
How are we fighting in your neck?
Wet.
Okay.