Three,
two,
one.
Boom.
Hello,
Jack.
What's up?
Nice to meet you,
man.
Nice to meet you finally.
Yeah.
Keep this soccer like a fist from your
face.
Oh,
that's good.
First of all,
Dude,
you started a company when you started
twitter.
When you guys first started.
Did you have any idea?
There's no way you could've added any
idea what it would be now?
No,
but one of the things I always try to
emphasize with people when the people
are like,
oh,
twitter's crazy.
Like how could it not be crazy?
There's never been anything like it
before.
Like imagine trying to predict
the kind of,
the president of United States uses
twitter to threaten other countries.
Yeah,
I mean fuck.
Saw that coming.
Nobody saw that coming.
You think it was going to be when you
first did it?
Well,
you know,
we were building this thing for
ourselves and that's how that,
that's how everything starts.
We wanted to use it.
We wanted to,
we wanted to,
you know,
stay connected with each other.
We group text like a group text.
We loved our phones.
We loved,
um,
technology.
We actually started this as a hack week
project out of a failed company called
Odeo.
Just podcasting.
I remember that super early on.
We were,
uh,
were really creative folks,
but we weren't that passionate about
where podcasting was going in our
particular domain.
We just got a lot of competition early
on Itunes,
just released their podcast directory.
But we knew we wanted to work together.
We knew
we love this idea of one button
publishing.
We love this idea of collaboration.
We love this idea of a being anywhere
and being able to share what was
happening.
That was,
that was the idea.
I mean that,
that was it.
And that's what we wanted it to be.
And I think the most beautiful and also
sometimes uncomfortable aspect of
twitter is it,
um,
we really learned what it wanted to be
and the people helped create it.
Like everything that we hold sacred now,
the at symbol,
the Hashtag,
the retweet,
those were not invented by me or the
company.
Those were things that we discovered,
things that we discovered people using
and we just observed it and we,
we noticed what they were trying to do.
They're trying to talk with one another.
They were trying to,
um,
collect tweets around topics with a
Hashtag.
Has anybody figured out when the first
use of Hashtag something was created?
Yeah,
it was,
um,
it was actually our lead designer,
uh,
Robert Anderson who leads our design of
the cash app.
I'm hired him for square uh,
later on,
but uh,
he was the first one.
He was actually communicating with his
brother and uh,
he put at buzz,
his brother's is buzz and it just kinda
spread.
It wasn't in mass but people were doing
it,
but what was most interesting is not
what they're doing,
but what they wanted to do with it.
They wanted to address each other and
that's,
that changed the company completely.
That changes the service because I went
from just broadcasting what's happening
to conversation and to being,
being able to address anyone publicly
out in the open,
which came with it a lot of power and
also a lot of issues as well.
Yeah.
The,
the use of Hashtags,
like a little looking up Hashtag,
you know,
fry fest or Hashtag,
anytime there's something weird that's
in the news that's a,
that's such a unique way to find things,
but to go on twitter and to,
to utilize that.
It's uh,
it's,
it's interesting that you're,
that this guy just did it just to
contact his brother.
Well that was,
that was the symbol of the Hashtag was
this Guy Christmas ina and he was trying
to,
he was trying to tag,
um,
Houston trying to tag around topics that
he was tweeting about.
And again,
that spread,
all we did was made it easier.
We made it more accessible.
We enabled everyone to do it.
Uh,
without symbol.
We made a page that collected all
mentions of your name with the Hashtag.
We allowed people to search a
immediately so you can tap on the
keyword.
And you would see everyone talking about
that or tweeting about that specific
Hashtag.
So these things were just emergent
behaviors that we didn't predict and
they became the lifeblood of the
service.
What's fascinating to me about something
like twitter or even something like
youtube is that there's not a lot of
other ones like it.
There's just this one thing,
like how does that happen where this one
thing sort of gets adopted by everybody
and takes over and then just becomes
this overwhelmingly massive platform.
I mean,
there's really,
there's Vimeo and there's a few other
video services,
but nothing on the scale of youtube.
And that's the same thing with twitter.
There's nothing on the scale of
distributing information in a quick,
short,
280 character form like that.
We,
um,
I,
I don't think we could plan for it.
I don't think we could necessarily
billed for that.
I,
uh,
someone said recently to,
we just,
you know,
gathered a bunch of our leadership last
week in palm springs for an offsite.
And someone said recently the twitter
was discovered.
And I think what's behind all that is
that it,
it,
it hits something foundational,
it hit something essential.
And my co founder Biz likes to say that
twitter can never be uninvented.
It's here.
It changed everything though.
The use of it has been revolutionary and
it's just this simple idea of,
you know,
if you could text with the entire world,
if you could actually reach anyone in
the world or anyone could see what
you're thinking,
which I think is also the beautiful
thing about,
about taxed and the,
and the medium.
You can actually get it,
someone's raw thoughts and anyone in the
world can see that instantaneously.
It becomes a subconscious.
It becomes this global consciousness.
And it,
uh,
it gets to some really deep places in
society.
And,
and some of those places are pretty
uncommon.
Well,
it also gets to some really deep places
psychologically.
Um,
there's,
there's some,
there's a weirdness to it,
right?
There's a weirdness to sending text,
particularly at anonymously,
you know,
um,
and there's so many accounts that are
just an egg,
you know,
so many accounts where they're clearly
designed,
if you like.
Sometimes someone will tweet something
mean to me and I'm like,
hmm,
I wonder what this person's up to.
So I go to their site and it's just them
tweeting mean shit at people all day
long.
Like it's probably some angry person at
work and then like,
I'm just going to find people and fuck
with them all day.
When did you realize,
or when did you realize,
I'm sure you're aware of it,
and when did you realize that this was
almost out of your control in terms of
the scale of it?
Uh,
there were,
there,
there wasn't,
there wasn't one moment,
there wasn't one moment that it just
felt completely resonant.
It's just,
it's,
it's unfolded into the next thing and
the next use case.
And it just keeps surprising us with how
people are using it.
We,
you know,
it,
it definitely.
Um,
recently I think we've identified some
of the areas of the service that we need
to pay a lot more attention to.
Twitter is unique in that it has two
main spaces,
one which is your timeline and those are
the people that you follow and uh,
you know,
when you follow someone,
they've earned that audience and then it
has this other world where anyone can
insert themselves into the conversation
they can actually mention you and you'll
see that without asking for it,
you can insert yourself into hashtags,
into a search.
Um,
and these are areas that people have
taken advantage of and these are the
areas that people have gained our
systems to in some cases artificially
amplify,
but also just to spread a lot of things
that weren't possible with the velocity
of that they're not possible before.
Now when this is all happening,
what's the conversation like at twitter
when you recognizing that this is
happening,
that people are kind of gaming the
system?
Like what it,
how do you guys,
how do you mitigate it?
What's the discussion?
Well,
early on it was,
um,
it was pretty surface level.
Like,
how do we change some of the APP
dynamics,
but more recently we're trying to go a
lot deeper and asking ourselves the
question when people open twitter,
what are we incentivizing,
what are we telling them to do when they
open up this app?
We may not explicitly be doing it,
but there's something that we're saying
without,
um,
being as clear about it.
So what does the light button
incentivize?
What does the retweet,
What does the number of followers and
making that number big and bold
incentivize?
So
I'm not sure what we should.
I'm not sure if we should incentivize
anything,
but we need to understand what that is.
And I think,
you know,
right now we,
we do incentivize a lot of echo chambers
because we don't make it easy for people
to follow interests and topics.
It's only accounts we incentivize,
um,
a lot of outrage and how hot takes,
because of the,
some of the dynamics in the service.
Not allowing a lot of nuance in
conversation earlier on,
um,
uh,
pseudonyms,
this,
uh,
ability to not use your real name
incentivizes some positive things like
allows for whistleblowers and
journalists who,
uh,
might fear for their career or even
worse their life and under certain
regimes,
but also allows for people like the
example you mentioned of just random
fire and a spread of abuse and
harassment throughout.
So those are the things that we're
looking at and how do we,
how do we enable more of the
conversation to evolve?
How do we increase the credibility,
reputation of accounts?
Um,
how do we identify a credible voices
within a particular domain?
I'm not just through this very coarse
grain,
blue verified badge,
but if you're an expert in a particular
topic,
how do we recognize that in real time
and show that so that we can provide
more context to who you're talking to
and if you want to engage in a deeper
conversation or just ignore mute or
block them.
But what is the conversation like while
you were at work?
Like when you realized that all this
stuff is happening.
Um,
and you realizing that now,
particularly because the president uses
it so often in such a,
I mean,
it's his preferred platform for
communicating with the people.
I mean even more so than addresses.
It's really,
it's very strange.
What's the conversation like in the
office when you're trying to figure out,
hey,
what's our responsibility here?
Like how are we supposed to handle this
or how do we.
I mean,
you're,
in some ways what twitter is doing is
it's really kind of its flavoring,
the public narrative,
its flavoring,
the way we communicate with each other
in this,
in our culture worldwide.
Yeah,
I mean,
the conversation has definitely evolved.
I think in the past we just got super
reactive.
Um,
we were reacting to all the negative
things that we're seeing in that led to
a lot of short term thinking.
Um,
more recently we've just looked much
deeper.
We don't react to the,
to the present day where we look for
some of the patterns and um,
you know,
we,
we have,
uh,
we have a company that,
is not just serving the people of this
particular country,
the United States.
This is global,
we have global leaders all around the
use all around the world using us in,
in different ways.
Some,
you know,
more,
um,
with higher velocity,
some,
uh,
recognize more of the power.
Um,
some put out statements,
some lead conversations,
but it's looking at all those dynamics
and not trying to hyperfocus on any one
particular one because if we do,
we're only building it for one portion
of the population are only one perceived
a present,
a crisis.
What I'm,
what I'm trying to get at was like,
okay,
look,
when things come up,
like say if you find out that there's
people from Isis,
the using twitter and they using twitter
and posting things like what is the
conversation like,
how do,
what do we do about this?
Do we let them leave this up?
We,
we recognize this as free speech.
Do we only take it down if they're
calling for murder or hate speech?
Like what,
how do you handle that?
Well,
it evolves.
I mean because like we first saw isis
when the world saw isis and we needed to
change our policy to deal with it.
What was the,
what was the initial reaction to it?
So once you realized that people from
Isis,
we're making twitter accounts and they
were trying to recruit people and doing
all these things,
what was the,
what was the thought process?
Oh,
it was a question like what are,
what are we going to do about this?
We haven't experienced this before.
We need to.
Nobody has.
I mean,
you're essentially pioneered.
No.
Yeah,
but there,
there are people who have experienced in
different forms in different mediums.
So we reach out to our government
partners,
for instance,
our law enforcement partners,
we reach out to our peer companies to
ask if they're seeing the same things
that we're seeing.
Um,
we have a bunch of civil societies that
we talked to,
uh,
to get their take on it as well.
And we try to balance that across,
um,
you know,
various spectrums,
whether it be a,
you know,
a more organizations that are more
focused on preventing online harassment
all the way to the Acu and the eff who
are protecting the first amendment
online.
So we,
we try to get as many perspectives as
possible.
Take that and then make some informed
decisions,
but also realize that we're probably
gonna make some mistakes along the way
and all we can do to correct some of
that is just be open about where we are
and that's probably where we failed the
most in the past is we just haven't been
open about our thinking process.
Um,
what led particular decisions,
how our terms of service evolve in terms
of service as an area in our industry is
just a,
it's a mess.
No one reads them,
you,
you know,
you sign up for these services and you
quickly hit accept and we expect people
to read these rules of the road,
but they haven't read them.
And have you ever read them?
I have read.
Have you read facebook's?
I haven't read facebook.
I'm not on facebook.
Facebook,
right.
Just kidding.
What about instagram?
Do you ever read theirs?
I was,
uh,
I was in the first 10 users of a,
of instagram.
Really?
Uh,
Kevin was a intern.
Kevin Systrom was an internet at Odeo
and um,
I was one of the first investors of
instagram and loved the service side.
Don't think I've ever read their terms
of service.
Yeah,
that's what I'm saying.
Even you.
Even me,
but I read ours and one of the things I
noticed
right away is,
you know,
you read are uh,
you read our terms of service and one of
the first things that we put at the top
of the page was copyright and
intellectual property protections.
You go down,
you scroll down,
you see everything about violent threats
and abuse and harassment and a safety
and it's not that the company intended
for that to be the order,
it just,
we just added things going on.
But even a read of that put forth our
point of view like we're,
we're,
we're actually putting copyright
infringement above the safety,
the physical safety of someone.
So we need to relook at some of these
things and how they've evolved and how
they reacted.
But is it above just because it's listed
in second?
I mean is they're essentially all in the
same one sheet there on the one sheet
when you.
When you bring it up,
when you discuss it first.
Is that really critical?
They're all.
They're all part of the terms of
service.
Yeah,
but I think that ordering matters,
like what,
what do we consider to be most important
and we have to consider physical safety
to the to be the one thing that we
protect the most and so I to go threats,
physical threats,
doxing,
anything that impinges on someone's
physical safety.
An area where I don't think a technology
and services like ours have a focused on
enough.
We haven't focused on the f off platform
ramifications of what happens online.
So what do you do?
Like like here's a good,
for instance,
this situation with this,
a young kid who had the Maggot hat on
and the native American gentleman who
was in front of him banging the drum and
then people are calling for this kid's
name.
They want his name.
They want us to address,
including Kathy Griffin.
Like how do you.
How do you handle something like that?
Well,
because that's essentially request for
doxing.
Yeah.
And that's,
that is a new vector that we haven't
seen in mass and this,
these are,
these are the cases that bring up
entirely new thing,
so we have to study it.
We have to see how we reacted,
what happened with a network.
Um,
but this goes back to the incentives,
like we are incentivizing this very
quick reaction and it's taking away from
some of them,
some more of the like considered work
that we need to do to really diagnose
what's happening in the moment.
And it was such an interesting case
study to see how that evolved over just
48 hours.
Yes.
And that's one of the most fascinating
new cycles or stories in the new cycle
and quantitative because it's nuanced.
There's,
there's many different levels to it.
Yeah.
And a lot of like really knee jerk
reactions.
Totally.
And,
but we helped that had to help it.
Well,
it,
it's just,
that's how some of the dynamics of the
service work,
but those are those things we can
to make sure the service or is it the
way people choose to use the service?
Like if you're a thoughtful person,
you wouldn't just like for instance,
the original image that was distributed,
uh,
came from an account that's now banned,
right?
And so it was,
it was discovered that that account was
a troll account.
What,
how does that happen and what was the
thought process behind that?
Because the image that they posted was a
legitimate image.
It really did happen.
It wasn't,
it was a part of an actual occurring
event.
So why did you ban the person or the
troll account that put it up?
I don't know about this particular case,
but it's likely that it was found.
There's,
there's a lot of what you see on the
surface,
the twitter and some of the actions that
we take on the surface.
But where we spend a lot of our
enforcement is actually what's happening
underneath.
So in many cases we have um,
trolls or people like the case that you
mentioned whose sole purpose is just to
harass or abuse or spread a particular
information and oftentimes sees accounts
might be connected or they start one
account that gets banned,
they start another account,
but we can actually see this through a
network Lens and we can actually see
some of those behaviors.
So that might have been one of the
reasons I'm not sure in,
in,
in that particular case,
but you know,
at the,
how do you know,
do you know because of Ip addresses,
do you know because of the,
a variety of things.
So it could be,
it could be trying to use the same phone
number or St Mil address Ip addresses,
um,
device ids,
all these things that we can use to,
to judge what's happening within the
context.
So we do have a lot of occurrences of
suspending or temporarily suspending
accounts because of activities across
accounts.
Um,
and,
and that,
that happens a ton.
But what I mean,
what I mean in,
in that we're helping this right now is
like some of the incentives,
like just just imagine seeing that
unfold and when you see someone with one
take,
it kind of emboldened something to
follow along and then this mob kind of
rules.
So there has to be a way for us to
incentivize a,
a lot more,
more considered and more nuanced
introspection of what's going on.
Yeah.
Give everybody mushrooms.
Probably the only way to know how are
you going to get people to be more
considerate.
I mean,
what your engineering social behavior,
right?
Yup.
Provided more context,
context,
context.
Like as an example,
let's say brexit for example.
Okay.
So,
um,
if I followed a bunch of accounts that
like,
like Boris Johnson,
who was constantly giving me information
about reasons to leave,
I would probably only see that
perspective.
Nigel Farrage.
Yeah.
And those.
And those,
a lot of folks just will not follow
accounts that have a completely
different perspective or a different
influence.
A number of people do.
Hopefully journalists do,
but most people won't do that work.
So this is the only tool we give people
follow an account if,
however,
during that time you followed the
Hashtag,
you follow the Hashtag vote leave 95
percent of the conversation and the
tweets you see are all reasons to leave,
but there's a small percentage that
shows a different perspective and that
shows a different,
um,
a different reasoning.
We don't make it easy for anyone to do
that and that is for anyone to follow
the bit of perspective,
follow the Hashtag follow topic,
follow,
follow an interest.
And because of that we help build an
echo chamber and something that doesn't
really challenge any perspective and not
to say that we should force that upon
people,
but we don't even make it easy for
people to do.
In the first place though,
the way you do that today,
as you go to the explore tab,
you look,
you search for a Hashtag or you tap into
a Hashtag and you can see all the
conversation.
But that's,
that's work.
And most people just won't do the work.
They'll stay in their timeline,
they'll see what they need to see.
And I can certainly imagine,
you know why if I'm just following a
bunch of people who have the exact same
take on this,
it just continues to embolden in Bolton
bolden and they see nothing of a
different perspective on the exact same,
the exact same situation.
What's interesting to me is the
difference between twitter and
instagram.
Essentially.
It's not just the photographs.
What's weird that has happened was
there's shitty people on instagram as
well.
I mean there's.
There's a lot of arguments and things
along those lines,
but they don't overwhelm the,
the initial post.
Whereas with twitter on a different
surface.
Yeah,
it's.
Instagram is a is a post.
I mean it's a post.
It's not really eliciting conversation
and soliciting comments.
It's difficult to follow the
conversations.
I don't think there was a conversation.
It sometimes there is some,
some.
Sometimes people are going back and
forth about a particular subject that's
discussed in the initial post,
but it's not.
It's not very clear.
Whereas with with twitter,
it only conference,
it's only conversation,
but even if there's a photograph,
even if somebody posted a photograph on
twitter and has conversation under it,
the photograph seems to be like of
secondary importance.
Super Fluid and super messy too.
But yeah,
the thing is every on instagram or any
any blog,
you have this,
this post the statement and you have
comments underneath.
Whereas with twitter,
everything is on the same surface.
It's all one surface.
Yeah.
My friend Kurt Metzger likes that about
facebook.
He says,
because in twitter egos I post something
and then all these fucking morons post
something and he goes,
you know Kurt,
he's very animated.
He's like in their shit looks like just
like my shit.
It's all together.
I'll pile up.
He goes,
but if I post something on facebook,
he goes,
I have this whole thing like this is the
statement.
And then underneath it,
yeah,
you fucking say whatever you want,
but no one's no one's reading that.
They're reading the original initial
post and it's clear that there's a
differentiation between the initial post
and the secondary post.
Yeah,
I,
you know,
there's room for both models,
but I,
this conversation,
most conversations,
it's not you making a statement and me
just reacting to that,
like the,
our conversation evolves based on what
we say.
We can interrupt one another,
we can,
you know,
we can completely change the subject.
I can take control of the conversation
and the people who might find that
interesting follow it and the folks that
don't just stop listening,
whereas you can't do that in a post
comment model.
Yeah.
It's also text is so limited there.
It's,
I mean,
it's great for just getting out actual
facts,
but it's so thinking.
It's just so close to thinking like if
there's no composition,
right.
You know,
and,
and that's uh,
that to me is the most beautiful thing
about twitter,
but also something that can be
uncomfortable.
Like I,
I can compose my life on Instagram,
I can compose my thoughts within a
facebook post and it can look so
perfect.
But the best of twitter is just super
raw and it's right,
it's right to the thinking process.
And I just think that's so beautiful
because it gets to,
it gets to consciousness,
it gets to something deeper.
And I think that deeper.
How so?
How is it different than a post on
instagram or post on facebook?
The speed demands,
you know,
the character constraint,
the speed of just demand to a more
conscious present focused thinking
versus stepping back and composing a
letter.
Yeah.
And composing a letter and thinking
about all the outcomes.
But oftentimes people do compose it as a
letter and they break it up into
separate 280 character posts.
Yeah.
The blue was the thought process in
going from 1:40 to 80 because the one
thing that I liked about 1:40 is that
you can't be verbose.
Yeah.
You can't just,
just ramble and,
you know,
like,
it's great for comics because he forces
us to write jokes like with economy of
words.
Exactly.
We,
uh,
we found a lot of resonance with what
journalists because the headlines we've
found a lot of resonance with,
with comics because of the rhythm.
And we found a lot of resonance with hip
hop as well because of the bars.
And just the structure and the
constraint allowed that,
that flow.
Um,
the,
the thinking was we looked at um,
our,
you know,
languages around the world and,
and uh,
there's some languages like German,
140 characters.
You can't really say much,
can't really say much at all because
words are so long.
There are some languages,
like Japanese 140 characters is 140
words.
And what was interesting about Japan was
Japan is one of our largest,
our largest countries were bigger than
facebook.
There were a lot bigger than facebook
and America know what the fuck.
I don't even use facebook,
sorry.
Facebook.
I don't either.
I mean I use it in terms of if I post
something on instagram it goes to
facebook,
but when I go to facebook it's,
it just seems like a lot.
But this seems like twitter to a lot of
arguing.
But what twitter seems to be more fun,
if that makes any sense.
Even though it's,
there's a lot of chaos when something.
One of my favorite things is when
someone post something stupid and then
underneath it is a bunch of Jeff's say
gifs or jifs.
I say Gif.
Does anybody know him?
Gifts?
I say gifts.
That's the jury's out.
A bunch of gifts that are hilarious now.
Like was just mocking someone
relentlessly.
Like that is one of my favorite things
about twitter.
I when someone like Donald trump posts
something ridiculous and then I'll go
and I'll look at the responses like how
do you care if it's a public
conversation and you can see our own
racks,
but like it's all.
The interesting thing about twitter is
there's.
There's not one twitter.
It's like you have politics.
Twitter which can be super toxic.
You have sports,
twitter,
you have NBA,
you have mma,
twitter,
you have a UFC,
you have k-pop,
twitter,
you have a black twitter,
black twitter has jamie's you.
He loves black.
All these different twitters and you and
you have a.
You have a completely different
experience based on what twitter you
follow in order to participate in.
Some of them were are like super
engaging,
super funny.
Some of them are,
um,
you want to walk away from it?
Yeah.
I got to a certain point where I
couldn't read replies anymore.
I just,
it's just not as,
not that it's that toxic.
The vast majority of interactions I have
with people are super positive.
That may mean absolutely like more than
99 percent,
but it's,
um,
I didn't,
I don't have time and I don't have time
to be constantly responding to people
and it just didn't.
The sheer numbers.
I think when I got around 3 million ish
followers,
I'm like,
I can't do this anymore.
It's just,
it's just,
it's overwhelming.
Like I don't have the resources.
I'm a huge believer in serendipity.
So you,
you,
you look at your replies once and you
might see something that just strikes
you and that's enough.
You don't need to read through all of
them.
Yeah.
And sometimes you might miss something
groovy.
You might.
But I also believe that the most
important thing is to come back up.
What I used to do a lot without go
through my mentions and when people
would essentially use it as almost a
news aggregator.
I go through my mentions that people
would post cool stories and then I would
retweet those and so because people knew
that I would retweet them,
they would send me a lot of cool stuff.
So because of that,
because of reciprocating a got a lot of
really cool stuff sent my way,
you're pushing,
you're pushing more out and expand the
network and I reinforced it.
I just wanted to thank people for
posting cool stuff and they love the
fact they would get a retweet and so
they would send me like interesting
science stories are very bizarre nature
stories and I just retweet them all the
time.
Go to.
But then after awhile I'm like mmm,
this is a lot of time.
So a lot of times.
So now essentially what I do is I just
post something and I just kinda like,
I just walk away.
But that,
I mean that speaks of what we want to
incentivize more.
We want more people contributing things
that back to the network.
Back to the back to the public
conversation,
and I,
I know it doesn't feel like this today
for most people,
but my ideal is someone walks away from
twitter learning something and they're
actually learning something entirely
new.
That might be a new perspective.
That happens a lot.
It probably happens more often than we
follow.
Exactly it.
It's all dependent on the,
on the twitter.
You follow her and like the,
you know,
the health.
Twitter is amazing.
Uh,
you know,
I learned some,
I like,
I followed a Rhonda Patrick and I'm sure
in the sauna and I'm Wim Hoff and ice
pass and uh,
uh,
Ben Greenfield and you just follow them
and you just get all this new
information about alternative views of
how to stay healthy,
how to live longer.
And I can't find that anywhere else in
one place like that.
It's not just them broadcasting when
they retweet something or when they
tweet something,
there's a whole conversation about it.
So,
you know,
some people will say,
this is,
this has not been my experience or this
is not,
this is not true for me.
Or actually have you seen this connected
thing and I,
I just go down this rabbit hole and I,
I learned so much,
but that's not the experience for
everyone.
No.
Well yeah.
It's not the experience for everyone and
it's not really.
I don't think it's what everyone wants
either.
Sometimes people just like to go on
there and
talk shit.
I mean if someone that's trapped in a
cubicle right now and they just want to
go on there and get in arguments about
gun control or you know,
whether or not Nancy Polosi is the devil
and this is,
this is what it,
it serves a purpose for them.
The thing that gets strange though is
who's to decide.
You know,
there's this,
there's this concept,
there's a discussion I should say where,
uh,
some people believe that things like
twitter or facebook or any forum where
you're having a public discussion should
be considered almost like a public
utility.
Like anyone has access to the electric
power.
Even if you're,
you know,
even if you're a racist,
you still can get electricity and some
people think that you should have that
same ability with something like twitter
or the same ability with something like
instagram.
Obviously this is,
we're in uncharted territory and you
are,
you are in uncharted territory.
Totally.
It just,
no one has been there before.
So who makes the distinctions when you
see someone that,
that it's saying something that you
might think is offensive to some folks
but not offensive to the person who's
saying it.
Maybe the person who's saying it feels
like they need to express themselves and
this is important to say and how do you
decide whether or not this is a valid
discussion or if this is air quotes,
hate speech,
which is,
you know,
there's some things that are hate speech
and there's sometimes people use the
term hate speech and it's just a cheap
way to shut down a conversation.
Yeah,
we.
So the simple answer is we look at
conduct.
We don't,
we don't look at the speech itself.
We look at conduct.
We look at how the tool is being used.
And you're,
you're right in that like I think when
people see twitter,
they see and they expect it to be a
public square.
They can go into that public square,
they can say whatever they want,
they can get on a pedestal and people
might gather around them and listen to
what they have to say.
Some of them might find it offensive and
they leave.
The difference is there's,
there's also this concept of this
megaphone and the megaphone can be
highly targeted now with twitter as
well.
So it's not,
it's not the,
it's not the speech,
it's how it's amplified.
So what do you do is say,
let's say there's someone in the media,
uh,
let's say it's a prominent feminist and
then you have a bunch of people or let's
say just one person and their twitter
feed is overwhelmingly attacking this
prominent feminist.
Just constantly attacking her,
calling her a liar,
calling her this calling that when do
you decide this is harassment?
When decide this is hate speech when
like how do you,
I mean this is a look at the conduct is
a fictional account.
Write fictional person we're talking
about.
But in this,
for instance,
what,
what would dictate something that was
egregious enough for you to eliminate
them from your plan?
Well,
that's a.
that's a heavy action.
So that's a last.
But we look at the conduct.
We look at oftentimes as you said,
like the probability of someone who is
harassing one person,
it's highly probable that they're also
passing 10 more people,
right?
So we can look at that behavior.
We can look at how many times this
person is being blocked or muted or
reported,
and based on all those,
all that data,
we can actually take some action,
but we also have to.
We have to correlate it with the other
side of that because people go on and
they coordinate blocks as well and they
coordinate harassment and they and they
coordinate.
I'm sorry,
not harassment,
but reporting.
I'm reporting a particular account to
get it shut down into a to take the
voice off the service.
So these are the considerations we have
to make,
but it's.
It's.
It all starts with conduct and all.
Oftentimes we'll see coordinated
conduct,
whether it be that one person opening
multiple counts or coordinating with
multiple accounts that they don't own
to,
you know,
go after someone and there's a bunch of
vectors that people use,
retweet for that,
uh,
the quote tweet for that a lot as well.
Like,
you know,
they'll quote tweet a tweet that someone
finds and they'll say,
look at this idiot twitter to your thing
and then just this mob starts and goes
and tries to,
uh,
effectively shut that person down.
Um,
so there's a bunch of tools we can use.
The permanent suspension is the last
resort.
One of the things that we can do is we
can down rank the replies.
So any of these,
any of these behaviors and conduct that
looks link linked,
we can actually,
uh,
push farther down in the supply chain.
So it's all still there.
But you might have to push a button to
actually see it.
You might have to say,
show more replies to actually see this
harassing account or what might look
like harassing language.
And there's this manually done or no,
this is,
this is all,
this is all automated.
It's automated.
Yeah.
But how would you the ranking in the
end,
looking at amplification and looking at
the network is automated,
right?
Like in terms of ranking,
is there a discussion as to whether or
not this person's reply should be down
ranked?
Like how do you,
how do you figure that out?
It's a machine learning and deep
learning model and they say I and they
and they learn,
you know,
and we,
we look at,
we look at how these things are doing
and where they make mistakes and then we
improve it.
It's just constantly improving,
constantly learning.
And does that feel like censorship to
you?
Like automated censorship doesn't mean
who,
who is to decide other than people
whether or not something is valid?
Well,
we're not,
we're not looking at the,
at the speech.
In this particular case,
we're looking at the conduct,
the conduct,
the conduct of someone in fast velocity
attacking someone else.
Right?
So those are the things that our
technology allows changes,
the velocity of changes,
uh,
how to broadcast a message that someone
didn't really ask for and didn't want to
hear.
We don't touch.
If I follow Joe Rogan,
you'll see every single tweet.
We don't touch it,
right?
But that's an audience that you earn.
But in your replies page we have a
little bit more room because this is a,
this is a conversation that starts up
and some people just want to disrupt it.
And all we're saying is we're going to
look at moving the disruption down.
Not that it's hidden,
but it's still there.
But you know,
you just see a little bit farther down.
Like there was a,
what was the incidence with Ari?
I should text him right now,
get them to answer me in real time,
but are you should fear got kicked off
twitter because he said something to
bird like bird,
I'm going to fucking kill you.
Bert Kreischer being our good friend,
all of us are good friends and he's
like,
you fucking dummy.
I'm going to kill you.
Or something like that as a record
albums.
He said he was gonna steal and I'm
breaking and got jokingly got mad.
Right,
right,
right.
That's already though Bert.
Bert was.
I think it was all bullshit.
Right?
I don't think Bert really stole his.
Him.
Yeah.
He gave them back to them eventually.
He's like,
I'm going to fucking kill you.
So what happened there?
What probably happened there,
and I'm not sure of the particular case,
but will probably happen there,
is someone might have reported that
tweet one of our agents,
a human agents without context of their
friendship or that relationship,
uh,
saw it as a violent threat and took
action on it.
Right?
And those are the mistakes that we're
going to make.
That's why we need an appeals process.
And Burt needs to keep his fucking
greasy hands off.
Are his records.
Right?
That's probably not going to happen.
We need to,
we need to make sure we need to make
sure that we're reacting to the right
way.
Like,
look,
we're going to make mistakes where we're
trying to.
That.
The problem with the system right now is
most of the most of the work is actually
in the burden is actually on the victims
of abuse while they're getting harassed,
so a lot of our system doesn't
enforce or act and less,
uh,
these tweets are reported,
right?
So we don't take suspension actions or
removal of content actions in less that
reported the algorithms rank and order
the conversation,
but they don't take suspension actions,
they don't take,
they don't remove content.
They might suggest to human to look at
this who might look at our rules and
look at the content and,
and try to look at the context of the
conversation and then take action.
But we would like to move towards a lot
more automated enforcement.
But more importantly,
how do we,
how do we highlight,
how do we amplify more of the healthier
discussion conversation?
Again,
not removing it,
I,
we're,
we're going to a world,
especially with technology like
blockchain,
that all content that exists,
that has ever created will exist
forever.
You won't be able to take it down.
You won't be able to censor it.
It won't be centralized at all.
Our role is around what we recommend
based on your interest and based on who
you follow and and,
and helping you to get into that onramp.
But if you look at the architect
neurology,
it's a given that anytime something is
created,
it's going to exist forever.
This is what blockchain helps enable
down the line and we need to make sure
that we're paying attention to that and
also realizing that,
you know,
our role is like how do we,
how do we get people the stuff that they
really want to see in the find valuable
that they'll learn from,
that they'll make them think that will
help them evolve the conversation as
well.
Now when you say amplify the messages
that you deem to be more positive,
right?
Like how do you decide that people
decided?
People decide.
People decide it based on like are they,
are they engaging in replies?
Are they,
are they read tweeting it?
Are they liking it?
Are they.
Sometimes it's really negative,
like sometimes the people that are
engaging and they're engaging in because
they're attacking someone.
So d,
is that valuable or is it just
unfortunate?
It's valuable.
I mean every,
every signal is something that we can
learn from and we can act on,
but it,
it's going to constantly evolve.
I mean it's,
these,
these models that we have to build will
constantly have to learn what the
network is doing and how people are
using it.
And um,
you know,
our,
our goal is healthy contribution back to
the public conversation,
that that is what we want.
We want to encourage people into more,
bigger informative,
global conversations that they'll learn
from.
Are you like constantly aware of how
much this is changing society and that
you are one of the four or five
different modalities that are radically
changing society,
whether it's facebook or instagram or
any of these social media companies.
It's radically changing the way people
communicate with each other.
Like there's a,
there's a,
a giant impact on the way human beings
talk and see each other and the way we
process ideas and the way we distributed
information.
It's unprecedented.
There's never been anything like that
before.
And you setting up something that you
think is going to be a group chat.
Do you remember the early days when you
would say like at Jack is going to the
movies and you would say like that's how
we'd say it.
I would say at Joe Rogan is on his way
to dinner.
That's how people would do.
It's fucking.
It was weird that somewhere along the
line that morphed
and that's what the world wanted to do
with it.
That's where,
that's where they wanted to take that.
Yeah,
and I just think it's so reflective of,
of what the world is and in some cases
what the world wants to
be,
so it's a a pathway for thinking.
Just a pathway for people to get their
thoughts out,
but a really powerful one and
unprecedented method of distributing
information.
It's really nothing ever been like this
before.
No,
no,
and in it,
it won't.
This,
this mode of communicating will not go
away.
It'll just get faster.
It will,
it will become a lot more connected and
that's why our work is so critical to
figure out some of the dynamics at play
that,
um,
that make it a,
that,
that caused more negative outcomes and
positive outcomes.
I,
I think about it because,
uh,
well I think about it because it's,
it's just a hugely significant thing,
but I also think about it because of
podcasts because podcasts are in a
similar way,
just no one saw it coming and the people
that are involved in that are like,
what the fuck are we doing now?
Like me,
I'm like,
what am I doing?
Like,
what is this?
No,
like for me,
it's like,
oh boy,
I get to talk to guys like Ben
Greenfield and,
and Jonathan Haidt and all the,
all these different people and learn
some stuff.
And I've have clearly learned way more
from doing this podcast than I ever
would have learned without it.
No doubt about it unquestionably.
But I didn't,
I didn't fucking plan as.
So now all of a sudden there is this a
signal that I'm sending out to millions
and millions of people and then people
are like,
well,
you have a responsibility.
I'm like,
oh great.
Why didn't want that?
I didn't want to responsibility to what,
what I distribute.
I just wanted to be able to have a freak
show.
Just talk to people like what?
Whatever.
You know,
like there's certain people that will
have on whether it's Alex Jones or
anyone that's controversial where people
will get fucking mad.
Why are you giving this person a
platform?
I go,
okay,
I didn't think about it that way and I
don't think that's what I'm doing.
I think I'm talking to people and you
can listen.
Yeah.
But it's giving that person a platform
because they say,
well no,
they'll tone down there like Milo
Yiannopoulos.
That was one of the arguments people
gave me,
like he toned down his platform when he
was on your show so you could get more
people to pay attention to them.
Like,
okay.
But he also talked about he,
he.
That was one of the reasons why he was
exposed was my show because he talked
about that it's okay to have sex with
underage boys if they're gay because
there like a mentor relationship between
the older gay man,
the young and people were like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
And that was a big part of why he's kind
of been removed from the public
conversation.
That was one of the thing.
And then there's the discussion like,
well what is that?
What is removing someone from the public
conversation if someone is very popular
and they have all these people that like
to listen to them.
Like what is the responsibility of these
platforms,
whether it's youtube or twitter or,
or anyone know what is their
responsibility to decide whether or not
someone should or shouldn't be able to
speak.
And this is a thing that I've been
struggling with and I've been.
I bounced around inside my own head and
I see that you guys struggle with it and
pretty much everyone does.
Youtube does.
And it's,
um,
it,
it is a hugely significant discussion
that is left to a very relatively small
amount of people.
And this is why this discussion of what
is social media,
is it something that everybody has a
right to or is it something that should
be restricted to only people that are
willing to behave and carry themselves
in a certain way?
I believe it's something that everyone
has a right to everyone has a right to,
but you still banned people,
like say like,
like Alex Jones,
you guys were the last guys to keep Alex
Jones on the platform.
You were the last ones and I believe you
hung in there until he started harassing
you personally,
right?
No,
no,
he,
he did come your house.
He begged.
He uh,
you know,
he,
he did very different things on our
platform versus the others.
So we saw this domino effect over a
weekend of one platform,
a Banningham and then another,
another,
another very,
very quick succession.
And you know,
people I think would have assumed that
we would just have followed suit,
but he didn't violate our terms of
service.
And afterwards he did.
And,
and we have,
you know,
we have a,
we have a policy and if,
if,
uh,
you know,
the,
there was a violation,
we take enforcement actions.
One might be asking the account holder
to delete the tweet,
another might be a temporary suspension,
another might be a permanent suspension.
So were you saying the solar,
let's use it in terms of like him saying
that Sandy Hook was fake.
He did not say that on the platform.
He did not say that on twitter.
He always said that on his show.
I don't know.
I don't know all the mediums he set it
in.
What did he do?
What we're looking at is the,
is the conduct and what he did on our,
our platform.
So what did he do on your platform that
was like,
that you all were in agreement that this
is enough?
Uh,
I'm not,
I'm not sure what the,
what the actual like,
you know,
violations were.
But we have a,
we have a set number of actions and if
they keep getting,
if,
if an account keeps violent in terms of
service,
ultimately it leads to permanent
suspension.
And when all the other platforms we're
taking them off,
we didn't find those.
We didn't.
We didn't find those violations and they
weren't reported.
But again,
it goes back to a lot of our model,
people weren't reporting a lot of the
tweets that may have been in violation
on our service and we didn't act on
them.
Right.
I'm like a good instances.
What's going on with Patrion?
I'm sure you're aware of the Sargon of
cod thing.
He did a podcast a long time ago,
I believe,
six months or so ago where he used the n
word and the way he used it as a
actually against white nationalists and
he also said a bunch of other stuff and
they decided Patriot undecided that what
he said on a podcast was enough for them
to remove him from the platform even
though he didn't do anything on their
platform.
That was agregious.
And also they had previously stated that
they were only judging things that
occurred on their platform.
There's been a giant blow back because
of that,
because people are saying,
well now you're.
You're essentially policing and not
based on his actions.
Just on concepts and the communication
that he was using,
the way he was talking a year,
you are eliminating him from being able
to make a living and that you are doing
this because he does not fit into your
political paradigm the way you want to
view the world.
He views the world differently.
This is an opportunity for you to
eliminate someone who you disagree with.
Yeah,
I mean I don't know the nuances of their
policy,
but like we have to pay attention to
folks who are using twitter to shut down
the voices of others.
Right.
That's where it gets weaponized and we
also have to pay attention to where
people are using it that put other folks
in physical danger and that is where we
need to be most severe,
but otherwise everyone has a right to
these technologies and I think they also
have a right to make sure that they have
a very simple and open read of the rules
and we're not in a great state.
There are rules and our enforcement can
be extremely confusing to people.
What has been the one thing that came up
that was perhaps the most controversial,
like I know my friend Sam Harris was
trying to get you guys to ban Donald
Trump.
He was saying if the fall,
your terms of service.
I just did a podcast with him.
Actually,
you should come out today or tomorrow.
He's.
He's a fascinating guy.
Sam Harris.
I love him to death,
but what he was trying to do is like
saying,
hey,
he's threatening nuclear war.
Like he's saying,
Hey Korea,
my bombs are bigger than your bombs.
Like what else does the guy have to do
to get you to remove them from the
platform?
When you guys saw that,
what was your reaction to that?
Was there an internal discussion about
actually banning the president of United
States?
Well,
so the two things there.
One,
it was the context that presidents of
this country have you similar language
in different mediums.
They use it on radio,
they use it on television.
It's not just through twitter and even
if you were looking at you were to look
at the presidency of Obama.
It wasn't exactly the same tone in this
exact same language,
but there were threats around the same
country and we to take that context into
consideration.
So the second thing is that we need the
most controversial aspect of our rules
and our terms of services.
Probably the claws around public
interest in newsworthiness where I'm
powerful figures are public figures,
might be in violation of our terms of
service,
but the tweet itself is of public
interest.
Yes,
there should be a conversation around it
and that is probably the thing that
people disagree with the most.
Um,
and where we have a lot of internal
debate,
but we also have some pretty hard lines.
If we had a global leader,
including the president of United
States,
make a violent threat against a private
individual,
we would take action.
We,
we always have to balance that with
like,
is this a,
is this something that the public has
interest in?
In I,
I believe generally the answer is yes.
It's not going to be in every case,
but generally the answer is yes.
Because we should see how our leaders
think and how they act in essentially
forms voting that informs the
conversation.
Then forms whether we think they're
going to,
they're doing the right job or we think
that,
you know,
they should be,
they should be voted out well.
It's very important to see how someone
uses that platform and when someone uses
it the way he uses it and then becomes
president and continues to use it that
way.
That's when people are like,
what?
He's been consistent and I think he,
I think he joined
then in 2009,
2012 and you look at all of his tweets
all the way back then.
And it's pretty consistent.
Yeah.
Being he likes to insult people on
twitter.
It's fun for him.
He does.
It's just.
I never thought he would keep doing it.
I thought once he became president maybe
just lock it down and try to do a good
job for the country and then,
you know,
after four years or eight years,
just go back to his old self,
fuck you fuck the world.
Fuck this.
But no,
he's,
he's just,
it's just in one way it's hilarious.
See as a comedian,
I think it's awesome because it's just,
it's so hilariously stupid.
It's so preposterous.
That even has the time to talk about
Jeff Bezos is a fair and the fact that
he got caught with the national
enquirer,
getting text messages and calls him Jeff
Bozos like,
don't you have shit to do man?
As.
But as a comedian,
I,
I am a gigantic fan of folly.
Almost a against my better judgment.
I like watching.
It's,
I,
I've watched.
I like watching disasters.
I like watching chaos.
When I see nonsense like that,
I'm like,
oh Jesus,
I'm drawn like a motto flame.
But on the other part of me is like,
man,
this sets a very bizarre tone for the
entire country because one of the things
about like Obama or hate Obama as he was
very measured,
very articulate,
obviously very well educated,
and I think that that aspect of his
presidency was very good for all of us
because he represented something that
was of a very high standard in terms of
his ability to communicate his access to
words,
the way the way measured his words and
held himself.
I think that that's good for us.
Let's just parishioner.
Well it's.
Yeah.
It's like,
look at that guy.
He's better than me.
That's why he's the president.
But you know,
you lady see trump,
he doesn't talk better than me.
He does.
He doesn't use twitter better.
He's not.
He's just this fucking madman.
But isn't an important to understand
that and to see it.
Hopefully that informs opinions and
actions 100 percent.
That's my point.
That's my point is that this is this
weird gray area where I think overall I
definitely support your decision to not,
not banned him for violating your terms
of service.
We need to know,
yeah,
you know,
and it's
how do you know,
how many accounts are bots,
how many [inaudible] do you know,
how many accounts are from a Russian
troll farm,
how do you know that?
So this is a real challenge and
something that we're,
uh,
we're trying to wrap our heads around,
but one of the things we're trying to do
is like let's scope the problem down a
bit and let,
let's use the technology we have
available to us.
Like face Id,
touch id,
like the biometric stuff to identify the
humans.
Let's identify the humans first APP
because it face id is not really
available.
Is it available to you guys?
Did you know you just leave leaks?
We shouldn't have done that.
No,
we haven't.
We haven't used it yet.
But you can use it for things like,
is this like a human operating this say
you can use it for that.
So it's,
it's completely locked into the local
device.
We don't have access to images of your
face or whatnot,
but the operating system can tell us
that this is the legit owner of this
phone and therefore it is,
it is human and technology always has to
change.
People will find ways around that and
whatnot.
But if we go the opposite direction and
we look for the bots,
the problem with looking for the bots
boxes,
people assume that they just come
through our api,
but the scripting has become extremely
sophisticated.
People can script the APP,
can script the website and make it look
very,
very human.
So we're going after this problem first
trying to identify the humans as much as
we can.
Utilizing these technologies,
you know,
of this is live right now.
These are,
these are considerations that we're
making and trying to understand like
what the impact would be and,
and,
uh,
how we might evolve it,
but we need to because that information
would provide context for someone like
this is an actual human that I'm talking
to and I can invest more time in it
where I can just ignore the thing
because it's meaningless.
Now is apple to share that with you,
I mean when you,
when you're talking about biometrics,
fingerprints or face,
it's not the data,
it's just the operating system verifies
that there's an individual as an
individual and it's unlocking know,
like,
um,
you know,
when,
when you use the,
um,
our cash app uses us,
right?
So squares,
cash APP.
When you want to make a transfer to
someone when you want to send someone
money or when you want to buy Bitcoin,
we turn on face id and you verify that
you are,
you and you are the owner of the phone
and then it goes.
We don't get images of your face.
We don't see who you are.
Oh,
that's what you want me to think.
I know
that's how locked down by the operating
system and that's what it should be,
right?
Sure.
Um,
what,
has there ever been any consideration to
not allowing people to post anonymously?
Well,
like what you said earlier about
journalists and whistleblowers that is
political.
So look at a look at platforms that have
a real names policy.
Look at facebook or other problems.
Any different.
I don't know because I don't go there,
but for I understand there's a lot of
still a lot of arguing there.
It's the same at a political argument if
the same vectors,
same patterns.
I think older,
like older in general it seems.
I also am not really hanging out there,
but it seems a little bit older.
It's a lot of grammys looking at
pictures of their kids,
grandkids and stuff and that's what it
was made for about.
It's connecting,
it's connecting with the people that you
know and that to me is the biggest
difference for twitter.
It's connecting with the people you
don't know what they find interesting
and like it's around.
It's around topics and stuff that you
find that you want to learn more about
when you saw it.
Zuckerberg testifying and in,
in realizing like how this platform is
being used and what are the dangers of
this,
and then you see these senators that
really don't know what the fuck the
technology is or it's wow,
it really highlights how we're set up to
this.
Really.
Yeah.
Well,
not just a gap,
a gap in the critical understanding of
how these things work and what they are
in terms of how these really important
politicians who are the ones who are
making these decisions as to whether or
not someone has violated laws or whether
or not something should be curbed or
regulated.
They don't really even understand what
they're talking about.
No,
I mean there's,
there's a few people do because they're
not,
they're not using it directly.
They're not using in the way that people
are using it every single day and I'll
have the same experience that people
have every single day and you know,
in terms of regulatory and our
regulators and our government's.
I,
you know,
we,
I think the conversation is often about
how regulators will come in and start
writing rules and,
and setting expectations for how
companies or services might behave,
but there's a role for the company to
educate and there's a role for the
company to,
on like what technology makes possible,
whether it be positive and also some of
the negatives.
So that become possible as well.
So I think we have a role to help
educate and to,
and to help make sure that we're really,
we're,
we're pushing towards what I think the
job of regular regulator is,
which is number one,
protect the individual number to level
the playing field and make sure that
those two things are not compromised by
special interests trying to protect
their own domain or profits or,
or a dominance within a particular
market.
What do you mean by level?
The playing field level,
the playing field so that a,
an individual has the same opportunity,
uh,
that uh,
someone else might have or a company
might have.
So.
Okay.
So like anybody,
anyone,
anyone can have a twitter account and
you know,
they have,
uh,
at least,
you know,
an equal opportunity to contribute to it
and whatever they do with it will change
the change the outcome.
Some people might become very popular
because they're saying stuff people want
to hear.
Some people won't see any following
whatsoever because they're not adding
anything original or interesting or,
or,
uh,
we're different in terms of perspective.
Where do you see this going?
When you look at these kind of emerging
technologies,
not necessarily emerging anymore,
established now,
but still,
you know,
a,
a new thing in relative terms of human
history,
where do you see this going and does it
get more intrusive?
Does it get deeper into our lives?
Like what,
what?
And when you look at new technologies
like augmented reality and things along
those lines,
do you see new possibilities and new
things to make things even more
complicated?
I mean,
yeah,
I mean we just have to assume the,
we,
we naturally use more and more
technologies.
More and more things become open.
More and more things,
uh,
increase their velocity.
There's more communication,
not less like this is not going away and
it's just,
it's just a question of what we do with
it.
So where,
where I want it to go as an where I want
twitter specifically to go is I,
you know,
I,
I think it's existential right now that
we,
we have global conversations about some
things that will become crisis climate
change being one of them.
There was no one nation state that's
going to solve that problem alone.
Economic disparity being another,
the the rise of Ai and a job
displacement and just like us offloading
decisions to these,
to these algorithms,
those are the things that,
that no one nation,
no one community is going to solve
alone.
It takes the entire world to do so,
so I want to make sure that we're doing
our best to get people seeing these
global conversations and ideally
participating in them because it helps.
It helps us solve the problems.
I just believe that more open society
allows us to solve problems much faster.
So you in many ways see twitter is
having some sort of a social
responsibility in this.
Totally.
Yeah.
And I think a big part of is like right
now,
like how are we,
how are we ensuring that there is more
healthy contribution to that global
conversation and you know,
I,
I just think it's so critical that we
start talking about the things that are
facing all of us,
not just one nation.
I do think you know that that's where
our current model really puts the world
at a disadvantage because it
incentivizes more of the elk echo
chambers,
which lead to things like nationalism.
Instead of taking the broader picture
and looking at what's happening around
the world to all people,
to all of humanity,
what do you do though to balance the
conversation or what responsibility do
you think you have to balance the
conversation in terms of the way
conservatives view it versus the way
liberals and progressives view it?
Balance.
It shows there,
is there a responsibility?
Do you have a responsibility or is it
just leave it up to the people and let
them figure it out the same way they
figured out hashtags and everything
else.
I think we have a responsibility to make
it easier to do that easier.
How so?
Right now it's just.
It's just too hard.
Most most people will not venture
outside their mindset.
They will.
They will not venture out.
They will not break their bubble,
but if you.
Because it's right now on the surface,
it's just so hard to do that.
I,
I can only follow accounts and I have
to,
I have to look into and just imagine
like,
you know,
trying to get an understanding of your
own politics.
People can't just look at your bio,
they have to look through all your
tweets,
they have to listen to a bunch of your
podcasts and whatnot.
And that's a bunch of work.
If we shifted more towards topics and
interest,
at least we have the potential to see a
bunch more perspectives.
We see.
Do that.
The simplest thing as like follow a
Hashtag,
follow a topic,
like why can't you just follow warriors
twitter or uh,
you know,
NBA,
twitter,
why do you have to go and find all the
coaches and the players and,
and the team.
So we can do that.
We can help make that a whole lot easier
for folks.
So there's something like brexit or
something like that.
So if you go to Hashtag Brexit,
you're going to get the whole
conversation.
You're going to get the pros,
the cons,
the left,
the right,
the whole deal,
the centrists.
You're going to get everybody versus
following the people that you already
follow that agree with what you think
the probability is higher that you'll
get more,
you'll get more variety of perspectives
and not even doesn't even follow Brexit,
follow vote leave if you want to leave,
but within that topic there might be
some dissenting opinions and you get to
choose whether you those inform you,
whether that emboldens your or not,
but and,
and again,
I'm not saying that we should force that
upon it,
but it's not easy to even do that today,
right?
The only tool we give you is finding and
following the accounts and that's what
people search hashtags.
They do search,
right?
They don't.
They send the timeline.
I mean it is a small percentage of
people that people that really know
twitter know how to do that,
but most people,
they follow an account and they stand
the timeline and what their world is,
their timeline.
Hashtags can be corrupted to totally.
They can be gamed.
It can be gamed and taken over.
I took over Hashtag Vegan cat go to and
what is,
what is it?
It's a wrap.
That's mine.
Now.
My last,
my last Netflix special about a woman
who said a bunch of horrible things to
me,
uh,
because I put a picture up on instagram
of some deer meat and I wrote this is
some meat from a deer that liked to kick
babies and was about to join isis.
And I wrote Hashtag Vegan,
which was a mistake right to the right.
Hashtag Vegan,
but the Hashtag Vegan people went
fucking crazy and came after me because
I entered into their timeline with meat
hashtag vegan cat.
It's all either pictures of see like it
says Joe Rogan right up.
Thank you.
I haven't laughed that hard to while
Hashtag Vegan cat.
It's people that are feeding their
fucking cat vegan food and they're all
dying.
And I in the specialist say every cat
looks like it's living in a house with a
gas leak.
Like they're all like laying down like
where the fuck is the real food?
But this is real.
Like this is just a conversation to
have.
But the thing is,
if someone does something like that,
like you can like pick a person,
you know,
whatever that person is,
whatever they're,
they're,
they're doing,
if they have a Hashtag that they utilize
all the time for their movement or
whatever,
someone could mock them and then use
that.
And if it's a public figure or someone
who's got a prominent voice,
then all of a sudden that Hashtag
becomes people just take it over and
start mocking them with that Hashtag.
But it has to be done in mass.
I mean,
it has to be coordinated.
And sometimes people like figure out how
to gain the system and coordinate it in
a,
amplify that message in an unfair way.
And,
and that's what,
that's what our systems are trying to
recognize.
How sick did that cat look?
Fucking cat.
That was a real one.
That was a real Hashtag Vegan cat.
Wow.
Support Bastards.
Um,
so when you look back at emerging social
media,
like we go all the way back to my space,
my space,
you got Tom,
Tom was sitting there and you're in your
top eight and you know,
people would like post music that they
liked and it was never political.
It was very often very surface.
And for comics it was a great way to
promote shows and it was,
it was an interesting way to see things.
But it was,
it was like,
like the seed that became twitter or
facebook or any of these is one of them.
I think we,
at least for us,
like we got more of our roots from
aol instant messenger and Icq Icq
because it was,
you know,
you remember the status message where
you said like,
I'm in a meeting or I'm listening to
music or watching a movie right now.
That was the inspiration.
And what we took from that was being
able to,
like,
if you could do that from anywhere,
not bound to a desk,
but you could do that from anywhere.
And you could do it from your phone and
you could just be roaming around and
say,
you know,
I'm at,
I'm at Joe Rogan's,
um,
studio right now,
that is cool.
I don't need my computer.
I'm not bound to this chain,
to this desk.
I can,
I can do it from anywhere.
And then the other aspect of,
of,
in some messenger was of course chat.
So one of the things that the status
would do is you might,
you might say like,
you know,
I'm listening to Kendrick Lamar right
now and I might hit you up on chat and
say like,
what do you,
what do you think of the new album?
But now it's all public so everyone can
see it.
That's,
that's the biggest difference in the.
And that's,
that to me is what twitter is.
It might,
my space was,
it was profiles and you know,
people organized around these profiles
and uh,
this network that develop between
people.
And that is facebook,
facebook,
facebook optimized the hell out of that.
And they scaled the world.
We,
we were something very different.
you know,
we,
we started with a simple status and then
people wanted to talk about it and we,
we decided that it should be on the same
surface,
it shouldn't be suburbian to the,
to the,
to the status,
it should be part of that flow.
And that's what makes twitter so fluid.
Now when you look at this sort of
metamorphosis,
this evolution between those initial
social media,
whether it's aol instant messenger that
eventually became Lux Icq.
And what was that one that we would use
that gamers would use?
That it was like a all live stream sort
of message board
for awhile people were using teamspeak
but I don't know.
No it wasn't,
that wasn't,
that wasn't teamspeak it was.
I'm like you would go there and share
files and stuff and people would uh,
would,
would go,
like if I used to play a lot of online
video games and we play on teams and we
have teams go play other teams and he
would use this sort of a.
It was like,
it wasn't a message board because it was
all in real time.
What the fuck was it called?
No.
Alright,
forget it.
Anyway,
uh,
guys would go there and you could send
people files through it and teams would
go and meet and it would be a chat,
like an online chat that would be in
real time.
Yeah,
it's,
yeah.
I mean we have a lot of our roots and
aol instant messenger,
but also like IRC Internet relay chat
and use nut which were the,
you know,
these old internet seventies
technologies is what I was talking
about.
IRC.
Yeah.
Okay.
So Internet relay chat is,
is like this giant room that anyone can
join and so range around topics and
that's what's interesting about that is
you could see people typing,
see it occurring in real time,
see it popping up in real time,
you know,
I'm
just wonder like what is the next
evolution of this?
Because because no one saw anything
going from ICQ to twitter,
no one saw anything going from that to
instagram and to where we're at right
now where it really does flavor the
conversation of our entire culture.
I mean,
before it was just a thing that was
happening that was happening on people's
computers.
Now it's a thing that's happening on
people's computers and now phones and
now your whole life.
It's a,
it's,
it's a very different influence and I
wonder because everything does
accelerate things constantly move
forward and become more and more,
more and more integrated into our life
experience.
And I wonder what is the next stage of
this
if I mean like the,
the secular trends and you know,
you look at technology and you look at
technologies like blockchain for
instance,
and I think,
you know,
we're,
we're moving to a world where anything
created exists forever,
um,
that there's no centralized control over
who sees what,
um,
that,
uh,
you know,
these,
these models become completely
decentralized and all these barriers
that we,
that exist today aren't as important
anymore.
Something like Gab,
Gab seems to be a response to the fact
that some people are getting banned from
other platforms and they're just
allowing anybody to come on and say
anything they want.
The downside of that is,
of course the most horrible people are
going to be able to say anything they
want with no repercussions.
The good side is anybody can say
whatever they want.
Yeah.
I haven't studied them too much,
but I do know that they have taken
action on accounts as well.
They have suspended accounts and they,
if they have a terms of service as well,
what are they suspended accounts for it.
I don't know.
It's probably conduct related.
It's probably,
it might be doxing.
I'm probably right,
but it's just a,
it's just a question of like,
you know,
the rules and if you agree to the rules
then you sign up for the service and if,
if not there will be other services.
But like if you look at,
you look at the trends and I think um,
you know,
certainly things become a lot more
public and certainly things become a lot
more open.
Certainly the berries and the boundaries
that we have in place today become less
meaningful and I think there's a lot of
positives in that.
And I,
I also think there's a lot of danger
that we need to be mindful of.
Now you as a ceo,
oh,
as a guy who's running this thing,
what,
what is this?
Is the experience been like for you?
Because I got to imagine that it wasn't
anything that you predicted.
No.
Predicted twitter,
right?
Yeah.
So to all the sudden have this
responsibility,
what are changing everything.
I mean it.
And you're a young guy.
How old are you?
Forty two.
That's young to be in control of that
much and to have it over the time of
what has it been 11 years or 10 years
old?
They're 13 and Marcela.
Yeah.
So you were really fucking young,
like what has that been like for you?
It's been a,
it's been both beautiful and scary and
uncomfortable and learning.
It's just been a ton of learning and
evolving and it shows me every single
day where I need to push myself and what
I don't know.
And uh,
and I think a big part is just the
realization that we're not gonna be able
to do this alone.
And I don't think we have to either the,
these are,
these are what the technologies that
continue to allow us,
we can,
if we have to have all the answers
around enforcement or policy when we're
not going to serve the world,
we have aspirations to serve every
single person on the planet and we have
aspirations to,
you know,
be the first consideration for the
global public conversation.
And you know,
if,
if we're the bottleneck for all this,
we're not going to reach those
aspirations.
So it just thinking deeply about how we
might distribute more of this work and
decentralize more of it and look at look
at the platform itself and like what we
need to change to reach that reality.
And I think we got to look really
deepened.
Foundational that it goes back to,
you know,
the,
your question on 1:40,
one of the things that we saw was,
you know,
we,
we shifted to 280 characters and that,
you know,
there's 140 characters is so sacred.
You know,
it,
it became this cultural thing and I was
in love with it.
And so many people are in love with it,
but one of the things we noticed as we
move to two 80 is that the vast majority
of tweets that are broadcasts don't go
above 1:40 even with that limitation
raced,
but where they do go above a 1:40 is in
replies when people reply,
they tend to go over the hundred 40
character limit and even bump up into
the two to 80 limit and what it allowed,
what we've seen it allow us just more
nuance in the conversation and allows
people to give more context and,
and uh,
and kind of just get their experience on
the table a little bit more,
whereas 1:40 did not allow that.
So we,
we have seen that increase the health of
those conversations and the discussion.
So it's stuff like that that we need to
question and not hold.
So,
so sacred.
Is there any consideration to expanding
it further?
Uh,
now,
right now we were about a million
characters.
I know.
Well,
we don't have edit tweets right now.
So we did.
That's good or bad.
Well,
if you can't edit a 140 characters,
you're going to be really pissed off if
you write a million characters in cad.
Those things,
you know what I would like,
I would like the ability to edit,
like if you make a typo or something
like that,
but also the ability for people to see
the original like edit,
but see the original.
Let's say we're looking at exactly that.
Oh really?
We're looking at exactly that.
The reason we don't have it in the first
place is we were born on sms,
were born on text messaging.
When you send a tax,
you can't take it back.
Right?
So when you send a tweet,
it goes to the world instantaneously.
You can't take it back.
So when we have to exist anyway,
I mean,
no matter what,
if you send someone something,
even if you're on Instagram,
people are gonna know the original.
Yeah,
they screenshot it and they do their
thing,
but like you could build it such that,
you know,
maybe we introduce a five second to 32nd
delay in the sending and within that
window you can edit.
I'm going to need more time than that.
Do it.
If I fucked something up,
I like someone has to tell me,
but did you misspelled that word?
Oh Shit.
Did I?
God Damn it.
The issue.
Autocorrect gets you totally,
but the issue with going longer than
that,
it takes that real time.
Nature of the conversation will flow out
of it.
Then we're delaying these tweets and
like when you're watching UFC,
are you watching like warriors
basketball?
A lot of.
A lot of the great twitter is just like
in the moment,
just like you know,
it's the roar of the crowd.
It's like,
you know,
looking across a at someone you're in
this virtual stadium with and just
saying like,
oh my God,
that shot.
Can you believe it?
But this isn't clarity more important
because you're not.
It depends on the context that you still
have the ability to communicate quickly,
but you also have the ability to
clarify.
That's,
that's where we need to really pay
attention because
if you're,
if you're in the context of an NBA game,
you want to be fast and you just won't
be able to moment and you just,
you don't want to be raw,
but if you're in the context of
considering what the president just did
or making a particular statement,
then you probably need some,
some more time and we can be dynamic
there.
What's interesting to me is how few
people use video.
Like I thought when you guys have video
on twitter,
I'm like,
wow,
a bunch of people going to be making
videos and putting those up on twitter
and it's not,
it's not that often.
It depends on who you follow it.
It's huge for some aspects of twitter.
It's,
it's,
uh,
it's less so in others,
but aspects is huge for um,
a lot,
a lot of sports.
I mean we see a lot of like just the
replays and the recaps for sure,
you know,
aspects of a,
of a particular shot that people want to
comment on.
I don't like.
I think it's dangerous for us to focus
too much on the medium,
whether it be images or gifts or video.
It's,
it's more about the conversation around
it.
That's what we want to optimize for.
It's definitely very popular for sports
and,
and folly.
And you know,
there's uh,
what is,
uh,
there's,
there's a bunch of animal attack videos.
Yeah.
Nature is metals a good one and hold my
beer.
That's another good one.
I mean it's all videos,
but what I meant was people making a
video talking about something.
This is what I was trying
to say,
what I think is this and that and blah
blah blah.
You don't see a lot of that.
And I thought maybe that would be
something that people would adopt more.
Two different speed.
I think like the,
the consumption of video.
I mean you see this in the technology
right now,
like people are subtitling every single
video because people might be in an
environment where they can't turn the
audio on or like a video like I have to
scrub through to see what's interesting
like it with text.
I can just see it and it allows for a
lot of serendipity to find something
that I probably wouldn't have seen
unless I watched the whole damn video.
So like the ability to clip something,
the ability to like index in I think is
really critical.
So it's not,
to me,
it's not about the format,
it's about the use case in the context
that you're in
now.
Going back to the responsibility that
you guys have and you in particular,
like when this became what it is now and
when it became evident that it became
this gigantic way of changing the way
human beings communicate with each
other.
Was there ever any regret or was there a
moment where you're like,
what the fuck have I gotten myself into?
I mean,
um,
there's um,
always reflective of where I am and what
I'm doing.
Um,
I think the,
the biggest has been around,
um,
twofold.
One,
how the dynamics of the service allow it
to be weaponized in order to silence
someone else or to drive them off the
surface entirely,
which goes against the entire concept of
free speech and free participation.
Like we,
we,
we just can't stand for that.
We,
we,
we need to make sure that everyone feels
that they have an opportunity at a voice
and when you have these coordinated
attacks,
it,
it just,
it's not fair.
The second is around,
you know,
this,
this concept of an echo chamber and the
filter bubble.
I,
I just,
I don't feel personally good about that.
I don't feel.
I don't feel I'm,
that we thought that through enough.
In the early days,
I think we should have moved a,
towards biasing the service towards
topics and interests much,
much sooner than we are now considering
doing
no.
When you have these considerations,
when you take these actions,
do you consult with psychologists or
sociologists or historians or people
that try to put in perspective for you?
What the ramifications of each
individual move would be?
I try to read as much as possible.
I try to talk to as many people as
possible.
Just get completely different
perspective.
And is there any internal disagreement
about actions that you take?
Oh yeah.
There's,
there's always,
there's always debate,
but I think my role is to ask,
ask questions and make sure like,
are like what,
what is our goal here?
What are we trying to do?
Um,
you know,
in that evolves that,
that evolves,
that evolves like,
and is this over the long term going to
be a net positive for all humans,
all,
all humanity.
Like how do we balance the
considerations of,
of how we serve everyone and like how do
we get down to something,
how do we get down to a fundamental
answering the central answer?
And that to me is where the real truth
is when you can get to something
foundational.
But I like,
you know,
I like having conversations with as many
people from as many different fields as
possible and getting their perspective
on it.
So I asked questions all the time.
It's interesting the way you're phrasing
this too,
that you,
you are looking at this as a method to
save or to,
to,
to help people,
to serve people.
You're looking at this as a way that you
can benefit society.
The society can benefit from your
platform,
can benefit from this,
this ability to communicate,
um,
you're not just looking at it as a tech
company that has to remain profitable
and that's one of the more interesting
things about tech companies to me.
I mean,
there's been a lot of criticism maybe
justified in some ways the tech
companies all lean left,
but what is interesting to me is that
name another corporation that willingly
have its own choice,
takes that into consideration that they
want to serve the world and surf culture
in a beneficial way regardless of
profit.
Yeah.
I mean,
because you're not really selling
anything,
right?
You guys have a platform,
obviously it's financially viable,
but you're not,
you're not selling things.
Well,
I mean,
we,
we do our models based off people's
attention.
Yeah.
And they're paying us with our attention
and that's extremely valuable and
something that we need to really,
really honor.
Um,
but I agree with you.
I mean like,
look at,
look at Tesla,
you know,
I just listened to,
uh,
um,
the,
the recent earnings call on.
One of the things that you said was,
look,
there are two reasons,
uh,
for Tesla,
number one is to advance,
um,
uh,
you know,
different sources of energy and more
renewable sources of energy because it's
a fundamental and existential crisis
that's facing all humanity.
And number two is to advance autonomy
because it'll save lives and give people
time back.
And then you started talking about how
to make that possible and that's where
our business comes in.
How do we,
how do we make that possible?
And we,
we have,
uh,
we have a great business.
We,
we need to improve all bunch of it,
but we,
it,
it serves what we think our larger
purposes,
which is serving the public
conversation.
We want to see more global public
conversations.
We want to,
we want technology to be used to make
the world feel a lot smaller,
to help see what common problems we have
before us.
And ideally,
uh,
you know,
how we can get people together to solve
them faster and solve them better.
You also seem to be embracing this
responsibility that you're,
you're helping to evolve culture.
And this is part of the pro providing
this method of communication,
of communication,
rather it's helping to evolve culture.
And this is a,
this is something that is really only
applicable to tech companies in some
strange way.
And it's weird that so many of them have
share this.
Like I was personally a little weirded
out when Google took out.
Don't be evil.
Like that was a big part of their
operating model.
Take that out.
Yes,
yes.
Right.
Make sure I don't want to get sued.
I'm pretty sure they removed that from.
What would the,
would you call that?
Their,
their operational directive.
Like what is the code of conduct code of
conduct and it's not there anymore.
Right?
They're moved it.
So the other article that says they
removed the clause and
a weird thing to tell people not to be
evil,
is it?
Where did it take it out once you've
already said it,
it's way weirder to say fuck it,
we were wrong.
It was another way of saying that they
changed it to do the right thing.
Yeah.
Oh well,
what does that mean?
The fuck does do the right thing.
Mean do the right thing so you can make
more money.
You know,
like,
hey,
we're going to make money,
we'll do the right thing.
It makes more money.
You know what I mean?
It's,
I mean,
that's,
that's why like that's why this openness
is so critical.
I mean,
that's why I like the public comment to
me,
the public conversation is so important
is we can talk about stuff like that and
there will be companies forming today
that look at um,
objectives and mandates like that and
base their whole culture around it.
And is that the right idea?
But if we're not talking about it,
we won't be able to answer that
question.
What's also interesting,
because Google is so all encompassing,
right?
You have gene male,
you have enjoyed.
I mean that they are the number one
operating system for mobile phones in
the world on top of being a search
engine.
There's so much involved in that
company.
And again,
like almost all tech companies,
they heavily lean left and they be.
Because they had that don't be evil as a
part of their code of conduct.
It seemed like something that was a good
idea to have,
like,
and it sort of defined what I was
talking about that tech companies are
uniquely progressive.
Yeah,
I mean,
I dunno,
I dunno what makes it,
um,
I think um,
no matter what,
like we,
the Internet allows for a very healthy
skepticism of nearly everything.
Um,
I'm from,
I'm from.
It's the show me state.
Are you ready?
Yeah,
I'm from Saint Louis,
Missouri.
We're all skeptics.
My mom was a democrat.
My Dad was a republican.
My Dad listened to rush limbaugh and
Hannity all the time.
I found myself somewhere in the middle,
but one of the things I appreciate it,
we had a ton of fights and arguments and
yelling matches around the kitchen
table,
but like I appreciate the fact that we
could have them and I didn't,
I felt safe to do so and I didn't feel
like,
I mean obviously then my parents,
but they weren't judging me because of
what I said.
And they didn't force you to be a
republican or a democrat.
It forced me to,
to,
to think a particular way.
And I,
like,
I,
I think they were good,
at least showing different perspectives
even in this,
in this union that,
that they have.
And I don't know,
it developed.
It developed a skepticism in me that I,
that I think is,
is healthy and I have a lot of
skepticism of companies like ours and
leaders like me.
I think that's right.
And people should.
And we,
I mean I was,
I was,
I was formed through a lot of the ideals
of the Internet.
I just fell in love with what it made
possible and I,
I,
I never ever want to run a foul of,
of those ideals and,
and you know,
the,
the removal of barriers and boundaries
and,
and the connection that we have because
of it.
And I,
you know,
I,
I think often in reflect often about my
role and the centralization of my role
in our company and I,
I wanna,
I wanna figure out and help figure out
like how we can continue to add massive
value and,
and be an amazing business which is,
is us and will always be us.
But at the same time,
be a participant participatory force in
this greater good that the Internet has
really started and it's not,
it's not led by any one individual or
anyone company and that's the beauty of
it and I want to,
I want to make sure that we find our
place in that and we can also contribute
massively to.
And then I think we can,
it's just gonna take a lot of work and a
lot of introspection and a lot of
experimentation,
a lot of making mistakes and failures
too.
Well,
it's very encouraging that you have that
attitude because a,
you know,
a lot of people I think in a similar
situation would try to control the
narrative.
They would try to reinforce their own
particular perspective on things and try
to get other people to adopt it or try
to push it.
And I think it is,
it's very important to just have this
open discussion and,
and I think it's very important
to review your own thoughts and ideas
and one of the best ways to do so.
Put us through the.
Yeah,
put it out there,
put it out there.
And have other people review,
peer review is a,
is a great process and that's the way
this podcast has evolved more than
probably anything.
That's the thing.
I mean you,
you,
you did this because you want to learn
from people and,
and the,
the platform that you,
you've created millions get to learn
from it as well and that's just so
amazing like I learned from your podcast
all the time and
that's what technology makes possible.
But with that power also comes
ramifications and if we're not talking
about the ramifications and like at
least being open about what we know and
what we don't know.
And I think we're,
I think we state and post a lot more of
what we know rather than what we don't
know when that is so interesting.
Why don't you guys steal?
Don't be evil.
Put that in your own shit.
Fuck.
You don't know if that's going to help
anything.
Then what is that telling our employees
that do don't leave.
It's real simple.
There'll be a dick.
Yeah.
I mean like how do,
how do we,
how do we get deeper?
And just like seeing more conversation
around what is quote unquote eval,
have you guys considered expanding your
influence in other venues?
I'm like,
you know,
Google started off as a search engine
now it's fucking everything.
Have you guys considered doing something
similar?
I think we probably did too much of that
early on.
And that's what led to a bunch of issues
from a,
from a corporate standpoint.
We're just trying to do too much,
too many times.
Uh,
I dunno,
we were trying to be everything to
everyone and like,
you know,
we,
we had a,
uh,
a video thing and we had um,
we're looking at um,
gaming stuff and messaging and it lost
focus of what we are good at.
What we're good at is conversation and
what we're good at is as public
conversation.
So we now have,
as a company,
we have just such an amazing focus on
what that means and how that evolves.
And there's just,
there's some really cool things that we
can do.
They're like,
we have this,
we have this app called periscope.
And one of the things that we're
discovering is like a lot of people are
using it to podcast,
a lot of people are using it to share
their thoughts and these people come in
and chat and have a conversation.
And uh,
one of the things we did recently is we
allowed the audio to play in the
background.
It's super simple,
but what we found was that people didn't
necessarily want to watch the video of
people talking.
They just want to hear what they're
saying.
And that just opened the door for more
types of use cases.
And there's some really exciting things
coming out with periscope that I think
add a new dimension to what conversation
looks like and how it is experienced and
how it evolves.
And um,
those are the things I get really
excited about is like how,
how can we conversation better and,
and how,
uh,
you know,
how,
how do we,
how do we make it feel more live?
How do we make it feel more,
um,
electric and a,
how do we bring new,
um,
new technology into it that,
that just opens the door for an entirely
new way of talking.
And,
and that's the thing that I think has
been most educational to me about
twitter as we,
you know,
as we,
as we talked about,
we started with this idea of sharing
what was happening around you and then
people told us what they wanted to
wanted it to be and it became this
conversational medium.
It became this interest networked and it
became a,
it became a thing that was entirely new
and it,
you know,
we observed it and uh,
we learned more and more of what it
wanted to be in.
We as we get deeper and deeper that
we're going to be surprised by some of
the technologies that we thought would
be used in this way,
but it turns out that the,
the massive use case and the resonant
use case in the fundamental use case is
going to be created right before our
eyes by the people using it.
Now,
did you guys acquire periscope?
What was required postcode and what was
the thought process when you requiring
it?
Um,
we,
uh,
we liked the live nature of it.
We liked the broadcast,
uh,
aspects,
whitey black and why keep it as
periscope?
Why not have it be like twitter live?
There's a,
there's a specific community on,
on,
uh,
on periscope.
And I think it's interesting from an
experimentation standpoint,
we can play with ideas there.
It's a small tigress I think uses it
better than anybody he gets.
He's,
he's,
he's really good at it and he's,
he's one that I think has figured out,
um,
you know,
just the NAC behind it,
he,
he starts every one of them with,
uh,
with this,
simultaneous sip of coffee.
So he gets his listeners and his viewers
engaged right away.
And then he just goes on and then every
now and then he'll,
you know,
look at the comments and,
and riff off of them.
So people build up to like,
he,
he'll announce that he's going on and
then wait a little while and say hello
to some people.
Then once a bunch of people are in the
room,
then he starts talking.
Yeah,
and I,
I just,
I find A.
I find that so interesting because that
is the future of conversation.
It's looking at the patterns,
it's looking at what people are trying
to do with a thing and then you build
technology around it and that becomes.
That becomes the next big thing and we
just have to.
We have to hone our power of observation
in our power of like connecting the dots
and looking at all the patterns and what
people are.
It's what's the question behind the
question?
What's,
what's the statement behind the
statement that they're making and if we
can get good at understanding some of
those fundamental central things,
then we've reached,
we've,
we've at least created the probability
that most people in the world will find
it useful and find valuable.
Joey Diaz
is the other person that uses periscope
better than anybody alive,
but he just gets it.
He just gets baked.
That just gives you a morning.
He call it morning bond.
Morning joint.
The morning joint.
Yeah.
He'll,
he'll smoke a joint or smoke a bowl in
the morning and then just sort of let
everybody know,
do you in.
Sometimes mine
doing something in sync with one,
with,
with more people's interesting.
Like,
uh,
we've um,
we've had some folks who are interested
in doing meditations through periscope.
Oh,
that's a great idea.
You can't.
I mean if you,
if you looked at,
at the surface level,
I can't imagine anything more boring
than like watching someone meditate,
but if you're actually meditating with
them,
there's something powerful about it and
like what can we do to improve that
experience?
What about people using it for group
workouts?
Is anyone doing that?
I'm sure it's happened and I haven't
seen it personally,
but I'm sure it's happening.
How much more people do you have on
twitter than periscope?
A lot.
It's a,
it's one of those things that I
personally just have a lot of conviction
around and I have a lot of belief in the
format in.
I know every now and then we don't have
instant hits.
It just requires a lot of patients and
we need to really learn what it wants to
be in the.
Sometimes that takes time and you know,
I think oftentimes I've certainly done
this.
We,
uh,
you know,
we shut down,
we shut down things a little bit too
early and we did this at square.
Like we had this amazing technology and
app I love cold a square wallet and it
allowed you to um,
you know,
you link your credit card and you have
all these merchants around you here in
La and you could walk up to a coffee
merchant and as you walked up,
your name would pop up on the register.
So you could say like,
I want a Cappuccino,
put it on Jack and it just automatically
charge your card.
And they would only happen if you were
with him like two feet.
We're using Bluetooth and geolocation
would not.
But we,
uh,
we,
we had it for about three years and it,
it,
it just didn't take off and we shut it
down.
And I kinda regret doing that.
But it also paved the way for another
thing that I didn't want to give up on.
And that was,
that was the cash app,
like for four years.
Uh,
it was just a slog,
like a lot of people in the company
wanted to shut down the thing.
They saw it as something that wasn't
successful.
And you know,
recently the team reached number one in
the,
in the APP store in the United States.
Like we,
we,
we were all,
we were against all these incumbents
like Venmo and paypal and,
and uh,
it finally clicked and it's just because
we had the patients and the conviction
render our belief.
Yeah,
it's a great app too.
And the ethics behind it are really
fantastic too.
We're really thankful for the cash app,
especially my friend Justin wren,
and it's fight for the forgotten charity
that every time you use the code word
Joe Rogan all one word,
it all goes.
Where matched $5 goes to,
to that they've built two to the pygmies
in the Congo and they've raised
thousands of dollars in building more
wells right now.
It's really,
really cool.
Yeah,
we're really,
really happy about that.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I love it.
I think it's um,
it's a great way to save money too.
I mean when you can save 10 percent at
whole foods,
I mean that's real.
Well,
if the other thing is like to the
population that we serve typically are
underserved by banks or unbanked
entirely.
We are their bank account,
but more importantly they don't have
access to things like rewards.
You don't get rewards on a typical debit
card or credit card.
So like just you know,
going to your favorite place and getting
an instant 10 percent off or whatever it
is,
is out of reach for most people because
the financial institutions don't enable
that and they won't even enable them to
get in the door,
in the front,
in the first place.
Well,
if people are listening,
is this on youtube,
you don't know what the fuck we're
talking about.
The cash APP has a thing called a cash
card or a debit card that you get with
it and there's a thing called boosts and
with boosts,
all you do is pick a boost in the APP
and then use your cash card as a debit
card and you get these automatic
discounts and they're real discounts.
Yep.
And interest for folks with bad credit.
There's no credit check.
You can direct deposit your paycheck
right into the app and the fact that you
guys do do things like support fight for
the forgotten and you're supporting UFC
fighter ray borg son.
He's got some serious medical bills.
No,
it's really,
really cool.
Yeah.
I'm really.
I'm really proud of that.
I'm really proud of the team.
It's A.
It's a very small team,
but they're doing some big things
well.
I hear a lot of good things about it
too.
I've,
I've run into people on the street that
tells me they use it in the very happy
about it,
so it's nice to see,
again,
a,
an emerging technology that's profitable
but yet also has a really good at it.
Really good set of ethics.
Yeah.
Do you have,
don't be evil in cash.
Maybe we should.
Maybe we should take it.
So when,
uh,
one of our,
one of our like equivalent operating
principles within cash and square is
like under like how do we understand
someone's struggle?
Like how do we understand like how do we
have the empathy for what they're
struggling with and like when it comes
to finance,
they're struggling with a lot.
Yeah.
Typically they're struggling with a ton.
What was the,
the thought process with.
I mean,
one of the things that's kind of cool
about the cash app is that you can buy
and sell bitcoin with it.
Are you going,
are you guys going to consider other
forms of crypto currency as well?
Not right now.
I,
so back to the Internet.
I believe the Internet will have a
native currency really.
They don't have a native currency and I
don't know if it's bitcoin and I think
it will because just given all the tests
it's been through and the principles
behind it,
how it was created and um,
you know,
it's,
it was something that was born on the
Internet that was developed on the
Internet that it was tested on it.
It is of the Internet and the reason we,
um,
you know,
we enabled the purchasing of bitcoin
within,
within the cash APP is one we want to
learn about the technology and we wanted
to put ourselves out there and take some
risks.
Were the first publicly traded company
to actually it as a service where the
first publicly traded company to talk to
the sec about the coin in what that,
what that means.
And it made us uncomfortable.
We had to,
we had to like really understand what
was going on and,
and that was critical and important.
And then the second thing is that we,
you know,
we would,
we would love to see something become a
global currency.
It did,
it enables more access.
It,
it allows us to serve more people.
It allows us to move much faster around
the world.
And um,
we,
uh,
we thought we were going to start with
how you can use it transactionally,
but we noticed that people were treating
it more like an asset,
like a,
like a virtual gold,
and we wanted to,
um,
we want to just to make that easy,
like I'm just the simplest way to buy
and sell bitcoin.
But we also knew that it had to come
with a lot of education,
had to come with constraint because,
you know,
two years ago people did some really
unhealthy things about,
you know,
purchasing bitcoin.
They maxed out their credit cards and
um,
put all their life savings into bitcoin.
So we,
we developed some severity,
simple restrictions and constraints like
you can,
you can't buy bitcoin on the cash app
with a credit card.
You have to,
it has to be the money you actually have
in it.
And we look for day trading,
which we,
uh,
we discourage and shut down like that.
That's not what we're trying to build.
That's not what we're trying to optimize
for.
We made a children's book explaining
what Bitcoin is and where it came from
and how people use it and where it might
be going.
So we really tried to take on the role
of education and,
and,
and to have some like very simple
healthy constraints that allowed to be
allowed people to consider what their
actions are in the space.
Now when you have something like the
cash app,
which is a,
it's very much a disruptive technology
in terms of like decentralization of,
of banks and,
and,
and currency and you know,
to have it where everything is going
right at your direct depositing a
paycheck right in the app if you so
choose.
And then you could also buy bitcoin,
which is another disruptive technology
mean that this is another step towards
this sort of new way of doing things.
No.
And is there pushback from,
from any companies or is there.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
I mean like you just look at some of the
major banks and their consideration
around bitcoin.
They all love blockchain because of the
efficiencies that can create for their
business and potentially new business
lines.
But,
um,
you know,
I think there is a explain blockchain to
people for people who don't know what
we're talking about.
Blockchain is a distributed ledger and
what that means is that,
um,
it's basically a distributed database
where,
you know,
the,
the source of truth can be verified at
any point around the network and you
can,
you know,
um,
this,
this annotation around how content or
how around money like traveled.
Um,
so you don't have to go to an
institution.
So the records,
yeah,
there's no centralized check,
there's no centralized control over it.
Um,
and I think that is a threatening.
It's,
it's,
it's certainly threatening,
um,
to certain services behind banks and
financial institutions.
It's threatening to some governments as
well.
Um,
so I,
I just look at this and like how do we
embrace this technology,
not react to it in a more from a threat
standpoint,
but like what does it enable us to do
and where does our value shift?
And that's what we should be talking
about right now is like how our value
shifts.
And there's always really strong answers
to that question.
But if you're not willing to ask the
question the first place,
you will become irrelevant because
technology will just continue to march
on and make you irrelevant and it's the
people that like are,
are,
you know,
growing up with this technology are born
with the technology only knowing that
technology or are asking the tough
questions of ourselves that are going to
be super disruptive to their business
and they're,
they're thinking about right now and
they're and they're taking actions and
you know,
we're doing,
we're doing that at square and we're
doing that at twitter and like that to
me represents longevity.
That represents our ability to,
to thrive and we,
we got to push ourselves going to make
ourselves uncomfortable and we got to
disrupt what we held sacred and what we
think is success at it because otherwise
it's not going to be bigger than what we
have today.
Yeah.
I couldn't agree more.
And I think that cryptocurrency to me
represents one of the more interesting
discussions on the Internet.
What is money and why are we agreeing
that it's these pieces of paper that the
Federal Reserve prints out.
Totally.
It's,
it's a fascinating time in technology
because like that,
that to me was one of the,
one of the last big,
um,
centralized natch,
a nationalized instruments is his
currency is money and when you think
about the internet as a,
as a,
as a country,
as a market,
as a nation,
it's going to have its own currency and,
but what's interesting about the
internet as a nation,
it's the whole world.
It is the whole world.
So the world gets one currency,
it gets,
it's one thing to communicate in and
that,
to me it's just so freeing and so
exciting.
Yeah,
I,
I'm very excited by it and I'm also very
excited that the fact that it's only
been around for such a short period of
time,
but yeah,
10 years and it's become a part of the
global conversation,
good brand.
I also think that it's going to open up
the door to potential universal
languages and I think this is,
this is.
Yeah.
That excites me a lot about twitter as
like how do we like it if we want to get
the world into a conversation into a,
not a single conversation,
but at least being able to see that
global conversation,
like we gotta work on technologies that
like instantly translate.
Yeah,
we got to work on technologies that I
can speak as I'm speaking right now in,
in real time.
People are hearing it in their context
and their language and their dialect.
That is amazing.
That is so exciting.
And like just how that evolves.
Um,
and uh,
how it,
how it impacts not just communication
like this,
but music.
Uh,
and just like,
you know,
how hip hop and rap and you know,
just,
it just,
it,
it's,
it's amazing to think about where that,
where that can go and where that can
take us.
Yeah.
And I think
you and I are extremely fortunate to be
alive right now during this time because
I think it's one of the strangest and
most unique times in human history.
Totally.
I don't think there's ever been a time
where things have changed so radically
so quickly.
Totally.
Yeah.
And I,
I feel,
you know,
we,
um,
we're,
we're just,
we're able through technologies like
twitter to at least see and acknowledge
some of the issues that we're still
facing and we're probably in the dark
before and I think that's so critical to
making any sort of improvements for,
for making any sort of evolution and a
and for making it better for everyone on
the planet.
And I,
you know,
as,
as uncomfortable as,
as you know,
sometimes twitter makes people feel,
I think it is necessary to,
to see those things and have
conversations about them so that we can
understand how we might move forward and
how we might.
I'm really good at the biggest problems
facing us all and you know,
there's some huge ones,
some huge ones right now that if we
don't have,
if we don't talk about it,
like it will drive us to extinction and
like it will threaten our ability to,
to be a planet to live on this planet.
I agree.
Thank you.
Thanks for everything,
man.
Thanks for being here.
Thanks for doing what you're doing.
Thanks for having the attitude that you
have.
I really,
really appreciate it.
Thank you.
My pleasure.
Bye everybody.
Thank you.