Did you see this?
And we're back.
Trump's latest conspiracy.
You know,
what is it?
He's,
I guess he's saying that there's a New
York Times piece that contains a
paragraph saying,
trump suggested that the access
hollywood tape wasn't real.
So he's like saying that never existed.
Oh No.
You know,
he said,
well,
I think those are the two microphones on
or something.
So I was up,
the TV was on.
So it,
it's,
um,
I think he said like in passing to
someone,
like how do we even know?
That's real,
dude.
Do you know how tired he must be?
I'm so tired.
Just listen.
Just think how tired you are,
right?
Just doing normal stuff.
Doing podcast,
dual comedy shows,
you know,
having a girlfriend,
right?
Tiring.
Imagine being 70 and being the fucking
president and being in a position where
you're like,
why did I do this?
Why did I do this?
He's got,
I mean,
maybe,
maybe let's just give him the benefit of
the doubt.
Maybe you went into this job with the
best of intentions,
but it was just overwhelmed by conflict.
Every step of the way.
He's tested in a way that his character
was never tested before and all these
people are mad at them.
It's just hell,
hell on earth.
70 so tired and he's getting the worst
comments ever have.
He did like this tired.
But here's the thing.
There was an article that was written,
not married men not meaning in any way
to disparage the great president of
ours,
but there was a article that was
written,
um,
a while back that were this guy found
out that trump had some sort of a
prescription for an fentimans like way
back in the day,
which again,
that word's a dirty word,
but let's just break down what that
means.
It's a series and a class of drugs
that's a stimulant and there's a lot of
people that use stimulants,
including me.
I love coffee.
I drink these caveman Nitros for a lot
of people.
This might as well be a drug,
just 270 milligrams.
This little can,
270 milligrams of caffeine.
So I'm a hypocrite.
I try not to be at least.
So I'm just being honest.
It's nothing wrong with stimulants.
I enjoy coffee,
but that's the only one that I fuck with
other than that new vigil.
I've tried that stuff a few times and I
will try it.
Like say if I have to drive home,
if driving home from San Francisco,
it's like 10 o'clock at night and know
I'm not going to get home until three in
the morning,
four in the morning,
I will take one of those cause it'll
keep you from falling asleep.
That's what it's made for.
Yes.
It's not high.
Apparently what I've read was that it,
that's what they prescribe it for,
but it would,
it's made for the guy and it was
originally called pro vigil.
Right?
It's two different ones,
but they're pretty much the same.
Yeah.
But one of them's a new one.
Think new vigils.
A new one.
Right.
And I think what they did is like,
there was probably some sort of a,
I don't know,
one of maybe maybe it's an improvement
or maybe it was some sort of a copyright
thing or a trademark thing.
I'm going to ask Jamie that.
Google a bunch of shit.
What did we start with?
Start with the trump,
uh,
amphetamine thing.
But here's the thing,
that's what adderall is folks.
And I know a fucking shit load of people
that are on that stuff and I've talked
about it ad nauseum.
I'm sorry if I'm boring you.
I just,
just for people that have never heard me
talk about this,
you got to get it out.
Fun Fact.
19.
Excuse me.
I said,
I think it came from this tweet is which
is guy that was a contributing writer
for Vanity Fair.
Yeah.
Kurt,
I can walk,
I believe is the way you say his last
name.
I says fun fact.
In 1982 s trump started taking
amphetamine derivatives.
He says abused them,
but that's,
that's his classification,
right?
Only supposed to take two for 25 days.
Stayed on for eight years.
Really?
The second tweet,
where were the one below?
It says wives.
White House admitted to edit to me.
He took it for a short amount of time
for a diet.
Oh,
a diet.
When he was not overweight,
I counted with med records.
They cut me off.
People misreading dread was drug was
though propane,
75 milligrams a day.
Prescriptions filled at Duane reed on 57
wow.
Not that I know things.
He gave out the fucking address of the
Duane Reed where it was prescribed or
fulfilled.
Yeah,
man,
I think I'm for sure.
Without a doubt.
Right?
Like there's a lot of people that enjoy
some stimulants.
Can you see him now
getting tan his tan on and get taking
diet pills?
Like that's,
that's how you get,
that's how you get ahead and this is
gonna sound fucked up and it's not
entirely true.
Okay.
This is why it sounds fucked up because
other people have done it with nothing.
There's people out there that are just
fucking getting up early and run in
mountains and drinking water and kicking
ass.
There are people like that,
but there's a lot of people in business
in a lot of different walks of life that
enjoy stimulants and I am not knocking
them.
I just don't want to be really clear
about this.
This is just sort of a discussion of it.
I'm not knocking him.
Maybe it's awesome.
I'm scared of adderall.
I'm scared.
I'd love it.
I,
I've tasted it.
It tastes like,
I mean,
I've had it,
you know what it reminded me of,
I tried to do it once.
My friend gave me one and I took half of
the wine and I went on stage like later
and it felt like I was on coke,
like in the,
you know,
like if you tried to do coke on,
uh,
before you do comedy,
your timing's off.
You know,
you start like you're just going through
your shit super fast.
And that's what I felt like.
And I'm like,
I'm never doing that again.
And then I had it one more time,
like years later,
uh,
when I was doing something,
I had to stay awake and I just felt
jittery.
Like I,
I didn't like it compared to like
nuvigil where you didn't have like the
jitters or the,
the adderall type feeling
nuvigil doesn't give you any of that,
right?
Yeah,
you're just on.
Yeah.
It's weird,
but it doesn't,
um,
it doesn't,
you don't feel like it stimulates you.
I feel like it just doesn't,
that keeps you out of level,
but it doesn't take any heart.
Jesus sounds like a new vigil.
Add this,
this,
this shit is.
So this is the thing about new vigil.
I had a conversation with Tim Ferris
about this,
you know Tim Ferriss didn't put that in
one of his biohacking books specifically
because he felt like if he did,
people would eat it like candy and I
went holy Shit.
Like when on a guy like Tim Ferriss,
extremely influential guy that spends a
lot of time doing like biohacking and
improvement shit like he does for that
guy to say he didn't want to write about
new vigil or pro vigil at a book because
he didn't want people eating it like
candy.
Like Holy Shit.
Listen to him.
And one of the things that he said that
I thought was very important,
he said there's no biological free
lunch.
So there's gotta be some sort of
repercussions for taking that.
And maybe we won't know for 20 years.
Right.
That's the thing,
like something's happening,
right?
You're doing something.
If it gets you fired up now it's not a
natural thing.
So it's not like you're taking vitamins
and those vitamins like b 12 or
something like that stimulates you.
It gives you energy.
It's not that,
okay,
so is it bad that it's not that is it
bad or cat?
How much,
how many chemicals are bad and how many
chemicals are okay and how do you know?
I mean
look at sugar man.
W we we are now learning a sugar is like
the worst thing in the whole entire
world because of the sugar industry.
And back in the day was like sell this,
sell this fats bad,
you know,
and him and now we know that sugar is
one of the biggest things for heart
disease and all that crap and the,
they're weasels.
What'd you pull up?
The comparison chart on new vaginal and
provigil.
They're almost the same thing.
One is modafinil and the other one is
our modafinil.
And so they have some sort of a here.
The mechanism of action is slightly
different on them.
That's the only thing I can tell.
It's different.
Is One an improvement of the other eye
can't really looks at new bridges,
has slightly different functions to
shit.
Yeah.
It's something about electronic couple
anyway.
Thank you.
The fact that I've taken this,
no,
they'll listen to what this is.
This stuff is,
it may activate orexin peptides via
stimulation of Orexin receptors.
Oh x one and x two and may also
increase.
Ready for this one glue to glue to
Metta.
Metallurgic Gluten,
Matt Dirge,
Dick [inaudible],
Gouda muttered chick.
Is that I say it and it sounds right.
Glutamatergic concentrations decrease ga
be allergic activation and increase
electronic coupling.
I who knows what that means.
Rhonda.
Patrick.
Well she,
she probably would have to go.
Okay.
And then she to like lay it out and then
we would listen to it afterwards.
Like,
oh,
whenever she talks,
I always feel like I'm some sort of like
a a stupid monkey person.
I'm like stupid monkey of question for
smart
lady.
Please tell me how the body works.
What is electronic coupling that we've
got to get to the bottom of that cause
that's electronic.
That's a problem.
How do we have something electronic in
us?
How was like a thing?
You have to worry about what you're
trying to stay awake.
What is it the fuck?
We're robots,
dude.
Magic.
That's how we found out by looking at
the ingredients of new vigil and were
like,
Hey,
hey,
what does this mean?
Then all of a sudden the fucking
overlords turned the switch and we can
see them in front of us.
Sorry,
you guys are robots.
Because his entire time was that God
damn ad agency the whole time that let
it out.
We're doing the bid
bidding for the robot world.
You know what the creepiest fucking
quote I ever read it was um,
uh,
God,
Marshall Mcluhan,
he said human beings are the sex organs
of the machine world.
I want,
what the fuck man.
And he wrote this Mcluhan was a bad
motherfucker and like our one of a
really underrated visionary,
like you read some of the stuff,
you're like,
Jesus.
Like this guy had some insight and I'm
pretty sure he wrote all this stuff in
like the 60s you know,
think of what,
find it,
see if he could find when that quote was
said by Mcluhan or written however it
was,
human beings or the sex organs of the
machine world.
I feel like it was in the 60s you wrote
this,
which is like,
wow,
that's so how the fuck did he see that?
That's what it is.
We are some sort of a,
a weird being that makes better and
better technology every year and we'd
get pumped about it.
Which is why I wanted to show you that
razor phone.
Oh,
that's so sexy,
man.
I can't believe you have that.
1964 64 just stop and think of that.
1964 that motherfucker figured it out.
That was all kind of mine.
Probably was covered is that,
that's like,
so look at that.
Look at that.
Bright.
That's beautiful man.
It's just the razor phone that's
supposed to have the best speaker phone
do to speakers and saying,
yeah,
like it's like a bluetooth.
It's not that loud.
Not that loud.
It's not as loud as a bluetooth,
but it's fucking crazy.
Like you watch a movie on it,
it's dope.
You can play games on it.
It's incredible.
Yeah.
Sounds like God damn ad for this now.
Nuvigil and raised.
No,
no one's paid me.
This is a,
they gave it to me for free and all uh,
all honesty,
but it's pretty dope razor mixed quality
products.
I have that big high end or high end
laptop,
but the blade pro and it's really good.
Is that the iphone 10 I did.
I just got the iphone tench yeah,
it took me,
I gave in,
I saw Jamie is,
I'm like,
I give,
I tapped two things about it that I
liked.
Good face id,
a hundred percent legit,
hundred percent legit.
The only time it's like when you wake
up,
you know you've pillows like in the way
or your eyes are puffy down but you just
go to the passcode.
But anytime you look at it,
it just unlocks,
you know,
you can close your eyes and it won't
unlock.
So when you're sleeping you can't like
just put that up to your face and the
size of it.
Cause it's the same about the same size
as the the plus,
which is what I told that bitch.
But it's like having an old small phone
again.
So I was starting to get carpal tunnel
and my and my finger and my thumb from
the plus after awhile.
So you can just swipe up and I can get
to all of your,
um,
I got to all your notifications.
Yeah.
There's,
there's different swipe systems.
It shouldn't say anything other than
notification though.
Does he looks at it.
Oh Shit.
Yeah.
That's the one of that.
Let me back and I was trying to cancel
it doesn't trust me.
Cancer Pitch Dilly Dally and won't let
me cancel it.
It's making me enter a password.
Cancel.
Oh there it is.
Here's some notifications.
Now can you see anything?
Cause I'm already,
nobody wants to fake face Id.
Look at me.
Look at that will look,
I'll unlock it for you.
That's why.
Hold on.
Perfect.
Perfect example.
So it fucks up sometimes.
Sometimes,
but I'll tell you what man,
this a,
the form factor is very interesting.
That's my security camp.
So it's a huge ass camera,
but it's not second three or four
cameras I think.
I mean it's the shoe as huge as phone
rather,
but it's not a huge ass phone.
Right.
And it has a killer camera.
What a weird world man.
Just 10 years ago the first iphone came
out and if you saw that thing today,
but that thing was made out of wood.
I still have mine.
Do you have some amazing all mine and
two of them are starting to explode
like,
and it's not fair because I bought him
and I wanted to keep them like a
collector,
but my like iphone three is like bubbled
up and it's about to blow up any day
now.
So do you get used to all this
difference?
You have different swipes now because
you don't have a homepage.
Like how do you,
you have to shut it down to get out of
there.
Yeah.
Interesting.
If the swiping system actually is very
like,
I can't believe I used to do it that
different way.
Like if you want to go in between like,
uh,
like programs now you just go to the on
the bottom left or right.
You know,
so you do that and then now the top
right,
it gets you to the control center.
And I mean,
and it took me about two days for me to
finally go,
oh,
this is so much how it's supposed to be.
Yeah.
Well yeah.
Who's figure,
you know,
like if they figure out a better way,
even though it's a better way,
like,
you know,
cordy typing,
do you know the whole deal behind that?
Apparently this is not the fastest way
to type like the keyboard Qwerty is set
up the way it is because in the olden
days they made it that way because old
keys would get stuck on each other and
they would mash them and they get stuck
together.
So they had a separate,
the more commonly used keys.
So they changed the way they did it,
but the right way to do the typewriter,
goddammit,
I forget the name of it,
but uh,
some people try wacky fucking nerds.
You wacky nerds,
these wacky nerds,
they touch it.
They take their keyboards and they
reprogrammed them or they buy a specific
keyboard that's in this way and then
they learn how to type with this super
unusual keyboard,
but it's supposed to be fast.
Sure.
Here's a plug in.
I think that you can do it on your ipad
and your iphones and stuff like that.
They'll realize it.
Like,
what is it called James?
The devora Kita for act.
That's,
yeah,
it's
a little different layout.
Yeah.
So there's cordy and Devorah.
So yeah,
like it's a e U I d h.
So it's not corny at all.
P Y F,
G,
C R L on top.
Like what?
Like you would,
it would take a long ass time to
relearn.
You can't relearn.
You'd have to start from the beginning.
I don't know,
man.
I don't think it's worth it.
He just,
I just,
I'm too stupid.
It's like my thoughts about learning a
new language.
Like,
well I'm good voice,
right?
Your students so much already there that
we're not going to have keyboards very
soon anyways.
What have you heard about those google
ear buds that you put them in and you,
they translate for you in real time?
Uh,
my friend has him there.
They,
they,
they're not good.
I wasn't thinking like how could they be
good when people have like crazy flow to
their language.
Like,
you know,
you talked to like some serious Puerto
Ricans and like
there's like all these words are like
flowing into these other words,
you know,
I mean there's like a flavor to it that
I just don't think that little computer
thing is going to be able to figure out
what the fuck that guy just said.
You know,
I think you could get already do it in
Google,
you know,
so you don't,
you don't need the headphones and you
just need your phone.
So I think in here it just does it on
speaker phone.
Okay.
The new Pixel,
by the way,
that camera on that,
the best camera of any,
any phone,
the new pixel two.
It's crazy is it's a single camera where
all these other phones are doing it with
a dual camera.
It is interesting,
you know,
um,
what's really interesting is the level
that all these phones are at now,
it's,
everything is at a super high level.
Like technologically speaking,
the jump has been giant.
It's like where is this fucking thing
going?
Like where,
where are we going to look at for the
iphone 20,
you know,
I mean is it going to be in your skin,
get it?
Is it going to be aware of blindness?
It's going to be wearable.
I think one day there's not going to be
a device,
a phone.
You're just going to be wearing it
somehow.
Like you look at your sleeve to make a
phone call.
You can check your email.
You're using your shoe to some mad
scientist is going to figure out a way
to make it
eyeballs that work better than our
eyeballs and they'll go,
we're going to swap out our eyeballs.
They're going to be the first to go and
swap out your eyeballs for these super
electronic eyeballs.
But everything is like a shade of color
off like red is purple.
They got to get it.
It's like one of them old led screens
and he's got burned in like we're going
to get,
we're going to figure it out.
But right now you just give up your
eyes,
you give up your eyes for the computer
world.
That's how it start us off to start us
off with better eyes.
First it'd be our blind friends,
uh,
pro,
blind friends.
We'll get new eyes and they're like,
dude,
I see so much better.
I'm actually happy that I went blind.
Like,
what the fuck did you just say?
And then next thing you know,
you're going to try it.
There's going to be some someone,
some crazy fucker with good eyesight is
going to go,
I want to be able to see better.
It's like the girl with a perfect body
that gets boob implants like,
no,
how'd you do that?
You know,
the girl already has double d's and goes
to like AAA.
He like,
no,
no.
Why did you do that?
It's interesting.
It's interesting to think of like all
the blind people would be the first ones
to get all the new eyeballs and be
seeing better.
So they're all going to be like those
people with the glasses,
the blind people,
and they take off their,
and they're all robots like they live
with the movie they live.
Remember that Rowdy Roddy Piper recipes,
respect.
Remember when Rowdy Roddy Piper was a
movie star for a little bit doing some
action movies and he was like one of the
first guys like the rock to break
through,
you know,
and uh,
that day live movie.
That was fun.
I miss that guy,
dude.
This is,
it's a real possibility that this could
happen.
Like this is not a,
I mean,
I'm not saying it's going to happen in,
in a decade,
but if human beings live to be another
hundred years,
we're going to find they're going to
have better replacements to tweet about
that.
A robot was scared.
Everybody just the way he worded it,
he said,
this is nothing in a few years,
that Bot will move so fast.
You need a strobe light to see it.
Sweet dreams.
Oh fuck that guy.
So awesome.
The shit out of me.
But he's right.
Listen man,
he's probably one of the smartest human
beings on the planet earth that guys,
you know that they think he might have
invented bitcoin.
There's a lot of speculation online.
You know what?
Here's the thing,
I want to talk about this and this
podcast.
I didn't even read the article.
I looked at the headline,
I'm like probably,
and I kept moving.
He started paypal,
right?
I didn't hit him like Peter Teal started
paying.
Yeah,
I believe so.
I believe that's what like made him and
there was a video of him from like the
1990s where he got like a million dollar
car delivered.
Like it was just starting to ball and
he's just starting to ball out of
control.
He's probably like one of the smartest
human beings ever.
And he sports car though.
There's Tesla.
He's a fascinating guy,
man.
Do you know?
He just like made a whole town out of
like a battery,
like a term.
He made like the biggest battery in the
history of the world.
Did you hear about that one?
Yeah.
They just isn't some new thing that he
just built.
They just built the largest battery in
the history of the world.
It's like a building.
Like this guy is fucking Nikola Tesla.
We're going to be some madman.
We're going to have battery explosions
in the future.
That's going to be a big thing for sure.
Now,
right?
Like this whole town's going to go up.
A Tesla has built the world's largest
battery in Australia.
What in the fuck tech and Leon Musk.
Elon.
Elon musk is making good on his promise
to solve energy,
an energy crisis in Australia.
Can you make that bear
okay.
Besides,
um,
screw that up.
Oh,
here it goes.
It's fully installed.
The world's largest lithium ion battery
in South Australia.
The state government said in a statement
Thursday,
Tesla teamed up with a French renewable
energy from and a local government to
install the battery,
which must promise to deliver within a
hundred days of signing the contract or
it would be free.
He's crazy,
but he did as a crisis.
He's,
he's a mad man.
He's like,
I'm fucking mad scientist from a,
he's like a guy from a movie,
right?
Like if you had a movie and there was
some mad billionaire Robert Downey
junior type character that just kept
invented the newest crazy shit and was
at the cutting edge of science and was
telling everybody to look out for the
fucking robots are going to kill us.
It would be Elon Musk and let him know
the comedy show one night.
I was panicking.
He watched you though,
right?
I think he,
I think he did.
He had a nice army with them.
Yeah.
I bring a lot of money with guns can
move very good.
Especially if you're worried about
robots.
Fuck man.
He's right though.
That's the scary thing.
When you watch that one robot,
there's one mini robot is this little
yellow one in this video and it's
running on the ground and like a very
fast rate and you're like,
wait,
wait.
Like you're trying to wrap your head
around this thing.
Like what is this thing has guns?
What?
It's got a little camera and it's got
guns and it's running at you like this
and it's like the size of a 44 magnum.
It's like a series of 44 magnums pointed
at you.
It's about that big and it's running.
I'll go a hundred times faster than you
could ever run.
Like what?
Oh God.
This is like probably how people in
Yemen feel like,
yes,
I've been telling you you can't,
you can't let them use robots.
You know like the people that get bombed
with drones,
we've just sorta like,
that's not real.
You don't even have to Blake,
tell us about it.
No one has to tell us that they're going
to do it.
They just do it right.
And something like 80% of the people
that they kill her innocent.
There's some crazy number of people that
the drones of Kilt,
I know we've gone over this before.
What is it like 80% do you remember?
That sounds about right.
It's some,
let's see if we can find it.
Just cause it's so,
I know you're a guru.
Can you were in surgery to get it
probably might be like 78% whatever it
is,
but it's even if it's more than 50%
that's fucking crazy.
We just have robots that shoot things at
people and we hope we get the right
ones.
You would never think that transformers
like what actually happened one day
we're going to have like good
transformers and bad transformers.
Good ones are going to hack the badger
ones or vice versa.
Michael Bay was right all along.
God,
we need to bring Megan Fox back into the
franchise.
What I just,
that's hard to imagine man,
but it's probably inevitable,
right?
It's probably inevitable that someone is
going to make some super smart robot
that does his bidding and this and we're
going to have like a war of worlds and
we're going to have robo cops fight the
bad robots.
Drones.
You imagine if the argument would be
let's let the robots fight because
therefore it'll save human lives will
dictate how the world is one sort of
just like the Olympics but with robots
fighting to the death to see who gets to
run the world.
I'm like Elon must,
should be doing instead of making
batteries is trying to invent force
fields.
You know like for real we need on the
personal force fields,
we'll see he's,
this is the thing,
he is at the cutting edge of science and
in terms of like implementation of all
these new inventions like lithium ion
batteries that are hooked up to a giant
fucking
whatever that structure was committed.
Then drone raise this one on Espn all
the time they pee do to put on like a
almost a Vr headset and race through it.
They did have him in arenas.
It's crazy.
A lot of times it's at night with lit up
like neon obstacles they're going to go
through and you'd be like 70 miles an
hour.
I think they go really fast.
So cool.
That's incredible.
That's so much cooler than a video game.
Cause this is an actual thing out there
that you're moving around,
you know like to play a video game.
Like that's the new video game.
The new video game is you put some like
10 k camera Vr headset thing on and you
put these cameras on these robots and
then you go do shit where the actual
thing is really doing it.
It's not valid.
It's not a video.
You're just watching some real physical
thing take place.
And then you have these physical wars.
So like instead of,
you know like if you built together an
army of semi indestructable robots,
right?
And you had to duke it out with another
army of semi indestructable robots and
that would be like a television show or
drone laser tag where it's like star
wars and you're fighting and if you have
you shoot your laser at it,
like turns off the drone.
It doesn't destroy it.
Maybe it makes it fake.
Yeah,
but you'd have to have high stakes.
See,
I think things would be so cheap back by
the time it gets to this point.
It's like everything gets cheaper and
cheaper.
Like you used to be,
like you had to be a super baller to
have that Michael Douglas brick on the
beach.
Right?
Remember when the movie greed or
whatever it was,
Wall Street greed is good.
He's walking with that giant brick.
Like you had to be a super ball or to be
able to afford that.
But now that's like nothing and everyone
has a cell phone that's way better than
that.
Like every person walking down the
street you can serve.
Do you have a fallen on you?
Yes,
I do.
And he pulls out his phone.
It's way better than Michael Douglas's.
Super baller all time.
High money guy cell phone here except
ours.
But Ari,
he hasn't said No.
Ari's phone,
it's still way better.
Right?
It's still way better than that stupid
piece of shit that Michael Douglas had.
So if we just keep going in that
direction,
they're going to get cheaper and cheaper
and cheaper to do crazier and crazier
things.
You remember this movie that came out a
few years ago with Hugh Jackman?
Oh yeah,
they had fights.
What is it?
It's called real steel.
It's like rock 'em sock.
'Em robots.
How did they,
how did they,
uh,
did they do it with like remote control
where almost like what you're
describing,
there's some capturing their body
movement and that just re like copies
what they do.
And really it also is ai and has
feelings.
I don't know how dumb was it?
Wait a minute.
He's on the ground.
How's he fighting?
Was it someone else doing it and then
he's going to go back in there.
Oh God,
he did the thing with the,
oh no,
he's going to,
is it training?
Montage.
Stop this.
Don't you rode Wolverine Jolt.
You root for,
don't you ruin Wolverine from me?
You piece of shit.
Sorry.
I got dumped in that look.
Oh,
that's so sad.
He's going to show the little boy,
the little boy and tells him,
Hey,
come on man.
You gotta get in there and when for us
it pulls the sunglasses down.
Well,
I'm going to have to start training,
which I took it.
Did Anybody Watch that movie?
I don't know.
That's why I don't,
don't know much about it.
They must've gave him Hugh Jackman.
Oh Shit.
A lot of money to make that look like a
good idea.
He had to be sitting in his house in
Australia.
Going,
how?
When?
How much again?
How much?
Okay,
okay,
so I'm a fighter robot guy.
Is that what's going on?
How many weeks?
I watched it on an airplane.
No sound.
That's about it.
That's what you do when you're so high.
You're thinking you got to fall out of
the sky.
They'd watch that and go,
what?
That guy's awesome as wolverine.
Even though he's not supposed to like is
not supposed to look like that.
Wolverines not supposed to be a big guy.
That would be like a bear hug.
We'll run.
It's like a little little blockhead guy.
Wolverine would be built like um,
you'd have to go like who?
Samar Paul Horez.
Perfect example.
Who some are.
Paul Harris is a guy who fought in the
UFC.
He got,
he got kicked out of the UFC for I think
unjustly.
He's got it.
He's,
he holds on to submissions too long and
people get really mad at him cause he
fucking mangles people's legs.
But I think the last one,
like east the people are they out there
on him so hard that I think the last one
was just,
it was a tiny minor infraction.
I think he's just get super excited and
I think he's definitely held on to
things too long in the past,
but I think he's learned from that.
But anyway,
the UFC as a zero tolerance policy for
that shit.
He doesn't fight for the UFC anymore.
I get it.
But my point is the guy looked like
wolverine from the comic book.
He's just fucking jacked.
He was like this five foot eight,
five foot nine.
He might not even been that tall,
hundred 85 pound goal.
Willa just ripping people's legs apart.
He was one of the scariest guys hour.
See if he can find a good picture of who
some are.
Paul Hi-rez just try Pahara it's,
there's no way I'm spelling who some are
correctly.
It's who some are within our reach in my
area.
Yeah.
It's,
it's spelled with an r,
but the,
the porch.
A gay,
see,
please use,
uh,
these h they call me Joe Hogan.
Joe Hogan.
There he is right there.
Jesus Christ,
man.
Wow.
Look at that fucking picture.
We kind of jacked.
He is,
man.
That's what wolverine is supposed to
look like,
if the almost exactly like that.
Just so like super jacked pit bull of a
man,
because that's what a wolverine is.
A wolverine.
It's a crazy fucking animal.
He's still fighting to get the size of
that guy is,
he's still fight.
He got fucked up a few times and some
other organizations,
he got beaten by some tough guys.
Like a meal,
meat meal.
A meal.
Meek.
Sorry,
I'm saying his name wrong.
Amil Meek,
the mad viking dude.
He fucked him up and that,
that's what got him over into the UFC.
That's like a Gi Joe Body.
Yeah.
He's ridiculous.
Um,
but that's what if like wolverine was a
human,
that's what he'd looked like.
Wouldn't look like Hugh Jackman but you
Jackman pulls it off.
Like you don't have to be totally,
I'm can you kind of get a movie star in
there?
It's not like let Paul Horez play
Wolverine.
Like Wolverine has to say a bunch of
Shit and you got to believe you means
it,
you know?
So it was probably hard to find like a
super jacked movie star who could be a
savage unless it's jack man who
jacqueline could be a savage.
I'm buying it.
I got my t levels results today.
How's everything going?
I don't know what it means,
but I'm in the normal range.
Like here's the,
that there's like the normal range.
You have a chart.
We had a doctor I just spent,
I spent,
I use this every,
well every well thing and he spit in his
little thing and like two weeks you'd
get like full graph.
That's like 24 and me.
But for you and 24 it's 24 hours.
But like I showed you,
like I,
I'm on the low side of normal,
but so I don't even know what that
means.
And I guess I should test it every
couple of months to see if it bounces up
and down.
But I definitely have lower normal.
Well,
you could fix that.
I know I,
but here's the thing you should do.
Like if you,
you really,
you really like we have in a
conversation about health.
No,
I mean I'm just checking my t levels,
bro.
I know,
It's all connected.
What I'm saying is that I guarantee you
if you just changed your diet,
it would have a significant effect on
that just changed your diet.
I'm going to go to,
I'm going to do this new thing.
If you want to do it with me all through
December,
discipline,
this is what I'm gonna do.
I'm going to work out five days a week
at least.
Minimum.
I owe five days a week.
No bread,
no wheat,
no pasta,
no sugar.
All month.
Two drinks a week.
Geez,
that's it.
Okay.
So if you go out,
have a drink wine,
you get one more of those in a week.
So what are you going to eat?
Mostly just stake healthy food,
man.
I watched another week document or on
the plane,
shit,
my fucking pants.
I was terrified.
It was talking about the stuff that's in
roundup and how it's only supposed to
affect bacteria and they're the
scientists in this documentary like,
yeah,
but you have bacteria in your gut.
Like they're not taking that into
consideration.
They're not taking into consideration
gut flora.
And they were talking about how many
people are having issues because they're
eating bread that has pesticides on.
I'm like,
okay,
is this like some pseudoscience shit?
Is this some nonsense?
Like I got to get to it and eventually I
will,
but I can't imagine that stuff that
kills bacteria would be good for you.
I just can't imagine.
I don't know how much of that you would
actually wind up having in your body,
but how the fuck could that be good for
you?
Like all that roundup that's,
that should scare the fuck out of you.
What is going on there?
Man,
you know,
I,
we sure we share.
That's okay.
For you,
like one of those things,
there's a certain amount that's
allowable per probably,
but who set that standard and is that
standard been updated based on what you
know,
like there's too much money involved in
all this stuff.
You have to realize like anything that's
going to slow down the money when it
comes to in his old bro,
you couldn't talk and conspiracies.
But no,
like for real,
this is important when it comes to
environmental regulations.
If you look at the fight,
here's a Ryko super good point.
When it comes to this,
if you look at the fight when it comes
to environmental regulations,
who the fuck would be arguing against
preserving the environment to stop,
stop and think about how crazy these
conversations have to be where someone
saying,
Hey,
no,
you can't dig that oil well right next
to this river because it'll kill
everything in the river.
You fucking cunts.
And the people still wind up doing it
somehow.
Like how it,
how is that conversation even taking
place that we're,
we're in,
we're getting involved in doing things
that we know for sure is going to have
some consequence and we're willing to
accept a certain amount of it.
Some consequence on the natural world
around it might,
you might just the keystone pipeline,
just,
just the other day release 200,000
gallons of oil a little bit.
Just a little bit.
Whoops.
House bill.
Want to fix?
This is what we're trying to fix this
thing.
Whoa.
Like we should be like before we agree
to anything,
right?
I guess,
I guess there's gotta be some trade off,
right?
If you want to do a big city and you
want to have all this power,
like there's gotta be some sort of
environmental consequences at this stage
of the life.
Is that at this stage of,
of people like the way we're running
things and has elan musk can make us
those big ass batteries everywhere.
It's solar power collectors,
man.
Like,
like lh.
Every building should be required to
have solar collectors on them in la.
No Shit.
And it's not that crazy expensive,
like it's not that you could do it
yourself on Amazon prime,
prime dropping,
that's for sure.
It's dropping.
You know,
they make some things where you can like
charge your phone.
Like they make these a solar panels.
Like you could sit them out on your
patio.
It collects a electricity enough to you
take it with you the next day.
You could charge your phone with it,
you charge your laptop with it.
They like backpacks that have solar on
it.
She got to be like,
why the sunniest places should have be
required to do shit like that.
You know,
in the windiest places should have
windmills.
And what I've read is,
the only issue on any of this stuff is
where are the minerals coming from to
make these magnets?
You know,
there's things called conflict minerals.
There's minerals that are,
you know,
taken out of the ground in the Congo by
slaves.
You know,
there's little children working in these
camps that they've documented polling,
I think it's called [inaudible] Tan,
that's the name of it.
Out of the mountains and stuff.
They used to make cell phones.
It's very depressing and I don't know if
they still do it there like that
anymore.
I don't know if since uh,
it's been exposed,
it's had any sort of an impact on how
they do it.
But um,
Shane Smith was the first person that
talked to us about it and I remember
talking to him about it going,
Whoa,
wait a minute.
Like stop and think about like what a
cell phone is like your flip that bitch
overseen.
I have to stare at your notifications.
Everybody so scarce,
not be connected,
but you know,
he,
if you just think about the,
the pinnacle of like what we use as far
as like technology is like one of those
things,
right?
And if you take that,
which is like the most pervasive
technology,
the most advanced aspect of our society,
right?
The Internet in a phone that takes
pictures and you can ironically connect
that all the way back to a child slave
that's digging rocks out of the ground
with a stick.
Whoa,
that's dark.
I used to do it as a kid.
It was fun.
You've mined minerals.
I mean,
I would just take it out of the Congo
that malaria is digging in my backyard,
get rocks.
I collected rocks,
polished him.
It was fine.
I love doing that.
Yeah.
I met a dude once who pan for gold.
We were coming across the country and
uh,
I met a dude who was a legitimate
prospector and he was not making a ton
of money,
but he had like this idea that he could
at any day like go in one of these
rivers and pull out some serious gold.
It happens.
It does happen,
especially like in Alaska.
There's those TV shows where it's in
Alaska where there's these guys go and
they,
they get a certain amount of gold out of
the ground every day and sometimes they
hit good pots and they can really,
really collect and stack them up.
But this dude was just like,
and that brought him some shit that I
thought it was gold and like,
dude,
I found some gold.
He's like,
no,
no.
That's pyrite.
That's fool's gold.
And I started thinking about,
it was like,
well,
why is gold worth anything?
I come,
this pretty stuff was not as much as
that pretty stuff.
Like what the fuck is fool's gold might
be worth more than gold.
One some day we will like you fools.
It was right there in front of your eyes
the entire time.
Natalie,
what is fool's gold made out of?
Fool's gold looks pretty dope.
I think I should have some shit made out
of fool's gold since I'm a fool.
That's good move.
We should make it happen Bro.
How dope would it be to have a fool's
gold watch movement?
Get on that shit.
Rolex with pass.
Imagine a dope ass fools gold chain.
Why not?
It's pretty like,
it's weird how like some shit is like
worth a lot of money that's pretty and
some shit like we don't give a fuck
about rubies.
The only thing that's coming up as the
Matthew mcconaughey movie called fools
gold,
it's him and the girl on a bottle of
wine on the page and there's a lot of
singing.
Wait,
this flows go to actually exist or is
this something we've always thought it
was you described.
That's
beautiful.
And the watch that he's wearing,
his keeps popping up
and they both have their crotches
leaning towards each other.
They do.
They do look at the shadow works.
They're like moving in on the deep dick
and right there.
Just real close
actually vaguely remember that he just
like a pirate treasure hunter I think.
Have you ever seen anybody do that or
heard of people that do that?
They like find a place and they can't
tell anybody about it cause they know
there's probably like $2 million worth
of shit down there and they got to be
careful because those are real kill him.
Oh yeah.
That shit is real.
Yeah.
There's a whole industry of that and
there's people that finance these guys.
See there's the mad men that know where
the fuck and mad women's are and non
binary folk that know where the treasure
might be.
And then there's the people that need to
finance that bitch and usually they make
some sort of a split.
Like the guy's like,
hey,
I'll invest and people have invested
hundreds of millions of dollars and come
up with Zilch and they just think around
the corner,
around the corner.
It's got to be my pot of gold,
a Roman ship that crashed.
Just fill to the fucking brim.
Those greedy cons,
these to bring so much gold with them
that it killed their boat,
poison them from the inside.
Imagine that he just got hundreds and
hundreds of pounds of gold.
There's another movie,
he an acts that came out last year
that's sort of about it to where he goes
to somewhere like Thailand and they're
like,
they know the spot where they're
prospectors are going to like dig all
the gold out of the out of the mountains
and demanding thing,
but it's not a in the ocean.
Pretty Dope wasn't as good.
You know what was good
that I liked a lot of people did not
like the dark tower.
Oh yeah,
it's not good.
Right?
That Idris Elba Guy,
he could sell me anything.
I'm buying it.
He's,
he's like,
he's a guy that's like you believe is
like a legit Badass.
But also can act like the,
like I believed him in this movie.
He was a wacky movie.
It's like very wacky.
It's always whacking.
When you have a Stephen King book,
he tried to make a movie out of it.
So you have a British accent?
No,
not quite,
but he has like some sort of a noble
accent like the way talks,
you know like I do not aim with my hand
to aim with your hand,
just to forget the face of your father.
That kind of shit.
You know?
It was like intense,
weird world that they live in,
in this movie.
It's very strange.
But I enjoy the shit out of it.
You know?
Cause you,
when you watch a movie that's a Stephen
King book,
you got to realize they have to
abbreviate the fuck out of this.
Like this is a complex story that gets
woven into all these different places
and you've got to condense that to an
hour and a half to make it palatable for
movie.
It just use,
it was very hard to do.
Like I those,
it's almost like game of thrones have
made movies obsolete.
It's like movies or like clunky.
They're like cds,
like why Karen had cds do you don't have
a phone?
Like who are you?
I I think the same way about game of
thrones.
I can't get into it.
I'm like,
God damn.
I'd rather watch.
Fuck you.
Fuck you man.
I heard that.
The punisher,
the Guy John Byrne,
dawn,
I said his last name,
he said that it gets a 13 episode movie.
I got 13 hour movie.
It's how it's supposed to be watched or
sorta.
That makes sense.
That guy's a good fucking actor.
That guy was great in the walking dead.
He was fucking great.
As the best friend wants to fuck the
wife and then turns into a Zombie.
She blow.
Are you still watching that?
No.
I gave up man.
I gave up.
No.
I read people getting mad about
episodes.
I'm like,
no,
no.
What shows are you watching right now?
Like what's some,
what's some shows like you would never
think like just like a reality show or
like,
I don't watch anything like that,
but I do watch ozark.
That's,
that's the shit.
That's a,
that Netflix show,
ozarks or Ozar goes dark,
just hose artist.
Um,
that's awesome.
Which then stranger things,
Ozark is a like,
I don't want to give too much of it
away,
but it's Jason Bateman and it's this,
it's,
it's like a,
it's like a drama,
but like,
uh,
based on like financial shit,
that's all I want to give away.
I don't want to give away anything,
but it's fucking crazy good.
It's really good and it's fucking wild
man.
Like wild shit happens in this show.
And you're like,
what the fuck?
I don't want to give away too much of
it,
but it's about money laundering and the
guy's like a legit financier financier
and he gets himself in a bad situation.
It's fucking good show man.
And that show got me.
I watch like the last five episodes all
in a row.
That's a good fucking show.
Fast.
Is that one of those that polian faster?
You have to give it some time.
Um,
you know what man,
it got me like five minutes in.
I don't want to say how this episode
first episode right away you go,
what?
Oh my God.
Oh Shit.
I mean,
they just,
they start off like a Quentin Tarantino
movie.
I mean,
it's guns blazing.
I don't want to say,
I don't want to say too much.
I'm gonna stop right there.
I'm gonna stop right there because it's
good.
Um,
stranger things,
stranger things is fucking awesome.
I love the son of a bitch.
I should love that.
That shows you got to go to a doctor.
It's too cheesy for me.
I don't know.
It's supposed to be cheesy.
I know,
but it's like they're just copying
everything I love and making and making
it better and making it better.
Okay.
You know,
Jesus.
I love it.
It's great.
What do you like?
Uh,
like stupid shit.
Like fixer upper.
What's that?
It's where they buy these houses and
that in Waco,
Texas for like $50,000 and they spend
$100,000 and they make it like this huge
mansion and it's cute.
I like fixer upper shows.
Those are,
you don't like stuff like that?
No,
I do.
I'd like those.
There's something satisfying about
those.
Yeah.
Like Adam Carolla show was good.
Satisfying.
Well,
you would bus people but then they'd fix
it.
He'd bust people that are like shitty
carpenters.
They were really bad contractors are
doing terrible jobs on people's houses.
That's a cool show too.
I always,
when I was a kid I always watched it,
this old house with Vila and all that
shit.
It's like,
I prefer the positive shows though,
man.
I don't want to watch all these
contractors that are like ripping people
off and had a chef Gordon Ramsay.
Shit you don't like separate and I love
that motherfucker.
I do.
He gets very upset about food.
But I think that this,
um,
the what the style of show that I like
is when they take a house and then they
redo it.
Right.
Those are the,
those are my favorite ones.
Yeah.
This show is really cool because it's a
husband and wife and she's just like a
bad ass designer.
Like she,
she'll take it like just her paint style
and,
and like how she makes this stuff is
very,
very cool.
And so the these houses and makes you
depressed living at in La when you're
like I can't buy a house,
$50,000 anywhere in Los Angeles at all.
No.
Right.
So it's,
it's amazing to see that exists.
If you want to live in the pile spaces
expensive cause there's not as much of
it.
That's the craziest thing is New York
City,
you know New York City,
they have apartments that are $20
million and it's an apartment.
You're like,
wait a minute,
it sounded apartment,
apartment.
No,
it's an apartment.
Even apartment.
You have a great view.
It's a great view but it's a fucking
apartment and it cost $20 million.
You're like,
wait a minute.
How many people are in the building with
me?
Thousands.
No,
really?
Yes.
You're on the top floor.
There's thousands of people and you're
all in a giant metal and concrete box.
That'd be 20 million police.
Like why in the fuck are you talking
about who wants to live like that?
If you ever like a pet,
is it like 1.2 million a month or a pet
you nail?
You have to pay extra because you
haven't done much.
I think you might have exaggerated.
No.
I think if you're buying it,
you own it,
but if you're renting it,
I bet there's a lot of places that won't
want to rent if you have a dog because
the dog wants a fucking things up,
you know,
dogs will we bite things and shit on
places and Piss on things.
We're not supposed to dealing with that
now it can happen.
Yeah,
but I just,
it's hard to imagine that that's the
right way to live.
I bet it's exciting as fuck.
I bet.
Living in a giant apartment in New York
City and deep and everywhere you go,
there's just overwhelmed by giant
numbers of people.
It must be exciting as fuck.
It's really interesting.
It's like you're in the middle of the
high line,
but I just don't think that leaves you a
lot of time for quiet and reflection.
I mean,
you can force yourself into a room and
shut the door,
but I think this is just a theory,
but I really think we need a certain
amount of actual space between each
other.
To relax.
Absolutely.
This is just my feeling.
I feel like if I go over someone's
house,
they live in the country and I go sit
out on their porch.
It's like,
why don't I live like us?
How can we all live like this?
So this is how you're supposed to live.
Like this feels great.
Like you go,
you look,
you see fucking rolling hills.
You see birds and shit.
Like this feels great.
Like you see the trees see water
dripping off of him and the sunlight's
peeking through the leaves and you go,
God,
this feels so good.
Like,
why don't I see this all the time
instead of fuck you.
Fuck
you,
go back to you fucking country queer.
You know,
uh,
the
fucking smoke and farts and cigarettes
and people smell like truecar.
Ah,
ah.
What have we done?
Pissing in the streets?
Garbage bags piled up,
ripped at the bottom.
Nobody cares.
Guy Picks it up.
Some of it falls out.
They drive on fuck Bram Bram or
just sitting,
chilling.
Just sit in on some soft grass.
You back against the tree just sitting
there.
It feels better than on some stupid ass
fucking park bench watching some wine.
No heat zone shit.
Right.
I did not understand how people do it.
Like
he loves it.
He loves it.
Oh,
you talked to Ariba,
New York City.
I love it.
It's the best.
It's the most to grover.
I'm living there for toy dog.
Yeah,
definitely.
Fuck the winter though.
Who Kick?
He's the best.
He bails every winter.
Fuck.
Que New York.
I'll see you dummies later.
He comes La.
He lives here for three months.
Then it goes back.
It's awesome.
It's fucking funny shit man.
That's the way to do it.
It's a funny way to do it.
I mean,
I think he's going to do somewhere to
time,
but that went to Tom.
Did Dunkin in salaries you back?
Yes,
he's back.
He's back.
We had him for a little while and we
lost him.
Now he's back.
He's coming in.
We're doing a shrimp parade.
Uh,
Christopher Ryan,
him and me.
Yeah.
I knew Duncan would be back,
you know.
But uh,
just like that winter is a different
thing,
man.
You,
you're either used to it or you're not,
and if you're not,
you better change.
You gotta change your expectations for,
for your,
the way you interface with the world.
Because if you're not wearing a certain
amount of clothing,
you're going to fucking die.
Okay?
Get your kids bundling mob.
No,
you can't wear sneakers.
you have to wear socks.
Okay.
Fucking zero out.
Zero and the streets are all covered
with black guys,
so we can't walk very fast and cars are
going to be sliding the area.
They can't stop.
Bang.
You get
drown like bowling balls.
That's real shit.
That's real winter stuff like you,
you tried shoveling your way out of your
apartment building and you're like,
wait a minute.
What?
What the fuck?
You can't drive anywhere.
Stones stacked up on the sides.
There's nowhere to put it.
Like you better be ready for this.
You're feet are cold.
Oh,
okay.
Want to go back?
Who's cool book?
Good move.
Never again.
I'll tell you what,
dude.
I liked it.
I liked it when I go into snow now too.
Like one of the things I like,
I don't even really like skiing that
much,
but I like being in the snow.
So what I like,
I like,
I like this feeling like,
hey,
we barely got this one under control by
early.
Like you can go out,
but you gotta be wearing down and shit
all bundled up.
You got to have things over your little
fucking bully,
bullshit,
fleshy digits,
these little soft bitch ass hands of
yours,
his,
those things break off.
They freeze,
they freeze and they turned black and
snap off your feet.
If you,
if you keep your feet too cold,
your feet,
you lose your feet.
They hack your toes off and shit.
He gets frostbite.
That's real.
People lose toes cause ears.
Oh yeah.
Fuck yeah.
Frostbites no joke man.
Frostbite kills your skin.
Like that's a wrap.
It's over.
You're like,
you want gang green?
No,
we gotta chop this piece off.
This piece is done.
That happens to people.
That doesn't happen out here
except for in a cryo chamber or whatever
and that's only one girl never,
and she fell asleep.
That was a very unfortunate story.
She was apparently working there and she
did
to herself.
She looked,
she set the machine up for herself alone
and uh,
she was too short and the nitrogen got
into her lungs.
She's like breathing it in.
She wasn't breathing in air and she
blacked out.
Horrible,
horrible,
horrible story.
Ooh,
just hearing it makes your fucking whole
body clench up.
Like,
Ooh,
what a way to die.
That's so crazy.
Frozen to death at a cryo chamber.
Have you seen this map going around?
That is,
there's this little county right here is
Los Angeles.
Oh,
there's more people in this county then
these other 41 states together.
Not combined,
but each of them,
none of them are,
have,
are more populous than this little tiny
guy.
That's craziness.
I think that's only with the 10 million,
uh,
official population counts.
Yeah.
We're a mad Hubba people sun.
It's so crazy.
The 526 square miles,
which isn't even that big.
I feel like,
I mean it looks big,
but we keep talking.
Where are we going?
Where do we go?
What if we're going to bust a move.
Oh,
do I say Seattle still need good
internet?
Yeah.
So now it might be the spot.
You know why?
Cause you get like a little bit of
weather.
You Go,
hey bitch,
listen.
You better appreciate June.
Okay.
You better appreciate July because
November is going to roll around just
like it did last year and everyone's
going to be depressed.
Okay.
I appreciate it.
So if you go out in Seattle in like
August people,
what about Oregon?
Cause it's in between the,
the mother hubs of Google and Amazon are
bad spot right between them.
I think the move is Eugene.
We move in next to Dan Carlin and
Cameron Hanes.
Climb that mountain,
climb that mountain,
all Santa Barbara,
my bus spot and my butt's and that's a
good guy.
That's a good God damn spot.
It's like la light and has good wine and
places to go.
Yeah.
Nice people.
I like Santa Barbara to chill beach to
you.
Go to that beach people.
Super friendly.
Cute Zoo.
Oh damn man,
that's a good spot.
Santa Barbara might be the perfect spot.
It's a good spot.
Shit,
I shouldn't have told everybody you're
going to run out there
and Barbara Bro.
And they promise Seattle is the,
you know like when you,
we're from Ohio where it's gray sky
every day and Seattle,
I think it's going to be kind of like
that.
I think there's way too many gray skies.
Here's the thing though,
are you willing to trade some grace guys
for cooler people?
The thing about it,
and I'm not saying everybody in Seattle
is cooler than everybody in La.
I love people in La.
I'm not saying that,
but you're getting a kind of,
this is just my opinion,
and this might not be right,
but I have a feeling that you have,
you develop more character in an
environment where your comfort is
tested.
I think if you live in a cold
environment where it's cold in the
winter,
if you live in,
where would it really rains and you get
soaked and you,
you hear the thunder outside.
The [inaudible] is a humbling to that
experience that people that live in la
just don't fucking get.
And it's one of the reasons why people
in a lot of these other states get
annoyed at some of the attitudes that
people in La have.
It's because you were not experiencing
anything other than traffic.
Like these people get snowed on every
year.
Every year they're digging themselves
out.
We're like,
yeah,
well what the fuck,
man?
I'm stuck in traffic,
man.
Like she don't have any constantly.
It's one day it got too hot and you had
to turn the fan on.
Ooh,
you're going to be okay.
You're going to be okay.
Just drink water and go buy ice at the
store like you're going to live.
Even if it sucks,
you're gonna sweat a lot.
Drink a lot of water.
You're going to live.
It's 110 stay inside.
Stay in the shade.
You're going to live.
It's going to suck,
but you're going to live.
You might not live if you're living in
Chicago and you can't,
and your old lady and your power goes
out and you're stuck in your house.
What's that?
Traffic,
but that traffic.
Do you see the traffic last night of
everyone coming home?
It was just as bad.
Look at that.
That's insane.
Yeah.
It's a video and it says Thanksgiving
traffic,
Los Angeles,
four or five freeway at a complete
standstill and it is fucking miles.
I mean miles and miles and miles of
people that look at the going five miles
an hour in either direction
and when Satan is red because of the
rear lights and the other one's white
because of the headline.
That's crazy.
Videos.
Crazy.
Fuck this place.
We got to go.
Where do I go?
I was just telling me when I'm weird.
We go,
here's the thing,
where do we go?
I'm up for Seattle or Santa Barbara.
Maybe we should go to Arizona.
No,
I would go right next to where the walls
being built.
That'd be a party.
I know it doesn't,
it's still like we saw the sunny days in
Denver.
[inaudible] get cold.
They're like zero or is it just,
yeah,
definitely.
Can I think about Denver's,
it's Super Fun.
Flexible.
Denver will go to zero.
You get nine degrees for a few days and
then there'll be 60 it's weird.
It's weird because you're like way up
high.
You know,
you're,
you're literally at a mile high.
I think Denver is 5,000 feet above sea
level.
5,500 it's exactly a mile.
Yeah.
So that's,
it's a,
it's a very high city when,
when you're talking about a lot of other
words too.
It's a very interesting place man.
It's a,
it's a different spot cause like Denver,
either they're in this weird like
combination world,
right?
This is the way I put Denver.
Like you have a city that's like a real
city.
You have the comedy works.
It's one of the best comedy clubs in the
world.
They have to,
comedy works there.
I think they have an Improv there too.
Don't they have a Denver Improv?
I don't know.
I've never heard of I improv everywhere.
Those fuckers,
they're out there.
They're constantly bringing,
bringing the funny to the people.
Yeah.
They,
they're everywhere.
The end probes are everywhere.
Right?
But Denver has like everything that it
has restaurants,
it has like a real urban life.
It's a real cities,
real buildings and shit.
And then on top of that,
you're right next to the God damn rocket
mountains.
Like you look out the window,
like we were just there the other day.
Me and Tony did a Gig at the Belko and
we were driving home.
I was like,
Dude,
look at that.
That's right there.
That's the rocky mountains.
It's right there.
Like these fucking people are staring at
the continental divide.
I mean,
they're just looking at the rocky
mountains.
You could just go,
you could drive up to the top of the
hills like uh,
up near Nederland and shit like that and
see these like quaint towns.
It's still exists on dirt roads into the
woods.
You're like,
Whoa,
oh,
I'd probably did Denver.
That would be the only place that had
snow I would move to.
That's the spot.
I think Denver's a spot.
It's just seattle.
My go.
My go with a good quake.
Yeah.
Good and quick volcano mount.
The volcano could blow and if Mount
Saint Helens volcano could blow tsunami.
There was some tsunami shit about
Seattle that was in the newspaper for
years ago that was actually causing a
drop in real estate in Seattle.
Cause people were like,
wait,
what?
Like they were talking about how someday
the next hundred years a giant
earthquake and tsunami is going to level
Seattle.
And what,
you can't just say that I'm trying to
sell my house,
the disaster waiting to happen at the
northwest.
Huh.
See if you can find the article.
Like the article was something about con
dammit.
If I can remember,
uh,
earthquake,
earthquake in soon.
What does it look?
Natural disaster danger zone.
I don't think so.
Experts,
they've uh,
on the really big one,
here's what will actually happen.
That might be it anyway,
point being scared the fuck out of
everybody because it was one of those
stories that was kind of like one person
reported on it and then it went around,
you know,
you know those like you get them on dig
or something like that and you and then
you go to twitter,
someone will have,
it will be linked to another website.
You can go and check and be like,
Whoa,
whoa.
Is this really happening?
Seattle go on under what the fuck?
I'm like,
out of nowhere.
But uh,
in my,
we might lose Seattle.
So let's,
let's think,
get off the list.
How much are you scared of bears,
right?
Toronto.
See if you're not scared of bears,
the move is Montana.
Montana is the move.
You know why?
Cause Montana's like Denver.
Well with less people,
like you got an airport.
If you're willing to give up a day,
you've got an airport you can get out.
Okay.
You got to give up an extra day though
for travel.
Cause you've got to get out and fly
somewhere and then from there you fly
out.
And so like the odds are you doing a
show that night?
You can really probably couldn't do it.
You'd probably have to leave Thursday
for a Friday night show.
What did you get back the same day?
Same weather.
Yeah,
but bears like the big kind of now I
kind of knew people,
grizzly bears for cool people.
What do you do?
He started fly fishing camp.
Why are you laughing?
Why is that the first
cars fly fishing the awesome and you
could do it there.
It's a great place.
I mean,
look,
I'm in at night like after you set up
and you put a gun right by your bed in
case the wolves come cause they're
wolves to just,
whoa.
Did you see the rocks in the movie that
has the 34?
Yes.
That's perfect movie for him.
I'm very excited to see it.
Did you see his new Tattoo Nikko
Hurtado?
I made this fucking dope like bull
skull.
He used to have that bull on his arm and
he updated it with this like insane bull
skull that uh,
um,
Nikki Hurtado made here.
It make that larger so we could see.
Wow,
look at that.
Sweet.
That is insane.
Tattoo man.
I mean,
and the other,
the old tattoos still in it.
See it how the old tattoo is like the
cracks now.
That's so cool.
Yeah.
He made the old tattoo like a part of
the new tattoo.
I mean it is fucking dope and it doesn't
like you have to look at it to know the
old tattoo is in there cause he's turned
it into these cracks in the bones of
these,
the bison skull.
Fuck man.
It's awesome.
Or The bull,
Scott,
whatever it is.
That guy's a bad motherfucker.
You were seen his dad tunes.
Yeah.
Pull up some of his dad to is go to his
instagram page.
His fucking tattoo work is amazing.
Amazing.
He does all kinds of weird shit and a
lot of photographic stuff where you
don't,
he'll have like a photograph of,
you know Elvira's I'm shit.
And it'll just like,
perfect.
I don't know why I said Elvira,
go to Nikko.
Hurtado has a page.
Oh,
but go to his page.
As I said,
I said,
Nikki,
it's Nico.
Sorry.
Nico.
Are you done with tattoos?
You're going?
Nope.
We're back.
Yeah.
I'm going to do a tramp stamp.
I'm gonna have her on my back.
The game of thrones.
Lady,
Queen of Dragons,
mother of dragons.
Oh my God.
How dope is his artwork though?
It's,
wait,
look at that.
It's dude his,
his artworks and saying,
where's he from?
What?
He's a California guy.
Look at the lips on that thing.
Oh my gosh.
It's crazy.
It's just crazy.
What does that woman's supposed to be?
She had a demon or something.
He's got a skull.
Wow.
It's amazing when you zoom in on it and
see how,
how good the details are,
these incredible style.
But um,
yeah,
I mean there's so many really good
tattoo artists now.
I mean,
this is a weird time for the art form
because it's,
for whatever reason,
I guess probably a lot of those tattoo
shows in specific,
they,
they made,
it seems like more people understand it
more as an art form,
you know,
like give more like legit worldclass
artists worldclass word way to put it.
But legit,
talented,
super talented artists that decided to
become tattoo artists,
you know.
See this thing.
What is it,
temporary tattoo printer on your arm
machine?
I mean,
not,
not to think that,
I don't know if that lasts as long as
like a temporary tattoo,
which isn't very long at all.
But,
um,
at full color and probably just works
off a jpeg or something.
So you could try out then.
How long does it last for?
I don't know.
I was guessing as long as the temporary
tattoo,
but I feel like it's a little bit
longer.
It's like a stamp that says,
they might say,
okay,
better
what?
Design your own tattoo on the APP.
Oh Man.
We're getting little kids
this indoctrination.
They're trying to get these kids to
accept the numbers when they come and
collect the all for camps.
God,
what was he saying the other day about
robots?
It was that what it was you like said
something like you tweeted him back like
something like lol.
What?
Glitchy.
Yeah.
What was that?
I love that guy.
But sometimes you say shit that I just
go,
what?
He needs someone like me next to you all
the time.
That's what Alex Jones needs.
He just needs me to go,
hey man,
what?
Stop.
Stop,
stop,
stop.
That might not be it.
Some people need a rudder.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
And by the way,
if I'm your rudder,
you've got a serious fucking problem.
You got a serious fucking problem.
I was hoping that flat earth or what's
going to like the rock.
I was waiting,
I was so excited for this.
He's done it before.
He shot himself like 160 miles into
space or some shit.
Not really.
No,
he did.
I think he did shoot himself like 1.6
miles into the air.
Something ridiculous in the past and he
recovered.
Took him like several days to recover
from the g forces.
I do believe that this is something that
was in the article.
It might be something he said.
He might just be crazy.
Yeah.
He's trying to be like evil knievel.
He was trying to do a bunch of different
things and he jumped onto the flat earth
thing about a year ago to gain money.
So,
oh,
he's trying to like jump a limo over a
boards,
some dumb shit like that.
Well no one believes it.
Come in.
How do you know?
Oh,
do yes they do.
I'm a bitch.
I read the article about it when it
first was coming out last week.
Yeah.
You know what,
I've,
I've read one of the craziest fucking
arguments.
Someone said one of the flat earth
proponents said about it,
it's,
this is going around apparently,
so forgive me,
forgive me if you've heard this,
but the idea that a ship doesn't really
disappear over the horizon do,
you can always zoom in on it if you just
have enough of a,
of a powerful lens on your camera.
So they think that that in some way is
proof that the earth is flat.
That's just proof of how far you can
see.
It's all it is.
He likes,
you don't understand like the,
the curve of the earth.
It takes forever.
It's fucking huge.
Like you're,
I get what people are doing.
Like who come if you zoom out,
you can see,
well you can't forever.
That's why he can't see Mt.
Kilimanjaro from your fucking living
room in Santa Monica.
Dip Shit.
All right.
Like it's a curve to it.
It just takes a long ass time and you
can't see the boat long before it goes
over the curb because unless you're
talking about a giant ass boat and even
a giant ass boat at 30 miles away,
which is what you still be able to see,
some of it that's too far for your eyes.
So if you zoom in with some sort of a
crazy spotting scope or something like
that,
yeah,
you'll be able to see it for a little
while and then in another couple of
hours it would be gone.
It's going to go over the topic,
but they want it to be real so bad.
They want it to be real so bad that they
come up with these things that aren't
true as examples.
Why the earth is flat and the big one
was know there's how come every photo of
the earth from space is a composite.
You didn't even bother to look into it
because that's not true.
If there's a fucking satellite that
takes a high resolution photo of the
earth,
something like every 10 minutes,
so the him Awori eight to Japanese
style.
You could go online,
you could look at the pictures.
It shows where every fucking storm cloud
is all over the country in real time.
So if there's a storm that's hitting
Cuba,
you go to that.
You look at that image from that day
where the storm's,
you'll see the fucking storm,
like it's all real.
If you don't believe that's real.
Do you believe that someone is so good
at hiding shit that they've kept all the
images of the flat earth from ever being
published,
that no one has been able to treat in
the history of people,
it's been able to travel,
pass the ice wall and to the Nether
region of hobbits and gnomes and pixies
elves.
It's just mental health.
You know,
we have a huge problem.
Lack of education,
lack of education,
and then it's also being committed to
these ideas to the point where they're a
part of you.
It's Aye.
It's idea identity,
politics.
This is what it is.
When you,
when you believe in an idea so much that
you don't,
and I've been guilty of this and I think
everybody has at one point in your life
you've been guilty of not really looking
at it for what it is,
but instead looking at it for what you
want it to be and for what you've
already committed yourself to believing
in.
That's a big part of the problem.
A big part of the problem with people is
you commit yourself to believing in
something and then when you commit
yourself to believe me,
it's something.
Anything that's contrary to that belief
gets fought viciously.
You shut it down,
you into robbed.
By all means necessary.
You mock it,
you deride it.
You don't examine it objectively.
He don't look at it objectively.
You just look for a way to shoot it
down,
look for a way to shit on it.
Look for way,
if in any fallback on the government
lies all the time.
I never believed that fall back on all
these different positions,
but at the end of the day,
okay,
if you look at it from just like,
well,
okay,
what's the most likely thing?
The most likely thing is it's round.
They figured it out.
They know it's round.
You can see it from space.
They've taken pictures of it.
People have absolutely flying in the
space station.
There's videos of the fucking the thing
landing on the sky.
People pulling people out of the water.
They they've seen,
they've gone into space.
Okay.
They've taken pictures.
This is all real.
There's satellites.
They're real.
If you get satellite radio,
it's real.
Okay.
It's really from a satellite.
When you get direct tv,
it's real.
It's in space.
It's orbiting the fucking earth.
There's flight patterns that are
carefully calculated that are going
around the earth.
Everybody would have to be lying.
Do you understand how crazy it is?
I'm with Ya on a lot of conspiracies.
I'm with you on operation northwoods.
I'm with you on the Gulf of Tonkin.
Shit.
He'd get me high enough.
I'll go area 51 on you.
I'll go.
Bob was our,
I'll go,
I'll,
I'll go deep on some what?
Who the fuck knows?
Wacky Shit.
Take it to the earth being flat and
that's when I go,
you're just chasing your tail.
You're chasing your fucking tail.
Angry little pricks.
Call me a shill.
They're just showing you around her and
she'll share it on what a perfect,
perfect advertising is.
Advertising.
Show jamie.com [inaudible] dot com give
yourself a round earth shill tee-shirt
votes and I have one done by Christmas
and they're very soft cotton.
It feels wonderful on this camp.
Yeah,
I think it's almost like a troll man.
I'm telling you.
I used to think that too.
It started out as a troll.
This is what I think happened.
I think it became an exercise in
psychology from what I've understood.
One of understood,
and I might be wrong,
but from what little I've done poking
around about this,
it seems like it's might've started on
four Chan and it might've started as a
joke that there's always been a certain
percentage of people that believed that
the world was flat.
There's always a certain percentage,
just like there's a certain percentage
of moonies.
There's a certain percentage of people
that you know are Satan,
watch Brazil.
People just,
there's wacky beliefs and people get
attached to these wacky beliefs and they
fucking clean tim,
Matt,
and to say in whatever it is,
whatever,
whatever the belief is,
there's a certain percentage of people
that have always thought the earth was
flat,
but then what I read was it someone on
four chance started trolling and that by
trolling and trying to post this fake
evidence about the world being flat,
a bunch of people bought it and they ran
with it and not only do they run with
it,
they started to ramp it up and add
things to it and flat earth theory
became a thing and these people all
decided that this was like a legitimate
pursuit.
That there is some Illuminati,
some group of Jews.
It's always Jews that are hiding all the
information that somehow or another
they've talked.
All the map makers,
all the people that work in commercial
shipping,
all the people that are flying
airplanes,
all the people that are making
satellites.
Anyone in aerospace,
all these fucking people,
all these people,
all these people are all together and
they're all lying.
Okay.
And I am.
I am too.
Or maybe just listen to this.
Maybe you're chasing you're fucking tail
and you confuse the shit out of some
people that are dumber than you because
of your inability to look at what it is
versus what you want it to be.
You heard me?
I'm not writing about everything.
Don't get me wrong.
You're fucking,
I'm right about this.
There's no fucking reason why someone
would lie about the shape of the planet.
There's no benefit in it.
There's no reason why anybody would
conceal that information.
There's no benefit.
If someone found out the earth was flat,
they would be fucking singing it from
the rooftops.
And he real scientist and he real person
has been in the space station and he
real person flying a space shuttle.
They're real.
I know you're a girl.
You don't know him.
I've met him.
I had that,
uh,
Chris Conrad Guy.
Is that his name?
Chris Hadfield.
Chris Hatfield.
I forgot his fucking name.
Commander Chris.
I blamed the weed.
Chris Hadfield.
He was wonderful.
He was in space for a long time.
It's talking about the effects of it
when he came down and how it,
how bad it fucked up his body.
That was a fascinating podcast.
I remember had,
I think I got like 40 minutes with them.
Then he had to go.
It's like one of those quick little
things and he was amazing.
You're talking to a guy,
it's been circling the fucking planet in
a metal box.
No,
let's do it real.
It's real.
No,
it is real.
This is the reason why your phone works.
Understand this.
The people,
this is what's ironic.
The people that are doubting the highest
minds and the most competent
technological innovators in the world,
like the most competent people are the
people that are involved in like
aerospace,
airplane construction,
jet pack,
construction,
cell phones,
computers.
Those are the people that are at the top
of the fucking heap and these apes that
are using these devices to say that the
world is flat.
You're doing just what a massive
disservice you're doing to the very
minds that have created the thing that
you're using to complain with this
ridiculous idea that someone's hiding
the information from all the people
because they don't want you to know that
the world is like your phone.
Man,
I get it.
I want to believe big foot's real.
I want to believe if you show me some
fucking half ass big foot footage,
I'll watch it three,
four times in a row.
I'll go one day.
Maybe,
maybe,
maybe.
Hey,
you never know.
There's a lot of parts of the world we
never go to,
and also more deep in the Congo.
I wouldn't be surprised,
right?
I want to believe,
but I'm also objective.
You gotta be both.
I know you want to believe the earth is
flat.
I'm super sorry,
but it appears to be round as fuck.
Just like every other planet we've ever
looked at.
All of them.
Imagine how crazy would be if earth was
flat.
Well,
here's the problem with this idea.
You fucking dummies.
A lot of the people behind this idea
believed that it was created by God,
like on a pizza tray.
Like this is part of a religious belief
is that God made this flat earth and the
cosmos and it's all about us.
This is part of it.
This is,
this is a connected to your group,
Julie.
You're so arrogant with your idea.
No,
I'm fucking dumb.
Okay.
But I'm smart enough to know the world
is round crazy assholes.
Have you talked about net new Trenton
neutered trouty
net new neutered and trout trout.
Yeah.
You know,
I saw mark Cuban saying positive things
about nick net neutrality and I was
really surprised,
but then I realized he's a rich old
white guy.
And if I was a rich old white guy,
be like,
listen,
we don't need regulation.
We took care of Arizona,
we clean up our own neighborhood.
He also has a lot of money.
So no matter how much it costs,
he doesn't give a shit.
You know,
there's that for sure.
But then,
um,
he was making some arguments and I'm too
fucking stupid to know what their
nineties right.
You know,
I've,
I've heard the arguments against it and
I think those make the most sense.
But apparently there's some big business
people and a lot of,
I get your hippies,
Yolo drove.
Of course there are those fucking
aerosols.
They never have enough money.
You're right,
you're right.
But also like you got to let them,
you've got to let them do their thing.
You know,
It's like I,
I don't know who's right and I would
love to hear a really educated objective
analysis on whether or not that enhances
competition or hurts it,
whether or not that's good for business
or bad for it.
Most of the stuff that I read says it's
bad for it,
but I need to look at it really closely.
It's definitely letting them censor the
internet and that's like,
like what is the exact restrictions?
Do you know?
Um,
it's,
it's up to the ISP to be too,
like,
hey,
you want this website?
We might give it to you.
They said they can start editing stuff.
Say as an example via Viacom who is
owned by Time Warner or whatever.
Cause they like something comes out
against the CEO of time warmer.
They can actually go in and edit the
Internet where it's nice.
See Right now it's free.
You can do whatever the fuck you want
it.
No one's editing it really,
you know,
unless it's like peto websites or
something like that.
Right.
But uh,
so it's going to be like in the future,
like we're China.
If they don't want you to go to my
space,
China will be like
soft dude.
I was reading about a Vietnamese blogger
today who was sentenced for seven years
in jail,
a 22 year old Vietnamese blogger.
Um,
it was in the New York Times.
he was writing about an oil spill and
they said that he was,
uh,
talking negative and you doing
propaganda against the state.
They locked them in jail for seven years
for doing journalism on an oil spill and
for pointing the blame at the government
or whoever the fuck was responsible for
the oil spill.
She's 10 years.
Did lockman dl for 10 years because
somebody wrote an article now a
different one.
That's the girl.
That's a girl.
That's another one.
She's from earlier in the year I went,
I went deep.
Dude,
there,
they're locking bloggers up over there.
Vietnam apparently they have great good
issues with like gay rights and you
know,
a lot of progressive ideas that we
subscribe to in this country,
but they do not tolerate criticism like
it's apparently in that way very
totalitarian and that if you do
criticize them in the form of like
propaganda,
like blogs against them,
they'll lock you in a fucking cage for
like a decade.
It's scary.
We've got to really appreciate,
this is one of the reasons why,
I mean,
I don't know if trump understands this.
I guess he does,
but he doesn't give a fuck.
I think his idea is like,
you're going against me fucking,
I'm going against you.
Fuck you.
CNN.
You know I get it.
But by just like completely deriding
them like that,
like you,
you run this risk of getting to a
position where there's not like this
objective powerful force that's watching
over the president and reporting on all
of his actions.
Right.
This a chart that I read today though
that was a little disturbing and it was
like a truth chart and it was like how
many times CNN has said things that were
not true?
How many times does it have to correct
itself?
How many times did they say things that
are true?
And uh,
I don't know if it's right.
I don't know if that,
that might have been some horse shit
that I read,
but if it was right,
I was like,
whoa.
Are They Brung that often?
Any News,
especially when it has breaking news
guys,
it's at least they're correcting
themselves.
Where like our president won't correct
himself in.
True.
That's good point.
Maybe,
maybe that's what they mean by being
incorrect and that like,
you know,
the latest report says,
but it,
see that's just what the latest reports
as the latest report might not be.
Correct.
But if you say the,
that's the latest report,
you're not wrong.
You just don't have the right
information.
Right.
And I think everyone knows that when
you're watching the news,
you know?
Right.
Like if something happens like some
crazy shooter type situation.
Right,
right.
It's just very dangerous when you see
the president and the free press going
after each other like that.
So he tweeted today what
he said,
we should have a contest as to which of
the networks plus CNN and not including
Fox is the most dishonest,
corrupt,
and or distorted and its political
coverage of your,
your favorite president in parentheses.
Me,
they're all bad winter to receive the
fake news trophy in all caps.
It's her fucking president.
Wow.
That's so weird.
This is so weird because here's what's
weird.
It's not weird to think this,
but to broadcast that,
to write that down and to put that on,
that's like that.
It's crazy.
That's a crazy thought.
I think I would like him so much better
if he'd never tweeted like,
like if we just had news and that's it.
Yeah,
but you're getting to see like we were
talking about this,
the stress of this thing.
I mean this is how he's always been
fires back at people when they fired
him.
That's his thing.
I mean,
should have known,
but people's for some reason expected
them to be different.
Once he got in there,
they expected,
well,
he's just doing it for now.
Just trust me.
It's going to get in there.
It's going to be super cool.
All right.
Have you tried to Bait Bait him yet?
Oh,
I don't want to get to bait him.
No,
no,
no desire.
I don't want to ever do that to anybody.
I just looked.
This is the world that I'm seeing.
You know?
I'm just,
I'm reporting on what I'm seeing.
I'm a reporter.
I'm like a journalist.
That's what I'm seeing.
I'm seeing a bunch of like whether
they're justified or not,
there's,
there's a bunch of this pettiness,
this all that should be avoided by
advanced human beings.
That's what's the problem is the lack of
humor to it all and the,
the angry pettiness of it all is what's
most disturbing.
Not the idea that something wrong with
this system because if that chart was
right and a wrong a lot and if they're
wrong about him,
that's there's one thing,
but the,
the way that that should be handled as
always pointing out exactly and
specifically how they were wrong,
how it could have gotten back to them.
That was the wrong information and what
they've done to correct it.
If they have it,
acknowledge it and then that's it.
Like that's,
that's what should be done when you're
in that position,
when you're just a regular dude and you
want to just go on twitter and talk some
crazy shit and you know,
say the sooner is fucking fake news.
It feels like some firefighters
somewhere.
I don't think she'd be fired.
If you say that,
like I don't care that you can say that.
Right.
It doesn't bother me when you're the
president,
you got to go,
come on man.
You definitely are.
You're setting an example like is as
weird as that seems to say to someone
that like this is a part of the job.
You have to set a good example.
You can't,
you're setting the tone of the country.
That's the problem.
Like I wouldn't write that.
Would you write that?
You write that to somebody's never fake
news.
Trophy exclamation points.
So come on.
I hate it.
That's crazy.
And whoever let you do that needs to get
you some mushrooms and have you seen as
boomerangs,
like a boomerang and his snapchat.
Oh,
we have snapchat.
I'm just kidding.
Imagine though,
if Tega you had,
that would be hilarious if he did.
Uh,
you know,
people get tired of all this anti trump
stuff and you know,
people get tired of just hearing the
subject.
It's almost like just,
it hurts them.
But those,
those kinds of things,
that's like fuel for the fire.
It's almost like he's doing,
he's doing the work of the people hate
him for him.
He just keeps providing more and more
ridiculous shit.
Do you think
trump is,
he get mad at him for,
do you think trump's a flat earth
earthers no.
No.
I mean some of that probably a look,
man.
I would like to know what he thinks
about Kennedy,
but he keeps releasing these documents
and I'm happy.
Um,
and some of these documents are crazy.
You know,
they've um,
there's a lot of like,
one of the ones was about Jack Ruby,
Jack Ruby saying the day that Kennedy
was going to get shot a get ready,
going to see some fireworks today.
Like what?
Like what did he really say?
Like how do I know he really said that I
want to know.
I really,
I really owe it.
But if the FBI got it from a credible
source and that they really believed
that the problem is like the people that
Jack Ruby was hanging around with some
crazy stripper is doing like some 1960s
version of speed.
Yeah.
He told me,
he told me fireworks was going to
happen.
Yeah.
And then she runs off into the fucking
forest it where the fuck knows.
Maybe check Ruby just had like a nice
party surprise party later could have
going to set off president got shot.
What would be the best evidence that you
would need right now to like know that
that was true?
That's a good question,
right,
because I've seen people argue that the
photo of Lee Harvey Oswald is convenient
photo of him in the backyard with a
rifle in one hand,
a newspaper and the other hand that is
photo shopped,
not photoshop,
but photo edited is,
I don't know if it is,
I don't know if it is.
I don't know if it's been proven that it
is,
but I know that that's a common
statement and then if people have
broken,
they've done some analysis on the
photograph and I do not know enough
about photography to know whether or not
they're right.
The shadows are all off.
I think that they found out that they,
the magazine did it too for some reason,
like at the magazine did it not like the
government or anything.
Maybe I remember it being a
controversial photo,
but then I remember someone saying
recently that they believe it was not
faked and that there was new evidence to
indicate that it was not fixed.
It's just the problem with being like a
surface reader.
Yes.
The one in the far left.
Yeah.
That's a Dallas police reenactment.
How do you know that?
They're the exact same time?
You don't have a camera when he was come
on stupid.
You can't take a photograph as a
reenactment unless you know exactly when
he took the photograph and you have the
same clouds in the sky and shit cause
they're,
I guess they're trying to like find out
whether or not that was a real photo or
whether it was Lee Harvey Oswald's head
put on somebody else's body,
but the body matched his body go to
focusing on his face.
Don't go to this one.
There's one,
there's one that's like a better
resolution version.
Right?
You go to the one right above it
actually
without him right there.
Yeah.
That's the photo.
It looks a little off like the head
definitely looks a little weird head.
I guess the shadows is what they're
talking about.
The shadow that's coming from the bottom
of his Chin's not the same as what the
shadow is,
blah,
blah.
On this feet.
Oh no
ma'am.
I'm not smart enough to know whether or
not that's true,
but it looks okay to me,
but it's so grainy.
Let's look at that photo.
Imagine if that was,
but pictures are today.
I can,
you had to check out a girl's tinder
account.
You'd be like,
hmm,
what do you really look like this?
I've seen there's the full wine now.
Now Look,
look at his feet like zoom out of Louis
is his feet shadows.
See what we see it.
There we go.
See how the shadow is going that way on
his feet and then if you look at his
face,
the shad is like kinda going to make
that picture of the smallest.
We can get the whole picture in there.
Yeah,
something like that.
I don't think that's correct.
The thing that would make me feel like
something was weird
is just that it's so old that you
couldn't really tell whether or not
someone doctored it and they might have
had reason to doctorate.
That's it.
That's what makes me think that it might
be fucked with not the actual picture
itself.
When I'm looking at the picture itself,
I'm trying to find reasons why it was
fucked with,
you know,
but then again,
I'm losing,
I know Jack Shit,
I recreation.
Oh,
you guys
just tell you right now,
there isn't,
that guy tells boring stories.
Oh,
that was legendary.
Half beyond.
That was jock Louie.
He was depressed and he made fun of him.
Your stupid fucking buck up.
Sorry.
Sorry in advance.
I'm just joking.
I'm sure that guy has great stories,
but that those days,
man,
you'd get away with a lot of shit.
You know,
there's an interesting article that,
uh,
David,
what's his name,
David from,
from the,
he's a a conservative writer,
New York Times bestselling author.
He wrote something about it.
Shit.
I'm trying to remember what it was.
Oh,
it was Richard Nixon's letter to,
uh,
JFK,
his widow.
It's like heartfelt articulate,
interesting letter between an opponent
of John F.
Kennedy
and Richard Nixon.
I mean that,
that's who he was.
The opponent of John F.
Kennedy wasn't just Richard Nixon,
like they were running against each
other.
And so he writes this like really
heartfelt letter and it's like,
Whoa,
you read it and you'll out.
Wow.
Which it,
Nixon wasn't as stupid as people want.
Think he was.
He was very smart of course,
but just was fucked up.
I think this job just does it to
everybody.
I don't think anybody gets gets out of
this one alive.
I mean,
look at Donald Trump's hair.
It's already getting kind of white like,
yeah,
but it's all painted and who knows what
the real car that stuff is.
That's true.
It's probably all white.
He's probably just given up.
Fuck it.
Not going in today like Switzer.
Today's die day.
No,
now it says cheetos and the couch day.
Fuck you golf.
I'm going to watch Fox News and they
gonna tell me on awesome.
He just sits there stroking it,
watching Fox News.
Fox News loves him.
It's interesting to see white one one
network just going full gung Ho we're
going to go trump all the way.
And I supposedly,
that's why he's getting involved
with that merger of Time Warner or
whatever to get rid of CNN or something.
So,
so god,
that's crazy if that really happens.
Yeah,
that's the idea,
right?
Like Time Magazine's being bought out a
t and t is trying to buy time Warner,
the whole company or something.
Dude,
these gigantic companies.
See the thing is,
I don't know shit about this,
um,
net neutrality thing.
I don't,
I need to know more about it because I
need to know if in some way,
here's the real scary thing that
everyone who owns a giant company would
be able to control their own internet.
Like you would have like a network,
like you would be on,
you'd be on the verizon Internet thing
and he'd be on comcast like,
oh,
you're on comcast.
Ah,
you can't go to my website,
Shit.
Yeah,
that's what we don't want them.
There's,
there's a,
there's an article I tweeted the other
day where on the,
I think la times or something like that
word,
somebody,
a woman who works for the FCC a row.
Like,
like,
please don't let us do this.
You know,
like,
oh,
I read that.
And there's,
there's a website you can go to where
it's automated,
where you can put in your information
and we'll write an email or a letter to
the FCC.
So I recommend doing that.
I mean there's,
there's,
I think we have like 10 days til they
vote on this.
That's what's crazy.
Is this,
this should be something cause this is a
very important issue.
This should be something that's debated
on prime time television.
Absolutely.
It needs to,
it really should be.
I mean all of these kind of really
crucial,
this is where you stop listening to me,
her shoulder memory,
all of these crucial issues,
they should all be discussed in the,
like the public forum.
They should be discussed in like the,
the center of the town.
That's what the show should be like.
What CNN and any of these shows should
be.
Part of what they should be is like a
town center where people talk about
these like super important ideas.
This is an important idea that needs to
be like they need to interrupt
television shows for this because we
might be signing off on a terrible idea
and we might be letting companies get
away with having more and more control
over us.
I don't know.
I need to go look at it.
I need to really look at it carefully,
but we all need to look at it carefully.
If this is really happening in 10 days,
the average person's not going to have
the time nor the ambition to go and
investigate this.
Yeah,
scary.
Think Jamie.
As I was looking,
there's it.
There's another thing that happened too
that they're voting on I think this
week.
Monsters,
the PR.
Another problem I have it is too,
there's five people on that panel of the
FCC board that decides these decisions.
It's usually one person that's the
flipping vote that makes it a three two
vote.
It's never like five of which one showed
up and the solid gold Bentley,
which one got out his next covered in
lipstick.
This guy,
he's the analysis,
but the FCC wants to relax when a
broadcast media as big as rules that has
to do with like a small,
like a small city having one company
owned the TV station and a newspaper in
that area,
which is like a media rights issue.
Oh.
So they want that to come back there.
They're trying to,
yeah,
stop the rule
that prevented that or like re Redo the
vote on it or whatever.
But um,
I get that rule.
But the problem is like if you're,
you want to open,
I mean it's also,
I get the idea that you should be able
to open as many companies as you want.
There should be some sort of fair
competition.
But the problem with like fair
competition in the news,
it's like in the news,
you don't always want to get the most
ratings.
Like you want to like report like an
APP,
like,
uh,
an honest account of all the issues that
are actually happening.
But you can't do that if you want to
sell ads.
You gotta he gotta be spicy.
You've got to go to that fucking fire
quick,
get to that fire.
Let's see.
Let's see the car accident.
Chase's please chase the shit.
We interrupt this basketball game to
show you a guy that's never gotten away
from the cops.
Said that's what you see,
the Oregon one.
You know what I'm talking about there.
There's one in Oregon than recently.
And it was the craziest thing ever.
He was like going through a fields,
Oklahoma to him,
Oregon told them ost data stuff.
I'm not going to,
wow.
There's a show called out.
I was gonna bring it up a second ago
called shot in the dark.
It just came on Netflix.
It's sort of like the TV show version of
the night crawl or movie.
So it's following some news crews around
Los Angeles every night while they're
going to find these like crazy news
stories.
Wow.
And they actually,
the first episode that catch a parked
car on the 10 and uh,
they're like thinking a,
it's gonna be an accident can be real
bad.
And literally like five seconds later,
boom.
Fireball guys to go save the guy pulled
him out of the burning car.
Whoa.
It was really intense.
But that's what's happening all the time
too.
And the news that they're catching and
sell.
I saw it last night when I was watching
the news popped up is another thing,
a hostage situation.
But some guy got paid probably 500
bucks.
We're going to find video of this.
It's real weird.
Do you ever see that night?
What?
What does that movie nightcrawler.
Nightcrawler's yeah,
that was a great movie man.
How dare you?
That's good guys.
All right away my movies and my past
Coco.
Have you seen coco yet?
There's Coco.
Coco is the,
um,
the new pixar movie with a,
it's all about the Mexican holiday day
of the dead,
you know,
and,
and all.
But I did see one other Mexican day of
the dead movie.
It was crazy where they went to this
other dimension.
That's Coco,
but I saw this,
this the second one.
No,
this is the first one.
You might've saw it early though.
No,
I saw it on like it on Itunes,
on Apple TV.
Oh,
there was another one that's
interesting.
There was another crazy ass movie with
day of the dead characters that I
watched recently.
A book of life.
That's it.
The book of life,
Dude.
It's fucking amazing.
You haven't seen this?
No.
Is that just like a trailer?
Animation is fucking insane.
It's so why wait,
this is it.
So there's these like wooden people and
then they,
they get somehow or another taken into
this other dimension and then this other
dimension,
it's like tron drugs.
Man did this looks like the same
characters.
If no seat.
This is like,
why is no one about this yet?
I have no idea.
This is sort of like when they did those
two,
what'd you go switching?
What does this now here's the new one.
Yeah,
but go back to that one cause it didn't
quite get totally freaky yet.
They start getting really freaky towards
the end.
Wow.
It's Guillermo del Toro.
I,
yeah.
See this is where they,
they're entering into this other
dimension and everything is like super
bizarro.
Like the people are weird.
It's really strange,
like everyone's dead.
It's so bizarre.
And that's exactly what coke has a bad,
but it's like you remember that?
And when deep impact and Armageddon came
out the same time,
it's like it like somehow or another
somebody figured out like,
Hey,
these day that dead things are dope.
Look,
there's two other ones.
That volcano movie and then like Tommy
Lee Jones was in one and then Pierce
Brosnan was in one,
but there were like two movies about
volcanoes and it came out like the same
week.
Yeah.
They always do that in la.
And one was not once next earthquake
when we,
he's like,
look at this new dimension that he
enters into.
Sam,
same shit.
This is the same shit.
It's exactly that.
That's,
I can't believe no one's talked about
this weird man.
This is
more dead people.
And the other one was more like bizarro
weird bond.
This is pretty bizarro dead people.
I mean,
look at this.
Yeah.
It's like they find that like a bugs
bunny and you know,
whoa.
We're going to have her own bunny are
bunny's name is Tim Gaffey and Donald.
Yeah.
Daffy duck and Donald Duck like,
hey,
which one was mark?
Which one is warner brothers?
Which one of those Taffy Taffy guy more
than a donald.
Donald's the Oji though.
And uh,
they were the only ones that had the
balls to have a hunter that like a bunch
of moon,
elmer fudd and then a bunch of other
mean hunters and some of their movies
like the Bambi movies,
a mean hunter.
It's a bunch of other ones.
But the uh,
elmer fudd that was like the first dumb
white God you could mock in a cartoon,
wasn't he?
No,
I think they had a lot of dumb white
people.
You can mock.
Is he the first and when we're filing
the rabbit gets away all the time.
The rabbit lake treats him like a bitch.
Like you fucking dummy.
You're never going to get me.
Like he's never threatened bugs.
Bunny's never threatened by Elmer Fudd.
He's a rabbit and somehow or another
elmer fudd is so fucking stupid in
elmer.
Fudd wants to shoot this talk and
rabbit.
He such an asshole at it.
It's wabbit season
and he's got a giant head like a baby.
Like what does that,
why does he have a baby head wait,
homer fund.
It's an enormous baby head.
I never even noticed that.
He's like a baby with a gun.
What's the other one?
That was elmer and then there was
another one that looked exactly like
elmer,
but it wasn't elmer.
Elmer and that's right.
There was another one and another guy.
There was another dude who was the other
guy.
I always thought that was strange.
Like,
yeah,
there's more than one hunter.
Right there was was the other guy.
It was like the second Mister Roper
when they changed the Darren on
bewitched.
Yeah,
they changed the husband.
The husband got crazy and he asked for
money and they're like,
mm,
Nah,
bitch.
Okay,
no,
no.
We got a new dad.
He's like,
well,
I'm the cold star of the show.
No,
no,
no.
It's I dream of Jeannie motherfucker.
Nobody cares it.
Darren is trashed house Sam.
They pulled the fucking court.
The floor dropped out.
He disappeared.
I don't think there was another hunter.
Yeah,
there was a,
it was another dude.
There's another dude,
didn't have another buddy with them.
Might be like one particular cartoon
that maybe his brother showed up for
something and they went hunting
together.
Fool's gold in the fake Elmer Bernstein
bears.
I actually,
I saw that a long time ago,
but that wouldn't freak people out.
It's just like,
it should have been a different name.
You Dummies Zam movie.
Where was it?
Or Exist?
Can exist.
What are those called when people like
collective.
Yeah.
What is that?
Emory,
you forget what it's called.
Fake collective memories.
Those are super common electronic
coupling.
Yeah.
Those are super common about the Mandela
effect.
That's it.
That's right.
Yeah.
That's simulation
shit.
Yeah.
Um,
so we were talking about this elsa gate
thing.
Yes.
This is,
this is weird.
No,
this is not a conspiracy theory,
ladies and gentlemen.
So before you go,
oh,
I can't believe in show.
Here's the morgue.
So true.
It's hard to Solon,
listen,
there's something going on where they're
making these youtube clips and they play
like,
you know,
how have you watch,
if you watch a youtube clip,
say on the brand new 2019 corvette Zr
one like I'm,
I'm a car freak.
I love watching those videos.
Like wow,
look how fast,
look at it.
Go what a beast.
And if you just let that play ill,
youtube will suggest a nother corvette
movie or video and play that and maybe a
video on a shootout between a couple of
different types of cars he would handles
better.
And then you'll just keep playing like
car videos cause it thinks you're on
that loop.
Well somewhere along the line,
if you're on a kid's loop,
you can get looped into one of these
elsa gate videos.
Now some of them,
like the one brian showing me,
he's like really shitty CGI second life.
And it's like these cartoon characters
get together and they become like
sexualized and they drink sometimes and
the babies keep getting their heads
busted open.
Like the babies fall and the beer bottle
flies through the air and hits the baby
in the head and cuts the baby's head
open and blood's all over the place and
that one happens all the time.
It repeats itself over and over and over
again.
That same scene in a bunch of different
weird cartoons with like babies and baby
animals and you know there's
anthropomorphization videos where it's
like,
you know the,
the,
the wolf has a bunch of pigs with them
and shit and the pigs get drunk.
Like that kind of shit.
But there's like hundreds and hundreds
of them and youtube is me.
They had to be alerted of this stuff.
You know,
people were watching them with their kid
and it would go on auto play and your
one year is all sudden watching a beer
bottle fly through the hair and head in
a [inaudible] rather and bash a baby on
the head and causing big Gash.
Have you seen any of those?
Yeah,
I just,
cause I used to watch the ones that you,
you know,
the second life ones where it's just
ridiculous.
Like this stuff is crazy.
It's weird.
I didn't even know about this.
They dress up in these cartoons.
They have little babies that are dressed
up like spiderman or like Elsa and like
this.
This scene keeps happening over and over
again where they have beer,
they get fucked up and then as the baby
falls,
the beer bottle bounces off his head and
shatters and lands on the ground and the
baby's bleeding.
It happens over and over again and so in
this one with the minions,
a little baby minions,
they fall,
Bam gets caught in the head.
It's the same scene.
Here's the Mickey Mouse.
One little babies get fucked up.
They fall.
Beer bottle hits the baby in the head is
another one with a little foxes.
They get fucked up.
Beer bottle hits the kid in the head.
It's always the same shit.
It's stupid.
It's not stupid.
It's weird.
It's weird because it's not.
It's not just things happen and it's,
it's the same violent scene over and
over again and the babies are the ones
that are getting brutalized in these.
They're getting hit in the head with
beer bottles,
giant Gash.
His blood.
Like what is that?
Yeah,
it's almost like that.
What's that?
Yeah,
the youtube crap or that you used to be
really popular where they would just
edit things together real fast and an
end with like ha,
like screaming.
And what was that shit called?
That was user created.
There was a bunch of people like you
could see those people doing them.
They just decided to try to talk real
fast and cut out all the breaths in
between it and slam it together.
Look,
you have no intention span whatsoever.
Now this stuff like in what we're
watching now I find,
I feel like they're all,
they're all using the same characters.
Right?
So it seems like to me it's from a
message board.
It's like when we were back in the day
on your message board and we would like
make all these videos and stuff like
that.
It seems like it's from a group of
people that all are doing it.
You know,
collectively like to me it seems like,
like you'll find like a deep four chan
thread in it or something where like,
Oh I did the baby falling video or
something.
No,
there's a bunch of different ones man.
I mean there's,
there's this was like with real people
but the ones that you're talking about
with the,
uh,
the cartoon ones,
they're being made in other countries.
They're not speaking English in any of
them.
It's all like noises and stuff and
they're generating like if their ad
friendly and some of them were approved
for ads,
they're generating a tremendous amount
of money.
You got to think about how many hits
these fucking things are getting and how
many like see if you could pull up one
and see how many millions of hits it
had.
Got It.
Yeah.
I just pulled up,
had 5 million,
5 million.
Okay,
so 5 million hits is the business.
All right?
If you've got ads on a video for little
kids,
that gets 5 million hits,
that's a business.
Now,
if you've got those things in there,
generating them by computers.
So you're making hundreds and hundreds
of them and you put them all over the
Internet and they all have 5 million
hits each.
You're talking about a substantial
amount of money that you're getting
every month and they're just making
these things.
And then the real fucked up thing.
It's like apparently there's some,
again,
I just read the beginning of this and
then never read any further into it but
read it.
Ah,
how to thread apparently where these
people were trying to decipher some of
the things that are being said in the
comments and they think that they're
using the comments as like ways we're
child trafficking.
People can communicate with Jonah.
This is like speculation,
which sounds like wow,
that seems far fetched.
But so it doesn't child trafficking
sound far fetched.
I mean,
you know it's real.
All right.
Child trafficking sounds crazy
farfetched.
Like the idea that someone's so evil
that they're selling children,
right?
It doesn't,
it doesn't it?
Yeah.
So if that is,
then why wouldn't it be that they would
communicate?
I mean,
is it more far fetched that they
communicate in code in some sort of way
in the comments?
Yeah,
because they probably wouldn't do it on
kid videos.
Would probably do it online.
Like just like any video,
like tractor.
It could be videos or something.
I think.
Yeah,
it could be.
Maybe they're not that smart.
That's where the trauma Lester's right.
But,
but also that,
um,
like these why else?
These kids are not going to make
comments.
So who's making comments on these
videos?
It to me,
again,
it seems like it's a,
it's a group of people somewhere and
it's making these now the fact that that
youtube is letting them sell it as kids,
they need to change.
Youtube needs to change how they have
kid videos.
Cat Videos should have a team of people.
You get approved then you become in for
sure two kids.
That's it.
You can't just upload anything and put
the kid to tag on it.
You should have the kid tag.
Yeah.
How kids find out about it.
You give your kid the user response when
you get your kid like the ipad and he
put it on Youtube.
Kids that should be selected videos
only.
It's been approved by eyeballs and so
on.
I should not be able to make a kid
video,
you know?
That's true.
Definitely not be able to make kid video
where a kid gets hit in the head with a
fucking
bottle right now.
If that shit was like just on like once
someone,
one of us did it and were like,
I just made all these stupid videos of
kids falling down on the ground and it
wasn't for kids.
And then you'd be like,
that's just a stupid cartoon that you
would see on like adult swim or
something like that.
Four in the morning,
right in there.
You could see something like that on
adult swim at four o'clock in the
morning,
especially the ones that I watched,
those stupid ones
that could actually be like some sort of
a,
an like some thing that,
what's that called?
What's interspliced inside of a show
where like a non sequitur video comes
in.
And what's that called?
Uh,
it's like an adult swim cartoon where
you're like,
what the commercial work commercial out
of nowhere that's just
get stuck in there where the Mickey
Mouse Daddy is drinking with the babies.
The babies fall and gets hit in the head
with a bottle.
Like what the fuck?
And then you cut to some wolf that's
telling you about the past of robot
chicken a lot just to real quick 15
second thing and be like,
what?
What's that?
What does the word interstition what
does that word?
I don't know.
There's,
I know you're talking about it's blank
interstitial,
cause that is,
uh,
that was,
matthew mcconaughey was in that too,
but he was in this movie.
He was the
dark tower movie.
Oh really?
It was.
Yeah,
he was,
he's the bad guy.
Matthew mcconaughey's bad guy.
And all I could think of that was all I
could think of was,
um,
Louis C K is bit about Mad Mike and,
uh,
Louis C.
Case bit about Matthew mcconaughey.
Do you remember it?
And he's like,
the law says you can't touch,
but I see a lot of law
burgers out here
has lilly does
brigette he talks about how he,
he was,
he loved the movie so much.
They was walking around his house saying
that thing over and over and over again.
So when I was watching this movie,
Matthew mcconaughey is the bad guy.
All I could think of is Louis C K is bit
going on things.
A lot of law burgers out here.
Match of a guy.
It's a stripper.
That's all I could think of.
That fucking happens,
man.
That happens.
Where a good comic.
We'll do a bit about something like
that.
Oh,
that subjects ruined.
He's got me every time I see Matthew
mcconaughey,
I think it was a thing is a lot of long
burgers.
Hbo Pulled All the Louis C K Shit
offline tid.
They really?
Yeah.
Okay.
That's a hard one.
That seems silly and it's still funny
comedy.
He wasn't jerking off in front of
anybody when he did the comedy.
Like just like you can't invalidate
everything everybody's ever done.
If they did something bad,
it's not good that he did it,
but it's kind of fucked up that day.
Did that even though he,
you know,
the situation of him asking permission
and him admitting it and coming out and
apologizing,
but yet didn't,
there's that,
that masterson scientologists guide that
all his shows are on there and then
there's like real,
the more people.
Do you think that those are real,
those stories are real?
I think a lot of them are real.
Yeah,
I really do.
I mean like why haven't they done
something?
If that story is real,
it seems like that one would be
something that would get a lot of
attention
hold.
It happened
yesterday and,
uh,
the,
I guess sports world and the Ohio state
world to the,
so the defensive coordinator who used to
be an nfl coach was rumored earlier
yesterday afternoon or I think maybe
even Saturday,
that he was going to be hired as the new
head coach for Tennessee's football
team.
Um,
they were going to make the announcement
yesterday evening I believe,
but at some point after the agreement
had been signed,
um,
it hit the media in Tennessee and there
was protests in front of the stadium.
All of their fans and alumni were pissed
at this is going to happen.
Someone out of that,
he was on the Penn state team,
he was one of the assistants to Jerry
Sandusky.
Ooh.
So the uh,
tying to that,
although he's already been vetted by
Ohio state,
like he's already the coach there and
Urban Meyer's team has vetted them and
backed him and all that.
So before the night was over,
they already canceled a contract and now
he's,
I think even going to sue them for money
that he was supposedly going to be owed,
cause he probably,
he could have already got rid of his
house like in that day because he was
going to leave,
you know,
so all sorts of things happened and
just,
it was like literally 24 hours or less
that close to,
he worked at Jerry Sandusky,
I don't know,
cause he was an assistant.
He was younger.
There's other,
there's a couple of other coaches on
there that claim to not know anything
too.
I believe man and sort of some other
people like Kirk Carpentry.
I started tweeting out last night that
this was a,
um,
like,
do you really think that you should do
this with no evidence?
There is no evidence in this case
apparently,
and he's lost.
He doesn't have that job opportunity now
I guess.
I think you need a real investigation
before you commit to something like
that.
And He,
I mean,
I don't know the case.
He might have not known.
It's possible that he didn't know.
But if you didn't know,
like don't you think there'd be like a
story you'd hear something melt down
over potential hiring of Greg Ciano is a
bad look for Tennessee program.
Hmm?
What's a bad look?
Hmm.
I don't know what it see.
I don't know what the fuck is going on.
If you knew that this guy knew,
then you would have this feeling like,
hey,
fuck that guy.
But if you,
if you knew that he didn't know,
you'd be furious.
He'd be like,
no,
you're,
you're labeling an innocent man and
saying he's a bad person.
Like there's needs to be an
investigation.
If there has been an investigation,
you've got to accept the results.
Otherwise you're on a witch hunt.
You got to figure out what's really
happened.
I don't know.
See,
I don't know the particulars,
but if you know the particulars,
you know,
and you,
you're,
you got to make a case for it.
It's like,
look at Al Franklin.
I like it like that.
That let a little vague picture of him
like acting like he's grabbing that
girl's boobs and then you see the,
all the stuff that comes out about her
after where it's like,
oh,
she,
she was like groping all these people
the whole time.
You know,
Leanne tweeting.
No.
Yeah.
If there was a been fake
dude,
I didn't see any of that.
There's video of apologized for what he
did though.
Like,
I mean,
what he was doing was trying to be
funny,
trying to be funny,
taking a picture and he wasn't even a,
he was a comedian bank then.
He wasn't even a state representative.
But either way,
it's like you don't do that.
That could be your mom,
that could be your sister.
She's out cold.
It's not like it's your girlfriend.
You joke around.
It's one thing that was your girlfriend.
If you girlfriends out and you take a
picture like,
and you'd be silly,
right?
She loves you.
That's your girlfriend.
She knows the joke.
It's like I've heard she takes a picture
like sit next to your Dick while you
were unconscious.
She goes like this one,
I wouldn't be upset.
Right,
right.
Um,
but she wasn't his girlfriend.
She was working,
he was working,
they're always doing this charity tour.
And she said that he tried to kiss her.
There was like,
it was more than one thing.
So he apologized for that.
And then there was the other women that
were saying that he grabbed her butt.
Well it's that dance do that.
He said that was just like,
you know when you're taking photos.
And he said,
the one girl said like,
he put his hand on my bike.
I mean,
when you're taking a photo,
you just put your arm around somebody.
Maybe a touches your,
but I be,
I be old
dudes like to grab butts too though.
It's an old dude thing.
George Bush.
George Bush,
George W.
Bush likes to take pictures of people
and a ride as they go to take the
picture.
He squeezes their ass,
but that might be like some old Texas
man.
Thanks.
Hey joke.
Plus he's almost dead.
Leave him alone.
Like people have to realize he's the
longest living president ever
at this point.
Yeah,
he's the oldest one.
Yeah.
Jimmy Carter Carter still
now he's not his old Herbert Walker.
Bush is older than Carter.
I think you right now he's the oldest
surviving president is what they say.
But Carter is the longest,
longest to go that he was president.
Yeah,
man.
He's almost dead like he's got to grab
acids.
He's going for it.
That's what's also ridiculous looking.
If you,
if you became like like a president or
something like that and then you went
through all the photos you've ever taken
with fans after a show or at shows and
stuff like that.
You can take any of those photos.
My,
Oh my God,
look,
he's making a blowjob face to a woman
under the age of 17 or so.
If you freeze every people take so many
pictures.
We're taking pictures when you're not
looking at your mouth is open.
Yeah,
but it's like,
I think that those old dudes just
grabbed acids.
I think that's what's coming out.
They just thought it was a thing.
They get away with it.
They grabbed acids when they took
pictures.
They probably grab yours do just to get
to look in your face like,
oh,
totally.
There's probably a joke.
Sports.
I don't think anyone really slaps butts
anymore.
It used to be a thing all the time or
they certainly,
they slapped butts.
There was a video that Morgan Murphy
posted and it looks like a,
I think it's on her instagram and it
looks like some dude comes from behind
or refereeing smacks his buddy in the
ass and the guy like goes,
yeah,
see if you can find it.
It's on Morgan Murphys.
Instagram from I think yesterday.
I think soccer player is constantly do
crazy shit,
like grabbing each other's dicks and
shit.
Oh Damn.
It happens in football,
but that's like in a scrum than not like
a friendly,
right.
Right,
But this is two referees.
This video is a referee doing it to
another referee.
It's hot.
This is here,
it wants this.
So this guy,
he's my off times man.
They talked to each other and watched.
The guy comes by and Oh,
the flag in the face.
Oh,
he took a fine his butt pinched.
I know.
Yeah.
That's another thing.
Barely pay attention.
Parents.
That's me hoping that it was a buck and
that's why I freaked out.
That's how I look at things.
I'm like,
just show me any reason why this is more
exciting than it really is.
Wow.
Or just seeing a guy get hit in the face
of the flag.
My brain was like,
not good enough.
Not good enough.
I've been drunk for five days.
Oh yeah.
I did vacation and uh,
just got hammered every night.
It was wonderful.
Wine.
Drunk wine.
Yeah.
Wine bonk wine just puts you out,
man.
Like,
I don't know how the fuck the barbarians
invaded countries on wine.
Just seems like they would have no
ambition.
Like wine just makes you so tired.
We're lucky they didn't know about like
whiskey,
Magid.
The barbarians had whiskey instead of
wine.
Been way bloodier
I can't,
I haven't done one in awhile.
It gives you a puts out bad morning I
think I,
yeah,
there's something
then going on right where you get like a
weird headache sometimes.
I've talked to people about that.
I never got a satisfactory explanation
that I wind up.
Are Men remembering.
Yeah,
I bet that's it.
I bet it's like eating a lot of cake.
You eat a lot of cake,
Ben.
You get that fucking feeling the next
day.
Like what did I do?
I didn't watch anything at eight all
week eight,
whatever the fuck I wanted to eat.
That's my go to vacation move now.
Yeah.
Cause then you come back,
you feel so bad that you want to like
get back on a diet.
It'd be like real cautious and that's
why I'm going to do this.
No wheat,
nope.
No Pasta,
no sugar workout.
Five days a week.
Two drinks a week.
That's it.
I've been trying to eat steak a lot.
Just just steak,
like steak kabobs.
Those aren't my thing.
Dude watches wheat documentary,
you'll throw a pizza away forever.
No more sandwiches.
Pizza,
no more burgers.
I can't wait for the meet doctor to come
on soon.
Right?
Yeah.
Yeah,
the meat down there.
Better way to describe it.
But yeah,
the carnivore,
he's a full carnivore.
That's all he does is eat meat.
He thinks he's been like this crazy
proponent of meat eating only
the has to be badgered.
Stanker you're something,
right?
Cholesterol or a site owner.
It seems like it would be
perfectly healthy though.
I just,
I dunno.
I mean,
I think one thing is like,
I would think you would need some
nutrients from vegetables,
right?
And then there's some things you can
only get from vegetables.
But then are you getting any of that
from me?
Because they eat vegetables.
Like that's the idea.
It's like lions don't really eat a lot
of salads.
They just fuck up zebras
and zebras.
They do plenty of salad eat and for the
lion and the lines are good.
You know,
they don't really have to,
uh,
eat it on their own.
If that blueberry affects the bear meat
so much that it changes the shape and
color and taste of it,
then it not all that shape.
I didn't mean that but like that
definitely,
yeah.
Changes the color and the taste of the
meat.
It would only make sense that you're
getting something from the grass when
you eat a steak,
which is why grass fed steak is better
for you,
like proven for you.
Then corn fed steak because corn is
basically sugar.
I mean well it's not good when you shit
and you see,
hey that's not even digest
it like the reason why he's he corn in
your shit cause that your body's like,
what am I doing with this?
This guy's eating plastic.
Just spit this out.
That's such a weird thing.
You're assholes.
Just like get it out,
get it out.
When I'm going to try to process it.
We're not going to break it down.
Did I tell you a long time ago,
I think I already told you this,
but back in the day when like hands
across America and all that shit we were
supposed to write in school,
like how do we help starvation and stuff
like that.
If we have any ideas.
And I wrote about how we should just
feed everyone in corn and then they
could wash it off the next day and eat
it like a few more times.
And I got in trouble for that.
Like mom had like,
brain's always been
gross.
My Mom's like had to get caught in and
it's stuff like that because of that.
And I was thinking like,
well you can eat it twice.
Like that's like make sense to me.
Like it's untouched.
Did you know that some native Americans
used to call it a second harvest and
needs to eat thrown shit.
Really?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I read that somewhere.
I think the cooked it or something.
They call it second harvest.
I mean,
you gotta be hungry as fuck.
Oh,
by the way,
the person told me,
this might've been crazy,
might've made this up.
I,
I'll remember who it was.
I'm trying to remember.
Oh,
okay.
It was one of the wardrobe ladies on
Newsradio.
She told me that.
I was like,
what did she seem pretty cool?
So I just listened to her and back then
you couldn't really look anything up.
Now I haven't looked.
Is it true?
Confirmed by urban dictionary.
But I thought,
well then texting urban dictionary is
Hashtag woke what top definition Hashtag
woke anyone could add to Irv urban
dictionary.
That doesn't mean it's real.
Native wa a method developed by native
Americans to conserve as much food as
possible during deadly winters.
The act involved sitting through,
sifting through Ugh,
feces for chunks of corn and nuts.
Sleeping Wolf,
my little bear.
Your poo is rich with the second
harvest.
Oh,
that's not real.
Yeah,
you can get very porn.
By the way,
I'm connected now to a group of all
outright furries.
I am,
um,
I'm investigating.
I'm a journalist.
I told you earlier today,
and I'm investigating outright furries
cause a white,
white people who go crazy who are,
um,
very reactionary and quick to jump the
gun and call everybody a racist.
Wrote this article about,
um,
I don't know if it was a white person
wrote it.
I just assume probably wasn't about,
um,
these Nazi furries like Neo Nazi
furries.
Well,
the absurd obscure a subculture of
furries has a problem with neonazis.
Any groups of sexual abuses.
Here's a lot of Nazis.
I mean,
cut the fucking shit.
Please.
Just please cut the shit.
Please,
please.
I can't,
I can't keep going.
It's just too crazy.
Every day it's more and more fucking
weird.
This stuff I can get.
I think this is as the same people that
watch this youtube videos or make the
youtube videos.
I think the people who make the youtube
videos,
dude,
I think it's just like they're lit.
They're in Asia or somewhere like that
and they have a script and they just
keep throwing the script over and over
and we're looking for like hidden
messages in the script.
I think the script is probably just
fucked up.
They think it's fucked up to have a
cartoon character hit himself in the
head with a bottle.
And I think you're probably right.
Like maybe these fucking child
predators,
maybe they communicate on all sorts of
different websites.
Maybe they just decide like,
hey,
let's meet on this tire forum and we'll
just say things in code and attire means
this.
I mean it wasn't that always the shit
with pizza gate.
Like they thought that they were talking
in code.
Like all the conspiracy theorists
thought that a slice of pizza meant like
a kid and the youtube one,
I mean them being there being so many of
them sort of says that there's money in
it.
They've tapped into an algorithm and
they're just beating it to death.
Yeah,
and they just have the same script and
they just do it with a computer change.
One little thing,
little thing here and there and that's
what I think it is.
I think it's not as nefarious as
everybody likes to think,
but it's really fucking weird to keep
seeing the same video playing out over
and over again with a bottle flies
through the hair and the baby gets hit
in the fucking head.
You'd floods.
I think the activity was a little weird.
Or when it's people actually people
doing it.
You can't just have a computer make it
to where people are.
God damn nuts.
They're nuts and they're out there.
I like furries.
Uh,
I th I get that.
I have a bunch of outfits that I make
videos with and stuff and that's pretty
much what that is.
That's just basically cross play.
Any kind of a roleplay.
Yeah,
they're having fun,
having fun.
They don't feel like normies.
Right.
I'll say it right.
Yeah.
And I'm sure having sex like that,
it's probably fine.
And that's Kinky.
Like,
hey,
you're dressed up as my pretty pony and
I'm spiderman.
Yeah.
Probably a lot of that.
A lot of dude on dude crime.
Other words,
these hats,
they're wearing fucking weird animal
hats and their bone in each other.
Paints.
Why not man?
But you know why?
Because this is crazy.
So why not?
Why to do it?
Why not do it?
See,
look at that.
Just like a Fox and you're fucking each
other in the Fox is fucking the chicken.
Why not?
Why?
Really?
Why not?
I just,
I don't know.
Why not?
I can't tell you why not.
Why is it okay that people were crazy
fake eyelashes and extensions in their
hair and they pumped fat into their ass
and put silicone bags and their tits?
Why is that okay,
but it's not okay to dress like a big
chicken and get fucked by a big rooster.
Why isn't it?
Why can't you pretend to be like a fox
in the hen house,
right?
Why not?
Like if as long as everybody agrees,
like do you agree to be the Fox?
Okay,
cool.
Them dog.
I'm going to be the bulldog mascot,
the big bulldog head and we're going to
bone.
They're going to make some,
some rendezvous was,
why the fuck not?
Why not?
Yeah,
I'm down for that.
They just do whatever they want.
I mean,
I dressed my grow up as a school girl.
You know she's Asian.
There you go.
Why not dress her up like a anime school
girl?
Give her a big fake head.
Where would it be?
A boner with a big fake head on big
anime eyes can actually kind of crazy
fake ponytail.
I got her,
I got her some tentacles.
The other day.
Wow.
Technical Butler.
That's the weird thing.
So tentacle Porn,
how did that ever take off member?
That was the thing when we first found
out about tentacle porn,
I remember like collectively the
Internet was like,
what?
Wait a minute.
How much of this stuff is existing?
How much?
How much is out there?
What the fuck is going on in Japan?
Tentacle Porn was a loophole for or
report insertion because she can't show
a insertion.
Yeah.
See like energy finds a way.
You have the,
it finds the weakest link and it makes
its way through.
You can't suppress it.
That's why I like what you see with
Catholic priests.
That's why you see in this.
You can't show penetration,
Huh?
Huh.
Okay.
How about crackings with a,
a dick on the end of every octopus arm
and they're banging eight different
school girls.
How about that?
Good.
Cool.
Here's the,
here's the magazine.
Thanks.
They're all school girls.
Japan is so weird,
man.
Big veiny Dick.
So it'll like ripping their lower jaw
out,
but it's just coming out of an octopus
so it's okay.
Have you seen their game show called
like slippery stairs
the other day?
I wonder what the,
like the cheating would be a,
how would you cheated?
Slippery stairs seemingly someone in
America would figure out a way to buck
the system.
Right?
I would say it would have something to
do with pulling the other guys down.
Yeah.
I don't think you can touch them though.
I don't think so.
Can you?
Yeah,
I think you can.
If you did,
I think people would just get ahead and
you would never let anybody get close to
you,
but I think the problem is for people
listening,
it's,
Oh my God,
he was there.
Oh my God.
He was there.
He took everybody out like a bowling
ball.
This is amazing.
It's amazing.
And then the other guy went down to the
guy who was ahead of them.
He got cocky and he fell all the way
back.
Yeah.
This is a great show.
That looks fun.
It looks like they should call it like
tooth,
the chipper or something like that.
Who would be a good host to this?
You know it's somebody else who'd be a
good host.
Tony Hinchcliffe be good host.
Maybe not.
I would love it.
Dude.
Japanese game show cause they,
that's just one.
Jesus Christ popular.
Perfect for it.
Yeah.
Koreans and Japanese people don't get
along.
So it'd be even better.
Yeah,
it's girl.
There'd be people mad at him.
Did you know that Koreans and Japanese
people have a sorted history?
Absolutely.
Um,
oh Jesus Christ.
Your speed skating down at like a slope.
Oh my God.
This is insane.
There's the two other sports and this
was one of them and that slippery stair
thing came out.
I was like,
this new,
this is new.
Very,
very,
this as to fall [inaudible] 13 a red
bull.
This is insane.
Oh my God.
These guys are gone.
Saw.
This is incredible.
People are hanging over the edge.
I hope people don't smack them.
What's this called?
Ice Logos.
Lizzy.
Crack crashed ice I think is what it's
called,
but it's like,
oh,
this is insane.
It's like a downhill hockey speed.
Cross x type.
I don't know.
It's real weird event.
Just a matter of time before somebody
figures something like this out,
right?
Like eventually people just make things
crazy and crazy.
You're like,
this is way better than like a lot of
shows.
Like just look at this right now.
Just the just intensity of this race,
and now compare this to golf,
right?
If you watch golf on TV,
this is riveting.
Like this is way more riveting than
people racing cars,
isn't it?
People stop playing football.
They're going to want to do something
crazy.
Yeah.
This must be it.
Roller Derby Downhill,
pretty much.
But this is an agility thing.
You know,
like Wayne Gretzky was not a big guy,
but he had incredible agility on the
ice.
Like you would have to be like one of
those Badass hockey players.
Like bieber is bieber hockey pile.
Yeah.
Justin Bieber.
Imagine if he became like the top dog in
this stuff.
It just,
people are so mad at him.
He's a little punk.
He can't be good at this too.
Piece of shit.
He's also a boxer.
Thunder.
That's a boxing and ass.
Nice somebody.
He's talked to him about the amount of
tattoos.
I'll be the guy,
hey,
stop.
Stop.
Which to do your stomach covered
yourself up with tattoos.
Settle,
Bro,
you're young.
I get it going crazy.
Got All the money in the world.
You're balling,
banging bitches left and right.
I get it son.
Just slow down your tattoos on your
chest.
Don't make sense.
Is that unless there,
does he have a Lesnar?
What does that and that's across anyone.
One of those things in the bottom is
that a ship?
What does a lion?
A bear.
What?
Eagle.
That's an eagle,
right?
Here's the need.
What are those things above it guy?
There's so much chaos going on there.
What's up?
But the nipple lines,
one of the things,
if you talked to tattoo artists,
like they want to make sure that like
design stand out,
you know like the rocks Tattoo,
right?
And Nikko Hurtado Rose Tattoo the rock.
It's arm.
See how that stood out?
Like it popped,
right?
That's because Nico is a master.
Not that this guy isn't covering that
up.
I think whatever it is,
he had some written,
oh,
oh he had something written.
Well,
hey bro,
get that shit lasered.
That's,
that's a lot of laser,
you know,
be a man.
This lie.
They like this.
Ah,
pretend that lasers making it more
powerful.
So you gotta think you gotta think with
eat with us paying I grow with each one.
I'd be calm.
Stronger.
Yeah.
You don't write over writing when you
can erase it.
Everybody knows that.
Why would you ever know you don't do
that?
Don't do that.
Burn it off.
At least there's a way around what
you're doing.
Okay.
That's a way around it.
There's people that get those.
Uh,
what does this branding,
branding that's gusting open.
St prue has that.
He's a top UFC light heavyweight.
He's got that,
uh,
like one of the fraternity things that
his arm,
he's a football player.
Tennessee.
Yeah.
He does that thing too.
When he wins sometimes it makes the,
what is it you,
it's there.
I forget what it was.
It's crazy.
A lot of basketball players used to do
it.
I think Michael Jordan's also in that
frat fraternity shit.
They banned all fraternities at Ohio
state the other day.
Too much rate.
Yeah.
It happened.
The kids get to rape at all.
Shut down there.
That's crazy.
All the hazing or something was going on
probably that they should never have
fraternities anyways.
Well,
you are guaranteeing some crazy shit's
gonna go down.
It's like you're just going to,
you're going to have to have some sort
of an agreement.
Like how much crazy shit are you gonna
allow?
Because if you're going to let a bunch
of dudes who are just starting to have
boners all live together in a house,
they have a house like they let girls
in.
Can they let girls?
Then they're gonna open the door.
Girls can come in,
can they drank?
They can.
Okay,
what the fuck are you doing?
I can get a bunch of people that are
dude's shacked up with other dude
smelling each other's butts,
getting crazy together.
I'll fucking drank and I watching movies
of every bachelor party,
every fucking fraternity movie ever.
We get a group of guys together.
Every fucking,
what is the,
the hangover.
The hangovers.
Another example,
every time you get a bunch of guys
together,
fucking chaos,
chaos.
Every single movie,
you get 10 guys together,
they go somewhere.
Wow.
Is that a control?
People getting punched?
Somebody get shot always.
Right.
So imagine you're letting these 18 year
olds who don't even know how to control
their bodies yet.
You're,
you're barely an adult.
You can't even believe.
You can think for yourself.
You can decide when to wake up.
Your parents aren't there with you
anymore.
Finally,
your dad is not fucking pissed at you
because you forgot to mow the lawn and
like,
fuck you dad.
I'm not here to mow your lawn,
Bro.
Okay,
the next thing you know,
you're,
I know that other,
and a bunch of dudes are just like you
and you're all drunk and girls come over
and they're drunk too.
You're like,
Holy Shit,
this is the best
laurie about life.
Make some mistakes.
You weren't no frat parties work crazy
though.
I mean,
they were,
they would have like hookers there.
That's where all the drugs,
when you first saw like drugs and you're
like,
what the hell?
There's drugs here the most,
the closest to a frat.
I live with two dudes once and uh,
there were good guys sorta.
One of them was a little fucked up,
but it was a,
how about a bunch of men together like
that?
It's just super sketchy.
It's unnecessary.
It's super sketchy.
You can go,
you can go bad.
But bunch of young guys,
I remember hearing stories of,
it wasn't even a Frat,
but it was like the ski club house at
Ohio State would have 30 kegs at their
parties on Saturday.
Yeah.
It's like there's 15 people living in a
house.
What the fuck is that?
Don't do that.
That's not good.
Plus Alpha plus liquor plus plus all the
other things.
Yeah man.
When you get a bunch of people living
together
and especially when you're young,
you make shitty decisions and then the
three of you are making shitty decisions
are the four,
the five or the 10 all like the same
age.
I'll just as dumb all fucking trying to
out agro each other.
All out of hammered.
Come on,
you know.
And then on the other side you've got
some crazy bitch who finally got away
from her dad and cheese.
Fucking Jack and nobody tell me she
and everybody figures out life together.
Yeah,
we should keep sororities.
Definitely
they have sorority still at Ohio state,
right?
Because they're like,
oh Scott.
I think it was both of them.
Oh really?
I only heard,
I only heard fraternities.
I think sororities like good cause it's
about dorm rooms.
I mean dorm rooms.
And what about that?
Dorms are crazy toward him,
sir.
Everybody knows dorms are crazy.
They're just not.
The thing about dorms is you don't have
to join.
Right.
Dorms are like more egalitarian cause
like you get to have a bunch of people
did like different things,
different interests,
different.
They're just different men and women,
different parts of the world.
Everybody lumped together in this dorm.
They all just can't really afford an
apartment.
And they're all living together in this
university setting.
But they could be anybody.
Your net and you roommate could be
anybody got to share a bathroom with
everyone in the hall.
That one shit in the news recently where
that woman was,
uh,
they didn't get along and had a dorm and
so the woman was like putting her
toothbrush in her ass.
She started getting sick and they found
out that she was doing all this shit.
Oh my God.
How'd they find out?
Hidden Camera,
uh,
toilet camp?
No,
I don't.
She probably sued because she got
something in her ass white woman
arrested for torturing black students.
She called Jamaican Jamaican Barbie.
Whoa.
And I guess she admitted to it on
facebook or something like that.
Oh yeah.
She's like,
how's the people rallied at Ucla and set
fire to a trump and Yada unrelenting
story.
It's unrelated.
It's showing up on here,
but at the video,
this is all just about various pieces of
racism that people are finding.
Huh.
Wow,
that's crazy,
man.
That's fucked up.
Magine stick in someone's tooth,
brushing your asshole and then watching
them brush teeth with it.
Clam dip in or lotions rubbing.
Use tampons on her backpack for a month.
Oh my God.
That's what she did.
She,
she did crazy shit to this poor girl,
which probably want to hear buzzing.
Yeah,
she probably wanted to it just probably
like fighting off the gay.
Yeah.
Look at this and then she tweeted about
it.
Oh my God.
She treated it.
Come on,
I can finally say goodbye.
Did you make and Barbie.
Oh my God.
Make that a little bigger.
Finally I did it.
Yo girl got rid of her roommate after
one and a half month of spitting in her
coconut oil,
putting moldy clam dip and her lotions
rubbing,
use tampons in her backpack,
putting her toothbrush and places where
the sun doesn't shine and so much more.
I can finally say goodbye.
Jamaican Barbie.
She said she was making that up as part
of her defense,
but whether or not she wasn't not,
I don't know.
Story came out a couple of weeks ago.
Yeah.
See the thing is like,
you might think it'd be funny to say
something like that and make it up and
it might be made up.
That's true.
You might think it's funny to make,
but boy did you fuck up by saying that
like you gotta make something like that
up and then put it on the Internet where
anybody can find out about it.
That seems crazy.
I guess you can test her toothbrush and
stuff like that for every day.
Like you have the time.
Do you have to know when the last time
you tested your toothbrush for,
but juice every well has it.
Yeah.
That's one of those things people just
don't test for.
Test your toothbrush to see if it's been
someone's ass hole.
It's just a lot of things I'm thinking
about.
It's not one of them.
Yeah,
and I just,
how bad they hit each other,
but that called them on a stick.
A tooth brush.
My brows bitch eat my shit.
Well that's a sick type of person.
I'll sit there and watch.
You brushed their teeth,
their asshole juices.
Good in there for a weekend in the gums
and the gums allegedly.
Yeah.
Hmm.
I wonder if she did it.
She did do it.
That's a sick bitch.
Ooh.
Magine as in the thought that has to go
through your head to do something like
that.
Maybe she didn't realize how gross other
people would find it.
That's the crazy thing that she told
everybody.
Like people would probably been doing
that to each other forever.
I think the first thing she did or was
it a slow build up?
This is a spin brush right to the lower
ribs frauds,
frauds at the lower ribs and she's,
she's got the toothbrush like this with
their fingers.
What she's like barely got the bottom of
the toothbrush.
She's knuckle deep in her own ass hall
and she barely has the bottom of the
toothbrush and she's got a kind of user
shit muscles to force it out when she
could pinch down on and pull it out and
sometimes she has to do it over and
over.
And again man,
I wonder what you imagine you get a
drink prune juice to try to get that
toothbrush out of your household and you
got to keep,
you don't want it to hit the wall coming
out and then bounce back up.
So you've got to really open it wide so
like you probably got to have to wear
like long gloves,
you know like Lube your ass all up and
they just were like some of the gloves
you wear when you like clean and bundles
of sticks and shit.
Those,
you know those ones made out of swings
this way.
Good grip on things that are slippery.
He's pulling your butter part,
trying to get that toothbrush out and
right when it gets out,
you hear the keys in the door.
I got the pictures back and put it in
the glass clink and you shut the door
and just wash your toothbrush off real
quick.
But you've got to dry it too because
otherwise should pick her toothbrush.
I would go,
why the fuck is my toothbrush already
wet Donna?
And like if you put toothpaste on a wet
toothbrush,
you know that's a fucking wet
toothbrush.
He looking down and I think it looks
different.
Why is it when you feel that your
finger,
you know,
whoa,
it's cold and wet.
What the fuck?
Who is just using my toothbrush?
You think about it?
I've been at work for nine hours.
How the fuck is my toothbrush?
Not Dry.
It would be dry or something like that
in her asshole.
All you smell it.
It smells like Madison,
Madison and Jim Poultney.
It's smells like roundup
and went out into the fucking garage.
Got Some lawn spray.
Do you see that new thing that's a,
you put in your mouth and it brushes
your teeth for you?
Lazy?
Yeah.
In 30 seconds it's brushed your teeth.
Is it better?
I don't know.
It's an interesting idea that we'd like,
you know,
you could just put it in your mouth in
the car or something like that in 30
seconds later.
I don't know how proven it is and it
seems like it would get down now.
It's just weird.
I wonder how much of an impact fluoride
in the water has on preventing tooth
decay,
if any.
I've been reading about Florida and the
water and it's so hard to figure out
who's nuts this ten second automatic
toothbrush could save you hours every
year.
She's hot.
I hope she brushed her teeth.
Wow.
I put that in your pussy.
Imagine of her.
No.
Imagine for breath,
smell that she's out pretty would suck
lik that.
And she goes,
this is like a ball gag.
This is like if you were going to like
practice strengthening your neck,
you'd bite down on that thing and attach
that rope to like a bungee cord.
Like the iron neck device you that thing
that you chew down and it strengthens
your next book.
Makes Sense?
Yeah.
This guy go back to that guy like,
come on Bro.
I don't care how much they're paying you
for this,
but he's the same one and his girlfriend
comes by and kisses him on the cheek and
leaves like he doesn't need to have time
to get a good kiss on the lips because
you too busy sucking on this robot Dick.
This thing is just cleaning out your
face.
How about you brush your teeth like a
fucking normal person?
Maybe have the newspaper open beside
you.
I just wonder if it's better.
I mean that dedication.
Here's my question.
Is it better to go to the car wash or
wash your car by hand?
Mm hmm.
Of course it's better to wash a car by
hand.
That's why hand washing costs more
money.
Well,
it depends what car washing,
what's better,
what's better to give you your teeth,
the attention they deserve and go over
each one with a fine brush or suck the
robot Dick.
And he cleans your teeth out.
It should be just to save time or not.
I don't know.
It's a good question.
Yeah.
But how much time should you save and
how much time should you like?
I've been reading a lot about
meditation.
It's something I'm also considering I'm
getting get into during discipline.
December.
It's cool because the tank is not going
to be here for another couple of weeks.
So I gotta wait.
So,
uh,
I'm looking for other ways to expand the
mine.
So I'm thinking to do a little 10 minute
meditation session every day.
Every fucking day.
That's the thing.
Every day you got to do it every day it
got to commit yourself.
That's a long ass time.
Seems like it's not,
but it is.
You're like,
God,
I have 10 minutes.
I gotta go to work.
Nope.
You gotta do it.
Gotta do it sometime during the day.
A couple of those apps,
I think they help you like start streaks
and stuff so you can kind of game in a
little bit of help me get to your
fucking phone.
That's what they helped you look at.
Watch when nine o'clock rolls around,
get out of bed,
meditate,
get 10 minutes to hear about this new
dating app.
Caught Hater and a,
what you do is you put what you hate and
it matches you with people that hate is
named the same thing.
Oh,
perfect.
So it's like it,
it's interesting though.
It's interesting though because it's
backwards,
you know?
So it's like,
what if you only get matched?
Like what if I only got matched with
black women for some reason?
You know,
so all the thing,
it's so unnecessary.
Yeah.
It's,
I think people are probably getting laid
more now than ever before.
And I read this article where they were
putting the blame on stds,
the jumping stds on tinder and grindr.
Like,
no,
no.
You can't.
No.
Okay.
Are you going to sue?
All the nightclubs were giving people
herpes.
No,
you're not.
You can't do that.
You,
these are the places where people meet.
They're not responsible for whether or
not someone's got herpes or Vd.
Stop it.
We'll make it too many people.
They're just trying to,
it's a money grab.
They realize that a lot of money in
tinder and someone's gonna start some
class action lawsuit and all these
people that got the herps or a real
strong stuff like it's like a real car.
You're legionnaires' disease broke out
at Disneyland.
Oh yeah.
What?
And nine people got it.
What in the fuck legionnaire's disease
or is it,
what the fuck is that stuff doing around
like we gotta have some old,
you know,
because of like preservatives and food
or some shit.
Have some old diseases.
Make it come back.
What is legion like?
What is this symptom question?
I don't know.
Because there's another old sounds
terrible though.
Yeah,
it better be strong.
I better be able to fuck you up.
I'll get super pissed if they name like
some bitch ass.
Common Cold Legionnaires' disease,
a slight diarrhea.
It just makes you fart.
All Great.
And it doesn't spread from person to
person,
but through mist.
Yeah,
it's from the lottery.
Oh Man.
So it's from their water sprayers from
an air conditioner.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
Is that what it was from?
No,
it's from,
it could be from that.
I thought it was from outdoor mystery.
Wow,
that's crazy.
Yeah.
So it's somehow or another got on
outdoor mres and then got into how many
people?
Nine.
I think nine.
How many of those people were weak
pitches?
Yeah,
the kids.
I mean
that's just a joke folks.
I'm sure they weren't.
They were wonderful people.
Uh,
elevated levels of Legion area bacteria.
Wow.
Causes Disneyland.
The shutdown cooling towers.
Notice shutdown cooling towers not shut
down,
bitch.
I'm sorry.
The show must go on.
15 people have when 15 people.
Holy Shit.
Now what is,
how dangerous is this stuff?
Find that out.
We removed our roof,
viewed our water quality testing data,
including testing performed by our third
party water quality maintenance
contractor and learn that to cooling
towers had elevated levels of legionella
bacteria,
Legionella,
legionella bacteria.
Fucking amen.
That's like some 28 days later.
Shit.
Right.
That's where it breaks out.
Like when is it going to,
when are we going to get a disease?
It turns people into crazy people.
Some we already have it right.
28 days later type shit though.
I think you just get sick from it.
It sounds like maybe diarrhea or getting
the chills.
Fever.
It can get diluted with the antibiotics
sensitive people.
Hmm.
Well,
that was this week document or saying
that everybody's more gluten sensitive
than you realize.
Right?
It's like,
it's like being allergic to a cat.
Everyone's allergic to cats,
but some people have.
Yeah,
everyone's allergic to it.
But about dogs.
Is everyone allergic to dog dander?
I think.
I think so.
I think,
but yeah,
definitely.
Your levels of it.
Severe often lethal form of lum oh,
of pneumonia.
Oh my God.
It's a severe,
often lethal form of pneumonia is caused
by the bacterium.
Legionella pneumonia fell into both
potable and non potable water.
Holy Shit.
That's not good.
Can you get it when it one happens on
water?
Because fuck,
I hope those people survive,
but those people are going to be okay.
Did the people from Disneyland get
treated and released.
Oh,
okay.
I need information.
This is a,
this is the dumb Bro News Network
checking in.
Hey Bro,
Delta,
Delta [inaudible] Bro.
Right.
I heard a,
the fucking zombies are a Disneyland
Bro.
Just keep it on lockdown.
Doesn't want you to know bro.
They all over 50 to 52 sick.
50 2:00 PM now the age they were over
the age of 52 kids.
One was 94.
Oh Jesus.
What are you doing at Disney?
Well,
maybe their immune system is more
compromised when that old,
yeah,
the body can't fight it off.
Can't fight off the funk.
Fuck man.
52 that's like Dean del Ray's age.
Isn't it weird that that's uh,
all of us are eventually,
if you keep going,
you're going to be a hundred.
Like if you live like one day you'll be,
if you survive,
you'll be,
who knows?
With medicine science,
you can easily survive.
Yeah.
Wouldn't put all my money and you make
it a hundred be 77.
But if you did,
I mean,
did you,
you never know though.
Dude,
I'm telling you.
We're so close to like innovation,
breakthroughs,
medical breakthroughs.
What's this?
What do you got?
55 cases were found in Orange County
last year and they don't know why.
God,
Orange County's recorded more than 55
cases of the disease is here and the
seen the number of cases jump in recent
years,
similar upward trend has been seen
naturally and elsewhere in southern
California according to the healthcare
agency though.
What's causing that is unclear.
Don Don Don to coop the two towers ever
shut down where a in the backstage area
more than a hundred feet from the
nearest people.
Huh?
Oh,
that's why only a few people got it,
Huh?
Yeah.
Wow.
Maybe that week we can be in system,
but maybe just some,
Tommy didn't clean the thing.
He was supposed to clean because he was
lazy cause he wanted to put on as furry
outfit and go,
Fuck Huh.
Go on a furry fuck fest.
Maybe that's what happened.
How many furries working distantly
lands?
Probably all of them,
right?
Yeah.
If you are a furry,
that'd be a dream job match.
You could walk around pretending to be
goofy.
Go to goofy's kitchen and wave at the
kids is on top of her showing up.
What's that thing for?
Security is on top of furry showing up
on on the parking lot and want to get
them Outta here.
You'd have to use a um,
incognito social media
account,
which all the firies do anyway that I've
come across over the last three days of
research.
All Furry group especially,
they have to be super careful,
especially the art fairs.
That'd be super careful.
Well,
what's the difference between off like
all right there all right people to
trump supporters that are fairies,
fairies and maybe fairies to brownies.
Brownies are,
yeah,
they're right up there.
I like bronies now I can get down some
brown brown.
I don't know if that's real.
By the way,
if you're,
if you're an ot furry and you're mad at
me,
now that's not,
I don't know if it's real.
I don't know.
But one guy was calling himself for
Nazi.
Yeah,
that sounds like a troll to me when
maybe,
but isn't that what a lot of this stuff
is being silly?
What we're supposed to pretend that
that's not like the spirit of the
Internet sometimes.
That's what got me so mad about that
whole pepe,
the frog stuff.
It's like,
listen,
this spirit of the Internet is in
fucking with people.
It has been forever.
People are bored.
They're at work.
They come up with hilarious memes and
some of them are really fucked up.
Does that mean that guy's a real Nazi or
does it mean he's just an asshole who's
bored at work and he's mad at everybody?
It might be that,
you know,
I don't know how many of them are like
real Nazis and how might have been.
We're just people fucking around.
That's like the Internet,
right?
The Internet is all right.
Like so much of the Internet is people
fucking around.
It's so hard to tell what's going on in
any given moment.
You know,
like this flat earth thing.
I,
that's the great thing about it,
but doesn't change.
It can't change.
Do you think it'll change?
Do you think that really it'll get to a
point where they'll have so much control
over the Internet that there'll be able
to stop content like that.
Like there'll be a closed down like
message boards or a social media where
people are allowed to talk about stuff
like that.
They do it in every other country.
All must,
you know,
they just,
the main reason they want it is because
too many,
I mean net netflix takes up like 75% of
the bandwidth right now.
Does it really?
Yeah.
It's like something crazy where all
these videos and we're all,
we're,
it's going to get worse.
Four K Eight K,
12 gay.
So they want to have control of,
you know,
if you're gonna use video or if you
want,
they want to like pretty much it's,
that's what I think they're saying
there.
Well,
I kind of get it from their perspective.
If say they have a limited amount of
bandwidth and then the one application,
like Netflix is using up most of their
bandwidth of paying the same amount of
money.
Right.
I don't know if that's the case though.
That's the question I'm not sure about
is is there a limited amount of
bandwidth?
It seems like there's always been an
infinite amount of bandwidth,
right?
Why would there ever be true socialist
Commie?
Just wondering you bad for business.
I get the pipe.
The pipes might get clogged,
which could be a thing.
It's all happening at once.
You would really freak me the fuck out.
When I found out there's a real pipe,
it goes across the bottom of the ocean.
I went,
wait,
what?
So if you send an email from somebody
from Australia,
there's a God damn pipe as someone laid
across the flat ocean of the flat earth
all the way to the other side,
if that,
those people have to be in on the flat
earth conspiracy as well.
By the way,
why does it just go by satellite?
Why does it have to go through this pipe
anyways?
I don't know.
It might not be a pipe to Australia,
but it's definitely a pipe to Japan.
I believe.
Trans Atlantic Communications,
cable and transatlantic communications
cable,
transatlantic communications cables,
a submarine,
Whoa.
Submarine Communications cable
connecting one side of the Atlantic
Ocean to the other.
After mid century,
coaxial cable came into use with
amplifiers late in the century,
used for optical fiber,
uh,
and most now use optical amplifiers.
So that's only one cable.
It's only one
probably really big.
And their mouths,
they can't be just one.
But this just made me think of something
else I wanted to show you that I just
found the other day that's kind of
scary.
That has to do with fiber optics
done.
Done.
I gotta get to it,
but it's time for another episode of
Jamie Vernon scares the world.
Me a link that showed that uh,
people can hide a microphone.
I don't know how big and how well it can
listen inside of an ethernet cable.
Oh Geez.
And they were like,
check all your cables cause you never
know what could happen.
And then so I started looking through
the tweets of that and it showed there
was a link to a,
a company that made a fiber cable.
And the description of what the fiber
cable could do is that it could listen
the entire length of the cable.
And
it was sort of saying it was just to be
able to listen for like a water
underground,
like water pipes that are leaking and
things like that.
But it doesn't say the limit of what it
can here and where it's being used,
which is uh,
alarming.
Could you imagine if it turned out that
everything,
every wire in everyone's house is
secretly a microphone and the government
has been years ahead with this data and
tuning into everything you've said at
every moment.
All,
all your life.
So here's the microphone inside of the
same,
what?
That little tiny thing is a microphone.
Oh my God.
And then where's your God now?
Whoa.
Serious.
Leat kids.
I bet he spells it.
L three,
three T.
I don't know if I'll be able to find
her.
Three.
Seven is three,
three,
seven
l seven three,
three,
one.
Sorry,
I can't,
I don't know if I'm going to go to find
this.
I was like taking a shit while I was
looking through this deep tweet.
There's like 5,000 things in here now.
So,
but it's a scary thing.
And the fiber,
I didn't really know you could even hear
audio through fiber that way.
I know that it's used,
um,
like uh,
the light cable you can use in the back
of your any box.
That little red light that's always on
is looking for a fiber audio cable,
which is the best,
but
that's how it,
Mike's Wick told me once,
Mike Swick was working for the United
States government in Russia and they had
like a Russian ambassador,
a Russian embassy building,
you know,
American US embassy building in Russia.
And they had developed these devices
that they found in the walls of the
building that were powered by the
movement of the building.
Like cause the move,
because it's a skyscraper would have a
certain mass sway through the wind and
they had figured
out to how to make a device that didn't
require any sort of additional power
source other than the movement of the
building.
Right.
And it could transmit sound.
They're like,
this stuff is so far ahead of anything
we knew even existed and they were using
this in the building spine people.
Mike Swick told me about that in like
2002 and it happened to him way before
that,
so we might be,
you know who the fuck knows what they
can,
I mean John Edward Snowden does might be
the reason why they kept that guy
running like because they want to
discourage anybody coming out.
Now,
at any moment we're going to find out
that all of our phones are on 24 hours a
day.
Whether they're at of batteries are not
that there's a certain amount of battery
life.
I think your phone retains and the
government could listen.
They know where you are.
The GPS tracker is tracking your phone,
whether it's on or off everywhere you
go.
No,
a lot of those phones actually do work
with gps when the phone is on airplane
mode.
Oh yeah.
Well it's just,
yeah,
yeah.
There's a gps chip in your phone.
That's why find your phone works.
Like you can go on apple,
find your phone.
Hey,
my phone's in the Bronx.
Hey leave it there.
Don't get shot.
But listen,
there's,
that's how they can do that.
They can find your Jamie once they take
your eyes,
man,
if they give you those robot eyes,
it's in the air pod.
That's in the Apple Watch too.
It's in all your apple computers.
Lots everywhere.
Yeah.
How's that possible?
Because she lives shit.
Fuck.
I like it.
What if I try to lose me?
So I'll tell you what.
I'm digging these airpods I've been
using it a lot like fucking awesome.
God,
I was so skeptical.
Look,
I keep with me all the time too.
Now.
My favorite thing about them is that the
case that,
cause that's one thing I always had with
Bluetooth headphones.
I always like,
fuck,
I forgot to charge my head and look at
this.
[inaudible] welcome to the future
pitches
and I stick them in Miami and worry
about them falling out.
They don't really fall out.
They're hard to fall out.
I had to like hit it.
I made them fall out of the gym when I
was doing Chin ups because my shoulder's
touched my ears and I made him fall out.
And when one goes out,
the other one stops.
Yeah.
Which is crazy.
If you have the Apple Watch,
which much?
No.
But then you don't need your iphone for
music too much.
You're using your phone.
Got To draw lines.
It's a better for jogging so you don't
have your phone in your pocket when
you're listening to music.
I have a fanny pack that is a neoprene
waistband.
My phone sits in there perfectly.
Car Keys.
It's extra weight,
Bro.
Not No problem.
I don't mind.
I'm stuck.
I'm running with my dog.
I'm not shaving any seconds.
Do a lot of calling,
trying to get him out of the bushes.
My dog fucking loves it now.
He still hates going in the car,
but uh,
he's more reluctant.
He's less reluctant.
He gets right up to the car cause he
knows we're going to go run and he loves
running.
And then when we come back,
a lot of times I give him a bath too.
Oh,
he loves that leash.
No leash,
man.
He's a really good,
he really listens.
He'll wake me,
obviously he's
some fucking goofball
online.
I posted a video and I was like a fool.
I read through some of the comments.
One of them said,
don't let him get ahead of you bro.
You're the alpha.
And I'm like,
look,
I hope you're either joking around,
maybe trolled me.
You might've told me,
but you might be just a dummy.
I'm thinking you probably more of a
dummy.
No,
I think your dog ahead of you when you
walk on a leash,
stupid or otherwise,
you're not.
Your dog's walking you.
You dumb cunt.
You know you're always going to be in
the back.
See the dogs in front.
That's the other leash.
That's where you're wrong,
Joe.
It has to walk next to you.
I mean,
cause that's what Cesar Milan tells
people.
I don't know.
Shit.
He doesn't run.
He's not running with his dog.
I run with my dog.
My top totally listens to me.
And when he gets to far goals,
stop dude.
And he stops like he's smart.
I go,
come on back,
buddy.
I'm going to take a breather.
Like he'll come back and hang out with
me like he's,
I don't let them off the leash.
I liked the fact that he's,
he likes to be free.
He likes to run around.
I want them to run around,
let them have a good,
he's a sweet dog.
He's not going to be mean to anybody.
You know,
my,
my new dog is,
doesn't know how to use a leash and it's
been trained to not use a leash,
but I don't trust it so much because
it's like one car honking his horn or
something and he freaks out and runs
into the traffic or something.
Yeah.
When his cars,
I always have him on a leash.
Anytime there's cars that had him on a
leash,
but when I get out of the car and we go
off into the trails,
you know,
I mean,
if people see him,
he's like the nicest dog ever.
Anybody meets him.
I was like,
oh,
he's so sweet.
You know,
so it's not like you have to worry about
it being dangerous.
He just likes to run around,
man.
It's fun to watch.
It's like you're watching like a little
dog,
little kid.
Why don't you bring him here so we can
look at him?
Well,
because he's at home.
I was like,
Sabine is yard man.
Go in the pool and swam.
He swims whenever he wants too.
That'd be funny if you were the new
comic that always brings his dog
everywhere.
But you Brian Golden retriever.
He's 75 pound dog everywhere.
Tales knocking people's drinks or ass
hall.
Can you fucking dog out of here man
tales.
So many people are so stupid with their
dogs.
Like their dog is like a baby.
Like they can't leave it alone anywhere.
Eliza can't leave it anywhere.
No,
Eliza's I've seen her without the dog
occasionally.
Yeah,
he holds it.
The husband,
he clings onto that thing.
She's a sweet dog.
She's definitely a super,
super loved and friendly dog.
I Love Blanche.
Yeah,
she's awesome.
I love dogs,
man.
You know what I mean?
That's another,
um,
a good argument for not living in the
city.
Live somewhere where your dog can be
free,
you know,
live somewhere.
We can go out the back yard and throw a
Frisbee for your dog,
you know,
go go on hikes,
goddammit.
Dumpy stuck in that red and white horror
show of tail lights and headlight
traffic.
Fuck man.
Yeah.
What do you mean?
What's that going to be like in 20 years
and the skywalk?
Shouldn't we be planning for that?
You know that's just going to be in the
sky.
It's just going to be like 20 feet up.
You might've been right with Santa
Barbara.
You know why I think you might've
been right because Santa Barbara's only
an hour away so he'd go up there.
It's an hour away.
Important Shit.
We could always come back to drive us
in.
Is that how that works then?
Yeah,
just has slightly honestly drives us in.
Oh,
one of them.
Jammies.
Yeah.
Is that going to happen?
I think he's just doing la though.
He's probably not going to do the Santa
Barbara.
Same County.
Right.
He's probably going to go right up to
San Francisco.
Have you heard of Tesla loop in Los
Angeles where you can just rent a,
it's like Uber.
They said you have to go to San Diego,
you rent a,
somebody will drive a tesla for you and
it's pretty cheap.
Like $49 down to San Diego and you just
ride in a tesla for 49 bucks.
Pretty cheap uber type thing.
I saw them.
I want to got to the airport last time I
was there.
Yeah.
Testing nine bucks.
The San Diego just talking about that
seems super cheap.
Yeah.
How are they going to make money?
Test a little loop.
That's the thing is that new sports car,
they came out with that new roadster
goes 600 miles without a recharge.
Now you're talking now I'm interested.
Now I'm listening.
600 miles.
Huh?
Did he just not a top speed but
fuck.
Just go wherever you want to go.
They go to Los Angeles,
San Diego,
Orange County,
palm springs.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
that's amazing.
It's at $29 that's amazing.
Smart.
It's smart.
It's free advertising for the cars.
People get in and they're like,
Holy Shit,
this thing is nice.
And then you see that guy giant
dashboard and you go,
Whoa,
you got an ipad and you're down.
What is that?
Is it like a airplane seat?
Your bias?
You could be sitting with other people.
Yeah.
I mean it's $39 just by the seat next to
have someone as far a bus that goes
every day now from San Francisco to la,
that's like a overnight sleeping bus.
Were you sleeping a pod and they have
like really?
Yeah,
that's not,
that's obviously not the fastest way to
do it,
but if you need to go overnight and you
kind have that time to rest was a driver
stays away.
Okay.
That's the scary,
I mean I hope the same with the pilot,
but a driver sleeping,
I don't know if it's a pilot,
it's all shot on auto pilot.
Pilot can adjust,
but maybe those tests of buses,
maybe a tussle bus like when them big
ass,
those,
those big giant trucks that he's making
now put pods in the back of the truck.
There's only three or 500 miles though,
right?
So far?
I think 500 miles Max one I think so you
go,
uh,
you stop and San Luis Obispo.
I start carrying battery charge.
How long they have to charge for.
What is the distance in miles from La to
San Francisco?
If you had to guess?
800 and I don't know.
No,
no,
not nearly,
not nearly.
I would say probably in the 400 it's
like 420470470 you think?
Yeah.
Okay.
I've never done it.
You say 800?
I say for 25.
600 you say for 75 you say 600.
Okay.
That's good.
That's good bet.
I don't think it's right though.
I think it's way less.
Is it from Los Angeles to San Francisco?
Let's see.
82 miles from lawson.
Wow.
Interesting.
What's that mean?
That means you have a raven bro.
They got straight.
Yeah.
Straight.
Then go above
that.
That's never heard that.
Never heard of that.
That's cool.
Say that kind of talk.
I'm used to it and I thought you fucking
city slickers.
Uh,
that's good.
Um,
so yeah,
a regular tesla can't do that.
But they said the new one would be able
to drive all the way there and back.
That's not true.
Cause that was one of their sayings.
They said you could drive from San
Francisco to La and back will.
You definitely couldn't do that because
that's more than 600.
That's,
that's more maybe the edge of the
county.
Maybe Carolee,
let's lock.
Stop lying.
You gonna leave me stranded in the
desert.
I'm going to be somewhere halfway back
where there's no water and that stupid
piece of Shits gonna run out of
batteries.
Stop lying.
Just say it's awesome.
It goes 600 miles.
Don't say you can go to San Francisco
and back.
You can't,
you shouldn't make it.
They should make it a,
the electric cars.
They should make it wireless charging
and then have the [inaudible] road
speed.
Like big mats.
I think they've talked about too.
Oh really?
Yeah.
I think they have talked about doing
that.
They've talked about having people in
some sort of tracks where you know you
can't change lanes unless like you're in
a specific spot.
And that that track charges the the lane
up.
It'd basically be in your own little
trolley car.
It's cool.
Knows man.
I think the idea of driving your own car
though,
that's on the way out for sure.
I think we only have like a few,
maybe a decade or so.
More of that shit.
Yeah.
Mike,
Mike Carr would just with the lane
guidance,
you know that's,
I did it on the way here.
I barely drove off from Burbank to here
just because of my link.
My car just drives itself pretty much.
I just have to put my finger on it so it
knows that my fingers on it.
What do you think,
man?
Do you think like,
do you think people start moving out of
la?
You think people will realize that,
look at this and go,
this is unsustainable.
I've got to get out now.
What do you think?
It'll take something like a fucking
earthquake or something.
Earthquake or thanksgiving.
Hollywood continues to die.
You know Hollywood's not going to
continue to die.
Now it with Youtube and people are doing
it in their houses.
You don't need to be in Los Angeles
anymore.
You could.
That is true that people are making
shitloads of money just from their
fucking basement.
That is true.
I mean,
and then the tech community is booming
and other cities to like Seattle has a
huge tech community.
You still have to come here though.
So if you're only here for four or five
days out of the month,
what are you considering that,
why would you have to come here?
Work for a cooperate?
I don't know if someone just wants to
stay in La,
you know what the fuck he saying?
Listen to them.
There's a reason why when youtube
started,
all the big people moved here.
They didn't have to move here then they
were all making money at home.
They'd be like the glamorous thing to
do.
And Youtube does have offices here.
The glamorous thing to do I think is
part of it.
Like come on,
we're gonna move to La.
If they made the officer's here though,
cause everyone was here.
That's right bitch.
So well we're here.
Why we're here.
They go to the offices and he'd be here.
Well,
the one thing that keeps me,
there's the comedy store,
there's the podcast and having a great
supply of guests and being around
all my friends,
there's,
this is the reasons to stay here,
but we could just have our mass exodus.
I've got to get everybody to make enough
money when they could just pull up and
bail.
That's what everybody's got to be able
to just pull up and bail and just like
start a new community.
We could just all move next to doug.
Stan hope too much NYC and you don't,
you're not going to sleep.
You gotta make your own thing.
I think we go to like Santa Ynez.
We go to some weird cow country type
place or people who have their own
chickens.
Yeah,
that's the move.
No where like that.
The purge happens like that and then
they had five years into it,
everyone comes and just kills you and to
like your city.
Now it's a ghost town.
Fucking be prepared,
bro
Brown kind of look all the cool shit in
a cool city.
It's going to be like the dark tower
movie.
You gotta be prepared when they come.
Let's just move the solving.
That's not a bad spot.
If you like to drink a lot of wine.
Right.
And listen to the ladies talk about the
health problems and the yamas are llamas
are,
yeah,
they have like Alpacas up there and they
have to fight off the mountain lions.
Mountain lions coming chapter.
I'll pacos.
Yeah,
there's a,
there's a bunch of amazing spots up the
coast.
You know,
it's real interesting.
We lost like hundreds of yards of a
route.
One a from a giant landslide and they
still haven't figured out what the fuck
to do.
Yeah,
it's still right till it still closed.
Yeah.
They're thinking about putting a road
over the landslide,
but they don't know when and they want
to let it settle.
Like,
Hey,
what?
What do you do inward?
A little were driving,
if you're driving near that thing,
he'd be like,
oh my God.
Oh my God,
please don't fall please.
And I'll fall like those 300 yards or
whatever with a landfall was,
look how big it is,
late 2018 how far is it?
How much of a,
how much of a landslide is,
oh,
it's pretty far,
dude.
You gotta look out tiny.
Those cars are,
that's hundreds of yards for sure.
Doesn't,
we'll pull up just so I could see it.
It ruined 5 million cubic yards.
Hold on.
Go back up a little bit.
5 million cubic reigned.
5 million cubic yards of rocks and
debris on the third of the mile.
Okay,
so it's one third of a mile.
Wow.
That's a lot.
That's so big.
You know,
miles,
5,000 feet.
Is that what it is?
Three.
So it's like Holy Shit.
So they should go back to the photo
again.
Scroll down.
So I could look at how big that fucking
slide is.
Just comes off the mountain.
There's a before and after to where they
show a,
the two stages of the landslide.
They show it before and then they show
the second stage and then the third
stage where it finally is.
Now it's fucking crazy,
man.
Wow.
Yeah.
It's um,
they have satellite images of what it
looked like.
See,
look how much fell off,
man.
Look at that.
Boom.
Just so what do you have to do now?
You just can't even go anywhere near
there.
Oh No,
don't drive there.
It's kind of keep following some of
these houses right there.
Two guys.
Fuck I'm screwed.
He's so fucked.
It's going to keep falling like more
parts are going to fall and they think
part of it is the root system isn't
strong enough to keep the uh,
the,
you know like the more trees and roots
you have,
the less likely it is to have the
landslides I guess because the trees and
the root system keep all the dirt.
So then if you have poor rainfall then
the,
the trees don't grow as much and I have
as much weeds.
You don't have as much shit on the side
of the hill.
And then there's like,
you ever seen me drive by Malibu and
they got like cement all up on the side
of certain hills and like mash and shit
to keep things from falling.
I these people like holding onto their
chunk of dirt with every tooth and claw.
Okay.
Yeah.
It's supposedly like a lot of places
because of all the fires.
Like this winter it's going to be land
law,
mudslides everywhere for for us.
That's what I've heard.
Yeah.
Burbank.
They say that the fire,
one thing that the fires are good for
though.
It's like you need to burn some of that
shit down and it's supposed to be
healthy,
puts minerals in the soil and then it
builds things back up and then these
fires through like lightening strikes
are like super common and then the
things were burned down and the rain
would come and then they would
repopulate with new new seeds and shit.
She,
this guy figured out how to put
together.
You could stand on it.
Yeah.
The car on it.
He put pieces of paper in between the
sand and then he pulled the sides off of
it and the paper,
the paper being compressed in between
these pieces of sand allows it to hold
tremendous weight without losing its
form.
Weird.
Yeah.
It's super weird.
See how it is.
It's like each thing is like a slice,
right?
Like see if they show how he did it.
Yeah,
it's pretty crazy.
It's just sort of how it works.
Similar how side of it.
That means you said the side of a
freeway.
Yeah.
Okay.
So that's what they do with the side of
the freeways thing.
That's how they reinforce those things.
Yeah.
If you see him slowly build it up,
it's kind of crazy to watch them do it.
But dude,
I watched something really crazy.
You ever go to the,
if you hi,
I started falling it cause you retweeted
it.
Yeah.
If you go to,
if you high,
they have a thing where they're building
a bridge and they're moving a fucking
gigantic girder and his girl,
there's like a hundred yards wide and
they're picking it up.
Look at this,
this thing,
it's a machine.
It goes to the end of the bridge where
the edge is cause they're,
they're building the bridge,
it stops and then this other thing comes
down and then it moves forward and then
connects.
It connects with the other side.
You've seen this.
This is sweet.
Fuck Dude.
It's crazy.
So it connects to the aside.
Extends and then once it does that,
then they bring in this huge cement
girder.
I mean it is fucking,
you see how small the people look next
to it.
It's fucking huge.
This is cool.
It's like a football field,
right?
I mean isn't it,
is that close to a football field?
How far is that?
At least half of one if not at least 50
yards.
Right.
50 yards of solid and steel.
It's huge.
And they set it down on top of these
stone pillars and everybody must be
shitting their pants.
Go do and we'll get you on up here.
Where's this?
Japan?
China,
I don't know.
Asian while joint machinery company.
I mean that's how they do it man,
right at soc.
The crazy thing is to think that they
built the Brooklyn Bridge back when when
they built that God damn thing.
When did they build the San Francisco
Golden Gate Bridge?
When the fuck did they build that thing?
I mean that was a long goddamn time ago
and I think still up so weird.
The idea of building over water till you
have to like go to the point where you
can drive a car over.
Yeah,
it's nuts.
1933 the Golden Gate Bridge was built.
Whew.
That's crazy.
How long did it take them
people back then?
Worked harder.
There were different.
Did stronger hands?
What?
How?
How many years do you think that took
the bill?
I want to say it took two years.
I say five years.
What do you say,
Jamie?
I don't know.
At least 10 10 hmm.
Easily.
Okay.
Let's see.
I think I'm right.
I think it's like two years.
What'd you say,
Brian?
Five to five.
10 all right.
How long did it take?
How many workers?
What do we got?
35 million bucks.
That's it.
Shit.
That's like j Lo's house.
Things you may not know
I'm on.
Why don't you just google?
How long did it take determined?
How long did it take?
How long did it take to build the Golden
Gate Bridge for a half years?
Oh yes.
Four and a half years.
You went over,
Bro.
It doesn't count.
You went too far.
I ain't go right.
Isn't that a price is right word go over
21 no,
you said hit me and you fucked up.
I go,
I couldn't with one on one.
Yeah,
you could have one with one with one
because I had to,
so I was closer with one day.
You want a one?
Yeah,
you would have one that would have,
you would have got that.
We're not playing by those rules.
That's amazing that they built it that
quick back.
Then think of that like less than five
years.
They built this incredible bridge that's
still up.
Why they did it in the stone age.
It's a lot more slaves back then.
You know,
they weren't,
they probably were though.
Right?
The Chinese people that built the
railroads,
they weren't technically slaves,
but they weren't going anywhere either.
The Brooklyn Bridge was in 1870
we did it first started in 1870
beginning.
That's a technically 1869 because it was
January 3rd.
You know what's interesting about that?
They're tearing down a bridge in
downtown La Right now.
Um,
the sixth street bridge.
Yes.
Did it last year,
I think.
Yeah,
they're there.
They're rebuilding it because it has
something called concrete cancer.
Like the concrete was rotting out.
Like how these dummies do such a shitty
job.
Goddamn la thing.
Bridge smoked a lot.
Ah,
all the fucking shitty traffic and bad,
bad air.
Imagine if that like pollution actually
destroyed concrete.
Yeah.
Policing has been bad this year in Los
Angeles.
Wow.
Beautiful Bridge.
Last night we were on a no chimney.
We weren't allowed to use fireplaces.
If you had a fireplace,
it didn't seem weird.
They can't just fix that.
Yeah.
It doesn't seem weird.
I mean,
I guess it makes sense if it's the
concrete starting to break down,
just what a shit design can you get your
money back?
You know,
that was built in 1932.
That's what was always said to those
nine 11 troopers.
You know,
like everybody was,
uh,
they were pissed at this guy that owned
tower seven that,
you know,
he said pull it,
pull the building.
You know,
when I was driving crazy,
like,
why didn't that Guy Freak out?
That building just collapsed.
That was my building and it lit on fire.
Just collapse like that.
I'm like,
who the fuck design this piece of shit?
Like look at the building.
Look how collapsed.
Like,
did you guys not know that?
Maybe it could catch fire.
Did you plan?
You didn't plan for that.
Okay,
well you make me a new building,
motherfucker make it so they can light
on fire and I can just rebuild it.
So make it so collapses shit about the
extended warranty.
The apple care insurance.
Right.
That's what,
that's what those conspiracies about
that he told them to pull the building.
I have it all collapse.
Taller insurance companies alive,
you know like look at all the houses in
Puerto Rico and Texas and all that stuff
that happened this year.
How has like nationwide still fucking
not running out of money?
That's a good question.
That's a very good question.
Yeah,
I mean that's a lot like the cars.
You see a lot of cars of all the cars
that got ruined for in Houston,
like judge like thousands of cars and
you can't do anything with those cars.
You can't sell those cars.
No.
And one if they can even use the frames.
I mean the frames might be rotten Rustin
shit,
everything.
1 million cars and Houston and they're
saying that a lot of them are being sold
in like Los Angeles and stuff.
People are buying them and trying to
clean them up to make them look like
they fine.
Well I wonder if you could as rewire
them.
No,
there's,
I mean there's so much like mold and
stuff in there and all of a mechanic now
I saw,
I think I saw a thing on it on the news
like,
like why they can't use them.
I forget what his car got flooded when,
when like in the 90s when it flooded in
Ohio,
we lived on the bottom of the hill.
Whole shit flooded.
A lot of people's houses are owned.
Car was fucked and didn't even get that
much water in it.
Wow.
Here's total it.
Shouldn't they made a car that you can
get wet?
Yeah,
like a little waterproof car.
You can drive it in the lake,
but like,
no one ever wanted that piece of shit
like member when they couldn't do that
with the iphone.
So like there's no work can make a
waterproof.
Right.
Well that's one thing to raise.
Your phone's not waterproof.
It's not.
Nope.
Nowadays,
yeah.
Nowadays you need that.
But it does have a,
um,
the power button right here.
It's also a thumb print sensor sensor.
Yeah.
I mean,
it's a beautiful phone.
It's,
it's weird how the designs,
I can't square,
like,
it's a,
what's the battery life on it?
Phenomenal.
It's 4,000 Milli amps or using it as
your main phone right now.
No.
Hmm.
Mostly using it to play games on fuck
around with it.
Yeah.
Just,
yeah.
It's,
the sound is amazing when you play music
on,
it's fucking incredible.
The game.
And it's supposed to be bad ass.
Like watching a youtube video,
like it's fucking loud.
Like you're watching it on a laptop with
really good screen speakers turned out
in the 120 hertz.
Right?
Yes.
That's the other thing is that it's one
of the very few,
um,
cell phones that has 120 rate a hertz
frame rate that's crew fringe.
So it means that you get 120 frames per
second sometimes,
you know,
depending upon the game,
which is like Super Silky smooth.
If you're playing something like,
and you're watching video and think most
things,
it's not gonna be able to take advantage
of it,
but games,
a lot of games can cause this out yet.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
Dude,
there's a lot of,
there's one called a,
I was watching unblocks therapy on
blocks,
unbox therapy.
He,
uh,
Lewis had a,
an article or a video rather on the one
fte.
Is that it?
Yeah.
Five t is that it?
One plus five team is that,
I say it,
see if that's the right thing to say.
But that thing looks fucking incredible.
The big one.
Yeah.
And it's,
uh,
it's half the price of like a,
a galaxy note.
Eight or $299 500 bucks.
500 bucks plus five.
Yeah.
The thing.
So,
so like my point was that the level of
cell phone,
look,
your iphone x 10 sorry,
sorry.
Nervous,
don't get mad.
It's x doin bro or even you know any of
the new,
the new Google pixels,
the level's so high now.
Everything the Samsung note.
So like these everything is like I was
watching a video comparison and there
are nitpicking.
I mean these guys are nit picking,
try to find anything wrong with any of
these phones and like these things are
like they're,
they're literally like science fiction
from 10 years ago,
10 years ago.
The things that these things can do,
the opens with your face,
you look at it and it opens the one ft
has that too.
Yeah.
One plus my note has it,
my note eight.
It does have that or whatever.
Yeah.
I mean he has it but it's not,
it's the same level.
Like you have to like stick it in your
face and be like do like if that was the
thing that the note has a retina
detection,
which is different.
This is facial recognition.
And then the one plus ft has an even
better version of [inaudible] facial
recognition than the iphone.
And Louis was showing a quick,
it opens this.
Oh Wow.
Maybe pan.
Yeah.
And it also has a fingerprint sensor in
the back,
which the iphone doesn't have.
Yeah.
And a big ass screen.
It's got a big ass green,
a little tiny ass bezels look smooth,
like the level,
my point is just super high right now.
We're dorks like you and me.
Very lucky.
And they're saying the next year one,
they're already guessing at what nick
next year's.
I don't fold.
You know,
they,
they got a patent for folding fold,
which is cool in some ways.
Like imagine having like a normal size
phone,
but then you could fold it and make it
an ipad.
You know what I mean?
Apparently they're really close to doing
something like that
and that's,
I think there's at one point in time
they're gonna figure out a way to put it
in your,
in your glass.
Yeah.
I think it's going to be more like,
like glasses or even just like a contact
lens that you never take out.
Kind of like
dope sunglasses,
like some cool like frame,
like Elton John's style frames and you
have like just a full screen computer
playing a virtual reality in front of
you all the time.
Yeah.
That might be the way to go.
I can't believe Google glasses didn't
really take off too much stuff that
good.
Yeah,
it was too small.
You were looking at it.
I tried it once.
I did it.
I've worn during one of the UFC wayans
here.
Um,
you're looking at this little thing over
here and you look down,
you could see it and you can look up and
you don't,
you kind of look past it but it's kind
of,
there wasn't right.
It wasn't the right thing.
I think augmented reality where you
either looking through your phone or you
have glasses on,
like that's what I think you're going to
have like clear glasses on and you're
going to have your phone and you're
going to be able to do is switch to
glass mode and your phone will be in
your pocket and it'll bluetooth with the
glasses and the glasses will be able to
pull up anything.
That was the other thing that's pretty
crazy about,
um,
some of the new google devices.
You take a photo of something and it
tells you what that thing is.
Like you take a photo of the coliseum
and it'll say there's the colosseum in
Rome.
You're like,
what?
Yeah,
the new pixel does.
It has that built in.
This isn't,
how about this.
They have this thing called the pixel
book.
We've seen the pixel book.
You buy a pen and you circle things on a
screen and it tells you what those
things are.
Yeah.
My it has that.
My no aid.
My note eight.
You can just circle like a sentence and
it will translate it on four year,
dude.
Yeah,
it's pretty second how long
for that becomes just standard,
you know,
and how much we're going to get to some
sort of Rosetta stone type situation
where we can read each other's thoughts.
Like you'll be able to just talk.
I mean,
right now the note taking software is
pretty damn good.
It's pretty God damn good.
Like if you talk into your phone,
whether it's with Google notes or
anything else with apple notes,
it'll pick up your voice very,
very well.
But what,
what is it going to be like in five
years from now?
It's going to be incredible.
And you're gonna be able to do it in
real time like they're doing with those
ear buds,
those Google earbuds,
you know,
they're gonna be able to do that in real
time all the time.
And so there's going to be no language
barriers than anybody ever has with
anybody else.
It's amazing,
isn't it weird?
Yeah,
it's crazy.
And then when you have the robot fights
between the robot fights and no language
barriers.
Yeah.
Arrange.
What is this?
I saw this at twitchcon.
Is this eye tracking new?
Uh,
it's replaces your mouse basically using
your eyes.
Yeah.
It's a little sensor that's on the
bottom right below your,
uh,
right below your screen.
Kind of like where the folders on your
laptop basically.
And you do a little bit of setting up
and it literally tracks everything
you're looking at.
Oh my God did it really well.
I saw,
I saw a little test right in front of
me.
Well,
that worked for games.
That's the idea.
If you're a tired though,
maybe you bitch,
that'd be insane.
You imagine if you got that down to
games and your,
your,
your cursor moved exactly where you
wanted to go.
It might be too easy be fucking people
up with that.
Wait a second.
This is,
is this an old video?
Because it just said like,
they were just advertising the head u s
2.09 instead of 3.0 I just works over
two point doesn't need 3.0 I see.
Wow.
Tagged your enemies by glancing at them.
Boom,
boom.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
So whether or not games actually needed
or it becomes,
uh,
something actually useful in the future.
We'll see.
But that's just,
it's been announced and that's coming
soon or it's out now.
Some alienware laptops that think or
having it built into it.
I do not even with my eyes,
daymond my eyes.
Just forget the face of your father.
Yeah,
we're,
I mean,
we're at the cusp of some really wacky
virtual reality,
augmented reality type shit that's just
around the corner.
It's going to happen.
It's going to take us by storm and it's
going to be just like all these other
things that we use,
like automatically wouldn't even think
about it because before twitter existed
that you didn't even think about it
before podcasts existed,
you'd never even thought this would
could be a possibility.
That's going to be the new one that's
going to,
that's going to be fucking crazy.
Some augmented reality type shit that
you were then eventually they're going
to have the robot eyeballs.
Brian's going to go,
he's going to be an early adopter.
I do.
One of them starts hard,
worn glasses can read my phone.
I've lost my glasses but I would do one
first if if after a few years of testing
and stuff like that.
But uh,
what did you do one and try one out?
I think there's gonna be a bunch of
options.
I think there's going to be options in
terms of like augmented parts and then I
think there's also going to be options
in terms of like dumb being able to
regenerate parts.
I think that's just around the corner
too cause they already being,
they can regenerate a lot of shit now
with stem cells.
They grew a woman's bladder.
They made a bladder with skin cells and
grew.
She had bladder cancer,
they grew her a new bladder.
There was that guy that's growing a new
nose on his forehead.
Have,
do you see that?
Is that from the same thing from stem
cells?
Jesus.
And it's weird like on his 40
[inaudible] he has a nose growing or
it's an ear and he's growing it for him.
His nose
let us do that for,
I don't know where hats,
no one would know.
I saw a dude.
We're a video rather,
where dude was getting,
there we go.
Oh Jesus.
It's going to have a crazy knows guide
one.
That's so weird.
It looks fake,
but it's on national geographic's.
Yeah,
it's real.
What's wrong with his regular knows it.
I think
some,
I forget what happened.
Wow,
that's so strange.
Oh,
it looks like it was burnt,
man.
That's,
that's another really crazy thing.
Have you ever seen what they do with,
um,
with a skin that's been burnt now?
They spray stem cells,
all of the skin and it kills the burns
and a regenerates fresh tissue in those
areas and you don't have a scar.
That's sweet.
That's like science fiction.
I mean that's literally out of star wars
or something.
Like when you see it,
they,
they show people with these like really
bad third degree burns are pretty fucked
up and they spray this stem cell mist
all over them and then their skin just
regenerate tissue,
like sweet feeling.
Yeah.
But it's really,
essentially we're talking about
something that had just a decade or two
ago would be absolutely witchcraft.
You know,
fuck man.
And they're,
they're blocking it to like,
we could be farther ahead in this whole
field if they let stem cell shit be
little bit more legal here now then it
then it used to be,
but I think the real issue was during
the Bush administration,
I think it was like fetal stem cells
they had a problem with,
they're really worried that people are
going to get abortions just on purpose
so they could sell the babies to stem
cell places and that people would be as
super immoral and just have a bunch of
abortions and make money off the baby
tissue.
I was like,
Ooh.
Which it tells my son.
So that's the problem,
right?
The problem has like,
like no,
nobody would do that.
Yes they would.
Motherfucker hasn't been approved yet.
So put it on paypal.
Jane's crimes when you're waiting
forever.
Ah Dude.
If you got burnt and they offered it to
you,
take it.
There's videos.
The videos are good.
Just here's the thing.
All the people that are like crazy
conspiracy theorists and worried about
science and Ugh,
you got to realize that science is
responsible for this kind of shit.
Science might be able to save one of
your kids.
Science might be able to fix your body.
These people are smarter than us.
We need to respect them and they're not
lying about this stuff.
Yeah.
There's people in the medical industry
that make a lot of money off of
pharmaceutical drugs at a bunch of
things that make people super addicted
and fuck up your life.
There's that too.
But there's also this,
it's like,
it's not perfect.
You should definitely call out the parts
that are bad,
but you kind of respect the people that
are smarter than us that are making all
the awesome shit.
Cause it's not you and it's not me.
Right.
But Jesus,
Joe,
Jesus made the people that made the
awesome shit.
So there,
I'll give you that.
How about that?
We'll leave it up,
uh,
and walk away.
Friends.
Ah,
you got to show big show is tonight.
Tonight.
Yeah.
Thomas Shore.
Asher,
Marilyn rights.
Got a bunch of people bringing Shoub
Brendan Schaub.
Um,
Lucas Lucas our,
yeah.
Well my watch and my Watkins Pat Reagan.
Oh Shit.
Going to be fun is that,
that's an Iot comedy store.
And then tomorrow I'm doing Sam Tripoli
show that's in the main room.
That's got a bunch of killers on it to
good times.
Ah,
this weekend,
Detroit,
I think shows are sold out.
I don't know.
I should pay more attention,
but we'll be back tomorrow with ct
Fletcher and Brian Callen.
It's a fucking double header day.
No,
I won't let Brian Cowen ruined ct
flushes interview.
Don't worry.
CTB be by himself then.
Brian Count will be later.
Ah.