The Joe Rogan experience.
So,
so what is it with scientology?
Um,
that's a good question.
I don't know,
like if they have ceremonies,
if they,
I think when you look at that Tom cruise
recruitment video,
which is fucking fantastic,
you know,
when he's standing out there,
if you've seen the one where they give
them a metal guests,
which is she fucking just so rich.
It's a giant metal,
many times larger than an Olympic gold
medal.
Uh,
uh,
he's wearing this metal and he's
standing there in front of a fucking.
It's called the freedom middle of valor
and he's standing in front of all those
people and he's such a charismatic
person.
There it is right there.
Oh,
Jesus Louisa's.
We'll look at that fucking thing.
Come on.
Just the,
the lack of like understanding how you
come across that would allow you to wear
that,
the lack of objectivity that it will
allow you to put that on and,
and,
and be able to do this fingertips down
thing on the,
uh,
on the desk.
Like you're making a very important
point while you're wearing a fucking
Frisbee,
a gold frisbee around your neck.
It's almost like he's trying to convince
himself by tricking all these people.
I think there's something to that.
There's something to,
if you can get a thousand people to
cheer at these words that you're saying
and you know,
no matter how fucking crazy they are,
if you can get all these people to
believe you and listened to you,
it sort of validates.
That may be you're not fucked up because
you're in with all these other people
that agree and fetuses and fucking,
you know,
all the other wacky shit that they
believe.
There's something to that where he's
putting on his massive performance.
Not just for them but for himself as
well.
I have my own bill o'reilly story.
Please send it to me.
Well,
the 48 laws of power just come out in
[inaudible] 98 and Bill O'reilly decides
to have me on the Riley if o'reilly
factor,
which was big then,
but not as big as it became later on.
And so I'm like,
this is like one of my first shows I've
ever been on.
No,
no,
nothing like this ever happened to me
before.
And basically you go to a studio in Los
Angeles where he's in New York and
you're in this room and there's nothing
around you.
And they put an earphone in your head
and you're staring at a camera.
You don't see anything.
You just hear bill o'reilly's stupid
fucking voice in your ear asking you
questions.
It's like you're on drugs and it's so
disconcerting.
It's like the guy who's trying to put
you off your game before you're already
put off your game,
the moment you start.
Anyway,
he interviews me and I prepared like
shit for this interview because I knew
the questions coming.
It was all about Monica Lewinsky and
Clinton and the scandal and the 48 laws.
And I nailed it.
And he said,
oh,
that was a great interview,
Robert.
I'm going to have you on again.
Okay.
Wow.
And so I'm feeling pretty good about
myself.
So four weeks later I trudge back to
that office and I sit in that same chair
with a little earphone in my head and he
proceeds to just rip me to shreds about
what?
Well,
essentially he hated the 48 laws of
power.
He liked the writing or whatever,
but he was just using,
posing his game.
He was just,
you know,
completely.
He was just using it as a way to attack
Clinton,
which I wasn't wanting to do that.
So anyway,
sorry.
He was just like totally messing with me
and I was so expecting the opposite that
I was like,
Ooh.
And then he goes,
and then he says,
well,
what about this law about use selective
honesty?
And I said,
well,
it's something that politicians and
business people use all the time.
Like Lyndon Johnson for instance.
And then I was about to explain how
Lyndon Johnson's and he cuts me off.
Yes,
yes.
The same man who said 58,000 men of our
young men to death in Vietnam,
let's break for a commercial.
And that was the end of the interview.
So he like made me look like I was
supporting Lyndon Johnson,
mit massacring,
58,000 Americans in Vietnam.
He manipulated me and humiliated me and
like,
and the whole thing was he hates the 48
laws of power because it's all about
manipulation and ugliness and he's the
most fucking manipulative interviewer
you could ever imagine.
Look how he manipulated me.
He completely set me up by making me
think this was going to be like a,
a softball interview where we were just,
you know,
I think.
Did I tell you this?
I've told it,
I'll stop.
We've found out it was on a little
plane.
You're on a giant plane and it was on
like a 7:37 year old that you in
Australia,
Virgin,
a Virgin Australia,
which has a groovy airline.
So on the flight with me and my wife has
the game,
you know,
this guy is rapper rod,
he's got a tattoo and whatnot.
And Carrie Hilden who's also a rapper
and,
and their policy,
right?
So it's hectic,
It starts to get them p and the pilot
comes on and goes like everybody's strap
in.
Okay.
For like ever,
and Australia's 15 hours,
16 minutes long this whole day.
And this lasted literally five hours,
right?
Jess?
Bouncing up and down,
side to side,
pitching yard,
the whole thing.
And on the,
on the sky map it says like,
Paygo,
1500 kilometers,
meaning your 1500 kilometers from paygo,
paygo.
In other words,
the Pacific Ocean is so big,
there's no land masses,
nothing anywhere near you.
Where are your going over?
Right?
So you're not going to go in because
it's turbulence,
it's not your fucking freak me out.
This is electric turbulence make planes
crash and doesn't,
unless there's some sort of shitty as
structural defect on the plane,
like the,
you know,
the wings aren't glued on or whatever.
But I mean,
not a structural defect.
Generally.
Generally you've been in a pilot
turbulence data,
you know,
that's not what makes them crashing,
you know?
But anyways,
he said it's terrible in any case.
So we get through it and the next
morning,
uh,
the rappers get up and they're all like,
oh my God,
I thought I was going to die.
And you know,
it was so bad last night I was praying
and La,
la La,
they're all like really shook up and
carry.
Hilton is a very lovely young rapper.
Lady wakes up.
It's been all night.
Mind you,
no one can move.
I stopped holding my wife's hand for
five.
You know,
like,
like this for you goes like this.
Oh,
what happened?
And the wrappers because you didn't feel
that we are going to die that night.
She goes,
I take a pill.
I didn't see any ambien's a
motherfucker.
And then she ate one piece of fruit and
put on a leopard miniskirt and came out
with their makeup and signed autographs.
And I was like,
you're a star.
I want you on my team.
You are Alexander the Great.