Hello Freak bitches.
You can converse in like an a type the
type of English we're talking right now
almost,
which creates this weird tension between
the things that you're discussing and
how you're discussing them.
Like for instance,
to have a guy just in conversational
English talking about problems they're
having with neighboring schamens and
their own Sharman putting curses on each
other and it like creates like,
there's like a strange tension between
like how it's being conveyed to you.
You know,
like how,
so like,
okay,
if you're talking conversational English,
I guess like a life,
it's almost like you'd want it
to be when he's telling you this,
you'd almost want to be reading it in
like closed caption and he'd be saying it
in the indigenous language because it
sounds weird to have to have an idea
that's so foreign to us,
which would be like a battle of schamens
battling over access to wild animals.
Okay.
Um,
to have that delivered in conversational
English has struck me as unusual.
And because like usually
when you're traveling,
you're getting all of your information
like traveling and Bolivia,
a guy would tell a story
and he'd tell a story in um,
Sim Shyanne no one was staying
in that same Shan Chimani.
Okay.
He tells story in Chimani to
a person who spoke Spanish.
The person who speaks Spanish
would tell it to a person.
No,
no,
no.
Chimani guy telling someone
who speaks Chimani in Spanish.
Then that person telling it to a person
who speaks Spanish and English and then
that person giving you the information.
When you get it through that
it takes on a mystical quality.
Like you're crossing
some space time thing,
right.
Where you're seeing like these ideas
discussed in their ancestral tongue.
Okay.
Yeah.
Tamara sent you a video of a guy
talking about killing a Jaguar.
Yes.
Right.
The language you've never like
when he's speaking you're like,
I've never in all my travels,
I've never heard of language.
It sounds anything like that
right here.
Yeah.
I don't want to leave.
You can use a Kombucha bottle.
Yeah,
man.
It's the healthiest for all of the PD.
You've done this twice.
Really?
Yeah.
We've done this on the podcast for great.
For sure.
I liked the fact that you're
willing to do that too.
I don't think we could
show it on youtube though,
so we'll have to,
we'll have to move away up or
he's got his dick out great too.
Cause I got a big opening.
Yeah.
So it doesn't vacuum up.
How often dup dup several times.
Every day.
You like one of them are
healthy water drinker dudes.
I PLR.
Do you,
are you a healthy water drinker?
Dude?
Interesting detail.
This just happened.
Oh,
you ran out?
I don't know.
Uh,
hold on a second.
I to go to the recycling.
Got It's all right.
I'm pitching.
I've got a strong grip as you can move,
but it's all have to take it lightly.
Touching them.
A bottle.
A cop,
not a bottle.
Hold on,
hold on.
Oh,
model.
Seems like.
Oh man,
it's going back in though.
I can feel it starting to swell back yet.
That's unhealthy.
I'm putting,
I've been pitching too long.
Should I pay into the cup or bottle yet?
Oh,
you emptied it.
thanks man.
Oh yeah.
A lot went back into my urethra.
Ari should fear,
uh,
couldn't hold in his pee.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Couldn't means wouldn't
filled up one Kombucha bottle.
Here's a cap they're feeling
and then fill it up again.
I had to go empty it out for him.
Thanks for doing that.
Applies on the front.
Yeah.
I didn't want to leave
you hanging in there,
dude.
Really?
There was only one solution.
I almost went to the kitchen
sink and then I put it like,
Ooh.
Then we'd have to rinse that out.
That shit would be nasty there.
That bathroom sick as nasty.
You're going to have a cleaner in here?
No,
it's like,
it looks like a bachelor.
We're on our way out of the spot.
Oh Man.
It's not that bad.
I just use the time to fucking tweet
about my new record saying had I kept
tweeting that James Comey was,
it was all code for my new record,
that he wanted people to buy it.
I know.
I saw some of the Instagram posts and
how to call me endorsing your album.
Yeah.
He's a big fan.
He,
he,
he said he wanted to talk about it
during the hearings cause that's a big
audience.
But apparently they wouldn't let them go.
Yeah.
Collusion between me and Comi
would have fucked things up.
Is that what it's called?
Yeah,
it's uh,
well I actually,
it's funny cause this guy,
cause there's,
they say there's a chance which looking
less like there's this guy Luke combs
who's like my arch nemesis
even though he's a good dude.
I just,
he was up against me this week on the
country charts cause my album comes out,
my new album came out this week
and I'm trying to beat him.
And I said on Twitter that Russians have
colluded with Sony records to like have
him outsell me and he
kind of played along.
So we'll see.
I think,
I think they are,
I mean Nashville is definitely
trying to keep me down,
but
are they really,
are they fucking with you?
Like how,
how were they receiving you now?
Now that you've become
a mainstream success?
Cause I hear about you all the time.
Donald Cowboy Cerrone,
I think you know that he listens to your
music before he goes out and fights.
Oh,
cowboy Cerrone reached
out to me thanks to you.
He called,
he called me up and he was on the set
of a movie with Michael Madsen and uh,
they go,
I don't know how it
seems like last second,
but they go,
hey capital,
you had a scene tomorrow where you
sing Karaoke with Michael Madsen.
And he saw you on saying,
and he's like,
fucking eating pussy
kicking ass producers.
Like fuck you talking about.
He's like,
I want to sing eating pussy kicking ass.
do you have the rights to this song?
He's like,
I'll have it in like five minutes.
And he just fucking calls me.
I call my peoples like now I'm in a movie
with cowboy Cerrone and Michael Madsen
singing and eating pussy kicking ass.
He said he was in the trailer,
you know,
like,
rehearsing with Michael
Madsen and you know,
it gets to the sucking Dick Parker.
I think he was just like,
what the fuck we sing in here?
So it's just the,
uh,
it's the threat of losing
everything in moderation.
Yeah.
Being ostracized by and just sort of
expelled into this world that you believe
and have always believed
is as evil and without
hope and doomed.
So how did you do it?
How did your,
your,
you got all your stuff packed.
People are coming in,
they're saying,
yeah.
I mean like they're,
they're,
they're trying to convince us,
but once they understand that
we're not being convinced that,
that,
you know,
they,
they walked away.
So I mean that night our dad dropped us
off at a hotel and then Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
Like it's,
it's,
it's so immediate that you become this,
you become other,
you become an outsider.
Like in the next morning
when we went back,
I rang the doorbell,
I rang the doorbell and I lived in
that house from the day I was born.
Whoa.
Felt like you had to ring the doorbell.
This is not my world anymore.
Wow.
Chris was like,
why don't you ring the doorbell?
And it was like,
there's,
there's no other,
there is nothing else.
Like it's,
this is not our home.
It says not so we go and,
you know,
we're packing all of our things.
It was just,
it was awful just to,
I had been in those four months,
I had been so terrified of not
knowing what was coming like this.
Imagine you're going to lose everyone
in your life that they're just,
you're just going to like,
you're not going to like how your
parents met and fell in love or like your
grandparents and family recipes and photos
and memories and what did the house,
I'm like taking photos and voice
recordings and just all the time,
like in every,
it was just,
it's just,
it's overwhelming.
It's just,
um,
it may be at least understand that the
source of my dissatisfaction in life
wasn't internal.
It Wa it made sense.
It was that I was having a healthy
reaction to circumstances in society that,
that humans were not adapted for.
And even that was enough to bring
a kind of peace of mind for me.
Um,
I also very consciously and deliberately
try to live in places where there is
the possibility of,
of um,
uh,
sort of close communal neighborhood.
I live in a very poor neighborhood in
New York City at which for some of the
hassles at least has the sort of rich
fabric of human connection that you just
don't get in wealthy neighborhoods.
So you'd do it on purpose.
Oh yeah.
What would,
I don't want you to say,
where do you want to say where you live?
I live in lower east side
Manhattan and I mean,
he's not very,
very poor,
but it's,
it,
you know,
is a Dominican to Dominican neighborhood,
have half the people in that neighborhood
really don't speak English very well.
So it's,
you know,
it's a very,
it's a very rich or ethnic neighborhood.
People are quite poor.
Um,
and,
and I know everybody and we,
everyone knows each other by sight
and we look out for each other.
And it's,
I mean,
during hurricane,
a hurricane,
when hurricane sandy hit New York,
I mean,
a lot of the people that had young
children had to leave because there was no
light,
there was no water.
The power was out right to half
of Manhattan was completely dark.
It was really actually quite dangerous
at night in the dark half a Manhattan
and,
uh,
where there was no streetlights.
And,
um,
so this building,
it's a tenement building that
I live in with my wife and um,
and a lot of the people left and that
they were worried about being robbed and
these are poor people,
right?
It is not a wealthy building at all,
is quite,
quite poor building.
And so they,
they,
they organized a guard shift.
One of the people,
one of the women in the building had a
machete and they organized guard shifts
at the front door with
a machete and the young,
the young men in the building took turns
like two hours at a time guarding the
building with a machete.
Oh yeah.
And um,
you know,
I wasn't associated with
the building at that time,
but boy would that have made me
feel good to be part of that.
That,
you know what I mean?
Like that is what human beings,
that's what they are.
Right.
It's that right.
And you,
you didn't see that in
a wealthy neighborhood,
partly because the wealthy
neighborhoods actually had light.
Right.
Okay.