Um,
my boy woke me up at like every hour.
I'm hoping I didn't have mommy brain
boom.
And we're alive.
The newly mommy.
Dr Rhonda Patrick.
First of all,
congratulations on making people.
Thank you Mandy.
For Person.
Yeah,
the colonial project was a success.
We were talking
for the show about what a strange
biological shift happens in your mind
and isn't it?
It's amazing,
isn't it?
And not just your mind,
right?
Like your person.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
It's completely amazing am.
I had no idea that I would love being a
mom so much.
I kind of waited till later in life to,
to have a child and that was for a
reason because as you know,
really driven and loved what I was doing
in science and I felt I didn't feel that
calling to like I've got to reproduce
it.
Forgot to reproduce.
And then finally I was like,
well,
if I don't reproduce now I might not get
a chance.
So,
you know,
I,
that sort of pressure kind of nudged me
a little bit I think.
Um,
but yeah,
the whole process of getting pregnant
and having this like,
you know,
person growing inside of me,
just the whole thing was amazing.
And then after having the baby and he's
like a person now and he's four months
old and developing this little
personality,
I'm like so amazed by how in love I am
with him and how like,
how much I would do anything for him and
how almost nothing really affects me as
much like stress of various things in
life,
you know,
I just look at him and you know,
see him,
smile at me and do some little things
that are like uniquely him and the
wonder and awe in his eyes and it's just
like gone,
like,
it's really amazing sound.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
It changes your life.
It changes who you are as a human being,
you know,
in uh,
changes in a way that you did have a lot
of friends that are like,
I don't want kids.
I never wanted kids.
And like wow,
I kind of didn't really want kids either
when I was 30 kids.
But then once you have them,
you realized like,
oh,
like I was just sort of attached to this
idea of living my life the way I was
living it,
and I'm like,
this is the way I like to live life.
And then you have a kid,
you're like,
oh no,
I love this kid more than anything.
Like.
So now my whole idea of what life is
shifts into this new paradigms and also
the thing like reproduce always weirds
me out because you're not,
you're making people not reproducing
anything.
You know,
I mean you're,
you're making people.
It's a whole new person.
You're not reproducing you.
True.
I mean it,
it is in a way.
I mean there's definitely reproductions
the right way to say you're passing on a
lot of the same,
you know,
variations in genes that you have and
you're obviously,
you know,
there are similarities in the way they
look to,
to,
to both you and your spouse.
But yeah,
it is a completely new person with a new
personality.
But of course,
all that is shaped a lot by your diet
and exercise
and all those things that you do,
even aside from your actual genetics and
passing on the sequence of DNA,
like just,
you know,
things that you do in your lifestyle
actually can affect,
um,
you know,
the child's neurocognitive development
and uh,
you know,
met metabolism now where you cognizant
of that or you obviously you're very
aware of that.
But did you,
what did you do to act on that?
I should ask?
Yeah.
So I mean I did.
I'm definitely became obsessed with
trying to optimize everything I could,
you know,
because I'm a scientist and I can sort
of sift through the literature.
I think I,
you can,
you can kind of get stuck in this loop
where you want to like optimize
everything and you kind of have to like
chill out a little bit.
But you know,
during pregnancy I wanted to make sure,
you know,
all the micronutrients I was getting,
because they're so important for brain
development and like full late
magnesium,
iron,
zinc,
and then Dha,
vitamin D,
All these things were super important.
I'm actually with the Dha,
I found out that I'm taking,
so Dha is the marine omega three fatty
acid that's predominantly found in like
micro algae for vegetarians versus,
but in fish fatty fish,
well it turns out that the Dha that's in
what's called phospholipid form,
which is something that's found in the
row of fish.
So like fish eggs,
it's also found in Krill as well.
Um,
and fish only have like a small
percentage,
so fish have Dha like one percent of
their djs and phospholipid form.
Whereas the row of the fish,
anywhere between 40 to 70 percent is in
phospholipid form.
And the thing that's really cool about
this is that the fossil liquid form,
it's been shown when you take that
orally,
it stays more of,
it ends up in the phospho lip,
a certain type of phospholipid form in
the blood that has been shown to get
into the developing fetal brain 10 times
better than an Dha and non libet form
free fatty acid form.
So it was just something that should be
consumed.
Look for regular people as well or for
primarily mothers.
So yeah,
for I think both,
but the fact that it gets taken up into
the developing fetal brain 10 times
better was enough,
you know,
ammunition for me to be like I'm eating
the Salmon Roe,
you know,
but,
but yeah,
so they're all have also been studies on
preclinical studies on,
on,
uh,
taking Dha,
EPA and fossil performing in,
in mice.
It's taken up better than non fossil
Lippitt.
And then there's been some clinical
studies where they like radio label and
follow it in humans.
And again,
it's taken up better in the brain by
humans as well.
And actually what's really interesting
is I just submitted a paper for
publication on Alzheimer's disease and a
certain variation in a gene called apoe
e four,
which I think you and I talked a lot
about traumatic brain injury,
um,
and susceptibility to Alzheimer's
disease.
And basically I'm a bunch of,
you know,
dementia type of problems.
Um,
well April before sort of helps increase
that risk.
So I've,
you know,
turns out there is because there's
different transport mechanisms to get
Dha into the brain.
The phospholipid form appears to be
better for April before,
and that's sort of my finding.
I'm not going to get all into the
mechanism,
but that's hopefully fingers crossed
going to be accepted for peer review
from peer review with the next couple
months.
That's fascinating.
So you eating Salmon Roe,
that's what you were saying you were
getting your source from?
I was,
yeah,
I was eating Salmon Roe.
Um,
I was ordering it from a company that,
you know,
has wild Alaskan Salmon Roe and then you
can buy it in bulk.
The company was called a vital choice is
nasty.
It tasted nasty during my first
trimester.
I was like,
Oh,
maybe I should wait.
But you know,
the texture a lot of people don't like,
like Dan doesn't like the texture
because like the salmon roe is like
bigger.
The fish eggs are bigger and so it can
kind of pop in like you get like little
fish to fish for trout really trout
would eat salmon roe.
So we would fish for trout using salmon
eggs.
Well,
I mean the salmon eggs are like quite a
bit larger.
Yeah.
The credit larger,
there's other ones like I think it's the
flying fish that are really small in the
Fascial Epa,
Dha and foster the bid form varies from
species,
you know,
different types of fish and things like
that.
But generally speaking they're,
you know,
it's,
it's a good thing to eat and especially
during pregnancy.
So how did you consume it on Avocados?
I put it on top of Bob Ocado is with
some lemon juice and like,
like hot sauce.
So just kind of like a Paleo training.
Yeah,
it was like a lot of fat.
So avocados have potassium,
low,
mono unsaturated fat and vitamin E,
all the different forms,
you know.
So Avocados,
a mono unsaturated fat and saturated
fat,
right.
They have a small amount of saturated
fat.
Probably a small amount.
Yeah.
When I say they have,
like,
typically when I talk about foods,
um,
I'll talk about what's,
you know,
what's concentrated,
so it's like really concentrated in
Mahnomen saturated fat.
So whereas like if you say,
you know,
butter or cheese and it's concentrated
in saturated fat,
but typically you'll find mono poly and
saturated fat in all different forms of
fat.
It just very varying amounts.
Right.
And to some degree it's like,
well it's not even really significant.
It's such a small amount.
I don't know how much of the Salmon Roe
were you consuming?
It really depends.
Like I started to really start to ramp
up my consumption.
I'm in the third trimester when brain
development and just like really getting
crazy thinking about this every day.
So every day I was putting a big old
tablespoon full on top of my avocado.
A really third trimester was like,
I was like almost everyday trying to
consume it,
but it was hard for me.
The first trimester I was,
I started to try a little bit and it
made me a little nauseous.
Like I know if your kid can read minds
when it,
it comes out and he's like super brain.
Everyone probably is super biased about
their own children,
but I'm like,
he's got great verbal skills and him
super smart.
You're super smart.
Like this,
and you're eating all these fish,
eggs,
kids.
This kid said,
oh,
thank you.
It'll be interesting.
It can.
We can talk to him.
He's going to be forced sitting right
there.
What's funny is he was like early on
when he was six weeks old,
he was,
he went through a really short stage of.
He was making sounds that sounded like
hello.
And so my mom would come over and she
would in his face,
she would go,
hello,
hello.
And he would.
And we have a video of it,
like I could send it to you,
I'll send it to you.
He would go and it like literally seems
like he's saying it,
but clearly he's not.
I mean he's six weeks old,
you know?
But he was able to sort of mimic the
sound because I think it was easier for
him since he was already sort of making
those sounds.
So of course Dan and Ryan and Dan and I
were super pumped.
We're like,
he's gonna be a genius.
We're sending the video to other family
members.
You should really listen to what we say.
See,
oh,
that's,
of course you know,
he's not really saying hello,
but making noises,
he's making noises.
It sounds like it.
And it was totally coincidental but was
just the difference between like a kid
making a noise and a kid knowing what
the noise means.
Like when they're actually talking to my
mom,
my seven year old,
the seven year old,
she didn't really start talking in full
sentences until she was like a year and
a half,
but my,
my nine year old,
like when she was like nine,
10 months old,
she was talking.
It was weird.
It's like she's really smart.
Like she was talking like right away,
like,
and she was stood up quicker too.
She,
she was standing at like nine months
old,
which I found pretty shocking,
like an unassisted standing.
That's when she wanted to stand in nine
months old.
She was getting her stand on and I'm
trying to take some steps and I was like
this crazy,
like she's just,
she's like,
that's how she is as a little person
too.
She's a little go getter.
I often wonder,
you know,
that the earlier the first borns and the
ones that are born earlier,
like if they get more attention to,
because it's novel here,
they're first time parents and then as
more children come,
you know,
it's like you're just,
you're,
you're spread a little more thin and you
know,
I mean,
it's not necessarily the case,
but it's certainly something I've often
wondered,
you know,
if,
if we,
if I want to have another child,
will I be able to do it,
you know,
it's because I really just wanted.
There's so much work that goes into not
just,
you know,
the nutrition part.
And I was talking about,
you asked me about,
you know,
things during pregnancy and something I
think people don't realize is that,
you know,
epigenetics,
which is basically the transference of,
um,
it's,
it's heritable.
Like you can transfer things that
happened to you in your lifestyle
without actually altering the sequence
of DNA.
And you can do that by changing how much
gene is activated or not activated.
And there's been studies,
lots and lots of stomach studies in
animals showing this to be the case.
Of course,
that's animals and how much of that
actually translates to humans,
but there was a really interesting study
a couple of years ago,
I think it was late 2015 that was
published that looked at the effect of
obesity and obesity was actually looked
at,
not in the mothers but the fathers.
Um,
and so a sperm DNA was collected from,
for males that were obese and males that
were lean and that there's a variety of
different genes like hundreds of
different genes that were looked at and
about 300 different genes were different
in how they were activated or not
activated in the sperm Dna of the obese
men.
And a lot of those genes had to do with
cognition,
learning,
memory and metabolism.
So that's very interesting.
But what was super interesting was that
these men,
they were morbidly obese or obese.
They underwent bariatric surgery and
their sperm DNA was collected,
uh,
you know,
a couple of months after then,
like close to a year after.
And as time went on,
their sperm DNA looked like the lean
people.
So the,
so basically losing the weight,
just losing the weight.
Had an effect on these genes that are
involved in cognition and metabolism.
Like I said,
you know,
lots of animal studies have shown
obesity has a negative effect on like,
you know,
causing type one diabetes later in life
and different cognitive disabilities and
things like that.
So you know,
it is something like people that are
wanting to conceive my might consider,
you know,
their,
their health before trying to procreate.
You know,
it's,
I'm not saying that,
you know,
you shouldn't procreate if you're not
healthy,
but it's just something,
you know,
another thing to think about and also I
think it's a motivating factor for
people because sometimes you don't care
as much about yourself.
I mean some people don't,
they're just kinda like,
but their child or their unborn child,
that's probably,
you know,
a driver for,
for people to make a change like that
would certainly hope it would be.
I mean,
you have this opportunity to really
literally changed the way your child
develops.
And it's just by your discipline,
right?
Just by whether or not you're taking
care of your own body,
you can literally change the future of
your trial because you're saying that
these genes that are in this obese man
sperm,
the way they're represented that's going
to be passed onto the kid versus the
lean version of him pass those genes.
We've passed on to the kid.
The kid literally will have a different
starting point.
Exactly.
Different starting point.
It's totally crazy.
Yeah.
I mean,
of course the child itself can change
things through epigenetics,
through their diet and lifestyle,
but you're giving them a baseline here,
right?
I mean,
so it's,
it's,
it's definitely a very,
it's a growing field.
A lot of the research has done in
animals because it's really difficult to
do that sort of,
these sorts of experiments in humans.
But I think that this is sort of a proof
of principle at the very least looking
at sperm DNA.
Um,
you know,
so it,
it's,
it's something to consider.
And I've had like,
like friends of friends that have,
you know,
that are,
that are overweight or obese and wanting
to have children.
And so it's like,
I tried to talk to them about that in a,
in a way that's not like condescending,
you know,
some people,
some people do have a hard time,
they're trying to lose weight and you
know,
this,
they have to find the right combination
of things that works for them.
But,
um,
but I do think that people would get
more motivated if they're like,
wow,
I can,
you know,
affect my future child risk for type one
diabetes or for,
you know,
like how well what their Iq is,
how well they're performing on learning
and memory test.
So it also avoid the horrific guilt that
you would feel if you didn't do that.
And you started to see these things
manifesting in your child when you
realize,
oh my God,
I sent this kid up in a shitty way
because I'm lazy.
Which is essentially what a lot of the
problem is with people.
It's just that they don't have what,
whatever.
The mental,
you know,
and people get angry if you say that
either they're lazy because they don't
die it for.
Forget that word.
Forget to take away the word Lazy.
You're unmotivated will say that,
but for whatever reason,
if you choose not to take care of your
health and you see that transfer into
your child and you know that you're
unhappy with your existence,
you know you're unhappy with your
physical body and you refuse to do or
for whatever reason don't do enough,
and then you see these same problems
manifesting in your own baby and you
realize like,
oh my God,
I started this kid off in a shitty way.
Like you're going to be riddled with
guilt.
Totally.
I mean,
the thing is most people don't know
about avid genetics and they don't
really know that they're,
that they're able to do that.
So the more.
The more people are educated,
I think the better the outcome will be.
But like you said,
the people that do now and then still do
it,
it's like,
yeah,
the guilt.
I mean that's like unbelievable.
Well,
it's like people who smoke when they
have a kid,
you know,
that's,
that's so insane.
You see people that are pregnant,
smoking.
I was in,
I forget what state it was in,
but we were outside this convenience
store and there was a lady who was
clearly pregnant and she clearly was
smoking cigarettes and I was like,
fuck man,
that's just gross Canada.
It was like,
this hurts my feelings.
Just watching.
That just hurts my feelings.
It doesn't,
it just make you sick.
Yeah.
That's like,
you know,
and there's all sorts of studies that
have shown,
you know,
of course smoking during pregnancy
causes or not causes associated with
like Adhd and um,
uh,
what's it called?
Like the movement,
just like a,
like a dyskinesia thing,
you know,
all sorts of problems.
So it's certainly like I having the
knowledge and continuing to read
throughout pregnancy.
Then once,
you know,
having the baby,
like one thing that I knew that I
really,
really wanted to do was I wanted to
breastfeed.
Like that was,
you know,
like they're,
the benefits of breastfeeding are just
amazing and this is something that like
my,
like my stepmother for example,
her generation also my,
my grandmother,
they didn't know about like,
so they weren't
recommended to breastfeed.
You know,
back in like the fifties,
like it just wasn't,
you know,
the benefits weren't known,
but now we know like breastfeeding,
it's kind of amazing.
There are something,
there's something in breast milk called
human milk oligosaccharides.
Have you heard of these?
Hmo.
There's like 200 different of oligos
human milk oligosaccharides in breast
milk.
In fact,
it's like the third most common factor
in breast milk behind lactose and fat,
200 different ones and they cannot be
digested at all by like the infants.
I'm digestive system.
It's like they co evolved specifically
to feed the microbiome in the gut of
these infants and they're in there
specifically increasing the species of
bacteria.
I'm bifidobacteria in fantasy is one
really,
really important one,
but it's,
it's amazing that they're,
it's really,
that's the only purpose that they serve
is to feed and you know,
basically populate the infant gut with
this beneficial bacteria and you know,
this bacteria has been shown to one
setup the immune system because they
digest these oligosaccharides and they
produce other molecules called short
chain fatty acids and those short chain
fatty acids like lactate,
butyrate,
Acetate,
things that you've heard of those act as
what are called signaling molecules to
basically determine what kind of immune
cells you're going to make.
So a big one that they do is they make a
t regulatory cells,
which are kind of immune cells that
prevents autoimmunity,
autoimmune responses.
So like children that are not,
um,
that,
that are not breastfed,
they lack like four different species
of,
um,
of gut bacteria and they have like a
three,
three fold increased risk of allergies
and um,
you know,
autoimmune related diseases.
So it's like,
it's doing that.
And also it's like preventing pathogenic
bacteria from,
from like taking residents there.
Um,
because these human milk
oligosaccharides,
not only are they feeding the beneficial
bacteria will recently,
it's been found that they like break
down biofilms that bacteria create to
like,
you know,
basically escape antimicrobial activity.
So there's a lot of antimicrobial things
in breast milk like lauric acid,
which is also found in coconut oil.
Um,
but the,
the human milk oligosaccharides
basically break down the biofilm so that
the lord acid can work better.
So it's like,
you know,
and their stem cells,
there are stem cells in breast milk,
mammary stem cells.
Like,
that blew my mind.
I think it's been like 10 years since
the discovery of that.
But like it's been.
So it's that the studies have been
mostly done in mice,
but they have measured.
Humans have the same memory type of stem
cells in their breast milk.
But in animals and preclinical studies,
it's been shown that those,
that,
those breast stem cells,
they get digested.
They go into the bloodstream and they go
to various organs.
They go to the kidney,
the liver,
the brain,
and they start to,
like in the pancreas,
they start to make like insulin
producing cells.
Like,
it's crazy.
Wow.
So that's amazing.
That's only 10 years ago.
They didn't notice.
Yeah,
I know.
It's all happening so fast when it comes
to knowledge of nutrition and the effect
on the body and especially
developing children.
Well,
the breast milk thing is really what's
interesting because once I like,
you know,
I had my son and you immediately start
breastfeeding.
Like I had no idea it was going to be so
difficult.
Like I thought it was just,
and maybe it's not difficult for
everyone,
but I think it's difficult for a lot of
women and a lot of women give up after
like the first two weeks they give up
because you know that it's just for
various reasons.
It gets,
it can be extremely frustrated.
You're a new parent,
you're getting no sleep and you know,
so um,
like I,
my son had a little bit of a tongue
time,
right?
Like the little thing on underneath his
tongue kind of prevented a tongue from
moving like as much as it's supposed to.
So like he,
when he opened his mouth and he'd latch
on,
there was a little bit of problem.
So the first two weeks were really hard
for me,
but that sort of resolved,
but I really had to try like my,
like Dan and I were,
were taking,
I was pumping some,
some milk and we are putting it in a
syringe with a little tube and like
putting them on the breast,
you know,
because I didn't want to introduce the
bottle so early.
So I mean,
and that was hard.
I mean,
I was getting no sleep.
I could totally see if you didn't know
all the benefits of breastfeeding that I
could,
I could see how new mothers would,
would give up because it's extremely
difficult.
So,
um,
that's something that I completely
understand.
I understand now.
I think previously I was like,
how can anyone not press feed,
you know,
it's so,
but it,
it really,
it's not easy for everyone.
There's all sorts of problems that women
have,
but there are actually breast milk banks
that like,
so women can donate their breast milk
and um,
people,
you know,
can,
can buy the breast milk instead of
getting formula.
Now of course there's all sorts of other
problems.
It's like,
wow,
they're getting enough vitamin D and
Omega three and what else are they
taking?
You know,
you,
there's so many different things that
happen once you have children,
breast milk,
being a breastfeeding,
I'm sure being one of them,
but the lack of sleep thing,
which I think most people just really
don't,
don't have any idea like what,
what is happening and that they also
don't understand how difficult it is to
watch a child.
And right now it's difficult.
Wait until the kid starts walking.
They start walking around and you have
to follow them around.
You're literally like walking around
with them everywhere they go.
I got,
don't put that in your mouth.
Don't touch that lick that you'll get
electrocuted until it's like everywhere
you go,
it's,
it's such a,
I don't want to say a project,
it's,
um,
it's just way more difficult in
consuming then.
And also your protective instincts are
ramped up so high.
Like my friend Eddie had a cats and
rabbits and he's talking about how much
he loves his rabbits and he's like,
dude,
just wait until you have your kid.
You're going to want to kill fucking
rabbits.
He's like,
no way,
man.
I love the cats.
I love the rabbits.
And as soon as he had the kid,
he's like,
fuck you,
right cats.
He goes,
my cat wakes up,
my kid.
I want to kill this fucking cat.
It's true.
Your protective mechanisms I know
changes you.
It changes you so much and you know,
people that don't have children and who
complained about kids that are crying.
I used to,
used to bother me if I was on a plane
and babies are crying,
you know,
I used to be like,
aww baby won't shut up.
But now I'm like,
Oh,
poor little baby.
Like literally it doesn't bother me.
Like,
like someone could be a break right next
to me with a crying baby and I feel bad
for the baby.
It doesn't bother me.
Like,
damn,
his baby won't shut up.
It's like a different.
Totally.
I,
I've started to experience that to some
degree in,
in various ways as well where it's like
you just,
Oh,
the poor baby.
You become a different person.
Yeah.
You do.
You relate to it.
It's amazing.
Yeah,
it's,
it's the best thing ever.
Wow.
I mean,
it creates so much empathy.
it just changed my whole perspective of
what a person is,
is different.
Uh,
my,
my idea of a person used to be a static
form like Jamie's 35,
35,
34.
Like I would say,
God,
that's 34 year old Jamie.
That's who he is.
I never thought,
oh,
Jamie was a baby.
Like Jamie used to be a four year old.
Like Jamie went to preschool.
Jamie went to kindergarten there.
I never thought about it that way.
I'd be like,
oh,
there's Jamie.
Hey,
what's up Jamie?
Jamie's always been Jamie.
You know,
that's like how I used to look at
people.
Now we're looking at everybody as a
baby.
I called,
that's a baby that became a grown man.
Like that's how I look at everyone now.
It's so,
it's,
it's weird.
It's like a paradigm shift happened in
my brain.
That is,
that's,
that's definitely weird.
It made me way more compassionate.
Way,
way nicer to people,
which is way I just,
I think I don't want anybody's life to
fall apart anymore.
I used to like,
quieter.
I hope that guy gets hit by a truck,
you know?
Now I'm like,
man,
I hope that little baby figures out why
he's such an asshole.
Interesting to kind of see the brain
activation pathways that change.
Like,
you know,
if you're talking about being more
compassionate,
that's almost like,
I mean there's a certain type of
meditation,
like the compassion meditation that
people do that changes like certain
parts of the brain.
It kind of interesting to see my,
like Dan thinks that I've gotten more
creative because I make up all these
like mommy games and mommy songs.
Just like I never was really a super,
super creative person.
I'm more analytical,
you know,
I've got,
I definitely have some creativity,
but like he,
he's kind of like,
I wonder if just like becoming a mommy,
like you just all of a sudden become
more creative,
you know?
I don't know.
I'm sure there's a bunch of stuff going
on.
I mean,
your brain just gets activated.
It.
I do stuff with my seven year old
sometimes and half the time we're doing
stuff I'm like,
I can't even believe you're real.
Like I'm having these little
conversations with her were playing
little games and you know,
like we play this really stupid game.
It's so dumb.
So you spin this thing and it's like,
it corresponds to a different color
acorns and you know,
and when she wins and she jumps up,
she like,
oh I beat you.
And she's like doing her little dance
and she's like throwing her arms in the.
And I'm like,
this is like half of me is laughing
because she's funny,
but half of me is going,
this is so strange that you're a little
person that I'm talking to.
Like you,
you were a baby and now you're this
little seven year old playing this game
with me.
It's like,
it's so odd.
I feel that way with my four month old.
I see little personality things already
kind of creeping up and it's like,
that's amazing.
So I can only imagine like as he
continues to develop and that's why it's
very.
I think it's very difficult for people
that don't have children to sort of
develop that same level of
compassionate.
It sounds like a cop out.
It sounds like it sounds weird,
but I really do.
I think there's something,
there's actually something to be gained
and as far as like everyone reproducing.
Well obviously we have too many people,
so that's not.
I don't know if that's the best thing.
I certainly think that you could be a
fully formed,
healthy,
wonderful person who contributes an
amazing thing to the world if you don't
have children.
I don't think you have to have children,
but I think for me it was,
it was very much.
There was a,
there was a giant learning experience
along with it.
There's a giant evolving experience
along with just being a parent.
It was,
something happened to me.
It's,
it's,
it's absolutely life changing,
you know?
Um,
it's,
I,
I had no idea.
Like I've always heard people say that
the best thing that happened to me,
it truly is.
It truly is the best thing.
And,
uh,
so,
you know,
I'm,
I'm excited to,
to continue to see how it changes me and
it just unfortunately corresponds with a
lot of financial stress with a lot of
people,
time,
stress,
financial stress,
last lack of sleep and sometimes they
just don't appreciate it,
you know,
just you're so overwhelmed by the burden
of just trying to get by that sometimes
you can't appreciate this amazing moment
that happened in front of you and it's,
you know,
it's hard,
it's hard to,
it's hard to have a good perspective and
it's hard.
It's hard to like be able to see things
from above,
like to sort of rise above and look at
the big picture of this thing.
And that's,
for me,
something that really helps with that
is,
is exercise.
Sure.
I think that also,
you know,
I didn't have any postpartum depression,
at least I think I didn't.
I mean I think there's a variety of
factors.
I mean,
so for one,
you know,
your,
um,
during pregnancy,
your estrogen levels,
like they,
like they go through the roof.
I mean it's like 100 fold higher and
undertold something like that.
Like it's really high compared to your
baseline,
and don't quote me,
I'm going to be something I'm thinking
something like that,
like I've just orders and orders of
magnitude higher and estrogen and has
been shown to increase the expression of
a gene called Tryptophan hydroxylase to
in the brain that produces serotonin
from tryptophan.
So you're constantly making serotonin
constantly,
constantly.
And then,
you know,
after you have the baby that goes away.
So it's Kinda like
a withdrawal.
So that's sort of one biochemical
explanation.
But there are many others.
One,
I think your circadian rhythm is off.
You're not,
you're not getting enough light because
you're like nasty,
like you.
Like,
I don't think we left.
I mean,
I don't even remember going outside for
like two weeks maybe.
Yeah.
It was like,
you know,
especially with the difficult
breastfeeding part.
So it was like you're constantly inside.
You're not getting that bright light
exposure.
Your sleep is completely disrupted.
So your circadian rhythm,
which is,
you know,
extremely,
extremely important for,
for mood,
for the way you feel,
uh,
that is completely disrupted because
you're,
you're waking up,
you know,
multiple times a night and that's
completely gone.
Um,
and uh,
and it's stressful.
It's like completely new experience.
You have this very fragile baby,
you know,
that you're responsible for.
And so I think that combination of all
these things really can play a role in
that.
Uh,
and for me,
I,
I really tried to make sure I was
getting exercise as soon as I could,
you know,
so that is something because exercise
for a variety of reasons,
one,
it's been shown to increase the
production of Serotonin by getting
transport of Tryptophan into the brain.
So branched chain amino acids which are
found in a variety of,
of um,
proteins,
uh,
they can outcompete trip to fan and to
get into the brain.
And so if you're not exercising,
you're constantly getting the branch
chain amino acids in the brain which are
serving other important roles,
but you're not getting that trip to fan.
So you're not getting the precursor to
make serotonin.
And so the exercise alleviates that,
that competition,
branch chain amino acids get taken up
into your muscle where they're,
you know,
they're used to help build muscle which
is good.
And the Japan gets into the brain.
So you're making Serotonin,
that's one.
Two,
you're making,
um,
you know,
endorphins,
a Beta endorphins help so that,
that's another thing.
And then the,
you're,
you're increasing the production of new
neurons through Serotonin also through
brain drive neurotrophic factor that
also has been shown to help alleviate
depression and,
and prevent depression.
The actual neurogenesis,
the thing that helps you to stave off
brain aging,
which by the way,
there's been like,
there was like 14 clinical trials that
have been analyzed on looking at humans
that,
that undergo like a real big exercise
and how they have like their left part
of their hippocampus doesn't like
atrophy.
Like people who do not exercise,
you know.
So that's like because the neurogenesis,
but that,
that's another reason you can visually
see it atrophy you some sort of animal
products.
Have you ever looked,
if you like google,
like Alzheimer's Disease Brain,
like there's,
there's even images all over the place
where they show like before and after
and there's just like big holes in the
brain.
I mean it's just like,
it's like because someone was comparing
it to a football player was,
what's the guy's name who fell off the
car?
The guy was Henry,
Chris and Chris Henry.
He was,
um,
I think he was only 28,
right?
Twenty six.
He was a young man who was an nfl
football player.
No one had any idea he had cte.
This is like a earlier,
understandably,
this is like seven years ago,
somewhere around there.
Right.
I'm much less understanding about the
effects of cte and he had some sort of
an altercation with his girlfriend,
chased after her.
She was,
she jumped in a car and he didn't want
her to leave.
So he jumped on top of the truck to try
to hang on and fell off the truck and
killed himself.
Um,
yeah.
So they do an autopsy on him and they
find out that he has a brain of a 70
year old man with Alzheimer's.
Well and he's 28,
26,
28,
whatever it was.
He was young under 30 and super athlete
just and they were stunned and they
looked at his brain and they're like,
well this is,
this is,
this doesn't even make sense and now
they're finding that this is the case
with so many football players.
Just when you,
you,
when you went to see the UFC,
when you and Dan with the see the UFC
and I talked to you afterwards,
we all went to dinner afterwards and
you,
your eyes were as big as dinner plates
and you were like,
this is so bad.
So many bad things are happening.
And then you started going into detail
about the various things that were
happening.
It was so fascinating to watch you a
scientist.
Watch people get head kicked and punched
in the face and watch.
Watch mma take place.
Yeah,
I mean it's,
it's kind of crazy to think about how
people will like as a profession go and
get,
like they're getting Tbi,
like constantly getting their head and
you know,
there,
there are,
there's definitely like if you look at
the non,
you know,
fighting forms,
martial arts where there like it,
it seems a lot more beautiful like cool
moves and stuff,
you know,
but like,
like the actual like getting your head
bashed and stuff like that's crazy.
It's so crazy,
you know,
and I understand money is a big driving
factor because they probably make a lot
of money but you know,
what,
what's it worth when you're not able to
enjoy it when you're older and you just
lose your brain.
It's not just money,
it's the excitement of it.
The way I describe it is it's high level
problem solving with dire physical
consequences,
high level problem solving.
That's what fighting is like you have a
skillset.
I have a skill set,
like we're playing a game and the game
is I want to try to hit you with my
bones and you're trying to hit me with
your bones.
And we're trying to figure out who's
better at it and I know that you know
what I know you,
you like if you get to a certain level,
like say what are.
One of the things that I love about
Jujitsu is a Jujitsu sort of solve this,
but it does.
So without hitting each other.
Jujitsu is all grappling and there's
obviously a lot of injuries that come
through from Jujitsu.
I think that's what I meant when I,
when I was using something that looks
kind of cool.
Yeah.
I like the world you just do.
Championships just happened this past
weekend.
I was watching some of the videos online
and you watch these really high level
guys going after it and it's,
it's amazing is beautiful.
They're attacking and counter attacking
and you just.
And me in my mind,
I'm thinking of the countless hours of
dedication and focus.
It's required to reach this level of
proficiency where they're just,
they know what to do and when to do.
Trying to counter and they know and
they're both black belts at a very high
level.
So it's like you're,
you're,
you're examining this game.
And it doesn't have the same feeling
when someone loses that an mma fight
has,
like,
I watched the UFC this past weekend and
there's some brutal knockouts and when
you watch someone get caseload and you
see their,
their brain shut off,
their leg stiffened up and they'd go
flat.
I saw,
I saw someone get knocked out,
I forgot who it was,
but it was like one of the last,
like most exciting fights.
And it was like he,
it was,
it was crazy.
Yeah,
for sure.
And,
and I think we talked about this last
time a couple years ago,
but the apoe e four gene I think really
is something that would at least give
some insight because I mean it's known
that people that have at least one of
those gene,
that gene,
they can have really,
really bad consequences if they get Tbi.
I mean we're talking 10 to 20 fold more
risk for Cte for other 20 fold more if
they have.
Yeah.
If they have two copies of it.
So they're like homozygous,
which is a lot less common.
One copy is more common.
That would be,
um,
you know,
anywhere like a,
like a two to five fold,
but when you have two copies it can be,
it can be up 10 to 20 fold higher.
So that's something that's like,
you know,
with,
with the,
with the MMA,
the UFC kind of fighting,
I mean,
or football or boxing or you know,
fill in the blank sports that you know,
is very,
um,
has a high risk for,
for Tbi.
Like I think that's something that
athletes should consider and,
and you probably would find ones that
would say,
hey,
maybe I shouldn't do this,
you know,
especially with football players,
know quite a few football players who
are aware of this are actually backing
out of the NFL at a very young age.
I think headaches.
So there was a guy recently was 24 years
old,
just retired and he's like,
I'm done.
Yeah.
You know,
when he has a bright future apparently.
Well let's do it.
We got sidetracked.
So you were talking about exercise and
the um,
what put the hippocampus.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
So the,
the,
the benefits of exercise on the brain,
which I know that I constantly talk
about this to you because it,
but it's just so,
you know,
it's so damn important.
It's so important,
so important.
And it is,
it's one of those things that like,
it helps me with everything with the
brain.
Aging is like,
it's like it's the longterm effect.
So it helps me with the short term which
is like handling life and handling
stress.
You were talking about how people have a
hard time seeing things from a higher
level and,
and it's so true,
you know,
because life is hard,
you have to like make it,
you have to survive and if you don't
have a starting place,
a starting,
if your baseline is,
is kind of like you don't have a lot to
start with and you have to work all,
you know,
all the more work you have to put in.
So I think that,
you know,
getting distracted with trying to make
money,
you're trying to like survive and try to
look,
you know,
try to like live a good life and get
married and have kids and all this.
It can be really stressful.
So,
you know,
I have of course my own stresses,
but I think that the exercises,
the short,
the short term effects I get from that,
you know,
are helping with clarity.
Helping me with,
um,
being able to kind of take,
take a step back and not be so anxious.
And there's,
there's controlled trials showing this
as well with,
with exercise.
Um,
you know,
I,
for the longest time have been a runner
and running is like,
for me,
you know,
I love the,
the frame of mind I'm in when I'm
running,
like it's kind of like this reflective
daydreaming,
which some people in some studies say,
well Jay dreaming is not good because
you're ruminating when you're
daydreaming.
But I think the daydreaming that you do
when you're like running is a lot
different from like if you and I are
having this conversation right now,
but I wasn't present.
Right.
So that's called rumination and that
that's like,
that's a stressful kind of.
Yeah.
Where you're,
where you're not present because you're
worried about this other thing you have
to do.
Right.
But the,
the daydreaming effect when I'm running
is a little bit more of a reflective.
Like it's a good.
It's like a cleansing for me.
So I've always.
When you run.
Yeah.
I saw that you've recently gotten into
that,
which is over the past year.
The literally last January started
because a friend of mine how to run a
in,
in Vegas.
So five.
I jumped in it with zero running at all.
I'm like,
God,
this is fucking hard.
I was like,
I'm in shape.
I'll just go run.
But I never ran.
I literally never.
Now I run every week and it was hard for
you,
right,
because you're right part.
But what's interesting is my cardio for
everything else has gone through the
roof.
It's because I'm running like brutal
trails,
like really steep mountain trails and
I'm doing the most.
It was four miles.
The least I do is one mile.
Sometimes I do too,
but it's,
it's essentially hill sprints.
Okay.
So you're doing something,
you're getting some high intensity in
there,
you're sprinting.
It's very high intensity and it's all,
it's all like really extensive cardio.
It's like it's heavy duty stuff.
I run with my dog now.
That's awesome.
So what's interesting is for me,
um,
after pregnancy,
like I couldn't wait to go out running
and so I think it was four weeks in four
weeks,
four weeks postpartum.
I went out for a run.
I saw your instagram post.
Yeah.
Okay.
So I went out for a run.
I was super extreme.
That's probably the only post I did
because what I found out as I was
running is I didn't feel so great.
Like I felt like my bladder felt full
even though it wasn't like.
And so I would,
I would stop and go to the bathroom,
like on my run and then I was like,
okay,
and then run again.
It still felt full and I was like,
this is not normal like this,
you know,
so um,
so I went to my ob Gyn,
talked to him and apparently your pelvic
floor,
like changes
after having a baby and that can like,
you know,
fall down and kind of hit your bladder a
little.
And so it feels,
some women actually like pee urinate
when they're running.
Like I never had it like that.
Well he looked at my pelvic floor was
like on a scale from zero to 10,
zero being the best,
your one.
And I'm like,
really?
Because I feel like a seven,
you know?
And so he was like,
well you probably shouldn't have started
running so soon,
so don't do that.
Why don't you start doing some low
impact exercise and start doing these
like strength,
like strengthening your pelvic floor
with like key goals and some core
strength,
which I've been doing so.
So I was like,
crap,
what am I going to do?
Like running.
I would just walk out the door and go,
you know,
run.
And that was like my escape.
So I started doing this.
The cycling class,
high intensity interval cycling class,
which is,
it's an hour long and it's a spin class
but it's not like the dance spin,
so it's the,
it's,
it's a spin class where you do hills and
sprints and it's,
it's an hour long,
but you're mixing it with just a robotic
and so you get these sprints and these
hills and I really,
really,
really like it for multiple reasons.
One is the group setting where I feel
like the people around me and like
they're still going at it,
you know,
so it's like motivating.
So I keep going to.
There's something about that group that
really like I push.
If it were just me on that bike for an
hour,
there's no way I would be pushing it.
Like I do,
like I am pushing it.
It's like amazing pushing it.
I feel that way about yoga class.
Yeah.
For the growth is everyone's sort of
feeding off each other.
Right,
right,
right.
And then also having the instructor,
like there's a couple instructors that I
really,
really like and you know,
because they liked their style and
they're kind of more like coaches and
then the kind of instructor that kind of
makes you want to feel there's an
instructor that's like,
they their cheerleader kind of want to
make you feel good.
And then there's the instructor where
they're like a coach where they're like
the trying to help you get better.
So this icon does high intensity,
high intensity interval training.
And I've never really been into it that
much.
Like I was,
you know,
I would do some like jump squats and
things like that,
like at home,
but this is the first time I'm like
really it's structured environment and
really doing it.
So I started reading about it,
like wanting to know because that's how
I am.
If I do something I'm like well I'm
going to look into it.
And either it will motivate me to like
really keep it up and do it more or I'll
be like,
no,
this isn't good,
you know?
So I started reading more and more about
it.
And it's amazing the benefits of the
high intensity.
So you were talking about how,
how your,
your,
I think what you were describing was
your aerobic capacity
change for the big one.
Is kickboxing like the when when I hit
the bag,
he used to be that I would,
I would struggle to do a three minute
round of,
of high,
high intensity,
like hitting the bag kickboxing.
But now I can,
I get through it,
the bell goes off and I'm like,
really?
Okay.
Like the bell just went off.
All right,
that's three minutes.
And then I'll have the 32nd rest by the
term.
30 second rest is up.
I'm fully recovered and I'm back in
again.
I just,
it's,
I mean like I have more than double
the endurance stay.
So.
So they're,
they're.
What you're experiencing has been
studied in clinical studies.
Basically this aerobic capacity also
people call it a vo two Max,
which is basically the ability of your
lungs and your blood and your heart to
carry oxygen to your muscles are places
that are,
you know,
during that intense push.
So the capacity to do that.
Right?
Well as we age,
over the age of 25,
once we hit 25 and we continue on,
our aerobic capacity decreases by 10
percent per decade.
So like one percent per year.
Right.
So you're basically,
you know,
25 year 35,
your,
your vo two Max.
Your is like 10 percent less than you
were when you were 25.
Well it turns out doing these high
intensity interval classes during 24 of
them,
which in this study it was like there
were 40 minutes long and there was four
four minute pushes and then there's,
you know,
recoveries in between and all that,
blah blah blah stuff they were able to
improve.
And after eight weeks of doing 24 high
intensity classes improve their vo two
Max by like 12 percent.
So you're basically adding a decade,
you know,
back to your point.
Many weeks.
Well they did it.
They did 24 classes of this in eight
weeks.
Wow.
So what the interesting thing about that
study was they were also testing whether
or not like,
like I'm doing it,
I think it was like four weeks or
something really like short,
just packing them all in the actually
didn't increase the vo two Max as much
because the recovery time was actually
important.
It's actually changed the way I think
about when it comes to training and my
advice that I give to people for
training because I used to think that it
was adequate to just do the sports
specific workouts like say if you wanted
to get better at Jujitsu,
just do Jujitsu.
Do you want to get better at kickboxing?
Just to your kickboxing.
The cardio you get from that will be
enough.
I don't think that's the case anymore
because I'm stunned at how much of an
increase in cardio that I've gotten from
these hill sprints and now I realize
like,
okay,
what you can do is you can do it
independently of that work and it
doesn't really mess with that work.
Like say if I run in the morning and I
get a good two mile run,
I can still hit the bag at three in the
afternoon,
but the difference will be is I like,
my legs will be tired from running,
but they're not the same muscles that I
use when I kick box.
But what's similar in a lot of ways,
but with what's really changing for sure
is that my aerobic capacity is just way
bigger.
It's just awesome.
It's just different.
That's actually a marker of aging
aerobic capacity.
Vo Two Max.
I've never actually measured my own vo
two Max.
Um,
I probably have to put that hosting.
I don't want to do it because now that
I'm doing all this high intensity work
and I'm totally going to stick with it.
Like I love it,
but I definitely want to get back to the
running and I've been sort of worried
about I can only do so much as a new mom
and working on a trip.
Would you be interested in a treadmill
or.
No?
You know,
I love running outside like in nature,
whether it's in the beach or I'm like in
the hills,
rolling hills and stuff,
but you know,
for
the longest time I lived in Tennessee
and the weather there is not great and
so I did do treadmill running and so
yeah,
I definitely,
I don't,
I don't have the same daydreaming like
effect that I,
but I do definitely.
I mean it's definitely good and I get a
lot from it from a treadmill,
but there's something about,
in fact there was some interesting study
that I don't know how long ago,
maybe a year ago or two that looked at
people that exercise,
I think they went for like walks or
something in nature versus like in the
metropolitan area and the benefits there
was,
there was more benefits in going for
walks in nature in terms of like,
you know,
psychological benefits,
but also some of the variety of like
biomarkers that were measured.
So it kind of interesting.
You know,
it is interesting.
I think we like to think of ourselves as
being detached from what we experienced
just in terms of even just visually,
but I,
I think that those things have an effect
on not just how you think,
like how you feel,
but who you are.
I mean,
I,
I think we are,
we have some sort of a symbiotic
relationship with our environment and
when your environment is cement in glass
and concrete and rubber and all the
things that we've created in cities that
there's a dull feeling that you get from
those things and then when you,
you can go and see a green meadow and
birds flying around and,
and the,
the wind whistling through the leaves
like you,
you just,
it does something to your body does
something,
not just your mind.
There's something going on like you,
you,
you have like this feeling of,
Oh,
this is medicine.
This is,
I'm getting something out of this.
Yeah,
absolutely.
I think that there's the noise
pollution,
the sound,
you know,
like the cars and all that.
That's been shown to have a negative
effect on people's emotions.
And,
and I'm in,
of course,
there's the environmental things,
you're breathing in pollution and that
has been shown to increase inflammatory
biomarkers and all that.
But there's certainly,
I think the just going out into nature
and you,
you,
you feel better.
You Do,
you definitely,
you definitely feel better.
It's not,
you know,
not I live in the city and I live off of
a busy place and thankfully we're going
to be moving.
But that's something I'm considering
where it's just like,
are you moving specifically for that
reason?
No,
we're just in a small apartment right
now and it's like I have a baby now and
it's fun to people.
Yeah,
it was fine.
It was close to the beach and you know,
it was,
it's fun like,
but just,
it's not something that,
that,
you know,
I could do with,
with,
with the baby,
especially in such a small space.
And there's motorcycles that go by and
it's like,
it's crazy.
Like the motorcycles that they wrap up
their writing by exactly the writing by
and it's like that's a bummer.
It's,
yeah,
to now.
So I'm also like a yard is good for a
kid.
Right,
right,
exactly.
But it's hard.
It's hard in,
you know,
I mean
like we were saying,
you know,
it's not easy,
so there's things you have,
there's just all this stuff you have to
consider when you're,
your priorities changed now,
now that you,
when you have a child,
it's like you've got to think of all the
things schools and this and that
neighbors and who were they going to be
friends with and like,
oh my God,
before I forget,
I wanted to tell people,
go to Chris Kresser,
his instagram or his,
excuse me,
his twitter page,
and there's an article on Acetaminophen
and women who are pregnant consuming
Acetaminophen and the negative
consequences it has for children.
See more evidence.
It says here that the exposure to
Acetaminophen may be a part of adhd
puzzle.
A Norwegian study,
pregnant women took Acetaminophen for 29
days or more,
had a more than twofold risk of having
children with Adhd.
Yeah.
Wow.
Tylenol,
I think I've seen.
I think I even tweeted something like
this like a couple of years ago where
this isn't the first study where in New
York Times right now apparently,
and that's what people are prescribed
right during pregnancy.
Scary Shit.
There's,
I mean it's how many things we find out
from like the 19 sixties were terribly
detrimental to children and doctors are
telling you this is the way you should
go.
I mean there's.
So that's the,
you know,
with,
um,
when I was pregnant there was,
there were certainly some things that I
opted out of that we're probably more
standard of care,
you know,
so,
uh,
just because of concern and,
and not that I knew for a fact that
something was gonna happen,
but I had doubt and that was enough for
me to sort of weigh the benefits and the
risks.
And I was like,
well,
you know,
so.
Well there's even talk about vaccination
protocols.
Like not whether or not,
I mean,
I'm not an anti vaccination person.
I think vaccinations are important,
but I think that there's a lot of merit
in the idea of that.
You shoot a kid up at 36 different shots
when they're six weeks old or whatever
age they start them out right out of the
box.
They give a lot of doctors want to give
your kid a series of shots and that
there's some,
there's some concern that the actual
consequences of all these different
vaccines being put into your child's
body very early and a large number of
them have some sort of negative
consequences.
It,
you know,
I'm,
I'm with you.
Like I'm also not an antibody or I think
vaccines are important.
I'm going to vaccinate my son.
But um,
and I've,
I've already given.
I'm a little behind on the schedule.
I've given him one.
But.
So what you're saying is true there is
like even on the CDC website,
it says that,
you know,
some of these vaccines can cause I'm
fevers and epileptic seizures,
seizures,
seizures in infants and,
but that there's no longterm consequence
of that.
And,
and that's kind of like,
you know,
if you look,
if you look at the literature and,
and how the immune,
the immune system response to some of
these vaccines,
especially if you're giving like five at
once.
I mean the first round of vaccines that
I'm supposed to do,
it was like,
it was like five different vaccines.
And so what I'm opting to do is actually
do them in singles where you.
So yeah,
because it's like why the immune
response is,
you know,
kind of the thing that's scary and you
don't really know how a child's immune
system is going to react.
And there are studies.
I was particularly worried about it
during pregnancy and that's when one of
the things I opted out of was getting,
um,
the td APP,
a vaccine,
which is they want to give it to you
when you're,
I forgot how many weeks pregnant.
I'm 30 something I think.
And uh,
to protect basically pass on antibodies
for whooping cough,
you know,
to the,
to the baby.
And so I opted out and I said I would do
it post basically postpartum,
like one day postpartum because it takes
about four weeks to transfer the
antibodies in breast milk.
So I still was gonna,
you know,
get the vaccine.
But I was going to do it after I had
the.
And the.
And the reason I made that decision is
because there have been multiple studies
now in nonhuman primates that have
looked on these studies,
came out of UC Davis,
looked at pregnant female monkeys on
when they're,
when they have a really strong immune
response.
So like a strong infection or you know,
who knows a vaccine.
The study didn't use vaccines,
but I'm sort of drawing a parallel here.
Whereas just the immune response having
very strong immune response.
There was an autoimmune response that
ended up having antibodies that attack
the developing brain.
And the monkeys that were born from
those mothers were had autistic like
behaviors.
It's been shown in humans that mothers
of autistic children are five times more
likely to have antibodies floating
around in their blood against fetal
brain proteins.
Like they're not supposed to have
antibodies against fetal brain proteins
in their blood.
So there's definitely been some link
with the immune system and autoimmunity,
particularly during pregnancy and autism
risk.
Now,
in terms of like the,
the young baby,
you know,
I'm,
I'm scared too.
And I do.
I do worry that,
you know,
my,
my son's developing so great and like I
don't want to do something wrong.
It's,
it's scary.
It really is.
And you know,
I definitely,
like I said,
I'm going to vaccinate my son and I have
been doing singles and that you have to
like,
it's,
it's a little more inconvenient because
you have to go to the doctor like so
many times to do it.
But the thing is is that when you don't,
when you're not giving so many different
vaccines at once,
the immune response isn't going to be as
strong.
And there's a problem with this
conversation and one of the problems
with this conversation is as soon as you
talk about vaccines,
you immediately get lumped into a bunch
of fucking crazy people that think that
vaccines or some sort of a conspiracy.
And the government's trying to make
money from you and you were an
anti-vaxxer and they immediately box you
in and start getting angry at you.
It's,
it's,
it's almost,
it's a weird thing because you're
talking about chemicals that you're
injecting into a child,
right?
Yeah,
but still people are very hesitant to,
to even look at that.
They're very,
they'll you want to automatically just
go with whatever the doctor says when it
comes to vaccines until.
But the real problem is until you look
at like how much work has been done,
determining what the consequences are
and how can you find out?
How can you even know?
No,
you really can't unless you have to have
the exact,
you know,
a bunch of copies.
You make a bunch of clowns have a baby
and you expose them to the exact same
environment.
Zach,
exact same epigenetics,
exact same environmental factors and
then one of you and inject a bunch of
chemicals into and one you don't.
I mean we know that vaccines are
amazing.
They have prevented polio.
They have prevented a host of different
diseases becoming real issues and we
know that people who don't vaccinate
their kids,
the the reason why measles are coming
back,
they might just.
There's real concerns.
Absolutely.
I think vaccines are amazing.
I'm so happy they exist,
but I also think that we have to be very
careful with just jumping into things.
Just like we were talking before about
things that they did as standard care
during the 19 sixties are now
prohibited.
Like we know they're dangerous for you.
Yeah.
I mean I,
I completely 100 percent agree and I
think that there,
there,
there are now it's a growing field at
least in science where there are,
there are scientists that are trying to
understand the,
the gene interaction,
that gene interaction with the immune
system because it obviously almost
everyone gets vaccinated,
right?
I mean,
and you don't have everyone walking
around with all these with autism and
all this,
but there,
there is something that is going on and
you know,
a lot of parents have noticed changes of
course after the vaccinations.
And so there,
there is a new field of inquiry.
I do know that's ongoing.
We're scientists are beginning to now
look at,
in addition to how the immune system is
reacting to some of these vaccines,
how specific genes,
you know,
regulating certain immune functions may
differences in those genes called
polymorphisms may predispose a child.
Now how are you going to know that?
Like without doing a DNA test before you
do the vaccine?
I mean it's a risk,
like you said,
how do you know it's it.
It definitely is a risk and that's,
that's what's the scary thing,
you know,
and it's like,
it's,
it's a,
it's a dilemma that I've been facing
and,
and you know,
I,
I'm currently,
the reason I even delayed,
I've only given my son to vaccines so
far,
but just because I'm trying to like
exhaustively read the literature as much
as I can.
Well good.
I'm glad.
I'm glad that you're looking at it this
way because it's something that there's
a lot of pressure on people to not look
at it that way.
There's like this just having this
conversation,
Joe Rogan and Rhonda Patrick are
anti-vaxxers.
That could be,
that could be the title of some bullshit
arc article that someone writes about
this.
I mean I've seen it time and time again
where someone will write a clickbait
title to an article and then someone
will just that and go,
oh,
you're an anti-vaxxer.
Of course you are,
you loser,
and they'll get angry at you and throw
some twitter message your way.
That is not representative of your
actual thoughts on this at all.
This is a very complex,
very nuanced issue and like,
like I said,
I do think people should vaccinate their
children.
Do as well.
Have been all right.
I.
I agree.
It's a nuanced topic that we,
you know,
we don't.
We don't know what the answer to.
I mean I think that this guy,
what was his name?
The guy,
the doctor that got disbarred because he
liked falsified some data on a thumb
Rosalda mercury and causing autism.
Falsified some data or something.
What was the story behind that data that
was published that,
that linked thimerosal,
which is the agile that was found in a
lot of vaccines in California.
They don't use that as far as I know,
as far as like it's not used anymore.
Was that the needle,
measles,
mumps,
rubella,
MMR,
you know?
Yeah.
And so what did he do?
What was,
I don't you know,
it's not like I haven't done super,
super in depth analysis of what he did
to my understanding was that he just
hold it up here.
Journal retracts 1998 paper linking
autism to vaccines are prominent.
British medical journal Tuesday,
retracted in 1998 research paper that
set off a sharp decline of vaccinations
in Britain after the papers.
Lead.
Author suggested that vaccines could
cause autism,
the retraction,
blah,
blah.
Reassessment,
uh,
there's lasted for years,
in the scientific methods and financial
conflicts.
Dr Andrew Wakefield,
who contended that his research show
that the combined measles,
mumps,
and rubella rubella.
How do you say it?
Rubella.
Rubella vaccine may be unsafe,
but the retraction may do little to
tarnish Dr Wakefield's fields,
reputation among parents groups in the
United States,
despite a wealth of scientific studies
that have failed to find any link
between vaccines and autism,
the parents fervently.
I love that word,
believe that their children's medical
problems resulted from vaccines.
I know a lot of people that think their
kid's medical issues came from vaccines
and I'm not wanting to tell them they're
wrong.
I don't know who's right or who's wrong,
but I know there's a massive amount of
money to discourage any sort of talk and
thinking that no one wants you to think
there's anything wrong with vaccines and
vaccines can do no harm,
but you know,
millions of dollars have been given out
by the vaccine courts.
It's not like there's.
There's vaccine courts that take care of
cases where people have been damaged by
vaccines.
It's not.
There's no way.
We were talking about this before the
podcast started that we're going to
discuss the,
the.
There's people very biologically,
so much that one person can eat at my
friend Brian,
his,
his mom,
if she eats a Brazil nut,
she will die.
I could eat a whole bowl of those boring
fucking nuts.
They don't do anything to me.
I think they're boring but increase your
selenium.
Oh,
that's nice.
It's good to have,
but I mean they don't do anything
negative to me,
but his mom will eat them and she dies.
Now that you can,
I believe that you can extrapolate that
and you can look at all sorts of
different things that you take into your
body.
There are some people that are allergic
to a host of different things that don't
do a damn thing to me and there's going
to be people that are going to have
reactions to vaccines.
It's just it's a chemical.
There's going to be something that
happens in your body,
so the idea that there's no link
whatsoever to a chemical causing an
adverse reaction.
That doesn't jive.
It doesn't make sense to say that it's
impossible.
You could say it's extremely rare.
That makes more sense,
but when they say there's no link,
when you say no link,
I have to go,
what's motivating this?
What's motivating you to say no link?
Because with when you're dealing with
chemicals,
there's always going to be a small
percentage of a chance that your body
has an adverse reaction.
Those chemicals,
and it's not just chemicals.
I mean,
this is,
these are,
these are live bacteria,
bacteria and you're listening and immune
response and immune response is very as
well,
dramatically.
I mean some people have autoimmune
disease diseases because their immune
system gets so ramped up.
I mean,
you know,
some people have type one diabetes
because their immune system is
destroying their pancreatic Beta islet
cells that produce insulin.
People are different like you said,
and it's funny because when that,
when Jamie pulled that up,
my mind went to the same place where
it's,
it's just,
it's the perfect example of how people
respond differently to different things
and you know,
it's not,
it's not just a chemical but food,
and this is a big,
big field of inquiry is like the food
because you've got people battling just
like with the vaccine,
people that are anti-vaxxers versus
people that want to vaccinate.
You've got people that are saying
saturated fat is bad.
It's good proteins bad.
No,
it's good.
You've got all these camps of people
that all you know are just basically
like.
It's almost like a religion where they
just,
they know what the best diet isn't.
Everyone should do it.
And,
and the reality is,
is that it may not be the best diet for
everyone,
you know,
and that's something that we all very.
Yeah,
I mean that's something,
you know,
so,
so before the industrialized
civilization occur,
like occurred,
food was like,
the food you would eat was,
you know,
according to where you live
geographically,
right?
Because you weren't getting food from
all parts of the world,
like you were basically were at whatever
you could grow and that part of the
world is what you would eat.
Right?
And so like people would eat
carbohydrates or fats saturated fats or
you know,
various foods,
different at different rates because
they were,
you know,
that's what they had,
right?
And it's thought that,
you know,
uh,
over over time that humans have adapted
to the,
to the region and they've adapted so
that they could process,
you know,
basically processed that food better.
And at least that's the theory.
The reality is it doesn't matter how it
happened.
We know that it's true when people have
different variations in genes that are
involved in nutrition and also in
everything else.
So regardless of whether or not that's
how it actually occurred,
it,
it happens.
And I think one of the best examples of
that is the study that was published in
2015 in the journal cell from the
Weizmann Institute.
800 different people were given a
continuous glucose monitor where their
blood glucose levels were measured every
five minutes.
And these people were then,
um,
they submitted samples,
uh,
for their,
for their DNA to be analyzed.
And then also their microbiome,
which is the bacteria that live in the
gut.
And so scientists then gave these groups
of people various food types,
either refined carbohydrate like white
bread,
complex carbohydrates,
like,
you know,
like a banana,
and then saturated fat like cheese.
And they measured people's Glucose
response to these various foods,
800 different people.
And what was found was that the glucose
response varied vastly according to a
person's genetic and also microbiome
makeup.
So people,
you would think,
well,
people are going to have a high blood
glucose response to white bread and
maybe maybe somewhat to the banana,
but there's fiber in there.
And that sort of changes the way,
you know,
the,
the glucose levels,
um,
uh,
reach the blood.
But the reality was that some people had
high blood glucose to the saturated fat,
which is sort of,
you know,
not people don't think about that.
I'm so that this is,
this was sort of like one of the first
proof of principle studies showing and
800 different people that people are
different and they measured the various
genes to show it.
And also their microbiome,
the gut bacteria varied as well because
that changes the way you're metabolizing
food.
So,
um,
some of these genes,
like we know,
we know for example,
Ppr,
Alpha,
Gamma Fto,
April before,
which is what I have all changed the way
your body metabolizes fat and also the
way your body transports like fatty
acids and cholesterol throughout the
body.
And the people with some of these
polymorphisms in these genes,
if they eat a high,
you know,
saturated to low poly and mono
unsaturated fat ratio,
they can actually have more adverse
effects.
They can have higher blood glucose,
they can have higher ldl cholesterol,
they can have higher obesity rates,
higher type two diabetes risk,
you know,
so,
and that's like,
like I said,
that's,
that's something that most people that
were,
that would eat a high saturated fat diet
wouldn't have.
And so I've actually been able to look
at some of my jeans because there's
companies now that allow you to do that.
And um,
so,
you know,
I know that I have in April before,
so that changes my,
my diet in a way so you know,
it because the Aicpa we for not only
predisposes you to Alzheimer's disease,
um,
and also from um,
adverse effects to Tbi,
but it also affects the way cholesterol
is transporting your body and it doesn't
get recycled very well.
So I have more cholesterol circulating
in my body at any given point,
um,
compared to my husband Dan,
who doesn't have an APP for a little and
we eat the exact same diet,
like my ldl will be like 20 points
higher than his,
you know,
like is there a negative health effect
of that?
So that it gets a little more
complicated,
but um,
so the,
the,
the ldl cholesterol by the way,
for a long time it's been,
it's been thought to be a predictor of
heart disease because with nutrition,
and here's the thing with nutrition is,
is that a lot of our studies are,
are,
are what's called observational studies
where we look at this population and we
look at a disease risk and we say,
oh,
this person eat that and they have a
higher risk of that or a low risk or
that.
Right?
So it's a correlation.
It's not,
you're not,
you're not showing it's a causal factor,
right.
It's a correlation.
And it's notoriously like,
actually my mentor from my Postdoc,
Dr Bruce Ames,
he has this joke,
that analogy of.
It's a joke that he tells that really
illustrates this type of study.
Epidemiology.
It's,
it's.
He says that people that are born in
Miami are born Hispanic,
but they died Jewish.
So you're born Hispanics and if you
don't know the rich cultural history of
Miami,
whereas a lot of big Latino community
people come there from Cuba and various
races,
but then old people go there to retire
because they hate the cold and they want
to like,
you know,
movement move to Florida.
So you just look at the data.
If you just look at the birth records
and the death records,
you'd be like,
oh,
people are born Hispanic and they die
Jewish.
Wow.
That is epidemiology.
That's like,
that's very funny.
It is.
And it's,
it's a great analogy because it really
does highlight the complexity of doing
these types of studies.
There's all sorts of other factors that
play a role,
right?
I mean so.
So the thing is is that with nutrition
in particular,
you have to look at not just the
epidemiological study,
but you have to look at controlled
randomized controlled trials where they
use biomarkers as predictors of certain
diseases.
You have to look at animal studies where
mechanism has done to understand how
things are working.
You know,
you have to look at the whole picture
because if you just use these studies
were,
oh,
you get a low protein diet,
it's,
you have a lower all cause mortality,
boom,
I'm going to be a Vegan.
Well guess what?
Lots of other things are complicated.
You know,
there's,
there's lots of other factors or the
saturated fat one.
So you asked me,
does ldl like,
does that predict your heart disease
risk?
Well on a population level for a long
time it can.
Because LDL LDL is,
you know,
one thing that transports cholesterol
and higher levels of it have been
associated with a variety of different
heart disease risk factors.
But the thing is is that as you know,
as time has gone on and tools have got
better and when we're able to like look
more at mechanism,
scientists have now started to uncover,
oh,
there's multiple types of ldl.
It's not just one type.
There's different sizes of it that are
circulating in the blood and one size
is really good.
The large size,
the large buoyant size,
it's really good because it's delivering
cholesterol to yourselves and delivering
fatty acids to yourself where you need
it.
Every time you make a new cell in your
body,
guess what?
It needs cholesterol and these fatty
acids,
that's great.
But there's also smaller sizes that,
that,
um,
that are more dense and basically they
can't get recycled back to the liver.
There's a,
there's a,
uh,
basically a,
a life cycle of the cholesterol.
It's made in the liver,
it goes out in the bloodstream,
you donate all this stuff to your
various self and it goes back to the
liver and it's,
you know,
it's sort of like recycled.
Well if you can't recycle it then it
stays in your bloodstream sort of
indefinitely.
And then it can undergo inflammatory
transformations there and all sorts of
things.
You know,
bad things happen.
And so the longer you have something in
your bloodstream,
if it's there for,
for,
for like decades,
chances are some shit's going to go
wrong.
Right?
There's this a dietary issue or a
hereditary issue in terms of like the
size of the ldl.
So I don't know how much is known about
the hereditary aspect of it.
It's known that April we for can
increase the risk of just having more
ldl total there.
Right?
And so what type of Ldl it not known,
just like regular total ldl,
not looking at the particle size now
that particle size,
what we do know is there's a big
nutrition factor that regulates that and
the nutrition factor that regulates that
is refined sugar and that's been shown
in controlled randomized controlled
trials were like healthy men given
almost like something that was like a
soda,
you know?
Um,
they were,
they were given a big drink of just
sugar,
sugary drink for three weeks every day
and it completely increase their,
their inflammatory biomarkers for like
100 percent.
But it also ramped up their small ldl
particle size.
The limit.
Let me stop right here because this is a
really important point for people that
think that drinking a large glass of
orange juice is different than drinking
a glass of soda.
It's really not.
No,
it's not because you're not,
you don't have the fiber crazy.
I mean,
that's crazy.
If you,
if you say that to most people,
they're like,
what are you talking about?
You're talking nonsense.
No,
if you have a 24 ounce glass of orange
juice,
you're getting a giant dump of sugar in
your system.
Right?
And it's.
There's many people that think that
that's a healthy thing to drink,
right?
And so and that's,
and that's what complicates all these
studies is that you then have people
eating,
for example,
saturated fat which is known to increase
the large Ldl ldl.
It's known to increase that and in
combination you have people that are
drinking orange juice or even worse,
eating cookies and cake and drinking
soda and bread,
all that refined carbohydrates stuff.
Now those two in combination together,
you've got that.
You've got the Ldl,
and then what happens is with the
refined sugar is inflammatory
transformations happen and you get the
small dense and why it's a problem when
people try to look at Diet and very
simplistic ways,
right?
When people try to say,
if you eat saturated fat,
if you eat cholesterol,
you're going to have
high cholesterol in your body and your
going to have heart attacks,
they're going to have a stroke.
I mean,
this is this a very simplistic thing
that people will often say.
Yeah,
it is.
It very,
it,
it really,
truly is.
Like I said,
it's,
you have to look at mechanism,
controlled trials.
You have to look at observational
studies are also important.
Um,
you know,
we also have looked controlled trials
where people that are put on a high fat
and low refined carbohydrate diet for a
month or so,
or something like that.
I don't remember the exact time,
had all like biomarkers lowered for
heart disease risk.
Is there something that people can do to
take on that diet?
Like how do,
how do you do that if you want to go
vegan is.
I know a lot of people will like to be
Vegan,
but in order to get all those fats and
especially low carbohydrate.
Well,
so I think that first of all,
for anyone doing any diet,
like whether it's a Vegan diet or a
ketogenic high fat diet or a low carb
high fat diet or whatever diet they're
doing,
first thing you should do is definitely
measure these biomarkers.
LDL particle size can be measured
triglycerides,
inflammatory biomarkers like high
sensitivity,
c reactive protein.
Where would someone go to do that?
Like what's a good place to go?
Um,
true health diagnostics.
I mean,
I don't,
you,
you can ask your,
your primary care doctor.
Um,
I know truth,
true health diagnostics is one that does
like whole panel of really good ones,
including the small dense ldl particle
size and a growing number of physicians
do measure Ldl particle size wellness.
Fx is something if you don't want your
physician to know what your ldl is
because they don't want them to have
some opinion about it.
Wellness effects is a company that will
also measure your ldl particle size and
a variety of other biomarkers as well.
Now what you're saying
about um,
refined carbohydrates or refined sugars
and Ldl and small Ldl,
Laura,
large Ldl,
is this common knowledge amongst primary
care providers?
I mean,
is this something your doctor's going to
understand?
Are they going to try to put you on
standby?
It's,
it is not ubiquitous.
It's not standard of care and it's not
ubiquitous,
ubiquitous in,
in,
in the medical profession yet because
it's just within the past decade have
been starting to.
Scientists and researchers have been
starting to uncover these mechanisms and
it usually takes a long time to
translate this knowledge because now
large scale clinical trials have to be
done in x number of them have to be
done.
A lot of,
I don't know,
everything that goes into how
regulations are made,
but it's a lot.
It's a lot of clinical trials and a lot
of things before any sort of,
you know,
regulations are changed.
So that's something that is not standard
yet.
You can always print out papers,
give them to your physician.
I interviewed a Guy,
a guy on my podcast,
he's a cardiologist.
I'm an md.
[inaudible] name is dr ronald krauss.
He's actually the guy who pioneered the
test to measure small dense ldl particle
size and he's really been a leader in
the field for understanding the role of
small dense ldl particles in
cardiovascular disease risk and,
and how basically a person with high ldl
total cholesterol may not actually be at
risk for heart disease unless you look
at the actual particle size and,
and things like this is what confound
the literature because you can.
And this is what people often refer to
as cherry picking.
It's kind of a pet peeve of mine have
hand people say that because it's like
anyone could do that.
I feel like really the response that
someone should say is look at the
totality of the data,
look at the clinical trials to look at
the observational studies looking at
mechanism,
look at everything and get the picture.
Like that's,
that's,
that's the way you should,
you know,
approach nutrition,
science.
So,
um,
you know,
he's really been a leader in looking at
all that.
But I kind of didn't answer your
question about the people that are vegan
and want to go eat more of a,
um,
a high fat,
low carb diet or even a ketogenic diet.
Right?
You know,
so that's,
that's something that they're vegans are
interested in doing as well.
And you know,
I've never,
I personally,
um,
because my ape a background and by the
way that's kind of what motivated me to
get.
I got super into this new field called
nutrogenomix interaction between genes
and diet because I found out I had this
illegal and I knew there were sorts of
risk and I'm like there's,
there's absolutely things you can do and
your diet and your lifestyle to modify
that disease risk.
And so if that's something that I'm
really interested in,
um,
and people can actually,
you can measure your dna,
but the dna doesn't tell you everything.
You have to measure blood biomarkers.
Like the blood biomarkers are really key
to know if a diet it's working for you
or not.
And if it's not working for you,
like I've had people emailing me,
they've used,
I have a genetic tool that people can
use and if they want to look at april
before ppr gamma,
those are like free reports.
They've,
they've tried to kenogenic diet and it
was like awful for them.
Their inflammatory biomarkers went up
there,
small dense ldl particle went up,
all this stuff that happened and then
they'd use the tool and found out they
had,
for example,
the ppa,
our alpha gene,
which is a gene that's key for the
process of ketogenesis producing ketone
bodies from,
you know,
from oxidizing fatty acids and,
and people that have a certain one don't
do it very well.
And like the diet can be detrimental.
Like it can,
it can do more harm.
That's critical because,
uh,
you know,
first of all,
I've been the irresponsibly telling
people to do that too.
Like I said,
I think he'd agentic I responded very
well to it.
So I've been telling people to get on a
record,
delete,
try it.
So for what is exactly the gene,
what is the issue?
So there,
so ppr,
alpha,
it changes,
it's a gene that's involved in,
it's involved in fatty acid metabolism,
absorption of fatty acids.
Um,
it's also,
it's in the,
in the liver involved in producing
ketone bodies from,
from the fatty acid,
so that specific gene is essential for
the process of ketogenesis during a
fasted state and also if you're doing a
ketogenic type of diet and so a certain,
there are certain variations in that
gene that don't do it very well.
And so the high fat diet,
what ends up happening is,
uh,
you're not,
you're not metabolizing the fatty acids
and producing the ketone bodies quite as
well.
And so you end up having more free fatty
acids floating around in your
bloodstream which can antagonize insulin
receptor and make you more insulin
insensitive,
which is exactly the opposite of what
ketogenic diets really do,
you know.
So there's this very response.
You can also,
um,
have more inflammatory biomarkers for
various reasons as well because you're
not oxidizing the fatty acids and ketone
bodies as well.
So there's lots of things that change.
But like,
you know,
knowing the genes is one component.
I think I think that you have to measure
the biomarkers first and once you,
you're doing something like a ketogenic
diet,
for example,
then you would measure all your lipid
particle sizes,
your triglycerides,
inflammatory biomarkers to want to
measure hba one c,
which is your glycated hemoglobin,
which is a marker of sort of your
longterm blood glucose levels.
You have one test initially with a
baseline test before you enter into.
Exactly.
That's really key.
Do you think the origins of this is your
ancestral origins?
Like what your ancestors diet consisted
of?
Low fat,
high carbohydrate.
That's what I was kinda getting at
first.
I mean,
that's the theory at least,
right?
Like,
we don't,
we can't prove that,
but that there are scientists looking at
like different regions,
like people that live,
for example in northern europe,
how they eat more fat and they're able
to do that better.
And so there are scientists that are
investigating that because it's
interesting to know why a,
why that is.
But yeah,
that's,
that's the thing that's,
it's.
And I think it really explains a lot,
like with the ketogenic diet,
um,
there's,
it's something that I've become really
interested in recently because I've been
following the field and it appears as
though there is a really,
um,
there's something about it that is
really important for the way your
mitochondria age.
Like it really seems to help your
mitochondria age better.
And I think that there's,
you know,
there's multiple,
I talked to,
uh,
a sort of an expert.
He is the president of the buck
institute for research on aging,
um,
and he,
his name is eric burdon and he just
recently published a really big paper
showing that in animals,
cyclic ketogenic diets could extend
their health span.
So they are basically healthy part of
the life they're living.
They were living longer and they're
living better and,
and,
and also their memory was dramatically
improved.
And when you say cyclic,
is there a specific range that your
cycling.
So that.
And,
and this is how these questions for him
that I,
that I asked him about,
um,
and the cyclic.
So it was every other week.
So one week they were key to genic,
next week they were just getting normal
normal chow diet and then ketogenic,
so they're recycling every other week.
And the reason for that is because for
whatever reason,
um,
animals,
when they just,
when you just give them food to eat,
like,
like ad lib them,
like whenever they want,
even if it's ketogenic,
they'll just,
they'll keep eating,
like they'll just keep eating it and
they can become,
it can become an obesogenic diet where
there,
where they become fat and it can
actually decrease your lifespan even
though it's key to genic.
And I think that's partly because fatty
acids,
um,
in order to use them,
they have to get inside the mitochondria
to be used and that energy.
And if they don't get inside the
mitochondria,
then they just get taken up into adipose
tissue and stored as fat and fatty acids
themselves will,
when the levels are high enough,
shut that transport system that does
that off.
So it's like a negative regulator.
So if you just keep on bombarding the
body with fat,
fat,
like nonstop without a rest,
then you start to like not be able to
use those fatty acids because it
inhibits the transport system.
It's called the karnataka,
pama.
Total transfer is for those nerdy,
nerdy biologist geeks out there,
um,
that,
you know.
So anyways,
I totally digress tigress there.
But,
um,
it's um,
uh,
yeah,
the cycle can inject dye so that,
that was something that extended their
health span and I became very interested
in that.
And so the thing that's super
interesting and as I was talking to dr
budin about this is that,
you know,
there's a couple of things.
One,
obviously you're not getting a lot of
blood glucose hits all the time,
right?
When,
for the most part,
if you don't have gene polymorphisms
that are changing the way you process
saturated fat,
right?
So you're not your,
your,
your insulin response is not happening
quite as often.
That's lowered and there's,
there's,
there's benefits with from that alone,
right?
But for someone like me that doesn't eat
refined sugar,
doesn't eat any refined carbohydrates.
I mean,
all of my carbohydrates come from leafy
greens or,
or vegetables and berries and some,
some,
some other fruits,
um,
you know,
so,
and my blood glucose levels have always
been pretty,
pretty good,
like fasting blood glucose and all that.
Um,
with the exception of my lack of sleep
recently in,
you know,
but so the question I wanted to know was
like,
okay,
well,
what else is going on?
And it seems as though the production of
the major circulating ketone body,
beta hydroxybutyrate really is having an
anti aging role and you know,
dr dan's work show that it,
it's,
it's changing the expression of genes
and it's like activating longevity genes
and all this.
But the thing that's super,
super interesting to me is that the way
it's metabolized by mitochondria is
different than other energy sources.
And without getting too much into
chemistry,
it's not,
um,
in order to produce energy,
you have to use something called
electron reducing equivalents.
And they can be in the form of nad nadh
ratio or fad to agent.
So it's not going through one of those
pathways that generates more free
radicals.
And we're basically leaky electrons that
can damage mitochondria,
it doesn't go through that pathway,
like other energy sources.
So it's like you end up net not,
not,
you know,
basically having lower,
lower inflammatory and lower oxidative
damage.
Your mitochondria.
It also doesn't have what's called
proton proton,
a fork activity.
So it's almost like the way your body,
your mitochondrial metabolizing it is
better because metabolism,
you're constantly generating damage,
like damaged constantly.
Right now all the time it's just from
normal metabolism.
And it seems as though there's something
about that beta hydroxybutyrate that's
superior and it's,
it's,
it's definitely gotten me super
interested in it.
And you know,
for,
for like the longest time I was
thinking,
well I'll get my beta hydroxybutyrate by
doing time restricted eating right.
Or I'm eating all my food within like 10
hours.
And then I'm,
I'm fasting for 14 hours and I'm,
you know,
depending on how active,
what your activity levels are and all
that,
how quickly you deplete your liver,
liver glycogen,
you can start to make beta
hydroxybutyrate even within like seven
hours if you're really active,
you know.
So I was like,
well I'm getting my beta beta
hydroxybutyrate from the fasting part of
the time restricted eating right.
But I've become super interested in,
in this possible even because there's
other reasons I don't eat a ketogenic
diet.
I like to get all the micronutrients.
I like to get prebiotic fiber,
you know,
that's really good for the gut
microbiome.
But then again I don't,
we don't know exactly how ketogenic
diets even effecting the microbiome.
So that's sort of still an open,
you know,
open fields.
So I,
I'm sort of thinking can I do some sort
of cyclic,
you know,
cogenic die and also for me because I
have april before I do eat saturated
fat,
but I eat it from like whole foods I
don't like.
I used to do a lot of cooking with
coconut oil which is high in saturated
fat.
And I'm like what do I need to do that
for?
Like I don't really need to cook with
coconut oil.
I can use avocado oil,
you know?
And so I changed that and my ldl just
dropped 20 points from just that alone,
you know.
So it's like,
and what it will with large versus
small?
Yeah,
my ldl overall,
the first time.
So my baseline,
I didn't measure small dents so I don't
know what my baseline was,
but I did measure the large,
so the large and like I said,
the large can transform into the small
events and so with,
with refined sugars,
that's what's.
No,
but like you mentioned genetics,
there may be something that we don't
know.
What is the mechanism for the
transference of the sugar with the ldl?
Like w what?
What causes it to become small?
Dense.
I'm not sure we entirely understand that
yet just because it's definitely a
correlation in their head and it has
been shown in clinical studies to,
to not just be correlation but causal
where you give people refined sugar and
they're.
They're small dental school.
Yeah,
same diet,
adding refined sugar.
You see a radical difference.
You measure their small dense ldl before
giving them the refined sugars,
same diet,
and then you measure after the soda
blast of refined sugar for three weeks
and they're small,
dense ldl particles going through the
roof.
So that's causal because you're giving
them something,
you're measuring it before and after
effect,
and if there's anything that we can
conclusively point too,
it's that refined sugar is absolutely
bad for you.
There's no doubt about that,
right?
I,
I think so.
I think that,
you know,
there's so many studies that have shown,
the inflammatory biomarkers go up,
your small dense ldl biomarkers go up.
There's correlation studies showing that
people that eat refined sugar have like
tila
mirrors,
which are a biomarker for aging that
looked 10 years older.
You know,
even though people,
they're the same chronological age is
other people that don't eat the refined
sugar.
There's studies and men would like,
they give men 75 grams of refined sugar
and their testosterone drops by 25
percent.
I mean,
it's changing a lot of things in the
body in a negative way.
Well,
mine,
my testosterone doubled when I changed
my diet.
When I cut out the pasta,
when I cut out the bread and I started
eating more saturated fat,
more protein,
and I went to the ketogenic diet,
literally a doubled doing everything
exactly the same.
It was stunning and I felt different
like I can feel the difference,
feel the difference in my energy levels,
feel a difference.
Cognitively.
The cognitive thing was a big thing and
I attributed it to cutting out refined
sugars and refined carbohydrates.
I think.
I think that stuff's poison.
Well,
there's been studies showing it also
affects your brain and negative way as
well,
and people that eat refined sugar,
you know,
there's,
there's more brain atrophy.
I mean,
there's lots of correlations.
The one thing I will say is that,
you know,
there are people that are super
physically active and they're like
working out two hours a day and you
know,
those guys,
they all use refined sugar.
Yeah.
To,
you know,
their,
their increased transport glucose
transporter,
their muscles and are using it as an
anabolic way to like get bigger muscle.
And I know guys who do that after they
work out the candy.
Yeah,
I'm and,
and it,
it's not like it's,
it's.
You can't compare like people that
aren't working out like two hours a day
or you know,
like that to normal people.
Raymond,
sedentary weightlifters,
weightlifters,
yes.
Folded or just ripping their body apart
there.
I mean there's a lot of savages out
there that are doing crazy power lifting
workouts and benching and squatting and
I know a lot of guys who like to eat
candy afterwards,
right?
Yeah.
No,
it's,
it's certainly,
you know,
I think that those people,
they're,
they're not,
it's not,
it's not acting the same way,
be different requirements that their
body needs in terms of glucose.
And the thing is,
I mean still it's like the way I think
about it is it's not really nutrient
dense,
you know?
I like to like,
I'm like,
well there's lots of.
There's reasons.
Yeah,
there's a reason why I like to like take
it if you want the sugar and eat an
orange or an apple or something like
that,
or you should probably the better move
than eaten candy,
but I think
they just want a ton of it.
And what is the,
what's the anabolic factor?
Like if you were going to eat candy or
something like that,
has a bunch of refined sugar after like
an intense workout.
What would be the anabolic effect?
Well,
the glucose,
so the,
the workout causes glucose transporters
that transport glucose to like go
through the roof and so you start the
glucose from your bloodstream,
gets sucked into the muscle,
and then in the muscle,
you know,
you're,
you're basically,
you can,
you can use that as,
as,
as a way to,
to,
to have insulin and it can be anabolic,
right?
Where,
where whereas if you weren't doing that,
then the glucose in your bloodstream and
it can also tip small dense ldl
particles can start to form because the
inflammatory transformations that
happened and things like that,
that's at least my understanding that's
in combination of course with amino
acids which are also important for the
growth of the protein and muscle.
But um,
my understanding of it,
I think.
So in general though,
if someone could cut one thing out of
their diet,
refined carbohydrates and refined sugars
would be a great way to go.
I think the one,
if you were to think about the one
easiest thing that you could do that
would have the biggest impact on your
health.
And if you're talking,
if we're talking about,
we're not talking about someone who's
already paleo or someone like,
you're right,
we're talking about standard american
person.
Yes.
The one thing that they could do to have
the biggest impact on their health,
I would say,
is to cut out refined sugar.
Like that's probably the biggest thing.
The easiest thing.
I mean,
I don't know how easy it is,
you know,
it can be addicted and that's been shown
dopamine levels,
you know,
can get activated and that it's also
your gut biome.
Correct?
Right.
Your gut biome literally has an impact
on what you desire,
right?
Yeah,
it does.
So you're,
you're the,
the thing about your microbiome and your
gut is that like,
you know,
the,
the microbiome eats,
it's at the distal part of your gut.
So it's in the colon,
the large intestine,
the very end of the large intestine is
where most of the trillions of bacteria
are.
And those bacteria actually eat the
fermentable fiber that we don't digest.
We don't,
we don't process.
And the fermentable fiber comes from a
variety of plants,
from,
from plants,
and from seeds and nuts.
And you know,
I'm like qms as well,
uh,
you know,
so there's different types of
fermentable fiber that are found in
different types of foods and they feed
different species of bacteria.
Well,
when you don't get enough of that
fermentable fiber,
what ends up happening,
in fact,
there's been studies showing that 75
percent of the microbiome population
changes.
And like when,
when you don't get at all any fiber,
and what happens,
a couple of things,
one is those,
mike,
those bacteria species,
they start to eat,
um,
the carbohydrate that's lining your gut
called mucin,
which is what makes up the gut barrier
that separates the immune cells in your
gut from the bacteria.
They start to eat it because it's
carbohydrate.
And so you actually start to break down
your gut barrier just from that.
The second thing that happens is what
you mentioned is that a lot of the
pathogenic bacteria will swim up to the
small intestine where they're really not
supposed to be.
Small intestine is where you absorb
sugar.
Protein,
fats,
this warmup there,
and guess what sugar they start,
so they start to like eat the sugar and
they start to multiply.
And the thing about having bacteria in
the small intestine where it's not
supposed to be,
is that it causes the same response
that,
that eating gluten causes,
where it basically those,
those,
it's called small bacteria,
intestinal overgrowth.
And what happens is that the tight
junctions that make up the gut barrier
starts to open up and open up and that
allows the inflammatory immune cells to
be in contact with bacteria.
And of course the immune cells go
bacteria and they started to like try to
kill it because they think this not
supposed to be there.
It could be potentially harmful
pathogenic bacteria.
And so that starts to set off an immune
response,
inflammatory immune response.
And the more you have,
the more sugar you eat,
the more your population of bacteria is
flourishing.
So,
so that's like,
that's another thing that's,
that's,
um,
that's changing that.
But it's also the one of the reasons,
like I was saying with um,
and I've never actually tried a
ketogenetic diet,
but,
um,
because,
you know,
for various reasons,
but I,
I'm not sure how much plants you eat,
like what,
like can you eat like a good amount of,
can you get like some roots,
depends on the individual on a very
small scale.
Uh,
robb wolf and his wife have done some
pretty interesting tasks where they'll
both eat the same thing and they'll both
tests themselves.
He'll test the,
both of them,
you know,
x amount of minutes later and they have
a radically different response between
the two of them.
It's really interesting.
Like his wife is much more resilient and
he has much more of a difficult time
getting back into ketosis.
It's real,
it's real.
He's just documented a lot of it on his,
um,
his instagram page.
But I think it speaks to what you were
talking about before that it really
depends on where your ancestors evolved
and really has.
There's different.
We very biologically so much
right?
We do.
And that's,
that that affects how we respond to
these foods and all that,
you know.
But um,
anyways,
uh,
what was the other thing I wanted to ask
you about?
Oh,
the nad to remember the nad I was
talking about like the nad and nadh
ratio in ned.
So this is something,
what does that add stand for?
Again,
nicotinamide attending die nucleotide
and it's something,
it's something that,
um,
it's kind of in a way similar to atp
where it's used as an energetic currency
throughout the body for,
for,
for various things,
but it's actually required to like
forgive metabolism,
like you need it to metabolize fatty
acids and glucose and amino acids,
but you also,
you need it to repair damage.
You need it for a variety of other
things that are happening.
And the thing is,
is that these nad levels in tissues that
are very energetically demanding,
they deplete.
So for example,
if you're immune,
if you have chronic inflammation and
your immune system's chronic chronically
being activated,
the nad levels are going to that.
And it's kinda like triaging.
And so what happens is your metabolism
suffers and it's been shown now that nad
levels in like multiple tissues with
age,
they deplete.
Lots of preclinical studies have shown
that it plays a role in the aging
process.
And if you,
for example,
take like a mouse that has progeria this
pro aging phenotype,
and then you give them the nad it like
can like basically kind of rescue that
in a way and they like live a more
normal health span and more normal
lifespan.
So it's like,
and there's lots of studies showing that
in various ways there's recently been a
lot of interest in it because the nad
there's a way to replenish it through
supplemental form called nicotinamide
riboside.
So nad is actually formed from vitamin b
three,
like nicotinic acid or nicotinamide,
or from tryptofan.
But nicotine in my driver's side is,
um,
another precursor that you can take in
supplemental form.
And there's been studies over the past
few years looking at how in animals it's
been able to eat,
increase nad levels.
It's able to like basically improve
physical performance,
cognitive performance.
It's able to make your tissues age
better,
your organs,
age better and in,
in animals.
So I'm now,
there's like ben preclinical trials that
are,
sorry,
clinical trials that have been under
undergoing one showing that you actually
can take the supplemental form of nad
nicotinamide riboside and you can
increase your nad levels it just
dependent manner so as to say that just
came out recently and there's now um,
um,
there's now like 10 clinical trials that
have been under that are undergoing
right now looking at the role of
supplemental nicotine,
nicotine in my right beside,
in a dementia in obesity,
um,
traumatic brain injuries and other one
and then some other type of metabolic
dysfunction so that the,
these are currently being investigated
in humans.
So the sad thing is another real big
interest of mine.
I did buy the supplement,
but I'm not taking it right now because
I'm breastfeeding and I'm just not sure
how that,
you know how that goes.
But you're asking me about the ib stuff.
I think that's something that is now
popular everywhere I've looked at,
I've looked it up.
It's like it's becoming really popular.
But the thing is,
is that there's really no clinical
evidence of it,
you know,
of like if you,
if you intravenously take ned,
is that gonna have the same effect that,
you know,
taking nicotinamide riboside does,
does it get into your cells?
So it's an open question,
but it seems,
it seems like people are.
I'm getting results and obviously it's
all anecdotal.
I don't have anything ivy.
Have you ever done like ivy vitamin
infusions?
No.
No,
I haven't either.
I haven't done anything.
Always look at it.
I go,
oh,
that's good.
What?
Right.
I mean I don't want to sit there and
have vitamins pumped into my veins for
nothing.
I've had people,
I've had people tell me that like great
things about doing the nad nad plus is
what it's actually called.
But I've never actually,
I've never tried that.
And I think before I would do something
like that,
I would probably try the nicotine in my
beside,
which we know for a fact does increase,
you know,
nad levels and multiple tissues.
And it would be nice to have some of
these clinics that are doing it,
like aggregate the data.
And publish it because no one's going to
fund this study like people aren't
studying that,
you know,
so there's no way to really know if it's
placebo or really,
you know,
because there's no data.
So it'd be,
it'd be kinda nice to like people would
start to aggregate data on that.
But well it's really interesting when it
comes to data
when it comes to diet,
because you know the whole throw the
baby out with the bathwater thing.
One of the studies that I've read pretty
recently was about the amount of people
that suffered ill health consequences
that ate red meat five days per week
versus people who didn't.
But what they didn't take into account
was what the people ate with the red
meat when they drank soda with it.
How did you get your form of red meat?
Was it grass fed beef?
Was it bison or wild game?
Or was it a burger from wendy's with
fries and the sugar bond and all the
bullshit that people eat along with the
food and that you,
you literally.
And people would cite these things as
being evidence that something is
negative for you,
that red meat is negative for you,
but you're not taking into consideration
all of the things that we're eating with
that red meat.
So these studies that come out like that
are so they're.
They're really annoying because it's
like you have to,
you usually talk to people about it.
You have to like sit down with them.
Okay,
sit down.
this is a long process to try to try to
figure out what is the cause of these
issues when you're talking about a
lifetime of abuse,
you're talking about like all sorts of
different health consequences of a
variety of different foods and you're
attributing it all to one part of your
diet and that's very difficult to do
unless you,
you've isolated everything else and done
a bunch of different studies where okay,
I ate nothing but fruits and vegetables
and I really healthy and I read meet
five days a week or I nothing but shit
and fries and bonds and pasta and I
didn't eat red meat at all.
And now here's the result.
Right?
If you're making a really good point and
that is the combination of how these
different foods are interacting in our
bodies,
extremely important.
Like we talked about the refined sugar
and saturated fat combo.
Well,
you know,
the,
the red meat and even just protein like
itself,
like,
you know,
essential amino acids that are coming
from animal protein itself and how that
is interacting with,
you know,
eating,
eating a terrible diet like refined
sugar which is causing damage to
ourselves.
You know,
also exercise and this is something
really,
um,
the,
the protein,
a exercise thing seems to be really key.
But there was a recent study that was
published that was the largest study
observational study done so far,
looking at protein intake and all cause
mortality and cancer mortality.
And it found a,
like a lot of other studies that higher
protein consumption,
higher meat,
protein consumption from meat was
associated with a higher all cause
mortality in a higher cancer mortality.
But then when the data was analyzed and,
and,
and other unhealthy lifestyle factors
will look at.
So.
So if,
if someone had one other unhealthy
lifestyle factor being either obesity,
smoking,
excessive alcohol consumption or being
sedentary than they had a higher,
they were,
had a higher all cause mortality in a
higher cancer mortality if they meat.
But guess what,
if they had zero,
none of those other unhealthy lifestyle
factors they didn't have.
They had the same aisle all cause
mortality and cancer related mortality
that the non meat eater tat.
So I think that really highlights the
importance of other lifestyle factors.
Other foods,
you know,
that's really important when we're at,
when we're looking at these
observational studies,
when you were talking about saturated
fat and the negative consequences of
eating refined sugar with saturated fat,
is there a negative,
I'm a corresponding negative
consequence.
Like if you had a negative or if you had
um,
a,
a diet that didn't have any saturated
fat in it,
but you ate refined sugar,
like say if you eat a vegan diet,
does saturated or does refined sugar
have less of an impact
of eating refined sugars?
The ldl,
it's an issue with fat it,
I think.
Yes.
So the ldl will go down if you're eating
a vegan diet and even though you're
still eating cookies or some whatever
vegan stuff,
you know,
fine.
Sugar's probably like less dangerous to
someone on a vegan diet.
Is that?
Yes,
I think so.
And,
and the thing,
the thing with that is,
is that if you look at,
but if you look at refined sugar,
also refined sugar is associated with
heart disease risk.
In fact it's like one of the,
you know,
there was a big,
big study like 400,000
different individuals looked at refined
shirt,
people that had the highest refined
sugar intake,
but again,
saturated fats,
a confounding factor there had like a
four times higher risk of getting heart,
having a heart attack.
But it's perfect.
You illustrated it perfectly.
And that is,
and that's where I think a lot of these
guidelines,
like the american heart association come
from.
If you on a population level,
if you say to someone reduce your
saturated fat intake,
you're going to lower the ldl risk and
regardless of all the other stuff
they're doing,
you know,
it probably will on a population level,
lower their heart disease risk,
but on an individual level like someone
like you and I,
we don't eat all that other stuff,
you know,
we were very health conscious and do all
these things.
You and I,
if we stopped our saturated fat intake,
likely,
you know,
for me,
I guess my jeans are a little different
but likely wouldn't have the same
effect.
So if you were to take that same
population of people and say,
okay,
eat your saturated fat,
but take out the refined sugar,
we may see the same thing where the,
where the heart disease risk goes down
just like it does with saturated fat.
In fact,
there had been studies where a
replacement foods have done,
have looked at,
um,
replacement fruits for saturated fat.
And if you replace saturated fat with
refined sugar,
it does not,
um,
lower the risk of heart disease.
So basically that's kind of a proof of
principle there,
but I do think that it's,
it's an,
it's an important point and it's
something that the american heart
association there,
they're now starting to at least
mentioned the small dense ldl particles.
So I think that moving in that direction
is because it means
that possibly then,
you know,
over the next decade we're going to
start to see,
okay,
now we got to start.
It's not just the ldl,
I'm confused about something you just
said.
You said if you replace saturated fat
with refined sugar,
if you replace the saturated fat with
refined sugar,
refined carbohydrates,
which I usually think of as refined
sugar,
refined carbohydrates,
it does not.
So the idea is of saturated fat was so
bad.
If you replaced,
if you took the saturated fat and
replaced it with refined carbohydrate,
it would lower the risk of heart
disease.
And it does,
it doesn't.
It doesn't lower the risk.
Right?
So,
so basically other saturated fats,
the saturated fat along with refined
sugar that has some sort of a negative
synergistic effect.
That's what,
that's what the data and aggregation,
looking at the clinical trials,
looking at the mechanism,
looking at the observational studies and
and understanding the interaction of all
these foods together and the wideness
when the american heart association puts
out sort of a blanket statement like
that.
A lot of people take it as fact and then
what my research has shown my reading
rather shouldn't say research.
I'm a dummy,
but the people that I've read who have
criticized this are actually scientists
and researchers.
They have a huge issue with that
statement.
They think that this is just,
it's too simplistic.
It's not taking into account all the
various nuances in genetics,
diet,
ancestry,
all the different factors,
but people read that and it sort of like
this cookie cutter approach and then
they paired it out to everybody else.
Yeah,
it's true.
I mean that's.
That's exactly what happens and that
same thing goes with the protein in it
being bad as well and there's all sorts
of nuances and the combination of the
protein with the,
with the bad diet and also the exercise,
which is one of the.
One of the things with the,
with the protein is that it increases
igf one and igf one growth factor and it
can allow b cells that are damaged,
that would otherwise die,
not die,
and so it can allow precancerous cells
to form a tumor and that's.
We know that from mechanistic studies
and you know that's.
That's kind of a big part of the the
eating protein essential amino acids
specifically or what does it do do this
and they're found in animal protein and
that.
Sort of the big argument there,
but there's also this whole argument
where if you are one exercising the igf
one goes into your brain.
It's been trying to cross the blood
brain barrier.
It goes into your brain and also in your
muscle where it grows new neurons in the
brain and actually repairs damaged,
damaged muscle tissue and helps grow
muscle tissue.
Which is also an a predictor of of all
caused mortality.
So you know the,
again,
the exercise comes in there and then
also the fact that if you're eating a
good diet and you're not,
you're not causing as much damage to
happen in the first place,
then those growth factors being there
aren't as big of a deal because you
don't have all these damaged cells from
all this refined sugar you're eating
that can basically become cancerous
cells.
So that's kind of,
you know,
with that study,
the observational study that looked at
people that were eating me,
if they didn't have any of those
unhealthy lifestyle factors,
guess what?
They're all cause mortality and cancer
mortality was the same as the
vegetarians.
And I think that's kind of highlighting
that,
that issue,
you know,
well I have a friend who's a scientist
who's talking to me about me and he
goes,
ms dot essentially amino acids,
protein and water.
He's like,
it's not going to cause you cancer.
It's like this is not what the problem
is.
He goes,
you,
you have some issues with the way it's
cooked.
So for sure like things that are charred
or not good for you,
there's carcinogens right?
And in the black and charred.
Yeah,
I mean there's heterocyclic aiming
second forum when you cook meat at a
really high temperature and those are
carcinogens and.
But our body,
our bodies have genes that are able to
inactivate those somebodies,
but some not people can do it to,
to various levels.
There's certain polymorphisms in genes
that I'm basically,
some people can detoxify it really well
and they're,
they're called detoxification enzymes
and some people don't do it quite as
well.
And the people that don't do it quite as
well probably shouldn't charge their
meat as much.
Like you shouldn't eat it like everyday,
like charred,
but,
but that's not.
The big issue isn't so much that as the,
the igf one,
which doesn't cause cancer,
but it allows cancer cells to grow.
So the difference,
it's like one is like,
oh you eat meat,
it causes cancer.
Well no,
that's not necessarily true.
You eat a lot of meat and you don't
exercise and you keep having igf one
around and you have all these other
damaged cells because you're eating all
this other crap which is causing damage.
Then you're allowing the igf one no,
to allow those damaged cells to grow.
So one is like a promoting where it's
promoting the growth of cancer and the
other one's saying it causes so it
doesn't cause in that sense.
Now in the carcinogen,
if you're getting a ton of carcinogens
and plus there's studies showing that
eating cruciferous vegetables,
the isothiocyanates and people that have
that gene polymorphism that don't
detoxify the heterocyclic amiens as
well.
If they eat a diet high in,
in cruciferous vegetables and they have
isothiocyanates it,
they also inactivate those,
those web pro carcinogens and so a
broccoli sprouts,
broccoli,
cauliflower,
cabbage,
brussels sprouts,
broccoli sprouts industry.
The last time you were on it,
it's amazing.
I've had people emailing me that like
they're either them themselves or their
father or someone there taking care of
their prostate cancer biomarker.
The prostate stimulating angela antigen
has like gone down like two fold after
doing the broccoli sprouts every day for
x amount of time,
which is something we talked about
because it's clinical.
Clinical trials have shown that it's,
it's very powerful.
Now when you,
um,
when you look at animals,
animal
protein,
and I'm including fish in this for this,
um,
is there any benefit to a specific type?
Like someone was telling me that red
meat is better for you than chicken and
I was like,
well,
how do you know?
And they're like,
well,
how it makes me feel kind said,
okay,
well that doesn't seem to make much
sense.
Like what is.
But is there a difference?
I mean obviously there's a difference in
the protein content,
like have some meats or wild game has
much higher protein content than say
domestic beef.
But when you
think like fish,
like is there,
is our living animals all created equal?
That's the question.
Well of course there's lots of
differences.
I mean if the protein,
the amino acid makeup are different and
I'm not an expert on that so I can't
tell you all the differences there.
But there's differences in,
in the micronutrient concentrations.
I mean omega three fatty acids are in
fish,
are a lot of irons and in red meat.
So there's difference,
different zinc,
you know,
iron,
selenium,
omega three fatty acids,
all these different things are found in
different concentrations,
in different types of meat and you know,
so for that reason it's kind of good to
eat a diverse array of different types
because you're getting,
you know,
22 percent of all your enzymes in your
body require micronutrients as a
cofactor to work,
you know,
and the omega three fatty acids are
important,
you know,
really important for the brain,
hugely important for the brain.
So I think that in that respect,
you know,
there are obviously differences in terms
of the different types of meat that
you're eating,
right?
I mean,
so,
so yeah.
But um,
and then the ratio of the proteins are
different.
I don't know exactly how,
what,
what those differences are,
but you know,
there's,
that affects things as well.
So do you think what a good healthy
approach if someone does eat meat is to
d a little bit of everything,
like a little bit of salmon,
maybe a little bit of red meat,
a little bit of bias and a little bit of
chicken.
I think that's the approach I like to
take because I like to,
I like to look at things in terms of
nutrient quality and why am I,
why am I eating this food?
Oh,
I'm eating this food because I want this
type of amino acid profile.
I want these micronutrients,
you know,
I,
I want 'em either this type of prebiotic
fiber or not and you know,
so I kind of look at it as these
nutrient delivery vesicles that I'm like
taking in.
And that's,
that's the approach I like.
I,
you know,
it's,
I'm a little biased because I've been
doing a lot of research on
micronutrients and so I,
you know,
I know how important they are and I've,
and I've,
I've studied even in people things like
biomarkers of aging,
like dna damage and seeing how they
change with different micro nutrient
intakes or different types of fiber
intakes or you know,
things like that.
So,
so,
you know,
for me,
I kind of am a little biased in that
sense,
but um,
you know,
it's,
it's the approach that I like to take,
you know,
for example,
this is a really good story.
And my,
my mentor Bruce Bruce ames,
who I talk about a lot,
he was the inventor of the ames test,
which is a test that really cheap test
that you can do to determine whether or
not something is a carcinogen.
In fact,
I'm sure the heterocyclic amines were
determined from his test because you can
dump something on and he can base it,
basically can tell you like in a matter
of minutes.
Right?
So he's,
that was his,
like he,
he was,
um,
pioneered that back in like the late
seventies,
early eighties,
and he was responsible for getting
carcinogens out of hair dye,
women's hair dyes out of children's
pajamas.
Lots of,
lots of really big health impacts that
he was in pajamas.
Um,
there was some kind of polyurethane ish
thing.
I don't remember exactly.
It's not there anymore,
but it was,
it was,
it was to prevent them from,
it was a flame retardant.
Oh,
it was a flame retardant and it was,
it was completely a carcinogen and it
was ending up in children's urine and
stuff.
They were measuring it.
Yeah.
So anyways,
my point is is that he used to be in
this whole like cancer or chemical
carcinogen field and then one day like,
you know,
someone in his loud did,
blab,
did an experiment where they like left
full laid out of the sample and there
was massive amounts of dna damage
happening.
He was like,
what's going on here?
And they started to do this in mice and
found that like a low folate dial diet
caused damage to dna,
the same as being irradiated by an x ray
machine.
The exact same.
And then he went into people and found
there was a really small pilot
experiment but similar the cause dna
damage on people that had a low full a
diet.
And he said that one experiment right
there changed the whole course of his
field of study where he all of a sudden
went into nutrition and micronutrients
and that became his thing from the
eighties on and kind of from an
accident.
Yeah,
from an accident,
doesn't that happen all the time in lab?
All the time.
It's with the best stuff.
It was funny because the guy in his lab
was like calling.
He was trying to figure out what is
going on here and then he.
He looked at his assistant had ordered
this media that you put on cells and he
looked at the media,
try to figure out what was in it and
they saw it was a specific type of media
that the assistant had ordered
incorrectly that lacked full late and so
this whole thing was all started from
that and so credible.
Yeah.
So he published that seminal paperwork.
Literally he compared my being
irradiated under an x ray machine to low
folate and it was identical.
Now,
would that be
be something that people should take
into their diet of say if they are
flight attendants are pilots because
don't they isn't like flying like a form
of radiation.
You do get some radiation that's similar
to an x ray,
right?
Yeah,
I mean that's the full eight.
It's a different mechanism by how it's
preventing it.
Basically eight is needed to make a
actual precursor to dna and without that
precursor,
you don't make the dna right.
And you incorporate a nucleotide from
rna into it and so you basically make a
break in your dna strand.
But um,
but dna damage is,
yeah,
is something that happens with,
with pilots and astronauts and things
like that.
And I'm had been measured.
Uh,
yeah,
it's been measured.
And if there was a really weird study
that came out recently that astronauts,
they had like exceptionally longer
telomeres than.
Yeah,
where it's like,
it was totally counter intuitive where
dna damage usually causes telomeres get
shorter.
And so like if you were to have asked
me,
I would have predicted that the
astronauts would have had shorter
telomeres.
So,
so definitely some weird stuff going on.
We don't understand,
you know,
but,
um,
and there's obviously a variety of other
things you can do to protect yourself
from that.
But I forgot why.
The whole point is that the
micronutrients were important.
Bruce ames is,
has been my mentor and friend for many
years and,
and I've sort of been in this field of
study for,
for awhile and so it's,
it's,
it's how I think about food and doesn't
mean it's the best way,
but it's the way that I've convinced
myself so far with the tools that I have
available to me that that's how I like
to eat.
Um,
and again,
anyone that's doing any sort of diet
should always measure biomarkers and
things like that to know if it's working
for them.
What's a good source of folate leafy
greens.
In fact,
my bruce,
his mentor when he was a graduate
student is the guy who identified,
he actually discovered full life by
identifying,
isolating it from spinach.
So spanish.
Um,
yeah,
leafy greens are great source of fully,
um,
but the leafy greens,
like the other thing that gets me on
this,
and I know I talked about this last time
was like other compounds that are in
the,
in the plants where we're sort of just
scratching the surface on understanding
them like what they're doing in our
bodies.
Like one for example,
is looting,
it's president leafy greens,
kales are really,
really great source of it.
Looting is like,
it's found in the,
first of all,
it was known that routine's important
for the rods and cones in your eyes,
so people like they'll take supplements
with ludy and to help with their vision.
But all this recent research over the
last few years is found is like
accumulating in large amounts in the
brain or like what is lutein doing and
the human brain.
Well,
it turns out it's like there's been
clinical studies now controlled trials
like giving people looting and,
and,
and it's,
it plays a role in,
in cognition like people have better
learning and memory scores after taking
moodiness.
Um,
it's involved in a crystallized
intelligence which decreases with age.
No.
So there's like,
there's things like that and other one
is this one that I'm really interested
in.
Now I'm actually supplementing with pqq
and that one is it's made by bacteria
and bacteria in the soil.
So it's made by bacteria because it's
important for,
um,
it's a cofactor for enzymes for their
metabolic enzymes to work well.
Plants take it up from soil and then we
eat the plants and get an our diet and
it's been shown now in like in a few
studies,
lots and lots of preclinical studies.
It's been shown to regulate
mitochondrial function,
improves mitochondrial function,
clinical,
a couple of clinicals trials now have
been done looking at how it affects
humans.
If you supplement with like 20 minutes a
day,
improves cognition.
It also improves markers of
mitochondrial function.
Um,
lowers markers of inflammation will
turns out pqq has like 20,000
times the catalytic activity,
um,
than something like ascorbic acid.
So it's a really powerful antioxidant.
And what I mean by that is,
so ascorbic acid goes through cycles of
vitamin c,
it's,
it's either oxidized or reduced and it
can,
it when,
when,
when it does this antioxidant thing,
it becomes oxidized and they can do that
four times where it goes,
it donates,
it,
donates this,
this hydrogen and you know,
help.
It helps to,
you know,
basically combat the oxidative stress.
But then it gets oxidized again and it
can do it again four times.
Pqq does it 20,000
times,
like,
isn't that mindblowing?
Often times
and it's really concentrated in breast
milk.
So I'm actually taking it right now.
It's super interesting.
It seems like something that everyone
should supplement.
I think maybe so.
Yeah.
Because,
you know,
I,
you never really know,
but I,
I'm,
I'm supplementing with it and,
and uh,
I certainly don't notice anything
because like sometimes those,
those sorts of changes are really hard
to,
to measure.
Um,
and especially you have to wait until,
I mean who knows,
like later on in life,
but I think it may be something that's
important that may be a,
has beneficial effects in humans as
well.
So,
and like again,
you can,
you get it from plants,
but 20 milligrams a day is when I'm
taking because that's what the two
different clinical trials have shown.
What's the best plant source of it?
I don't know what the best.
I'm sure you could find that google,
but because various various plants take
it up from the soil,
so probably things that are growing in
the soil,
right?
That would be the best.
Um,
but yeah,
it's like,
it's found like five or six fold higher
and higher levels that it is an art
tissues and plants of course,
because the plants are the source of it.
Um,
but,
but yeah,
taking a supplemental form you'll be
getting orders of magnitude more.
Do you have a supplement company that
you rely on the most?
I do.
So the thing with supplements is that
there's,
there are really risky,
uh,
there's lots of studies that have been
published showing that a lot of
supplements don't contain what they say
they contain or they contain a fraction
of it and they got a bunch of other
filler like cloverleaf and stuff.
So,
um,
one of the supplement companies.
So,
and there's a scientist friend of mine,
his name is dr jed fay.
He,
he's like,
he's the guy who discovered that
broccoli sprouts are the best source of
sulforaphane.
He,
um,
he measured a variety of supplements and
then he was looking specifically at,
like precursor to sulforaphane and uh,
he looked at a variety of different
companies and one of the companies that
was just really,
really,
really good and reliable was thorn.
Thorn t h o r n e,
and that's something I don't have any
affiliation with them or anything but
that I always there my goto brand.
Whenever I'm looking for a supplement
like I took,
I took their prenatal from throughout
pregnancy.
Um,
actually I'm still taking the prenatal
and breastfeeding.
I take vitamin d and vitamin k two a,
I take pretty much a lot of my stuff
comes from them and the pqq,
however,
that,
um,
I've only been able to find from life
extension and I think life extensions
pretty okay so far as I can tell.
But thorn is like my,
my,
my favorite company,
uh,
so far just because I've got data from a
scientist that I,
that I trust is a difficult issue and
tainted supplements a or a huge problem
with athletes.
A lot of false positives are not even
false positives.
A lot of athletes will take supplements,
like if they go to like some just
generic vitamin store,
you know,
whatever name the name and they pick up
some of a creatine
or muscle enhancer or this or that.
And a lot of them are tainted with
steroids or they're used in the same
labs or created rather than the same
labs and they don't clean the bins.
And so like the vats,
they used to mix up one supplement will
the whatever was in residual traces of
it will wind up in some other stuff.
It's a real issue.
I think there's um,
what you were referring to there.
A lot of supplement companies that have
a stamp on it called nsf,
which is the national sanitary
foundation.
I believe they go and they investigate
where the supplements manufactured and
they look at the quality and they also,
I think even look at some,
some of the what's in the supplements if
the,
if they contain what they're supposed to
contain to some degree.
But I know they definitely look at the
manufacturing place to see if things
like that were,
you know,
things aren't being cleaned right in.
There's contamination,
all that.
So supplements that have that stamp
probably a little more reliable than
ones that don't.
But it's still not like a sure thing.
Right.
And so it's not like it just because it
has that stamp,
it's,
it's going to be the best,
I think a lot of people listening to
this and they're going to probably have
to listen to three or four times and
take notes and go over this and try to
figure out if they're going to do
something,
how to act.
A lot of people have a hard time
digesting all of this data and trying to
figure out what is the best way to
proceed in terms of investigating their
own health and monitoring their blood
levels and,
and trying to find a primary care doctor
that will kind of understand what
they're trying to do.
Yeah,
I mean the,
the,
the primary care doctor thing,
finding one.
I certainly can't help with that because
I mean that's the struggle that you and
I have,
but you know,
in terms of taking,
taking your health into your own hands
and monitoring blood biomarkers.
I mean there's a,
there's a few that are really,
really key I think for anyone doing
anything,
any type of experimentation that,
that they should do.
And we've,
we've talked about them already.
You know,
the,
the small dense ldl,
the total ldl,
you also want to measure triglycerides,
high sensitivity,
c reactive protein or hb,
one hba,
one c,
which is the marker of longterm fasting
blood glucose.
But also there's another test that you
can do that actually is a really
comprehensive metabolic tests to measure
how your body is metabolizing
carbohydrates,
fatty acids and amino acids.
It's called the organic acid test and
genova diagnostics offers it and
unfortunately you do have to get your
primary care physician to prescribe or
order that because that's not something
that's,
uh,
available to
people.
But it seems like there's room for a
company to do this,
like a one stop shop company that sort
of analyzes your health and prescribed
to you,
you know,
explains to you what's lacking in your
diet and what you could benefit from and
what you can.
And it seems like there's a,
there's a big opening for some sort of a
business like that.
Yeah,
I mean,
I think some people are actually doing
it.
Like genova diagnostics I think is one.
They do sort of do that.
Like they'll,
they'll tell you what's missing or like
the help interpret
your data and genova diagnostics.
And is it a nationwide company?
Nationwide?
Yeah,
but I don't know about worldwide.
So if you're in europe.
Yeah,
yeah.
So,
but I think there's other companies that
are kind of wellness effects,
kind of is doing that a little bit as
well.
They give you a consult with someone
after you get a variety of blood markers
measured and you know,
that we try to help you figure out that
as well.
And uh,
you know,
so it's,
it's certainly,
I think there's other people,
it's just a matter of finding a good
one.
It's always the,
the catch,
right.
It seems like with this kind of stuff
for the average consumer,
the average person listening to this,
it seems very daunting.
It's like,
boy,
there's so much to think about.
There's so.
I mean in a lot of times when people get
inundated with that much data,
they sort of shut down,
let it go.
This is just,
I can't do this,
this is too much.
And I really wish there was like a
nationwide network of places like this
where you could just go to sort of like
you can go to,
you know,
a dentist,
there should be like a place where you
can go to to get this kind of
comprehensive information about your
diet and the effects on your body and
what genes you have.
And the problem is we're still figuring
out all those nuances and so,
you know,
even even getting the data,
having the person interpret it,
it's,
you know,
it's constantly evolving and you would
have to have someone who's completely on
top of it all the time.
So we'd have to be like sending them do
literature constantly because we're
constantly changing the way we think
about a variety of things and seem like
some billionaire dude would look one of
hire you up and have them like have you
watch over them all the time and monitor
their blood and try to figure out what
they're doing wrong and prescribe things
to them.
Monitor their blood,
give them youngblood.
Yeah.
Some george soros type of care.
Is that real?
That young blood thing.
Because I know that's a real thing with
mice,
but are they really doing that with
people?
Because I had heard that peter teal had
done it,
but then he says it's bullshit.
He's never done it.
Oh really?
Yes.
Find that jamie.
Peter teal.
Denies ever get injected with young
blood.
Get to know they're there.
I know that the clinical trials that
were done at stanford,
I don't know if they'd been established
yet.
Fuck no.
Peter teals,
not harvesting the blood of the picture
of him with stories of cow.
Countess is bathing and virgin blood
vampyr ignoble.
Suck the juice out of the young have
captured our attention for centuries
when the story's coming out of the tech
billionaire peter teal was interested in
transfusing the blood into his own body
scent.
Silicon valley to a fever dream.
But,
but there is something.
So there's a company that does this.
Oh,
is there?
I didn't know that there was a northern
California company,
a startup that does this and see if he
can find that so that that is a real
pair of meiosis is what it's called.
And there's this anti aging is charging
thousands of dollars for teen blood.
Look at this kid.
Kids probably high on ecstasy,
right?
They're always given up his blood.
So they take this young person's blood.
It says like plot points from hbo.
Silicon valley.
Peter teal.
Yeah.
Just ask peter teal.
Incredible.
Well it says no.
He saying I'm looking into parabiosis
stuff,
which I think is really interesting.
This is where the sea,
he probably is looking into it.
He just hasn't done it because he's
probably waiting to see if someone
starts growing a foot on her head.
Jesse a karmazin karmazin karmazin
agrees his startup ambrosia is charging
what?
$8,000
a pop.
Expensive for blood transfusions from
people under 25.
He said at code conference on wednesday.
Ambrosia.
Which buys it's blood from blood banks.
Now.
How's about 100?
Okay.
Buying his book.
So they must specify who the people are.
Now when you go to the blood bank,
how do they even know?
Like what the fuck you've been doing
with your body?
I'm wondering.
I mean I know they monitor for certain
disease like diseases and stuff.
They're like,
well,
no,
but it's like all the other nuances,
all the other stuff.
I don't,
I don't.
Sugar and candy and bullshit.
Is that a that represented in your
blood?
Uh,
I mean there's certain biomarkers that
you can.
Yeah,
you can absolutely measure and you can
certainly look at telomere length or
length,
dna damage,
things like that.
I just have a joke about dick cheney.
Dick cheney had an extra secret service
agent that they put on this,
like super healthy diet and he couldn't
figure it out and you know,
who would have to run when everybody
else did everything.
He was just really there in case dick
had a heart attack.
They're going to cut this guy open like
a fish or pull his organs out,
give dick his heart.
But this is,
I mean this is what you would want sort
of.
You'd want someone like,
okay,
I want your blood,
I'm going to pay you for your blood,
but look,
can't be drinking.
No smoking,
no sugar,
no bullshit.
You'd have to monitor them like you
would like someone like the surrogate
moms.
Exactly fresh,
but you'd have to.
They'd have to live with me,
I'd have doing them right.
Well this is,
and this will be up and coming.
It's not just fresh blood.
So for people listening,
they don't know transplanting blood from
young animals into old animals like
rejuvenate's their brain.
It makes them live longer,
do rejuvenate's,
all their organized so like they're
healthier.
And conversely,
and conversely,
putting the old blood into young animals
messes them up,
makes them age basically.
It makes them perform worse cognitively
and all that stuff.
He's got somethings gonna pull up here.
It's saying they found it in one test
that it might have worked,
but it hasn't been replicated in these
two paragraphs.
Say that it might not even be true.
Which one interesting.
So some aspects of aging.
The 2013 study found could be reversed
when older mice get blood from younger
ones,
but other researchers have haven't been
able to replicate these results and the
benefits of para biosis and humans
remains on.
I remember that what happened was they
didn't,
they couldn't replicate the mechanism.
They thought it was this growth factor
called bdnf
and they're like,
oh,
that's not replicatable,
like that's not what's doing it.
And then this other study came out
showing that you could transplant the
old blood into the young and it would
reverse the effects.
And so now scientists are going,
oh,
is it that the young blood is a
rejuvenating or is that the old blood is
accelerating the aging.
Right.
See the difference though?
So that's kind of like,
I think we're,
it's possibly at now,
but um,
I was gonna just mention to you that
microbiome that's heading there as well.
Like there was a preliminary study that
was published not long ago in kill fish
were that the microbiome from young fish
was transplanted in the old fish and it
extended their lifespan by like 40
percent.
Whoa.
You take the microbiome from a young
person,
like my son breeze it down.
Yeah.
So,
well,
it's funny because,
um,
they think the mechanism has to do with
the immune system.
Remember I was telling you,
your microbiome makes these short chain
fatty acids and it totally regulates
your immune system.
You know,
you,
it regulates the amount of um,
you know,
a variety of different immune cells that
you're making.
And so like hamata police,
this is one which is making new blood
cells and there's been studies that have
looked at the microbiome of like really
healthy 90 year olds and they look like
the microbiome looks like,
like a 30 year old even though these are
90 year old people.
So usually the microbiomes vastly
different in older people.
But these healthy 90 year olds obviously
they're healthy if they make it to 90,
it's not,
that's not an average age of most people
make it to their microbiomes looked like
a,
like a 30 year old,
which is super interesting.
So it's a whole new.
I think we're going to start to see like
kind of like the of biosis.
It's like the microbiome microbiome
transplant.
That's it.
Yeah.
I love headlines or they break headlines
down and just get you to click on it.
Will pope's the easiest,
right.
Because now it's like,
you know,
and they're doing these,
these,
these capsules now or they're taking
poop.
Yeah.
And it's like helping people with their
ibs and of course,
like I think the problem was like making
sure it doesn't taste like shit when
it's going down on me because like the
capsule cannot pronounce,
just makes it was sugar.
And then you've got other problems,
right?
A spoonful of sugar makes a poop.
I know it's,
it's,
it's crazy.
What do you think about steve?
You stay like,
so the stevia,
um,
there's,
it's,
it's a non-nutritive sweetener.
So it's not like,
it's not like a aspartame or sacrifice
or what's the other one is sucralose,
which,
by the way,
those have all been shown to like screw
up the microbiome.
Yeah,
those are really bad.
Yeah.
They like changed the scope is what the
president drinks 12 cans a day of.
No wonder why he's making shit
decisions.
12.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
So New York times story,
they said that he drinks 12 cans of diet
coke a day and watches as much as eight
hours of television a day.
So he's,
he's,
he's literally like a test monkey.
Is that really true?
That's crazy.
It's really true.
See if you can find that article,
12 cans of beer.
It is.
Trump reportedly drinks 12 cans of diet
coke.
It looks like you're losing it using an
ad blocker.
That's the main,
um,
the main sweetener in diet coke.
Aspartame.
Aspartame,
yeah.
Trump drinks 12 diet cokes per day.
What can that do to a person's body?
And then they have a scientists thought
we're fucked.
I'll tell you what it does to the
microbiome changes the composition so
that you're like,
you're,
you're getting the kind of bacteria that
are really good at harvesting the
glucose from,
from like the small intestine area.
And it makes people become obese.
Like that's the associative studies and
people like that.
They've shown that in people.
And then of course they've done causal
studies in animals showing that.
But stevia is interesting because,
um,
I've seen positive studies with that
where it seems to improve insulin
sensitivity,
which is kind of weird.
I,
I personally am always,
um,
I,
I'll use stevia.
Like if I'm like gonna,
let's make some hot cocoa with 100
percent cocoa and it just tastes like
ass.
And I'm like,
I need some stevia.
It's like otherwise you're just doing a
shot of it.
Like hot cocoa with no sugar is 100
percent cocoa or cacao.
There's all sorts of benefits with that
too.
But.
But yeah,
with this I don't really use a lot of
stevia.
Like my,
my inlaws they,
they like to put it in their smoothies
because I've gotten so used to my
smoothies,
tasting kaylee that I guess,
you know,
and,
and plus I don't eat any,
anything sweet so I don't really need
it.
But they like to put it in their
smoothies and you know,
I don't,
I don't know if it has any.
We haven't really seen negative health
consequences with the exception.
I think there was one study in rats
where they gave him like exceptional
amounts and it like changed the,
the hormonal profile or something.
So I didn't consume any during pregnancy
because I was worried about that.
But um,
we'll don't be a rat study study,
but I think that's probably my choice.
If I were to sweeten something like my
put it in my coffee or something,
I'd put stevia with trump is grossly
overweight.
So the microbiome,
what's funny is that people are taking
diet coke or trying or they're trying to
like improve.
They don't,
they don't,
they don't want the refined sugar.
They don't want to have the,
the constant insulin response and so
they're drinking the diet coke.
It's kind of ironic that it's like,
it's like making them more be obese by
changing the gut microbiome know is,
is it safe to drink just one can every
now and again or it's just something you
can every now and then it's okay.
You know,
it's not.
I mean that's not going to like
completely not 12 cans a day or even one
candidate.
You're constantly under certain your
microbiome.
You're constantly going to keep shifting
it in towards,
you know,
the one Canada probably.
Yeah,
because it's.
The microbiome is.
Yeah.
Diet coke,
diet coke.
I haven't had diet.
Coke was like 2006.
I had one yesterday and the hotel
cracked it open.
Really?
I haven't,
I really haven't had one since 2006.
I used to drink,
um,
I used to drink them,
when,
uh,
for lightened college and stuff to stay
awake and study for exams and all that.
But if you're taking something like
that,
um,
should you take a corresponding like
some sort of a probiotic to try to
combat that?
I mean the problem with that is,
you know,
the probiotics,
which by the way,
there's all sorts of interesting studies
that have shown effectiveness of certain
probiotics that are,
you know,
have a lot of that or have live bacteria
and a lot of them.
But you know,
in order for the probiotics to work,
you either have to constantly take them
or there needs to be space in your gut
for them to take residence in.
Right?
So if you're like filling your body with
all sorts of sugar or diet coke and all
this,
then where,
where's the probiotic that you,
you're taking in gonna attach,
right?
So it's kind of flow through and the
flow through that has benefits,
but you have to keep taking it,
you know,
for that.
For that to happen.
So the,
so really a healthy diet is the way it's
not,
you can't just counteract with
supplementation.
You're healthy,
healthy diets the way meaning,
you know,
the,
the fermentable fiber which is what
helps grow,
helps the commensal and good bacteria
basically grow and thrive.
But um,
probiotics helped me a lot.
Like after I had some,
I had some gut issues from,
from stress with graduate school,
graduate school.
And so that definitely helped me.
And um,
I don't,
I,
I take them once in awhile now,
like,
you know,
but I don't,
I don't take them everyday like I did
when I was like trying to like kill
myself.
Um,
and,
and the one I was taking,
I think we've talked about this $450
million.
It's called vsl number three,
but now there's another company called
[inaudible] biome that is like the guy
who made [inaudible] vsl number three is
doing this is by all make the same
formulation.
I've tried it out as well.
Um,
but it's like a little cheaper anD I
don't have any affiliation with either
of those companies,
but theRe's been clinical clinical
studies with both of them showing
effectiveness.
and so,
um,
it's,
it's certainly an interesting field
growing field and there happens in the
clinical studies in humans where,
for example,
the one that's super interesting,
the brain,
the brain stuff,
the way it's affecting the brain is
interesting.
And there's clinical studies.
There was one recent one I thinK I
tweeted where there was like 10
randomized controlled trials.
They weren't really high quality but
it's a start and it improved measures of
anxiety and people,
other studies have shown in randomized
controlled trials have been a couple of
others showing it improves depression
scores and also in cognition.
So tHere's,
you know,
again,
immune system modulation of the immune
system will affect the brain immune
system.
It definitely is kind of,
you know,
basically inflammatory factors and
things like that can cross over to the
blood brain barrier and getting the
brain and disrupt neurotransmitter
production and all sorts of stuff.
But also the gut brain access,
the bagel nerve where like you can make
certain things that are like if you,
if you have certain bacteria in the gut
that are making,
for example,
gabba that can stimulate the nerve in
inhibitory way that like comes in and
does something calming to the,
to the,
the brain part.
We don't really
understand all the mechanisms.
That's just fascinating field that I'm
like trying to follow and keep up on,
you know.
But I mean,
the question is,
do you do normal healthy people need to
take probiotics all the time and I don't
know the answer,
but I do think that we need to,
to eat the right foods to get our
microbiome healthy and avoid things
like,
you know,
what's it called?
Aspartame.
Yeah,
aspartame.
Nutrasweet.
Although that's the same stuff,
right?
That's nutrasweet.
I think it is the blue packet now.
Well,
getting back to developing fetuses and
uh,
an infant developing in the womb.
When you were talking about,
uh,
foods that cause inflammation and
autoimmune diseases,
there's,
there's a correlation between those two.
Correct.
So when your eating inflammation causing
foods,
refined carbohydrates,
refined sugars,
and you have a baby and if you have this
inflammation in your body and you are
having autoimmune reactions,
uh,
and this can trigger many autoimmune
diseases that people have.
Um,
what's,
is there.
Has there been studies done trying to
understand what happens when you consume
a lot of pro inflammatory foods,
foods that cause inflammation and what
kind of a reaction that has to the
developing child?
Well,
studies have been done,
um,
you know,
to,
to establish causation in animals and
looking at correlation and there've been
correlated correlative studies in
humans.
So for example,
most of the time though,
people,
the correlative studies aren't looking
at whether or not they're consuming the
quote unquote inflammatory foods that
cause inflammatory types of reactions
like refined sugar.
They're just looking at obese mothers.
And usually someone who's obese
typically is not eating a healthy diet.
So I think that more times than not can
say,
well,
they're probably eating a lot of refined
carbohydrates and things like that.
But you know,
and,
and so that,
you know,
the correlation between that and looking
at,
you know,
negative health consequences and
offspring like type one diabetes,
even poor,
doing poorly on cognitive cognition
tests and things like that that's been
looked at.
Animal studies,
there have been studies that have shown
causally that you can do that by feeding
a mouse,
a high fat high sugar diet and then,
you know,
making the female mouse obese and
changing basically the way there,
the offspring metabolism and their
immune cells are reacting.
So things like that definitely have been
shown in animal studies,
but it's,
it's really almost impossible to show a
causal study like that in humans.
Right.
So it's like you kind of have to,
like,
you've got these,
like you were showing with the
acetaminophen and adhd to reduce risk.
Like you're not going to have a
controlled trial where they're going to
give women acetaminophen during
pregnancy and see if it causes adhd.
Like that's never gonna happen.
Like you can't,
it's not,
it's,
it's unethical.
Right.
You know.
So then the next best thing would be to
like then go to animal studies.
And show it,
you know,
the problem,
the problem with the animal studies,
and this is,
this is always problem is you know,
you never know how much of it translates
into things.
Things are different,
like the way they're,
they metabolize the livers of,
of mice,
metabolize xenobiotics can be a little
different than humans.
And so things like,
you know,
these,
these mice can be a little more
susceptible to things like bpa in,
you know,
things that are,
that are damaging,
um,
than,
than humans,
which,
which contain certain enzymes that some
of these mice lack,
that can,
you know,
basically alter their metabolism and
make it not so harmful so to speak.
Um,
but,
but still,
I think it's good if you've,
if you've got like the perspective
studies in humans that's correlating.
And then you've got the mechanistic
studies in animals,
it's a stronger,
it's a stronger argument than if you
just looked at one or the other.
You know,
good studies that show.
There's a correlation between gut,
my gut microbiome and children with
autism and asperger's and several other
diseases.
Yeah,
yeah.
There have been.
the gut microbiome seems to play a major
role in,
um,
there's definitely some changes with
autistic children and I'm an asperger's
like being on the autistic spectrum.
So,
and,
and that's something that's like,
I'm not sure it's entirely understood,
but there's a connection there.
There's a connection with the gut
microbiome and parkinson's disease with
multiple sclerosis.
I mean these are,
these are lots of studies are coming out
showing these connection with brain
problems,
not,
not just,
you know,
autoimmune type of,
of,
of um,
diseases like multiple sclerosis,
but neurodegenerative diseases and just
even behavioral diseases.
So,
you know,
there's,
it's a whole,
it's a,
we're kind of just starting to scratch
the surface of this field with the
microbiome and even cancer.
Like there's,
there's,
you know,
it's known that the,
the,
some of the short chain fatty acids that
microbiome,
certain species make,
um,
increase the production of something
called natural natural killer t cells.
And there's been animal studies where
you inject them with like human tumors
and literally it can you give these
animals a big dose of probiotics which,
which help create the species that make
these short chain fatty acids that make
t regulatory cells,
they can kill cancer cells almost as
good as the chemo control that they're
giving these animals.
And then if you look at,
there's some preliminary human trials
like for example,
humans that had colorectal cancer and
they're given a high dose of probiotic,
like close to 400 billion probiotic
products a day.
It like lowered their cancer recurrence.
Of course they had their colon removed,
surgically removed,
but,
you know,
still it's lowering their cancer
recurrence.
And I think that's a interesting along
with knowing what we know about animal
studies and natural killer t cells and
all that.
So,
you know,
it's not just brain,
but it's also a lot of diseases,
cancer,
you know,
um,
autoimmune diseases,
lots of things.
And gut is so important.
It really is.
It's the,
it's the major sources of inflammation
in the body.
It's the major source.
Like people are so worried about taking
this x thing exogenously from
some chemical and it's like,
yeah,
you should be worried about that,
but you should be worried about your gut
health.
Like really,
and probably one of the loose understood
in terms of like the general public.
Yeah,
I mean,
and even scientists like we're just now
really diving into that and I think that
I should say at least aware,
right?
Yeah,
exactly.
Most people have no idea that it's even
an issue now.
When you consider the fact that the rise
in children on the spectrum or
corresponds with the rise of refined
carbohydrates and refined sugars in our
diet,
do you think that there's some sort of
connection there?
It has a negative effect.
Refined sugars have a negative effect on
your microbiome is certainly.
I mean there's,
I think there's lots of contributing
factors to autism.
You know,
I published a paper on this with vitamin
d deficiency being one.
Um,
I think that diet,
you know,
diet,
um,
a lot of other factors play a role.
Paternal age actually plays a role.
Um,
smoking is also been shown like a
maternal smoking apparently,
particularly for the father,
the father.
Paternal age.
Yeah.
So that,
that seems to,
and that's something that's a couple of
studies and publish and I think even
recently it just kind of a big one came
out that was confirming because most
people think it's maternal right.
But it's actually both maternal plays a
role in down syndrome.
So,
but uh,
I'm not aware of maternal age being
linked to autism,
although I wouldn't be surprised.
Um,
there's probably an interaction with all
these things in interaction with,
you know,
the,
the quality of,
of the dna in a woman's egg or sperm,
sperm and the type of diet they have and
whether they're taking acetaminophen or
whatever,
fill in the blank.
Pharmaceutical or diet of the father and
the diet of the father you were talking
about before with obese people.
Yeah.
And what's interesting with that now in
that day,
I mean that study,
that was totally a pilot experiment,
just looking at how it altered gene
expression.
But if you look in the animal studies,
paternal diet,
so so males,
male mice that were given a high fat
high sugar diet most of the time,
by the way,
when you see headlines and it says high
fat diet causes blank,
high fat diet and animal studies is
always high fat,
high sugar,
and they always,
oh,
it's all,
it's almost always almost always high
high sucrose and high high fat.
But why don't they say that?
I don't,
I don't know,
because I guess you know,
they're,
they're so,
so drastically changing the fat
composition that they just kind of
always say the high fat and the
interaction between these two things
just really is now starting to be
understood.
But it,
it,
it really is a high fat is almost
always.
So I always call it high inflammatory
diet because it's a combination of the
two.
But anyways,
they feel that if you feed male mice,
this diet of high fat and high sucrose,
they become obese and then they have
offspring.
If you feed the feed their offspring,
normal diet.
So not,
not the high fat.
So they're just fed a normal child.
I had those offspring,
female offspring don't become obese,
but they get type one diabetes.
So it's because,
and then what and what was found is that
the,
the um,
the obesity was changing genes that
regulate pancreatic beta cell,
uh,
insulin production in their sperm dna
and that was passed on to the,
to the offspring.
So that's kind of again looking at.
It's also comp works.
I know it is,
it's complex.
It's interesting.
I'm,
I certainly am constantly trying to
optimize,
you know,
everything I can to,
the best of my ability and things are
always changing,
you know,
that's the thing with science and that's
also the thing with,
you know,
following,
following someone or following a certain
dogma,
you know,
things change and you have to be able to
like accept that things change.
The more data we have,
the more tools that we have at our
disposal to add our,
you know,
to investigate things are paradigm
shifts like saturated fat.
I mean that's a huge paradigm shift.
You know,
people in my parents' generation like my
dad,
and you just convinced that like you
say,
saturated fat is going to kill you,
you know,
it's parented by people everyday.
And you know,
we've talked about this before.
I believe on the poc,
josh,
you and I about that study.
The studies were either with the
scientists were paid off by the sugar
industry.
Right?
And that's the sugar industry is
probably one of the worst examples.
Like it's not always the case,
you know,
like if you have someone funding your
research that is involved in whatever
you're investigating,
the sugar industry is particularly bad,
but it's not always the case.
Like I wAs involved in research,
um,
with blueberries and the research was
funded by the high bush blueberry
council.
And so we did this placebo controlled
trial where we are looking at,
you know,
there's a whole panel of scientists
involved.
And I was just one of the scientists
involved in.
I was looking specifically at dna damage
and um,
you know,
how blueberries modulator that dna
damage which can lead to aging and
cancer and stem cell dysfunction,
all sorts of things.
And there was a placebo group,
so it was an enormous amount of work,
you know,
we had to isolate blood from patients
that they were given this blueberry
powder,
they were taking twice a day for eight
weeks or placebo powder.
And then we had to,
you know,
look at their dna damage.
And um,
what my work found was that,
to my surprise,
so blueberries lower dna damage,
which is what I thought because they
have a variety of compounds in them that
are known to be antioxidants.
But what was really surprising to me was
that it,
uh,
the placebo actually lower dna damage
just as well,
if not better,
then the blueberry powder and the
placebo powder had a little bit of
refined sugar in it.
And some.
I'm like coloring food coloring and
stuff.
And so I was like,
oh my god,
what's going on here?
How is the sugar lowering dna damage?
Well,
it turns out I had looked at gene
expression data as well.
All these genes,
um,
that are,
that are involved in stress response.
And in hormesis,
the reason I was looking at that is
because there are certain compounds in
the blueberries that can have a hormetic
response and I wanted to see if that was
being activated.
Well,
it wasn't really
robustly being activated in the
blueberries,
but in placebo,
some of these pathways,
the same pathways that like sulforaphane
can activate really well to some degree
was being activated because we think it
was slightly stressful.
Of course it was a very small amount of
sugar and,
and also the uh,
the dyes that were used or have been
shown to cause a little bit of a
hermetic response.
But you know,
we're going to publish that day.
It's not like because the blueberry
foundation funded this study,
you know,
it's,
the data is still this data is the data.
We didn't change anything.
So it's not always the case.
And again,
there's something very interesting here
and like you said,
science always surprises you and always
the things that you like.
It's something to predict.
So completely the opposite.
and there's something always
interesting.
They're always,
you know,
like as humans,
we think we know biology and we're like,
oh,
this is going to be predicted to be that
and all of a sudden it's complete
opposite and you're like,
what's going on?
The time you come on the podcast though,
I'm reminded of the fact there's so much
data.
It is impossible to keep it all in your
head and especially for one person.
We do dealing with all these different
fields,
all these different,
different scientists working on all
these different studies and it's almost
impossible for one person to have all
this data in their head.
yeah,
it is,
but it's interesting to me.
It's fascinating.
It's unbelievably fascinating,
but it's one of the reasons why boiling
something down to a clickbait title of
an article is so it's so enticing
because it's like,
oh,
tell me high fat diet kills the mites.
Fuck that.
All right,
I'm on dumb dumb.
Going back to low fat vitamins give you
cancer vitamins,
give you a cancer.
That's going to make a headline.
Yeah.
When you thInk some hilarious,
you have to dig into them and you're
like,
wait a minute.
The sugar industry study was from the
1950 [inaudible] and 19 sixties probably
pretty difficult to have something that
biased and fraudulent today.
There was even another one that just
came out recently,
like we talked about one last year,
but there was another one that came out,
another study,
I think it was published in like plcs or
plus one of those two showing that they,
they,
um,
suppress data that,
that refined sugar played a role in
cancer and in heart disease.
So,
so,
and this was the seventies I believe.
Um,
so there's more,
more than one study that have now linked
them to basically a holding back data
being published.
Um,
you know,
so they're,
they're one that's definitely,
I would say pretty bad.
I had someone send me some review
articles that were basically stating
that refined sugar was not bad and the
review articles were,
we're funded by the sugar foundation and
I was like,
oh,
this is the one.
I usually don't say this.
Like I usually don't say like,
you know,
based on who funds a study like this,
the conflicts of interest disclosures.
But this is one time where it's like,
you know,
the sugar foundation,
they're just notoriously bad and it's
also contrary to everything else has
been established right.
Yet when you understand,
it's like when you look at,
like I say all those things,
the mechanism and you look at the
interaction between foods and how the
body is processing these things.
and you look at the observational data
and controlled trials.
I mean,
you know,
how many things can you say,
you know no to.
I mean you just,
you know,
just looking at one thing there,
that's not as strong.
But you know,
looking at all of it is the big picture.
There's just so much money in sugar.
So many things have sugar in them.
I mean,
what,
what we've allowed to have done in this
country is literally allowed this one
thing,
this one substance to be in.
I mean,
what percentage of our food do you think
has sugar in it?
If you had,
if you go to a restaurant or you go to
get some condiments or food.
Yeah,
I mean those things.
There's,
there's,
it's slipped in everywhere.
Like thai food or you know,
it's like you go and say,
oh this tastes sweet,
like sugar.
It's got sugar in it,
you know,
so it certainly.
But that's almost acceptable.
So like I get what you're doing,
make something taste delicious because
you're an artist,
you're,
you're cooking a meal and the meal is
not just nutritious.
It's all supposed to.
Supposed to be a delight to the census
data kind of get,
you know.
But what I don't get is that it's
permeated our entire diet.
The average american diet.
it's at,
it's in everything.
It's in the drinks we drink,
it's in the foods we eat,
the bread that you consume,
it's in the pasta,
it's spaghetti sauce.
It's in me.
It's in everything.
If you go down the aisle at a
supermarket and just grab a random cam
thing,
grab it,
turn it,
you're going to recheck her.
You're gonna see it much more often than
you're not going to see it.
Right.
Stunning.
Yeah.
And now that happened to me not long ago
when like sent dan to the store to get
some,
like some kind of like I was wanting
some wishes.
Her sauce,
like for my steak for some reason I was
like having a stylistic thing.
I was like,
wait a minute.
Oh I can't eat the sugar in it.
Yeah.
What's your sheer sauce?
Tastes like shit.
Why does it have sugar?
Because it take more,
tastes more like shit if it didn't,
it it for whatever,
you know.
It's something that I ate as like a girl
and I had this craving for it and
received another kid to maybe it was
like more common.
We were young.
I think so because it's really easy.
It's not as common anymore.
No.
You never even hear about it.
Like,
my kids don't even know what my kid
loves cholula.
It's probably got sugar in it.
I don't know if that one does.
Actually I think about that might be one
of the better ones is my seven year old
fucking love cholula.
She puts it in everything.
She put it in milk.
We to tell her,
stop doing that is so gross.
She thinks it's hilarious.
She'll squared it right at our tongue,
so let's shake it right or wrong.
She loves it.
Doesn't no sugar.
Beautiful.
Great.
Yeah.
That's got something.
I'll probably get some weird red dye.
It's probably not even really read.
Probably brown.
I think if people are going to eat sugar
though,
the one thing they should do is eat it
within a time window.
What's in there?
Nothing.
Sodium,
gold,
water,
peppers,
salt,
vinegar and xantham gum.
Oh yeah.
Xantham gum.
Spices.
Susan seem that bad,
but xantham gum.
But some of the other emulsifiers have
been shown to also disrupt the
microbiome of course by.
Okay.
That stuff,
those Little yogurt things the kids
drink.
You know what I'm saying?
I don't know,
but it sounds familiar.
Like yogurty thing that the kids would
drink sugar probably.
I'm sure it does.
It taste sweet wood.
It's got.
It's supposedly got some sort of
probiotic in it for kids.
Do you.
Do you like limit?
The other is bio kids.
We they take regular bio.
Okay.
They take that stuff 100 percent
probiotic,
zero percent yogurt.
Okay,
so it doesn't have any lactose.
I'm bullock what's in there.
Does it have a ingredients thing more.
Where's the sugar bitch?
Like ingredients.
Like on every page.
A hundred percent probiotic.
Come on.
What's in there?
You fuckers doesn't say.
Does it say ingredients?
They're hiding in front of you.
It's sweet,
man.
I'm telling you.
It's.
I have a hard time believing there's no
sugar in there.
well,
the other thing with those probiotic
supplemented things,
is that like the amount of probiotics in
them or like minimal,
right?
yeah.
I mean my kid likes kimchi.
Really?
Yeah.
She's a freak sugar,
nine grams grams and those little
things.
You know,
my,
both my youngest kids are a combination
of me.
It's very weird.
You know,
there's traits like the seven year old
is way funnier.
She's hilarious.
She's purposely funny.
That's so cool.
But the nine year old is just psychotic.
She's like,
she'll,
she'll do things like we went to a
resort once on vacation and she does
cheerleading and gymnastics.
She's really into gymnastics.
She did cartwheels,
a half a mile home.
We had a walk like a half a mile.
She did cartwheels the entire way back.
That's crazy.
Psycho.
Yeah.
She's straight up psycho.
Like she's really driven.
oh,
she's crazy.
She's got a six pack.
She's really driven.
Yeah,
it's sad seeing the nine year old.
How much you fucked kid.
I'll show you.
I'll show you later.
Oh wow.
Yeah,
it's disturbing.
Yeah.
Like,
I mean like ripped.
I would get dizzy sheets.
Everything.
It's not like she's like a,
you know,
like anorexic or anything.
She just exercises constantly.
Early life exercise is important to
know.
Yeah.
They do mma,
they do karate.
Both of them do.
There are two martial arts.
I've got one of them into jujitsu.
Did you expose them to like different,
like different things to see what they
like.
Yeah.
I mean it seems like gymnastics is her
big one.
Kids,
little girls love other things where
other little girls are also
being active,
you know,
so gymnastics is a good one because you
know,
they're all doing their tumbling and
there I did that one.
I think it'S really good for body
control too,
and I and I,
and I was talking to her like she likes
jujitsu and she likes gymnastics too and
I said,
well they really help each other because
your jujitsu will benefit greatly from
your body control that you get from like
the ability to move your body,
like do backflips and stands and it's
just also just the,
the balance and the ability,
just the dexterity that you get.
I totally agree.
I,
I started ice skating when I was really
young too,
and a half.
My mom started when I was two and a
half.
Yeah.
So I started asking.
I was two and a half and that also is
like a lot of balance and more very
similar to like ballet too or just
graceful sort of things.
And um,
it really I think helped me with a
variety of other sports I did later
surfing.
Surfing was,
you know,
a lot more graceful dance like you still
serve.
I didn't,
haven't served since prepregnancy yeah,
I would worry about sharks.
You're a mommy now.
I haven't eaten getting more concerned
about sharks.
I forgot what those things.
The last thing.
There is something.
I am.
yeah.
I'm getting a lot more worried about the
show.
Did you see that video of the guy who
was swimming?
He was underwater scuba diving and the
shark came from behind him and bumped
him in the head.
But you showed me the start for one on
that freaked me out.
Or the woman goes surfing.
The shop is right next to them.
There's so big and all it takes us.
I mean they're eating machines that
takes us.
Look at this sky is underwater.
Check this out.
Boom.
Put that again because it didn't.
Is that a great white?
That thing's is huge.
It is.
look.
Oh,
oh.
He opens his mouth.
It hit him in the head.
I mean that thing easily could have.
Where is this somewhere you shouldn't
go.
That's the carry.
Fuck that.
So do you do like snorkeling or
anything?
I didn't like it.
I was terrified.
This one
cool thing where we were on the Big
island last year and they take you out
to where the dolphIns are.
They're like fine schools of dolphins
and they.
When the dolphins are in the area,
they'll take you out on the boat.
They find out where the dolphins are,
they spot them,
and then you jump in the water and you
snorkel with the dolphins.
Yeah.
It was amazing today.
Were they friendly?
Did they come up to you?
Don't give a fuck about you.
That's there.
Dolphins are really smart.
Yeah.
well they're.
They're wild dolphins.
They're not like,
why do I care about you man?
I don't even know what you're saying.
I don't know what you're doing.
Why?
Why are you wearing a watch like this?
Didn't want to have anything to do with
you.
Why are you monitoring your heart rate?
Just avoid you,
but it's just.
It's a crazy feeling just to be in
literally the middle of the ocean,
miles from the water or miles from the
shore rather,
and you're just looking down and you see
the vastness of it all.
I think it's in a lot of ways,
there's a reason why beach communities
are kind of cool.
They're like peaceful.
They're very mellow.
I think part of it is because you're
humbled by this gigantic body of water.
That's in your face every day.
I think it's.
It's akin to staring up at the stars.
There's just something,
something about the vastness of the
ocean.
It's so undeniable.
Your,
your,
your insignificance in the greater
scheme of things is so undeniable that I
think it chills people out.
Whereas I think cities make people like
more like to fucking get over their cars
are in my way,
get out of my way.
Bitch.
It's like your,
your too much of an important factor in
your immediate world.
I think that's why I was really drawn to
surfing in the first place.
It's because I'm a really.
Gogo gogo kind of go get her constantly,
constantly.
Next.
What's next?
One thing and being out in the water was
the one place that I would put all that
behind and I would chill,
you know,
and I felt really good just sitting on
my board and having the water.
Of course I wasn't thinking about the
sharks,
but just having the water on me and just
sitting out there and watching the waves
and you know,
it's,
it's certainly,
um,
there is definitely a very chilling
factor to it.
And for sure,
humbling,
oh my goodness.
Like I still am like terrified,
like on a big day going out because the
oceans is really scary.
Like,
aside from the sharks,
like waves are freaking scary.
Just the power of them around.
Oh yeah,
I've had um,
I mean I've had some scary.
It's kind of amazing.
I get back in after that but,
but um,
where it's so powerful,
I mean,
you know,
where it's just slamming you down,
you're doing
donuts and you're like,
what's going on?
You know,
I can't even imagine.
And um,
some of those crazy people that get,
they get dragged out on a boat all the
way out
to your max towing.
Yeah.
They get towed in and then they just
jump on those waves that are 100 feet
high.
Like my,
I get sweaty hands when I watch videos
of that because I know the power of the
wave and I'm like,
they're insane.
How can they,
it's like huge,
like just because some of them do,
you know,
end up in the whitewash.
And it's like how powerful that must be
upfront.
Dorian.
He's one of those world record holder
champion type,
big wave surfer dudes and I've seen some
videos of him doing it.
It's just,
it's.
I don't understand.
He's loud.
He laughs about it when you bring it up.
It's just what he does,
but it's.
I,
I've seen videos of him doing it.
What does this.
Is this ham?
Yeah.
Here it goes.
Jesus christ.
Jaws to look at it like,
come on.
I go bow hunting with that dude.
Went in Hawaii,
went to lanai and we,
we both wanted to look at us like how,
how big those waves are and he's right.
So he came up out of that.
Oh,
it's so crazy.
If that came down on you,
you're dealing with what?
A million pounds of water and I don't
even know how like I want to know how
they like survive that stuff because it
does come down on them.
Well,
I just think the.
This is how he lives
his life.
He loves it.
I mean,
I think he's been doing this for a long
time and it's just a natural part of
life to him and he lives on the big
island.
This is insane.
Totally insane.
He's clapping.
He's clapping in the middle of it.
It's like he's obviously having a great
old time.
Fuck that.
For sure.
I mean,
I like surfing,
but I wouldn't do that.
Yeah.
And the sharks too.
I mean the big island,
like you always hear about people get
bit by shark,
especially tiger sharks.
Is that where bethany hamilton,
the one that the girl that lost her arm
machine in Hawaii?
I believe so.
I believe so,
yeah.
That.
How about that?
The little kid loses her arm.
She's like,
well I got another one still crazy.
It just shows you how awesome surfing
was.
Bay,
but not for me.
I wouldn't be that awesome for me either
and I haven't gone back out.
I mean I'm just,
I can only get like I've got so much
time in the day to like work out and I
need to like I need to get the biggest
bang for my buck.
Yeah.
So you're back running now.
I'm actually having,
I haven't gone back running,
I'm planning on it.
Like what are you doing for exercise?
High intensity spin stuff so you can
continue that one months.
Your son you said is five.
He's four months old.
So yeah.
So you,
how long are you going to give yourself
before you try to start running?
You think after the holidays I'm going
to do it.
Yeah.
What about things like crossfit or
something like that?
Well,
I only have so much time.
I think the organized I like to spin and
like I said,
it's not like your dance you spend.
I tried that,
I didn't like that.
Um,
you do a lot of weight lifting type
exercise.
I need to do more.
Um,
I have like,
I do it.
I don't have a gym membership anymore.
Um,
so I have like weights and I'll do it
like,
you know,
at my place,
but I haven't been doing as much of the
strength training as I should because
that's also extremely beneficial.
And you know,
bone density,
it's big one density,
muscle mass.
I mean like there's been studies showing
that people that do strength training,
like they have a 23 percent lower all
cause mortality and like a 30 percent
lower cancer related mortality,
independent of any other health factors
like obesity and all that stuff.
So um,
you know,
the muscle mass is another thing that's
really important.
In fact there was also another
interesting study showing that like
people that had lake strength,
like their leg strength was correlated
to like massive improvements in
cognitive function.
Legs,
not arms but only the legs.
So there are various,
various different exercises we're done,
like hand grip strength and all that,
but it was leg strength specifically.
I don't know if it's like something
bloodflow something about your,
how strong your legs are,
is somehow somehow indicative of blood
flow to the brain are.
So dudes who do squats are jesus.
If you know anybody who does a lot of
squads go to them.
So I do,
I do air squats,
body weight squats.
Yeah.
I do those.
And like,
you know,
do the hindi are ones where you come up
on the ball of your foot,
do you kind of jump as well?
No.
You can do
squats.
You,
um,
you,
I could do it for you real quick.
Essentially you start off like this and
then as you go down your heels come up
off the ground like this and then your
hand touches the floor and then you come
up.
And what it really does is it works the
quadriceps really well around the knees
and a lot of people find it to be an
excellent stability exercise called.
What do they call it?
Hindu squeegees.
Here.
This guy's going to do it.
This one,
see how's he's going up on his heels.
This is like part of it.
He dropped down.
Your heels come up and then as you press
up when he's not,
he's not dropping his heels as he comes
up,
which I think is weird.
He's,
I think he's doing a kind of a Variation
on hindu squats because his heels are
never coming down.
He's also wearing raised heel shoes,
which I don't agree with.
Your heels come all the way down when
you come up.
Yeah,
yeah.
Once you go heels,
go all the way down.
See if you can find someone who's like,
I just don't.
Those shoes are not.
Those aren't wise.
Those shoes were invented.
Those kind of shoes are.
Those are running shoes that are
invented back when nike came up with
them where you land on the heel instead
of landing on the ball of the foot,
which the way your foot is naturally
supposed to absorb shock,
you know,
not.
You know.
I'm sure you know about all that.
We're nike sort of changed the gate.
No,
nope.
Nike literally changed the way people
run.
They put this big fat heel and the back
of your sneaker and people started
running on the heel.
Instead of running on the ball of the
foot.
When you land on the ball of your foot,
your foot is a natural shock absorber,
and what they did was made people run
with their heel first lifted fight.
It's not good.
It's terrible for your knees.
It's terrible for a lot of things and
people develop all sorts of issues.
You run into that with running long
distances and knee problems because I'm
sure I used to be a jump rope or I was a
professional drunk.
Proper.
When you professional jump roper,
I want to get paid.
Well we,
we got um,
we were sponsored by like the american
heart association really.
We had like,
um,
donations and stuff.
But uh,
yeah,
so I started jumping rope.
It's called the international rope
skipping organization at that time.
That's hilarious.
I think it's called like the universal
universal rope skipping organization
now,
but I was,
I would compete so we,
we'd go every year and compete with
other teams from around the world.
I would travel to other places,
other parts of the u,
s and setup,
do demonstrations in schools inside of
teams.
Anyways,
I was really good and I can still jump
rope like I could do next.
Like next time I see you like jump,
like if you have a jump rope or if I can
remember to bring one,
like I'll bring one for you next time.
Next time you get to do two things,
you've got to try out the tank.
Coming here early.
We'll set you up with the isolation
tank.
We'll do a sauna.
We should do a podcast on.
That would be awesome.
We're going to start doing that because
we have the sauna here.
We're going to do a little podcast last
long.
Yeah,
the heat with the recording equipment
and stuff,
but if it breaks it breaks.
I just like.
There's more new interesting stuff on
the sauna like that.
I would love to talk to you about like
new studies coming out and so next one.
Next one.
Scheduled a couple of from now and then
the jump rope.
Jump rope.
Jumping on the balls of your feet.
That was the point as I was going to
say,
if you jumped on the heels,
it was awful.
It was like sound.
Would imagine it'd be teRrible,
but when you look at a running shoe,
you think of an average running shoe.
The average running shoe has a lifted
heel.
Now people are understanding that this
is negative and this is bad for you,
so you.
You see what are called zero drop shoes,
like the vibrams or minimal issues as
what I run in.
I run in either a vibrams or running
those.
I have some murals that are running into
and what they're essentially they have a
wide toe box,
so you're,
you're toast splay out and there's
almost no padding.
There's is very little bad before.
It's just enough of a hard cover to keep
you from getting cut from like rocks and
stuff.
So that for me is when I tried them out,
I was running on hard concrete who um,
it was like I was running around this
lake because I lived in oakland at the
time and um,
and so I didn't really like it.
Were you running on the heels of your
feet out all your calls?
Yeah,
it's too much.
It's too much because of the concrete,
but I think even that is okay if you
build up to build up,
but you,
but you develop your foot strength
changes radically.
So maybe I'll get some again and try.
You've got to go slow because we'll be
training.
It's probably a lot easier to.
Yeah,
I run the beach and those when I'm on
vacation,
I'll run with a minimal shoes,
but when you're doing it,
you have to build up to it because you
can get plantar fasciitis where you
start really destroying the bottom of
your feet are very common.
So what do you mean,
like just don't run as long distance or
something.
Take your time.
Yeah,
they like the vibrams.
Uh,
they got in trouble because they were
telling people that their shoes can
prevent injury and strengthen your feet,
which they can,
but it takes a long time.
So what would happen is people would
say,
oh,
I'm gonna.
Use these shoes going to prevent injury.
Fuck,
I'm injured because they would feed a
week.
The idea is that your feet in regular
shoes are essentially like in a cast.
This is what your feet are like,
you're,
you're relying on the structure of the
shoe.
It's tightening up around your foot.
You have a nice fat cushion to the
bottom of it and you're using minimal
musculature of your toes and all of the
different fee.
You're not articulating everything is
individual joints and pushing with all
the muscles and so when you switched
from a thick,
fat running shoe,
like a vibrams five finger this,
there's definitely a adoptation curve
and you have to be careful with that.
I,
I certainly think because when I was
doing it,
I was running long distances.
Like I just,
I didn't ease into it at all either and
I was doing it on concrete.
My friend neil brennan got plantar
fasciitis from running on a treadmill in
with vibrams.
YeAh.
He's running on treadmills as well.
I'm just kidding.
Uh,
I'd say that to them.
um,
but,
uh,
yeah,
he just got too crazy with it.
He's,
he's kind of obsessive person.
He,
he got into it and he's like,
oh,
this is the thing.
I'm going to do this now in Iran,
a few mIles.
And he blew himself out like right
away.
He fucked up his feet.
You reverse that?
Yes.
Yeah.
It takes a while to heal though.
It's a very painful.
I know quite a few people that have
gotten plantar fasciitis and you,
you know,
you get out of bed,
he could barely walk.
I think my mother in law.
How to.
Yeah,
it's rough.
It's rough.
So,
uh,
I didn't.
Luckily I've done martial arts my whole
life.
Sorry,
my feet.
My feet are pretty strong,
but I noticed a big difference between
running with minimal minimalistic shoes.
I mean just my feet just feel stronger
or they just,
they feel different.
They feel different when I'm walking
around.
My archers raised up.
I've always had flat feet.
My arches have actually gotten higher
and like my,
just the overall dexterity in my feet.
One place where I really feel it is in
yoga and notice a big difference in
yoga.
I have just more foot strength.
I'm going to try out.
The rebrand was again throughout my
other ones,
but my feet are like bigger now after
pregnancy.
So that's funny.
Like it stretches your feet out abbott,
maybe it's like,
you know,
maybe it's a cannon
to a weightlifting,
right?
Because you think it about it.
You have all this extra weight in your
body,
you're carrying around your feet and
your hips and.
Right.
Yeah.
You definitely have a lot of extra
weight.
I mean,
it seems like it like
pound vest on your back and you did a
lot of exercises with a 40 pound best.
Your bones are going to get more dense.
Right?
Yeah.
I would like to know.
I mean,
I know,
I know certainly my feet were bigger
during pregnancy because of the swelling
and stuff,
but,
but I'm four months out and my feet are
definitely bigger.
Are they longer and wider?
The wider there?
Probably you have more meat in your
foot.
Wider.
I was shocked.
I couldn't like this,
a pair of shoes that I'm supposed to
fit.
It didn't fit and it was,
I was like,
you know,
it was too narrow.
I bet that totally makes sense.
I mean,
think about how much weight did you gain
you allowed to ask gals that?
Um,
I.
So I actually lost all the weight,
so I'm allowed to ask.
I've,
I've lost a lot,
most of it,
but I still,
you know,
there's,
there's this a little more to me,
but my god,
it's crazy.
It's amazing that we bounced back.
I gained probably more I would get,
they say like 30 pounds.
I gained the close to 50.
I know women to gain 80,
but I was eating all healthy foods.
I started out very thin maybe and that,
so I was talking to my ob gyn about that
and um,
he was telling me that really because I
didn't like look obese or anything.
It wasn't ambitious.
I start,
when you start off with a starting
point,
your body wants you to gain a certain
amount of weight.
Sure.
And so my body wanted me to gaIn 50
pounds and I had an eight pound 10 ounce
boy and just think about 50 years
pounds on your back for nine months.
Of course your feet are going to get
bigger.
They're going to be stronger.
Yeah.
It was an interesting study showing the
v max actually improve vo two max
improves after pregnancy.
Sure.
Makes sense.
it's kind of like training in I have a
bath or whatever.
Yeah,
I have this thing.
It's called a company called
outdoorsmen.
They make a pack that's designed to
condition people for backpack hunting.
Um,
when you,
you go,
uh,
you
carry everything.
He carry your entire camp on your back,
so you carry your sleeping bag.
I'm a jet boil.
One of those tanks that you cook on,
you carry all of your equipment,
you carry everything that you ate,
all your food.
I mean,
you,
you could carry as much when you,
when you're wearing a backpack,
when you're going into camp,
you could carry as much as 70,
80 pounds on your back.
So what they do this company called
outdoorsmen is they make a pack frame
that has a,
an olympic plate bolt on the back of it.
We slide olympic plates on it and you
clamp them down.
So you have like a,
like literally an olympic weight on your
back.
You could put a 45 pound plate or a 90
pound plate and you do hike to condition
yourself.
So they have the right posture and
you're building that.
Exactly.
it's,
it's one of the best ways,
like weighted pack exercises is one of
the best ways to prepare yourself for
that.
That's really one of the only ways
because you're dealing with many,
many miles of hiking.
That's kind of cool because I've,
I've often,
like,
I haven't really ever done any like big
camping like that,
you know,
I'm,
I'm always like go for a hike of the
day,
come back,
go to the cabin,
you know,
it's kind of fun to do that,
like where you hike many miles in and
take up a camp and you know,
so um,
but I thought like,
how am I going to carry all that stuff?
It's grueling.
Yeah.
I can imagine like there's no way I
could do that much,
but when some people do it,
if they're only going to go for a few
days,
they can get it down to as little as 40
pounds.
You know?
Some people are super minimalist,
like my friend adam,
he does it for many stretches at a time
and he'll do like 28 days in the bush by
himself.
He lives in Australia.
He's done it in Montana to one.
Um,
he did it and documented it all on his
instagram story,
but he's so extreme.
He cuts hIs toothbrush and half,
like he only has the,
he cuts weight in so many different
places that the handle of his
toothbrush,
it cuts off.
So he's brushIng his teeth with like the
little end part of it toothbrush,
which I think is just stupid.
Like how much weight are you saving?
C'mon man.
It's ridiculous.
Give yourself a real toothbrushes
psycho.
But these people I'm really concentrated
on making things as minimal as possible.
Bringing as little gear as possible and
just gettIng all dialed in.
You have to kind of figure out how much
water you need,
how much food you need.
Most of the time they map out,
they'll use like I'm a google earth and
map out where the natural springs are
and try to figure out uh,
how much water they have to bring with
them and how much they can get from
these sources.
And so then they have to have either a
steri pim or some sort of filtration
system to clean out the water to make
sure that they don't get to understand
how,
what's the longest amount of tIme that
you've done?
Like one of these campaigns.
I've never done it where they did it
like that where I carried my camp on my
back and I lived out there for.
The only time I've ever done it is with
a group of guys and we've camped for a
week in Montana.
But we brought everything in on canoes.
So we had all these supplies.
We brought them in on boats.
We got out,
we staked our tents
and we had food with us just,
you know.
But I know a lot of guys do it and they
don't bring much food.
They just try to live off the land.
They just try to get successful quick
with the hunting.
And then theory.
It's crazy,
but it's the added challenge of it,
you know,
but the weight.
But the point being that weighted
backpacks or an excellent cardiovascular
exercise.
So to me just make sense of being
pregnant.
It would make your feet stronger and
increase your vo two max and a lot of
walking four miles a day.
I know what I was doing.
A great thing that there's this girl,
this woman in my spin class and she's
like,
you can ask them.
She's about to have this baby like any
day and she's their bike and away.
And I'm like,
geez.
Yeah.
So she used to get crazy with it.
She's real tiny.
Like,
I mean I look back at pictures of me and
I'm like,
I can't believe I like bounce back from
that because it's just like I'm just so
enormous,
you know?
It's,
it's crazy.
It's incredible.
the whole thing is incredible.
Do you think you're going to do it again
or you want it done?
I think I might be one and done.
I don't know for sure,
but you know,
I spent some time to think you only got
four months old.
I got a little bit of time to think,
right.
I mean like I've got pressure like my
half sister and like other people are
like,
okay,
you got to wait a year.
You got to get pregnant again.
I'm like,
oh gosh,
you know,
you don't have to do anything crazy.
It's so good.
I have one kid.
I kind of,
I've kind of,
I'm kind of just so in love with him.
Then I'm like,
I don't want to share my love,
you know,
having kids,
like my kids are two years apart,
uh,
the youngest ones and when they hang out
together it's just amazing.
You watched them hug each other and they
play games together and you know,
there's still like little sibling
rivalries.
There's always going to be.
But,
but there's something magical about
having a sibling,
you know,
I grew up,
the sister is one year younger than me.
My brother who's four years younger than
me.
Yeah.
I don't know,
just something to it,
but it's also something to have in one
kid and given them a lot of attention
and being able to do other things too,
like science.
So speaking to science,
tell people where they can listen to
your podcast and contribute to your
research because you,
you have,
you were saying you have,
what is the,
the,
the patron,
patron and also we have a direct
subscribership where people can,
if they want me to continue to,
um,
do the podcast but put out,
you know,
articles.
So my podcAst is on itunes,
it's called family fitness,
but you can go to my website called,
found my fitness.com
and there's now episode pages we have
where I'm starting to now put a lot of
information and found my fitness on
instagram,
twitter,
and um,
there all those codes.
So here's the episodes and if you click
on one,
there's a summary and sometimes we're
getting transcripts now,
so I'm going to put a lot more
information there as well.
And so yeah,
people are,
are,
are contributing money,
whatever they can,
they can do a one tIme or like a one
five,
$10 a month.
Some people do more than that.
And um,
it's,
it's really cool.
It really has been a lot of fun and I
enjoy it like,
like it's just.
I love it.
Well,
you're awesome at it and you,
you're awesome at this too.
I mean,
it's ridiculous.
You haven't looked at notes once.
All this shit is all from the top of
your head for people that are listening
to this.
She's not reading off of anything.
she's just rattling this off.
It's very humbling.
Thank you.
So thanks for doing this and next time
we'll do the tank.
Do the sauna.
We try to do a podcast host.
I'm gonna.
Hold you to that.
Okay,
let's do it.
We'll do it.
Okay.
Thank you so much.
Thanks rhonda.
Patrick,
ladies and gentlemen.