Tim, I'm stone. Yeah. You
think boom on both ends, which,
but it's just, we're broadcasting,
we're live. We're reaching out.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by the fleshlight.
If you go to Joe rogan.net and click on
the link for the fleshlight and entering
the code name Rogan, you will get 15%
off the number one sex toy for men.
Both Brian and I have used it. And by
the end of this show, Josh McDermitt,
we'll have a complimentary fleshlight
that he will be taking home with himself.
They have Zombie flashlights now,
like ones that are all fucked up and
broken looking. And Scott's awesome.
Also were brought to you
by on it.com o.N n, I t,
the makers of Alpha brain and Alpha
brain is a nootropic supplement.
It is a basically a stack of vitamins
that help cognitive function.
I like them, I use them.
And uh, that's why, uh,
that's why we got him here working
with us. Go to Joe rogan.net.
Click on the link and enter in the code
name rogue and then you get 10% off of
that.
All right.
Cue The music so we make an official
Josh Mcdermott's in the house for you.
[inaudible] listen to that music.
I have like an extra echo in there.
Are you sampling your own shit?
I'm just fucking around with the
mixer. Oh, is that what you did?
Did you go DJ on us right there?
Did you go straight Russell Peters on a
bitch but test low or whatever his name
is. You'd like to a class
once at a community college.
You're trying to put that to good use.
I know.
Who was the guy that he ate a Tesla guys.
That huge guy. The guy who was of no,
what is that guy's name?
Stoats. Yesto. Yeah. Ts though.
I was trying to explain him to Mrs Rogan.
The end of the day.
We were driving down the highway and
there was this big billboard for this ts
tow guy and really that billboard.
Oh Dude,
I don't think you and I haven't
any idea how big that guy is.
I've looked online and
watched his concerts where
it's like him on a stage and
he's got like a bunch of laptops and a
bunch of musical equipment and he's like
pumping his fist and there's a huge
audience of people that are like dancing
along to him. And I, I don't know
how many big Djs are like that.
We'd have to get Russell Peters back
on to explain to us the whole world of
deejaying because Russell doesn't like
the guy cause he says that what he's
basically doing is sort of like pressing
play on all the computers and then
waving his arm up. But you know, I,
I've been listening to it because my
friends are like set a lie and I've been
listening to it and it's, you know, it's
not bad. I know. Wait Russell saying,
but it's all about like how you
feel when you're listening to it.
I'll take that any day over
at [inaudible]. Oh shit man.
I mean that they just crammed down her
fucking ass is your friend that likes it.
A girl or a guy? A girl, a girl.
But I like that same kind of music,
that kind of chillax music where
you're just like, yeah, it's, it's um,
what he's doing is interesting.
You know what I mean? It's,
it's not d I understand
where Russell saying,
it's sort of like a guy going on
stage in a statue, a sketch group on,
on stage saying he's a standup
comic and you're like, you know,
it's still good. I mean, come
on man. You can't deny it.
Like some sketch shows like
in living color or you know,
some Saturday night live sketches, they're
fucking brilliant. It's fun to watch.
A lot of them suck.
Like I'm not a fan of like sketch comedy
because it's too much miss to the hit,
you know?
It's like a,
for every really good sketch
you get on senator didn't live.
You have to endorse him. Bullshit.
Yeah. I can't do it man. But,
but Russell is saying this do just
pretty much just pressing play.
Like it gets all the music together
beforehand or whatever he programs at all.
But he's making it pretty bad
ass if all these fucking, I mean,
I know I'm not a fan of it.
I never got into it.
Maybe I could get into it if I really
sat down and listen to it, but damn,
he's got these fucking huge arenas
filled with people jumping up and down
whatever drug they're on or not.
You know what it was on.
If it's an x to see situation
Molly, yeah, whatever. Or maybe not.
Maybe it's just they're having a good
time, but you know, I don't, I don't know,
but whatever it is for them,
it's fucking awesome.
You can tell that that music for them,
it might not click for you or me,
but he can't say sucks.
You know?
And Russell just says he
sucks sorta because he's not
really a Dj like Russell's
at Dj.
Like Russell,
like remember when Russell was over and
he picked up this fucking beat that like
a secondary beat in the back
of a song like you said? No,
they're also sampling like salt and
pepper right here. And we were like, what?
Like play that back again.
We had to play it like three or four times
and still we were like an uneducated,
a morons trying to like test wine with
a Somalia. You know what I'm saying?
Well I would, I would see, I don't even
consider Tashi or tests or whatever.
The guy's Tsl. Yes. Though I
don't even consider him a DJ.
I just music of electronic music producer.
That's a good,
yeah, you're right. I know a few djs
but I've never heard of this guy.
And you said you've seen a billboard like
Dane Cook of Dj even bigger than Dane
was when Damien isn't,
it was in his prime.
This guy is [inaudible]
nationwide or worldwide rather.
He's huge all over Europe.
He's huge.
This guy does like 50,000 seat arenas
where people are out there like pumping
their fists and he's
fucking playing records.
I mean there's one thing
if the music's good,
but I mean there's art to being a Dj
about mixing the stuff right there when
you're on stage being in that moment.
But if you're just sitting there
pushing play fucked up. Well,
I think a lot of people are looking for
cool shit to do when you're fucked up on
drugs and when it comes to cool shit
to do and you're fucked up on drugs,
this guy's need device to go
sweat like a laser show. I tuned,
if you're on ecstasy and you'd go
to one of his shows, first of all,
you're going to be sure there's going to
be a lot of other people on ecstasy to,
yeah,
I mean,
it's electronic music and everyone's
dancing and everyone's drinking. Come on,
there's going to be ecstasy everywhere.
So if that's the case, you know,
this guy is really providing this fucking
cool symbiotic service with people
that are tripping on an ecstasy he make.
He creates the full experience. You know,
you know that you're going to,
he's going to draw them all and they're
all going to come to him because they
know what he does.
And then you,
so you're going to have your likeminded
people there that are going to want to
meet up at the [inaudible] concert and
then a everybody just fucking dances and
he puts on a show.
And,
and you're blitzed out of your fucking
head and you know it's going to last for
four hours. Perfect. So He's like
the Dane Cook of Djs where he,
he's mixing songs and it just
really get that extra punch.
He just does a leg kick or something.
He goes home at the end of every
show and emails. He does that.
He goes home and emails.
Everybody who came to his show,
there's a new sample. Yeah. Dane
would really do that, you know? Yeah.
He's a machine. Dean is, he's a
phene as far as like emailing people.
It's really fun. But I mean
it's, the guy did it, you know,
the way he did it and it worked.
There's no,
no one else has ever become famous from
the instrument the way. Dang cooked it.
It was really, truly
spectacular. You know what he,
what he did like his comedy or not what
he did as far as like the marketing
himself was fucking genius. Dane had
some good bits over the year. Dangerous.
You know, I like Dane. He's
not a bad dude. He's just, he,
he lost his way a little bit there in the,
the great tide of wanting to be famous
and wanting to be a big comedian,
you know. But I think he's
paid for it. You know, think
he's paid his latest album,
his, his blues stuff. I guess what uh,
what's it called where he was like raw
on stage and it was just filmed one take
called an intimate evening or something.
The whole shit. The whole Bon Jovi,
the whole episode was filmed one Katie
went, went that's, I love that shit.
Yeah that was great. Even though it was
good. It was good. It was good stuff,
you know. And that was sort of like a
retribution thing for him. You know,
he hasn't done standup in a long time.
I ran into him at the warriors from here.
Let me just name drop real quick cause
you know I've been to like four.
I haven't had a formal, your true,
isn't it 20 fucking years
I've lived out here,
but my friend was in Brian
Cowan who was here yesterday,
was in warrior and I saw,
I met them. There. Is that
that came out warriors. Yeah,
it was it good. Yeah, it
was pretty good. But anyway,
Dan said when I met him there that
he hadn't done standup in six months.
Good grief.
Yeah.
I saw him when he was working
on that blue, the blue stuff.
Was that what this album was about? All
that kind of rocks? I didn't like it.
You didn't?
Yeah.
I mean he's one of those guys that I
think I heard his standup first back when
he was like on top of the world and I was
like, Nah, I don't, I don't really know.
And then I saw him live and I was like,
oh I get it. I see why people love this.
And then I went back and heard
the bits and it was great.
But having never heard him or,
or, or, or uh, seen him live.
I don't know how people can
understand his jokes cause cause he's
so fricking physical. Yeah.
Some of it is a, it's hard,
but some of the earlier stuff
wasn't nearly as physical. Like,
so there was some stuff,
I've heard his stuff on like
Sirius satellite radio and
it translates. Yeah. Okay.
I mean I just, different
beds. Yeah. You know,
for a while he was getting like
super crazy physical with shit,
but he's also doing 15,000 fucking
scene of arenas. Yeah. You gotta go,
you gotta get big. But this was at
like an improv where you know, there's,
there were like 150 people.
Yeah. Who preparing for it.
He does those theaters in the round two,
which is interesting.
I've only done that a couple of times.
I did like the stage spins
I did in Phoenix. Um,
celebrity theatre. Yeah. I've done it
twice in Phoenix and Phoenix is, it's
interesting because,
uh,
that celebrity theater is as big circle
and that's where Kat Williams got in
trouble. That dude where you know, the,
he was, the guy was like fuck America.
And he was like, Fuck America Sarah.
Remember that, that whole thing.
And everybody was mad at him for telling
this Mexican guy that how great America
was and shit.
Who's heckling stories
when he goes to cities?
We're just an Ontario doing comedy and
be like, one guy guy's like, oh he won't.
He pulled a gun on him and the other
guy is like, oh no, that's not true.
What the fuck are you saying?
Have we had a cross reference?
We had to bring people in together. Did
Clark, who's the guy who runs a place?
I go, did Kat Williams put a gun on you?
And he's like, no, we'd put a gun on me.
Like it got crazy. And then like, and then
we had to go back to the first time. Oh,
that's what I heard.
I go,
he can't just scope saying a guy
pulled a gun on how my man cat man,
just going around [inaudible] I want
to hear the stories I haven't heard yet
from like Dayton, Ohio,
where he fucking, you know,
ate a guy's ass out or something.
Boy,
Brian Cowen making stuff up
now. He's silly. Fuck no,
but there has to be stories that just
never made it in a TMZ that was in the
weed store that was in
the weed store once,
and Cat Williams assistant came
in and she announced herself.
So I'm Kat Williams, I'm Kat Williams
assistant. I'm here to pick up his weed.
She was getting weed for Kevin.
Welcome to America.
Welcome to California where
your assistant can go to a,
we chop and just announce hello.
And you go in there,
you announce yourself properly.
This
girl. So yeah, it was
interesting. But anyway,
that's theater in the round.
That's a, that's a smaller place.
The one where cat was that I've been
at that place, it's like 2,500 seats.
Dane's doing that shit with, it's
like 18,000 people. Same goal.
Like what is that? That's so
bizarre. People eat that shit up,
but it's like really?
It's so cultive personality when it,
when it was really hitting what
people didn't like about it.
What a lot of comics who were upset about
the true reason is that he had packed
somehow another tapped
into this boy band thing.
So he hit this boy band
energy with common,
like this big boy band energy
like no one had ever done before.
Like backstreet boys shit,
where girls would go and fucking scream
to meet Dane Cook and he hit that
somehow or another.
He tuned into that frequency for a little
while and I don't know how the fuck he
did it. He just, you know,
he just was the perfect energy and the
perfect planning mean you've got to give
the guys is his props for
figuring that all out.
But that's what bothered comedians
because they knew that there was just like
boy band thing going on. It's almost
gimmicky. Yeah. Without it being gimmicky,
she did it all himself.
It's not like, you know,
Dick Clark productions put together some
comedian and taught them how to dress
and then foisted a month
to the American public.
Like what happens with a lot of music
acts, you know, they construct them.
You know, I mean it's, it's funny how
it's so open in the music community.
You know,
like our friend Eddie Bravo has had a
whole bunch of looks throughout his life,
music career with his long hair
or whether it's, you know, it's,
it's funny how like people like in the
music industry it's like, you know,
this is our band and we only wear
leather when we take pictures. You know,
it's like the, the idea of like
projecting an image, you know,
it's very much just accepted.
It's funny how a lot of them overused the
same looks cause they all use the same
photographers to make like,
like album covers. Like a
lot of them are all similar.
So like I was looking at some like just
an unknown bands recently and I was
looking at their, their,
their promo shots,
like their headshots and they're all
like sitting in like window sills,
like outside of factories.
Like looking off at each other backwards
and like the one singing that's looking
down at his shoes.
Yeah.
He's on the railroad tracks.
How many fucking people who are supposed
to be moody of taking pictures by the
railroad trucks, you know, like
Chaz Christ. We get it. Yeah.
You're just going to get on that
train and ride out of nowhere.
You're just going to disappear on us.
You're such a crazy rebel at any moment.
You're going to light a cigarette,
take a puff and hop on the train, man.
Yeah, those album covers, dude, you could,
you could put a hold blog site together.
Just every asshole has ever done that.
Why? You're looking away and all that.
Sending in window sills.
Guess what? The dude who's kneeling in the
front, he does not want to be kneeling.
He wants to be standing
up just like the singer,
but the singer's is not going to think
I show you the one who stands up and
talks.
You're the tambourine player man.
So tamarind players got to take
this like gangster slouch people,
I'm going to take me seriously in this
band unless I get down and if you're a
tambourine player, you have to have like
thumb rings and Shit. You have to work,
brings in your thoughts.
You have to be extra cool.
You know those banjo players that have
like a little pick on every finger.
You ever see that?
That's what they do every,
they have claws like damn talents.
Yeah.
They have those weird ones that like
the connect to their fingertips,
like metal kitty cat claws and they all,
they all have that piercing from the
belly button that goes down to it,
like their nipples and stuff.
For a lot of musicians,
it really is like trying
to get you to notice them.
There's like four other guys
on stage sweating it out.
I'm just standing here with this fucking
base. Yeah. I need something shiny.
They figured kiss,
figured it out the best.
Just have a whole fucking character show,
have a show,
you know everyone's wearing makeup.
You're blown firing into the crowd.
Yeah. It's the same makeup
too. It's not like a mixture.
I mean pretty much it's just black and
white and I can't tell the difference of
who they are, what their, their makeup on.
I've been to a lot of concerts in my life.
The greatest concert I've ever
been to ever was a kiss concert.
I've been to a bunch of kiss concerts
because my uncle used to work for kiss in
the early seventies so I was, yeah,
I was a little kid. I was like, fuck.
I was like maybe six years old
the first time I met ace freely.
Was this like your first concert or
you're like just the best concert and it
just happened to be when you were
five or six years old? Well, no,
just you know those and then I
saw them again with Kevin James.
Kevin James is a big kiss freak too.
And he and I went to see
them two nights in a,
in the 90s when they made
that comeback tour. Yeah.
Here's before neither one of us,
you know,
I think maybe I've just gotten on
news radio and Kevin, you know,
nobody knew who Kevin was yet.
And uh,
we went to see kiss to ninth and a fucking
row. We went to see it. It was awesome.
It's good.
It's fun to see a band like consecutively
like that and change up the show.
They came back to,
this is the real kiss.
It was like Peter Criss and ace freely
with them, which had never happened.
But we like for years they did like the
band had broken up and there was this
Vinny Vincent Guy and his other,
a bunch of other guys that came in.
But essentially the,
the only two guys that was constant where
Gene Simmons and Paul Stanley and then
this was like the big tour and having
him back again, it was just so fun.
It's like,
it's so much,
there's so much involved as like nostalgia
cause he songs that like, you know,
they're singing songs from Detroit,
rock city,
this thing had songs from like 40 fucking
years ago or whatever it was, you know,
that the time 30 years ago. And
they're still, they're not fat yet.
They're still wearing makeup and their
dance read like they look like they're
still their characters. It's
where it works, you know,
they're really still can put on
a fucking good show. So there's,
so it was so much involved and how
they all died in that plane crash.
What Gene Simmons is getting married,
if you've seen that shit. Yeah. Yeah.
How long was he with his,
uh,
it was going to be his wife of
28 years or something. Crazy.
Lindsay Lohan is going to be
in playboy for $1 million.
Who pays for this? You, it
should be just like, dude.
So we need to say them aside and be like,
look, no one cares about that at all.
This is sort of,
I don't think you're right though.
I think this is sort of the model
that he's based his entire career on.
It's like do something sensational
woman. No, won't see a broken woman.
Everybody wants the American
woman's ass hole. She's naked. Yeah.
If I can just see her asshole. Just the,
just the hint of it in the distance,
but mostly concentrate on the vagina. Even
if the vagina lips are closed, which I,
except with playboy,
you have to accept.
You have to accept they won't get all
gynecological. I would take Brittany,
Brittany's asshole Britney Spears over
Lindsay and I would like to see Lindsay
Lohan photograph drunk. That's what I
want to say. I want to see real drunk,
not fake drunk, real drunk. And
when she goes to the real, yeah,
no,
I'd be really interested in those photos.
I'd really interested if you could get
photos of her in her element. Obviously.
Look, I have nothing
against Lindsay Lohan. Okay.
She seems like a girl who's just looking
to have fun. She seems a girl who, yeah,
maybe she's partying a little bit,
but you know what? Guess what?
It probably wasn't too fucking easy
growing up on the Mickey Mouse Club and
being in the limelight when you were a
child and all your developmental years
and with your parents, people would take
it fucking photos of your all the time.
Your Dad's fucking nuts to me. Totally
say the girls just having a good time.
I want to see if she's going
to take pictures naked.
It should be watching as having a
good time, which the ankle bracelet.
She get high, she should get high. She
should do a bump. Drink a couple of shots,
you know, and then show me your
pussy. Let's see what's up. Those,
those should be the pictures,
the Lindsay Lohan pictures that we get.
I don't want to see that airbrush cropped
out bullshit where she's pretending
to get on a fucking Polo Pony.
[inaudible] hanging out of her
pants. But this is, I mean,
obviously a total PR moves,
so people who are kind of managing the PR,
this won't ever let that happen and
that's disappointing. Yeah, those dummies,
they don't know what they're doing.
They're doing it the wrong way.
What they should do is embrace it. You
know what? He should embrace what you are.
That's what brought you to the dance.
Lindsay.
Little hands is nothing wrong with that
girl. She's a freak. She's a freak.
She's not hurting anybody.
She's not out there clogging
people's fucking eyes out.
She's just getting fucked up. She's got
millions of dollars. It was 24 years old.
What do you want her to do?
What do you want it to do?
You want her to take yoga classes?
We didn't want it to,
not everybody's going to be fucking
mother Theresa. You know this curly bad.
She's just out there probably sucking
in some decks, getting cooked up,
getting fingered in the bathroom. She's
fucking, she's putting it together. Yeah.
It's called together an exciting little
life. Join her twenties she never see.
See, when I asked her if she
wanted to Fart in Katy far
cup, when I asked her, no,
you asked her. You actually, you harassed
her. What a piece of shit you are,
Bro. No, no. Poor girl.
It's pretty awesome.
Okay. You're going to
like this if it works. And
Brian, all right, here we go.
Hey Lindsey. Lindsey. Oh my God. Do you,
have you ever farted in a cup and put
it in the cat space just to see its
reaction.
What about what about puppy?
That's not really true.
You added all that shit.
Ain't [inaudible].
You already told me how you did,
but knucklehead joke for everybody.
Everybody tried to pull it over my eyes
and maybe watch a gag from four fucking
years ago. That wasn't even real. It's
real. [inaudible] tell you what he did.
Ladies and gentlemen,
he added his audio into the
previous audio of Lindsay Lohan.
This is a fucking fraud perpetrated
on the American people. It's fine.
It's fine. And it's funny, but you
already did the bit on the podcast. No,
but you did it to Joe.
I was doing it to America.
I knew disrespectful man. Yeah,
he's fucking tried to trick me, man.
The good thing is that people think that's
real and now the really good thing is
they don't know until you ruined it.
I ruined it.
I wanted to know what Lindsay
Lohan thinks about that video.
I think that would be hilarious to
see stuff. She already asked me that.
It's a stupid question she wants.
We thought it was a stupid question.
It's got 7,000 users a chance to,
you seen it?
Yeah, man. That's everybody.
That's a youtube is going to make you
a partner. There's a fucking videos,
some videos online. If you look
at and you go, Whoa, how many?
I finally started watching Zeitgeists.
There's a new site guys to film that
everybody tells you you have to watch.
So I finally started it.
I looked
down to views,
11 million views.
Right, and when was it uploaded?
Do you know how fast that came?
Good question because that stuff,
I mean there's like a formula almost.
I got a couple of buddies who are
like youtube partners and they just,
I mean it's ridiculous.
Once people start subscribing to you,
they'll just watch anything
and they just throw up shit.
It doesn't matter just because they need
to put more content out there and you
know that that part of it suffers,
which sucks.
Dude is only a bloated in January of
2011 so I guess it's been around for,
what is that, six months? February. March,
yeah, but when did you watch
this? A couple of months ago.
It's secret is black woman on toilet
equals 38 million hit black Raymond on
toilet?
No.
Was that the woman who was like
smacking her lips and singing some
crazy Dee Siggy type
black ones
and this woman looks like she's got a
Bandanna on her head
and she's morbidly obese.
I think she really is sitting on
the toilet too, which is cool.
It's not funny. Wow. This is,
this is one of those things.
What about wiping a dirty bitch?
I had a buddy who sent me that and I
watched about 10 seconds of it when this
chick's like trying too hard to be viral
and I'm pissed that she became viral.
Yeah.
Read a lot of hydro,
38 million people married and she would
have sped up her voice like times two
that would have made 80 million hits.
He has to do is setting up.
That's what you do.
And if you were an alien and you
were from another planet and you were
evaluating Earth and whether or not
the earthlink should be allowed to move
forward, he would look at things like
this and you would go, wait a minute,
what the fuck? They'd probably wasted
all their resources. Let's move on.
I might get one of the real housewives
of Beverly Hills checks to come on this
podcast.
This is Rogan is friends with one of them.
I can't say until we, until she says
yes. But that would be fascinating too,
because it was another perfect example.
I need to be a watch that could show
Joe. It's fucking, it's unsafe. Feeling
uncomfortable.
Yeah. And they, um, they're,
it's real gross man. Did the,
like the level of behavior, especially
the Beverly hills one is real gross.
They're just disgusting human
beings. Yeah. These women are foul.
I haven't seen this new season.
Have you been watching it this season?
I just watched one episode, the one
that misses Rogan's friends in the,
they are so fucking,
yeah. These women are,
they're ugly and doing drugs.
Girl keeps running to the bathroom and
doing drugs and she's coming out and
they're,
they're mean to this pretty girl and
they're mean to this pretty girl for no
reason. I mean, she doesn't do a damn
thing and they think it's hilarious,
but they're being mean to her.
You know why?
Because when you're a woman and if you're,
you're an an unattractive woman and
another woman is really attractive,
all of the sudden it's like
she stole something from you.
It's like she has this magical power just
to have some fucking roll of the dice.
And so they feel like it's okay to
be contrary to them because the woman
actually makes them feel like
we're already at a deficit
before the conversation.
Even starts,
they feel uncomfortable,
so they don't feel bad about turning that
uncomfortable feeling on the girl for
no reason at all. Right. Just for
the girl being pretty and it's,
it's crazy to watch,
man.
It's crazy to watch these like
really low level human beings,
like low level thing catty.
Yeah. It's worse than caddy.
It's just worried about is who's fucking
who and whose bag is who wearing and
where do you get your shoes and
low and they're monsters, man.
They're just just retard monsters.
I watched all of last season
and I don't know why, but oh I
did you feel like, did you see
the guy committing suicide coming?
Did you see that coming?
No,
but he was a little weird.
He was just kind of off and the
way his wife would describe him,
she was saying like,
oh,
he's a manly man and he's like a cowboy
and he's just muscular and all this shit.
And he just looks like a dude who sits
in a cubicle. I mean, I know he didn't,
but he looks like he's never been at
the gym and his life. But you know,
it wasn't like a fat tub of Shit, but he
was just all right. And I was just like,
this woman has blinders on,
you know? Yeah. Well, so I
think some people, you know,
they sit down, they go, well,
how are you going to talk about
me? Well, I'm going to say that
love wildlife. How are you
going to talk about me? Well,
I'm going to say that you're a
manly man. Tell people, meet you.
And they're like cowboy
pull balls down by the,
that wasn't even a plot point. And one of
the episodes they were, they were like,
wait,
she described him as there's like,
there's mainly cowboy and he's
just like a balding piece of shit.
Yeah. You know what? The producers
would probably smacking their lips.
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's a good way to describe on the
way to describe him. But I like to wait,
we've met this guy. Make sure
this gets to the year fast enough.
If there's any words that slurry, just
make her do it again. Do it again.
That's called, she had like major, major
botox. Dude, I don't think it's a botox.
I think it's actually an implant.
Oh really?
Well,
she was constantly going in and
getting more plastic surgery done.
Oh, jumps and stuff. And She
just looks ridiculous. Yeah.
They start fucking with her face man.
And it's way better to look old and
they look crazy and women don't want to
accept that. But there's, I
know women, they need to stop.
I know women that have become monsters.
I mean literally become monsters.
I've seen them become monsters.
I've seen them change from
this very nice older woman,
you know,
it's just accepting the fact that she's
entering her forties or 50s or whatever.
And this just life,
the cycle of life
for all of us. There's other things
to concentrate other than that.
And instead they just
whacked her face out, man.
I mean whack it out with like fillers.
So their cheeks stick out. Right.
And then they get, they get their noses
change and their eyes pulled back.
Well, the duck lips freaking the fuck
out there. Like w w what are you doing?
What is this?
It's almost like people thought that
because you were allowed to have duck lip,
tits, those blah, that's
fucking stupid tits.
We not only like, they were
encouraged like buck mom, nobody,
nobody went, you know, you've ridiculous
bitch. But if you go duck lips on the,
on the lips, then we go get outta
here. You can't go super balloons.
You can go super balloons on the tits,
but you can't go super balloons on
the lips. People drew a line there.
They're like, this is creepy
to tits. I can go with,
it's past the point of being funny and
it's just sad. Yeah. And ridiculous.
But it's more disturbing.
Like for whatever reason,
fake breasts don't bother me nearly as
much as fake lips. Fake breasts seem like,
yeah, I see what you did there and you
know you want him to bigger ones. Okay,
cool. That's cool. But fake
lips are like, whoa, Whoa, whoa.
That's your fucking mouth man. You
know, like you're, you're, you're,
you're jabbing some shit into where you
sit and eat to change the shape event.
Do you look at the before and afters?
Is anybody looked better with that shit?
Especially the eyebrows when they
started fucking with the eyebrows too.
Like people that shaped who much also.
And then there's people
that get those teammates.
At least your eyebrows grow back. That
doesn't bother me. But the tattoos.
Have you seen the tattoos?
Cat eyes and eyebrows. I,
I'd rather not do permanent
makeup too with a tattoo.
Like eye shadow on shit like that.
I don't like that Shit's weird.
Like a clown person.
That's a commitment man.
Who's got bits about the tattoo
on your face? It doesn't.
One of our friends have a bit about
tattoo on your face. Is it team?
Does team have been about tattoos
on his phone? Hey Thompson girl.
So Gurra has bits about guys
with tattoos on their face.
One of the guys on our board,
it's a stupid fucking picture,
but it makes me laugh every time I see it.
This guy a non on the message board,
he has this,
uh,
this photo of a dude who had
tattooed on his lip pussy eater it,
and it's a mugshot of this guy.
I hate the Mugshot of this guy.
And he's kept pussy eater
tattooed on his lip.
Can you imagine being there
and carrying that? I could. Oh,
he cares, man. That's why
he did it. Doesn't not care.
It's abuse, Bro. Somebody
abused that kid for sure. Yeah.
That's a kid that grew up in a terrible
environment. That's what that is.
I got a buddy who's got a, you know
those name tags that say like, hi,
my name is Tom,
or whenever it's got to as just he's,
he tattooed that on his chest when he
was drunk and Mexico and so it was that
and it says, hi, my name is Dildo tron.
Here's the best part. The Mexican dude
given him the tattoo misspelled Dildo.
Toronto does says Delo. Oh,
to go back and get it fixed.
Oh, that's hilarious. That's so beautiful.
That's so beautiful. It's
ridiculous. So much better that way.
That's so much better. There's some
hilarious misspelled tattoos online.
If you want to just,
just laugh your fucking ass.
Just go and look at some of the shit
that people have misspelled on tattoos.
It's like, my God. Fuck man.
Do you just not care at all?
Do you do not double check?
I'm pretty sure it's how it's spelled,
but let me check real quick.
That's why he just try not to get any
writing. Just do that. You can't have
design like that will. You could
always say, oh well then no,
that octopus was supposed
to have nine tentacles.
Especially if you do
like to Betten language.
Like I have a friend who was this big
Tibet and piece across his stomach like
come on Sunday,
can't read Tibet.
Know what the fuck does
that really says?
That can say some ridiculous shit.
Like what is your say you you,
you got a tattoo.
You thought it said Brian.
I thought it was the letter R and I found
out it meant what are flowing water or
waterfalls and he blames crying fits
in that Tattoo under my lip right here.
I thought it said, you know my
last name and it says cum bucket.
Are you doing bitch?
He felt like he was setting us
up there twice, twice, twice,
twice today.
Brian,
you try to sneak something in
there is that there's a porn star.
It has the word cum bucket.
And that's what I was thinking about it
because she had a Twitter the other day
and she was looking at like
her lips and as a company,
that's disgusting. I just,
some girls just say, all right,
you want to play slot? All right,
I'm going to play super slot. Right.
They just take it out.
Like when you watch those gang bang scene,
so you watch gang bang scene and like,
you know, they get together and they go,
all right,
and how many want to do all right,
what we're gonna do 300 today and
they'll do a 300 man gang bang.
And then another girl go, that
bitch, she had 300 I'll fuck her.
I'm going to do 150 more.
And so she'll do the fucking four 50 and
then some crazy bitch to 600 but that's
what they do. They just outside
each other they get instead,
since they can't be pure and loved and
they can't be accepted for who they are,
instead they just go deep,
deep into the slut barrel.
Brad, you know Brad Williams,
he was dating. Yeah, the
little, uh, the little guy,
he was a,
he was telling me that he was like,
he had been like fucking this porn
star. Whoa for a while. And then she,
you know, and this is going
on for two years or something.
And then she comes to him
and says, listen, we've got
to stop and this and that.
I'm getting out of the business. And he's
like, oh, is that just like what you do?
Like when you stop, you just don't want
to do when she goes, well, you know,
I want to be faithful
to my husband with like,
this whole time you've been having this
two year affair with this porn star.
Didn't even know, Whoa, maybe
I shouldn't have said his name.
Well,
see Shatsky these chicks,
these chicks,
you know, it goes back
into, you know, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna fuck 150 more guys. I'm going
to go fuck dwarfs or whatever. You know.
Well, you know, I mean I'm,
I'm a shitty arm chair psychologist,
you know, and I want to,
when I break down porn stars and like
why does a person do this and does a
person do that? There's different reasons.
There's a lot of different reasons but,
and some of them are really nice, like
Danny, the Armand, she's really nice.
Jenna Jameson's running
nice, you know, some,
they're really nice people
but I can't help. But when,
you know, especially since
I have daughters of my own,
whenever I seen something like that,
that there's this weird part of me
that has to do the math, you know,
I can't just watch a girl with a Dick in
her mouth and wandering around assault
and one in her vagina. I can't
go. Wow. They must be crazy.
Like this bitch is just
letting go and just wild.
I have to do the math in my
head has to go back to puberty.
It has to go back to
child and that's the girl.
What the fuck happened to you
that you're expressing yourself?
This word is your bond.
It's really like fucking sex like a lot,
like it feels so good and you just gave
up me like, you know what? Fuck it.
I liked the fuck it is possible.
But you know,
all all varieties of behavior
are possible, I guess.
Supposedly friends with her family.
No, nothing's ever happened to her.
She's just a good example.
Dana Dermo now that she's a very
strange girl. Yeah. You know she did.
She did a gang bang scene and afterwards
she was so happy about it that she was
crying. It was an awesome video. Just the
trailer alone. Totally legit. Awesome.
Totally legit. She's just crying
because she accomplished awesome senior.
No that. I love them. I love
them all and it's like, whoa.
Like for everybody else he watching you
go, wow, what the fuck? But she's nice.
She's a nice person. He's going to bring
a tear to your eye because you know her.
No,
not quiet before.
It's one of those Arsenio
Hall things that make you go,
you
remember that was a song for a while,
D and c music factory.
Is that what it was?
I wonder if they took that from
Arsenio Hall and I think it was,
I think it was the whole,
I think they ripped him off or was
either or the other backwards. Oh,
it could've just been like a same
time period though. Cultural thing.
Like they're just like a phrase
that people, you know, in that time,
Arsenio Hall show that
never fell off like that.
I would've loved to see that guy continue
his talk show ways like Jay Leno's
done like everybody else has done.
I liked the Arsenio Hall show.
He's a nice fucking guy and he
lives, he lives, uh, and, well,
I don't want to say where it lists,
but I've,
I've run into them a bunch of times
and he's always super friendly.
I keep hearing he's trying to
make a comeback or something
and then I never hear
anything about it at anytime.
I hear his name is always trying to get
things in order because he's going to do
a comeback and then you
just don't hear anything.
Well, he was doing standup
for a while, you know,
he came to the comedy
store a bunch of times.
Do you remember it came to a comedy store?
Yeah.
Well we saw him at the comedy Magic Club.
We hung out with him and
then got in the green room.
Yeah, I'm really, yeah,
it was like maybe two years ago. Three
years ago. Really? Yeah. He's a great guy.
Either way. Um, he's um,
I don't know why the fuck did we get
on to him? Oh, things make you go home?
It's called dead air.
No,
that shit.
Do you remember how they used to portray
or sending a hold on like Saturday
night live with that really long finger,
like, yeah, like this creepy long finger.
Oh, remember that? Remember that?
Was that Sarah and I think it was
Saturday night live in living color. Oh,
did you hear about it?
This a high school, uh, drug
bust that they pulled today.
And can I saw you,
I saw you tweeted that,
but I didn't get a chance to look at it.
Fucking ridiculous. One of
the most ridiculous things
I've ever heard in my life.
They told these kids that is
in Connecticut and um, Walcott,
Connecticut did this, this happened today.
No, I'm sorry. They reporting it today.
It happened last week.
Oh,
so they say that the over the loudspeaker
that an intruder has entered the
building, they think it's
a shooter. You know, they,
they implied that they think that there's
some armed person who has entered the
building that everyone needs to get into
a corner and huddle up and then they go
through the fucking high school with
drug sniffing dogs looking for pot.
That's ridiculous.
So they scared these fucking kids into
thinking that there was a shooter and
they're building now they don't
know the history of these people.
What if one of these kids was related
to someone who got shot at Columbine,
right?
Or many of those other schools shootings.
And you're going to give some
horrible trauma to some fucking kid.
Who remembers their uncle Mike who
got shot in the fucking hammer?
They did that then because their comments,
because morons run the school
systems in Walcott, Connecticut.
So they send dogs through
the fucking in the hallways.
They find no drugs by the way.
They find nothing. Meanwhile,
these fucking kids now are going to think,
oh,
they're willing to lie to us for
a shit reason. They're not even,
they're not even going to ask us,
do you have drugs?
And then search to the school
unexpectedly. Instead of doing that,
what they're going to do as a lie
to us about a fucking shooter,
about an armed intruder,
get us terrified now,
how the fuck are you ever going to believe
them if they come on the loudspeaker
again and say an armed intruder is
entered into this tool at fuck you was,
it really was an army. God Damn. Fuck
you. Yeah, you're right. Fuck you.
When I was in high school that were
like, you know, it's probably more today,
but like 10 dudes you knew did, you know
did did pot and stuff and that was it.
It's like,
I'm sure most high schools are like that.
Like you know who the fucking pot
heads are just like corner them or so.
You don't have to lie to the
entire school freak everyone.
You don't have to lie to them either.
If you want to search the fucking school,
search to school,
tell the kids to sit the fuck down and
put the dogs in the hallway and you know,
make sure you have the dogs on leash.
You fucking savages.
So no little kids get
bitten. But the, the disease,
this is whose idea it was like the
superintendent or the principal or,
I mean there's should be multiple
firings for this firings.
They should go to jail. You
guys are criminals, criminals,
and you're fucking up a kid's brain.
You're going to make kids
think the cops are idiots.
think the cops won't,
will lie to you to find out if
someone's smoking a fucking joint.
It's all high school.
Jesus fucking Christ.
How will you raising your 15 1617 year
old kids do not talk to them. Yeah,
you could do your fucking talk to him at
that age. They're fucking teenagers, man.
There are a lot of fucking
smarter than you think.
What you don't do is lie to him and
see there's a fucking shooter in the
building.
It's just so bad.
Associate or Duke Walcott,
police department.
You can't dumb dumb,
dumb cunts.
Did you fucking think
this shit through at all?
It's just one of the things where it
makes you just really realize that there's
no special qualifications to be in
charge of a situation like this.
To be that guy who comes up with that
Shitty fucking idea and then implemented
without anybody stopping him. Right.
Damn. How the fuck do you trust them?
You Morons not one teacher go, wait,
whoa, whoa. What the fuck are we doing?
But not one cop go. What?
What you want? I mean,
I know cops just want to keep their
fucking job and keep the fucking pension,
but when your boss tells you that
you got to be like Jesus Christ,
we're going to bring dogs to the fucking
high school and you're going to tell
them that there's a shooter.
Well, I mean it's doubtful,
but maybe the cops didn't know.
Maybe they said you just get the kids
off in one area and we'll come through
with the, yeah, there might be. Yeah,
there might be more to that story.
Like the cops had no idea what
they were doing. You know,
like they were just like what? There's
a gun really. This is the exact note,
the school administrator and now it's
over the public address system that a
dangerous intruder had entered the school
and that all students were to remain
in their classrooms away from windows
and ideally huddled in one corner of the
room.
They had the kids huddle in fear huddle
in one corner of the room for nothing,
for our fake drill. Cause I'm a fucking
moron, cop and Walcott, Connecticut.
And I think I'm smarter than people
because they have to listen to me cause I
have a badge because they
operate under a system of law.
These fucks these fucking cops and
they get into these situations, band,
they start thinking they're
better than regular people there.
Start thinking they can
tell you what to do. What?
I will just tell them
there's an intruder jets.
Why you're the boss always
with the great ideas
chief. How do we get all these kids to
huddle in the corner? Terrified in fear.
Well, denim, there's a Nandan Truda. Oh,
that's why you get all the big tax
dollars. We're paying this guy.
We're paying this cunt to lie to our kids.
You fucking dummy.
What a disaster of a human being.
You. If I've got the day off,
you need me to come in. Yeah, come down.
We're gonna scare the shit out
of some kids. Show up with dogs.
We're going to look for joints.
You fucking cunt. You just useless.
I think it was coke. If it was
coke, it'd be okay if they were,
even if it was coke, man, look, all
of it. Anything. You know, even pot,
if you're this pot
going around the school,
you've got to find out where the fuck
at pots coming from kids, 14 year olds,
he'd be a lot harder than it is
to get pot. I agree with that.
I don't think it should be high
all through fucking high school.
It can ruin you and ruin your motivation.
You're not developed. Yeah, you're not.
You're not fully a human being
yet. There's these, there's a way,
but there's ways to handle it that don't
get kids terrified of Jack boot thugs
for the rest of their fucking lives and
lies the lies that the people that are
in control are going to tell you,
no matter what,
you're always going to question those
kids that experienced this will always
question any official
announcement now forever. Right?
It's impossible for them not to write
and they'll have this story forever.
They will laugh about this store. They
should sue the fuck out of those people.
Yeah, and I know it's a down economy and
I know that, you know, there's no Melissa,
this is shit we're suing over. Not
Frivolous lawsuits you get all the time.
This is where it's soon over. If
that was my kids, I would fuck you.
I would sue sue the fuck out of that
police department and I love cops.
It's not the cops themselves. It's,
I know this is the work of one dummy.
You have to find that dummy.
You'd find that dummy.
You need to move him to Siberia.
Thought he was going to win an award or
something for some sort of, you know,
drug task force bullshit.
My new model might not be an edge. As
we came and I came up with a great idea,
score shoot or fish, Judah,
everybody's game, finish school.
It's fucking idiot. Running around
running a police department,
fill of grown men with guns and
this is what he tells you to do.
What a piece of shit you dumped.
Fuck, I wish I knew your name.
They don't list the name it and how could,
how could they not?
Listen to me a better officer. What do
you need to do is do mushrooms? Well,
you need to do officer is just
get alone in the woods is good.
As long as you know there's no bears,
you know you're not going to be freaking
out while you're in the middle of your
peak, right? Just do some
mushrooms. Now Find Yourself,
find how bad this idea was and
if you're scared of mushrooms,
eat one of those pop brown
is that you confiscate.
If you're not prepared, he two or three
pot brownies. If you're not prepared.
That's just as bad as it was doing
mushrooms that will introduce you to your
flaws. You know they have to
to to eat those already. Right.
That's I'm sure if they do a drunk bus,
probably just going to burn all that
weed or like dispose of it in one way,
but it's a Brownie. Yeah.
Yeah. I mean they're good.
They're going to be munching
on that on the way home. Well,
you can obviously you can
just say it's a Brownie.
You know it doesn't look like contraband.
Right? What's that? That's Brownie.
My wife pack went my lunch
there was black and brown.
Did you ever hear that video of the cops
are called nine one one because they
had stolen some pot brownies
from this kid and ate them.
I guess they stole a pot and then cook
them into brownies and then ate the
brownies and I think that's a story.
Either way,
the most important part was they were
calling nine one one they were cops and
they're calling nine one one. They were
like, I think we're going back in time.
I don't think that really, I think I
might already be dead like they were.
They were thinking they were already dead.
Like did they were so high
that they were like, oh my God,
I have passed into the great beyond that,
I'm just starting to realize it.
So they were calling essentially the
nine one. One in the great beyond, right.
They were calling as cops.
Hilarious. So funny. Yeah.
This cop needs to party with
those people. Yeah. Right.
Just get your shit together,
Dude. The are you doing man?
I'm in war right now with Wikipedia.
What's, yeah, it's impossible. I,
there's been so many people,
like I have tried to make me a Wikipedia
page and then it gets canceled cause it
says I'm not important enough.
Which I agree. That's fine,
but then you look who else is
on there and you're like, wait,
this person's on air because they f they
were a porn star for a month, you know,
or this person, it's like a notator
ship over there, man. It's so fucked up.
Right. And so that there's
all these, there's all this,
well there's all this controversy about
these people that kind of are like the
head editors and no one, you know,
it's, everyone can edit Wikipedia.
So it's all about the people.
It's like the moderator. Yeah.
But there's like these moderators that
they want to put who they think is
important enough to be put in there. So
you go through this and you're like, wow,
this is where you wanted there just for
promotional purposes. Do you want there?
I W I want it there because, well, one,
one of the things I want to be
is because Siri and all this,
all these technologies are incorporating
Wikipedia into it. So yeah,
it's it for search reasons
and for what I do, it's, it's,
it makes sense to be in Wikipedia.
Right.
And then the other reason is
because then I look at, uh,
who's in there and I'm like, that's
makes sense. They have a Wikipedia.
I should have a Wikipedia just for
as a kind of a quick bio, you know?
So when people are like, who the fuck is
Hilton? Have a Wikipedia course? And so,
so what, you're sort of a many,
many, many Paris Hilton. So,
so I'm at some asking the p one of
the moderators or editors or whatever,
and I'm like, you know, like what do
I have to do? And they're like, well,
you need to send links of like your work.
Uh,
like on other websites or other
publications or who you are on other
publications that are linked. So I'm
sending them like on Sirius Xm radio,
they talk about our podcast page. It's
probably, they listened to the podcast,
right? I know what it is. And
you're like trying too hard.
So then they have the power.
I know.
So I'm thinking about being in a
porn movie just to be in Wikipedia.
It's a good move. And wiki
leaks what you're doing. See,
your girl wants to start branching out
into male porn and you're resisting and
you'll say, well, I'll just fuck you and
it'll kill two birds with one stone. Sure.
It'll get me on Wikipedia and you can
do boy, Girl Porn. I make more money.
That's right. So I think it's
my transition and getting a wig.
I won't fire you.
There's some jobs will,
they'll fire you if they catch you
doing born. I'll tell you right now,
you can go do all the porn you
want and I will never fire you.
It was a part of your job growth at it.
You're free to do mourn.
You might get a hundred
percent job security. You
don't have to worry. I got it.
I got a buddy who is an attorney,
he's an attorney and he moved,
he moved from Phoenix to La. Oh,
just to work in the office out here.
He was living with a guy
who created a big TV show,
but I don't want to say what it is, but
everybody would know what it is. Bonanza.
And he was living with a
guy who created bonanza.
And so he's a lawyer and a, and then
the guy, he's living with his like, Hey,
do you want to come and do a
little guest spot on my show?
This is like a reporter, right? And
he's just asks two questions. It's some,
some little guest star thing. And,
uh, so what I put on Wikipedia,
I make a Wikipedia page for him just
as like a joke. Like, oh, Brandon,
Lombardy is a American actor. And
uh, but he's also a lawyer. He,
he, this thing is taunting him now. I've
tried to take that off several times.
You can't, like, you can't take it
off him and take that. I'll delete it.
It'll be back within an hours because
he'll, he's like trying, you know,
he's like interviewing for other jobs
and stuff at different law firms.
They're like, well, what the fuck is it?
You're an actor. Like what? And he's like,
no, no, no, no. They look, I mean,
he's on IMD be and that sort of thing,
but it's like he,
that's not who he is and it's,
it's like starting to fuck with them. Like
they're tyrants over there, dude. Yeah,
it's weird.
There's some kind of like government that
runs we Wikipedia and they want you to
know who they want you to know.
Almost like the media where it should be
an open source thing. Like it's rolled,
you know it. And it's really fucking
weird because if you can say, hey,
like I gave them a link list of links,
like 50 pages,
like how many Twitter followers do you
have now you're like 30,000 but I was a
guest on Adam Carolla radio show about
the Carla's been see a video I, you know,
have,
have little things that are,
I would gay more important
than somebody that is like,
I was in a blowjob video when I was 18
the blowjob video provides a lot of
people with something to beat off to.
You think it should be knocking it?
Like what's,
what's Charlie Sheen's girl that crazy
that his ex that day, the crazy slide.
Her name.
What's the Olson?
She is the most beautiful fucking
Wikipedia page with photos and lane.
She's a superstar though. She's a
porn superstar. Compare yourself
to her. That's ridiculous.
That's what I'm saying.
I'm just know what you
will never be hurt if you,
you know what you are and you're the
guy who confidently says, you know,
like if you have to choose to treat me or
fucking Bree Olsen, you'll let me live.
I know you will.
I don't even have to think about it.
And then it gets to the judgment
time when the guy was like,
I'll take Brielle's and what the bottom
falls out of the floor and he drops down.
He just doesn't understand.
He just wants some legitimacy. He just
wants to affirmation for what I do,
what I do, my videos and, and Margaret.
It helps promote stuff. It's pretty,
it makes more sense to me that that's
like my being not being able to be on I
MDB for you probably imagine.
You know, it's kind of like that.
It's kind of like a Techie,
nerdy.
I got,
what else?
What else I get is the fact that you've
had it up a couple of times and then
somehow or another it gets yanked back.
Yeah.
It's because it's,
they always give the excuse that you're
not important enough or you're not
showing importance at all.
I send them a link,
30 different things like article
reviews and stuff like that.
He listens to this podcast.
I fucking guarantee you he listened to
these podcasts. He's one of those guys.
It's fucking red being Nazi.
Every time we bring this up is another
six months of me not adding it.
Tired of red pens. Bullshit. Nobody
wants to hear about your cats Dick.
He's going to Applebee's on the weekends.
Just bitching.
Anyone who will hear and will be,
did I tell you I've got the craziest
Internet search story other ever.
There was a store,
I've told this before,
I think this is the the 1990s like right,
right around 2000 ish.
There was a
small mixed martial arts organization and
it was when they were just starting to
learn about Internet searches and they
had this guy who was fighting for them
and he's got, he's got,
he's a fucking beast dude.
Like six four two 40 built like a,
like a comic book superhero smashing
everybody and he was like a big star and
their organization,
so a,
they're trying to assemble some press on
this guy and they do a search and they
find out that a gentleman with the same
name had won something called the hungry
is but contests.
So
pre Google man,
this is like,
who knows what they had for
search engines back then.
So clearly this couldn't be our guide,
this couldn't be our gladiator,
our warrior and not be involved in
something called. So they click a link,
there's two dudes using him as Chinese
finger handcuffs, one's in his ass,
ones in his mouth and they got these
pictures of this guy, oh my God.
And so then my friend has
to sit down with this guy,
talked to him and he has
to say, uh, you know, um,
did you ever do gay porn?
Which is the guy fucking freaks out and
starts yelling, what the fuck you saying?
What the fuck are you saying?
And he has to literally click on the
link and then step away from the computer
while it loads. And he's like, and the
fucking few seconds and it took to load.
I'm locked. He goes, I'm locked in a
fucking office with a gay savage, right,
right. Big Day gladiator who is
lying to me and tell me he's not gay.
And I'm clicking this link and as it's
click, click, click, click, click, click.
It's old school internet where it takes
a long time for a personal loan and
slowly but surely he sees the Dick in
his mouth like slowly but surely you see
men's abdomens mag, men's
abdomens, someone's head,
your head, what's in your mouth?
Oh, that's a car once in your ass.
That's a cocktail and you,
you're watching this
and he's watching this. They're
watching this together. You know,
they're watch this together. And then
the guy says, listen man, listen man.
I just needed the money. It's not
that I'm gay. I just needed the money.
It was just a bad situation.
It turns out he did like a hundred movies.
Oh Shit. You can do like 15 movies.
That's a lot of money though.
I'd take her money movies. That's
what's a lot of money though, for fee.
How much worse?
It wasn't getting paid back then as
compared to what you would get today too.
Yeah. The joke is when I
talked about it in my act,
the joke was how much does
a lot of money to you?
Cause for a lot of money
to me is I do one movie.
I live like I'm in a fucking Jz
video for the rest of my life.
They did 15 you should have
all the money on a planet.
There should be no money left for
anybody else. You have everything.
You did 15 movies where we,
they like, man, fuck you.
You got everything and great memories
do, do, do, do.
How pissed off are you Brian
that I have a Wikipedia page?
I already know you'd already looked.
Oh goodness.
I looked it up because it's kind of you
coming off a little jealous. No, no.
I looked it up. I looked it up
actually when I was trying to get, no,
trying to get photos for you for the
show we did last week and it came up
as on when I did a search
and I, he, he's in a TV show,
so you should be on, have a
Wikipedia show. But I didn't,
I don't know how it got made or how,
I mean,
I would imagine my own voice if they try,
if they verified it
that I was on that show.
The way that you're saying they do that,
I don't know why they're not.
There's gotta be something else
as a reason why they're not like,
I know. I think it's because I'm
German. Josh has his own website.
Josh mcdermitt.com. What a handsome fella.
Hey, can I plug my Twitter? Fuck yes,
dude. This is what I like. Anytime
you say anything about me on Twitter,
I pick up like a hundred followers like
that. Please follow Josh McDermitt, m c d.
E r M. I t. T. Derm myth to be,
it used to be fat piece of crap,
which is easier to remember.
How can we change it?
Uh,
cause people who pay me a lot of money
asked me if I would change it so they get
promoted and I just kind of went, this
isn't a fight I want to have. I was like,
sure, whatever. But I still have fat piece
of crap so don't try and get it. But um,
this is what I'm going to do. Cause uh,
uh, no, this is kind of little plug.
If I could put,
November,
November is pancreatic cancer awareness
month and my brother in law died of
pancreatic cancer.
And so for every follower I get,
let's start it now through
the month of November,
I'm going to donate 5 cents to
pancreatic cancer research. And I know,
I think I had like six 82 or
something when I walked in here.
So everything from now on, uh, through
November I'll donate 5 cents. Oh sweet.
That's pretty good.
I get all the money in the world,
so I don't give a shit if I get a
million followers. Guys, you crazy.
What's a million followers? 5 cents of
falling or know who can do the math,
not me.
You know,
there's someone listening to this right
now already who's already done it. Yes.
Yelling it out. Killing [inaudible]
answer. Morons guy ain't talking.
I'm not Brian. We're going to get you on
Wikipedia buddy. It's going to be okay.
We gotta do it, man. So
me and Joe were talking,
we're still in the other day
talking about yawning and like,
like what the fuck is yawning for it?
And I was like,
what if there was some kind
of communication back in
the old days were we're not
figuring out.
And we went on this whole theory of like,
like what if we yawned and touched
her nipples at the same time?
Like a dragon head would come out and
teach us something or that was you not
wait, don't say we when you came
up with a stupid idea. So anyways,
last night it was
last night was watching. What's that
show where they tried to break a myth?
Myth busters.
I was watching mythbusters and during
doing theory on yawns and it was so weird
that out of nowhere that I saw this,
uh,
and they would put people
around in like groups.
And then like see if
like one person to yawn,
if it would start like a yawn off where
everyone would be yawning eventually.
It was really interesting. There
was a, it wasn't a high number,
which I thought it was,
but there was definitely shown negative.
You Yawn in a group that
there'll be more yards per, yeah.
Well I think that that's a smart
way to test that. First of all,
you know they did a few ways you,
but that's a terrible way to test it.
When you have cameras on people
and you make no, they don't. No,
they don't know there's cameras.
They think that they,
they got him off Craig's list. They had
to fill out to like some application,
like a doctor's waiting room. They
don't know there's cameras. Yeah. Yeah.
They didn't know there were, there was
cameras. Wait for someone to yawn. Yeah.
And they just waited for one person to
yawn and and see, see if it started.
Do the, do people yawn? Like,
or just like what if nobody dawned
than this? They had problems with that.
So they didn't, they did other
studies where the gas, the room,
then they did you sign the release
where they put them in like their each
individual rooms and did studies on them?
It was just kind of weird because I,
while watching that I couldn't
stop yawning. You're like I was
mentioning I'll, I'll
start yawning. Right.
Even if you're talking about that makes
sense that they studied it that way.
I was so stupid.
I thought they just got everybody
that that's how I was studying.
Get them all in the room.
Okay. You Yawn first.
Shit doesn't work at all.
But what if that was some
weird communication that
we're not, we're missing out.
Like you're supposed to yon
with the person next to you.
At the same time I'm like,
there's something there.
I think they believe in chimpanzees.
It had something to do with, uh,
with the Alpha position and with
like exchanging like empathy.
Like, so when one person
yawns like you're almost like,
you feel like, uh, obliged to let
them know. Yeah, I'm tired too.
Cause you don't want to be like,
you're taught bitch, I'm wide awake.
I'm going to fuck your wife while
you're sleeping. You know there's,
there's a little something too.
It's like a communication thing.
When you're young, your heartbeat,
I think it was 30% goes up,
30% rate and your lungs completely fill
up with air like and it does all this
shit when, when you, when you yawn,
it also makes me also wonder if
there was something else there.
Like you're sending a bolt of like you're
supposed to yawned at same time while
you want to talk to somebody else in
their head or something like that.
Did they talk about what the fuck are you
charging? You're charging your battery.
Did they talk about what your heart
rate dips too after you're done yawning
because you're, you're like
relaxing. I don't know.
I feel like you almost like relax even
more than it would be less than what it
was when before he started
yawning. Yeah, that seems silly.
Maybe it's waking you up.
I mean saying that your heart
jumps 30 beats per minute. I mean,
that's what happens when
you take a stimulant.
Maybe like the idea of this big burst of
this big burst of oxygen and
unusual fashion like that.
Maybe it sparks like an extra little pump
of blood flow that's supposed to like
send, like send a signal. Come on guys,
let's wake up. Let's wake up. Come on.
Because like, that's what a lot of people
do too when they're young. Like, oh, okay,
okay, okay, let's fucking
bear down. You know,
when someone like yawns and they're tired,
sometimes they'll do that.
They'll be on the go,
I got to wake up,
I gotta wake up and then they'll like
fire up whatever you supposed to touch
like a pyramid at the same time.
[inaudible] on one side,
blue monkey up your asshole
while you're eating a jellyfish.
I thought you guys like what ifs. I'm
just talking. This is the craziest,
what if ever, Brian, I'm so glad
you saw this through. So there's,
um, there's some evidence that the justice
department is proposing new freedom of
information act rules that
allow the government to
influence of form the public.
That records do not exist.
Even if they do.
So you know the freedom of Information
Act, you're supposed to be able to say,
Hey, is the records on, you
know, Blah Blah Blah, and
they're, they're supposed to,
you know, in cases where it's not, I mean,
I'm sure there must be some fucking
national security rules, right?
That's mine son I file. You're going
to drink out of mind. I'm like, ill,
you want some of this?
Anyway, what they're saying is
they're allowed to lie real.
They're allowed to tell
you that. It totally, it,
it cancels out the whole reason of
having the Freedom Information Act. Yeah.
I mean it's like, it's, it's, so,
it's like there's no way to keep a tab
of all the creepy shit the government
does on a regular basis.
They tried to sneak through.
It's like you have to read about this on
fucking wired.com which is where I read
about it. Somebody sent it to me on
Twitter. It's just, it's so gross.
It's almost like the,
the Justice Department is putting this
out now and doing that so they don't have
to talk about shit like that. Fast and
furious gun running thing. Yeah, exactly.
You know what I mean? They're like, ah, we
got to cover our ass retroactively. Yeah.
I wonder. I wonder. I wonder if
it's just another distraction,
but it's gotta be everything. It seems
like everything is a distraction nowadays.
It's so offensive.
It's so strange.
It's like it doesn't,
it doesn't make sense that at this stage
of the game that people still think
that they can communicate with people
like this or they can just lie to you and
just tell you that they don't,
that files don't exist.
Even if they do like 30 40 years ago,
freedom of Information Act comes out.
Nobody thinks anything of it because
how many people are actually going to be
asking for it.
But now that everyone's a blogger,
everyone's got their own
podcast doing stuff. I mean,
it's like anyone could get
that information and you
start really doing some
fucking damage. Yeah. Anyone can
get that information. We had,
we had yon over when we were young,
had stacks of them used to, fuck,
I've got the documents,
I'll release Jones. Yeah.
He had the freedom of information
documents like wow. Yeah. But even,
even though I know, I know that I could
get my hands on, I still feel like, ah,
it'd be too much work. I don't know.
Is it, it's, I don't want to do it.
I don't have the, I
don't have the, I mean,
you've got to sift through
millions of fucking documents.
You ain't gotta be a 90 person,
but every now and then you
find something really crazy.
Like they found the operation
Northwoods document that was like,
they didn't find that until
fairly recently. That's the
one where the public, uh,
the,
rather than the army was planning on
having fake attacks on American civilians
and blaming it on the Cubans to
get us to go to war with Cuba.
They were going to blow up a drone.
Jetliner they're going to send a
jet into the air and blow it up. Oh,
my blame the Cubans for it and
get us to go to war with Cuba.
And the guy who came up with that.
Then when I moved to Connecticut
and did that thing at the school,
I got another idea. Well,
the scary part about it,
it was signed by the Joint Chiefs of
staff and it was vetoed by candidates.
It's called operation Northwoods.
It's one of the creepiest documents
you'll ever read because it is 100% lock
down.
Solid proof that people in high office
think that way, that they really,
they were going to
attack American soldiers.
They were going to have armed Cuban
friendlies, attack, wan tot them,
obey attack American soldiers. They
went on fucking lob mortars. Yeah.
I mean they would killed, killed
kids who would kill, you know,
soldiers like American soldiers.
They're not pushing this through,
put it in over the everglades
or something where you know,
it's just going to kill a couple of
crocodiles. The whole thing is disgusting.
But the what's really terrifying,
it's like no one went to jail for that.
This is like, you know, this is, I believe
it was like 1962 somewhere around then.
Right. So it was right before Kennedy
was killed and nobody was, um,
nobody went to jail for that.
If nobody went to jail for that and
there's no punishment for that kind of
corruption and that kind of, you know,
the mismanagement of the government,
then all that happens is it evolves,
everything involves things.
They don't stay still. If they're
making five bucks a day under the table,
they want to make 10 bucks a
day under the table. You know,
it's a very few people stay at the
same level all the time, but that,
that document just feeds into why Kennedy
was assassinated, you know, probably.
Yeah.
Like with the,
with the Cubans and how he didn't want
to do the shit that the military sort of
wave of people recently I find that don't
believe the Kennedy was assassinated
by anyone other than Oswald. And
I think it's hilarious. Yeah.
It's one of the dumbest conspiracies.
It's one of the, if you know,
w you go with a conspiracy theories,
there's, there's, there's, you know,
some that are really out there and you've
got to really squint when you look at
them. And there's other ones that go,
oh yeah, there's something wrong here.
And the Kennedy is, there's
something wrong here. Yeah.
If you just look at the facts,
you know that Oswald didn't do it.
He didn't act alone so much crazy shit.
The fact that they found the bullet on,
on the, um, what are those things
they carry by on the Gurney,
they found the bullet on, on, on
Connolly's Gurney just magically fell.
Oh here's the bullet that shot
you and went through everybody.
And even though it's not even bent up,
right,
it's the whole thing is just preposterous.
And the only reason why they came
up with a third bullet, you know,
the reason why they had to
have that single bullet theory,
this is one thing a lot
of people don't know.
It's cause there was a
guy under the bridge,
he was under the overpass
and he got hit by a ricochet.
So they had account for that bullet.
And since they had committed to the idea
that there was three shots that were
fired from Oswald's gun, they had
account for all these different wounds.
One of them being a wound in the front
of the neck that in the initial autopsy
they diagnosed as a wound in the front
of the neck and then in Bethesda,
Maryland when they flew the body and
they said it was a trake wound and that
they opened up it to help him breathe.
Why,
why are you helping someone brewery that
is missing their fucking head. Okay.
His brains got shot all over the
fucking backseat of that car.
Stop pretending that that guy was alive
when they flew him across the continent
and they stuck a trake wound. He
didn't know that's an impact, won't it?
So it's an entry wound from a bullet
and they can't account for that bullet.
So all they came up with was,
oh well one bullet just went wiki,
wacky inside of his body and shattered
bones in two different people came out
looking almost pristine. It's, it's
amazing how few people believe that.
And it's because people like things
tidy and they like things and they love
this idea of [inaudible]
razor. The simplest solution
is always the correct one.
But that's not the case. Oftentimes
it is. But it's not always the case.
If you'd see in the operation Northwoods
document, there's real corruption.
There's your real conspiracy.
There's a bunch of guys who
really sat down and said,
how can we get people to be interested
in going to war with Cuba? Well,
here's what we can do.
We can say the Cubans are attacking us
and we can blow up airplanes like the
fact that they would drop a memo for that.
If you don't think they would get
together and say, this Kennedy,
this motherfucker, he wants us out of
Vietnam. It's going to cost us billions.
He wants to fucking end the Fed. He
wants to get rid of the CIA. The CIA.
At the time,
I'd only been around for about 20 years.
The CIA was created after World War II,
so from World War II to,
you know when Kennedy was shot in the 60s
it was building up steam and he didn't
like it.
He thought they should get rid of the CIA.
He thought they should get
rid of the federal bank.
He was like proposing to
restructure everything and
they shot that dude right in
the fucking head. And if you don't think
that's what happened, you're crazy.
Because Lyndon Johnson took over after
him and he's basically just a version of
George Bush.
Just play it by the book.
Good old boy version of George Bush.
And they went deep into
Vietnam right afterwards.
And they stay there for a while.
There was,
there's no doubt in my mind that they
killed that guy who, I don't know.
I Dunno. I Dunno. But I have a feeling
he thought he was really president.
Thank you know,
I think there's,
there's certain people that
get this idea in their head,
they're going to get in there and they're
just going to fucking change shit and
it's really gonna happen. And then
they get there and they'd go, whoa.
So this is how it works.
You know,
we were talking about Colin
Powell yesterday and I've
always thought that he was
one of those guys that like probably
could have been president, you know,
and when you're running for president,
I think they don't let you know. Shit,
I don't. I was like, you have
a clue as to how it works.
And then finally one day you're,
you're actually an office and you realize,
oh my God,
like they take you into the matrix room
where you watch all the fetuses that are
connected to these metals,
suck fluid brains to feed this mothership.
And you look at it and you go, oh my
God, this is the truth. This is reality.
And then your hair starts going,
that's when your hair turns gray.
That's your hair starts calling Greg.
But what about, what about Powell though?
You feel like he felt like he was a,
another one of those guys. It's like,
he was like, you know, a real man of
character and a guy who you trust would,
his word was then all of sudden he's
in the Bush administration. He's like,
Jesus Christ,
just watching the whole thing go down
and eventually had to get out of there.
You know, it's like the, the whole
situation was crows. And then here,
here's the guy was a genuine war hero
and is watching this chicken hawks,
you know,
forced us into these weird fucking wars
and he's creepy parts of the world and
coming up with these stupid fucking
reasons why we're supposed to be there and
occupy la.
They had these pumpkin's in each pumpkin's
was carved with a different president
or person in office, you know, and
every time they made a bush wine,
it would get smashed like 30 minutes.
Like so every time they played,
the guy told me he would walk by they,
it was always smashed.
The Bush Bushman is always smashed.
He's a figurehead. That's funny.
It's all he is, man. He's
just a figurehead. He's
just a dude who got a job.
You know, it's a not that much
different than me hosting fear factor.
See Obama is in Los Angeles.
He went to Roscoe's chicken
and waffles and there's photos.
Unless that was an evil Twitter
prank. I am sorry if this,
if I, no, no, no, no, no.
He went, but he went, he went to Roscoe's
and it's hilarious. That places amazing.
Can't, I can't get into that
man. What? Chicken and waffles?
It's like fried chicken fried chicken.
It's not like they put syrup on the
chicken and stuff. I don't know.
You don't have to put Syrup on the chin.
My mind,
that's what it is and that's when I'm
like, fuck this. I'm not going dude.
It's all delicious.
[inaudible] crazy.
Listen chicken with a little bit of
syrup and some hot sauce. God Damn Son.
I'll give it a shot.
It's like instead of eating cornbread
with your fried chicken at 8:00 AM you
eating a waffle? The waffles you get
extra butter and extra syrup. All right.
I just just go crazy with that bitch.
Just appreciate the fact that it's
going to be two days worth of calories.
What you're supposed to eat in two days.
You're going to eat in one. Okay, I'll,
I'll, I'll hold off until it
was all clear. My schedule.
You know what you gotta do?
Just do one day of heavy rock lifting.
You know what you'd do is just,
there's a lot of videos online of
guys who pick up these stone circles.
You ever seen those guys
that come with atlas stones?
It's like a very particular type of
working out. They pick up these stones.
They're like, it's like a giant
medicine ball. Me a stone.
And they carry these around.
They're very difficult to carry around.
They actually make special like wristbands
and shit so that they don't get the
skin of their forearms ripped apart.
They have these big long like padded
wristbands and he's fucking gods walk
around carrying these stones and this
thing's supposed to just like burn 800
calories full on caveman
shit. Uh, you know,
that's like what charges up to
system to be the most strong suck.
Carrying something really
heavy and moving it somewhere.
That's the hardest thing to do.
It requires the whole body to be strong.
Every single aspect of the
body. Right? Very difficult.
So that's your move to do that and then
go Wah Roscoe's chicken and waffles.
He'll be so fucking
tired. He'd be like, man,
I don't give a fuck how
many calories are in that.
I'm going to eat the shit out of that
stuff. I want to sit in the Obama booth.
There probably is one now.
Right.
Do you think they have the keep it light
roped off with photos of him and then
they said they weren't going
to do anything special for
the fact that he visited
the location because
apparently Reagan and uh,
who's the other president who's
from California? Nixon. Yeah,
it came in Roscoe's all the time.
Really didn't,
they didn't change the menu or
do anything special for them.
They're not going to do that for Obama.
Yeah,
but he's black and I know
that's what you're supposed
to say. US the rope it off.
Not only should they rope it off,
they should get Madame Trudeau's to
create a wax image of him sitting there.
Awesome.
And there'd be a photo there and you have
the whole thing in cased in glass and
kids will wipe their boogers on
it. They put quarters, they stick
quarters in the last year trying to remove
one. And if you do, you get to keep it.
One of those things.
It should be a big candle.
Light him from the top every day and see
the melt. While he's eating his waffles.
A big candle. Yeah, like a big
candle statue where he is like,
oh yeah. If someone was wax,
statues are fucking incredible man.
It's really amazing. Yeah. Some,
some of them I can't like they'll show
the celebrity standing next to it.
I can't tell who. Sometimes,
yeah, I'm doing rivers.
One of them looks weird and the other one
doesn't. But you still are like, well,
which one is it though? Yeah. You
know what I mean? And photos that,
just to show you how weird photos are,
you know,
especially when the photos get photo
shopped and have you ever looked at
someone's photos? Like you know like
especially like professional hot chicks,
you know,
they'll have like a girl,
it's like a ring card girl or something
like that and there have her all touched
up or someone along those
lines. You barely can tell
what they really look like.
Like you have to actually see them in
person to see what they're really looked
like. Because in this photo that's not
a real representative of who they are.
It's like it's weird paint thing.
It's like you painted,
someone's painted over you. This is
not the real picture. This is your,
you're showing me a God damn cartoon. This
is like artwork. Well, I think three d,
three d photos. I don't know if you've
seen like those new cell phones.
Cell phones. Yeah. I mean this
camera has a three d in it,
so you can take a panoramic views in
three d and then you hook up to your three
d TV and it's just like amazing
and real. Yeah, it's ridiculous.
You can like move your
head and look around. Wait,
show me a picture on the three d camera.
I've never seen that.
You can't see it on this. Oh, you
got to put on a three D TV. Oh,
that's a way to make money. Yeah. What
is it? Where's the the end of that?
This three d thing to me, I don't like
the movies where I have to wear glasses.
They have to figure out to
put something over the screen,
but I'm thinking that this is
just a hiccup along the way.
So get the Nintendo three Ds.
It's a little game.
Boy It's in three d without glasses now.
So it's just kind of show you five,
10 years. Yeah, it's going to be good.
Those three d TVs where they have some
commercials or whatever playing in a bar
and it's, you know, it's kind of cool.
It's not as as good as it when you're
wearing the glasses and watching like
avatar.
Avatar is like the only kind of movies.
If it's like a big crazy action movie
like that, I'll wear this stupid glasses,
those things. Or they're uncomfortable.
Then you used to wearing glasses? Yeah.
It's to you. It's in everybody.
Even even I don't like him.
I mean I have to take them off every once
in a while and just get my face arrest.
You never thought about getting an
operation? No, I can't do it, dude.
Remember that movie fire in the sky back
in like the late eighties or early Ufo?
You a phone guys.
Travis Walton,
I think the guy's name is very famous
Ufo case. And they showed, like,
I remember watching the trailer
when I was a kid and they were like,
the aliens were probing him in just the
needle was coming towards his eye and he
was freaking out and I just went,
I don't want anyone to ever touch my eye.
And that stuck with me since I was a kid.
I was born, I had contacts for a while.
That took me a while to, to start
doing contacts. I, I hated it.
They scare the fuck out of you son Travis
Walton. You, yeah. That's the guy's,
he's working as a logger
in the woods in 1975. Yeah,
in Arizona, Flagstaff.
And he was pulled out
into the fucking sky.
I used to have that poster in my room.
Huge banner like would get like banners,
you know, you're doing poster
here, uh, for the movie theaters.
And they would throw them away,
but they would,
you'd have to have them if you were,
you worked at the movie theater.
So I get all the cool ones and firing
the sky was like right on my wall right
when I walked in. Wow. That was a
dope fucking movie about abduction.
That was a fun movie, man.
Those, those alien movies
scare the shit out of me, man.
They still do. It's so easy
to say, AH, they're full of
shit. I don't believe them.
It's so easy to say that
because it doesn't happen
every day because it doesn't
happen every day. It's so easy to go.
Sad. It's fucking bullshit. Right?
But could you imagine if it
actually was happening to you?
How wonderful a fucking freak out
that would be. Like, Holy Shit.
They're real.
You're flying into the fucking sky,
into the space ship and they're
probing you and you're like,
[inaudible] real and you're not gonna
be able to tell anybody about it.
Well, this was one of the best movies
at sort of representing that, that fire,
this guy moving, because it really
did represent that feeling of like,
you like you. Like that guy really
did seem like he was stuck. I mean,
it was a terrifying
whatever the fuck happened.
Whether or not they they're full of
shit or not. I don't know. I mean,
but the character in the movie, if that
was real, what a terrifying experience.
But that movie was like a recount
of that Guy Story and experience.
But even movies like he t ski, they
still, it still scares the shit out of me.
I,
there was like my parents' bedroom was
around the corner or are there a bathroom
was around the corner and their bedroom
and every once we had a big family,
so I'd have to use her bathroom every
once wants while I was scared to death,
like as a little kid,
I thought fucking Iti would be sitting
on the toilet taking a shit or something.
I just,
kids think weird things and even to
this day I'll go home and I just, Eh,
I'm hesitant to even go in that bathroom.
I'm like,
I know eating is not going to be here,
but I still don't want to just walk
around the corner. What if it was white?
Do what if it was white t dragging
a leg? Like Zombie style. Wow.
He's made, eats he creepy. Did they should
make an Iti horror movie. Why he eats,
he's a lovable little character.
Was supposed to be. Yeah,
that was a little grittier. And then
gives you saw the thing last night. Oh,
how was that thing? Prequel dude.
It's not getting good reviews,
but it's fucking good. I did want to
see it just because I love the thing.
I don't know. I don't know what
rotten tomatoes gave it, but um,
sometimes he can't trust
that stuff, man. I mean,
I think trust in the car with some things,
but then there's other shit.
33%, man. They say they're saying
it sucks. I don't get it. I mean,
I was pretty sober actually. Sober. Yeah.
I had a glass of wine. That's it. Um,
but it was good, man. It's good. Look,
I'm a big fan of the John
Carpenter version of the
Kirk Douglas or Kurt Russell
version. Yeah. That's a good fucking
movie. That's fun. It's still holds up.
I watched that movie recently, like
a month or so ago. Still holds up.
That's solid. That's a solid
fucking movie. This movie was not
quite as good as that. First of all
because, um, I don't, I didn't quite,
the girl who was the lead is, she was
okay. She is her name. Good. I don't know.
I don't know her name.
She's okay.
But I think she's wasn't Mary
Elizabeth Winstead. That's her name.
So it wasn't a Kurt Russell. Kurt Russell
just brought so much to that park.
Her fucking Russell.
Then that's Kurt Russell in his prime
dude with holding onto a fucking stick
grenades with a blow torches hand. Fucking
with all that, the ice in his face.
I'll pull this whole fucking place
and you're like, Whoa, that's intense.
This district never hit that kind
of a, Oh my God, I'm about to die.
It was like she's around
aliens and craziness and the,
but still somehow or another,
she's like Dwayne to composed for me.
You mean to me, I think everybody should
have been really freaking the fuck out.
And I just, I, it just,
it didn't have that,
that's where the effects and
everything fucking insane.
Fucking insane. Sex were amazing,
man. The effects were incredible.
Whether they can do now is, well,
first of all it's a prequel. So it's,
it's basically what happens and it takes
place in [inaudible] 82 so it's all
what happens right before the
Kurt Russell version of sure.
So I dunno if they're going to Redo
that one. I hope they don't honestly.
Cause there's no need to just come
up with a new fucking idea. Please.
They probably will. The dude, everything's
getting remade though, if they redo it.
And so it's really,
it's really a shit trick because yeah,
you'll go back to see ky Kang,
the fourth remake of King Kong,
but you know he's going to fucking die
at the end. It's still the same story.
So you're just going to trick me with
a bunch of new shit in the middle that
wasn't in the original one.
So you're basically making your own
movie for the middle. You have a very,
very flimsy guidelines. Got To
pick up King Kong, grab bag,
bring them back to America.
You figure it out.
Then she's supposed to be there and
sacrifice. She's gotta be blonde.
You got to have a lot of
naked black checks and nobody
cares about con grabs and
then you get them and everything
else you can make up on your own.
So every version is, that's what
we're, we're, we're tuning in for,
we're tuning in for the shit that
they made up. It's like, yeah,
we know what's going to happen.
He's going to climb the empire state
building is going to get shot down.
He's going to die. That's the end. What do
you, what are you creating in there? Oh,
well we've got is this and
now he's going to battle with,
he's fucking kick his black.
I want to see super racist movie.
King Kong is,
I want to see Johnny English reborn
Johnny English. We see it. Mr. Bean.
No,
I was never big into Mr. I wasn't either,
but my little brother loved that and
so if I want her to hang out with him,
we'd watch mister. He loved all
that British shit and so we'd,
I'd watch Mr. Bean and after it was
hard growing on me, man. I'm like,
it's so stupid.
It's funny.
It's so stupid that it finally
becomes funny. And then I was,
I don't remember what
movie I was watching,
but the trailer for Johnny English came
out and I was laughing throughout the
whole fucking thing. Man. It's so
funny. I can't wait to see it dude.
We're going to have
Shane Smith from vice TV.
Come on.
The guy who goes to the lady boys
and the guy went to Liberia. Oh cool.
I tweeted him today and he tweeted, he's
going to, he's going to do the podcast.
He's in Beirut right now filming. Who
knows what kind of fuck with the lady boy.
Like he goes to Thailand and gets a
lady boy ever heard of the vice guide to
travel? No Fun at the best
one. It's on MTV now. Ryan is,
I would have told him, you
know, I only watch on Netflix,
so it's one of the best fucking exposé.
What's the best way to describe it?
New shows.
It's like a documentary online sort of a
show where they do a bunch of different
things. Like one of the guys is whenever
they have some sort of a drug situation,
they have one guy who's like
a serious fucking cycad.
He's like massively into psychedelics
and he's like super, super,
like uh,
educated about them and he sits down
with Sasha soul gin and they go over the
various thousands of different known
psychedelic compounds and human use and
it's just incredible shit.
He went to the jungle and did Iowasca
with the natives and I mean they have
incredible shows.
They went to Liberia and literally they're
in a whorehouse in Liberia where it
was like a dollar or it might've been
less than a dollar to have sex with
somebody. Yeah, it's increased. I mean in
these guys go there, they go everywhere.
They go to the Congo, they go everywhere,
it's nuts. And he went to North Korea.
This Guy Shane Smith went to North Korea.
They went to the Thailand one.
He's hanging out with lady boys.
Like they picked up some lady boys and
brought them back and we're sitting in
the tub with them, hang out with them,
I think. I think I saw that. Was that,
was that it also a documentary or is this
just on his show? It's just the show.
It's just, I don't know. I don't know
the history of it and that's what a,
why it'd be great to have him on
because I don't know how it got founded,
but these guys have fucking balls,
man.
They're savages and I've been a big
fan of their work for a long time.
And one of them,
my favorite one is the one where they go
up to visit that guy that lives a deep,
deep, deep in Alaska. That guy
that lives a member, um, he,
he lives alone with his wife and they
have like this little log cabin in the
middle of nowhere and like North
East Alaska, North East Alaska,
like way the fuck up there,
you know,
where there's nobody man and this
guy and they'd go hang out with him.
And he's just every day hunting
caribou fishing for fish.
Just every day is just foraging food and
these are bright guy and he's been up
there for like 30 years and he believes
that's like the only way people are
supposed to live.
And that's the best way to be happy.
Like he's super content up
there. He's like, you know,
I don't have any depression.
I don't have any problems. You know, I
just, I, I, this is what I like to do.
I like to hunt and gather and he's
that and he's not a dummy man.
It's a really fascinating fucking show.
And in the middle of the show they have
to kill a bear because the bear, uh, was,
uh, getting out his food,
you know, cause he's,
he shoots Caribou and then he
has to hang the Caribou. Right.
And sometimes they have a problem.
You're hanging in his fucking care about
and bear [inaudible] brown and when
they come around you have to kill him.
Yeah. So in the middle of the night,
they're chasing him with
cameras. Waste, fucking shooting.
It's bare. It's wild dog.
Cause they're in the middle of nowhere.
I mean someone has to come by and drop
[inaudible] goods for
them out of a parachute.
That's the only way that he's getting
a gooey Hannah. Yeah. Fuck. Well,
if he's been there for 30 years,
maybe you should.
Maybe he left like in the 80s where it was
like, oh look, set tapes suck. You know,
fucking Atari. 2,600 this is
lane. I gotta get Outta here.
You know how to be happy. Yeah,
I'll go out in the middle of Alaska.
I wonder if he's travels to like at
main city or peaches in a long time.
It has been. But as of the show,
as of the vice guide to travel,
I don't think he had ever
even seen nine 11 yeah,
I don't think he'd ever
seen the towers fall
check checkout TVs now.
You know,
like maybe he's just had
no idea how awesome it is.
Maybe. Maybe, but maybe he's
right. Maybe like, you know, we,
our bodies are still the same bodies.
I mean,
you've got to think that there's a
bunch of like reward systems that are in
place to ensure that people stay alive.
And for the longest time,
for a period of thousands and
thousands and thousands of years,
the way we stayed alive
was hunting and gathering.
That's the way we stayed alive.
We went out and we,
we killed our own food and we caught her
own fish and we grew our own fruit and
vegetables.
And I think to this day we're probably
wired with a reward system that enforces
that. Like when you, when you do that,
it probably feels really
good because I know a lot of,
I used to be hooked on fishing.
I used to love fishing,
I used to fish all the time. It's a
very primal thing. Like the, the, the,
the excitement of catching a fish.
It's very,
it's very much wired system
as his hunting, supposedly,
I haven't been hunting,
but they all say that people can't, you
know, they all say that it's, it's, it's,
it's wired into man.
And that's why people to this day,
even though it's easy to get food, still
go hunting, not even just for, you know,
for the meat and the, for the fact
that they need to meet to stay alive.
But just for, for the actual excitement of
it because it's, you know, it's, it's, uh,
there's an exciting thing
about procuring your own food,
going out and getting your own food and,
and sustaining yourself through your
own work instead of sustaining yourself
through a supermarket where
he just kind of empty.
We pay for things and just consume them.
You know?
And some people really believe that the,
the real true way to be happy is to,
I mean,
it's not very progressive
because eventually we have
to evolve past the state,
but some people think they're,
the true way to be happy is to live
as if people were living, you know,
thousands of years ago when
there was no electricity.
And then all this technology,
even though we are enjoying in it,
it's enhancing our life. We're not
really wired to, to use this stuff.
We're not wired to be influenced
by it. You know, like televisions,
we were talking about TVs and movies.
You think about the
influence that a film has.
Think about the influence that that has
compared to any influence that you would
actually see in the natural world.
And compared to what you're supposed
to be receiving the the human brain,
like as you're developing and
learning and going through life,
you're supposed to be impressed by
certain things. Acts of bravery.
He's supposed to be impressed.
Character and press by leadership and
all these things are supposed to impress
you because you should eventually take
on that role yourself. If you're a man,
you should actually develop to a person
of character and respect and leadership.
Hopefully if you ever will
want to become the leader.
But until then you follow the leader,
you follow the Alpha cause that's
the one that has all the information.
They've already lived a long life.
They've learned some things and if you
want to stay alive, you follow him.
Now this is what's programmed in our head,
but instead of that,
what we're getting in,
this is fucking a hundred foot screen.
We were wearing glasses
that make everything three
d and this paralyzed dude's
gonna fuck this blue chick.
You know,
and it's like our bodies and our
brains almost can't process that,
that much bullshit. It's like, even
though we know it's just a movie,
there's certain parts of our subconscious
or even our consciousness that I think
are programmed to expect movie
like results from real life.
And when you don't have
anything like that,
when you realize that the
reality of it is, well no,
I'm just some weird person who gets an
a metal fucking box and it's on rubber
wheels and I ride over this hard surface
to this same spot where I sit in a
cubicle every fucking day
and repeat over and over.
There's no Sandra Bullock movie for
me, man. There's no, there's no,
there's no beautiful ending. Like
what the fuck, man, this is reality.
But we're so programmed by this idea of,
of,
of happy endings and this idea of easy
to follow storylines where it all works
out in the end that I,
you know, and it's, it's,
it's a, it's a trip. It's a trip to,
to wonder whether or not we have created
something in our mass media and our
media,
in our television or movies we have
created something that influences us far
beyond what we can control.
And almost like that's how it's,
it's difficult for people to truly
understand people anymore. It's so,
I'm just like,
people aren't even influencing people.
People's creations are influencing people.
Artificial bullshit is influencing
people, you know? And the,
the actual what you know who the
human is below all of it. It's very,
very difficult to distinguish for a
lot of people. Wrap your head. I had
about that bitch. So I'm
reading the biography of Steve
Jobs, I think I mentioned,
but they're talking,
they're the one cool thing that they
kind of hinted at was the future.
How Steve Jobs thought that
he had mapped out the next TV.
He broke the,
the idea for the next TV.
And so there's like these rumors now that
apple might start making their own TV
sets. Like, you know,
like, well tell you what,
that Apple TV program is fucking great
man. I love it. Oh, the apple TV.
The actual box. It's a little
tiny ass box man. Yeah, I got it.
And so I was thinking with the,
with how good Siri is, what,
what could imagine being able to tell
your TV like a find me family guy Thursday
record,
turn the channel Hbo Record that you know
and how it's probably going to mix in
with the Siri into the TV.
Can you, wouldn't that be
awesome to be able to just,
yeah,
that's inevitable
I think. Why isn't it like
that? Like if you use connects,
obviously moving that
direction like we're going to,
we're going to get that
real quick, right? Oh.
Have you ever seen Bill Gates' house?
Have you ever seen no, there's,
there's a bunch of videos.
There was actually a thread about it
on my message board a few weeks ago.
I think I'm amazing house and you
wear a pin when you entered the room.
When you get into his house,
you put a pin on and this
pin has a microchip in it
and every room it recognizes
you. It knows that you're the
one who entered into the room.
So it changes the movies or a track
changes, right? The images on the wall,
it changes the atmosphere,
the temperature.
What's funny is that, so that, that,
that's so funny how that's
old technology already.
Cause even with connect with x box,
you have it in your house
and you walk in the room,
it detects your face and in
logs you win and connect.
Does it start playing music
and change the light? No,
but it logs you in and then like you
can have like your like Netflix and he'd
sit there with your hand and you string
through the movies with your hand.
Kind of like you can go through
Netflix with your hand. Yeah.
Yeah. Crazy. Imagine now
lazy people, even more lazy.
It's not incredible though.
I mean that is a big jump.
Big Jump.
The ability that we have right now to
sit in front of the TV and swipe things
with your hand in space.
Now imagine not having, didn't move
your hand now just being like theory,
find me this.
Maybe you do this kit.
I was just getting used
to the retinal scan.
Like that blows my mind that
you could put your eye up.
I mean when have you used that
on a laptop? I've never used it.
I just see it in movies. I'm like,
what the fuck is that? I love real.
They have it for life
tops now. They have fingerprint
ones and they have retina scan ones.
Wait, they have retina scan
one. I've only seen a finger.
When do it like to log in or I'm
just security. I know they do it for,
they have my gym 24 hour fitness I,
that's how I sign it.
Yeah, that's some of the, we don't
work out in the same gym, but yeah,
I never see you there. I know I'm 24
hour fitness. Which one did you go to?
Santa Monica.
Yeah.
I can't find this. I might've made that
up. How to buy retina biometrics. Camera?
No, they have them. I don't know
if they have it on laptops yet.
It wouldn't surprise me if there's like
a thing you plug into the back of your
computer sits on top.
You'd do like a retinal scan.
Then it brings up your
profile or something,
but then you know people would worry.
What if somebody cut your eyeballs out?
That's what I'm always at like with a
pencil, like you jam a pencil in there,
pop that sucker out and then you get in
behind the security wall that you're,
you shouldn't be,
but you got the eyeball and then uh,
you strapped the nukes to yourself
and pull the pin and yeah, that's it.
Getting kind of jealous.
My uh,
girlfriend's brother's building a computer
right now and he just bought his new
case on this case.
It looks like alien ware
Jealous Cause you're, you're, no,
because I missed those days buying like
you sit there and find the coolest case.
He Pan and you find which motherboard
that you've done before. Yeah.
Just pretend he's doing it
now. Yeah, I just missing
it. Yeah. It's kind of funny. I forget
that I get, and then there's like a,
that new game that just came out to a
battlefield three and there was showing
how bad acid looks and how I'm
thinking, man, I wish, I wish,
I almost want to build like some stupid
gaming computer so you don't get as much
free time as it is. I know I need
to clone people. No you don't.
You just enjoy less things.
But I'm with you on the computers.
I used to love the satisfaction of
putting together a computer, you know,
punching him, putting the
mush, the motherboard,
punching in the ram, you know,
setting everything up. And then the moment
it turns on you boot up windows like,
yes, what the fuck do I don't Miss Jumper
setting. So Jumpers, settings in the ass,
if they still have jumpers,
settings have tweezers and used to have
to like move these little things like
what the fuck were those things?
But how about that shit?
And then it was like primes where your
graphics card would interfere with your
sound card.
Like what was that called?
Like in that box bios you had
to change frequencies and shit.
Oh that was so knowing that shit you,
but I think you learn how
much does this one work?
My appreciate Max so much. I love the
fact that I don't have to do anything.
You know,
you could say that it's a computer for
people weren't power users or whatever
you want to say.
Let the fact that I don't have to do shit.
It knows what you're wanting to do.
It's like, Oh, do you want to do that?
I'll just do it for you.
Yeah, it's like that.
I Dunno if it's like a
sketch or something. It was
just like move. I got it.
You know? And I don't have to go into
the registry and tweak the settings.
Like what the fuck are you
talking about man? I'm like,
what am I even doing in there? I don't
know what to talk about this. This.
I've talked about it before.
This is the best coconut water I've ever
had in my life. Yeah. I tell everybody,
everybody says coconut water
tastes like Shit. Yeah.
And I never understood why they said
that until I tried other stuff and I,
these people are not paying me a dime.
This is all just honesty.
I think they have a great proxy to o
is the Shit. And I asked him, I said,
why is your coconut water so much better?
Cause it's really delicious. I go,
do you add sugar? And they go, no, no, no.
What we do is we get our coconuts
from a single plantation in Thailand,
they own the plantation.
And so this plantation in
Thailand is the apparently date.
The Thais have the sweetest coconuts,
real delicious coconut taste,
and very sweet. And that's
the key. So that's, this is,
I don't know what other companies
get their shit from Thailand too,
but you'd get it from them because
that's where c two o gets it there.
They're fucking, let's talk about coconut
water. And they're like, oh, I love it.
So I went to whole foods and,
and I bought three different kinds because
I figured I wouldn't like one of them
or whatever, just to try them out. I hated
all three of them. Yeah. This is amazing.
It's amazing when people, people think
I'm exaggerating and like I said,
no one's giving me a fucking dime.
I swear to God.
There's definitely bad coconut water
that other kind of you had a couple of
weeks ago. I did not even want to finish.
And that's, yeah, this is delicious.
This stuff is fucking, it's, and it's
so good for you, man. It's really good.
Like for when you're working out,
like it's a good like
natural isotonic beverage, whatever the
fuck isotonic means, whatever it is,
it's good.
Joe, do you know if it's
okay, you have a Vitamix?
Is it okay to mix like vitamins into
your drinks to like crush them into the
drinks with? Is that something that be
okay? Well, I guess you could do that,
but why would you do that when you can
just take them? Yeah. I don't know.
But what do you, uh, what are
you eating with vitamins? No,
I mean like I do like a bunch of, like
one of those packs of vitamins every day.
I've been throwing it into the,
he could do that. Sure. You
could do that, but you know,
you got to wonder how much of it is
going to get stuck to the walls. Right.
How much of it is actually in your,
you know, right. Yeah. I don't know.
You know what kind of,
what kind of vitamins you're taking
fish oil? Uh, it,
it's just one of those packs you buy
where it has a big pack of different kinds
and you take like a plastic baggies?
No, it's uh, from Costco. Yeah.
Do you notice any difference
when you take vitamins? Yeah,
my ps really yellow and the smells
bad. Smells bad. It smells like pee,
like hardcore p more waters.
A study recently the, I mean there's
always studies one way or another,
but this study recently had
said something about, uh,
there were doubting the efficacy of a
large doses of vitamins and they were
saying that may even be
harmful for some people.
It's really interesting because I,
I always wonder how the fuck do you
judge that? How do you figure that out?
Well, it's probably like
anything, if you overdo like a B,
12 or a c or something like that,
it's probably not good for you.
How much of it is placebo then?
You know, like with vitamins? Yeah.
It's like how much is, is this
vitamin C actually helping me? Well,
it's also like w how much do you need
as opposed to how much other people
though. It's not like it's
crazy, you know it's not,
I think it's just basic stuff to
you like fish away. I'll d whatever,
fish oil and d. Well you know
you don't eat and healthy either.
So for you and pretty healthy how to be
the problem is I only eat once a day.
Why do you do that? Well, like
today, you know, I wake up,
I get some coffee I can't eat before I
have my coffee. You know, coffee? Yeah.
It doesn't work. Like I can't eat unless
you get an upset stomach sort of thing.
I just zero hunger like it's,
it sounds gross.
Like I would probably
get sick if I try to eat.
If I have my coffee for some ranchers
then and then I usually do something like
this. Like I'm doing this podcast right
now. I probably will get home put, put,
do the podcasts,
put it up online and then probably eat
around seven or eight o'clock at night.
Wow. Yeah. So that's, I mean, my problem
is like last night I had, you know,
skinless grilled chicken,
lettuce, tomatoes, fruit. You know
my question when I read these things,
when you read a study that says
more evidence against Vitamin News,
my fucking tin foil hat always
goes up. And they always go, well,
how do I not know that this isn't some
shit that the pharmaceutical companies
have come up with? You
know, to discourage it.
They found out that if you take vitamins,
you're less likely to get certain amount
of things that we need drugs to cure.
And so they're trying to
cycle squash pharmaceutical
industry.
You know,
the pharmaceutical industry was trying
at one point in time and they have
recently tried it again,
they're there.
They've talked about doing this where
they want to regulate vitamins and
minerals and they want to make it
so they're only by prescription.
So they'd go,
you're going to cost a lot more and
you're going to have to get them from
pharmaceutical companies.
So instead of these companies like GNC
or all these different places that sell
vitamins,
those will essentially be taken over by
the pharmaceutical companies and their
massive amounts of profits will in
turn be absorbed by the pharmaceutical
industry.
The pharmaceutical SuiteGL industry,
by using the American government will
essentially jack the whole nutritional
market and take it over.
And they tried this in the past.
They tried to do it under
the name nutriceuticals.
That's what they're going to,
um,
call vitamins.
And they were going to make it so
that if you wanted to get vitamin C,
you had to get a fucking prescription.
You had to go through the whole rigmarole,
you had to go to a doctor, you had
to get a prescription. It's, it's,
it's disgusting. It's, it's,
it's really terrifying.
And so whenever I see studies like this,
and I know that this was a
very recently proposed thing,
I always wonder if they're
jocking for positioning.
I always wonder what the fuck they're
doing. I really do. Oh, really?
Do you know? And then you know, once
they take position they'll say, well,
if you get FDA approved
vitamins and minerals,
it's been shown that moderate doses of
FDA approved vitamin and minerals can
actually prevent certain diseases.
This is one of the benefits of
having the government take over the
pharmaceutical industry is that we're
able to run tests on them and get
conclusive results using taxpayer money.
Now everybody can be safe,
could take government approved vitamins.
So when I hear stories like this,
I don't necessarily, I don't
believe it. I don't know.
I don't know who's putting
these fucking things together.
And I used to think that all these
universities where beyond reproach,
I just think,
well you know,
if it's a university study for sure that
means until I watched inside job and
then I realized how the whole system
works with university professors in the
fucking studies that they put out.
And then the cushy jobs did they get
afterwards and they make millions of
dollars by playing ball with
everybody. Did you see inside job? No,
but I heard about exactly
what you're talking about.
It just makes me wonder like,
is there an honest,
is there any honesty left in the world
for anything when you're dealing with
that kind of money? I think the money
for the professors, millions of dollars.
All of a sudden they're
working from Merrick, you know,
and they're developing some fucking,
you know,
brain drug for American making millions
and millions of fucking dog for them.
It's like the, the numbers are too
high. Yeah. You know, I wonder,
I wonder if there is anything
on, on corrupt. Just,
I think the only thing that's going to
save people honestly is there's going to
have to be some APP that's created
eventually that lets us see the truth.
Always see the truth and anything.
No one's ever going to
be able to lie to anyone.
All your motives will
be exposed right away.
You'll be forced to tell the truth
and then, and only then are we,
we're going to really get it together
because half the problem with what it's
fucked up about human is the lies and the
bullshit in the real motivation behind
things. Whether it's operation
Northwoods or whether it's, you know,
them trying to fucking take
over the phone. The vitamin
industry under the guys,
they're trying to help us.
Nobody's, let me tell you something.
Nobody's dying from fucking
vitamins. No body, no body,
a negligible amount. 10,000 people
die from fucking caffeine every year.
All right.
And I love coffee.
Who knows how many thousands of people
die from aspirins 400,000 die from
cigarettes. Just shut the fuck up,
right? If they're going after something,
they're going after it for money.
The federal government is not trying
to take over the cigarette industry.
They're not trying to give you only
government approves cigarettes.
You need a prescription to get cigarettes
cause we're worried about the dangers
of cigarettes.
They don't think twice about cigarettes
cause the tobacco company pays them
billions of fucking dollars.
Those dirty, dirty cunts.
So the truth APP is the way to go. We
need a truth APP, Brian, until you,
until somebody figures
out how to manipulate that
hack, it's money off of it.
Of course, the whole don't make it a
fucking bought bought for the truth APP.
What's the solution? Brian? I don't know.
Thinking about how crazy that it, if
you really think about it, it's there.
There's a creator,
there's somebody did that created the
human person and whatever and they had to
like take the eye and try to like
design the eye to make it the best,
most efficient I and somebody created
the nos like no, it has to be, you know,
has to have these filters of hair so
it collects dust before they inhale it.
You know,
it's amazing that they're pro there.
Is there somebody that sat around and
had to design every single part of the
human person? No, there's not one person.
It's not a jet team of scientists and
they created these robots and we're robots
and
you know, there's the question of whether
or not there's intelligent design.
There's some pretty intelligent people
that believe in intelligent design and a,
the idea behind it,
everybody has a big red flag when you
bring it up because it's been co opted by
religious groups and they,
they,
they use it to sort of promote the idea
in school that you can push religious
nonsense on kids because the real problem,
religious nonsense is not that.
It's not possible.
What they're saying is true.
It's that there's no evidence that it's
true. And they're basically just talking.
They basically just making up
a bunch of fucking stories.
Somebody wrote it down and you know,
they try to pretend that it's history
and they try to sell it to kids.
There's no fucking evidence. But it
doesn't mean it's not right. It doesn't,
it does. It doesn't mean that there
isn't, you know, at one point in time,
some benevolent you one power
that oversees everything.
But we have eyelashes to protect our eyes.
I mean,
with each piece of crocodiles, what
would they make? Komodo dragons.
Why would they make monkeys throw shit at,
you know,
so those were all like
revision B, c, d e. Well,
I think there's a, is there some sort
of an ecosystem but does anything,
it looks alien.
It's us.
If you really want it to make the argument
and there is this a logical argument
if you really want to make the argument
that there has been genetic engineering,
there's two animals that you'd make that
argument with dogs and people and dogs
and people both very
substantially in size and
shape and coloring and the
what the where they live on
the on the earth.
But you can make them fuck each other
and they can have babies no matter what.
They're all interchangeable. Midgets
can fucked Shaquille O'Neal, you know,
you can, you could figure out a way to
put it all together. It's, it's a way,
you know,
there's only people in dogs and we know
for a fact the only reason why dogs are
like that is cause
people fucked with them.
But people through selective breeding
and some sort of genetic engineering that
they're really don't know
and a bunch of people,
thank you have sent me a
bunch of documentaries on
dogs that a problem I'm not
going to watch. I just watched
one last night. Interesting.
Dogs dissect it or something like that.
It's something I'm from wolves. Yeah.
They come from words. But how like also
like when humans look at each other,
they like look from left to right
for some reason to like, uh,
to judge you or I forget
what it was about,
but that dogs also did it and then that
we actually think closer to the dogs and
most chimpanzees or, or monkey.
And it was really weird.
It was interesting to the see did
they only bark like it though?
They're not designed to bark Burgum.
They're designed a bark were like wolves
don't sit around and bark all day.
Right. Yeah. Where that dogs are trying
to communicate with humans and stuff.
It was really interesting. You know,
wolves communicate with people too.
If you have a wolf, the for a pet. I have
a friend that, uh, has, uh, two wolves.
He had three for awhile and the
wolves fucking talk to you, man.
You come home and you're like,
what's up dude? What's up
dude? They go, Whoa, whoa.
They look like they're all on wolves.
While there there's something, you know,
probably seven eighths Timberwolf they're
really tricky. The real tricky pets.
Like once you, you're around them, you
go, okay, well this isn't a dog dude. You,
you live with an animal,
you live with a totally different animal.
It's just not a dog. It's a wise we
a grizzly man. Shit man, it's close.
Except they don't really attack people.
I mean they can if they're treated
badly and if they're, you know,
if they're in a bad environment
for the most part was, you know,
Timberwolf seven I don't have
a problem with their master's,
at least in any dog could have a problem
with someone else. Another person,
little kids, sometimes scary. Do you
think the little kids aren't our animals?
It's a real danger.
Some of the funniest shit.
My Dad had a friend who would come over
the nicest guy in the world, but our dog,
Larry didn't like the sound of his voice
and she would just bark like crazy,
just Rah Rah Rah and,
and like try to attack him.
But she was the nicest dog to everyone.
And this dude for whatever reason,
just come over and she would attack him.
Wow.
He probably fucked her
when you weren't looking.
Probably it's probably was always
fucking that poor dog. But you know,
the idea is that human beings
were genetically engineered
by higher power that
something came down here
and genetically engineered.
That's why we look so different than
anything else on the planet. You know,
we are so different than any other
primate. Our skin is soft and fleshy.
For the longest time we've been using
tools to the point where we can't even
remember. We just have to Kinda like look
at old stuff and trying to figure out,
they have tools then how
think they had on that.
And they just recently moved it
back way, way, way, way, way back.
They moved the dawn civilization back
almost 6,000 years really recently because
they found this huge structure and go
Beckley, Tempe. And they,
they used to think that back then people
were just living in caves and they had
these 19 foot tall carved stone
columns with animals on them.
And then this is like 12,000 years ago.
So to put in perspective,
ancient Sumeria was thought to
be the cradle of civilization.
That was the oldest known civilization
that we knew of that 6,000 years ago in
Iraq.
This is 6,000 years older than that.
So to them in ancient Sumeria,
it was to them go Beckley Tapley
was like Sumeria is to us,
which is impossible to even
wrap your head around where it,
what is the Biblioteca?
It's,
it's called go Beckley Tepi and it's
in Turkey. It's really an amazing,
amazing stuff. Yeah. They just,
I mean this is recent. This was,
the guy found this in
the 1990s. He was a, uh,
some farmer and he's fucking
digging in his backyard and Turkey.
It's like a goat herder or some shit.
And he found like some thing sticking up.
It's like,
what the fuck is this?
And it turns out there's all these
giant fucking stone circles of the huge
columns and shit all on his land,
all his land and all done like way,
way,
way before they thought anybody
was doing anything like this.
They had to rewrite the whole
situation because of this stuff.
They thought people were just
hunter gatherers back then.
So there's still trying to attribute
it somehow to a hunter gatherers,
but it doesn't make sense. Right,
right. Temple. Yeah, good luck.
It's just fucking crazy.
Giant stone carved temple.
And you want to tell me
that people who made this,
we're just running around chasing animals.
It blows me away that over time,
that much dirt and just shit has just
piled up to cover that temple and that
it's just on some dude's farmland.
Well,
actually this one I think they
believe was covered over on purpose.
They believe that a, that someone at
some point in time actually covered it.
Oh really? Yeah, because because of the
nature of the dirt that's covering it,
they believe that it's,
uh,
it's actually a artificial that
someone brought it in and covered it.
Covered up the stone structures under
the ancient backhoe. Yeah. Ain't shit.
It's dogs. A lot of dudes who
listened to him. That's what it is.
That was your number one
resource back then? Yeah.
But the slaves who built the
pyramids, they're like, oh,
we've got another project was so,
so what we are talking about then was
like 12,000 years. That's how long,
long time ago.
But even then it just doesn't make sense.
Like how the fuck where did,
where did this animal come from?
How'd his hand will get so much
different than all these other monkeys?
How did to figure out tools,
how did it figure out language?
Why is it so different?
Its ability to communicate ideas that
just somehow or another the aliens came
down and said,
God,
you know how long it's going to take
for these fucking monkeys to ever figure
out anything. It could take billions
of years and it can never happen.
They could go extinct. Look,
they live outside. They
haven't even figured out five.
This might not ever work out.
They might catch some crazy infection
or there might be some spider that's
fucking toxic that likes to live in
their sheets and eats them alive.
You know there might be no chance
of these monkeys making it.
How about we do this?
How about we just inject a little of
our DNA and just spice up the process a
little bit. And that's the
idea. That's the idea that,
and that's the,
I'll also the idea of,
there's a guy named Zechariah Cichon
and he wrote all these books about this
shit about the ancient Sumerians had
written this very controversial stuff,
but it's all about the Sumerian text and
how the Annunaki we're on this planet
that's in an elliptical
orbit and every 3000,
600 years it comes near our planet and
they hop off and fucking come hangout
with us for a little,
show us some shit and then disappeared.
And then by the time 3000, 600 years
rolls around, we forgot about it again.
When are we do probably like a week
or so if you just got to get online,
probably December 21st, 2012. Yeah,
right. That's probably the, uh,
one of the people think that there's
the people that believe there's a planet
out there and it's headed our way.
They can't see it yet,
but it's getting our way and it's giant.
What's really scary is that that
definitely can happen. You know,
planets get hit by planets all the
time in the solar system. Right.
Or in the universe rather.
It hasn't happened.
We know it's happening in certain parts
of our solar system I can think is
Uranus is spinning upside down.
Is it
one of them? One of the planets
is spinning like the, the,
the ravens are going the wrong way
and they believe more than likely it's
because it got fucking
nails by another planet.
They just fly into each other
and shit. Oh, that was hilarious.
That happened at Earth Earth. One in earth
too. That's how the moon was created.
Earth one like 4 billion years ago got
hit with some Mara size planet and just
slammed into us and knocked off a
fucking slab and that created the moon.
Useless Astronomy Mano La.
That was your last, uh, Thursday night.
Yes. Yeah. On the Internet
with this. No, man, I,
I've been obsessed with
all this shit forever.
That's what I love about you dude.
You're able to like retain
all this shit like from,
I don't remember anything man.
Well you would if it was
interesting to you. This, this,
this stuff is absolutely
fascinating to me.
So I retain all sorts of stupid
shit when it comes to that.
I find it fascinating,
but I'll get into an article and I'll
read like three sentences and then go make
a sandwich and I forget what I was,
you know, get some Alpha brain new
system from rain sun. Don't get scared.
Don't be scared of the Alpha brain.
Eat shroom tech and your feet.
Would you be for brain in your
head and you're not working?
Do you sit around and watch
documentaries? Like, do you ever,
do you ever like purposely sit down and
go, okay, I'm going to watch grizzly man.
I'm gonna get some fucking material out
of this. Do you ever do you do shit?
I don't sit down to get
material? No. You'd never know.
Do you write when, when you,
uh, write your standup, do you sit
down and go, come on over, sit down.
I'm gonna write some stand
up. Yeah. You do. Yeah. Do
you force yourself to do that?
Yeah.
How many times a week to try to do it.
Uh, if it's good, it's five
days a week. Wow. Good for you.
And it went from 45 minutes a
day to an hour because I figure,
I felt like an hour was out of reach,
but I could do 45 minutes and then a
lot of times I would end up going hour
anyway,
so then I would just go for
an hour. But then, you know,
when Shit just starts getting busy,
I don't sit down and maybe once a week,
you know, but so much. Right.
I don't sit down and go,
I'm going to go create all this stuff.
A lot of it's just like going over old
stuff, tightening it up, make it funnier.
Have like, I have a bank of old
shit that I'll open up a file.
You're gonna never did anything.
Is there anything in there?
I got that.
I got the tape recorder that I always
am still rocking a tape recorder.
It's digital.
It's great cause it uh,
I just dump it in and it's an MP
three and then I listened to it on my
headphones or whatever.
I used to do that until I
got an iPhone and the iPhone,
iPhone voice recorder
app is so much better.
I can actually write in the name of
what I thought of like that, you know,
a blue smurf, Dick boom.
And then that's like,
you look at it and you can go right to
the voice note and you can have Siri play
it. You could have say, Siri, play
me Blue Smurf Dick and it'll play it.
I just got the iPhone now so I don't even,
I mean I know about that stuff but
he just got it. Are you a newb?
I'm a newb voice notes is in there.
It's free. It's a free APP. I know,
but I mean it's like I have this, I spent
the money for this. I'm going to use it.
Cause it doesn't throw that into
the crowd when someone angers you.
That's the other cool thing about that.
The iPhone is you can
record all of your sets.
I record all my stats on the
voice thing and it doesn't,
you just make sure that you put it on
airplane mode so it doesn't get a phone
call.
Cause if you get a phone
cause there was a good that it'll kill
you. It'll kill the recording. Oh really?
Stops it. Stops it debt. Use Evernote. If
you haven't started that, that's awesome.
It's a program where you can type
your notes up on your computer and it
automatically just sinks it with your,
your,
you have to have mobile me
for that though. No, no.
This is a free app in the APP store
and evernotes on evernote.com I think.
And yeah,
Evernote
work with um, the, the new voice software
on apple. Can you talk to Evernote?
Evernote has its own recorder built
into the program, but it's a recording.
It's not a translation.
It's not transcript transcription.
So I don't think so because the
droids have like transcription.
Should they have it to different things?
Yeah, they have with dragon I think,
but or you can do it on Siri. You know
what I'm saying is like you don't know.
I don't know. Someone out there
will know. But if you can,
that would be a good move for Evernote.
We could talk to it and actually
writes it down, you know,
instead of just recording it.
Yeah.
Cause then it wouldn't be any
better than voice recorder. Right.
You know Neal Brennan, do you know Neil
Brown? Huh? He had a great line about,
about having something like
a piece of paper or you know,
having a voice recorder when
you're a comic and he goes,
it's like I'm fishing for ideas and I
catch one in my net and if I don't write
it down, it's going to get away. You
know? It was like, but I write it down,
then I've caught it forever. It's
in my net. And I'm like, yeah, yeah.
It is like sometimes it's just the
discipline to sit down and write shit out
because the discipline to write shit
out is such a different mindset than the
mindset that comes up
with something silly.
Like you'll come up with
something hilarious and
ridiculous and that mindset is
just like this shit talking.
Good time fucking around mindset.
And then the other mindset is we might
be able to make money off this year and
it's just this little piece of gold we
got here. Make sure what type this up.
You know, it's a, it's funny
how uh, they're, they're,
they're both completely different
mindsets where it's like we know a lot of
funny people that like never
write their shit down. You know,
it's, I'm a better comic when I
do that and when I don't, I, I
deck man. I always tell everybody that
man, I was like, just two jobs man.
One job is performing. There's another
job. It's writing. You have to do both.
If you just try to come up with only
shit on stage and that's improving it on
stage, you can do that. And I've done that
for years. I did that for a long time.
I did, I just only worked
on my material on stage.
But this was like pre internet days,
you know,
this is much less people
that have access to your,
your material if you want to like
continue to process new shit,
come up with new good stuff.
You've got it right.
I got it. Yeah, that stuff is fine, but
if you are sitting down to do it too,
that's,
that's the way to go because it doesn't
exclude the ability to add live on stage.
This whole ton of bitch only writes on
stage. She told me, you know who that is?
He's just a comic, but it's she suck.
No, she's funny. She's hilarious.
She's really funny. Um, but
she only writes on stage and
I was just like, I can't,
she goes, well, I just can't sit
down and write. And it's like,
well you got to force yourself to do that.
Yeah.
Our nobody wants to know why
are you so never read a stage.
I used to tell him my or only
write on stage. I just tell him,
did you sit down and write
man or road on storage?
That's not writing, dude,
that's performing. You're
lazy. But this is the same guy.
It didn't clean the sheets for six
months. Sure. Literally, there's,
when you're doing a bit like I'll do bits
that I've done for years and all of a
sudden I come up with a new tag on stage.
Like that new tag was only
going to come out on stage,
not when I'm sitting down
in my underwear or whatever.
Yeah.
And isn't it weird that you forget the
tag and then you'll be back in the bit
and go, Oh, here it is.
It goes right here. Yeah.
Taglines for folks who don't know, they're
like a little gift from the universe.
So like you'll be on stage,
you've got this perf,
I've had jokes that I thought were,
I was like, I really liked this joke.
And then you have a tagline, boom. And
it's like, oh, now this joke's a weapon.
And then now this joke is just hit
some critical mass. You're like,
this joke is good, it's done. No it's
not. I've never done. Do you, um,
do you have like a schedule?
Like what you try to do,
like put out shit for
like a couple of years,
put it down on a CD and then like try
to write a whole new schedule or a whole
new act. No, I want to
get to that point. Yeah.
I've been recently just recently
doing that over the last few years.
My last few specials have done that where
I've banned in one and start another
one. It's a good US forces you to get
after it. Yeah. Cause right now, dude,
I'm still doing shit from my
second year of comedy. Which Elle,
how long have you been in when we met
you? Uh, when did we meet? Like 2004,
2005, somewhere around there. Had
I done last comic yet? Do you know,
know before last time. And I think it
was like 2005 or it might've been four.
It was, uh, it was during the dark
joy Diaz days and what it meant.
So Joey Diaz,
I've told this story before,
I used to only bring one guy on
the road with me because you know,
I do like an hour and 20 minutes or
whatever. I don't really, I only need one.
And you know,
it's fun traveling with one comic
sometimes when you're traveling with two
comics, like I got to get organized.
Like we lost Brendan Walsh in Houston.
Perfect example. We got up in the
morning, Brendan Walsh, buzzard awake.
He just wouldn't fucking wake up.
Call this room when,
so we're trying to figure out how
to get the fuck to the airport.
And we had a band in Brendan Walsh
we had even behind but with jelly.
I just could never be sure he was going
to show up. I never knew it. Never knew.
And Phoenix was a perfect example.
He didn't show up.
He was supposed to go to Phoenix and
he's just fucking slipped in between the
howling.
You did like a Thursday
night show it at Tempe. Yeah.
And then there it was so fucking weird,
like after your show they had some weird
contest or whatever that Danny Maher
asked me to, to do. I don't even know
what the fuck it was. Four. And uh,
and so the whole crowd stayed you that
you'd like sold out Thursday night?
The whole crowd's stayed in the first
comic who went up just ate dog shit.
I don't even know who she was.
I mean,
just some horrible comic and like half
the crowd gets up and walks out and I was
like, and I'm last of this group
of people. I'm like, fuck this.
And then I remember,
I see,
I saw you sit down to eat a meal after
the show and you're sitting there and,
and you were even turning the Dan,
you're like, why? Why are they,
what is the show going on?
Like what did I finish the show now?
There's another show and the socks and
everybody in the audience and everyone's
like walking up and leaving.
And I got back up and there was like 12
people in the crowd and I was like, shit,
I was so pissed. I didn't give a fuck
anymore. So I started doing my jokes,
but like,
people were laughing,
but I heard you laughing the loudest
from the back. I was like, oh,
well this was a victory for tonight. And
then you had asked me, you're like, Hey,
can you uh, open for me the rest of
the weekend? Because it's a Joey Diaz.
Is it here? Yeah, that's how we met.
That was like two, it was like 2004,
but that was maybe my first
show was February of 2003.
Oh, so it was, yeah. You were really
recent rash. Yeah. You were really fresh,
I think you'd said you just been doing it
a year. Yeah, it was like a tight seven,
which was good.
You know?
Great job, man. For someone who
never performed, like, you know,
in that sort of a situation on a weekend,
a paid show, what's the difference?
A page shows a big difference.
You know, when people pay,
when there's money on the table,
they go, who's this guy? When?
When is Joey Diaz Get up there? You know,
and then they find out that Joey Diaz,
I ain't got a lot of your
dog and Never Las Vegas.
Okay.
What are the influence?
He did it a bunch of times,
but this is back in the dark
days. Joe, he's very reliable now.
Scares the shit out of me man.
Awesome.
Like I love him but he scares the shit.
I mean I did shows in Tucson with him
and it was so afraid to talk to him.
Why I did it was a great guy.
Well cause he's just like rough and he's
not like bad aggressive, but he's just,
he gets mad at me for,
he'll get mad at me.
It was the last thing we got mad
at me for Susko Hannah. We'd, yeah,
he didn't like my weed.
We fucked up and we w someone told me
you should grind your weed in a coffee
grinder. And I'm like, oh that seems like
it would make sense. You just be like,
it'd be really quick.
Right. But when you do that,
it makes it way too fine and it pack
these joints so thick you literally
couldn't through them. Oh,
hi. It was like, we figured
it out. We figured it out.
After a while you have to use like a
regular grind or you can't use a coffee
grinder.
It's just too much.
So we did it with Joey and he got so
mad he was swinging and you just give me
this fucking Susko Hannah,
we'd Susko Hannah.
We thought he was talking about Hannah
Montana and it turns out the Susko Hannah.
Cause that's what he'll say, you know,
like he wouldn't call you Josh McDermitt.
He would call you a fucking,
I like that guy like Josh McDougall.
He's fucking hilarious.
And he will come up with just a subtle,
and I think he does it a little
bit on purpose. Subtle fuck up.
And the way he still calls Nick
Swanson. Yeah, Nick's and Nick Swardson,
he calls Nick Swanson. You know,
he was listening. Brian Redman,
I'm tired of your bullshit.
Yeah, he's uh, he's, but,
but he's a great guy. He's a national
treasure to me guys like that.
It's just like, how do you, how do
you create a guy like that? You could,
you could throw a million people through
life and you will never get a Joey Diaz
and so rare combination of events that
have to take place to get a guy that's
just that comical and doesn't
give a fuck and just that's it.
That's our original human. So hard for
someone to really truly be themselves.
It's a very difficult thing
that we have in this life.
This want for self acceptance and sex
and money and poor Brian can't get on
Wikipedia round.
He gets upset about that.
There's very few people in this world
learn how to just not give a fuck,
not give a fuck. And Joey,
Joey, just Diaz is, listen dog.
If I'm on Wikipedia, I'm on Wikipedia.
Whatever dog. I don't give a fuck.
Give a fuck. I ain't got time
for that. You know what I'm on.
I'm on Joey Coco diaz.com go
hit me up on Facebook, Twitter.
Check yourself before you wreck yourself.
Big Dixon Yas is bad for your health.
Are you going to any Halloween parties
this year that you have to dress up for?
Yes.
And unfortunately I took my three and a
half year old to the Halloween stores.
Her, her idea like, Daddy,
we have to get you a costume.
We have to get you a costume. All
right, let's do it. Let's do it.
So she picked out this really
fucking scary mask. I would
go get it for you guys,
but it's upstairs. It's really
scary. Zombie masks. I'm like, oh,
I want to be a Zombie. But
uh, I showed it to the,
to the one year old and the one year
olds just started shaking her head,
thrown that away. I can't wear
it. And so then I said, well,
I'll just play with it with the three and
a half year old. But when I put it on,
take it off, Daddy, take it
off. Like I had to take it
off. I'm like, I'm just okay.
I'm taking it off and is okay. You put it
on again. I put it on and it's just, no,
no, no, take it off. Take it off. It's too
scary. It's too scary. So, so I fucked.
That was my mom dude. She would, she
would, she's like the female Andy Kaufman.
Right.
She would put the,
she would put these like ugly hideous
masks on and it looked like you'd dumped
acid on their face and everything
your mom would do that you had do.
My mom was fucking crazy.
Right.
So we'd come home from school and
she'd be sitting on the porch.
I get wrapped up in a blanket and
a hat with that mask on and she's,
and we'd be like, hey mom. She
was like, we were eight years old,
just scaring the shit out of us.
That's awesome.
Why did your mom want to scare
you so bad? I, I don't know, man.
She wanted to be like, oh, she wanted to
be a comic, but she just never really did
anything about it, you know? Wow. Like
she's a dude. She's the funniest person.
I know, isn't it? Uh, this, uh, uh,
for us, for someone who's done comedy,
isn't it a sad,
sad thing when you meet someone who
really should be a comic and they're not
doing it? Yeah. All met them.
Right, right, right. No, absolutely.
Some of the funniest people I know
are not comedians not tied to the
entertainment industry at all. Yeah,
I've met some hilarious regular people.
Hilarious.
My mom would do some crazy,
crazy dark shit like when she was like
nine months pregnant with my little
brother and I'm like four
or five years old. And she
says, um, I did something bad.
And she's like, come into the kitchen,
you're getting punished. I go,
go into the kitchen. She sits
down on a stool and she goes,
listen, you know, do we,
what do you want me to punish you?
I'm like, I dunno. I Dunno. She goes,
I'm going to kill your little brother.
Like she tells me this five years old,
she sat on a stool, lifted her
stomach, had a retractable knife,
which I didn't know is we're
tracking to get into her stomach.
Oh my God, my God. Oh
my God. You know. Wow.
That was the childhood I grew up, dude.
What's that type of shit? That's crazy.
So then of course, you know, she pulled
up, she goes, this is a retractable knife.
And knowing my mom, she would do that
shit all the time, but I'd be like, oh,
that's hilarious.
Like the mother version of those cops,
it made those kids sit in the corner.
That's like the mother version
that your mother is a criminal.
It sounds like growing up in
the Family Guy House. Yeah.
That sounded like so cartoonish. Is
your mom still around? Yeah. Yeah.
And she's still crazy as fuck.
Do you want to get revenge?
We could do something really cool.
Well don't listen to him.
He'll get you locked up in jail. Yeah.
I don't find career ahead of you.
You're an excellent standup comic. Thank
you. Spray. It's called liquid ass.
Don't do I love my mom. I next thing you
know, someone's dead hanging from a tree.
That's how it goes. They don't resent
her for any of this stuff, you know,
made you probably funny. It's one of
the reasons why you are so irreverent.
You know, you have such a funny
sense of humor maybe. Yeah, no,
that's absolutely what it was. Yeah. But
she uh, I mean, but now that, you know,
there's the sh she had six
kids and then you know,
everybody's got grandkids and everything
so she starts to fuck with the
grandkids a little bit. Hairy woman
has to be stopped. I'm like God,
you know,
my brothers and sisters and we're all
kind of onto her so we're a little more
protective. So like what my sister
had a kid like in, in, I dunno,
he was like eight months old or whatever
he was on in the back in her bedroom
like with pillows around them on the
bed so he wouldn't roll off or whatever.
And we were just sitting around and my
sister in law goes, where's Judy? And,
and you hear her from the bedroom?
She goes, I'm not doing anything,
which is scary shit cause my
mom's like always doing something.
And we went back there and she was just
sitting on the bed with the baby and we
don't know what the fuck was going on,
what,
we don't think she was doing anything.
But you still don't know with her because
she was always worried about what do
you think she would do? I don't know.
I mean it was never like dangerous.
It was never dangerous. It was never
like, she's really crazy, a fun, crazy,
not like crazy like you,
we're not going to let you,
would it be around the kids but you,
you were worried that she was
in there alone with the baby?
Well, yeah. Well I think it was more
like what will, where is she? Why?
Why are we all at her house and sitting
in her living room and she's not here
doing it. I'm not doing anything which
may have just been to fuck with us.
Like she would do that too. I
get it. It's not bad. Crazy.
Trump obviously stabbing your stomach for
your five year old was probably a poor
choice and judgment, but I knew my mom
well enough at that point that I was like,
oh she's, she's just kidding around.
And once she told me, that's so crazy.
I would come home from school,
I'd come home from school and she'd like
pops a blood capsules and lay on the
sidewalk or in the middle of the
way and I'd come home. But it,
we just step over and be like,
get up mom.
Like she's trying to get us way
that she passed out or something.
Oh my God.
But what if she actually did it's again,
it's just like that fucking shitty share.
Your mom cried wolf every day.
Every day. Holy Shit, US man. Wow.
But look, look at this sense of humor
you got out of it. Oh, she loves it.
She's milking it to with their friends.
And that you're a comic. The comic. Yeah.
I told you I was funny.
I got funny jeans.
It's all over Facebook or was she just
knocked it off like she's all over
Facebook. Yeah, it's, it's upsetting me.
The last time I saw a mom that
was into her son's career,
it was Stan helps mom at home. Mom was
pretty funny. She was hilarious. She,
she's to review porn for us on the
man show stand helps moms. Hilarious.
She was a character man. Really
fucking funny lady. Well, my,
my mom's the type of woman that if I
ever wanted her to do bits and everything
she would, but of course, you know,
fucked with us a lot, man.
I mean, I've got stories,
just tons of stupid shit that she would
do. That's how you become a comic,
I guess though, right? I mean, I don't
think you'd become a comic. Well,
it can't say, you'd never know.
We really, there's no clear path.
It could be just someone has a sense of
humor and regardless of how nice their
family was or they grew up,
I,
I've had guys with seemingly perfect
lives who become comics and they're funny,
but it's what if your child had an
upbringing? He was a little fucked up.
That's a mind for mine.
Gold Mine.
I haven't really talked about my mom
on stage much just because I don't,
I don't want to blow it too early
because you don't like the longer you do
comedy that funny you,
you become and you kind of understand
your point of view a little bit more.
I know that there's such great shit there.
I don't want to blow it early,
which you just told us on stage.
You don't think that could be hilarious
on a show or telling what you just told
us on stage.
The knife.
If you were talking about that on stage
a little bit and people didn't laugh.
So at that may have scared me away too.
It's like, I know this is great, but dude,
it's hilarious. Problem
is people are like, whoa.
More horrified then find this funny.
But just your sense of
humor is a little warped.
The you found it hilarious and then
you went, well that's fucked up.
You just have to relieve them of that.
You have to somehow or another relieve
them of that ad like right catch up
instead of gliding down fries
into it. Okay. Mother fucker.
As many of you listening, it's
just silly, silly, silly boy.
Um,
so if anybody wants to find
Josh,
Josh has a fine standup comics travels
all over the place and you TV show is
retired at 35.
We just got an air date.
Our second season starts in March 2nd.
What network is it on?
TV Land. It's a small cable network on
by MTV. That's cool. And the vet channel,
when I go to sleep to they,
they,
they do reruns of everybody loves
Raymond and Lucy. Lucy. Yeah.
Cosby show all that old Lucy you were,
you were a radio DJ for awhile.
Where at? In Phoenix and Phoenix,
Arizona. I would tell you
how to do, we got time.
Did I ever tell you how I started with
that? No. So I was like 14 years old.
Do you, do you remember the
Tim and Willie Show in Phoenix?
Do you remember radio shows at
all? Yes, Brian Remembers. Let me,
so that was the show. I worked him and
Willie, Tim and Willie's country music.
Okay. So anyway, we did their show.
I did a lot of different, yeah,
you would do are you did our show a lot,
but um, I did. Every time I did with you,
I was a producer, we would go to every
time we go. Right, right. And Tim,
we ran into Tim at the mall
one day wandering around.
Yes. Super cool guys. Yeah,
they're great. Yeah. So I
was like 14 years old and uh,
it was right when that Song
Achy breaky heart was like,
was out and people were starting
to make fun of it. You know,
the Billy Ray Cyrus Song, you
don't tell her keep brick. Yeah.
So I would listen to their show cause I
thought they just had a funny radio show,
but not necessarily because of the
country music. I could give a shit.
So one day I called up and I'm 14 years
old and I requested Achy breaky heart,
but I did a funny voice that
said, hello, my name is Coco.
Can you play a key breaky heart? And
they're like, what the fuck is your name?
And I said, well, it's Kako. And they
started asking me about it. Well,
I hadn't thought of like a
backstory and all that stuff.
So I'm like making it up on the fly.
Mcglynn Pilipino and it just,
I just moved to America. I love a
cubic yard. I'll sing it for us.
I started singing it for him and like,
uh, they loved it. They're like, hey,
call us back anytime. Kako is great. So
I'd call back every fucking day, you know,
and I'm calling and, and I became this
like mini celebrity on their show is Kaka,
which they didn't know was a,
a fake guy.
One of the story I told Hako in in the
split second where I was coming up with
this backstory,
I said I was born in England and my and
moved to the Philippines when I was two
years old because my father was in the
Royal Air Force that way I thought if I
ever meet them,
that will be,
that will be the justification
is why I'm a white guy.
So you were going to show up a white
guy with a Filipino accent. Oh my God,
it's brilliant.
So they go.
So they were like cargo call us anytime
and they would play the fucking phone
calls. Then I started calling up as
a guy named Josh and I'm like, dude,
I'm Kokkos biggest fan play
his phone call from yesterday.
So it's like marketing myself and
everything. They're like genius.
So they would do these little concerts
and like a Garth Brooks would come into
town and they would introduce Garth
Brooks on stage and they would invite some
of the players from the radio
show out. And then, you know,
Kako was like this big star and he
would come out there. And um, in fact,
the first time I met them I walked into
the studio and they just looked at me
and they're like, what the
fuck? And they're like, okay,
you can drop the accent now. And I'm like,
what are you talking about? [inaudible]
character dude really
never broke character. And,
and this whole bit came about
how I was looking for a job.
I was in high school and they're trying
to find me a job and then they would
find me these jobs,
but I couldn't go to the job because
it was a fucking in high school.
And they're like, hey, you know,
so they called me Taco. Yeah.
You never showed up for your
[inaudible] slipped in, you know,
Larry.
So I had like 10 different characters
going on in the show and they didn't know
it was all from one guy. And then
they said at one point they were like,
Kako you should work down
here, man. And I got sick.
That's when I got scared and I was
like, oh, this is my real voice.
[inaudible]
and their jaws dropped.
I thought it was going to get arrested
or something. And they're like, no.
They're like, dude, you have to
work down here. Oh, that's the list.
That's how I got the job with them.
And so from, Gosh, what was that,
90 93 until 2007 I worked for them.
Whoa, that's amazing. We
were syndicated for a while.
14 years.
Holy Shit.
We were syndicated for awhile.
I was the producer for that and I would
travel the country when I came in and do
it,
cause I never really remember sitting
down and talking to you until I saw you on
stage. Yeah, we met, I
met you before. That was,
it was just like a high walking
through the hallway. She was like, Hey,
can I get you some water?
We're going on the air in 10 minutes.
Some of that bull shit.
Probably remember this because I must've
remembered it when I first saw you do
stand up because I'm,
I'm remembering it now.
Like a glimmer of it and I think
you would ask someone from the club,
you were like, Hey, who was that that you
know, blonde fat kid with the glasses.
Who, who, you know who was funny last
night, I want him to open for me.
They're like,
oh we'll see him tomorrow morning and
you probably came in and did our show and
then you said hey do you want to, it
was something like that might have been,
it might have been that. Yeah, but
I was so long ago. Yeah, it's crazy.
Time flies man. We would have
all the comics on and I mean I,
I've met so many people and no one,
I don't ever expect anyone to remember
who the fuck I was but I must have been a
cool job.
You know,
like it was great doing standup and
well it started a sock and that's why I
started doing stand up cause we got bought
out by clear channel bump, bump bump.
No there it is. And it, that
just made me what happened.
It's they suck the fun out of it
man. What they do? Uh, they just,
all the budget cuts, all, you know,
like my mind just works in being funny.
I just want to be funny.
And then they were just like,
well we need you to start figuring
out ways we can sell advertising time.
And I'm like, I'm a fucking writer
and a producer. I'm not, you know,
talk to the salespeople and just,
they, it just made the show not fun.
We started out, you were, they
wanted you to find, it was like,
well what kind of bits can we do that we
can sell to an advertiser to this tire
company. So this tire company, we've
got this advertiser and they want,
they want to buy airtime with us but they
only want to do it on the morning show.
And they're like,
so can you figure out like a funny bit
we can incorporate tires into?
I'm like, no, what the fuck?
It's like weird shit like that.
And I'm just like, this is not fun.
That's a dumb way to approach it.
Or they should say,
just make it the funniest thing
possible and we'll sell regular ads.
Go our rating nutty.
Our radio station was owned by Buck Owens.
You know who buck Owens and
country star. Yeah, legendary dude.
And he owned like two or three radio
stations and we were one of them.
So we were like the focus of that
company when clear channel came in,
they got hundreds of stations that
could give a shit about us and it just
stopped being fun.
So I had a buddy who started
doing stand up and I went and did,
I was writing jokes for him and then
I'm like, oh, I'll give this a shot.
And it was more of an outlet
for me because I'd have to
censor myself on the air.
They got this guy,
I don't remember his name,
but he was like the CEO or something.
And he was always like,
I think it was like listening
to like a 50 cent song and uh,
and his daughter was in the car and he
like had to turn it down. He's like,
we got it. We're censoring
everything and we're, you know,
clear channel really started
putting their thumb on everything.
It was so much shit was confetti. It
says all that stuff. And so white girls,
Jackson, 50 cent, black girls,
just a big mess. You shouldn't you,
do you need a podcast hunting or said Oh,
100%. And what are you gonna do for me,
man, I'll get you that Wikipedia
page. Well listen man, you,
if you sign up on the desk squad and
be a part of his podcast network,
they right now are number seven.
There's a number seven all yes.
Right now he's in the top 10.
We great man.
Well we started doing this thing
live at the Ice House and uh,
we aired one half of it on mine and one
half of it on his and when we put one
half and I, his, his shit jumped
all the way. Oh, number six.
He's number six right now.
So by doing his podcast,
automatically you're going to get seen
or listened to by hundreds of thousands
of people that you wouldn't normally do.
So we'll just do it on his and dude,
you, you're perfect for this. You've got
great stories. You're a fucking smart guy.
It'll help your stand up.
It's easy as fuck to do.
And you could probably set it up where
you could do it from your own fucking
house and just getting
ready to file. Not Hard. No,
you got to come over to my house now.
Now you have to come to my house.
Why am I going to come over to the
house, Dude, I'm on a TV show, man.
I don't have to go to your house.
I think it's your own show too right now.
Well, I mean that's what I tell people.
No, I'm not. Who's The star?
George Segal. Oh, the old
dude. Yeah. From just shoot me.
Oh, that guy's a great act. Jessica
Walter, the old man, the old man,
the old woman from some recipe
development doing something with like her.
She's cute.
Maybe it was you.
And they were talking about him
doing something that George Segal,
I think we talked about this Friday night
at the ice house. Was that what it was?
Oh, that's what it was and we talked about
it on the actual live at the icehouse
podcast. Yeah, so that one, that one live
dice house podcast. That's what did it.
So in with us son, Collin dilutes
getting juicy comic needs this man.
Every comic is this.
It's like having your own radio station
with no fucking clear channel. Not One.
If it can't just step in and tell you
there's no way I'd be able to say cut this
much on a radio station
many times is that you see black con?
I tallied it only because it's habit.
I've tallied how many
you've set up 14 times,
but that's all because it's had a habit.
Do you do it out of habit because of
radio career? He years, yeah. Wow.
I said court cut 1415 now. Wow. Nice.
Some guys going to go back and check
now. Kinds of beautiful word. The end.
Thank you to Josh McDermitt.
Thanks for various standup comic,
my friend for many a year now
and please follow him on Twitter.
It's Josh Mcdermitt, d. E r m. I t. T.
That's Mick, d. E r m. I t. T.
Follow him on Twitter and
thank you to the fleshlight.
If you go to Joe rogan.net and click on
the link entering the code name Rogan,
you will get 15% off the
number one sex toy for men.
Thank you also to onnit.com o. N N. I t,
makers of Alpha brain and knew mood,
knew mood is a five HTP mood enhancing
supplement and we always say,
by the way, if you say load
stuff's expensive, I understand
if you're on a budget,
all the ingredients are clearly
listed online. If you would like,
please duplicate them yourself.
Go to a discount vitamin store,
get all the ingredients,
put it together yourself.
Tell me that you saved money and that
you're happy with the results and I'll be
just as happy.
I fucking swear to God.
But if you go to Joe rogan.net and click
on the Onnit link and enter in the code
name Rogan,
you will save 10% off of the Alpha brain
supplement that I will be giving Josh
McDermitt along with a free flashlight
as he leaves tonight. We'll your girl,
do you have a, a steady
woman in your life? Yes.
Do you think that she would be
offended by this, this new intruder,
this rubber vagina? They wouldn't be
offended. Right? Thank you for your help.
It's fucking shows over. All right.
We'll see you guys on Thursday.
Probably do a Thursday afternoon
show. We're going to do a laser. Uh,
she's recording or show stove,
but she's coming up soon.
You're going to do a lot to do on
Thursday. We're doing so many on Thursday.
I'll tell you. We'll figure it private
and Thursday bitches. It's a three, three,
three podcast week.
And this is UFC weekend too,
so we'll probably talk
about that on Thursday too.
Maybe we'll get Joe Diaz
in here. Yeah. Need Joey.
I don't give a fuck cousin cock sock.
I got other shit going on. All right.
You might not want to walk on
ice and might as well dance.
That's the end of this podcast.
As always,
all you people out there driving your
cars, listening to on your treadmill,
whatever the fuck you're doing,
we're all in this together and we love
Ya and we'll see you soon. Bye. Bye.
Okay.