We'll live,
dude,
we always,
we always say we're going to do these
regularly,
every like two or three years.
We pledge that we will do these
regularly and then a decade goes by.
We don't see each other,
but I hope that in your heart,
just like mine,
that it's not like I've had enough of
that.
Fuck.
No,
no.
I know how I see how busy you are.
You're one of the few people I follow on
instagram and I've said it on the
previous show.
I just love to look at your life because
I'm like,
fuck,
he's doing everything he wants and
nothing I'd ever want to do,
but fuck.
He goes to the hill and not in a judgy
way of like,
he shouldn't be doing that,
but just like,
you know,
you look,
I've said you live a man's life.
I live a boy's life as a 47 year old
man.
So you do things like you got a float
tank,
Johan,
you got to hug.
You know how to handle a bow and arrow.
I'm the guy that writes about people
that shoot bow and arrows to stop
crimes.
They usually have boxing gloves at the
end of them and shit like that.
That's good to know.
But I,
I do,
I do.
I guess the point is I know you're busy
as fuck and I know sometimes I get very
busy as fuck,
but I think we only don't do this
because of how busy we are.
Yeah,
that's all it is.
My very convoluted.
So that's.
Yes.
Yeah,
I'll buy that for me is for me,
for sure.
For me,
I'm like,
fuck,
I could do that once a week because I'd
walk away.
I always walk away with a real,
like I've never done cocaine,
but I imagine that's what it's like to
do a line of cocaine off.
I don't know if somebody beautiful or
something like that.
I always walk away with wisdom and it's
wisdom that even though it's on a
podcast and recorded and there's a
record of like,
well,
that's where you learned those things.
I still go out into the world,
present them as my own,
like I'm a smart well read person out
there.
There's dudes that have done a line of
cocaine off someone and they're like,
what the fuck is he telling you?
I've never learned anything from that
except to do it better where the cocaine
doesn't quite fall into the ass crack or
where.
Where'd all my money go?
To think that that was never my poison
man and never.
I still have never in this lifetime done
knowingly done cocaine.
Somebody might've slipped it to me and
you and I both really?
Yeah.
I never touched it,
but one time in man,
that's fucking,
you know what I'm saying?
Like,
oh,
were rare.
Yeah.
And also just like as entertainers were
rare as well,
does it ever make you feel less than
when you read about those of us who try
to be funny in this business and those
who have been insanely successful and
become icons,
they always have,
you know,
and then they did blow for hours and
blah blah,
blah.
Do you ever feel like,
oh,
that's not part of my matrix,
hence I must not be one of the greats.
No,
I'm very lucky that I know that.
You don't feel that.
I don't feel that right because I think
I'd have a real problem with speed and
amphetamines and coke.
I think I'd have a real problem.
That's what draws your eye like from a
distance.
I really don't enjoy it.
Um,
and I think it's the worst thing for
someone like me who's up probably person
to begin with,
you know,
which has served me well.
But,
but um,
that stuff makes you giggle,
giggle.
Not because it's not facetious is if you
walked into the facility that I just
walked into and had the grand tour that
you were given a gentle listener and
watcher at home.
Uh,
I was,
I was saying to joe before we went,
like,
he's got this new new to me.
I don't know how long you been here
since October you said?
Yeah.
But it's,
it's a paradise.
It's a,
you know,
fuck the term man cave.
This is like man empire and walk in and
it's just,
it's like walking into Joe's head.
It's everything he loves under one
fucking roof.
And I said it to him before,
like you did this with your mouth,
like you talked yourself into this.
Very strange.
Isn't that awesome?
I mean,
I know you've gotten,
you've got a zillion things that you do,
but like even in a world of the MMA
stuff,
that's still your mouth.
It's always your fucking mouth that is
taking you from where you started til
now you walk into this building.
It's not like he had a family fortune
and it was willed to them.
Your mouth put you in a building.
This nice painted the walls,
the color it is.
You walk in,
it's like a museum.
It's like you see pieces of of him hence
me all over the fucking place.
That's all out of your mouth.
If anybody's watching or listening at
home,
teetering on the verge of like,
I wonder if I should do a podcast.
Send them a snapshot of that fucking
room where you can launch bow and arrows
for 45 yards.
They'll start talking.
But I think if you're interested in at
all,
you should do a podcast talk to you.
It can be.
It can be a way to make a living.
There's enough people like this.
I'm not a one of those,
um,
famine thinkers.
I think the opposite.
Like you could do it.
Anybody can do it.
I've never like,
man,
it might not be enough for everybody.
I agree.
I'm always the guy who encourages you to
like,
hey,
try it because,
oh my God,
it's fucking fun for me.
And you know,
we've been,
we're rare birds and as much as we've
been around since the fucking art forum
started,
like you've been doing podcasts since a
minute after podcasts start.
At first he was the Guy Predate Corolla.
Yeah.
Well,
yeah,
for sure.
So,
but you're in the first five years you
were.
Well,
what year did you start?
I started,
we just celebrated.
Last year was our 10th anniversary,
so we're now a year 11.
So count back from now is two one.
Oh,
seven years.
Couple of years.
When did you begin?
Think?
Two thousand nine.
It was in two years of the Big Bang when
I,
when I jumped in,
it was Leo Laporte doing this week in
tech and I think he still does that and
the happy tree friends and that was like
the apple podcast,
top five and then me and Scott started
with smog cast and then later on we
added a bunch of stuff,
but getting in within the first two
years like we happened and then right on
the heels of us,
Adam was on the radio and that radio job
went away and where
Adam went to podcasting gotta be 2000 if
we started smart guests,
2007.
It's either in.
We start February 2007.
Either he loses the Radio Gig in 2007
and moves the pockets or it happens in
2008,
but it was,
isn't that neighborhood?
Yes,
and he's.
He was the model for a lot of folks now,
like Ralph Garman,
the guy that I do Hollywood babble.
I love Ralph.
Ralph's amazing.
He was let go byK rock earlier this year
or later.
Yeah,
at the end of last year.
Right before Christmas.
And so he to moved into a kind of online
world.
It can sustain a motherfucker.
Ralph's report is his show.
I liked him a lot.
He's a good dude.
Good Dude.
But I'm talking to him when you,
when you go to k rock and that's how our
friendship began.
And you sit there doing the show and
then afterwards I was a cigarette smoker
in those days and we'd sit there out in
the parking lot and smoke and slowly
like I remember I came in once k rock
just announced like,
Hey,
I've rented a theater on Santa Monica
Boulevard and we're calling it smart
cast when going,
we're the world's first live podcasting
theater,
then we're going to do podcasts there
and stuff.
And so Ralph was listening,
he's right there.
And then uh,
like months prior he had approached me
and he's like,
hey man,
would you ever want to do like the
Showbiz beat?
That's what he used to do on k rock on
Kevin and been like as a Saturday show.
And I was like,
Fuck Ya,
hear myself on the radio.
That'd be fantastic.
So we recorded a demo for the show,
gave it to his bosses and his bosses
were like,
nobody wants to listen to people talk on
the radio anymore.
And so it died there.
Just like how years ago things died when
you couldn't get past a gatekeeper who
was like,
we don't want your shit.
Was this after the talk radio station in
La went under this.
Okay.
So they probably were like current on
that and they were just,
you know,
k rock was reading the tea leaves,
which was like,
people don't want to hear people cheer.
This won't play music.
We're competing with satellite radio now
we're competing with streaming music
where it's like they don't have to wait
15 minutes to hear a song.
Dan could shows though runway steckler.
That was a really good show.
Yeah,
they were great.
There was a bunch of really good shows.
But the uh,
so he,
we had tried that and it was called
Showbiz beat.
And then months later when I was in
there going like,
yeah,
I'm opening this podcast theater
afterwards in the parking lot,
grabbing the post show smoke.
Ralph is just like,
hey,
would you ever want to try that radio
show at that theater?
And I was like,
fuck yeah,
you want to do it as a podcast?
And he was like,
yeah,
like yeah,
let's try it out.
And so I was driving home and I texted
him at a light.
I said we could call it Hollywood
Babylon.
It was an old book called Hollywood
Babylon that was about like gossipy
stories about Hollywood people and
stuff,
but we spell that of course differently
and stuff and that was my.
That's what I brought to Babylon.
Other than that,
Ralph built that entire thing and then
my job became to sit next to them and
react to the news,
which is why I love that part so much
because as you can tell,
I fucking love the sound of my voice and
I wind up talking,
talking,
talking on smog casts.
I would lead on Jay and silent Bob get
old,
which is really about Jason Muse.
I wound up wind up talking a bunch,
but with Babylon I get to sit there
while he's the main act and I'm,
you know,
the second banana,
I,
it's,
it's nice to be able to top and bottom
in the world of podcasting,
like you know,
it,
it's,
it gives you a place to go if I'm
tapping all the time,
right.
That I'm talking about my thoughts and
what I believe in and these are the
experiences I've had and people are
interested in that.
But then sometimes you just want to
check out and talk about somebody else's
shit.
None a podcast we do call fat man.
I'm battling.
That's what we do.
I just sit around and go like,
oh my God,
you watched the avengers and shit like
that.
So you get to concentrate on that kind
of stuff.
So yeah,
the Babylon thing grew insanely
organically.
We started that little theater,
sat 48 people and since he was on the
radio every morning he can just fucking
sell it out.
He'd be like,
Hey,
go to Kevin's website.
You get tickets for battle and be sold.
This is that you placed on.
What was it?
It was somewhere in West Hollywood,
right?
That little theater.
It was on.
Yeah,
it was on Santa Monica Boulevard in an
area of where they put up a few black
box theaters.
This,
this section is called the complex and
we had one theater in the complex and
repainted it and hung up like all the
artwork,
like you got our work based on the
podcast out in the hallway.
Same thing.
We were essentially built a shrine to
Scott Mosier,
my cohost,
smart kids,
which I'm sure on some level creeped him
the fuck out.
First time he walked in was just like,
he wants to wear my skin,
you know,
and so the idea was we're going to do
nothing but smart cast here.
But since Scott didn't suddenly go into
like,
yeah,
let's do five podcasts a week,
you know,
it stayed pretty much the same.
We had a theater with nothing going on
and it and stuff.
So I started trying other things.
Babylon became one of them.
Jay and silent Bob get old also came out
of that experience.
Still have that theater.
We let go of that.
Me and Maddie Cohen,
who's a cohost on this very fun podcast
he does with Macaulay Culkin.
Have you spoken to fucking Macaulay
Culkin?
Ya know,
I'm just putting a bug in your ear.
Oh fuck dude.
Fuck.
He gives good talk.
Good oral.
I mean that sounds filthier than I meant
to,
but you know what I'm saying?
Like as a guest.
Fucking fascinating and funny and it.
Anyway,
Matt and Macaulay do a podcast called
bunny ears,
and so Matt Cohen was the guy that I'd
opened smog castle with like guy going,
I wish I had a black box theater and
went out and found it and stuff.
So we kept it open for like one year and
then let it go.
Because what had happened was the Babel
show sold so well so quickly all the
time that it became clear,
like we move this to a bigger theater.
This is the thing.
He was on the radio all the time,
so it was easy to move seats.
So we went up to the lovetts member,
Jon Lovitz Comedy Club.
Ralph had went to the Improv and in
love.
It's the love.
It's with like you could have 95 or 100
percent of the doors,
something ridiculous and that was the
only reason we went up there with air
for awhile.
Things fell out with Lovitz and stuff
and then we moved to the Improv instead.
So we've been there ever since and now
we do it on the road quite a bit and
stuff.
It's always weird,
right,
because the people were way above your
head.
It was one level here and one level way
was meant to be.
It was bb king's originally back in the
day,
so it's like a jazz club where you
wouldn't mind looking down at the act
but for a podcast and with a guy with a
fucking bald spot.
It was nerve wracking because like,
how am I supposed to be funny knowing
they're staring down at me judging my
bald spot.
Some comedy shows there and it was
great,
but it was.
It was odd because it was a weird shape
tray flap and straighten up.
Let me.
I'm just jump off topic real quick.
What were you.
Was it the times you were featured in
for being like the source for news?
It's this thing that these guys are.
They're they're,
they're calling something to
intellectual dark web and they've
connected a bunch of people together
that are interesting.
People that don't follow poor standard
for name bad marketing because when I
read it I was like,
I don't think of him as dark web.
The dark web.
My friend,
I think of Weinstein.
She loves that sneaky.
You can dagger type stuff.
He came up with the name of it.
He just gets a kick out of it I think,
but essentially the piece was about how
you are doing media that the quote
unquote real media is not doing like you
know more about the rise of certain
intellectuals that are very
controversial like Jordan Peterson and
Sam Harris and all the debate about
them.
I'm just someone who they get a chance
to talk to for three hours,
you know,
in a pretty well.
Well we'll subscribe to base is a lot of
people that are going to listen to these
conversations and they get it.
They go,
well,
why?
Why haven't I heard people talk like
this before?
Why haven't I heard about the idea of
determinism versus freewill?
Why?
Why haven't I heard like last time we
were here,
we talked about the universal monetary.
Everybody starts with a salary.
Yeah.
Universal basic income.
I was super hesitant about that.
I was like,
that's nonsense.
And then,
um,
the more I thought about it,
I,
whenever I just immediately dismiss
something,
I always have to go,
okay,
why?
Why am I immediately dismissing it?
Like,
what's,
what,
why did I go?
And then I thought,
oh,
that's fucking people.
They're just lazy.
They just want money.
And then I went,
all right,
is that true?
Let me see what the fuck's going on.
Because there's a weird reaction that I
had.
Like I had a reaction against lazy
people.
The unexamined life is not worth living,
so it's easy enough for you to be like,
now I don't care.
But most people end their and their
story goes in a different direction.
You're like,
wait,
why don't I didn't have a clear defense?
My actions,
the way I thought not,
you know,
I didn't do anything but the way I
considered this subject,
I didn't have.
I didn't have a real bay.
I was very knee jerk,
so I said,
okay,
let me really examine this and what the
real issue I think is going to be
automation and artificial intelligence.
I think it's going to remove a
tremendous amount of jobs.
I think automation in terms of a car
driving and a different use,
different functions.
Once they get better at robotics and
being able to do things and then people
will be less and less necessary and they
have a real problem.
They think with cars,
with a number of males that drive cars,
it's in the millions for a job and that
they would all like almost instantly be
out of work if they ever get these
automated cars down and where everybody.
I mean one,
since we're a culture that believes in
technology,
one's inclined to believe,
oh,
they will get these self driving
vehicles down to a science.
I think they'll get it down there.
They're pretty damn close.
Close by fact that as soon as somebody
gets it right,
they get set back a couple of hundred
miles.
There's been a few fatalities,
right?
Several.
But how many have been fatalities
because of humans,
and I always say that's true,
but how many more humans are driving
that fucking robots.
I mean that shit is off the charts and
that number's got to be banana.
It's like how many actual robots are out
there driving?
When he got 10 and two of them killed,
people settled down,
but it's still.
If you.
If you look at the numbers though,
yeah,
billions of people driving cars.
Only 10 robots and they've already taken
two lives,
so that's pretty.
It was a pretty bad ass,
bro.
That's what's going to happen.
I believe that.
I've been talking about this a lot.
There's a fucking robot that I'm a Darpa
created and it's called the eater robot.
EA T R,
and it can fucking fuel itself with the
biological material.
Any or is it programmed for certain
biological material?
No Man,
but biological computer.
Dead bodies,
no doubt.
But does that mean that a,
it's aware of when it's powering down?
I don't know.
Here's remember either the military role
at this supposed to eat humans.
His is the thing.
I think the idea of biological material
is maybe it could sustain itself on
plants.
Maybe you could sustain.
Go.
It's possible.
It's possible you went right to human
remains possible.
If you can use this thing in a
battlefield that you would want to have
it eat people because you can have dead
people everywhere.
Have this fucking robot monster that
you're sending to kill people.
Also eat them.
So not only is it killing people,
but it's also cleaning up in the
background as well.
Taking dead bodies away.
I was a diabolical scientists and I was
going to come up with the evilest mean
his shit to to send to the enemy to go
them.
It will be a
robot that eats people.
Why?
Because it's going to kill people,
right?
It's going to be sent there that killed
your loved one watch in horror as a
consumer.
It's flush and power me further fuel to
kill you next.
And wouldn't we?
I mean pretty bad and and kind of
stereotypical and one might even say
racist robot voice.
I apologize for the race.
What race would that be?
Monotone.
I feel no love nor are paid and they can
make it look scary to man.
They can make it look like venom like
from a star wars books or spiderman,
Spiderman,
books that would be scary to people.
Be like,
Holy Fuck venoms here.
This rock.
It would be pretty close.
Our Denim Fan.
It needs to look like that face the
giant face with the wind.
I mean that.
If that was in the eater robot and just
inside all that scare you,
would that scare you more or would it
scare you more if there were like,
uh,
the eater robot,
its head is full of hypodermic needles.
Each one more toxic than the last and
infected at a moment's touch.
Whoa.
Those are terrible too.
You know,
it's.
Do you want to try option or do you want
to greet by the sharks?
Which question
have you spoken about Roseanne yet?
I'm not publicly.
Have you had private conversations?
Is enough to form some sort of thought
process on it.
I talked to Ben Shapiro about it today
on his show,
but it won't be out until Sunday.
What is,
um,
do you,
have you ever encountered her in the
world?
I know Roseanne,
um,
I talked to her on the phone and I
believe every word she said she told me
that she was taking the Ambien and that
she was drunk and Memorial Day weekend
and she tweeted a bunch of stupid shit
and she's out of her fucking mind and
she said,
you know,
in her words,
I need to adjust my meds,
you know,
I'm not thinking straight.
And she was talking about how exhausted
she got doing that television show and
she got bronchitis and she was
overworked.
I think she's stressing the fuck out.
She also told me that she did not know
that that lady was even black.
She thought that lady was Jewish and she
said to me like,
do you really think that I would make a
joke about a black lady and say,
planet aches,
I wouldn't fucking do that.
She's like,
I thought she was Jewish.
Look at her,
so I did look at her like pull up her
wikipedia page.
This lady,
she,
um,
I mean she most certainly pull it up so
we could see it.
I mean she most certainly could be
African American for sure,
but she also most certainly could be
like Hawaiian or native American or
point ban the Italian.
Maybe she thought Jewish.
Those what Roseanne said?
Jewish.
This is what she said.
I do not know.
I don't think she's lying to me.
I don't think she's racist.
Have you ever had an Ambien?
No,
I've never taken him,
but I talked to here ever taken a good
friend of mine about it today and he
got up
in the middle of the night,
cooked himself a meal,
eight it,
went to sleep,
got up in the morning and had no
recollection of it.
He had to be told that he did.
He was trying to figure out who put the
plates in the sink,
who ate this food,
where this food comes from and couldn't
figure it out.
He got up in the middle of the night,
doesn't remember a thing,
right.
And cooked himself a meal,
sat down,
ate,
and went back to bed at zero
recollection of it.
I said to this guy,
they shit out of it during that meal.
At any point did he get racist or
anything like that?
I wonder,
you know what I'm saying?
Like he's literally buckets one thing
and it's a spooky story.
It'd be like,
I took ambien and I made myself some
food.
It's an even spookier story to be like,
I took ambien and I fucking killed
somebody.
But it's a,
it's a stretch to be like it is.
I took ambien and I said something I
would never say in a million years.
It heartens me to hear you say that she
said that she wasn't aware of the ladies
race because it,
you know,
I don't know her all.
I know her from his Roseanne.
Oh,
I know her from his decades of watching
her and media or TV show.
I followed it before the TV show.
Um,
it didn't seem like
the Roseanne that I've watched for 30,
40 years.
Well see,
that's the thing.
I'm not close to her on a daily basis.
I have tremendous respect for her as a
comedian.
Um,
I think she's,
she was a real pioneer and a lot of
ways.
She was this brash,
like really confident lady who shit on
stupid men and she did it and it's like
really bold way and stand up.
That was very unique for the time.
I think if people go back and you watch
some of her early standup when she was
coming out of Denver,
the domestic goddess,
she was a beast man.
She was obese.
She was crushing,
she was crushing,
you know,
and then she got that Sitcom and it's
absolutely one of the greatest sitcoms
of all time.
Yeah.
But now she's 65 years old and it's
fucking hard for her.
And that schedule she was telling me was
absolutely brutal and that they were
killing her with all the work.
I don't know her very well,
but I do know there was another time
where she said something about Susan
Rice who is a,
another African American woman.
And she,
she said something about her and
compared to her balls.
Yeah.
Something like swinging eight balls,
you know.
So that's two for two.
It's two.
Yeah.
Well this one for sure.
Right?
Because this one,
there's no excuse for this.
This is one from the past that there was
no.
Like,
oh my God,
I was on Ambien.
I tweeted this.
No one said anything.
Susan Rice is a man with a big swinging
ape balls
and that wasn't meant to be a
compliment.
I guess.
13.
Okay.
So that's a long time ago.
That's five years ago.
Oh,
and you can,
I mean,
I don't know if it's still available,
but if you can go through a timeline and
see a bunch of things that are not like
a comedian being funny,
but.
Right.
You know,
beliefs,
right.
That one is um,
doubts are rough.
One.
That to me is a way rougher one.
It's way rougher.
Like that one is like,
that's what you said.
I mean it is what it is.
You know,
if you said that the other lady looked
like planet of the apes just because of
her haircut,
because she looks like the lead woman in
Sierra.
Yeah.
She looked like zero.
There was like a photo of her back.
It was just like the way her haircut was
and her outfit was.
I think some people would,
but if you didn't know that she was
black,
it's a totally different thing.
Yeah.
Do we know that for sure.
You know,
only she knows for sure.
You know?
Are you surprised at how quickly it all
ended?
Well that was the part of the story that
again,
I have no skin in the game other than I
watched the old Roseanne and I was
enjoying the new Roseanne as well,
but I came home from like I was vegas
the other day and I flew home yesterday
morning and then I had a meeting over
the studios like at noon,
so I took a nap when I go home,
like,
and also my wife wakes me up and she
goes,
you got a meeting,
don't forget like it's 1130.
Oh.
And Roseanne's been canceled and I'm
like,
that's,
that's impossible.
Like I was groggy,
but I'm like that's impossible.
It's like 20 million people are watching
that show.
And she said she tweeted something
racist,
so I'm fucking pick up my phone and I
look at it and stuff.
And by the time like this had happened
in the span of like the hour I took a
fucking nap.
They,
the network acted so fucking incredibly
fast.
There was no prevarication equivocation.
No.
Do they have that ax sharpened and
ready?
It was not like all of a sudden they
were just like,
we're done.
We don't know or disavow.
And,
and,
and it was,
I think it was so surprising because
it's been awhile since somebody did
something even superficially a moral,
you know what I'm saying?
Like I've read a lot of articles online
where people are like,
hey man,
abc didn't own the show.
So of course they fucking had,
didn't have as much skin in the game.
So it was easy for them to cancel it.
Would they have canceled with this fast?
If they own the show and dot,
dot dot,
you can,
you can make a bunch of kind of caveats.
But at the end of the day something bad
happened and then the network reacted.
A major come fuck the network.
A major company,
Major Corporation reacted.
That is the right way to handle it,
to just immediately cancel the show.
I personally would have maybe fired her
and kept everybody else done.
Like the,
you know,
Valerie never die off or just use
computer animation.
I could replace it with the pixars
character,
but I think you can sell it equally
compelling stories like without her
honestly like the nine episodes that
they've done this season.
She really hasn't been the driving
factor of stories.
It's been more about Darlene.
That's who I felt bad for when this
whole thing imploded because I'm like,
she's.
She put this show together.
Sarah Gilbert,
and she was crushing on it.
She was like
really good.
Showing off like what a great actress
she is,
but now everybody's out of job.
Feel bad for John Goodman.
I've worked with him before and he was
wonderful on the show.
Could sustain the show without her.
I think.
Can She be forgiven?
Sure.
I mean,
Ken,
didn't Mel Gibson get forgiven as any
working again?
Mel,
Mel Gibson,
it was also a case of him being
intoxicated right.
He was yelling some antisemitic stuff at
a cop.
I mean,
nevermind.
That also punch his ex wife like
violence action than him just saying,
hey,
sugar tits.
Like there were some that his wife had
recorded them or recording them,
yelling at her on the phone.
So we had nobody knows if he truly hit,
I don't know,
my bed.
I thought that was,
I don't know.
I don't know the,
even the specifics of any accusation and
also I also didn't follow it that
closely and not because I'm like,
man,
that's Martin Riggs and I don't want to
hear anything bad about him.
I just didn't follow it because I'm
like,
yeah man,
it's,
can she be forgiven,
forgiven?
I don't know.
I mean look,
she should have tweeted what you said
instead of a,
Oh my God,
I took ambien.
Like that turned into an opportunity for
a major pharmaceutical company to put
out one of the best singers twitter's
ever seen.
Like this is a company they're not
normally used to like,
hey,
what should we say to be funny?
Like they have to put out very staid
information and for once they were like,
how about this guys?
We say racism isn't a byproduct of.
It was really well said.
There was this was well worded.
You sit there and go like,
why didn't I tweet that?
Whoever wrote it,
it was whoever wrote it rather.
It's pretty slick.
I'm the thing ambient does do though and
definitely makes you act bizarre.
You.
There's some sleep,
sleep.
I mean if you just.
There's a smoke weed,
eat edibles.
That would help,
right?
There's websites dedicated to people
that have had crazy experiences on that
stuff.
I've seen a few of those stories.
The one that you told me about your
friend cooking dinner is about the
fourth time somebody communicate that
story now because they've been listening
to your show and you may have sold.
Ted said that story.
Probably have people drive cars on it.
They go places that don't realize what
they're doing to get places.
It's like the serpent and the rainbow
man.
You become zombified and you're like,
I'm not your bill pullman and a fucking
casket.
Well,
there was a.
There was a guy that got pulled over a
few years back who was famous and I
forget what he said,
something about like,
I got to get to the dance or something
like that,
and the cops were like,
what the fuck you talking about?
And they realized like he was kind of
out of it and then after it was over,
it was revealed that he had been on
Ambien and that he had gotten in his car
and really had no idea.
He didn't even know he was traveling.
I'm over like literally the guy was in a
dream.
It reminds me of when I was a kid,
this was not drug related,
but I was a kid.
I was asleep.
I fell asleep on the couch watching TV
and before my,
like my brother had lost his fucking
wallet at a school dance and my mother
was like,
I'll drive you up there and try to find
it.
And my father would get up for work
at about 9:00
at night and then had to work at 10:00
and I think he started working at 11:00
at night.
He worked at the post office cancel and
fucking stamps.
Um,
so he,
I,
my,
my mom tells me that and I fall asleep
on the couch watching like fucking
dynasty or some shit.
It was the eighties and then my dad
wakes me up because he woke up and
nobody was home.
Like my mom wasn't around,
nobody was there and he's like,
where is everybody?
And he fucking startled me awake.
So I was like,
what?
Oh,
Donald Donald,
they had to go to the school because
Donald lost his thriller and my father
goes,
what?
And I was like,
Donald last is thriller.
And he was like,
I don't know what you're saying.
And I was like,
dot mom said that Donald losses
thriller.
And I kept replacing the word wallet
with fucking thriller.
And my father looked at me and literally
sent these out the next day to be like,
are you using drugs?
And I was like,
no,
you woke me up.
I guess it was in some sort of,
maybe I was dreaming about fucking
thriller was 1982,
you know,
like eight brain just never clicked back
over into waking life.
Stayed in this weird Zombie land where
we're wallet meant thriller.
Did you find that,
you know,
what we were looking at got pulled over
and I'm trying to remember what he told
the cops where they realized that
something was going on.
I think it was,
it was in one of the articles that I
tweeted the store was in one of the
articles that I tweeted.
Um,
what happens in that instance?
You get in trouble.
Can they rescue for being the ambient
driver?
It's a rare reaction because a lot of
people take that shit right here.
This story all the time.
There's not selling just a couple of
those pills a day,
a webpage devoted to stories of people
who took ambien and got fired for being
racist.
He's right.
Well,
even better,
there's no stories of people that took
Ambien and,
uh,
you know,
became addicted to it and became some
sort of a.
or is there,
is that addictive?
Is Ambient addicted?
Yeah,
probably.
Probably.
Yeah.
I think they like getting addicted to
falling asleep and here needing it to
fall asleep probably.
Yeah.
I guess if you're somebody who like,
I can't go sleep with that,
that.
Yeah.
Wonder if it's addictive.
Like maybe like a heroin is addictive.
No.
Right.
Or like a speed,
you know,
like people get like physically addicted
to things where it kind of changes the
receptors.
Yeah.
Pr.
I don't know if it dulls the senses to
the point where like when you.
I mean that's the way I heroin's always
explained to me was when you're on
heroin,
the senses are dulled.
The nerve receptors like just don't take
in as much,
but when you're not on heroin,
that pain of withdrawal,
part of it is the receptors coming back
to life all at once and it was a light
skinned.
Yeah.
Jason,
Jason Muse.
Long time ago I had problems with that
shit.
So it was one of the Rehab doctors
communicated it thusly.
He said,
you know how when you sit on your hand
and fucking falls asleep?
I'm like,
yeah,
totally.
He's like,
imagine that was your whole body and
times it by a million.
That's what he's going through.
Wow.
That was like,
oh,
and then.
Yeah,
because up until then I
was always like,
just fucking stop doing heroin.
Just stop it.
And then meanwhile I was eating a lot of
sugar.
Just stop doing your job.
You might fucking drug.
But once that dude explained it that
way,
I was like,
oh,
that would be.
That would be fucking painful.
No wonder the kid doesn't want to get
off heroin because he's like,
I know the path to not being on heroin
is full of pins and needles,
but you never die from it.
That's the good thing about that.
Like you don't die from heroin
withdrawal.
We know from amy winehouse and other
cases that you can die from alcohol
withdrawal like you can.
You can get off.
Like when you're in jail and you're
kicking heroin,
you know the cops just be like,
you know the hair just keep throwing up
and piss in,
but if you're kicking booze,
they have to give you booze because your
heart could stop.
What are we looking at?
This fucking article,
he pulled up an estimated 446,000
people in the United States were current
hmis users of Ambien.
Now what is the misuse and dependency
onto ambien can develop after just two
weeks of use.
Don't attempt to quit without proper
knowledge and before putting a medical
treatment plan into place.
Wow.
Two weeks is all it takes.
Two weeks [inaudible] son maybe driving
around having conversations because it
uses Ambien,
gets a good night's sleep and you know
the worst that happens on the job in the
morning.
You,
you kinda where you're like,
you just lose a word like your leg.
Donald last is thriller and that's the
lowest mildest form of every now and
then you skip a word,
which I do now.
I call that hitting a pothole.
Roseanne is,
she's an older lady,
she's in her sixties and she's had some
mental problems and uh,
and she's drinking and she's taking that
stuff to go to sleep and she's not
taking it for just two weeks.
She's taking it a lot,
you know.
And she said she needs it to go to sleep
and I think there's a lot of people that
feel like they need something to help
them go to sleep that fine.
But then tweet ticket fucking works.
Yeah.
I don't think at the end of the day it's
not like she took ambien and that makes
her bad.
Like,
no,
it's that she fucking tweeted what you
did.
And it's like if you think for a second
that if in using this drug,
which I need to go to sleep because I'm
late sixties woman and any of my rest or
whatever,
I'm at war.
You just deserve fucking sleep.
Like you know,
I've merciful,
I've never suffered from a lack of
sleep,
but I know that people who have,
and it's fucking mind bending itself,
but if you know you have to do that and
you know,
there's the slightest chance that you
could become somebody else or say things
that are not in your character,
give up your fucking social media man.
Like I don't think she realized that she
was obviously going to do that.
I think she had tweeted ridiculous shit
in the past before and had flew under
the radar and nobody cared.
Right.
But it's,
it's a racism thing,
you know,
and what's,
what's fascinating to me about it and
what's positive to me about it is that
we have.
Our culture has like a fucking zero for
racism
now.
It things have tightened up so much.
Like it's entirely possible that within
a few decades like racism can be almost
completely eradicated.
I think it's possible with the spread of
the Internet,
we're going into like 50 years from now,
60 years from now,
racism could be seen as the ridiculous
idea that it is.
Racism can be seen the way someone looks
at it or someone like Jane,
there'll be like a roddenberry world,
there'll be like star trek people.
Like maybe back in the day there was
something like that,
but we haven't experienced that in
centuries.
Yeah.
The distrust in and hate for specific
gigantic general groups of people like
Asians or blacks or whatever and the
disparaging ideas that you have about a
race just because they're,
you know,
just because a person's from a specific
part of the world,
that shit,
it's got to be a thing of the past.
We got to get past that
because I would love to believe that,
but unfortunately we live in a bubble
out here.
Where do you live?
In a bubble.
It does kind of work in it.
You know,
at Dm.
That's unbelievable.
I've heard people out there about to
like,
judge the fact that he's fucking sell in
California.
California blows the one.
I'm not saying like,
Yay California,
fuck the rest of the world of fuck the
rest of the country.
But I will say this,
everyone here lives fairly
multiculturally and there doesn't seem
to be.
I mean,
granted we're in this area of the state.
Perhaps it's different elsewhere,
but it feels.
I'm not gonna say Utopian,
but it feels like people get along out
here.
Even if it's a plastic,
get along.
It's still get along pretty good.
Yeah.
So much so that I think a lot of people
in the state where that's,
you know,
we're mystified when the election went
the way it did because they were like,
what?
No,
because that's not the way life works.
Well,
it's not the way life works in most of
California,
but I think that's the way it went for a
bunch of reasons.
You know,
a lot of the middle of the country
didn't feel represented.
A significant say when it comes to,
um,
you know,
the um,
what's it called?
Electoral College vote.
That's when we get squirrely.
When you look at the points that
different states are worth,
like,
it's very weird that we still have that.
It's not a person,
one person,
one vote,
not even one person,
one vote.
It's like these weird fucking spots.
Why isn't it one person,
one vote,
like,
is this explained to me in high school
why the Electoral College was necessary?
And even then I was like,
yeah,
but well,
one person,
one vote kind of makes more sense.
No,
both you and I know Jack Shit about
politics makes this,
uh,
this journey of where people are
bleeding from their ears going fucking
idiots,
but the checks and balances that are in
play,
like the representative government is
what keeps someone from just like
running through the whole thing and we
get a little bit of a test to it by like
trump.
I met a buddy of yours on a plane.
What guy?
Oh yeah.
My favorite area.
Yeah.
Nice guy.
But here's what I want to pass on.
Like we were on a 45 minute flight,
maybe super smooth like in and not in
the way of like,
hello,
I'm Lando Calrissian.
But this dude had a thing like a,
like a rep parts and not like he wasn't
like having sex with somebody but he had
a,
a rep our tag going with the flight
attendant that was so effortless and you
know,
I sit next to him and we chit chatted
before the flight and I had mentioned
something about fucking Joe Rogan.
He goes,
I've,
I know Joe Rogan and he talks about like
content,
blah,
blah blah.
But in any event,
for the rest of the flight,
I had to like a front row seat for him
talking to the flight attendant and it
was like,
it was a real clinic in like,
oh,
like he's got that thing that like I,
I've had to make up for not having my
whole life.
But people,
well not even just talking to people
like,
like the way like you watched like a
fucking movie star,
say two things.
And the people like,
oh you,
you like he just had this person in the
palm of his hand and I'm being very
careful because I don't want it to seem
like he was making the moves on her and
he,
he wasn't,
but he easily could have been with that
person by the flights end.
And it was just as I sat there watching
it going like I've had to make up for a
deficit in my whole life.
Being like,
here,
here's some funny things.
And Hey,
I saw star wars and talk about all this
other shit to try to trick somebody into
fucking me.
This guy just like sits down on the
plane,
was like,
what's up,
and she was like,
oh,
you and instantly started going,
talking to them and I was trying to
discern throughout the whole flight.
Did they know each other as he see her
on this flight often or something?
No Dry.
He hit that flight as dry as anybody
else and literally could have walked
away hand in hand with somebody who's
very impressive.
He's got bowhunter confidence.
Is that what it is?
That's what it is.
It's got to be.
It's the same thing.
You exist.
Not even a regular bow hunter.
He's like a super advanced bowhunter
where a compound bow was too easy for
him.
He said that,
well,
he switched over to a recurve bow,
will cs to get closer to animals and
practice more.
He was explaining my friend Aaron
Snyder,
he's a little bit crazy without even.
He was explaining that and it didn't
sound braggy,
like a really good podcast.
He said he's cast.
What's it called?
Kfar.
[inaudible] K I f a r U.
it's a.
it's a company that he works for that
makes really high end hunting and hiking
backpacks and military backpacks and uh,
he does a podcast through them and he
said he's very good at it.
He's very good at talking.
He's a funny dude.
I couldn't fucking attest to it.
I sat there and watched him be 100
confidence.
Is that what it is?
I think so,
yeah.
He's not a swagger.
It's whole life.
Like there was nothing about him that
instantly.
I mean it was definitely very macho,
but there was nothing about his thing
that was like,
I am a guy's guy.
It wasn't even that,
like honestly flight attendant probably
could have been a guy in a barren was
just as interested in short,
short range bow hunting.
He would've landed that guy as well.
Like he was very,
I don't know,
it was good.
Like when he said I do a podcast too,
it made sense.
I was like,
I bet you do.
Yeah,
smart dude.
And so that's a weird way to live.
You know,
it spends 200 nights a year in the
forest,
sleeping in like either a bivy sack or a
tent or under a tarp,
like fucking,
just like Robin Hood.
He's out there all the time and it's
like there's not a whole lot of people
that are doing that more woods than men.
That's another guy was ex military too.
It's a lot of these ex military guys.
They get really in a bow hunting because
they find it very difficult in a
physical challenge.
It's nerve wracking and it's hard to
keep your cool under pressure.
And for a lot of guys who um,
they go from the military and maybe do a
few tours overseas and come back to the
mainland and just have a real issue with
being just not stimulated enough and you
feel detached and you don't feel like
you're involved in anything that's got
like a high adrenaline threshold.
And for a lot of these guys,
bowhunting is very therapeutic.
The.
So is that an issue when people come
back?
Uh,
the,
the issue I always hear about,
of course there's ptsd,
but that sounds like the opposite.
Like somebody who's like,
I was there for the rush and now the
real world offers like that's that her
not even necessarily that there were,
yeah,
that hurt like hurt rock locker.
Not even necessarily that they're there
for the rush,
but that once they experience that rush,
you know,
got to bring this book up too much,
but Sebastian younger wrote a book
called tribe and it's all about this and
it's about these guys coming back from
war and trying to just sort of assemble
it and having a really difficult time
and how so many of them talk about when
they were over there,
they had a purpose and that life was
intensified and cranked up to 10 and the
highs were the highest and the lows were
the lowest.
They come back here and everything's
just too flat.
It's just really hard for them to adjust
and they feel disconnected from their
community and they laid long to go back
and that's why a lot of them keep
signing up and going back and they feel
that that life at the tip of the spear
is actually more,
more satisfying,
more rewarding.
It just feels right for them and the
regular world just for whatever reason,
they've just tasted it or they've.
They've adjusted to it,
but there they have a very,
very difficult time.
Some of them do.
Was the closest you've ever felt to
that,
like have you ever gotten close to the
feeling of like what have you done in
life that has given you the adrenaline
high?
What's your highest adrenaline rush?
I guess I'm asking the probably the most
nervous I ever got was when I was
fighting when I was doing martial arts
because there was a nervous for a good
reason.
It's like you might get fucked up.
It's really possible you might get
kicked in the head,
but I'm the second most nervous was
before I did stand up for the first time
I was shitting my pants man.
It was fucking nervous.
I don't know.
I'm funny.
Like were you high school funny?
I was locker room funny.
I was A.
I would make my friends laugh in the
locker room.
I got talked to by a good buddy of mine,
my friend Steve Graham.
I'm still good friends with.
He talked me into it,
him and my friend Ed shorter,
they just,
they talked me into it.
I would make them laugh,
you know,
and,
but I thought that they were laughing
because they were my friends and I felt
like everybody else gonna think I'm an
asshole.
Like they're just being polite.
Well it's all that too.
And like my sense of humor was fucked up
because it was all fighters,
you know?
And so everybody was like,
they were hard men.
So you had to have like a certain
staying to your gallows.
Humor.
Well everybody was on their way to go
kick people in the head.
It was just a weird life,
you know?
It was very,
very strange way to be 15.
You now have 15,
16,
17.
That was like my whole life to.
That wasn't the adrenaline rush.
The adrenaline rush of doing standup was
unexpected.
That's why I freaked me out because I
didn't think I was going to be so
nervous and I was shitting my pants.
I just didn't have a background in
performing and right before I was going
up there I was thinking all the times
that I,
I fought and I should be comfortable
doing this,
but I was fucking shit in my pants.
I was so terrible.
Oh,
so I was so terrified.
It was in Boston,
a place called stitches.
Are they still there?
August 27.
Nineteen 88?
No,
no,
no.
The day.
Yeah,
for sure.
You're making me cry.
That's awesome.
Why do you remember that?
I don't know.
I always remembered it.
Say it again.
August 27,
1988 because then naturally everything I
hear I have to put through a filter of
how does this affect me?
So I'm sitting there going,
what was I doing?
August 27th,
1988.
I had just graduated high school in
June.
And where was I working?
I was working at buyright liquors and
shit like that.
Um,
and it would be two years before I would
go onto the stage at rascals in town
between the monmouth mall in the CV
square mall and try it myself.
And I didn't not tell West orange.
No,
that's,
that's up north.
Ours is down in like a by Asbury Park.
This place was like a couple miles from
asbury park south.
Yeah,
I did that one too.
as a pro.
I went in an open mic night just because
I didn't tell my fucking friends because
I was terrified my friends and be like,
why do you think you're funny and stuff.
I was not the funniest of my friends.
So I wasn't sitting there going like,
yeah man,
come support me.
I kind of did it on the slide and stuff
and I did five minutes.
I made like one joke that really worked
a bit about sucking my dick and that
wound up in clerks.
It was tested in front of the audience.
So I was like,
well I know that might get a laugh and
stuff.
So what was,
how long was your first beat?
Was it open?
MIC is open mic?
Yeah,
I think they gave you five minutes and I
don't think I even had five minutes.
I think I had four.
What'd you do observe?
No,
I just,
I,
I just told some terrible jokes.
Terrible.
Just literally set up.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They were awful.
The stuff that I've written,
you know,
just weird.
I haven had a piece of paper that I
brought with me on stage because I was
terrified I was going to forget a lot of
guys.
He knew you were a pro and you can put
that paper away.
I'm about to cry.
That's so fucking sweet,
man.
A young you.
How old are you at this point?
It was 21.
So why'd you wait so long after I have
to be 21 to get a little boost to go
into a nightclub,
you know,
that's what I thought.
Apparently I was wrong though.
And you,
they would allow you as a performer to
go in.
They're younger,
but I didn't know this at the time.
I thought you had to be 21.
So I waited until I was 21,
which was August 11th and then I went up
August 27th.
What was the,
what got the biggest laugh?
Who knows?
You know,
the fucking day.
I can't remember.
The material was terrible.
I tried to think past it as quickly as
possible.
The one joke that I remember,
this is my impression of a good looking
girl getting pulled over by a cop like
drilling fast.
We're going,
no,
do you like my tits?
So I do.
Here's a warning.
Like it was that bad.
That's how bad.
That's how bad the comedy I was
slinging.
Take you home man and put you on a show.
That's an adorable joke.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Wait a second.
How many years before news radio is
that?
I'm 88 was six years.
So technically if one follows the
journey backwards,
that fucking terrible joke lands you
eventually on Newsradio.
Yeah.
In a way.
Get you this building.
Yeah.
In a way that's not mock that joke
anymore.
That was a good strong.
Well that's the weird wings of a
butterfly that becomes a hurricane.
Right?
Like go back in your life and think
about weird little lefts you took or
right.
You took a bunch of those when I had
three months ago at heart.
Yeah.
Tech,
when I was on the table,
because of the good doctor was just
like,
uh,
you,
you have a 100 percent occlusion in your
lad.
And I was like,
I don't know what that means.
He says,
your lad is your,
uh,
is the main artery that goes across the
front of your heart.
He's going,
it's a 100 percent occlusion,
means 100 percent blocked.
You've got cholesterol is blocked,
there's no way for blood to get through.
And that's what's creating your mass
part of tech.
So he's like,
we're gonna,
we're gonna.
Take care of it right now.
He goes,
but you're accomplished guy,
right?
I said,
yeah.
And he goes,
you'll like this,
that artery.
That's called the widow maker.
And I said,
why?
And he goes,
because 80 percent of cases of 100
percent occlusion,
the patient always dies.
He's gone,
but you're going to be in the 20 percent
because I'm really good at my job.
And he fucking disappeared into my
crotch.
One of my grind through my femoral
artery and fucking went up into my heart
and put a stent in that,
in that lad.
And the moment he opened up,
he goes,
I'm gonna open it up now.
And he showed me what it was,
tiny little mesh wire thing.
He goes,
I'm gonna open it froome.
Suddenly it was like,
because that artery had been like a hose
of the it and it's fucking full of water
and shit and was pushing down on the
heart,
which was in turn pushing down on my
lungs.
I had no idea it was having a heart
attack.
I just felt like I couldn't catch my
breath.
I thought I was too hot.
And it was in between shows between two
gigs when you were filming?
We shot them both while we were going to
shoot them.
Both my only shot the one because I had
the heart attack and we didn't do the
second one,
but it was for,
uh,
for the folks that commented dynamics
and it became a showtime special.
So we were shooting two shows that
night.
It was meant to be like an hour and an
hour.
But you know,
once you get up there I feel like I'm
fucking rolling.
I'm rolling.
So I did two hours and after the first
show they were like,
we don't even need to do the second
show,
we can cut an that we're only cutting an
hour out of it.
So you gave us plenty and stuff.
I said I got two different hours so I
want to do the second show and plus
everyone was there.
They were lined up and so I took a big
swig of fucking milk.
I was dairy drinker,
heavy dairy drinker in those days.
I've since become Vegan ice,
be happy now.
I'm fucking Vegan.
But uh,
I took a big swig of milk then I went to
the green room and I chitchatted real
quick with Jordan,
who runs our company as Jason's wife,
Jason Muses,
wife.
And uh,
emily was there.
She does my hair and makeup.
So we're Chit Chat.
And then I was like,
man,
I feel fucking weird.
I feel sick.
I feel like I'm gonna throw up.
Can you guys get Outta here?
Because when I get sick I just want to
go off like an animal and fucking die
alone.
Like I don't want to be ministered to
him.
Like fuck off and shit.
So they were like,
yeah,
totally.
And I laid down on the floor and I felt
like nauseous,
nauseated and I never feel sick like
that and wound up throwing up some bile,
nothing chunky but just like fluid and
so I was like,
well maybe I'll feel better now.
Stood up and I looked in the mirror and
I was just swamp man.
Like now as a heavy dude,
you sweat when you fucking breathe.
This was like I'd look like I'd just
come out of the pool and I felt really
cold.
I couldn't get warm and ship.
Emily popped her head and she's like,
are you okay?
I was like,
no man,
can you turn on like a hairdryer?
And just like drop me off.
I feel fucking freezing cold.
And she touched back of my neck while
she's driving me.
She's like,
you never feel like this.
This is scary.
You should do something.
I said,
hey,
yeah.
I said I was still wanting to do that
second show as like someone to find a
couch.
Just a cast for me to lay down.
If I get like a half hour nap,
I'm sure I'll be fucking fine and I
couldn't get comfortable on the couch,
couldn't sleep and that's when I started
not being able to catch my fucking
breath.
So you know,
I'm no doctor but like fucking you
think,
you know,
I know my body and I know what this is.
I smoke too much weed and I've got too
much mucus in my fucking chest.
That's all this is.
So I said I better sit up and put my
arms up like this because that will help
me breathe.
And Jordan comes around the corner
eventually and she sees me.
She's like,
you're right.
And I was like,
you know,
having a hard time catching my breath.
I could breathe.
I just can't get all the way to the top
and stuff of the breath.
Can't take a full fucking breath.
I was like,
maybe I,
maybe we shouldn't do that second show
after all.
And she goes,
we already canceled it.
And I was like,
why the fuck did you cancel the second
show?
And she was like,
because I'd never seen you sick like
this.
She's gone,
you know this,
this is weird.
Something's going on.
I said,
yeah,
maybe I should see a doctor.
And she goes to Sunday night,
all doctors are closed.
So we called an ambulance.
I was like,
why the fuck did you call an ambulance?
Oh my God,
this is,
don't,
this is embarrassing.
She's like,
they're already here.
And six fireman came into the room.
Big Brawny fucking do is when you call
paramedics,
fire department comes as well.
So,
uh,
they're looking at me because I'm
sitting in the chair with my arms up and
like,
there are,
some of them were young,
four of them are young and it looked,
they looked at me like,
why is silent Bob celebrating a fucking
touchdown,
you know,
and shit.
Like all of a sudden the medics came in
and they,
uh,
there was a guy and a girl and the guy
puts a cuff on me.
He goes,
how you doing man?
As a good,
I can't really catch my breath.
And uh,
he goes,
well,
we're gonna.
Look at you right now.
Put the cuff on you.
You ever had this done?
I said,
Oh yeah,
I know how to do this.
And then the girl had a uh,
like look like a fishing tackle box at a
bunch of leads,
wires coming out of it and shit,
she put that down as heart monitor
thing,
you know,
they get your fucking blood pressure,
all that shit on one arm.
Then the other thing they put on your
chest to monitor what's going on inside.
So she's like,
I get to put these wires on you.
I said,
okay,
and I'm sitting in the chair and this is
40 pounds ago and sitting is no good
angle for fucking fat guy to begin with
and shit like that.
So she just yanks my fucking hockey
shirt and undershirt up and every tiddy
I have falls out of my fucking shirt in
front of these people and there's a room
full of people and I'm like,
Oh fuck and shit.
I yanked my shit down.
She's like,
what are you doing?
I was like,
man,
that's my fucking best friend's wife
over there.
She never seen my fucking tits.
My wife's never seen much.
It's like,
again,
you don't Yank my shirt up like that.
She goes,
Hey,
get these wires on.
And I said,
well,
all the shared out you reach up under
and put them on my chest.
He goes,
how am I supposed to say?
And I was like,
do you use my nipples as God posts?
Like it was,
you know,
I've spent all of my life trying to hide
my fucking fat and when your life is in
danger,
I've never been in that situation.
But when your life is in danger,
nobody gives a fuck about your fucking
ego and shit.
Like their vanity.
So they looked at their info and they
realize I guess what was going on?
They were like,
we're going to take you to the hospital
just to be safe.
And I was like,
don't do that,
that's fucking embarrassing and shit.
And they were like,
Nah,
we're so close,
man.
It'll be fun.
You ever been to the hospital?
I was like,
no,
not really.
Like,
Oh fuck,
it's fun.
He goes,
you're gonna.
Have a good time.
I was like,
all right,
and you know,
I'm a podcaster,
so I'm like,
look,
at the end of the day,
no time is wasted.
Everything's a fucking story.
So if this turns into the opening five
minutes of Hollywood Babylon where I'm
like,
they took me to the hospital and it
turned out it was just too fucking high.
Like,
life's great when your podcasts or
[inaudible],
there's no such thing as fucking bad
news anymore.
Like it hit.
It can hit you on the level of like,
Oh shit,
that's unfortunate,
but right away you repurpose it into
like,
all right,
well I've got something to talk about
and this latest setback is just the
longest is just a momentary chapter in
the long story or fucking telling.
So I was happy to go to the hospital,
not because I was like,
I think I'm dying,
but because I was like,
all right,
fuck it.
I'll have a story to tell after this
next week.
It will be fun.
I got to the hospital,
like Dr Layden Jaime,
he's the guy who's now my cardiologist.
They pulled me into the er and he's
like,
hi,
how are you?
I'm Dr Leighton,
and I said,
hey man,
how are you?
He goes,
what's wrong?
What's going on?
I said,
I can't catch my breath,
and he goes,
well,
that's because you're having a massive
heart attack.
It was the first time anyone had said
anything like that.
How did he know for sure?
That's what he does.
I think what he knew for sure was when
they put the leads on me and the blood
pressure,
they looked at each other at one point,
but I assumed like numbers that'll show
up.
That'll indicate that something just
happened and they made this wonderful
call.
I got to find these kids,
give them a hug one day on the call
sheet,
because we were shooting that night on
the call sheet.
It was a different hospital,
but they took me to Glendale adventist
because they knew that I was in having a
cardiac episode and that's shy of one
hospital in New York.
Glendale,
Dale adventist is one of the best
cardiology wings in the United States of
America.
So I happen to be in the right place at
the right time.
We were supposed to shoot my comedy
special at the Ryman Auditorium in
Nashville.
Um,
it wound up being shot instead at the
Alex in Glendale and stuff.
And if I hadn't been doing the show
there,
who fucking knows,
man,
I might have gone to a hospital,
but I probably might've fucking died
because homeboy told me when he went up
the heart when I was in the operating
room and he told me like,
they call that the widow maker and shit,
80 percent 80 slash 20.
I sat there going like,
these are the weirdest odds I've ever
had in my life.
I figured like you leave the house,
it's 50 slash 50,
you're going to fucking drop dead,
right?
They get hit by a car struck by
lightning trip of fucking dog.
And then the dog bite your juggler and
you fucking bleed out your look.
But I always loved dogs and you die
ironically.
But uh,
you know,
just dragging along.
But the 80 slash 20 million,
20 percent chance of life was fucked up,
fucked up thought.
First time I'd ever had that kind of
thought.
And in my head I had to cognitively
reframe it and go,
you don't know,
you might've been close to death so many
fucking times in your life.
There might've been like a cycle behind
you with a fucking knife and then all of
a sudden you got a cell phone call and
forgot about you or something like that.
So suddenly I repurposed it the whole
time I was laying on the table.
I get re purposing every not repurposed
and cognitively reframing.
I was sitting because I couldn't like at
one point they were like,
your wife's on the phone.
Do you want to say you want to talk to
her?
After they told me that I was having a
heart attack and that they had to get up
and be fast and stuff.
So they are holding up a phone and I see
it as the first time a crystallized
where I was like,
oh these,
these people think I'm going to die.
Like I didn't.
I was in no pain whatsoever.
I couldn't catch my breath.
They kept asking me like zero to 10.
How do you feel?
What's your pain level?
I was like,
negative three.
They're like,
you're doing this wrong.
I didn't feel pain.
It wasn't like I grew up in the
seventies watching Sanford and sons and
my idea of a heart attack is.
That's big and shit.
Felt none of the symptoms.
No numbness in the arm.
Anything like that.
I was sweating a,
I threw up bile.
Bile.
Um,
I was cold.
And,
and what was the last one?
It was just fucking shit.
You would never associate with a heart
attack.
Like he would associate it with like,
oh,
I just,
I feel under the weather.
But apparently these are symptoms of
heart attacks as well.
I like to share it because some cats
never heard that before.
And I've seen a lot of people on social
media since we were like,
you saved my life.
Here's why.
Because I talked about the fucking
symptoms and shit.
So while I'm laying there and they go
up,
you're growing,
they go up your femoral artery to your
heart.
And stuff.
He went up and he saw that it was all
blocked.
He said later on,
I was just like,
fuck man.
Like I like dropped 80 pounds three
years ago.
I've been like walking up a hill a mile
and a half every day and stuff.
He goes,
yeah,
but the kind of blockage you had.
You guys that didn't start fucking
recently.
He's gotten that started in childhood
now.
I was like,
man,
fucking hostess twinkies.
And then I remembered we had no money.
So I was like,
man,
fucking little debbie Swiss delights and
shit.
That's how it happened.
It started with little debbie cakes.
I'm with you because I was raised on him
and shit,
but you know,
we were trained to like twinkies more
because they had a commercial little
debbie would never bother with the
commercial.
Then didn't have a commercial that did.
They know you can't.
Well the leaders later they did,
but when we were kids they didn't
because how can you have a commercial
and sell your product for fifty nine
cents oyster cake?
Just like a better experience because
they had more of those trans fats.
Trans fats back then.
I think so.
Colin's fats probably.
Well,
think about it.
Trans fats are part of a.
When you eat,
like what were those cookies that were
not peak screens?
Um,
is like a white Oreo.
Goddammit.
I forget the name of it.
It was fairly well known,
but when I was a kid it was an older
brand from child,
some of my parents' childhood and Hydrox
hydrox their name hydrox comes from
hydrogen ised a palm oil or corn oil.
And so that's when it began.
They were like,
Hey,
we can take this and fuck it up and turn
it into something edible and shit like
that.
Not knowing you that block arteries,
but canola oil,
like all that kind of nonsense stuff.
But I went after a heart attack.
I want to fucking get there.
It is hydraulic.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
It's named after a chemical that could
fucking kill you.
And that's how they marketed it back in
the day.
Kids Chemicals.
Dude.
I used to fuck up some pepperidge farm
cookies.
Remember those pepperidge farms talking
to a fat man.
I've eaten every cookie cookie there is
man with milk.
Do you remember when they marketed the
almost almost home cookies,
almost home cookies.
So essentially there was a craze and
still they still exist to some degree,
but when we were children,
cookies were hard unless they came out
of an oven fresh.
Then they started serving these soft
bake cookies.
You can get them there.
They are almost tell them now I remain
your grocers island shit.
And so you'd take this cookie out of the
package and bite it.
And it was soft as if it came out of the
oven.
And that too is a chemical process I
believe because things are meant to get
hard after they come home.
And it didn't.
Exactly,
man.
It's like watching porn hard,
fast.
You're eating some much that doesn't
turn into mold.
I uh,
I went vegan post heart attack but I'm
certainly,
it's not an ethical thing like my kids
vegan because she's like,
I love animals,
but I went vegan because they were like,
you know,
if you go plant based you've got a
really great chance of dropping your
cholesterol.
And my kid had been bugging me to go
Vegan for like three years and stuff and
not,
but honestly not bugging me.
She would just make comments every once
in a while,
like not your mom,
not your milk.
Whenever I was drinking milk.
And so after the heart attack
nutritionist was in the hospital room
with mango and like 100 percent
blockage,
man.
He definitely time to change your diet
as a gay.
Right.
And Are you eating before?
I just fucking,
I'm not even like a lot of weight.
And when you lost lot of weight,
I remember you would do.
Doing a lot of juicing.
Yeah,
I was doing a bit of that.
Which vegetable juices I've since told
me is not good because you're supposed
to distribute the juice of whatever with
the fiber while eating the fruit and
stuff.
This juicing thing is,
it depends on what juice,
vegetable juice.
It's not really an issue,
but um,
but yeah,
like it,
like I'm part of now I'm a weight
watchers ambassador and people that um,
believe that like they,
they like vegetable juices,
they say that you really better off with
like a vegetable smoothie,
like when you get the fiber it is all
about the smoothie and keep some of the
fiber in it.
And the weight watchers diet,
you go by points and shit like that or
some shit like you can if you eat a
banana,
no points if you juice a banana or
blended banana than it has points
because then it's no longer about the
fiber.
It's all about the sugar at that.
Babies don't have any points anymore,
Huh?
No,
they took points away from like eggs,
Turkey and chicken,
which broke my heart because I used to
love Turkey chicken.
Then I realized I didn't love Turkey and
chicken as much as I thought like I went
on in order to after the heart attack,
um,
I read a while.
I listened to it on tape and not even a
tape digitally.
A Penn Jillette's book.
Presto about how he lost 100 pounds
after his heart episode and it's a
fantastic book.
I'm sure you had a similar issue,
like a heart attack,
but he didn't have a heart attack.
They were like,
you're on the fucking birds and they
were going to give them a bunch of
bypasses and then a friend of his was
like,
instead of that,
why don't you just try eating radically
different.
I could propose a way for you.
Ray Cronies,
he as a diet called just sides and so in
pens book Presto,
he details out.
Ray was like for the first two weeks,
just eat potatoes.
Nothing but potatoes.
You have as many as you want.
He as many fucking potatoes as you want,
but you can't put anything on him.
You can't fry them is just bake the
potato and eat it.
Eat everything.
And you can have nine if you're in a
certain but you can't put any butter on
them.
No Salt,
nothing.
Just flat up potatoes.
So for me that sounded tired.
Well I just come off the heart attack so
I'm like,
I'd rather not die,
so I'll fucking try one potato two weeks
straight up.
Just potatoes and raw.
Not Raw,
like uncooked.
You can bake them but you can't use
anything to cook and you can't wrap it
in tin foil with butter and salt or
anything like that.
Just flat out playing the victim and
then you must have been bored as fuck.
That's what happens to trigger the Diet,
at least in my estimation,
is that um,
you,
you're allowed to eat as many potatoes
you want and you think you like
potatoes.
When I was reading pens book or rather
listening to pence book,
I was like,
oh my God,
I can do that.
Like I fucking dig potatoes and then you
realize you don't like potatoes as much
as you like butter and salt and milk and
everything that goes into like mashed
potatoes and stuff.
So it's,
in the beginning there's a sense of
satiety because potatoes have some girth
to him and stuff,
but they're mostly water.
So it's an excellent diuretics or
pissing like a racehorse and that's
dropping weight like more water out of
your bottom good vitamins in the skin as
well.
A lot of potassium.
But some people,
like when I was telling him,
you know,
the moment you tell people what you're
doing,
you know,
everyone's got their fucking advice
about how to dye it and shit.
And when I was talking about I'm doing
this potato diet,
people can't eat potatoes,
carbs,
man.
Don't fucking nuts too much.
It's bad and shit.
But in two weeks of eating nothing but
potatoes,
I lost 19 pounds,
just like 19 pounds.
Just dropped off a lot of water.
Weight.
Absolutely.
But at the same time it taught me
something more important than like,
fuck,
I hate potatoes.
It taught me to fast.
Like it taught me to like now I eat a
meal a day.
I don't eat in the morning when I get
up.
I don't listen to the propaganda of like
you got eight of breakfast and shit like
that.
Not at all.
My Body has enough stored energy.
I don't need to fucking eat eggs and
orange juice in order to fucking feel
good in the morning.
I just have to wait for my body to be
like,
nothing's coming in great.
We'll hook over to the fucking stored
energy and shit like that.
And I got a lot of like intermittent
fasting.
So what are you doing?
It's not so much intermittent.
It's like I eat once a day and then some
days if I'm like feeling needy,
like you go through it,
you hit a wall every once in a while.
Like generally about 9:00,
8:39.
I get a first Pang of hunger and my
instincts are like fucking quick fix it.
And then I remember like just in 10
minutes it's going to pass.
And then 10 minutes.
Absolutely.
Talking about nine in the morning.
Yeah.
So,
um,
you're eating one meal,
typically dinner generally about 3:00
in the afternoon and then you go a long
time before you eat again.
Dude,
that's the way to eat man.
A lot of people think that's the way to
eat it.
I think so.
Smarter people than I like gray.
Who created the just sides?
Diet and penn who followed the Diet and
stuff.
Same thing.
One meal a day.
Pen.
I can't.
I'm trying to.
I don't think he's down to one meal a
day.
I think he just eats better than I do.
Like he was able to keep up with res
died.
I couldn't.
After the two weeks it was like,
okay,
now we corn and I was like,
I've never eaten corn in my life.
Wait a minute.
He's telling you just eat corn?
No.
He was saying to add corn to the Diet
and they were adding more things after
the first two weeks.
It wasn't like potatoes.
Now just corn.
This just sides.
That's his hook is that you're eating
the size essentially or eating
everything.
That's kind of just all plant based and
stuff and so I couldn't.
I was hoping that I could fucking go the
distance and be a vegetable.
I fucking hate vegetables and so I had
to figure out a way to be v eight
vegetated so much.
How could you be a Vegan and hate
vegetables?
You find a very thin corridor in which
you know to live and exist scooping up
that tow food pretty much eating pinto
beans,
eating black beans,
good source of carbohydrates,
right?
What else?
You know,
what I've fallen in love with and never
ate before in my life or chickpeas.
Chickpeas are great.
Such a great goto snack,
fucking full of protein.
And in Vegan comfort food cooking.
They use it as a versatile ingredient.
So like if you go to one of my favorite
restaurants in town is crossroads.
They've got like this,
uh,
they got real big place,
right?
Is that the,
believe it is.
I believe Travis Barker,
the drummer,
he,
that's his place.
I believe so.
I'm pretty sure they got a meatball sub
there,
dude.
I would.
I'd suck a dick for it.
So fucking good.
Immersively that don't make you do that.
They just make you pay.
That's very sweet of them.
It's good.
Is good business model.
It's supposed to be a very good place.
It is one of the fantastic.
There's meatball subs,
Travis Travis's place tastes exactly
like five miles from here.
Maybe a little bit more called.
Follow your heart.
Have you ever been in that place?
Yes,
I have.
That's why I met Ray to talk about the
Diet first.
Some killer fucking pancakes,
man.
I don't know what they're dealing with.
Kind of Voodoo they're doing to make a
vegan pancake.
Takes that good.
In New York,
they got a place in Brooklyn called
Champ's diner,
which is also like all plant based Vegan
food,
but they do comfort food like you know
like you can get a like an impossible
burger or beyond that or like you're
eating meat balls and you think about
it,
you're like,
all right,
the bread is most of it.
The sauces,
the next biggest part and meat balls
themselves aren't really that packed
with me.
It's much more breading than fucking
meat and stuff.
So I have to do is find something
that'll stand in for the fucking meet,
drench it in fucking Marinara sauce and
put it in between a nice soft roll and
they use like ricotta,
like a cashew ricotta,
like kind of finished it off.
It is fucking bliss dude.
Now you know,
it's just like,
it's Vegan comfort food,
so you can't do that every day.
Right.
But it's nice to know that if you're
ever,
like,
I've missed real fucking food,
I want to eat a goddamn animal,
they can hand you something that's close
to the approximate.
Now the good news,
because I know a lot of people like fuck
veganism and you're absolutely right.
It's no damn fun for me at least.
But after a month of plant based,
uh,
I was on a series of medications after
the heart attack and stolen and it was
on a full dose of Lipitor,
which is a cholesterol fucking cutter
and stuff like that.
So my doctor,
I was telling him about this potato diet
and he's like,
I don't trust this.
He's gone on to do so I want to do your
meds,
give me some of your blood.
So he takes my,
he's like,
I gotta make sure you're getting all the
nutrition.
And he's like,
you can't get it all from a fucking
potato.
I'm sorry.
So he did my labs and came back and he
was like,
you're fantastic.
He's going nutrients wise.
You're great.
Everything is crossed.
The board is great except for
cholesterol.
I was like,
well,
I did just have a heart attack,
and he goes,
no,
your cholesterol is in the toilet.
He's gone,
so I need you to break your lipitor and
half.
He's going,
you can't take that much liberatory
anymore.
So he's like,
what have you done different?
I was like,
I'm just eating fucking potatoes.
Cholesterol drops so radically that he
was worried.
Yeah,
and enough to take me off of my half,
half my prescription when is.
See I don't understand enough about
cholesterol levels.
This is what they told me recently that
I found fascinating.
I thought I was like,
this is liberatory.
It's gonna.
Eat up the cholesterol.
He goes,
no,
it's in your system forever.
And I was like,
really?
And he goes,
yeah,
I can loosen it up and move it about,
but then we have to be careful.
Make sure it's loose and soft and
globule cholesterol.
It doesn't go into your fucking brain.
Jesus if hard pieces like you know,
I don't know if you ever put like
fucking grid off your teeth after you've
eaten or something like that,
come back to the,
you know,
that's plaque technically I guess,
but that's kind of shit that's up in
your veins,
but in that shit gets hard.
It gets super hard.
Like the,
the cholesterol that was blocking up my
lad,
my man had to drill through it to get
the stent in there and you keep that
cholesterol forever.
Now I can't say that a hundred percent,
but that's the way it was communicated
to me because I thought I was like,
this magic drug will eat up the
cholesterol.
He goes,
no,
we have to be very careful with the
cholesterol because it moves throughout
your system chief.
So I guess maybe eventually it moves out
of your system,
but if it's in your blood system,
right,
there's a chance that it goes up near
your brain eventually.
So maybe that's what they're trying to
keep all idiots talking about medical
stuff that right now you can't be an
expert on everything Joe.
Sometimes you have to take shots in the
dark.
Yeah.
So,
um,
we know your audience,
you know,
the audience is sitting there right now
going like,
this irritates me if they're not going
to speak truth and hard facts.
Don't tell.
Understand science.
We don't,
we don't.
That's why we went in to entertain them.
But when you are,
um,
you're getting a full blood panel done
and all these different things.
They're checking all your.
I've also become,
yeah,
and I'd be the guy that does algae and
algae,
but are pills that this a re turned me
onto this doctor.
I bet you know his name,
but his name escapes me.
Who formulated this?
Uh,
these are the nutrients you need a
guarantee.
You've probably talked to this guy.
His name escapes me,
but ray was like,
get these supplements.
They'll cover everything is gone because
you're no longer immediate or anything
you need that would come out and meet
comes out of this.
But,
you know,
it was kind of explained to me when I
was like,
ah,
I don't know,
like my kid was going,
you could do it,
Kiddo.
Like we were raised differently.
Like I,
granted I didn't,
I wasn't raised with flaming neon,
I did eat steak,
I'm through most of my childhood,
but that's kind of a meat,
like it's tough to separate from
something that you've lived with for so
fucking long.
And she was like,
you gave up cigarettes.
And I was like,
oh all right,
you're right.
And stuff.
So it's nice to be able to go to places
where you can eat food that's not just
like grass and roots and shit like that.
What did you eliminate?
This is what I'm going to concentrate on
because I,
she's dairy,
all dairy,
cheese,
milk.
I was drinking no bullshit.
A two gallons of milk a day.
So that might've been part of the reason
I wound up having a fucking heart
attack.
So milk went away,
cheese went away.
Um,
animal food products one away.
So no burgers.
That wasn't a big burger guy,
but I did like burgers.
What about bread?
Pasta,
Pasta.
Pasta can be Vegan,
but I mean it shouldn't,
you shouldn't overdo it,
right?
Can't eat up.
Fucked on a bread and stuff.
You shouldn't know.
So shit just and honestly they prefer
went away,
like most doctors aren't like,
hey man,
eat all the bread you want,
but you know,
it's,
it's as part of weightwatchers,
it has a value to it that you can eat
bread,
but it takes up like a quarter of the
point you can go to weightwatchers as a
Vegan.
Was it tricky?
No.
Interestingly enough,
weight watchers so fucking simple
because they,
the APP,
it's all APP based now.
Like I was part of it when I was a kid,
like at age 14 I was part of
weightwatchers,
um,
and I was like the lone male in the
group and stuff.
Now it's so technologically based that
if you're in a food store and you're
like,
oh,
I want those.
But I wonder how many points.
You just scan the Barcode and it tells
you.
And so you can enter things like pinto
beans,
boom.
It tells you there's zero points.
So anything you entered,
they generally have a value for even
fast food chains.
So it's,
it's shockingly easy to use.
Take weightwatchers out of the equation.
Is Being Vegan difficult?
Yes.
Like I watched my kid go through it
where I'm like,
you have no choices,
you're really limited to the places you
can go in life and go out to eat,
but if it's a choice between wine and up
in the fucking emergency room again and
you know,
eating whatever I want to eat,
which is what I did for 47 years and
then wound up nearly fucking dying.
Closes diver came to death.
I'm okay to go plant based for,
for awhile.
Like I told the kid I'm doing it for at
least a year and if I can live like
this,
I'll keep going.
What?
So you cut out a milk,
cheese animal products and all your
meat.
Sugar,
sugar.
I cut out prior.
Prior to this now when I first met you,
you were a candy junkie and it look,
I'm still a candy junky at heart.
I just can't buy anymore.
I'll always be a candy junkie.
I'm a dry drunk right now.
I'm just like,
I wouldn't eat all the candy if you
presented it,
but it was mostly the dairy and the meat
that I had to say goodbye to cut out.
Yes.
So it was the most.
The biggest percentage of your diet?
Probably,
yeah.
Yeah.
Especially dairy now.
What about exercise exercise?
After the heart attack,
they don't want you to do shit for like
the first month.
So this is the only three months ago
that happened.
So once the doctor gave me the a okay,
then I was back to walking the dog up
the hill of the way.
I always did.
Um,
I haven't gone harder than that and I
don't honestly like I'm so fucking lazy
at heart that I.
It doesn't,
some people like I love getting out
there and fucking helps me think and my,
not me.
I can fucking think just fine at home
smoking a joint,
sitting there fucking watching Kobe or
something like that.
That's what you and I separate.
Right.
You liked the physical,
like the,
you know,
you,
you like the rush.
You're,
you're like the adrenaline junkies who
have kind of late raise their level.
And so it's not enough for you to just
sit in one place,
like you can do this and shocking that
you'll do it for three hours.
But then after this you probably do
something like Raza,
bare fucking knife,
hunt of species,
run
the hills.
Is that what you did at run hills in the
morning?
That's how far a couple miles at the
most I do because I'm.
That's real steep stuff.
Do you listen to anything or are you
today?
I did two that cheated.
I cheat when I listen to things.
I think it's cheating was supposed to be
alone with your Bosch supposed to be in
a meditative state where you're just
pushing yourself at a certain pace and
when you're listening to something,
especially something cool,
a distraction to the point where you
hear how heavier breathing,
but you don't think negatively about it
because you thinking about whatever the
music you're listening to is like.
It's really interesting because it's.
It's a nice trick because you can
actually work harder and not be bothered
by it because you're.
You're so tuned into the music that you
listened into or whatever it is.
You're really captivated with that you
can keep pushing,
but most of the time I like to do it
where I don't hear shit.
I just hear the pounding in my footsteps
and my breathing and also I have a
logical fear of mountain lions so I
don't want to.
Did you see that story about the fucker
outside of Seattle?
Scared the fuck out of me.
That was terrifying.
And those spots,
they weren't like.
Yeah.
They weren't gone.
Like,
Hey man,
we may encounter a mountain lion.
Do you know we did the right thing?
They swung the fucking bike.
Yeah.
At first they tried to get big because I
go to a place called the Canyon ranch
with the wife in Arizona and there's
like one trail where they have a sign
right at the gate that's like,
you know,
mountain lion area and it's got one of
those little graphic tutorials on what
you're supposed to do with your body.
If you encounter a mountain lion and you
know you're supposed to big up like the
way they're like,
hey man,
if a bear is charging at you,
you fucking big up at it or some shit.
Same thing here that get big up,
grab a stick,
make noise and shit like that.
And that story,
those guys did exactly as told and that
fucked off for a minute and then fucking
came back and that's when they start
swinging the bike at it.
Yeah.
And the one guy
took off,
um,
the one guy,
his friend got bit and dragged and then
he took off like he was going to get
help or I don't know what he was going
to do.
And the mountain lion said,
fuck this guy.
I'm gonna.
Go after you now.
And chased him,
chased him to wait to answer it.
It killed one guy down.
It didn't kill both guys fucked up.
One guy killed the other,
but one guy was down.
I mean obviously I'm just reading the
story.
I wasn't there,
but one guy was down.
Your deliberate,
the guy who survived,
he said that he felt the mountain lions
fucking jaws around his head and then to
go after his friend,
his friend ran and the mountain lion
tackled his friend and killed his friend
in the tackle or just a bit fucked him
up man.
And this was not even a big cat is a 100
pound cat and it was a macerated and it
wasn't doing well.
It was probably an old Kathy Ferrell.
They're all pharaoh.
Are they?
Yeah,
they're wild,
but it's like a.
what's the other word?
Rabid.
No.
Most likely just old and like they're
all fearful motherfucker there.
The wild probably couldn't catch rabbits
anymore and shit couldn't catch dear.
It was getting old.
You can't catch a rabbit and you're
like,
I'm going to go for this human with
machine under the air.
We're so slow.
We are so slow.
Is that right?
Oh my God.
The fastest human is a joke to a cat,
but it dear deers are so fast.
He received dear.
Try to run away from a wolf or something
like that in the video.
Not a wolf,
but I've seen deers runaway from us.
They were.
They were all around our house and
fucking.
Yeah,
you can't even come close to catch them.
A cat could catch a person so quick,
but even if.
Well,
all right,
so it's a 100 pound cat is still going
to be smaller than the dude that it's
attacking.
Did you ever get into fight with a house
cat?
Never.
No.
I've never gotten a fight with the house
to all animals.
I am as well,
but I had a feral cat.
I raised him.
They're all fucking good.
Farrah Joe?
No,
they're not.
All this is.
This is a cat that was actually born in
the wild.
Really?
Yeah.
He was born in the wild and I had a stay
with him in a room to get myself used to
him and get him used to me.
This is pre internet too,
by the way.
So this is like in the nineties and so I
locked myself in a bedroom with this
kitten and just brought a stack of
books.
I put a mattress in there,
brought a stack of books,
just hung out with this cat and every
time I'd get near this cat cat would
freak out and hissed at me and jump on
the curtains and fucking literally like
climb the blinds,
screaming and hissing,
and then I finally would get my hands on
him.
He would immediately start purring and
given in because once you realize it
wasn't trying to eat him,
that I was his friend,
I would pat him and he would put,
allowed an Auntie Kat would pro.
It was crazy.
Like I developed this bizarre bond with
this cat because the cat was so scared
of the world.
I mean he was that scared of every
action every time.
No.
And eventually calmed down and be like,
was the only one that could,
that could touch them though I was the
only person,
like my friends would come over.
He'd hiss at them.
He would like,
wow.
Like,
like let them know like bitch shit is
about to get really crazy.
Like I'm not a regular cat,
but I could go up to him and I could pet
them.
He was a feral cat,
you know what was my point?
Beginning this.
I Dunno what,
what did we were.
Oh,
I had to get them fixed.
This is what it was.
The cat.
I had to get them fixed and I had to
pick them up,
but I don't know how the fuck he knew
that something was going on.
Oh,
that's right.
Because I was trying to get them in a
laundry basket.
I was trying to put them in the laundry
basket because I wanted to bring him to
the doctors who tried who he trusts
comes at him with a fucking cake.
Not that deep into a relationship either
because he's the only like 10 or 11
months old.
He ran in my house,
man.
He's lifted his tail up and just
shooting piss on my walls.
I was like,
Hey,
you fuck dude.
He pissed all over the place.
By the time I realized like I had to get
him to a doctor.
You'd Piss to my house like 10 times
because they just piss in the house and
so.
And then I was worried like if you don't
get them quick enough,
like I've yet to clean everything up,
but deep clean all the carpets,
but if you don't get to him quick
enough,
he just thinks,
well he's spraying from now on,
even after you fix them that that can be
a problem.
So I tried to hold onto him and put him
in this laundry basket and he taught me
the fuck up.
He tore my arms up,
he just scratched and me and he was
remarkably strong.
Is a little cat.
And this was your friend,
like he was saying the same to me.
I thought you were my friend bitch.
Trying to stop.
I know what you fucking prick.
So I had a blanket on him.
He was hissing at me and trying to get
out of the room.
I had to throw a blanket at m and under
the blanket.
I scooped him up and I put them in the
laundry basket.
And then I slowly pulled the blanket out
so he didn't suffocate while keeping the
lid down.
And then tape the,
the uh,
the laundry basket up.
So I can put it in my car and he
wouldn't jump out in my car and call my
fucking face off while I'm trying to see
it in a Chevy chase movie.
Did you leave it at the vet and just
walk away the.
That was a good friend of mine who has
since passed on and it was a.
He was a really.
He that guy,
loved animals.
Eat the cat whisperer.
He know he knew how to take care of it.
He knew.
I told him the whole deal coming in and
you know,
he knew he knew how to handle it.
He's the only vet I've ever had.
Um,
cry with me over what animal.
I had a puppy that had distemper.
A friend of mine found these puppies at
a gas station.
Someone was given them away and he took
a bunch of them and he calls me up,
says,
hey man,
you want a puppy?
They were at the gas stations.
Said,
yeah man,
bring that puppy over here,
man.
The puppy,
just after like a couple of days of
being at the house,
we'd have these seizures like violent
seizures.
We just lie down and eyes would roll
back and you can just pet it a little
bit.
It would slowly come back.
Then it would be weak and delirious and
it would know it would happen.
And then towards the end it was having
them all day long.
I mean it was just all day long.
And that's distemper distemper.
So how does it manifest it?
Again,
it's just some horrible neurological
disease that dogs get and if they don't
get the right shots when they're young
they can get this and there's a bunch of
different horrible reactions and it's
fatal.
So I had to take him to the vet and the
vet was like,
there's really nothing we could do with
them.
He's having seat.
He was having seizures all night,
all night.
It was awful.
And he was like,
he's going to die any,
you know,
any hour now,
we're going to have to put him down.
So he puts them down and he comes out in
the hallway.
I mean,
I,
I held the dog,
I placed him down,
I gave him a kiss,
I said goodbye,
and he put the needle in the dog and put
the dog to sleep.
Then we both went outside.
Man.
He was just crying,
just weep.
You know,
the guys at the job or just loved.
He felt loved animals.
Man.
He had a ton of animals.
He had cats and dogs and all kinds of
shit.
And um,
he was killed by a drunk driver that
was,
you know.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it was rough.
That was a rough one.
I got an email,
I believe from his daughter.
It was a rough one.
The a super good dude,
man.
The WHO,
who are you crying more for the guy with
the dog because the dog.
What?
You started with the dog though.
You started getting teary.
The dog was a bummer,
but it was,
it was more of a bummer.
Even the way he was approaching it,
just human.
He was approaching it very humanly like,
yeah,
most doctors I guess or were expected
that they're like,
I'm sorry if this person is passed onto
the callous about it at all.
You know,
his,
his feelings about were super raw.
That's why I would imagine I would be as
a doctor just like,
I'm so pockets.
Ra did scared the fuck out of me with
marriage.
He,
he would talk to me about his divorce
and he,
he just,
he just grabbed me,
like,
grabbed me.
He goes,
don't you fucking get married?
Don't you ever do it?
Joking serious,
but he's like,
trust me,
you don't want to do that.
You don't want to have to go through
this kind of a breakup.
He goes,
he goes,
you got a girlfriend right now.
You break up with her.
What happens?
You get broken up.
That's it.
Get breakup,
and he goes,
you don't have to see them in court
every week for a year over and over
again while they're just trying to take
money from you and lying about what
you've done so they can get more money
from you.
He went through a bad one and I believe
some of his friends went through real
bad ones too,
and just,
he was one of those dudes.
I was like,
you know,
26,
27.
And I was like,
Jesus man,
you feel like this is a man of science
as a doctor.
He knows what he's talking about an,
you know,
a wise man who knew a lot of shit.
So when he,
you know,
I was a moron.
So he grabbed me.
Let's listen.
Don't fucking get married,
get married.
They got married,
he's just a,
you know,
he was just a guy that,
I mean,
I really firmly believe when it comes to
things like that,
there's just people that are supposed to
be doing what they're doing.
Right?
And he was the guy that was supposed to
be working with the animals like it.
It just worked,
man.
He had the heart for it.
Veterinarian,
you've probably seen how many animals
die.
How many animals injured and still the
guy's crying like a baby puppy is a baby
dog.
Nobody wants to see a baby with this
world without a chance.
So the dude's got his heart in the right
place.
That's the guy you want to bring your
animal to.
One hundred percent.
He's also the first guy that ever told
me,
don't get my dog fixed.
Why?
Well,
he said,
look,
he goes,
don't let your dog have babies,
don't be an asshole.
He goes,
but if you get your dog fix,
you've got to realize you're not going
to have any testosterone anymore.
It's going to be tired.
It's going to,
it's not going to be the same dog.
And I was like,
really?
And he's like,
yeah.
And so of course I got my dog faced and
just would not fucking listen to this
bag fixed.
I was trying to calm him down.
He was a pit bull and he was very,
uh,
aggressive when I want it.
Did calm him down,
but immediately lost most of his energy.
He didn't,
he just didn't have the same,
the same energy anymore.
It was kind of like bummed out.
It was weird.
The yellow lab that I had,
we had to,
like,
when I first met Jennifer,
my wife,
she got pregnant shortly after we met
Allah.
Yeah,
that's how fucking virile.
I'm like a,
like a cat.
So,
uh,
you know,
we,
we'd never,
like,
I'd never even a dog,
so
I was like,
we should get a dog to see if we'd be
good parents.
And so we went to the pet store in,
uh,
the Menlo Park Mall in New Jersey and
looked for yellow lab she had in her
head,
she's like,
I a yellow lab when I was a kid and
they're the best dogs for children's,
so let's go get a yellow lab.
I'd never had a dog in my life.
So I was like,
that sounds great.
I knew what they look like.
So we went to the pet shop,
try to find a yellow lab,
and we found this dog that was blonde
leggy yellow lab and they were marketing
it as a yellow lab,
but she'd been left behind.
All the other puppies had gone and she'd
been there perhaps a little too long.
Like,
you know,
she wasn't a dog yet,
but she was fucking on the,
you know,
uh,
what,
what was the Brittany Spears Song?
I'm not a girl,
not yet a womb.
And that's where the dog was,
she was too big for the fucking cage,
like her face was pressed up against and
no.
So we were like,
what about this dog?
And it was been priced down,
you could see like 2000 marked all the
way down to like 600 bucks.
And truly,
so we got that dog and you never see
like it was like something out of a
fucking cartoon because we were the ones
that were like,
get out of this cramped ass cage and
come with us out into the parking lot.
Dog instantly bonded with us.
He loved us.
So fucking much became so needy.
Um,
we called it scully,
we're big fans of the x files.
So uh,
after a week of having that dog and the
dog was a cup in our grill all the time,
just like,
thank you,
thank you for fucking getting me out of
there.
Like you are my people and Shit.
We were like,
we should get another dog to babysit
this dog.
This dog has a friend.
So we went,
instead of to the pet store,
we went to a breeder's Kendall,
like a pedigree place and uh,
they had puppies versions of fucking
yellow labs and they were adorable,
like fucking 10 of them falling all over
each other,
like an animated,
like a pixar movie.
And Jennifer picks up one and bonds,
but they're just like,
this is the one,
let's get this one.
I went over to the counter,
I was like,
all right man,
we just bought a dog the week before,
600 bucks.
And even then I was like 600 fucking box
man.
They,
he,
they,
they throw these things out,
you know,
we can get one of the free and shit.
But I was like,
I've never paid $600 for a dog.
So you know,
I went up to the counter expecting well
that's the rate,
I guess the going rate for yellow lab,
600 bucks.
So I went up to the counter and I was
like,
we'll take that one.
And The lady's like,
that'll be $4,000.
And it was like,
for all of them,
I just want one.
And she's like,
these are pedigree dogs,
and I just met Jennifer,
barely knew her so I couldn't turn
around and be like,
put that down.
That's too expensive.
I tried to represent.
So I was just like,
well,
4,000,
we're paying too low.
We are stealing from you.
We got that dog.
And to be fair,
we named a molder because again,
x files,
Fan scully,
and mulder and scully was just like
happy heart that just loved molder was
so smart and fucking thoughtful.
He wrote my four best movies.
That's why he died.
I made tusk and Yoga hosers like without
that dog writing for me.
How do you write for you?
It's a joke,
Joe.
He was fearful because he's just saying
he was so smart.
He was so smart.
How smart wedding.
He's so smart.
He wrote my last few scripts.
Joke didn't quite land,
so I was missing something.
I wasn't paying attention.
I didn't set it up properly and not a
fucking pro,
but in any event,
um,
he uh,
he was wonderful,
but we got them clipped and his demeanor
never really changed.
He was always very low key.
We called him kilroy because he'd go to
the other side of the bed and just look
up like this.
Yeah.
I got my massive snipped.
It didn't really change.
His personality stayed the same,
stayed the same,
but he was always kind of a mellow dog.
We got a very big dogs.
They don't like to do too much.
We got a rescue last year,
year and a half ago.
That was like when you mother died a
couple years ago.
Um,
uh,
he was,
he made it to 15,
which is like fucking old and for a big
dog too,
it's pretty deep.
Like a doctrinal stick around,
you know,
fucking like cancer,
but a fucking big dog like that.
Generally you don't make it past 10:11.
So we've got a lot of good years out of
him and stuff,
but it was fucking horrible when he
died.
I spent the last two years of scalies
life.
I'm almost as rehearsal for molder.
They're yellow labs.
So what usually goes first is the hips
and the back legs.
So scalies back legs when she just,
the rest of her body could work,
but she was literally dragging your
carcass.
What was wrong with her legs?
They just went.
Dr was like,
this just happens.
They're done.
And she was 12,
13.
So she'd made it a while,
but I will just stop working.
Just give out.
So the nerves start firing.
The legs stop.
There's no muscle left in language labs.
Yeah.
Wow.
So I put a scarf under her.
The back end of her called the magic
walking scarf and I would become the
back legs for her.
So she would walk and I would be the
back legs and fucking get shit and piss
all over and stuff.
But I'd doug the dog.
So it was no big deal.
So I did that all the way up to when
Scott passed away.
And then molder was always very healthy
and fucking mobile and loved walking and
stuff.
Super Athletic Dog.
Jen would take them up on Runyon Canyon
and shit.
Then one day he had his back,
legs started dropping and your fucking
heart sinks because your leg.
All right.
Scully.
She wasn't that active,
so when she lost her legs,
like as a bummer,
but she wasn't like the run around dog
because she used to chase moldy,
you throw ball molded would run after
and she would just chase molder and
tried to bite his back legs to prevent
him from doing it because she wasn't
nearly as fast molder was the go out
guy.
He loved to fucking be active.
So when his back legs,
when it was like heartbreaking,
and then he stuck around for two more
years.
So it was literally two years of me Walk
Magic walking,
scarfing,
uh,
this dog.
Uh,
then he got to the place where he did,
you know,
it wasn't just temporary,
but when you were talking about it
sounded so familiar,
he would do that thing,
this thing where he would be like,
oh,
and this will go on for fucking hours.
And you could tell it was exhausting him
and he couldn't fucking move.
So,
you know,
everyone in the family was like,
it's time to let them go.
And this was like when he first lost his
legs,
but I was like,
are you fucking shit man,
if like if I lose my legs,
you better fucking put a magic walking
scarf around my fat ass and not fucking
turned me over to the needle.
I like,
this is fucking family here.
So I held onto them for as long as I
could until he got to that place where
he was like an obvious fucking pain.
And I remember I shot a video of it.
I'm on my phone,
I still have it and it's not,
you know,
it sounds fucking cruel or sick.
But like it was,
it was just a reminder because every
once in a while like I knew eventually
that we would have to put them down and
like,
it's such a weird relationship where one
day you're like,
I love you to death and I love you so
much,
I have to fucking kill you.
So I had that video on my phone for the
longest time so that when in like the
wee small hours of the morning I would
wake up and be like,
you killed your best fucking friend.
I could watch that video and be like,
you had to.
He had like keep wanting to go.
So it was sick.
So the doctor came over,
we got the vet to come over to the house
and um,
it was like a big deal.
It was like we all knew it was coming
and shit.
I was flying home from a Gig and I kept
telling him like,
Jennifer,
like,
don't do anything just like freeze,
like I'll be there as quickly as
possible.
And so like Dr Kumar who is our vet,
uh,
was scheduled to come over and that last
fucking hour was probably hands down the
most of my life,
man,
because we all knew it was coming in
your program to,
to stop that at all cost program to keep
people around and keep yourself around.
And yet,
like we were just all sitting there
loving on them,
knowing that like at the time Dr Kumar
gets here,
it's all done.
It was fucking hard as artist thing in
the world to do and he was still in pain
the whole time.
So even though you knew you were doing
the right thing,
it was like,
like I understand why that vet,
you know,
got emotional stuff.
So in any event that we lost that dog a
while ago,
a couple of years ago,
and on my 45th birthday when we were
back east doing a show with the count
basie theater in red bank,
we're doing yoga,
hosers screening it and we were shooting
it for the kind of compliment show.
So I was driving down the highway in
Middletown,
New Jersey.
And I passed the place where we had
bought molder.
And so I was just like,
you know what man,
I'm 45 years old.
I'm a grown ass fucking man.
Like I,
I make my own money.
I can do whatever I want.
I'm going buy a fucking dog.
I'm going to replace that dog.
Like,
I'm going to get me another yellow lab
and we've had two dogs since then,
right.
We got a Louis,
which is a chocolate lab and check he
was my favorite little miniature
doctrine,
but like I missed molder and I was like,
I'm going to replace them.
And then uh,
so I went in to the pet store,
same place,
the puppies,
puppies,
where we had gotten older and uh,
I walked in and I didn't see any yellow
labs and there was nobody at the
counter.
So I was like,
all right,
I'll get outta here.
And The lady comes out and she's like,
can I help you?
And I was like,
um,
yeah,
it's was like,
wow.
I honestly,
I came looking for a yellow lab,
but like,
you guys don't have any.
She's like,
we have one in the back.
And so I was like,
I'm okay,
can I meet him?
She said,
oh,
sit right down.
They put you into a little room and
stuff like that.
Then they bring the dog in and in my
head I'm like,
I'm counting the money out,
you know,
I'm sure it's inflation has hit the dog
market so it's going to be more than
4,000,
but I'm ready to fucking go and then
they bring in this puppy and he was
good.
He was a good dog.
He's very bouncy and energetic as fuck.
You could cut this dog's nuts off and it
wouldn't have mattered,
but he wasn't molder.
He looked exactly like him,
but he wasn't him.
It was this weird lesson of like when
it's gone,
it's gone and you need to appreciate it
more when it's there because,
you know,
they tell you this from a young age,
but like everything,
everything dies and nothing's fucking
replaceable at the end of the day.
So as I sat there playing with his dog,
I was like,
it's not like it's not him.
It's never going to be him.
And I would sit there,
raise the dog his whole life expecting
to be something else.
Somebody else out there wants this
fucking hyper poppy.
Not Me,
but I took a picture of it because I
was,
I'm a fuck with my wife,
and so I took a picture of the dog and
texted a tour.
My wife instantly calls me back and be
like,
do not buy a fucking dog.
You can't do that.
I said,
I'm a 45 year old grown ass man.
I could do what I want.
She goes,
no,
we have two older dogs at home and it'd
be so unfair to bring a new dog into the
house,
and she hit me on that level going like,
you know what?
You're absolutely right.
She's like,
you got to wait until one of the other
dogs dies.
Then you could buy a new dog as it fair
enough and two days later,
my wife we've,
right before we go home to Los Angeles,
like uncharacteristically says,
there's this dog in my twitter feed.
Look at it,
and it looked like this,
a macerated fuck.
It looked like the dog from the Sarah
Mclaughlin Song.
I just didn't ask like the dog from the
haunted mansion ride dog you see on a
fucking can,
just like bones with a dog head on it
and shit,
and I was like,
that's so sad.
She's like,
they found this dog was tied up outside
of kill shelter with a rope and was
trying to be all through the rope and so
these people,
they took it home to foster it but they
can't keep it.
They already have six dogs so they need
a home for this dog.
And I'm like,
okay,
what does that have to do with us?
And she was just like,
we should be the home.
I'm like,
what happened to like,
we can't get a new dog because it'd be
unfair to the other two old dogs.
She's like,
Kevin,
look at this dog.
So we went over to the lady's house and
saw this dog that sounded like the
distemper case that you described with
the puppy.
This dog was fucking dead.
Three balls in the grave just weekly
looked up at us and fucking weekly went
right back down and shit look like hell,
look.
Like honestly looked like a skeleton
with just a dog had like glued to it,
but heartbreaking,
you know,
and so instantly I'm like,
dogs on death watch.
If we bring this dog home,
it's going to help these people,
you know,
so they don't have to take care of yet
another dog,
but this dog is going to die on our
watch dogging going to make it look how
fucking lethargic is.
When we picked her up,
she felt like she was like 12 pounds and
this is a dog that's mixed pit pit,
fucking head artist Shit and shit.
She was all like a Mesa.
We took her home after a week,
man,
that's when she started like getting an
alert and shit that had told me.
He goes,
I said,
what do we do for,
how do we fatten her up?
And he goes,
give her eggs is eggs.
He goes,
yeah,
my eggs.
Good for giver protein or fat and Rob,
but also be good for a coat.
He'll bring her hair back.
All right.
So I started making eggs every morning.
It's just scrambled eggs and I'd give
her the edge,
like suck it up and shit,
and then I was like,
these eggs are so plain,
so I started putting like bacon and ham
and cheese.
Started making omelets for the dog and
the dog got fucking fat,
quick healthy all the for.
Came back.
Took the dog into the vet and the
doctors is like,
what the fuck happened?
His dogs dogs like 90 pounds.
I was like,
you said to give her eggs,
but given her omelets every morning he
goes,
I didn't say to cook the eggs.
I was like,
what do you mean?
He's like,
you just break an egg and put it in a
bowl to fucking dog.
They just eat it like you made it eggs.
I was like,
yeah,
got in a fight with my wife many times
because she was like,
you never made me an Omelet.
And I was like,
well,
the dog is dying here.
So that dog,
we nursed it back to health.
We named it Mad Martin Marty and she
says,
we all know her history.
Like she figures she's six years old.
The doctor guest,
she's clearly a street dog and she lives
in her head.
I guess the same way that you described
did everything was fucking terrifying.
Took a long time for the fucking trust
and she loves my fucking wife.
Like she must understand that like she
was the one that fucking got her into
this house and shit.
So when other people come into the room
just goes fucking nuts because she's
very fucking protective of the wife and
shit like that.
She could flip fast and recently we had
an incident in the house because she
doesn't get along with two other dogs,
so we have to put up all these like what
we call a checkpoint charlies in the SC
series of.
Yeah,
dog gates.
The dogs,
cadaver dogs.
They're all female.
Three females that I've had problems
with that in the past females did not.
They don't give up the Alpha position
like males would give up.
Like if you have a couple males and the
boss will run the house.
Like I have two males.
One of them is 120 pounds.
He's,
he's a massive and the other one is a.
She blino English bulldog mix.
They have a very clear,
you know,
there's a one is way bigger so there's
no issues.
So who's the boss?
The ones the boss,
but females,
they don't.
They don't give up on that.
They just like,
I'm the author.
Keep going after each other.
It's really common,
really common with females,
especially if you leave them alone for
any length of time.
They fuck each other up,
man.
That it happened.
Not on my watch.
Thank God it happened.
Did it happen?
I asked her.
I used to have two females was terrible.
Terrible.
Ours was.
Ours happened when I was away.
I was just doing a show two,
three weeks ago.
I was in Vancouver,
a few Canadian shows that night.
My kids
and then she was like Marty and check.
He got into a and I was like,
what?
And check.
He is literally shine and adoption.
She's a minute reduction and Marty is
the size of a football and mixed pit,
so they've seen each other that walk
with each other.
We walk them in the hills,
the walk side by side and shit.
But the moment you get in that house,
it just territory of why?
Because they want your love.
Your love feels so good.
Like if you come over and massage them
and another dog comes by,
you might stop massaging them and start
massaging that other dogs.
They'll attack that dog.
I'm not kidding.
That's because the dog's a hundred
percent.
Yeah.
Especially dogs that had been
mistreated.
So jealous.
Yes.
My dog that had an issue with this was
also a dog that I got from the pound.
I got a couple from the one from the
street.
She was covered in mange and I nursed
her back to health in a similar story.
She was two years old.
She had a Greg Nipples,
so she had had puppies.
Wait,
wait,
wait.
This dog has also ics.
What'd you call it?
The standard extended extended.
I said,
ma'am,
I have the wrong foot.
They said like,
that doesn't necessarily mean like in
Marty's case he was like,
I was like,
did she have puppies?
Because it looked like she had nipples,
but he was like,
no.
It's also some cases that happens with
dogs that are associated,
but I can't imagine a street dog didn't
get laid,
you know?
I don't know.
I mean the vet said that she had had
puppies.
I Dunno,
I dunno why he determined that.
I think he had said because the nipples,
they were hanging low,
like I always have it.
Um,
but the two females,
like the male got along great with both
dogs.
He had no problems with them,
but those females,
man,
they would fight all the fucking time
and they would fight whenever one of
them,
when someone come over to get pet,
like they got into a big fight once
because the pool guy came over and the
pool guy was like,
Hey,
what's up?
Kids?
And he pat one of the dogs over the
other,
the other one.
And so they started going after each
other.
They're like,
fuck you.
No,
And you know,
I get this,
call him,
man,
your dogs are about to fuck each other
up over the pool guy.
I'm like,
Oh my God,
you're so guy.
So I had to keep the girls separate.
We were keeping them separate with
gates,
but you know,
somebody turned back and the two wound
up in the same space and fucking went at
it and so one dog's way bigger than the
other.
And so the big dog little dog up by her
hind quarters and was shaking the leg
shakes a toy.
But meanwhile shecky was the little one
is she has no napoleon complex so she's
got no idea of like,
you're bigger than me.
She didn't give a fuck.
So as the dog,
as Marty is swinging,
shecky the little dog,
the little dog is swinging from side to
side brightener and then swinging to the
other side and biting her.
She wouldn't go down dude.
Like I imagine if somebody bit me in the
ass and shook me from side to side,
I'd be like,
you when.
But this dog was just like,
fuck fucking hell's are a stab at the.
She kept trying to go right back at her.
So when I came home it was fucking
heartbreaking because I'd heard they got
in a fight and my daughter was like,
she's got stitches and stuff.
So I was prepared for stitches,
but when I got home it was like it.
It looked fucking terrible.
Like she is.
She looked like a fucking walrus from
Tusk,
like a Frankenstein version of her lane
was the other dog.
She had pieces of her like missing
chunks out of sketchy and she was like,
she knew she got in trouble because
Jennifer like put her into what we call
chickens,
prisons.
The other side of the gate where you
lured the dogs in the chicken and then
you're locked in the bathroom and you
could still see everybody else,
but there's a gate keeping you on that
side of the room.
So she went to jail for that.
And you could tell she felt fucking bad
about it.
But does it linger like you seem to know
more about dogs?
That little dogs always going to
remember that fight.
They're both gonna.
Remember it?
Yeah.
If you leave them alone,
they're going to do it again.
The girls,
if you brought home a,
an extra wife,
how do you think that would work out?
That's exactly how it's like with dogs.
They don't know that they told you that.
Dr Craig,
my friend who died.
Yeah,
he,
uh,
he just said you can't have two girls.
He goes,
just,
they're just gonna.
They're going to go at it.
He goes more often than not,
he goes like,
you leave them alone.
You have a nice big yard.
Doesn't matter because they're going to
find out.
I want to sit there.
Why you sitting there?
That's my spot.
That's my boy.
Dogs won't do that to no boy,
dogs,
cats or other shit.
I can do that.
They can fight.
But boy dogs.
If the alpha.
This is according to dog people,
not me.
I don't really know what I'm talking
about.
But what is the way it's been explained
to me is that boy,
dogs,
for the most part,
with few exceptions,
exceptions will pick an alpha.
Alpha would lead the pack.
Then unless he's challenged by a new dog
or one of the dogs gets bigger or
something happens and he gets older,
unless there's some sort of a shifting
of the chain of command,
he will remain the Alpha forever.
He's the Alpha,
he's the big dog.
So I didn't know this about the office
shit.
And with scully.
Um,
I was again,
a new dog owner,
right?
So I would go to La Scala and mold out
and scaly would barge through the door.
He's the alpha.
First she was,
she's the alpha.
So I what I would,
and I didn't know this until later in
life later in her life,
what I would get like fucking shitty
about it.
Like,
hey man,
first.
And so I'd hold her back and let him
out.
And the betrayal on her face and the
confusion on mother's face of like,
bro,
Bro.
No,
no,
no.
Let her go.
Let her go,
Bro.
Isn't it funny how we attached these
human characteristics to animals?
We decide that we're going to stop
bullying amongst like I know the order
of things.
You should go first.
Bullying and grade school,
bad bullying and dogs.
You Ain't gonna do shit about it.
You just let it,
let that go.
Just don't let them fight with each
other.
But I,
my,
my two,
my two older dogs,
they own the only ones that have issues.
Marshall's,
the younger dog.
He runs circles around everybody.
When I opened the door to feed them,
the big one comes in first every time.
And if the little ones to close the
door,
he'll fucking sideswipe bitch.
I'm eating first as we would clear
rules.
But I let them do it.
They don't fight with each other,
you know,
they,
they're,
they're cool with everything.
But this is just the,
the,
the leadership
that they've established and it's one of
those things that like hit me in the
wrong way because I'm not an animal.
You know what?
I'm sad.
I'm like,
I like,
they've obviously got a system down.
They've worked it out.
Everything's fucking cool.
My friend Whitney Cummings knows way
more about dogs and animals than I do.
She actually has like a horse that she
raises that's like a rescue horse.
She rides it with no saddle and she has
a bunch of dogs and weight rescue horse.
Somebody like gunbarrel?
No,
it's a,
it's a horse.
I think they use them for movies and
stunt horses.
And stuff like that.
They don't have one person who owns
them.
Some horses get abandoned and she
rescued this one horse.
So very similar to what happens with
dogs.
Someone abandons a horse,
horses get abused.
In fact,
I was talking to cat Zingano the other
day too,
is one of the top UFC bantamweight
fighters and she was talking about
equine therapy too,
that she's worked with horses and takes
care of horses and there's something
about a human bond with a horse.
You're petting a horse and riding a
horse and feeding a horse is like a very
good love bond that people develop with
horses.
But in Whitney knows a shitload about
animals.
My point she,
when I talked to her about her dogs,
she's like,
she goes,
well,
I'm the boss.
She goes,
I don't walk around them.
I walked through them.
I've walked through them.
I pad out of my fucking way like we have
a real clear,
like there's a power structure in the
house.
Whitney's the top boss and then all the
dogs have to just deal with her.
So she's,
she's the 100 percent.
She pushes him out of the way she
decides when they eat.
She makes them sleep and pens like she,
she.
Oh really?
Yeah.
She gives them rules.
Still a lot of structured.
Pretty gangster.
Yeah.
She's uh,
she's not want to be mothered in that
way.
You get your,
get your dogs.
She's like,
they're not people.
And we attached these human
characteristics and needs to them and
that's not what they want,
what they want.
It's order and they want you to be.
They want love and a lot of affection
and they want exercise and all those
other great things in good food.
But they also want order and her order
is,
she's the fucking boss.
She's the boss.
That makes sense.
It totally makes sense.
Yeah.
She's read a shitload of books on it.
I've read a couple books like way,
way back in the day on dogs.
I read some books on dogs,
but I don't know enough.
All my information species picked up
from fucking vets and also probably a
lot of theories that I stitched together
for me to project onto the animals,
like fucking crazy.
Do you give your dogs boys and shit like
that?
Voices?
Yeah.
Like do you do the dog's life for your
wife and stuff?
Like I'm always like,
no,
you don't.
I do sometimes for Marshall because he
so silly because he's such a silly dog,
so you'll be like,
oh,
you're a silly.
There you go.
Bugging my voice for Shecky is I check
him in my world.
The little doctrine calls me the man.
She doesn't know my name.
She just knows me as the man.
She knows my wife has that lady,
so she's always there.
Sick
man.
He's home.
Oh,
I love the man.
He's the pits and food because I.
I wonder how they view me.
Did they view me as an Alpha because I'm
the guy that's like,
I'll take you out a walk.
I'm going to
this deeper.
Your larger and you would be the most
intimidating if you had to fight to the
death,
but they don't see me like that because
they've never even seen me be mad,
but I'm always like to hear your voice.
You have a fight with my wife and like
you guys are arguing,
yelling at each other for sure,
but the fact that you have a deep voice
mean that it,
that it shows your mail,
that's enough for them to.
Not yet but are all right,
but let's say like Chucky I've had for
13 years,
over 13 years.
This little dog knows,
like I got him wrapped around my finger.
I couldn't do anything.
I want the way you talk and way you
look.
Yeah.
If a guy the size of Lebron James was
right next to you with is fucking crazy.
Deep voice and super powerful body and
he talked to that dog.
That dog would listen to him.
Oh,
we're going to be like,
oh,
that's the boss finally.
Unreal,
man.
Yeah.
Well,
there's just a hundred percent.
No doubt about it.
That's a way bigger organism than that
dog.
Right?
And it's talking with his deep voice and
it has confidence.
Like,
Yep,
whatever you need.
I'm just going to lay down right here,
but if you were like some little,
what's that fella like?
Give me a small person's name.
Her villa.
Shay's the no,
no,
no.
I meant like very thin wispy Tony.
Tony Hinchcliffe.
Well Tony Hinchcliffe.
So when Tony was 20,
let's say that and he tried to,
you know,
talk to the same dog in the same room.
The dog would be like dismissive,
like something used to Lebron James.
Give me directions.
I have called that a boy's,
he'll you call that timber.
I might be able to eat,
you know,
so I think like with Whitney's case,
she doesn't leave any room for any gray
area.
She just runs the roost but she's super
affectionate with her daughter.
So all these pictures on instagram or
her cuddling with her dog.
She,
she clearly loves dogs,
but she's cage to the book.
She's like,
how to take care of your fucking cage.
Some people sleep with their dogs and
shit,
which is cool,
but the dogs are farting in your face
and stuff and you're trying to sleep and
they're snoring.
Like you're losing sleep for a dog.
I don't know about all that.
I don't know if that's the move bro.
You literally cried about a puppy.
I know,
but now you're gonna.
Tell me like I draw a lot of dog farts
on care.
I'll fucking cute to have your own bed.
Dude.
It's over there.
You go over there.
I'm in here.
Let me call me boo with you.
They take their dog shit smeared.
Pause and rub your sheets with them and
touch your pillow.
That's part of the fleet part of the
deal.
That's why they don't sleep in the bed.
Man.
This is ridiculous.
Sleep in the bed with the dog.
She got very short hair too.
When I was in high school,
my dog had fleas real bad and I had
fleas in my carpet.
It was fucking rough,
man.
I would go through the house and I would
find fleas on my calves like in the walk
on my carpet from my bed to the bathroom
in the hallway.
I would have fleas on my leg.
When I lived with my parents in New
Jersey at 21 Jackson Street,
we were kept people.
He turned out flea me.
Motherfuckers in here comes,
watch this.
I am about to pull out my dick and throw
it on the table against your own fleet.
We had cats and the cats,
a lot of them are outside so they would
come in with
fleas and we'd never had pets when I was
a small child.
We didn't start getting cats in our
house.
Tell us about 12,
13 or something.
So my mom like having no prior
experience with cats and stuff.
Decided that like the flea problems are
too much.
We have to give the cats baths with,
you know,
fucking flee shampoo and stuff.
So you'd do that.
And cats don't like to be anywhere near
water and shit.
Like oh my God,
it was terrible.
Get scratched up while I know because my
mother also insisted that I clipped the
cat's toenails first.
She wanted them like declawed and I was
like,
you can't do that.
Been like,
cats need their fucking clause in nature
and shit.
She was like,
well you have to clip the cuts.
Kona toe nails.
They do that at the vet all the time.
So you know,
you take off the hooky point part man.
Right.
And then you don't like that,
they don't like it,
but they like it better than if you took
the fucking clause out altogether and
shit.
Um,
so I used to bathe the cat and then when
you bathed in the cat with flea shampoo,
every fucking flee comes to the surface
to try to live.
And so they would fill the fucking sink
in the water and you know,
they're dying in the water because the
shampoo is in the water as well.
But my mom would always take it a step
further.
She would give me a set of tweezers and
she would be like,
get that one and I would fucking pull a,
a flea off the cat and you have to press
really fucking hard because they're kind
of flat to kill them.
Otherwise they just jump away and then
come back to the cat when it's dry.
That was like my,
it wasn't a set schedule.
Like every Tuesday night I made the
cats.
But once a week my mom would be like,
you have to bathe the cats.
So once that included the fleeing,
did you ever get rid of the fleas?
Never ever,
you know,
what got rid of the fleas were,
there was a storm.
They eventually,
it was the Nor'easter of 92 on the east
coast.
We had this big storm,
like it was Kinda like a Hurricane
Sandy,
but though not as big and our town got
flooded including like our neighborhood
and we had like 30 outdoor cats that my
dad would feed.
We were finding those cats for like
weeks after the flood.
People will be like,
we found six of your cats under our
house.
And we're like,
they're not our cats.
Number one,
they arrive or drowned.
Dead Lot of these poor cats on fences.
Did I hit that maximum impact?
Dead.
Very theatrical.
Um,
we found a few like holding on to
fences,
you know,
like escape.
The floodwaters was fucking
heartbreaking.
Smart ones went up and trees though.
And they stuck around and live.
But after that flood,
no fleas whatsoever,
but not nearly as many cats either.
That might've helped Christ.
Yeah.
Forever cat guy.
Or were you always a dog person?
I've always had cats.
Yeah.
I've always had both.
Pretty much.
That's why I really don't want to die at
the paws of a mountain cat.
Well,
I just know what they are.
Nasty.
No fucking super predators.
They catch deer with their face when
they killed deer with their face.
They,
they use their face to kill a deer.
I mean,
they bite it in the neck.
They tackle it and take it down.
That's why mountain cats are scary.
They're unbelievably powerful.
I had this Guy Donnie Vinson in here,
yesterday's a outdoor maker,
and he was talking about a cat that
these guys had hunted and killed.
They weighed 200 pounds and it was two
years old,
two years old,
and weigh 200 pounds.
It had been eating so many deer,
just that it was just this massive
jacked fucking Super Predator has just
roaming through the forest and ask those
guys in Seattle that survived.
The one guy that survived,
the one guy that died from that attack,
the mountain bike attack are fucking
terrifying animals.
Why?
Um,
so do you think they attack the people
just because they were like,
we're fucking hungry?
Yes.
It was just always a macerated I think
that's exactly.
He tried to eat them.
He wanted to eat them.
He was starving and so he knew that they
were an organism.
There weren't a normal thing on the
diet,
but it was so risky.
It was so rather I'm hungry that it was
willing to take those risks.
It was willing to go after some people
even though the people are swinging
their bike at it,
and that was part of the story that got
me the most because you're like,
that's what I would do.
I guess I would swing the bucket and you
would think this bike will save me,
but no,
it brings it back to my story about the
house cat.
When I threw the blanket on him,
dude,
I couldn't believe how strong he was.
He was so strong because he was fighting
for his life.
He thought I was going to kill him,
so I'm trying to stuff them into this
laundry basket.
He's going fucking crazy and all his
thinking is,
what is this cat weigh eight pounds,
like maybe eight pounds.
I'm fucking terrified of them to do is
catch a juggler.
It's a little more complicated than
that.
Is it?
Yeah.
It'd be hard.
What do you mean?
Put your hand on it.
Stopped the bleeding and it's not going
to kill you like a lion kills you,
but what if it got both sets of clause?
What?
Alright.
When a tiger claws onto your juggling.
Shredding it in so many different
directions.
Really it's not.
It's mostly give can be killed by.
She'll scratches.
It's.
It's very rare that someone gets killed
by a house cat.
All right.
Here.
Here's the situation.
You're fucking a house cat and it
reaches back and claws into your femoral
artery,
but you should let it go.
But a cat.
It's clearly not continually this point.
Clearly if you fought to the death with
a house cat,
I would bet on you you would win,
but it would be ugly,
but it would be.
But what the force that you can generate
is lethal.
The force that it can generate is
ferocious,
but nonlethal like if you put me in a
room with a cat,
I'm coming out of that fucking room
hundred percent of the time with a house
cat.
It's going to be dead.
I'm going to kill that cat.
Yeah,
but it's gonna fuck me up in the
process,
so scratched up.
I'm going to have bloody hands.
I might get my face clawed up,
but I'm going to kill it as soon as I
think gets to half my size.
I'm dead.
Is that my size?
Yeah.
Fit.
Not even one quarter of my size.
When I say it's a 50 pound cat,
I'm fucked because it's too powerful.
Fifty pound cat is like 150 pound,
200 pound man.
Plus they have fangs.
They have claws that it would be much
stronger and faster.
You wouldn't be able to stop it from
biting you and clawing at you.
It would be too big and if you've got to
100 pounds,
you're fucking dead.
If it gets to 200 pounds,
your super dead,
you're dead quick.
It'll crush your head.
It's going to grab a hold of your neck,
it's going to crush her esophagus
crusher,
windpipe,
and it's going to.
It has sensors in its tafe like certain
certain big cats.
They can feel where your veins are with
their teeth,
their teeth have like a a sense where
we're like,
you know how like you ever eat something
and you feel like a hard piece of
something,
like maybe you're eating a crab or
something like that little piece of
shell gets in there.
You've got to move that shell around
inside your mouth while you're chewing
and you get the shell over here.
That sense of moving your tongue and
knowing what that.
That cat has a with a with a fan and
knows how to hit like an antelopes
juggled a lion when it bites into
something,
so tell you where the blood is.
It feels where the veins are,
think he does,
but it doesn't want the blood.
Right.
It's just like,
I know that if I break this thing,
this thing will stop moving and I can
eat it.
It's mostly cut off the air if you see
mostly what they do.
Mostly what they do is crush the neck.
They there.
It's more of that than it is like cut
you like a knife would cut your juggler.
It's mostly crushing everything.
Few.
If you had the presence of mind,
like let's say this thing is crushing
your windpipe,
can you reach up and choke a cat to
death?
I don't think so.
Why?
Because I think they're too strong.
I think.
What do you mean straws?
They're too strong.
So would it be swarmed at you or
something or too much?
Muscle or muscle?
Both of you put your fingers in his
eyes.
That would be one of the only things
that I could think might have an effect,
but it would probably just be a second
one as the second one.
You Jam your finger up the cat's ass.
Instantly.
It stops their son.
How are you going to get way back down?
That's what I do with my last few
breaths,
dude.
No Way.
A few feet away and you same way that
little kitten was attacking you.
It's like I'm a fuck you up.
I would leave this life and the mouth of
a big cat with my fingers up its ass.
It would know that I was there before I
left this fucking world because if you
stick your finger up a dog's ass,
it breaks.
It's concentration doesn't.
No,
no.
That's an old wives' tale.
Know you ever see two pit bulls fighting
each other?
Stick your finger up their ass.
Watch what happens.
You're holding your finger in the ass,
but dogs biting another dog.
That's what's happening.
Nothing.
They don't do shit.
They want each other.
I've always read that.
If you stick your finger up,
a dogs ass instantly stopped what it's
doing.
If you've got a bitch ass dog that
doesn't have to help drive it ain't the
dog and you.
There are certain dogs that are going to
hang on.
They're just going to hang on and you.
You can pick holes in the presence of
mind to be like,
I know your fingers in my ass,
but biting this other dog is the most
important thing in the world.
They're driven because you want to pick
it.
They're very driven.
Your cat may want to kill you.
Study says that in a heartbeat.
I believe that they would absolutely
kill you if you are big enough or if
they're big enough.
Rather,
look at the photo that she was doing.
One hundred percent would kill you if
they could as the joker of cats.
What?
The cat?
Yeah.
If you.
If you were the size of the cat and the
cat was the size of you,
you'd be dead.
Honest percent.
Yeah.
One hundred percent.
What have you were his friend from the
beginning?
They don't have friends like that.
Like if I have a joke in my act about
how you could have a dog and have a pet
hamster and that hamster could live a
long and healthy life in the same house
running around.
If you've got a good dog and you train
that dog,
if you got a cat that lives in a house
with a hamster on the hamster,
has an hour to live.
If it's lucky,
there's no such thing as a cat at.
Also has a pet hamster that's a dead
animal.
Next to that cat.
They kill everything.
Everything they can,
canaries lizards,
whatever the fuck you leave around that
they can kill.
That's what they like to do.
Like to kill Shit.
Why do we have this relationship with
them then?
Because they are small and like bitches,
where the bitches to the cats,
we feed them.
We give them free massages.
They don't do anything for us.
All they do is curl up to you and go and
willing you to touch me and you are
going to do a view to.
He didn't say he loves you.
If you die,
the first thing that happens to you when
he dies,
the cats eat your face.
Is that true?
Yeah.
They get hungry.
They start eating your lips if they
can't get to anything.
Yeah.
People that find dead bodies.
What does the sun nearly killed by a
stray cat left covered in blood because
cats are mean and all an honest.
I thought.
Wait a second.
Wait.
Go back to what we said before.
We've read that.
Um.
Which part?
I don't know.
The thing you just said it was shocking.
Yeah,
you totally took my head out the game.
But it was about the fuck,
it was just about the dogs.
The cow,
the cat was as big as me.
The cat would get 100 percent.
You have a cat was.
But what about a dog?
If a dog was as big as dogs can be giant
and still be your friend.
That's why a woman could be like 90
pounds and have a 200 pound mastiff and
that dog will totally listened to her.
She raised that door from the time it
was a puppy and she can ride it like
Khaleesi Roger Track it if she wanted
to.
Totally.
But that doctor listened to her.
If you have a cat that big,
like you better hope that that cat just
decides to not kill you because one day
it might just get bored and they're not
planning ahead.
You know,
they're not like investment bankers.
They just don't like the way you're
moving one day,
just jump on you and just fuck you up
and kill you.
It's true.
I've been hit by cats like,
not like in the face,
but like you're sitting there and all of
a sudden they're like,
yeah,
no.
Good reason,
so if you were,
if that cat was eight times its size,
did you see that video of the guy who
was a,
a long time animal trainer and he
trained Lyons and he trained this line
for like 10 years and he's in the pen
with the thing and the thing just looked
at him funny and the guy starts backing
up.
It's like,
oh no,
when he runs and this line just chases
after this motherfucker grabs him by the
head and drags him around and apparently
he survived the lion,
let them go and somehow know that they
got the line away from him and got the
guy to a hospital.
But he was an older guy,
I want to say he was deep into his
sixties and his line was dragging him
around by his fucking head.
And this is a line that he had trained
in that.
What happened to,
um,
what's her name?
Melanie Griffith.
Like her mom Tippi
hedren was into old animals.
Lions.
Yeah.
And I think Melanie Griffith Gut,
uh,
bit or scratched as a child in her early
teens or something like that.
She had to have a facial reconstructive
surgery.
I believe so.
Whoa.
I never heard.
There's a movie that they shot.
They shot,
I forget the name of the movie,
but they shot the movie of them
interacting with the documentary about
them living with big cat.
Yeah.
When you watch the video online,
it doesn't even look real.
Like,
wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Is that real?
That's really Melanie Griffin with lions
and tigers and shit.
How many different cats that they have?
There was a lot,
right?
I want to say there was five,
so the kind of thing you just asked
people get my cats.
I'm a big kid and the Griffin said,
looking at the article right now,
he's a wizard with that.
Google will pull it up so we could see
the photos.
It's so preposterous.
Look at that.
That's crazy.
It's crazy.
She's fun.
That looks.
It shouldn't that be the way life is.
You imagine if you were a burglar and
you broke into that fucking house.
Holy Shit.
What a mistake.
I imagine you break into a house and you
see a 600 pound African male lion just
looking at you with that gigantic head
of death.
Fuck man.
The bizarre tale of Melanie Griffith and
her pet lion did they talk about the
attack,
but look at her spitting water into the
big cats.
No one in the family was ever injured by
the lion.
No one will buy that line by that one.
Oh my neil.
But Neil certainly could have killed any
of them at a moments notice.
At one point he did attack Ron Oxley,
his owner during a dinner party at his
home.
Fuck all of that.
After Neil,
the family went on to adopt numerous big
cats,
but it's resulted in a series of serious
injuries.
Fifty seven years old,
melanie has learned from the experience
and runs a sanctuary.
She finds a sanctuary for 32 big cats.
Oh my God.
Look at that thing on the desk.
That is so insane.
First of all,
does that thing need exercise?
Just to keep it shit together?
Look at the size of that fucker.
How much you think you got to feed that
guy?
A lot dude.
And only meat.
They are obligate carnivores,
you know,
they're not like a dog looking at how
tall he is in the fridge.
Huge animal man.
And that's the point where I'm like,
I'm not working here anymore.
It's just laying around their house.
Look at the fucking muscles on that
thing.
And do you think they're like cats?
Like will they only shit where they're
supposed to?
Shit a.
That shit's wants.
Yeah.
The thing about the size of this cat,
I mean this is crazy.
It's so big.
It's.
It must be a thrill to be around
something that could just kill you at
any moment.
And apparently lions in particular are
pretty cool with people.
Yeah.
That's nuts.
They're playing the lion hazard by the
leg.
She's jumping into the pool and some
fake biting her.
Fuck all of that.
Everything about that picture.
Put that on a tee shirt with those words
at her.
They were friends,
dude.
They were buddies at a young.
She looked,
she looks,
she's a kid.
She's in her teens at this point.
She has a
giant line in our yard.
Go find the cooler.
Was there apparently than tigers.
Tigers are a little sketchier.
There's a little sketchier,
so like you'd have an easier time Tony
Alliance.
Then we would have done that.
I.
This is.
I'm talking way out of school,
but what I believe is the case is that
male lions are mostly there to protect
the pride.
They're mostly there,
so they're not the hundreds right there.
The bigger ones,
the females do all the hunting.
What are the size of that female.
Oh my God.
What's going on there in the movie?
It's attacking her in the movie.
Yeah,
that's what I mean.
That's what the link was.
This close call below.
So it's biting her.
It's got her mouth around the ribs.
Is it actually hurting her?
She doesn't look happy.
I'm not showing it.
Oh,
this is crazy.
All right.
This is fucked up.
So this was in the movie.
They were freaking out to the line was
biting somebody.
It says the father refused to yell.
Cut.
Oh my God.
No.
Blood was drawn and the lion grabbed her
hair and pulled her back.
So the line was just fucking with her.
But he is dangerous.
He was once Claude,
the face during that filming that
required required reconstructive
surgery.
Ge Story that I'd heard it.
She was clogged
more responsible and you know,
there's several lines in this house and
it's not just one.
So the lions who's there,
the lines are just running shit.
And I think they picked them and they,
they were lines that came from like
surfaces and shit.
$17,000,000
on the movie and it brought back to a
bargain.
Roar.
Yeah.
After this podcast,
get ready for another 50 bucks.
And that's 17.
How much?
Nineteen 71.
$17.
Million dollars in 1971.
Yeah.
This is a nice way to learn to cocaine
money,
son.
That's what's going on there.
What is that today?
Like $80.
Million Dollars.
Billion.
Trillion.
The what I was saying was,
I think what happens is that lions,
the male lions don't hunt.
They usually just eat the kill that the
female lions hunt.
They,
they're doing all the hunting.
But with tigers,
the male lions hunt,
like they're all hunt and they don't,
they don't operate in packs,
you know,
they're not independent than rogue.
Yeah,
they're not,
they don't.
They don't operate the same way.
Lions who don't have a pride,
you know,
I'll take.
I think tigers are pretty much on their
own know.
I think the females take care of the
cubs as long as they can,
but I don't think they have these big.
I could be wrong,
find out if I'm wrong,
but I don't think tigers operate in
like,
like that kind of a group
in a world where like I've got a
miniature doctrine that means that
somebody's genetically made that dog
smaller.
Right.
Well,
when you say genetically they're not
doing it through a laboratory,
they're doing it through selective
breeding and it's remarkably effective.
And then you do that.
I just needed that to get to this point.
Can you do that with a tiger baby tiger?
Yeah.
So could you.
That's
what happened.
All house cats have come from some kind
of wild cat that we turned into a
domestic cat.
And there's a bunch of different
varieties of cats,
right?
The difference between cats and dogs is
that all dogs come from wolves,
all of them.
Everyone,
every dog,
every dog started as a wolf.
Tigers did not live in permanent groups
like lions do for the most part.
They live solitary lives except when
females are raising cubs.
Although rarely seen the term for a
group of tigers is a streak.
Dope word.
Tigers.
Murder of crows.
That's pretty.
Um,
that's dope.
my mom used to come here when I was a
kid and now I can tell her mom if there
was another one,
we'd be a streak of tigers.
Tigers.
Fuck things up,
man.
They all fuck things up.
All the males hunt and they're,
they're fast.
Fuck an animal man.
Oh,
is this?
It will be.
It's on youtube.
He got fucked up.
Also roars.
Roar.
This is the whole movie.
It's on youtube.
If you go,
oh,
I just randomly click to a spot where
they happen to be attacked.
And the movie is about how they have
these big,
what the fuck seems like I couldn't seen
movie.
It's called the most dangerous movie
ever made.
Oh my God,
this guy's an idiot.
And when you say they said Jesus father
didn't yell.
Cut.
That was Melanie Griffith.
His Dad was directed.
Dude,
this is crazy.
They're all these lines are fighting for
dominance and this guy is running around
in between them while they're filming a
shitty movie.
Crazy hook it.
It's like,
fuck you bitch stabbed on my business.
Oh my God.
The lions just wanted him to know that
that little tree branch was not going to
stop them.
Jesus crisis because it cut each other
up,
man.
They're biting each other fucking each
other up.
It's what they do,
man.
And this was a movie that was meant to
show how stupid the guy.
The roar is in 1981 American adventure
exploitation film.
Written and directed by no Marshall
producing starring Marshall and his then
wife,
tiffany Hendra and costarring hundreds
real life daughter Melanie Griffith and
Marshall's real life sons.
John and Jerry.
Oh,
they were brady bunch type family.
The film follows a family who are
attacked by a range of ravening jungle
animals at the secluded home of their
keyboard.
I always thought this was a documentary.
They were literally making a movie with
fucking real lions about how lions were
attacking people.
70 members of its cast and crew being
injured by the many predatory animals
used in the film,
including its main stars,
sustaining life threatening injuries,
rating from bone fractures to scalping
and gangrene.
Much of the footage capturing the
injuries was included in the final cut
of the film,
resulting in real blood on screen.
It has been considered the most
dangerous film shoot in history.
Wow,
okay.
We need to do a fight companion.
They had tigers as well.
Oh my God.
They had leopards or jaguars.
Were those Jaguars and leopards?
Do you know the difference to look at
the tiger?
They just look at it for part of the
world,
but he just.
He just jumped in the boat.
Yeah.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
They hit him in the fucking face while
they have to.
I think you have to get it to think
who's boss?
Is that a pan?
Of course it is.
Fuck all this.
The tiger,
and then now the boat's sinking.
You fuck you.
Fuck it.
Fuck.
This is life of Pi.
Oh my God.
Look at that thing.
It's so big,
right?
We're going to save it for the computer.
Oh,
Jesus.
So what we'll do is one day we'll do a
fight companion.
Put that movie.
Like save it.
Yeah,
we'll do this week we're doing roar.
we'll do roar.
Got In trouble for that.
Can we get in trouble for a fight
companion for Ra?
People that did things like this?
Yeah.
No,
totally.
It's a.
What is it considered?
It's commentary here from rattling.
It needs to be seen.
That needs to be heard.
I'm completely educated.
I thought it was documented,
but they're actually make.
They were trying to make a fix of
narrative of pictionary.
I didn't even know there was a
documentary.
I just knew that she had lived with
lions and I'd seen it in a magazine
article or something or my real dad
that's.
Or stepdad.
Stepdad was fucking crazy.
Could you imagine your Stepdad's Jamie?
Get in there with the lion.
Would you put that evil on me,
Jamie?
Oh my God,
what is it?
The movie?
Look at all the cats in the room with
her.
Don't many fuck all that.
Fuck all that.
And they were crazy and I'm sure the
cats are like confused as fuck by the
rolling cameras as well.
Being like,
what is this all about?
Yeah,
they're horrible.
It's.
I mean those are the cleanup crew for
the world.
That's what cats are there out there and
taken out as as many of those fucking
zebras or water buffalo or whatever
where they can and so that's what they
want to do all the time and if you're
just feeding them and then you just have
many yard,
they don't even do anything.
Like you got to exercise the fuck out of
those girls to keep them from just that
kills lust.
That's in their body.
They evolved over millions of years to
get to this point where there's this
enormous,
hulking,
super naturally powerful animal that
kills things with its face and you just
take that away from them.
It's new.
You're going to be in the pool with us.
You're going to be in our movie.
We're going to start off in this boat.
Come on,
hop in the boat.
Pretend to fight.
And the liquid.
Pretend I'm Mrs.
It's like when the fuck do the antelope
show up so I could start jacking fools.
Would you.
You're.
Would you agree that since you do more
outdoors,
the activity that may I running it,
you've gone hunting and stuff like that.
Your chances of being eaten alive are
far greater than mine.
Oh yeah,
100 percent.
I mean it's like surfers.
I'm in a zero percent chance in most of
my life of getting eaten by a shark,
but I have friends who are surfers who
surf all the time and they fucking love
it and they're willing to roll that dice
because they like surfing that much and
I'm like,
you know,
you can't get bit by a shark if you
don't go in the ocean.
And they're like,
we've got this shark thing figured out
and defeated.
Just don't go in the ocean.
They say it's worth it.
I got to tell you,
man,
like there's a bunch of bad ways to die,
but I always felt like the most
indignity I would ever feel in death was
if I was something else's food.
It's one thing if I'm like my body goes
into the earth and fucking the worms and
the grass and shit like that,
but to be someone's fucking meal is so
it's a temporary or a permanent solution
to a temporary problem,
your life for their meal of the moment
and they're just going to shoot you out
in a couple of hours.
And that's why I think it's hard for
humans get their head around being
eating my son because like,
no,
I'm too special and then they'll just
going to poop me out.
But that would be the indignity man is
like,
fuck,
they ate me to stay alive I guess.
But then it's not like I sustained them
forever.
Like I sustained him for a couple of
fucking hours and they shipped me out,
you know?
Well that,
that is how it works.
Right?
Yeah.
Um,
it's very disturbing.
Seeing images of humans that have been
eaten by animals.
I've never seen any and I don't want to.
You don't want any finger starting to
move toward a gay boy,
but like,
no,
no.
Classic one of a body that they found
that bears at eaten and I was horrific.
It's just crazy to look at is even make
human anymore.
I mean,
you know what it is because it was still
wearing sneakers and it's still at heck
half of its pants on and it's still
like,
you know the one.
Yeah,
you could see the thigh bone.
I mean the,
the meat from the bone had been
completely stripped off and it was just
nothing but the thigh bone and it's just
horrific.
You gotta realize like those things man,
when they get ahold of you,
the amount of like,
the amount of power that a bear could
generate,
like especially at grizzly bear.
My friend John saw a grizzly bear kill a
moose by swatting it,
swatted it with its pot and broke.
It's back a moose.
I mean,
second deadliest animal on the planet is
a big.
Is it really that crazy?
Nobody thinks about it because when you
think about the logo,
a rookie be hippo is the most dangerous
animal to man on the planet in terms of
like how many people get killed aml.
Second is the Moose.
Wow.
Part of the deer family.
That's crazy.
They're the only dear.
Really,
that will regularly rush.
People don't want to be anywhere near
the Moose during the reading season.
There's that,
but really more importantly is you don't
want to be near a cow.
She's got her calves.
That's video that online.
Same thing with grizzlies.
Yeah.
They say the real.
The real fear is not running into a male
grizzly.
The real fear is running to a female
with cubs,
which they'll to lose.
Well,
they just didn't want you around.
You might be a hunter.
Maybe they seen someone shoot an animal
before.
Maybe they saw some.
One of their family gets to that little
cat that just like,
shoot suddenly,
like you're gonna kill me up.
Even though you were buddies.
It has cubs.
If it has cubs,
man,
they're.
They're on fucking full red alert all
day long because they get eaten all the
time.
Their cubs get eaten by other bears too,
so fucking weird.
It's like an animal has enough sense to
be like something to do here.
I'm going to protect my kids and we just
watched footage from a movie where the
guy's like,
get closer to that lion honey.
Spit water in its mouth.
Yeah,
because we're soft and we love the
thrill of being that close to death and
danger.
I know you're a smart man now.
I'm a chicken man.
You're a wise man.
No courage.
I just want to extend my life.
That is not true.
You have courage.
You just choose to not put yourself in
dangerous situations all the time.
He had never taken this path in life and
become this guy.
If you didn't have any courage,
you absolutely have courage,
but you just smart enough to know that
you're not like a physical person.
You're not into.
You don't want to do those things.
He definitely don't want to be around
some fucking giant ass cat.
I can kill you.
It's not a matter of being a coward.
It's a matter of being smart.
It's true.
But if that's a matter of being smart
now everything collapses and shit like
that,
then I got no livable skill.
No one does.
Ready to fucking take to the hills with
a fucking bow and defend yours,
just like you are.
How many hours do I have?
You know,
how long can I live with these arrows?
You know what?
What happens if I break that down to 20
arrows?
How many?
How long can I live with?
20 arrows?
How many things am I going to miss to
keep running?
You have to break into a Cabela's,
steal a bunch of Arrow shafts,
figured out they've got a gluing
machine.
I got to learn how to restrain a bow
with the.
What if the one of the risers snaps?
I gotta get some spare boast somehow and
have them laying around.
I'm not doing well,
man.
I'm going to be real skinny.
I'm going to miss a lot.
I'm not going to get enough food,
but you know it's going to happen.
You're going to be like,
at least I didn't die years ago.
Like Kev.
Oh cause he had no skills whatsoever.
I want to be one of the people that
restart civilization lock.
No,
no.
Do you know there's blamed when
everyone's like,
this sucks.
This is your fault.
You started civilization like,
like tried.
What's going on right now in Hawaii is
fairly minor.
What is in terms of volcanic volcanic
activity in terms of the world,
like there's.
There's giant events that happened every
know 100,000,
80,000,
whatever all over the world and the
giant events.
These super volcanoes had been
responsible for knocking people down to
an estimated.
What was the number?
Something like seven thousand seven
thousand people somewhere.
It was maybe a couple thousand,
70,000
years ago.
Is that where I'm getting the Fran seven
from a,
but it was a super volcano that the
human population killed every one except
for a few thousand people and there was.
This was somewhere around,
I think it was 60 slash 70,000
years ago.
Was it?
Say I pompei like event 70,000
roughly a thousand reproductive people.
Thousand people left 70,000
years ago.
A thousand.
That was the last of the humans and they
repopulate it from that number to us.
One says it was as low as 40,
40 people.
Maybe it's just a rough estimate.
Biblical where this information.
Well listen man,
if yellow stone blows,
we're dealing with the exact same
situation.
Again,
most of North America is dead.
What?
Expand?
Yellow stone is a super volcano.
Wow.
Might've hit as low as what?
What happened to Harry went to JFK
thing.
Conspiracies pairs
of people.
Well,
we've wax so we can win.
Once in our history of the worldwide
population of human being skidded so
sharply,
we were down to roughly a thousand
reproductive adults.
One study says we hit as low as 40,
40.
C'Mon.
That can't be right.
Well,
the technical term is 40 breeding pairs.
Children not included,
more likely.
There was a drastic dip and then $5,000.
10,000
bedraggled.
Homosapiens struggled together and
pitiful little clumps hunting and
gathering for thousands of years until
in the late stone age we humans began to
recover,
but for a time there says science writer
Sam Kean.
We damn near went extinct and that was
because of the volcano.
It's amazing.
What is it?
What killed the lava blocks?
The Sun
blocks the sun.
Everybody runs out of food.
Everything goes extinct.
This is the matrix.
Yeah,
it gets really fucking cold.
Oh my God.
Look at that.
Very scientific.
The difference in Mount St Helens.
Little Little Fart.
Vesuvius,
79.
And it said the Tobi Super Volcano is
the one that happens 70,000
years ago.
Yeah,
so that was a mess around from Mount
Saint Helen's.
You massive.
Super.
Yeah,
I remember that.
Captured my imagination.
I was a kid.
I was like,
we got volcanoes on this bitch.
Well,
yellowstone is the spooky one because
that's a super.
Volcano is just water.
No,
no stone is what they call a Caldera
volcano.
Meanwhile,
what it is,
is it gets to this peak in the eruption
is so violent.
It flattens out and the mountain
disappears and it's just left this
crater and so when they were first
looking at it,
they were trying to figure out what it
was.
They didn't know if it was an impact
crater was this crater from and then
they started using satellite imagery,
I want to say like 20 years ago,
20 plus years ago,
they realized that it was a super
volcano and enormous volcano.
I think it's something like 600
kilometers across and if that fucker
blows,
like that is a wrap for North America.
That's a wrap and it blows every six to
800,000
years and the last time it blew was
600,000
years ago.
So we could be on the verge of the.
Within the history within the next
200,000
years.
It's likely if the history repeats
itself again,
that we get some sort of unbelievably
violent event that comes out of
yellowstone that literally brings
humanity to its knees.
So all of our problems with
overpopulation destroying the
environment,
crime and war and corruption,
they will seem like nothing can because
there will be no fucking son getting in.
There will be nuclear winter plants
dying,
no snap and half the people disappear.
This is like these are the end times.
The Sky is black hundred percent
possible that something like that.
If especially if there's more than one
of them went off,
like say yellowstone goes off and then
say one goes somewhere else in the
world,
I think isn't there like seven or eight
super volcanoes?
There's,
there's seven or eight of them I want to
could split the earth.
I think we just cover the earth with
ash.
Think the problem is the ash,
the objections and all that stuff just
blocks out the sun and it lingers for
years.
Three of them are in the western part of
the United States.
What are the.
That's that's where we are three.
Fuck Dude.
What are the other ones?
Long Valley and Valley Grande.
What does that.
I've never heard of those.
That's super close to us.
Where the fuck is that one more sitting
on it right now.
We look it up.
I,
um,
I used to be scared of that shit and
then I don't get scared of that some
more.
If you feel different now that you've
had a heart attack,
do you feel like you're a different
person?
Do you have a second lease on life as it
were,
is,
but not in the way like you see in
movies where you're like,
can you feel isn't mammoth?
Mammoth is a super volcano called Dara.
Oh,
shut the fuck up with Jason to mammoth
mountain time to move.
We could blow mammoth could blow they,
but wouldn't you rather be that close to
ground zero like because you don't want
to live in the Glendale,
so it just,
it just rubs.
It just kills everybody.
Anywhere near.
I don't want to be like a million miles
away and watch it from the distance and
know that in a month you're gonna be
starving to death.
It's coming soon.
Yeah.
You're almost better off and having
happening right underneath you and just
sucking you into the lava.
Did you ever have a near death
experience?
No,
not really.
No.
It's not like it is in the movies where
you suddenly you're like,
now I see everything more clearly.
It's certainly an organizing an
organizer like where you're like,
you know,
I guess that Shit just doesn't really
matter so much anymore.
And periodically you sit there and go
like,
oh fuck,
I almost died.
So it puts things in a different
perspective.
But I saw a lot of folks online go on,
like I can't wait to see what he makes
next man because it can be so profound
and that's not true.
Next thing I'm going to make as Jane
Silent Bob Reboot.
There's nothing profound about it and
stuff,
but I figured I figured out because I
started thinking about that.
Why I think it's [inaudible] like I've
just always been,
at least for the last 20 years,
25 of my career just conducted myself in
a way like live a fucking bucket list
life.
I just do the things I want to do.
Exactly.
That's why I hate you saying that you
don't have any courage because that's
where she didn't take courage.
That's self centered,
no centered courage is like,
I don't know how it's gonna work out,
but like you know,
fucking and also courage comes in place.
That's not about you.
I think for me,
I just want to do shit.
That seems interesting.
It seems fun and you have the confidence
to pursue that.
Listen Dude,
if this shit to teach how to use a bow
and Arrow and you,
you'd figure it out.
Eventually.
Rise.
Just like you're losing all this weight
and readjusting your life and to do I
check if it all went down.
They'd be like,
eat him first and then I'd be so
insulted because I'm like,
you're just going to ship me out.
I'm good for a podcast or two.
Please don't eat me.
So I have Robert Schoch
on the podcast as geologists from Boston
University and he is one of,
of many people that's now pushing this
very controversial theory that the
sphinx and many of the other structures
in Egypt are far older than people
think.
They are not just like a couple thousand
years ago,
but maybe even 10,000
maybe even more,
and he bases it on water erosion marks
and the tempo of the Sphinx,
like where the Sphinx was carved out and
the Sphinx enclosure.
There's all these deep fissures that
they thought was sand and gravel and
wind,
but he has,
you know,
he studied.
He's a geologist so he studied erosion
his whole life and he looked at it and
he's like,
this is water erosion from thousands of
years of rainfall and he goes into it in
great detail.
The last time there was great rainfall
in the Nile Valley was 9,000
years ago,
which has many thousand years before
they think the pyramids were
constructed.
So it's one of these things like they
didn't even know of a civilization from
9,000
years ago that was capable of cutting
and moving stone like this.
Like this rewrites history,
history,
super reluctant.
But the idea that all of these people
have these people that are talking about
these ancient civilizations is that
humanity rose to a very high level and
build some incredible structures.
And then something like that Super
Volcano or an asteroid will impact,
or an ice age,
some gigantic catastrophic event wiped
out a shitload of fucking people and
then people were forced to rebuild and
sort of relearn.
So if you're looking at some of the
construction of the Pyramids,
like the Great Pyramid of Giza,
I'm pretty sure they've dated that to
2,500
BC.
So the people that made the Sphinx and
even some of the other structures they
might have been from a longer ago in
history,
in relationship to the construction,
the Sphinx,
than we are to the construction of the
Great Pyramid.
Like we might have.
What we were talking about,
the Great Pyramid was 5,000
years old.
Right now I have to.
It's entirely possible if the Great
Pyramid of Giza would say,
think of somewhere around 50,000
years old.
If that was 5,000
years old,
the Sphinx might be 4,000
or more years older than that.
There might be structures that are
$10,500,
even 30,000
years old.
There's some people's,
when they go deep,
like a guy named John Anthony West,
that was his deep speculation based on
the way this finks lines up with
constellations and the Constellation
Leo,
it does it at like 10,500
BC,
but also it does it uh,
or 10,500
years ago.
But it also does it at like 30,
30,000
years ago or somewhere in that range,
like really long,
which people are going to get the fuck
outta here.
That's just not possible.
And his,
his take was like,
we don't know,
we're were just talking about rocks.
We don't know how these rocks got into
this shape.
This is just no recorded history.
Or they used to have some,
but they know they've got hieroglyphs.
I've got a few things,
but they used to have only had like a,
a,
like a incredibly developed society.
The mayans and the aztecs built some
incredible structures and they were like
really into constellations as well.
They aligned up a lot of their
structures with the constellations.
They knew a lot about the summer
solstice and they had a really
complicated calendar that was like a 13
lunar cycle calendar,
you know,
they.
There was like the thing where the Mayan
calendar,
we're supposed to end December 21st 2000
a couple of years ago.
Yeah,
dude,
I thought it was over telling everybody
we've got a couple more years pro.
We have your life.
I've really seem to know what they were
doing.
Go back.
So if that turns out to be the case.
Humanity has experienced these great,
great,
like high achievements in construction
methods and their ability to put
together these enormous structures and
then capitalism.
People die off,
they get down to a small number and then
they rebuild and then they do these over
the,
you know,
these,
these dips and ups and downs over the
course of thousands and thousands of
years,
which we got to put it into perspective.
This country is only 250 years old.
That's nothing.
So if you went back just let's go,
let's go full crazy.
Let's go back 500 years,
go back 500 years,
which is nothing in terms of the history
of the planet and nothing in terms of
even the history of human beings
relatively,
but 500 years.
There's nothing here,
but native Americans,
there's no structures is a few Europeans
that have visited.
There's a few set of people that have
come over and boats,
but there's no buildings in terms of
like,
there's no New York City.
There's no Chicago 500 years ago.
There's nothing.
There's none of this goes outside and
sit around and do a three slash 16 and
look around and realize how improbable
it all is.
Go a thousand years before that,
same thing,
thousand years before that.
Same thing.
This is empty.
This is empty for thousands and
thousands of years now.
Two hundred and 50 years later.
It's crazy.
It stacked up with buildings and
construction methods that we were never
capable of 200 years ago,
300 years ago,
500 years ago,
we couldn't build these things.
We couldn't make airplane.
We didn't have the knowledge yet.
We didn't understand it yet.
The idea is that people have gone
through these great,
great heights many times and but they
did it in different ways and that's why
like when you look at the construction
of this finks and the pyramids,
nobody builds anything like the pyramids
today.
Two million,
300,000
stones.
Some of them cut from a quarry that was
hundreds of miles away.
They used to take the fucking rocks and
float them down on boats and fit them
into places.
It's crazy.
It's the knowledge.
They must have had the wisdom,
the,
the understanding of construction
methods.
If you're off just a little bit with
each rock,
it's not going to meet up at the top of
this perfect pyramid shape.
I mean it's a marvel of mathematics and
engineering and construction and by
everyone's estimate it's 5,000
something years old are in the range of
4,500
years old,
somewhere around there,
sane along and says it may be older than
you
might be older than that.
Well that not.
They don't think the pyramid.
I'm pretty sure,
and maybe this is controversial as well,
but I think it's based on the biological
material that they can pull out from in
between the cracks and the stones.
I think people who died was stuff like
anything physical or anything biological
rather like wood or or patrice that
might've went into building the chat.
That's how they'd carbon dates
something.
Apparently they need carbon,
so it's really tough to carbon date like
a stone because you don't know what your
dating.
Are you dating the way the age,
the stone was cut or the stone was
created.
Like what the fuck is that?
Have you had a giant piece of limestone?
What are you dating?
Are you dating the actual origin of the
limestone?
It might be millions of years old.
I don't know how long limestone is like,
isn't it?
I think limestone is seashells that have
been ground down and smashed by gravity
and layers and layers of earth until
they form into a stone.
See if I made that up,
it might have sounded awfully metal.
There's some shit like that for sure.
Like I know travertine is that
travertine is like old seashells that
have been compressed down at the bottom
of the ocean forever until they form
like this hard layer.
Pretty sure that's true too.
That might be.
That might also be bullshit.
Fuck,
you're well read.
Nope.
Incorrect.
My wrong.
Most limestone deposits are made from
the shells of Microsoft scopic sea
organisms.
Coral reefs are a beautiful example of
organic sedimentary rocks made by
creatures that are still living.
Okay.
So yeah,
it is.
So limestone deposits,
it's made by the shells of microscopic
sea organisms.
So these shells,
they compress down,
they make this stone they built,
they built fucking giant buildings out
of this shit.
So just think of the age of that stone.
Like how,
what,
how old was that shit?
So everything that we think we know
could literally be incorrect by a couple
thousand.
Yeah.
But even that,
it's like,
I think it's weird that we're holding
onto these numbers instead of like
saying,
well we have some tests that show that
we're pretty sure that this was created
around them,
but that you might be right.
That might be older,
but people like really resist what he's
saying.
They're really resistant because you'd
have to go back and a lot of people that
got degrees in Egyptology like do you
have to rewrite what we know?
Because once they.
Once they decide this is the age where
this was made and taught Moses,
the third is responsible for this and
this guy's responsible for that.
Once they write that and sell the books,
super hard to take that back and
suddenly be like a super hard to admit.
They don't really know and so this
and this isn't something like,
hey,
Pluto's not a planet anymore because we
were off by its size or whatever.
This is like we had literally no idea
that people existed that
far back when people existed,
but we didn't know they were capable of
building things like that.
But I'm saying like,
why is that even surprising?
If people 4,000
fucking years ago,
it could build something as crazy as the
great pyramid.
Like why would I be shocked that someone
4,000
years before that could build a sphinx
or 4,000
years before that?
I can build some other fucking temple,
I mean it's also just a number that's
really like fucking ridiculous to get
your head around where you're to wait
4,000
from now backwards and then 4,000
from that point,
like forget it.
And then to think that humanity was
probably restarted at least to a certain
extent,
somewhere around the end of the ice age,
like the humanity recovered and started
flourishing again.
So who knows,
you know,
w what,
what number of people we dipped down to
15,000
plus years ago if they were,
if they built the spanx further back
than we thought they did,
did they have language skills?
It must build something like that
without being like,
hey,
put a nose on it.
I think they're pretty sure that
language is 40,000
years old.
See if that's true.
I think that's what they think.
I think they think language in the form
that we would describe as language,
you know,
like maybe,
um,
you know,
I don't know what language is 200,000.
What?
Okay.
Psychology today though,
definitely probably smarter than me.
Um,
so,
okay,
so 200,000
years ago,
more over around 50,000
years ago for a period referred to by
archeologists,
the Upper Paleolithic and unprecedented
cultural explosion began to manifest
itself for human communities.
Maybe that's what I remember.
So 50,000
years ago is the number of this in my
head.
So language,
um,
they had it a long time.
They didn't start.
They don't think at least they started
writing shit until somewhere around
10,000
years ago,
but they don't even know if that's the
case.
But I think the oldest known writing
that we know of today,
I think is that stuff that comes out of
Iraq.
Cuneiform,
I think it's called.
It's from the ancient Sumerians.
They were the oldest civilization that
we're like modern,
not modern,
but advanced civilization that we're
currently aware of.
And they kept records.
Yeah,
they wrote with like old school.
Did you ever do any carpentry?
Oh No.
When I was a kid in Boston,
I've worked on a lot of houses,
demolition stuff and carpentry stuff.
And you would go in these old old houses
and they had these weird nails because
the nails were all handmade back then.
There weren't a nail like you think of a
nail,
like a table top with a pole underneath
it.
It's not what the nails where the nails
were like this weird kind of like almost
rectangle or triangle thing and that
that was exactly what cuneiform looks
like.
It has like a very specific pull up,
some,
a Sumerian,
Sumerian cuneiform.
So as a series of lines and it's really,
it's got to be insanely hard to decipher
like what,
what they were writing and what they
meant by all this.
But this is their language.
That shit that you're looking at right
there.
That right there.
So it seems like an intermediate between
hieroglyphics and an alphabet.
Yeah,
I mean,
I don't know.
I'm still considered graphic when you
look at it like it's still a little.
Well that's not,
that's more toward letter.
What is that?
That's like a.
If you saw that on a spaceship,
you'd be like,
oh,
the alien writing.
And apparently it's not that alien,
but doesn't that look like if you saw
that on a spaceship that looks like
something from like hanger 18,
right.
If that was on the outside of a spatial
star it.
But yeah,
it looks very.
Stargate to me like,
look at that dude.
Dad is like some sort of like if you had
a computer printout,
remember those old school printouts that
would run through computers,
like the little holes punched in them
that would look kind of like that.
The a man that's the oldest language.
I think that shit's 6,000
years old.
I think it's somewhere around there.
And that's like Babylonia has been able
to decipher an alphabet or be like 48
letters in the alphabet.
Yeah.
I don't know what they found,
but they found a lot of cool shit there.
Felt a lot of cool shit from the
Sumerians.
I remember as a kid,
like,
you know,
I went to Catholic school as a kid and
the big story when we were younger was
we got like new nuns,
sisters.
Uh,
like at a certain point,
like when I started Catholic school,
Our Lady of perpetual help,
they had old school nuns that would wrap
your fucking knuckles and shit like your
parents would talk about and then all of
a sudden these new sisters come in,
the sisters of the Franciscan sisters of
the infant Jesus,
and they were more like about education,
almost like a Jesuit priest,
so that,
you know,
they definitely had their vows and
whatnot,
but they were more progressive in their
thinking than like the previous
generation that had come prior to them.
So Sister Teresa was like,
our eighth grade teacher captured our
imaginations with the Dead Sea scrolls
through about how,
you know,
there was a bible that we all worked off
of.
And then thanks to some kid who threw a
rock in a cave.
They found all these jars and inside of
the jurors perfectly preserved where all
these writings on parts.
Yes.
Yeah.
And so that's where we started getting a
clearer picture of the Bible and that's
where they found bibles or gospels that
aren't included in our Bible.
And Man,
it was like,
this is a minute before raiders of the
lost Ark came out.
So then when that movie came out,
you were like,
it's all,
it's all connected.
Yeah.
The,
the scrolls are fascinating man.
You know,
they had to use DNA testing to make sure
that they were getting the pieces of
this parchment from the same animal
skin.
So like say if you had these pieces,
they did,
they had so many,
they studied them for years and they for
to decipher them would have to lay them
out
on tables.
You ever see what they look like,
like laid out on tables.
And so one of the ways that they had to
determine where pieces would go,
this is a incredibly painstaking
process.
They had to take small bits of organic
material because it's animal skins.
And then they would run it through a DNA
test and go,
okay,
this is the same animal.
This animal is where,
uh,
you know,
all these pieces go on here.
This is likely for the same piece of
skin.
Oh,
amazing dude.
And it's crazy.
And I,
I think it's the only version of the
Bible that was written in Aramaic.
Yes.
Well done.
Fuck.
You're well.
Read.
Well,
read about drugs.
See,
this is all about John Marco Allegro we
talked about.
Yeah,
that guy found out about the Dead Sea
Scrolls and the Christian myth and the
sacred mushroom.
And the cross is two books on that.
But he was a.
He was a guy who studied that.
The Dead Sea Scrolls.
At what point do we just saw an image of
the Dead Sea Scroll?
Parchment spread out point.
Do I give up instantly?
You know what I'm saying?
Like where somebody is like,
good luck.
You might have to dns.
Goodbye.
Yeah,
I'd be like,
Yo,
if you guys need funding,
I'm down to Tony.
I got to jet.
I got a spot at the store.
The store is not for me,
man.
I mean,
but it is for somebody and I'm grateful.
I'm grateful that there's guys like
that,
like Robert Schoch who's taking these
trips to Egypt to study this and really
putting his neck out there releasing
this very controversial theory.
I'm glad there's all these people out
there that are questioning these things
and looking into these things that
someone has the energy to study the Dead
Sea Scrolls and to go over and
apparently there's some wacky ass
fucking crazy stories in there.
Like they've tried to compare the
stories for the like way more extreme
way,
way weirder to the point where people
are only.
I think we should use these stories to
involve the same characters.
I don't know much about two years.
I don't think so.
What is like maybe we could find because
that story has a problem,
isn't chunk missing these 12 and then
next time they pick them up.
He's 31.
Yeah.
Um,
I think that's probably something that
can't be just googled.
I think where was Jesus probably have to
read a book on like what they learned
out of the Dead Sea Scrolls.
But I remember there was some sort of a
documentary on all of the hidden truths
of the deaths,
the Dead Sea Scrolls and why these
Christians were trying to omit it from
you and not put it into the final
version of the Bible.
You know,
it's,
it's so nice to gospels,
they pull a lot from,
from there.
The gnostics were people that it was a
faith,
I guess,
or a section of faith that they were
great record keepers,
uh,
but they were also not necessarily like,
and it was the Christ himself,
the mighty son of God.
They were a bit more practical in their
telling of the tale.
Yeah.
Didn't religion it up quite so much.
If you had,
if you could go back to a time and
observe life like being like a giant
bulletproof hamster wheel and observe
life,
would you go to the dinosaur era and see
like live t rexes running around and,
and predators and crazy thick atmosphere
and heavy vegetation of pre 65 million
years ago?
Or would you go and watch people from
like 5,000
years ago?
We get one shot,
one shot either,
you know,
does the dinosaurs because I'm like,
I've seen Jurassic Park and then realize
there's probably aren't going to be
nearly as impressive as of you.
That being said,
Jurassic Park,
you see that being said,
I,
I go,
I go to the.
I go to the Christ era because that
might solve a lot of problems if I can
come back and be like he was real and he
turns out he was the son of God.
Let's listen to the clerks guy time
travel.
He thinks he knows everything.
You got fooled by magician brow.
Who's the guy who literally a WHO's,
who's telling us that the Sphinx is
older than it is.
Somebody's got to put their neck out
there sometimes and I'd be willing to be
the guy to do.
John.
Anthony West was the guy.
He's dead now.
He just died recently.
What?
Yeah,
John Anthony West.
I thought this is the guy who's kind of
Robert Schoch.
That's what I'm talking.
He's another one of them.
He's the geologists.
John Anthony West was the guy who was
making all these dvds about it.
He's a really serious egyptologists that
just passed away,
passed away.
He's the one who's really trying to put
these old,
old age answer.
So he was the one that first flow the
theory that leg hippie older than you.
He just had a.
he's got this crazy DVD series called
magical Egypt.
It's phenomenal.
I think he's got a two,
one and two.
I really only watched one,
but it's so good,
man.
I mean it's like a six DVD series all on
the mysteries of Egypt.
Put the hell happened.
We just got some.
That's me.
Oh fuck you.
Siri.
Like it just starts recording me,
man.
Your phone just coming to life and she
just started the government man.
The found.
I'm talking to Roseanne.
Um,
where are we talking about?
What was I just talking about?
Magical,
magical age,
DVD series.
So this,
this guy is the one who got me,
like really just wrapping my head around
the concept of civilizations collapse.
And then a thousand years later rebuilds
again.
And then do you think about what the
United States was like 500 years ago?
It was non existent.
And now look at what it is now that
these great moments of change happen
periodically in human history,
especially in places where there's a lot
of commerce and there's a lot of food,
like the rich vast wilderness and a
river is filled with fish and places
where people could get enough food and
they would build these cities and then
they start inventing shit and innovating
and 100 years later they'd be better.
Two hundred years later they'd be better
than that.
Five hundred years later they'd have
crazy structures and then they'll be
building things and apparently this is
what it was like in the Nile Valley when
they were.
When they were constructing all these
things.
It was just a bounty of food.
And then somebody just shook it like an
etch a sketch or climate change.
That's the real theory,
really.
Rehab,
because this is what they're saying
about the Nile Valley,
is that before 9,000
years ago it was our tropical rain
forest and now it's all.
It's all sand and desert.
But before that it was like fucking
trees and just the climate changes
whether we fuck with it and make a
change faster or not.
It's not stable.
It's constantly going up and down,
you know,
and so this is probably also partially
responsible for what happened to those
people,
but those people had taken shit to a
another level man more so they need to
go there and give them.
Because I've only been watching dvds and
I'm scared of going to Egypt because
it's sometimes it's a little unstable,
but man,
what it must be like to see these 4,000
fucking year old gigantic stone
structures that were cut and moved by.
Who knows how many people and who knows
how the fuck they did it.
They just have theories.
There's just guesses.
They don't know.
There's no hieroglyphic wall that's
like,
here's the real story.
Not really.
I mean the problem was they think that a
lot of the information was in the
library of Alexandria was written down
there,
was burned when they were conquered,
so they don't really know.
Don't really know how they made them.
There's a lot of good guesses.
A lot of good theories,
but fuck,
you're talking about millions of stones
and they're huge and like how long did
this take?
They say if you cut in place 10 of those
massive stones a day,
it would take you 664 years to make the
great pyramid and we're all.
We know how long it took.
Just what,
wait a minute.
Say that again.
10 of those massive stones a day.
It would take you 600,
64 years to build all the great pyramid
to build just a great parent of Giza.
Just that.
Just that one.
So whoever commissioned it certainly
wasn't around to see it 100 percent.
Unless they had some wizard magic shit
that we're not aware of and they did it
way quicker than we think they did.
Well,
who knows how long they it took them to
build.
We don't really know.
It might've been a thousand years,
you know,
who knows?
Where do you stand on the faith or what
happens in your estimation?
We die.
What happens?
I really don't know.
And I think in that regard,
I'm right there with everybody.
I think you can have your ideas and I
think those ideas can strengthen your
resolve in this life and they could even
help you.
And this is something that I had to
accept as I got older.
More of the same thing.
Like,
okay,
why do I have this reaction?
Like there's certain people that are
like,
these ardent atheist,
they're like,
God is dead.
There's no god.
Shut the fuck up.
And like,
okay,
how do you know?
You don't know.
So even though logic would point,
I mean if you really paid attention to
the way human beings tell stories,
you would have to say,
well a lot of these religious stories
are probably fabricated.
Or maybe there was an initial message or
maybe there was some wisdom that these
people initially stumbled upon.
They wanted to document it.
But whether or not all this came from
God,
you know,
the Cain and Abel Shit and trying to
trick a brother and to kill.
And another brother like,
oh,
I almost got ya.
You know,
you got to do it for me.
You're my boy.
You're gonna.
Kill your brother.
Thanks man.
Or this is so many of those stories that
was a little more human than it's way
more godlike.
Yeah.
But does that mean there's No God?
No,
of course it doesn't.
It doesn't do this.
This universe is too bizarre for you to
leave anything off the table.
Any,
any possibilities of,
of what,
what created it,
what sustains it other than scientific,
you know,
you get down to like the,
the most reductionist perspective of
it's just a series of quarks and gluons
and Adams and an energy and maybe maybe
it is all that.
Maybe it is just that,
but maybe that in itself is God.
Maybe God is not a material thing,
but it's a creating force of the entire
universe itself.
And it also has good in its heart.
Like maybe the reason why we love like
hugs and good conversation and,
and you know,
a cute puppy and all these different
things we like love and we'd like
happiness because all these things are
powerful forces in the universe and all
these things represent the greater will
have the creator of whatever it is that
makes this universe so spectacular.
Whatever the fuck that is,
I don't know what it is,
but anybody who says they know what it
is is lying.
You're lying.
You're trying to trick people so that
you have the ultimate truth and they
don't and that's how we control people
and that's fine.
Up until around now it's fine.
When there was no internet,
it's fine with books were scarce.
It's fine.
When we had to keep order,
it's fine,
but it's not fun anymore because we know
too much now,
so it doesn't mean that there's no god,
but it means you definitely.
This guy that wants the jet,
who's that?
It's televangelists that wants
$50,000,000
to buy his own private jet for sure.
That guy's full of shit.
See,
there's like things that we can and it's
not even original hustle.
It's like,
I know what happens after this.
Give me your money.
God wants me to be wealthy.
That's what he's saying.
St.
Do you ever experienced the afterlife
yet?
I've met people that it.
My belief is that a lot of that can be
attributed to the chemicals that your
brain is capable of producing.
On a regular basis,
it does while you're sleeping,
it does what you're into periods of
extreme stress,
you know,
and that all of these different
chemicals most likely are released in
the brain during these overwhelming
periods of anxiety and fear and terror
and injury.
And when your body is thinking,
Hey,
this might be it,
you know,
and I think that's probably what a lot
of these near death experiences are,
is that people are experiencing what you
would call an endogenous psychedelic
experience that your brain is releasing
these potent chemicals that it has.
It absolutely has inside of it.
Your brain has a ton of different things
like dimethyltryptamine and different
psychedelic chemicals.
It's capable of producing as well as
Melatonin,
dopamine,
Serotonin,
adrenaline,
cortisol.
There's here's a fucking storm of shit
going on in your brain and in the moment
like,
yeah,
a moment like Jack's it all out,
pumps it through your fucking neurons
and everything's firing and you're
seeing things that aren't there and
you're talking to dead relatives.
Your imagine the pearly gates and your
imagination is on 10 and you just see
it.
Everything.
That's the reductionist perspective.
The,
the,
the hopeful,
optimistic spiritual woo perspective is
this is a chemical gateway and you're
seeing through the door of the other
side and then when they decide it's not
your time yet,
you're sucked back to where you lie and
then you're allowed to resume this life
because you have more work to do and
that's the perspective that a lot of
people feel when they come out of those
experiences.
Right?
They feel like I have more work to do.
I can't stop now.
My mom,
years ago,
guys,
like 10 years ago,
more than that,
even moved 15 years ago at this point,
I had a heart attack or a heart episode
rather.
My Dad died of a heart attack,
but my mom was on the table and they
were putting a stent into her heart,
into an artery and she was sitting there
chitchatting while they were doing the
surgery.
I guess she was on a local more so than
anything else.
And uh,
she was joking around with the doctor.
She's like,
Eric got hurry up doc,
because I got to pickup my mom for the.
And then went out well on.
So she died for a minute and a half
clinically fucking dead,
that fucking try to restart the art.
So I was like,
what,
just what happened?
What was it?
And she didn't.
She said,
you know,
she didn't describe a guy saw the bright
lights and I saw people and Blah,
blah blah.
She said I was floating and I was like,
floating up.
She goes,
no floating on my back.
It's like,
okay,
while you were on your back in the
hospital,
do you think that's what it was?
She's like,
I don't know,
but this is,
this is what I remember.
Every iota of responsibility I ever felt
in my life was gone.
She's like,
I felt free.
I felt instantly lighter and just as I
was heading in a direction,
that's when like they pulled her back so
she'd been dead for like a minute and a
half hearted stuff.
So I was like,
all right,
you been in this best of all possible
worlds for fucking 60 plus years.
Now you've seen a glimpse of the other
side,
which is better.
And my mom said the other side and I
said,
what?
What you were there for like a minute
and change why?
And she said I was completely fucking
free.
Like that was it.
I didn't.
I didn't know this one.
I don't have to care for this one.
I don't have to make sure this doesn't
take care of it.
I have to feed the cat.
She was like,
it was bliss.
She's like in.
If that's what happens,
then I look forward to that again.
So when I have my shit three months ago
and the doctor was like,
you got a 20 percent chance to live in.
I was sitting there going through all
the fucking shit in my head about like,
all right,
well this is it.
You're a fucking.
You've spent your life with your head up
your ass,
you know,
fucking trying to figure out who you
are.
Go ahead,
look at your head and heart.
What is your.
This is it.
This is the big moment.
Like what are your thoughts?
What's going through?
And now Dina,
I'm such a chicken shit in live.
I assume that I'd be like,
the guy was like,
I'll fucking suck your dick to stay in
this life because I know this live and I
don't know what happens afterwards and
stuff.
So I thought I'd be begging for,
you know,
for help from God or something like
that.
But I was like,
I made dog,
but I'm sure Jesus would be like,
go to hell.
Fuck you buddy Christ my ass.
So instead of doing the Gi,
the religious thing,
I started thinking about just the
journey itself.
I was like,
well,
if the journey is ending,
what are your thoughts?
Just like when the day held up the
phone,
they were like,
do you want to talk to your wife?
And I was like,
I know,
of course I did,
but I didn't want to because I was like,
I know in my heart of hearts finance,
if I speak to my wife right now,
I'm going to be in the 21st.
I'm going to die.
Had been the 80 percent,
I'm going to fucking drop dead because
that's the intensity of it.
Not even like,
oh my God,
it's killing it.
It just the way they were,
so like,
do you want your wife is on the phone,
do you want to speak to her right now?
Was very leading and you know,
they're professionals and these cats
deal with life and death every day and
this was my first experience with it.
So what I got out of it was you probably
going to die.
It was what they felt and it's still,
I was in the state of like,
I didn't even realize I was having a
heart attack and so I remember looking
at the phone and being like,
I'm,
if I answered,
if I talked to Jennifer,
that's going to be,
I'm not going to leave this room.
So I was like,
I'm going to play the odds if I don't
talk to Jennifer.
Maybe there's some part of me that's
like,
look,
I like talking to Jennifer.
We've been together 20 years.
I better enjoy talking to Jennifer.
Maybe if I put this phone call off,
you know,
they don't get to talk to Jennifer when
it's all fucking done.
So I said to the dude,
I was like,
you know what?
Tell our our color back and the guy goes
seriously.
And I was like,
yeah.
And I saw him talking and got a phone.
I was like,
what?
She said,
he goes,
she was fucking pissed dude.
And I was like,
wow,
I'm dealing with my own shit right now.
So I was laying there on the table and I
was like going through my life and I was
more grateful than anything else.
It wasn't scared anymore.
That was the thing as the love thing
that I love to communicate.
Spent my whole life terrified a fucking
dying.
And when I was closest to it as I ever
knew I was and for all I know I was
closer to someplace but like I was
cognizant,
been told by a professional,
this is fucking risky.
I was just Kinda,
I was grateful more than anything else.
I was like,
what a fucking journey.
Like yeah,
and I'm 47 and it seems short,
but fucking like you gotTa admit you did
more than fucking most people get to do.
And maybe that's why it happened at an
early age because you weren't going to
get the rest of this time and shit like
that.
But like I wasn't mad.
I wasn't like fucking wise.
This is unfair.
I remembered like a,
there's a issue of Sandman,
which I absolutely love Neil Gaiman's
comic book series back in the day.
And uh,
in,
like after the first story arc,
he,
we meet his sister,
the main character's dream,
morpheus,
character of dream is part of the
endless.
And he's got two other siblings,
delirium,
desire,
one of his siblings,
his death and they represent death.
And the comic book,
you know,
you're used to seeing the fucking sky
than the fucking grim reaper and shit.
She's the little,
uh,
emo girl,
goth girl wearing a knock around her
neck and shit like that.
It was written in the nineties and they
don't tell you right away that she's
death.
As you're reading the issue,
you're like,
oh shit,
I think she's meant to be death.
She's fairing soles over to the other
side.
You see a baby passed and she's holding
the baby.
And then there's the,
the,
the refrain is like the,
I hear the sound of her wings and that's
taking this soul over to the next place
as she's sitting around talking to her
brother.
And so she,
she eventually gets into a room with
this older guy,
um,
who's like,
who are you?
And,
and you know,
she's like,
I'm here for you.
You know,
I am.
And he's like,
that's it.
He's like,
oh my God,
I did all these things.
I worked my fingers to the bone and what
did I get?
This is at,
what did I get?
And she says,
you align that.
When I read it,
when I was 18,
it was powerful.
But when I was laying on the fucking
table,
it was constantly going through my head
and made it all easier.
Made me kind of at peace with the idea
of dying.
There's this line,
she says to the guy,
she goes,
you get,
you got what everybody gets.
You've got a lifetime.
And as I was laying there,
I was like,
oh my God,
I got a lifetime.
Like that's,
that's what it was.
Nothing more.
Nothing fucking less than I did some
shit in it and now it's going to stop
and people are going to go on without
you.
And that's not terrible.
Like I,
I thought I'd be fucking desperate to
live and instead I had that weird s like
Sam,
I understood what my mother said for the
first time because I was laying there.
I was like,
oh my God.
Like I made it to the end,
like this is it,
this is the finish line.
And it had been something that I was
terrified of ever getting to.
But then when really kind of faced with
it,
I was like,
oh,
like I'm done.
Like I'm not scared that I'm done.
I'm actually kind of relieved that I'm
done and like,
you know,
fucking like I didn't get killed and I
wasn't home,
invaded a shark,
didn't eat me.
Um,
all the things that like I've been
terrified of my entire life,
like I don't have to think about
anymore.
I made it to the end and it's kind of
okay.
So it's weird.
My whole life I thought like,
you know,
I'd be scared to death and most people
we all are,
we're all terrified of fucking dying
because we don't know,
but that's the closest I ever came and I
wasn't scared.
Like suddenly the fear just went away
and it seemed logical.
Like of course it's over like things end
and I didn't want to die.
I wasn't,
didn't have a death wish,
but I was like,
if it's done it's,
it's kind of,
it's done and count your blessings and
be happy and don't be a bitch.
Like don't.
If the fucking fairy man shows up
tonight,
don't fucking hold out.
Don't be the last asshole at the party.
Go.
No,
like just fucking pay the ferryman.
Get on a boat and go.
We'll see what's next and stuff.
And then ultimately in time did a good
job and I fucking wound up living and
stuff.
So I know this much.
I got to read a bunch of shit like after
I nearly died and it was all nice.
People wrote very nice things about me
and shit and I expected,
you know,
the creature of the Internet that some
people would be like,
I wish he had fucking died,
fuck them to death and shit.
I wish he'd stay silent,
but generally it was like very nice
things.
People were kind of positive and stuff.
So I was like,
fuck man.
Like,
you know,
again,
I didn't want to die,
but like if I had like,
that would've been okay,
now I'm back at it.
You know what I'm saying?
Like now until it ends,
like I've got a,
you know,
and it's kind of easy as long as they
don't wake up with a fucking dead girl
are alive boy,
I don't think like they'll fucking broke
me over the coals when I die in the
future and shit like that.
But it felt weird to be so close to the
completion.
And so having something that normally
terrifies you suddenly be like,
oh,
it's okay.
Like,
and I don't if you walked up and put a
gun in my face,
I'm sure I'd feel threatened,
but like,
I kinda lost my fear of death.
I'm not like death defying,
I won't go out and do anything
differently,
but that,
that dark cloud that kind of kills any
good time.
The moment you start thinking about like
the fear and anxiety you're going to die
one day like you know it's gone and I
will send them like,
yeah,
I'm going to die one day and it's going
to be awesome,
but not for the reasons that you think
I'm saying it's gonna.
Be Awesome.
Just be awesome because a finish like
it's nice to finish things.
We know how good it feels in life to
complete something and that's the
biggest fucking thing in life you'll
ever complete is your journey.
So I didn't walk away going,
I got to do more.
Like I got to fucking live life to the
fullest.
I just got to keep doing what I've been
doing,
like living life the way I enjoy it,
trying to do things.
Sometimes they work,
sometimes they fail and Shit.
Sometimes people are on your side,
sometimes people are you fucking blow
and just do that fucking time.
Have good conversations in the process.
Meet interesting people here,
new points of view and shit like that
and keep at it,
but it's nothing to be afraid of.
Like,
I don't want to get eaten by a cat.
Don't get me wrong.
Like I guarantee you,
I would not be philosophical as a
fucking big cat was crushing my,
you know,
I'd be like,
Jesus,
no,
I find prayer quick,
but death is no longer something.
I'm not looking for it and I certainly
won't put myself in harm's way,
but it doesn't preoccupy me anymore.
I've been there and it's not the thing
that I was led to believe.
It was like,
it's not the,
the,
the ultimate fear come true.
It's not the grim reaper.
There's a sense,
at least in my case,
and again,
I didn't have a painful heart attack.
I'm sure people have heart attacks where
they feel like they're fucking bodies
being ripped and cleaved in twain,
but it wasn't.
It wasn't that.
It wasn't scary.
It was,
okay,
well listen man,
I'm glad you lived because I love you
and you were one of my favorite things
to do.
I always love it and after the heart
attack I couldn't wait to.
We started texting and be like,
Bro,
you got to come in.
I was like,
definitely.
I didn't want to ask.
Quick Protocol goes like that so more,
but listen man,
you might not make it.
Can you think you can get in here?
Yeah,
but no,
I was happy to be here and stuff as well
as as we all are happy to be above
ground.
It's better than below.
Grab your perspective to really because
you're a seeker as well and it means a
lot to a lot of people that are
listening to because that's what
everyone's scared of,
right?
Oh,
blows everyone's scared of the ride,
but you know,
that's what we think we're trained to
think that way.
Every fucking movie,
every book you read,
every song is about like how it'll suck
when it's over and,
and that fear can keep you from enjoying
it while you were living and try and
cool things and stuff like that.
I don't mean like putting yourself in
harm's way like let's shoot a movie with
real lions.
That's been done.
Don't try.
Go watch the video,
but the things where you're like,
I'd really like to try it like a fucking
won't work,
or Ah,
there's maybe time later as the one
thing I did walk away from it,
like time.
You're fucking lucky for every goddamn
sec,
every God second.
So use it wisely and think,
and I think if you could just think that
way,
like today's a borrowed debt,
you know,
you'll have.
Sometimes you have to trick yourself
into like finding more enthusiasm.
You have to trick yourself to be pumped
up about stuff.
But if you can really do that and,
and,
and exercise those patterns in your
brain and get them normal.
There's,
there's people that have trick
themselves into enjoying all sorts of
things that they know are good for them.
They just fire up those fucking
chemicals.
And today we're going to just go out
there and attack this day because this
is a gift.
This is,
this isn't supposed to be here.
We got one.
I think that all the time now.
Honestly,
that's like an underlying that goes
under almost every thought I have and it
doesn't happen constantly,
but it literally happens about 10 times
a week.
You'll be doing something,
you'll be heading somewhere.
You'll be eating something fucking
whatever the fuck,
fuck in having a conversation and then
you'll be like,
this isn't supposed to be happening
right now.
A technique based on the odds I was
supposed to die back on that fucking
table.
So suddenly you're like,
I'm playing on house money,
house money.
You know what I'm saying?
Have it live a house,
money life.
Kids,
live a house,
money,
life,
kids.
That should be a fucking tee shirt.
Thank you,
Kevin.
Excellent.
I really appreciate you,
brother.
Appreciate you.
How many hours.