Good.
Oh Shit,
we're live.
Hey fellow.
What's going on dude?
What's up?
And thanks for doing this man.
I appreciate it.
We both came in here.
We had a meal together unprepared.
We both were.
We both were a little bit late.
We both had food.
I had a little food,
talked a little shit,
relaxed,
settled in a little nervous like I was
in.
I was in the right area for the podcast,
but when I rolled up I was like,
this doesn't look anything like a
podcast.
And I was nervous that you're gonna.
Be like,
what the fuck are you?
But we will.
The next place.
I guess it's going to be even less like
this place.
It's gonna.
I'm gonna.
Try to make it as discreet as possible.
Cool.
I'm going to hide it.
I'm going to,
I'm going to pretend to preschool.
I'm going to put like a preschool sign
on the outside.
So that just starts like young single
dudes.
Just avoid preschools at all costs.
That's the way it keeps dockers away.
Um,
push this sucker right up to your face
and okay,
so learning a little bit.
So Dude,
you're talking about a guy who's done a
lot of fucking cool shit.
You were on one of my favorite shows
last up until the end.
I got to be honest.
Yes,
at the end it was.
We can talk about fucking Jack your
phone or then that guy just driving me
crazy standard around that fucking pawn
that brings people back to life.
Like he's waiting for his line to come
up and then you know you,
you were part of the Lord of the rings
man.
I mean fuck dude.
You don't know.
Those are two amazing historical things
that you're a part of when you,
when you do it as an actor,
as a jobbing actor,
when you do it,
you stoked.
I mean,
I was super stoked to do those shows.
You don't realize at the time the real
gravity of what you do and until years
later,
but we,
me and Orlando and Elijah and billy went
out for dinner a couple of weeks ago and
we've sat around saying the further away
we get from Lord of the rings,
the more important it feels in our life.
So when my grandfathers and stuff,
I'm sure it would be like,
yeah,
we were involved in a piece of movie
history,
but at the time you just like great job
having fun and that was kind of the same
at last.
Although to be fair we'd lost,
cause we were isolated on an island in
the show,
but also in person,
you know,
we're all on together.
We wouldn't suddenly,
I wasn't as exposed to the size of the
show as much as when I went on hiatus
and then people will follow me around
and causing hassle and stuff.
But when you're in Hawaii there's like
three restaurants to go to.
I avoid those three restaurants.
If anyone follows me,
I'll go to the library and then sit
there for a couple of hours.
So I wasn't really aware that it became
this pop culture phenomenon,
you know.
And then the end,
the end is like,
you know,
I'm on twitter and stuff and a lot of
people on twitter ask me how'd you feel
about the end?
And in all honesty,
I didn't watch it and I've not watched
it.
You know,
I left at the end of season three,
came back in,
peppered in season four,
five and six,
but it wasn't in the show when it ended.
I mean I was in the finale,
but you know,
at that point I had injected myself from
that world and I was doing a movie in,
in New York,
in the lower east side,
playing a completely different
character,
grave robber that was working at night.
I didn't want to expose myself to this
charlie character who I played because I
felt like I was to bring the Charlie
character
onto set the next day.
So people are always very,
very jazzed to talk to him about the
ending.
How did you feel about it?
How did it make you feel?
Were you disappointed?
Did you love it?
And I'm always.
I always really fucking piss people off
by going,
yeah,
I didn't see it.
You didn't see,
you know,
I just didn't see it because it felt
like I was getting fucked towards the
end.
I was like,
I'm not doing this.
And I walked away and I actually had an
argument about my wife.
She's like,
you gotta watch the last episode.
I'm like,
I'm not watching it.
Not.
I'm done.
I don't feel connected.
Same thing with Dexter.
I walked away with Dex.
I was completely committed in the
beginning.
But you,
you walked away or your,
your character died during the golden
time of the show.
The show was flawless at that time.
It was so god damn good.
It was so good.
Yeah.
I like to end the season three,
which I really felt like it was kind of
peaking at that point was it was the
show that every late night talk show
hosts was talking about or daytime and
it was in magazines and you know,
buzzfeed loved it and all that kind of
stuff.
And then it Kinda felt like it was
cresting,
you know?
And then I think the real bonus for the
fens was the,
for the six years that it was on tv,
the creators that said,
it's not what you think it is,
it's something else.
Ultimately it kind of was.
Well,
a lot of people thought,
well,
they,
I think they say that they don't know
what the fuck they're doing when they
have a giant storyboard and they're
moving pieces around and they did a
phenomenal job though.
I mean given the constraints,
first of all of network television,
of knowing that you're going to have
commercial breaks and knowing that you
can have certain language and certain
things,
you're not going to be able to show.
They did a fantastic job.
I mean it's just one of the all time
great shows for sure.
Totally a great show.
Loved it,
loved being involved in it.
I think it will be,
you know,
something that people will talk about
with me for the rest of my life.
A lot of times.
I'm sure you experienced this as well.
Sometimes the things that you up
personally close to that you're working
in is a huge part of your life.
It takes on a different aspect than just
these simple look from a fan's point of
view.
Like for me last was,
it was Hawaii.
It was surfing,
it was being in love.
It was chameleons.
It was having a shitty day at work.
It was having a great day at work.
It was being hung over.
It was making new friends.
It was everything.
It was my life,
you know,
for a lot of fans.
It's like,
oh,
that's the TV show that I watched
Wednesday night at eight.
And it was always my friend,
but lost for me was sometimes not my
friends.
Sometimes my enemy sometimes he was
incredible sometimes,
you know.
So when people come up to me and say,
what do you think about the show?
How do I make sense that it's,
it's so much of me.
Do you know what I mean?
Your,
your point of view is completely
singular.
I mean,
no one is going to have that point of
view other than the actors on the show
and even their point of view is going to
be kind of different than yours.
Yeah.
People watching and they watched the
finished product and so their
association with is totally different
than yours.
Polished,
beautiful.
There's no agenda.
They just wanting to be entertained,
you know?
Uh,
you know,
no politics.
There's a lot of politics on.
Last,
I mean fuck,
I got in trouble for saying this when
lost was on tv,
but fuck it,
I don't care about that shit.
I watched,
I watched certain cast members go from
making the pilot,
which was a six week pilot where
everyone was hanging out with each other
real pie in at night.
We were all spending time with each
other.
I watched her and act as be like,
this is the greatest job I have ever
done.
I'm in Hawaii.
Is a tropical island getting paid?
Well,
the Castro amazing.
We're going on this journey together to
shoot in like episode three or four of
the first season and hearing people
saying,
I can't believe I'm not unless
Letterman,
why am I not on Letterman?
You're like,
two months ago it was the greatest thing
you've ever done and now you're like,
why can't fly to New York?
Why can't I be on a 12:00
flight to New York?
Why do I have to be on a 9:00
AM flight to New York?
What the fuck is wrong with you?
You're missing it.
You know?
That's so common though.
That's very common with actors.
Actors are strange breed.
When I was on news radio,
we once had this discussion about
Thursday night,
Thursday night lineup on NBC was where
you wanted to be.
That was Seinfeld,
that was friends.
That was the spot and it was fucking sex
in the city and the single guy.
And he's what?
Paul Simms,
the creator of a news radio called the
shit sandwich spot.
So like you have your two good shows and
in between your show you would put dog
shit and um,
everybody was complaining,
why can't we be on Thursday?
And I'm like,
guys,
last time I checked we're on television,
like we're on a sitcom on actual
television.
And it's funny,
like these are the golden years,
like we're going to look back when we're
old and we're going to say fuck,
we were so lucky.
But while it's happening and everybody's
like,
why am I not in the Hollywood reporter?
Why am I not getting a development deal?
Why can't I start my own movie?
And what,
you know,
why did he get it?
And I did that in my teens and early
twenties.
But how come he's got it?
And my agent knew,
um,
the,
my English agent knew I'm not with
anymore.
At one point,
you know,
we lived in and he sent me down.
He was like,
the reason why he's getting it and
you'll know it's because you are not
him.
He has a completely different journey in
his life.
He looks different,
yanks different.
You're not the same.
He won't get the roles that you're going
to get.
He won't get the opportunities that
you'll get and you won't get his book
quit that bullshit because that's not to
get you anywhere.
A great perspective.
So true.
It's hard to find someone to lay it down
like that.
My agent was not only.
That's great.
You had a good guy.
He was,
he was really good.
And then you have to absorb it,
right?
You have to take it in and you have to
separate it from your ego and all your
preconceived notions and assumptions and
actually absorb it.
Right?
And also swallow that very bitter pill
of regardless health of however unfair
you think it is and how it should change
and be justified in one day it will be
okay,
maybe it won't.
And that's really,
I mean we're talking about one very
specific endeavor,
but it's analogous to life itself
because people will look at people that
are doing other things life and there'll
be
upset that they're not doing those
things even though they've taken very
little or no effort to try to do any of
those things.
Right.
It's just,
they,
they become haters know.
And it's crazy that even a successful
person like honestly a huge show like
loss can become a hater.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Totally adorable.
I mean,
it's kind of funny.
it's a human characteristic,
right?
We're always going to compare ourselves
to other people.
I went for a walk yesterday around
Griffith Park and I was talking with my
friend about the whole comparison thing
and I was saying like,
you know that Bill Gates gets up some
days and he's like,
what the fuck?
No,
Jesus Christ,
I can't fucking catch a break,
you know?
Just having a shit day,
all your problems or relative,
you know,
and it's okay to have them,
we're all going to have them.
It's just you got to navigate your way
through them with a little bit of grace
and it seems like those
pitfalls in life or just a part of being
a human being in this weird world
because this world is not like any world
that was ever that ever existed.
There was never a million different
people that you could compare yourself
to that were on television or singing
songs or on the internet or like there's
all these different people that you can
look at and then you look at yourself
and make these comparisons.
It used to just be the people that were
around you and that's what it used to be
for the entire history of the human
race.
It was only the people you could see
with your eyes and come in contact with
other that you didn't have.
This weird perspective and I think it's
part of what a human being is.
We we're constantly striving to improve.
It's a why we stay alive.
It's why we build homes.
It's why we try to get good at a career.
It's like this,
this desire to get better at things also
leads you to compare your own progress
against the progress of others and
that's where the pitfall comes in.
Right?
And obviously a lot of people in in this
new society that we've created with
social media and instant information,
a lot of those people that have become
successful and famous are in those
places because they are the fucking
elite.
So now we're comparing ourselves to the
Like you could be a great basketball
player.
I have an amazing game.
Come home,
stop watching youtube feeds of Dwayne
Wade,
you know Lebron,
and you're like,
oh,
I'm fucking terrible.
No,
you're not terrible.
These are the exception.
And we're exposing ourselves to the
exception almost all the time.
Now everyone on twitter is brilliant.
You know,
everyone in that sense,
those comparisons are great and
beneficial because they force you to try
to achieve a higher standard.
As long as you can keep yourself from
going mad.
Um,
what about the fact that you'll never
get there?
Like,
I'm never going to slam dunk.
I've never,
I don't have the athletic body ability
to slam dunk,
so if my whole ambition was like,
I want us London,
I know Boykins can slam dunk.
He smaller than me,
I can't do it,
I just can't do it.
You know I've tried.
I'm don't get anywhere near.
I don't have the ability to do is now.
How much have you tried?
You know what I mean?
Like if you went to a strength and
conditioning coach,
he said,
listen,
I'm Dominic Monaghan.
I got a lot of fucking money.
Come on bitch.
You're going to get me in fucking top
notch shape.
Going to do dead
lifts.
You're going to get me pumped up with
steroids.
I'm Duncan,
dude.
I'm fucking done.
What is it that the vertical leap leap
down?
Maybe I'm not trying to the extent that,
you know,
some people have,
but I don't know.
I think there's,
I think there's something potentially
harmful.
You know,
it's like the whole thing with beautiful
women.
You know what I mean?
A lot of people,
a lot of ladies and maybe men feel that
pressure to be that perfect thing,
but that perfect thing isn't necessarily
real well.
You know what's really frustrating when
you meet a girl who doesn't like her
body and you love her body and she's
comparing herself to stick figures that
are like in models that are wearing
these weird outfits that way 18 pounds
on your body is a woman's body.
The fat,
the stuff that you don't like,
weed like that.
Like a fat ass.
Yeah.
I mean it's a part of being sexy.
It's like it's,
it's a,
it's actually attractive to men,
but women are comparing to the way
fashion models look and the way other
women perceive.
Like there's certain women,
like I know this lady who she doesn't
think that women look good unless they
look like sticks.
Right?
Like she has this weird thing in her
head and like her friends would try to
talk to her about it.
Like that's not true.
And,
but after awhile you just get tired of
talking about crazy.
Look,
you look great.
Really Great.
Like don't this,
this ain't about that.
You could be born in Ethiopia with no
feet,
you know,
you could,
you could have been fucked.
You could have been one of those kids
that's born in Iraq that has to deal
with the aftermath of all the fucking
hazardous waste.
It's in that area that's causing all
these kids to be born with massive
deformities.
Like you're lucky shit.
You can't go on about the fact that
you're not skinny enough.
I mean,
obviously a lot of that is the,
is the societal thing may not make a big
distinction between like a girl's body
and a woman's buddy.
You know what I mean?
There is a difference.
Most of the fashion lines,
one to put that models in the clothes
when they have a gills buddy,
because there they were calling.
Yeah,
a coat hanger.
That's the way to look at it because
that's what they really are there.
Clothes hangers,
like your clothes look best when they're
not being stuffed into like Jennifer
Lopez.
His body was fucked.
But to a man like that's what men like
to see that fucking ass waist.
Jesus fiance.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's a fucking woman,
yes,
but the,
you know,
those women we were talking about this
the other day,
like that didn't used to be hot,
like just a few.
Like if you go back and look at the
playboys when like the seventies and the
eighties,
they didn't even concentrate on assets
like it wasn't for whatever reason.
That wasn't a focus on what happened or
do we think it's the hip hop community?
Do we think it's.
The wrapper is brilliant.
I mean,
I remember being 12 and seeing a cover
of an ice tea album that had like one
onesy bikinis with big assets.
Oh Damn,
that's true,
right.
That one where ice had a machine gun
behind his back and the girl was in a
bikini and she had.
Yeah,
she had a thong on.
He may have ended up marrying a man.
I think he did.
I think that was his wife for awhile
before he got rid of her and got the
cocoa right.
And that was the first time I was
exposed to that,
you know,
because for me it was like Princess Leia
growing up was my thing,
my jam.
We didn't even know what her body looked
like.
We had no idea there it is.
But even then,
harass.
Yeah,
in comparison to today,
it's not quite that,
but at the time that was kind of
revolutionary.
I'm not hating it.
It's not terrible,
but that's nothing compared to,
you know,
what is her name?
The fucking Nicky Manila to go right
here on power.
Similar just to the right.
Then that goes click on that one,
which I bought that.
That's much more wrapper,
but it's what's interesting is it seems
the attraction to that seems
fundamental.
So why wasn't it there in the seventies
and the eighties?
It seems genetic,
right?
Was it seemed to be.
I don't know.
Obscene.
Oh God.
This folk hero.
Her ass is retarded.
Nicki Minaj.
Anaconda picture.
Like what is that?
Is that real?
Yeah,
I think so.
Wow.
A little extra brush and.
But yeah,
maybe.
But whatever.
That's insane.
It's phenomenal what genetics,
but again,
like Andale obviously it's a lot of it
is girls doing squats and girls
concentrating on that area and
developing their butt,
but I just.
It's weird to me that that wasn't a big
deal in the seventies and the eighties
and whatever,
and then somewhere along the line the
hip hop community sort of ignited what
seems to be a fundamental attraction
that men have.
Right.
Also like,
you know,
when I started to get interested in
girls and being able to actually make
out with girls and spend time with
girls,
those girls were girls that was,
you know,
11,
12,
13 year old.
There was no concept of any of those
girls having a Ba donk,
donk like that.
So maybe for me it was the thing that I
was reaching for.
I'm never gonna get them never going to
get this womanly thing.
I'm going to be with these little
waifish girls because I was a little kid
at the time.
And then later on,
I don't know,
there's a,
there's a fantasy element to it.
Right?
But why?
Well,
for girls though,
the look of a man being like a big
muscular,
like the rock or something like that,
that's always existed like Conan the
barbarian and you know,
that's always been around.
You go back to the Robert e Dot Howard,
illustrations that Frank Frazetta did
like way back in the seventies is
fucking yolked out,
giant barren.
It's universal Roman Greek gods,
sculptures that have been around
forever.
They're all cut and ripped and stuff,
but the women back then were all fat and
Rubin ask,
you know,
they didn't have those bodies.
The bodies have today is like a weird
change and it doesn't exist in the mail.
So it exists in women.
Yeah.
Interesting.
That is interesting.
I mean I,
you know,
I appreciate the lady that kind of takes
care of itself simply because I feel as
if I need to,
you know,
I,
I'm not the biggest dude in the world,
but I go to the gym when I'm free
because it gets me out of the house and
also I like to try and go to the gym
Monday to Friday so that my Saturday,
Sunday I can do whatever at one and I
eat relatively correctly so that on the
weekend if I want to chow down some
food,
there's a little noise.
It's not going to make a huge difference
if I'm doing that.
I would like to be with someone who has
the same common sense about the body and
the way that they look like it's a,
it's a bit of,
it's a bit of an issue,
but for me because like I love pizza and
I like buffalo wings and I could easily
eat all that stuff and,
and get much bigger,
but I'm aware of the fact that it's not
healthy for you.
You shouldn't necessarily be doing that
to your body putting you under that much
stress,
but also I want to feel and look and
present myself good because I want to
feel good about myself and the issue
with people just kind of abuse in
themselves in that way.
Excuse me.
Says something a little sinister about
how they personally feel about
themselves.
Self Abuse,
right?
I mean if you,
if you know the food is making you more
unhealthy and you're eating on a daily
basis,
that is a form of self abuse and I don't
necessarily feel attracted to people who
are abusing themselves on a consistent
basis.
Yeah,
I mean that's natural,
but it is.
It's also weirdly natural for people to
abuse themselves to get caught in that
cycle of overeating and then feeling
shitty because you're overeating and
that's a very common cycle for people
get trapped in and I really wonder what
the mechanism of that is like what's
the,
what's the evolutionary advantage to
having that in the human species?
Because it's so common.
I mean,
everywhere you look,
especially in America,
she just see overweight people
everywhere.
They know.
They have to know.
It's not like this is some secret that's
locked up in the fucking vaults in
Qumran.
You have to crack the code to find out
that you shouldn't eat pizza at 3:00
in the morning.
Right.
And they don't suddenly wake up and go,
oh my God,
what is this?
This.
They've seen it occur.
I don't.
I don't think that's the evolution of us
species.
I think that's those moments where we do
want to abuse herself.
We do want to feel badly.
It doesn't,
it doesn't extend us as a species.
To me it's,
you know,
it's the way that we feel that,
but light you,
you eat relatively healthy,
you work out and stuff.
Like what's your food?
Kryptonite?
What is the thing where you look at.
Oh my God,
I love it.
I gotta have it.
Um,
I do love pizza.
I do love Shitty pastas and pizzas and
things that I know that I shouldn't eat.
That's pretty much it,
but I'm pretty good because I,
I enjoy healthy food.
Like I had,
I was eating Vegan food when he came in
here because I want to,
you know,
because I just did yoga and I'm like,
uh,
that's a good thing to eat.
So it feels good.
Do you give yourself like a free pass?
You're like every Sunday I can have a
slice of pizza.
I
don't though.
I do,
but I kind of would,
if I was more inclined to eat shitty,
like if I was,
if it was like more of a thing that I
had to separate myself from,
but it's not that hard for me.
I eat relatively clean because I like to
eat relatively clean.
I mean,
I honestly relatively clean,
I shouldn't say overwhelmingly clean.
Most of the food I eat is really
healthy.
It's just,
I just,
I know too,
you know,
at this point in time I'd be upset at
myself if I didn't.
I just know too much about the actual
effects.
So the mornings generally in the
mornings I either eat fruit or I eat a
drink,
a Kale shake,
you know,
one of those,
a blended up shakes with Kale and celery
and cucumber and garlic,
all that jazz.
Um,
and then in the afternoon it depends.
But if I feel like having a
cheeseburger,
I'll have a fucking cheeseburgers.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well,
you know,
we were talking about this stuff that
like,
I,
excuse me,
I'm lucky enough to travel nine months
of my year pretty intensively,
you know,
a week in a place,
10 days in a place,
10 days in the place.
Because of that,
lots of long distance flying.
I have no semblance of a schedule in
terms of food.
So I lose weight based on those factors.
And also the fact that my metabolism
metabolism is very high running,
I need very little sleep to function if
this my mommy's tummy,
this all the time.
And I was a kid.
If there was something more interesting
for me to do,
I would forego eating.
So she'd be like,
dinner's on the table.
I'd be like,
wait,
can I just finish this thing?
She was like,
okay,
fine.
And she said you would just not have
dinner and then she would have to remind
me you didn't eat dinner.
And I'm like,
okay,
let me.
And then I'll go back to that thing.
So you would eat just like NASA,
like a necessity pleasurable thing.
I just got to get into your mind,
just get it down because my mom and dad
told me,
I mean I would,
I was obsessed by football,
soccer when I was a kid.
I would get up in the morning,
run out my house when I was going to
school right at my house before
breakfast,
no breakfast,
get to school,
play football for an hour before 9:00.
So from eight til nine and play football
with my friends.
Break time was 10,
15 to 1115.
Most people ate at that point.
Most people had a snack chips,
fruit sandwich.
I would play football.
Lunchtime was an ally.
All my friends would eat.
I would play football first thing that I
would put in my mouth,
pretty much all.
It's certainly more than average in
school.
Like I would say 65 percent of the time
would be candy on the way home.
So I'd walk into the convenience store
by,
by one lbs.
With a candy.
Must have been starving.
Dude.
I was amazed when I was a kid and I was
burning what I dunno,
10,000
calories a day and just putting sugar in
me,
you know,
so I was super skinny and that has
transferred over into my adult life.
Where my trainer has always said to me
is consistency.
Dom,
like you need to be in the gym five days
a week.
So I'm like,
Okay Ryan,
I'm here for a month,
let's do five days a week and get it
poppin.
And he's like,
okay,
cool.
And then like three weeks in,
I'm like,
I'm not like I put on a little bit,
but I'm not feeling it.
And he's.
And he says,
let's talk about what you're reading.
I'm like,
couple of mouthfuls of oatmeal,
breakfast,
some pine and pool and some grapes for
lunch.
She's like,
no,
no.
You need tuna steak.
You need salmon,
you need chicken,
you need Tofu,
you need fat.
You need to own the genie,
the Avocados.
And he would show me what I'm supposed
to be.
I'm not connie either.
I can't get it in my system.
I'm going to Puke.
But you know,
everyone's got their own thing that
they're dealing with,
but I'm never going to be as big as you.
Your frame is bigger and you're just,
you're,
you're naturally big guy.
What my train said is like you can get
caught,
you can get Bruce Lee ish,
but you're never going to get John
Claude van damage.
But the way to do that is to still eat
food.
That fire.
Or if you did want to pack weight on,
you would have to do these big compound
exercises like deadlifts.
You'd have to do squats,
you'd have to do things where your body
literally has to change your body.
Your bone structure has to change.
Your bone structure will change.
I mean,
it will densify it.
You did.
The density of your bone structure
definitely alters when you do heavy,
heavy lifting because your body
realizes,
hey,
this dumb mother fuckers going to pick
up big,
heavy shit all day.
We have to get thicker.
So it makes you,
it literally will make your bones
thicker and denser.
I want the biggest I ever asked.
Can you pull up the.
Can you pull up the,
um,
the poster for the pilot of lost,
like the first ever poster philosophies,
all of us on a beach.
The biggest I ever was,
I was probably like 158 pounds.
Something that,
which is big on me.
I put on like 12,
14 pounds of muscle and my fucking
biceps like this.
And I never got that big ever again.
And at the time,
what were you doing a.
no,
it's like a more of an iconic silhouette
on a beach.
Hang on.
Oh Jesus.
Okay.
Uh,
what was I doing?
I was,
I had food delivery and the food and the
food delivery was like,
I'm going to the gym,
give me clean food,
give me lots of clean food.
I was in the gym once a day and then I
did a little bit of running around my
local area and it was consistency.
Yeah,
that's right.
Consistent.
It's about getting a good groove gone,
right?
It's about just getting a good habit
going or this is what you do.
They say that if you could do something
every day for 90 days,
then it will become like a part of you
to become like they say that that's one
of the best ways to quit smoking is if
you can get addicted to something else
and get,
get used to doing that every day.
Yeah.
But there's a slightly high res version.
You can't really see it,
but I am huge death of me.
I mean I don't look cute because I'm not
the biggest guy in the world,
but like you can.
Well I can see at least let my fucking.
I see some muscle now.
My biceps are going off right there.
Was there any hesitation at all being
sequestered on this island like that and
being a part of this crazy show where
you had to change your whole life?
I mean,
you had to move.
Yeah.
I met Jj Abrams and he just,
he just solved all of those conundrums
foaming how?
So He's just a brilliant guy,
you know,
you meet brilliant guys every so often
and I think anytime you're around
someone who's brilliant,
you have to sit up and take notes,
you know,
and I just was aware that I was around
someone with a very fast moving smart
mind and I went in for a general
audition and sat down with Jj and his
partner Brian Burke and we just told
about English comedy for like 45
minutes.
Talks about Monty Python,
Eddie Izzard and uh,
the goons and the goodies and Derek and
clive and we did this whole thing.
We,
we're doing impressions for each other,
no audition.
And I left and I called my agent and he
was like,
how did it go?
And I was like,
it went well,
but we didn't talk about the show.
We just talked about comedy and goofed
around and stuff.
And he was like,
all right,
cool.
Then they got back in,
touch them and said we loved,
um,
they had this character of Charlie who
at the time was this 55 year old rocker,
like a,
like a Robert Plant guy at the time that
had been through all of it and was in
the tail end of his career and got stuck
on the island and they reworked it.
And when Jj and I sat down,
I was like,
what is more frustrating for the artist
to have the barest glimpse of fame?
You've got this one hit.
And it all almost worked out his entire
life.
It almost did it for him and it was on
this fucking island and he can't get
back to the place where he could make it
all happen.
You know?
And I think,
you know,
Jj love responded to that kind of
frustration level.
And I was just aware that it was gonna
be a big deal.
He directed the pilot.
He Co wrote the pilot,
it felt like something that was gonna
be,
you know,
big and impressive and I trusted him.
Um,
and there wasn't a huge amount when,
when it's a,
when it's a no brainer job like that,
it doesn't take a huge amount of
thought.
You're just like,
well yeah,
of course I'm going to do it.
There's no living in Hawaii would be a
really tough decision to make because I
wouldn't mind one day living in Hawaii,
but I would have to be really done with
cities.
I could just done like,
I need something different in my life.
I bought,
I got a job.
They want you to move to Hawaii.
Bill.
Ooh Boy.
I don't know.
It's.
Did you get island fever vault?
You know,
I actually didn't.
A lot of people in the cast did.
I'm into jungles and forests and animals
and stuff.
So for me I was kind of buzzed enough
that I had said to them before I moved
out there because they were putting this
in houses.
I was like,
can you put me in the jungle?
Can you put me straight up in the
jungle,
in a house,
the surrounded by trees and animals and
because they didn't know me,
the producers like,
you don't want to do that.
You're going to be isolated,
you're going to be on your own is going
to be nothing around you.
That's exactly what I wanted to do.
So I ended up moving,
living in Kailua for a little bit.
Then moved to Atlanta guy for a little
bit with Atlanta.
Kai.
Lenny has this loop.
It's a little half a mile loop,
very exclusive little part of the
islands,
south east part of the island.
Um,
Michelle pfeiffer has a house there,
so I was able to watch her go on a daily
run every day,
which is pretty fantastic.
Lives there,
Huh?
I think she has like a summary place
around there.
She's still,
oh my gosh,
you're so cute.
Some little as well.
She's doing well at the time.
She's probably in her mid forties,
mid fifties at least.
Yeah.
Maybe still hot.
So hot.
She'd wear a little,
you know,
cycling shorts and a little like running
thing.
And I was like,
oh.
She say hi to you ever.
No,
I never said hi to read them.
Make sure that I was just watching out
the window in my binoculars.
Fucking citing scope.
Right.
But Hawaii was,
you know,
it was,
it was cool.
I liked it.
I was,
I learned to surf in New Zealand,
which is a gnarly place to serve very
cold waves,
relatively dumb p waves.
There's no curl on that wave.
It just picks you up and drops you.
Which if it's the first time you've ever
served it,
you assume all waves of light that you
have to be in a wetsuit.
Last time you had to be in buoys.
Uh,
there were times where it was so cold
out.
Come out of the water.
They'd have to use two hands to unlock
my car door because I couldn't use one
hand.
It would,
it had frozen,
you know,
so I'd have to go.
Wow.
Meanwhile,
you moved to Hawaii boardshorts after
wear tee shirts,
water bottles everywhere.
I don't think so.
I was big on surfing and in the first
month or so that I was in Hawaii,
I went to the apple store in Honolulu
and uh,
I met one of my favorite surfers of all
time.
I got called Kalani,
rob,
and when I was playing Kelly slater's
pro surfer game,
I would always pick Kalani because he
did the most radical moves,
you know,
so I'm in the apple store,
he's there with his boys.
I was like,
shit,
that's Kalani Romp.
And then he comes up to me.
He's like,
Dude,
you're that guy in load the rings.
I was like,
Oh shit,
it's on now.
So I was like,
you're Kalani,
rob.
I was like,
I'm here for like nine months,
can you help me out surfing?
He was like,
yeah,
we're going to go to the no show now.
So I came with him,
hung out,
uh,
and we became really tight.
So a huge story for a while.
For me it was getting to know Kalani.
I mean he taught me into waves.
I had no business being involved in.
There's a place called goat island on
the north shore,
which is a heavy wave and you have to
paddle out to an island,
walk across the island because then
you're going to miss the break and then
paddle out past the break.
There's no concept of you're paddling
out through the break because it's so
big.
So as with Kalani and a few of his mates
and we were all getting ready and he
came over to me,
he was like,
okay,
this is the most hectic wave and ever
going to take you into.
Stay close to me.
If you need help,
let me know.
Don't fuck around because it can kill
you.
And don't go left.
Go right.
No,
no,
don't go right.
Go left because it's gonna appeal left.
But if you go right,
you're in the braking zone and you're
fucked.
I was like,
alright,
cool.
So sense of fucking terrible story
coming out.
So we.
So we paddle out and I'm having fun and
I'm watching everyone in the lineup on
about 10 feet away from the drop zone.
So I'm able to like sit down on the wave
and watched people like get on the side.
I'm like,
alright cool.
I got this fast,
I'm going to,
I'm going to take it.
So I paddled,
I battle a battle with,
picks me up big like Oh shit,
super powerful drops me and I really try
and go left.
I like cut the board and then try and go
left.
But it's so powerful because breaking
here on my left that it spits me to the
right.
I'm fully aware that it sent me to the
So I'm like okay shit,
I'm just going to wipe out,
take a big breath and paddle out.
So I wipe out are going to come up.
And as is usually the case with,
if you're surfing anything above
overhead,
when you come up that wave's coming
for you against what you have to do is
take a huge breath,
go under and it's the next time you come
up do you can make progress because your
out breath,
you disoriented.
I do that and Joe,
I just can't.
I can never catch a break.
So I go under,
thrown around by the washing machine,
come up the thing,
okay,
get on your board,
start paddling,
look where's right there.
I'm like,
oh,
go and drink in,
hold my breath,
come up again.
And I'm trying to time it so that I can
get it.
I just getting pounded,
pounded,
pounded.
And at one point I see Kalani paddling
over to me.
I'm like,
all right,
cool.
We're going to be okay.
So Kalani comes up to me and he's like
mad,
like I've never really heard him you
metaphor.
He's like,
Dude,
get on your board and go that way.
I'm like,
okay,
that's what I've been trying to do for
like 10 minutes.
But so now he's behind me.
He's paddling,
I'm paddling,
he's pushing me,
paddling,
pushing me,
paddling like fucking superman.
And we eventually get out past the
break.
So he's like,
all right,
you going to sit here for 20 minutes and
then when I'm done you're going to
paddle in with me safe.
And I was like,
okay,
fine.
I got it.
So when we come in,
he's like,
the reason why I came in to get it was
not only were you in the drop zone but
you were like completely lacking of any
color on your face.
And he was like,
people in the lineup was saying,
dude,
go get your boy because he's in trouble.
And I was like,
I was handling it.
I was definitely out of breath and a
little fucked up,
but he's a wharton.
Then he was like,
no,
eight more waves on your headlight that
you wouldn't have had the strength to
fight past the wave and get up here
because you get these little gas.
Dude.
It's so heavy and it has a really good
trick.
Colone told me this one.
He's like,
if you're under the water and you're
rolling around and you fucked and you
need to take a breath,
drink the tiniest amount of seawater.
Tiny sip.
Just go like that.
Tricks your body into thinking you took
a breath and it'll give you an extra
five seconds.
So because you've just taken an in,
well not an inhalation,
but you've,
you've put something in your body so
your lungs are like,
okay,
we can chill.
The panic goes for a little bit.
Yeah.
And I've done that a few times I'd been
under and I'm like think a little
swollen.
Come back up.
Wow.
Oh,
how weird.
Funny you fighting for five second
increments to.
It's so hectic.
Surfing seems crazy.
I mean,
you never done it?
No,
never done it.
Oh,
you look like someone that can handle
it.
I mean you need a,
you need a big book,
but you're an athlete.
You can handle it.
Yeah.
Seems like a lot of work.
It also seems like something get
addicted to.
I'm scared of things that you get
addicted to really addicted to work.
Oh yeah,
exactly.
I just don't have any more time.
I'm just so afraid of some new thing in
my life that I get addicted to.
And then I just think about it all the
time.
I go through different sessions and
stuff with certain things,
but what's so what's
like,
you're doing this thing right now on
instagram with the rock where he's
fucking lifting up kettlebells and
you're lifting up kettlebells.
Are you guys tight?
Do you know each other?
Yeah.
No,
I don't ignore them online.
We were pals.
Right,
okay.
You know,
and we uh,
we share,
you know,
we have friends and he's going to do the
podcast eventually we're working on
because his company,
one of his companies that he,
he's involved with is the roots of fight
this,
a company that does all these old fight
poster tee shirts.
Really Cool Shit.
Excuse me.
And he's always wearing their stuff and
he's coming in town to do with them.
So
you know,
somebody in San Andres and said he was a
lovely dude.
Oh,
you're supposed to be the best guy.
Super friendly,
knew everyone's name,
really accommodate and well,
he's the real deal.
Like he's really does get up at 5:00
in the morning and workout before the
set.
He takes all these instagram photos.
He's like the most inspirational guy
when it comes to like getting shit done.
Yeah.
Because he just gets shit done,
you know,
beast as well.
Fucking animal.
He's making it happen.
There is Samoan,
right?
Somebody has some genetic stuff that
he's definitely got some genetics
though.
He's a giant dude.
He's a fucking animal man,
but he's very motivated.
See that shirt that he's wearing.
That's a route to fight shirt.
That's the tie.
Yeah.
They have a lot of really cool old
school.
Different like fight posters from like
Muhammad Ali versus Joe Frazier.
Thrilla in Manila.
Like Nice Shit.
Like he's,
you know,
if I would see a guy that big on the
street light that it would be kind of
freakish,
but for some reason the ruc pulls it
off.
He's very proportionate.
Yeah.
He knows what he's doing.
If you scroll down lower,
that's another route to fight shirt.
Scroll down.
Lower that John Fan going.
That's a.
that's a Bruce Lee shirt.
He's got a bunch of these.
I,
he's an animal.
Yeah.
Hey,
I'm cardio.
Fucking animal.
Good for him.
Yeah,
I mean look,
there are people like that,
like Kevin Hart is stand up,
he's another one,
very inspirational guys always doing
something.
He's up 5:00
in the.
My,
yeah,
he makes these little videos of him
doing anything very good shape.
He works out every fucking day and he
puts instagram photos of and he's a
comedian.
He's constantly getting things done.
I don't think they found the right
vehicle for men.
No,
his standup is the right vehicle for all
those other things.
The movies and everything was great.
Just making them more famous and bigger.
But his standup is where it's at.
Yeah,
he's got to find it.
I,
uh,
you know,
friends with Kimball,
Kimmel,
Kamal's always impressed me just in
terms of like knowing what his day's
like,
but also the fact that he'll reply to me
pretty quickly.
I'm like,
dude,
on,
you're doing 15 things at the time.
He's like,
well,
yeah,
I am by,
you're the 16th thing that I can do.
You know,
I just really impressed by his work
ethic and it's very often the same,
the routine of going into the studio and
go and in the writer's room and breaking
jokes and doing the monologue and only
because it's the same every day,
but he's still of a to do it and he's
brilliant and he knows what's funny and
he knows what the joke is and I don't
know.
Those are the older,
late night tv,
older,
late night talk show hosts that I've had
the opportunity to meet.
I've always thought there's something
brilliant about you.
You know,
there's something brilliant about
working in that medium,
you know,
it's,
it's current and edgy and you know,
what they're doing at times can be a
little risky and dangerous and stuff,
but they're willing to get out the next
day and do it again and get the next day
and not get pounded down in the same way
that other people might.
Yeah.
That's their thing.
You know,
I mean,
that's what Jimmy Kimmel is best at.
He's,
he's got,
obviously,
he's got a fantastic work ethic and he's
obviously a brilliant guy,
but that's what he wants to do.
His thing,
you know,
like it works for him.
It's a beautiful gig too because you can
never rest on your laurels because it
doesn't matter.
Tomorrow there's another show that show
has to be good as well.
Like can you need new jokes and you need
new sketches and you need new gags to
pull off and you have new guest to
review and to go over what they're
talking about.
Yeah.
And he's done a lot of jumping up Jimmy
in a way that I really respect.
Like I did a show a long time ago,
maybe 12 years ago and at that point,
you know it's has different.
It's a little bigger than,
oh,
quite gray suits to fit yet the whole
facade of the show,
you know,
he was being worked on,
but Jimmy,
I think his drive and maybe the drive of
the people that he surrounds himself
with,
you know,
he,
he jumped up when he did the Matt Damon
thing.
He jumped up when he interviewed Obama.
He jumped up when he,
you know,
so it always hair and you know,
kind of dropped a few pounds and so it
dies.
Suit like he has a drive.
There's no sense of complacency with
Jimmy and I find that seems to be
relatively concurrent with talk show
hosts,
Conan's like that.
He's always reaching to know what I
mean.
He's never like,
okay,
we're done this the show.
Let's just,
let's just dial in reaching.
I appreciate watching people reach.
It's why I'm a huge fan of athletes in
general,
you know?
I always feel like athletes are always
trying for that next thing.
Yeah.
It's,
it's finding comfort and happiness in
that struggle,
enjoying the process that's very
difficult for people and for some people
that the monotony of showing up and
doing it all over again that wears on
them.
It's really just about finding whatever
the fuck it is for you.
For some people it's not that for some
people it's they kind of go to an
Anthony Bourdain is an interesting cat
and he had him on the show.
Yeah,
yeah,
a while ago,
but I've talked to him a gang of times
that UFC is a huge UFC as a firearm
while his wife trains.
I don't think she's,
she's competed in Jujitsu tournaments,
but um,
she's a mad man,
mad woman rather.
And he's doing it now as well.
He's doing Jujitsu now,
but the point being that he's a guy that
doesn't feel like he,
if he's home for a week or two,
he's like,
I gotta get the fuck out of here.
He's just constantly wants to go to
Libya or Africa or China just want,
he just wants to experience it at all.
And his work is going to places and
experiencing these completely different
worlds.
That's where it's where it's at for him.
So He's,
he got a totally,
he's got a totally unique way of being
ambitious.
Very different than like a talk show
host would show up and the same writers
room and drink the coffee and bang up
the jokes and he's just as ambitious.
But his ambition is to go to Moscow to
try their food and talk to their people.
Yeah.
And he also,
I don't know him at all,
I think it's fantastic.
I read kitchen confidential years ago
when it first came out and I thought,
wow,
this guy's insane.
And then obviously you blow up on TV.
He also has a through line of an addict
in his work.
He was an ex addict.
He holds his hands up and says that I
think when you meet a lot of ex addicts
or even addicts,
they have that thing that they're doing
which completely takes hold of their
life,
which is stopping them from doing the
drug that they're addicted to and they
can't.
If they chill and relaxed then that,
that Damon's going to come in and hang
out with them.
So I think baudins light,
well if I spend 10 days at home,
maybe that month is going to come out.
So he has to keep me,
you know,
I don't know him well enough to know if
that's true or not,
but I know enough addicts that say I
have to be on the new thing.
I have to be moving to the new place.
Your character was an addict,
right?
Did you have to do a lot of research
about that?
They didn't ask me to,
but I mean I've had my own,
you know,
fun,
positive,
great Jenny with drugs in my life,
you know,
it's like that Gray Bill Hicks joke
where he's like,
I had a great time on drugs.
Like,
um,
not,
not to tell people to do drugs.
I think it's a very,
very personal thing.
I was lucky enough to come from a family
background that was very consistent and
there,
you know,
my parents have been married for 42
years.
I always came back to a household where
dinner was on the table regardless with
that eight or not,
um,
you know,
a foundation of something that I think
made me feel secure.
Uh,
got interested,
was always interested in music,
got interested in the Beatles when I was
about 12,
13.
I started reading up about them and read
the rubber sole and sergeant peppers and
the white album were very much
influenced by drugs and thought,
oh,
that's interesting because I feel
autistic and I'd like to see if I can
make that artistic flower bloom a little
bit.
And at that point,
me and three other bills,
fans at my school site side started to
seek out marijuana,
which we ended up getting hold of.
And he did that,
a typical thing when your kids were,
you know,
you will smoke a joint in two and half
minutes and everyone feels lightheaded
and one of them puked and then you get
nervous and paranoid and you run off and
you think you're never going to do it
again.
And uh,
and then you do it again.
And then he'd do it again.
And then at one point you're like,
oh,
it hit,
you know.
And um,
I.
So I did that.
I mean,
fuck,
I remember as I'm a very dedicated
worker,
I,
you know,
obviously I never do drugs when I'm
working,
but in my downtime on my weekends I
might do that.
And I flew my brother out to New Zealand
to come check us all out making Lord of
the rings.
And at the time I was heavily into
marijuana,
probably the most.
I was into it in my life and I would
roll like 20 joints and put them in a
cigarette box.
I never smoked cigarettes,
put them in a cigarette box that someone
had given to me and I would just walk
around the house,
just smoking joints,
like I'm smoking cigarettes and my
brother who is only 16 months older than
me,
he sat me down at one point in that
shape and he was like,
I've never seen anyone smoke as much
weed as you and how are you functioning
and maybe you should consider not doing
it.
And I was a highly functioning stone.
I was like,
fine,
come on,
let's go.
And that's,
you know,
that's gone in different journeys in my
life.
So I think when I met Jj,
I'd spent,
I'd spent 18 months in la having not
worked,
exposing myself to La for the first time
and not necessarily on the biggest part
you've seen,
but certainly on a bit of a party scene,
hanging out with the wrong people,
the wrong women.
And I think Jay Jay's perceptive enough
to probably see when I came into a
meeting,
like I was a bit rough around the edges.
He didn't shave.
He knows what it means to have a
hangover.
He's,
you know,
he knows what it means when we say
certain buzzwords,
so he could have danced in these arenas,
you know?
Um,
so yeah,
it's a cautionary tale.
I think drugs and I'm really careful
about it.
Like I,
you know,
I'm aware that there are young people
who might follow me on twitter or follow
me on instagram that,
that would think,
oh,
well if he's done it,
it's okay.
And I don't,
I don't subscribe to that.
So I think you have to have your own
journey and you have to have your own
experiences.
But the abuse of drugs has never been
something that's been in my life.
The usage of drugs has been something
that I've done more often than not.
If I'm partaking in some sort of drug,
I have a notebook and a pen close enough
by me.
So if I feel like I'm inventing the
future,
I can write it down and then the morning
when I wake up I can be like,
oh,
there's a positive element of that thing
I took,
you know,
I'm like searching for stuff.
And I think searching for stuff in that
world can be quite significant.
Well,
that's a very honest interpretation or
very honest expression of what drugs
are.
Some drugs can be.
And I think one of the problems with
someone seeing you on social media or
some young kid saying,
well,
if he takes him,
I,
I could take them there.
Okay.
And the only reason why they would have
that thought at all is because they've
been lied to so much.
There's so much bullshit on TV.
There's so much nancy grace and
nonsense.
And marijuana is more dangerous today
than at anytime in the past.
Still Marijuana.
The end of the day.
It's just pot.
He has nobody's dying.
Nothing happens.
You get paranoid,
you wake up,
you're fine.
No hangover.
Your bones don't ache.
You're really okay.
No one died on an overdose of marijuana
and history of the planet.
You're saying that you will use to abuse
it.
It's like even your abuse.
Look,
you're functioning.
You're not throwing up in your own bed.
And No,
you know,
I've had,
uh,
several moments in my life where I've
said,
okay,
go flush that.
Like you did it last night,
you don't need to do it tonight.
You don't need to do it tomorrow.
Yeah,
yeah.
It's Thursday night in moving into
Friday night.
You're not doing anything tonight.
You know,
that little monster is going to be in
that drawer,
flush it.
But it's only been pot.
No,
no.
Been everything that's been everything.
I was like,
that's a weird one to taught,
you know,
because it doesn't usually taunt people.
I mean,
I find the friends that I have that I,
I believe,
you know,
I would classify as addicted to
marijuana.
They,
they do it because that's what they
think they do.
They get up and they do it because it's,
it's almost like,
it certainly can be an escape,
but it's also a comfort and a lot of
ways.
It's like that thing that you do,
like coffee.
I have friends that can't get coffee,
you know,
they're like,
fuck,
I get up in the morning,
I need that cup of coffee.
It's like a ritualistic,
comforting sort of a thing that they do.
I mean another way to describe it would
be a crutch.
Right?
And that is a negative connotation.
You don't necessarily want something in
your life that as a crutch,
whether that is marijuana or cocaine,
or having to call your mom every day or
needing to have the new Levi's,
whatever that is.
If it's a crutch,
it's not good the best.
If we're just talking about wheat,
the best times for me on we'd have been
ingesting it.
I don't tend to smoke anymore.
I put it in brownies.
Ingesting it in a way that makes the
next experience that I'm going to have
much more colorful.
Surfing on.
Weed is a beautiful experience.
You're in that flow,
you're in that rhythm,
you know,
watching a movie that you really like.
Listening to a new album.
I mean dude,
like I was still am in love with the
band cigarettes,
cigarettes,
no Icelandic band that kind of referred
to as the Icelandic radiohead.
S I s I g u a r o s separate word.
Yeah.
Cigarettes Way Sig you.
Uh,
and then a separate word r o s.
So it's Sigur Ros,
you a separate word.
R O s,
that first album has an alien fetus on
the front cover.
Standard Shit.
Yeah,
I'm an eighth.
I'm an atheist and uh,
I've always,
you know,
explored and struggled with the idea of
God concepts.
But I've always thought if there is a
heaven that playing Sigur Ros is the
most,
is the most truly like captivate in bw.
There you go.
That's the album you want know.
Wow.
Okay.
So cool.
I'll listen to on the way home.
So.
Right.
I just love that I could do that.
I can just order that shit up on my
phone and listen to it on the way home
or not.
I don't even have to do it now and
download it.
I could sit in my car,
look at it on the itunes,
plugging into the dash and then it'll
start playing.
Yeah.
That's very cool to society that we live
in.
So wonderful.
But I have an issue with the cloud.
I don't like this clown
thing is a lot of weirdness is
definitely out of weirdness in the whole
idea of the cloud.
You know that from happening,
that happened and all these poor folks
that had their porn up there got
exposed.
I think that's a,
that's a tiny tremor that will lead to
the ultimate earthquake that evades or a
privacy rather.
It killed.
It killed the cloud in a lot of
different ways.
That happening thing.
But also like not for the dudes who
jerked off like wild monkeys.
It was awesome.
Yeah,
that's true.
At Jamie,
Jamie's got fat,
hard drive filled with fat burning
content.
But like if I really liked the film and
I watch it,
if it's streaming from watching it on
Netflix,
if I really found guaranteed I'm going
to buy it,
go buy it on DVD because I want the
actual article wanting in my house.
And the same with music.
If I like an album,
I'm going to go buy that CD and I don't
want that medium to die,
you know,
I don't think it's going to die.
Um,
I was at the bookstore the other day
with my mother in law and she was
talking about a Zepplin how so the holy
was there and they,
they're selling these new vinyl versions
of houses of the holy and like Barnes
and noble in thousand oaks.
They filed these fucking,
these albums and it's wild.
Like these are 19 sixties,
19 seventies albums and people are
buying records and turntables and
they're getting into the actual physical
medium again,
opening it up and it's cool.
Yeah,
I mean I think the vinyl culture is
really fantastic and that is great that
the vinyl thing Kinda came back around
again.
I do think that those select artists
that make their way onto vinyl,
you,
Jimi Hendrix is your,
Elvis's you'd led Zeppelin's,
you'd deals,
they'll always be around,
but the smaller ones they're going to be
like,
well,
he's not big enough to go on vinyl,
so let's just put them on digital.
Someone's going to want him.
We'll put him on digital in this.
It makes me sad that there are albums
that I own.
If I break that CD,
it's going to be very difficult for me
to get it unless I pay $69 99 on Ebay in
the night.
Get a copy of that's been previously
used.
Yeah,
some comic Belper released a Carnegie
Hall special that he did on the album as
a vinyl thing where I think that's Kinda
cool.
So when I was a kid that was a big thing
was listening to like cheech and Chong
and bill cosby unfortunately arrested
piece,
still friendly recipes because they're
the real bill cosby's dead.
Sure.
It's still funny though.
It's still fun.
Yeah.
He was very funny.
I mean that to me is one of the most
fascinating.
I,
I say you could say scandals.
Tragedies are horrific crimes,
whatever it is,
whatever you want to call it,
but that,
that guy turned out to be a rapist and a
not just a,
a just a rapist,
but a guy who drug people and fuck them
while they're unconscious.
Like that guy was that right?
That's still bends my brain,
man.
It's,
it's a profound fall from grace.
It's not just a fall from grace,
it's just,
it's horrific.
It's,
it's,
it like twists the world.
The world's not the same world anymore.
Bill cosby's a rapist.
Right,
right,
right.
That's not the world's not the same
anymore.
I was the fucking.
The huxtable dad.
He was,
he was this guy that was telling
everybody to not swear.
Right,
right.
He was the Jello pudding guy.
Family Guy.
He's the guy that you want to pick you
up and sit on your knee and give you a
life lesson.
Now.
You don't want him to sit on his knee
when I was here or if you do,
you fucking don't drink anything.
You.
When I was a kid,
we used to listen to that album where he
would talk about Noah and the Ark.
Noah having that conversation with God
where God was.
No,
uh,
it's God,
right?
You know,
like,
it was a great bit,
man.
It was a great bit with no and not
believing that God really wanted him to
go out and build this ark.
It's just,
um,
that was,
that was how we listened to comedy.
We would all sit around and we'd put the
headphones on and we would all sit
around and listen to this,
you know,
whether it's cheech and Chong or we got
a hold of some oral old George Carlin
Jack.
Then so dangerous,
so edgy,
so brave guy and wasn't in the
beginning,
you know.
And then there's an interesting lesson
if you go see George Carlin's,
the early,
early,
early stuff,
it was like straight up tonight.
Show TV friendly comedy.
Yeah.
And somewhere along the line he just
cut,
kinda twisted.
Well,
I never knew him,
never met him.
I get the feeling that he got angry
about something and stop giving a shit.
And that's what his real voice came from
him.
He was just like,
fuck this man.
I'm not going to get famous.
I'm looking at my own late night talk
show.
Let's do it.
He's,
I don't know if that's what his goal was
or who knows,
whatever it was like Bill Hicks was
living like that,
right?
I mean,
he was great.
His material was fantastic,
but there was a point where he was like,
fuck this.
Like I see the fucking rip in the
universe,
I see it and now I'm going to pull it
out to all you guys.
He didn't have a chance unfortunately.
I met.
I met him a couple of high like,
but never like hung out and talked to
him.
Same with Carla and I met him like I had
the store passing by.
He was very friendly.
Hello?
Hello.
Carla is so epic.
I got to see Hicks live when I was an
open mic or which was a great,
great,
great chance to see like one of the all
time greats is a beginning.
A beginning of my career.
I got to see him bomb.
Oh well I got see bomb and not give a
fuck was me and Greg Fitzsimmons and a
few other comics in the back of the
room.
There was maybe 200 5,300
people in the room when he started.
By the time he was done there was 50 and
we were all screaming in the mood.
Um,
he was bombing,
you know,
it'd been,
wasn't going,
but the comics were laughing hard.
We were laughing hard and a few people
were laughing hard,
right.
And then there's a few people in the
audience that was trying to figure out
what everybody was laughing at that
stuck around and try to save like,
am I missing out on something cool here?
Like,
yes you are.
Yeah,
it was,
it was.
He went on after a guy who was like
really hacky.
The guy went on before was like,
he was doing impressions of cartoon
characters if they smoke marijuana,
you know,
it was a real standard,
like I mean like straight across the
board,
like cop donut jokes and that kind of
flown on an airplane and they,
the audience was fairly dimwitted and
they were enjoying this really stupid
comedy and then Hicks came out and just
did all this really radical,
crazy shit
that just,
they just weren't hearing it and they
just got up and sometimes it's difficult
to be in the presence of genius.
Right?
I mean it tends to be standup.
I think of his genius is absolutely
phenomenal.
Rolling Stone interview with a John
Lennon with the guy who invented
rollingstone yen went to.
It's like,
well,
he had the edited versions about 40
minutes,
I've got about three hours of it and
landon gets angry about the fact that
he's a genius and he's having to perform
like a clown in front of these fucking
retards that don't get it,
and he resents like,
I resent the fact that they're not
receiving it and they're also telling me
that Maya is x,
y,
and zed.
You don't get to fucking tell me what my
art is.
I'm the iced.
You just sit there and fucking listen to
it.
Right.
Yeah.
I appreciate that.
You're never going to get it.
You know,
I think the Hicks thing,
what was going on was that he hadn't
found those people yet.
This was all pre internet,
so no one had.
No one knew what he was doing,
so they were going to go see a guy who
was a funny comedian and they had seen
him on the Rodney dangerfield comic
special on Hbo and he only did like
seven minutes on that or whatever the
hell it was.
Whatever they do.
It was a very small,
short,
funny set,
but it was funny,
a bunch of jokes and so people went to
see him a lot based on that and they
went to see him.
They're like,
what the fuck is all this anger?
Dude,
he hadn't really found that audience
yet.
Right.
And then he died huge biggest standup
comedian in England for probably four
years earlier when he wouldn't a ward,
which is at the Edinburgh fringe
festival.
And he was huge.
He was,
by the time he died,
he was the Jim Morrison of standup
comedy for us.
Well,
he did relentless.
He filmed it live in England,
you know,
and you wrote a very risky thing to do.
It wasn't his best special.
He was very tight and one of the reasons
is because it was all one take was one
show,
one take and you know,
it's an hbo special,
so it's a.
But again,
he was a guy that if he found his
audience,
if they knew where to go,
you know,
like today,
if he was alive today,
my God,
who would have been so fucking monster
following be the king,
the king or one of the Kings,
you know what I mean?
So it's just a finding.
Then we'd find out that he's drugging
jerks.
Yeah.
No,
probably not.
But I mean,
I love what Louis Ck is doing right now.
I mean,
he,
he's an exceptional right age.
Very.
He's very artistic.
He's very,
he's very.
I'm on the edge.
You know what I mean?
He comes up with the joke and then he
retires it and that's it.
You know what I mean?
He's coming up with new stuff,
I think.
I think he's fantastic.
And the fact that he edits and writes
and directs and producing stars in his
show,
brilliant.
He's obviously a phenomenal.
I'm,
I'm okay with darkness and I know what
the darkness is for me.
There is.
There are moments when I'm watching a
show or I'm like,
oh,
just two.
Oh,
his TV show.
Yeah.
So it's two dogs.
The TV show,
I'm not a big fan of like depressing
shit.
I'm not.
I don't
want to watch.
So you've got kinda.
Yeah,
like he's getting frustrated is fixing
his kid's doll and I was like,
oh no,
no,
no.
The overlying themes of like,
you'll.
This is never going to get any bad.
You're fucked.
You're never going to find someone who
loves you again.
I don't buy another bad father.
It's duct heavy.
Yeah.
But he,
he minds that you know and comes up with
great,
hilarious shit from that.
It's just,
it's one of those things like
everybody's got their own little fucking
thing.
Have you ever seen Joey Diaz?
No,
but I heard him on your show.
Yeah,
he's funny as hell.
You got to see that guy.
Like what's his vibe standup wise?
He's a monster.
He's the funniest guy that's ever lived.
I heard you say that on the show.
Like never seen anybody funnier.
I've never seen anybody who kills so
hard.
So what's his.
I mean he was an animal.
He said it's $300 story.
He's got great jokes,
great stories.
He's just,
he's just a wild fucker.
Who's been through everything?
He's been to jail for.
Armed kidnapping was a cocaine addict
for most of his life.
He's just a fucking bonafide gangster.
Do you think that he was friendly?
He doesn't mean it doesn't give any
fucks.
He has zero fucks in his tank.
I mean for real.
Like,
look,
there's a lot of people tell you they
don't give a fuck,
but they do.
He really doesn't give a fuck.
You know what I mean?
Who gives a fuck about his friends and
his family and you know what he's doing.
But he's free now cause he's got his own
podcast.
He sells out everywhere he goes doing
stand up and he doesn't give a fuck.
He doesn't want to do anything other
than that because that's just what he
does.
But before he goes,
before he leaves this earth,
you've got to see him.
You have to show la all the time.
I'll let you know.
I'll,
I'll find out what it's going to be
around you.
GotTa.
Come see him.
I love standup.
I mean,
you know,
I love,
I just love that medium.
I think it's really,
it's super brave and I think a lot of
people don't necessarily know the
mechanics of hail.
A comedian found himself being onstage
with a microphone and if anyone did know
that people will shut the fuck up and
laugh or just politely leave because
like the disrespect shown by hecklers to
standup Comedians,
were you like,
do you have any idea how ballsy is to
get up on stage and show your ass like
that all the time,
but you know what that is,
man.
That's just.
It's the same thing.
It's like people that are haters on
twitter or facebook,
it's just too easy to do so.
It's too easy to speak up.
It's too easy to take.
It's too easy to just have an opinion
that's not nuanced and not objective.
It's to easy shit.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's so easy to do that.
It's so easy to be that dummy,
you know?
I mean,
there was that guy the other day at the
comedy store where there those fucking
guys were drunk in the back of the
parking lot and give everybody a hard
time.
There's just so many of them and they're
just dim witted dumb people that they
shouldn't have that ability to speak to
you,
but they do.
So they are just,
they are not smart.
They're not sensitive.
They're not thinking,
but they look forward.
How do you deal with hecklers?
I mean like your little imposing.
So I would imagine people heckle you had
called you a little less cold.
Got To all the time.
Everybody gets tackled.
People get drunk.
They're not thinking straight.
They're not thinking like maybe this guy
could kill me,
maybe I should shut the fuck up.
So I don't think like that.
Do you call them out?
Do you have fun?
Them?
Depends.
It's like there's no,
like,
some heckling is funny,
you know,
like there was like sometime one time I
was on stage in New York and uh,
and I said,
do you know what the most famous woman
in the world is?
It was a bit about Kim Kardashian
meeting the aliens and they're like,
if aliens came down and they met Kim
Kardashian and they had to,
they had to explain like Kim Kardashians
existence in her fame.
Like why is this girl famous?
If anybody had to explain it with the
how the islands would fail,
and I said,
do you think about who's the most famous
woman in the world?
And some guy goes,
your mom and I just started laughing
because it was fun.
It was in that moment.
It was a ridiculous,
smart ass funny thing to say and it
wasn't a guy who was heckling.
The whole show was just like,
he said that one thing and then I
started laughing and everybody else was
laughing.
I'm like,
we'll just let that slide.
That was very funny.
Sometimes it's funny,
you get to be.
No,
I don't encourage it.
You shouldn't do it,
but occasionally it works and that's not
a mean spirited thing.
No,
it's like sometimes people,
they just want to be a part of it.
They want to get a little drunk,
they want to say something and it's all
different and then sometimes you just
get more on.
So sometimes you could just get people
that just really don't.
They don't deserve to be there,
they just,
they can't handle the experience.
I've seen that as an audience member,
I've seen that where people are yelling
out and you just want to grab them and
drag them out of there.
Like that guy on stage.
You just,
you should not be talking to your
fucking it up for the other 300,
99 people in this fucking room.
Right.
You're so egocentric that you're
concentrating on yourself and your own
what you like and don't like.
They had a couple too many drinks at the
restaurant.
They got talked into coming to the
comedy club.
They didn't.
They don't know what it is and they're
like,
shit,
dark room,
but I'm supposed to show up.
I was in the middle of token.
It didn't.
I'm going to keep talking this that
there's alcohol which really fucks with
judgment and this also.
A lot of people have this really bizarre
and titled Thing where they're entitled
to their opinions and they feel like
this is something that they're allowed
to.
You know,
they're allowed to voice their
disapproval about and you should stop.
I had to give a woman yell out next
subject wants to me,
which is hilarious.
No,
I'm holding the microphone where there
was this bit I was doing for awhile
about a,
there was a thing called the second
coming project was before,
um,
genetics,
when,
when they first starting mapping out the
human genome,
there's just people that wanted to get,
they wanted to get DNA from the shroud
of Turin and they wanted to try to clone
Jesus and he thought that if they cloned
Jesus would bring him back and that,
that would be how Jesus Return.
And uh,
so my,
my take on it was like,
what have they brought Jesus back and he
was retarded.
Like what if it goes you,
Connie doesn't work,
like you have to do it a lot of times in
order to find an effective clung.
So the first one that you do,
like,
what if it comes out wacky,
like would have,
he has down syndrome.
Do you,
do you kill him?
And she's like next subject,
next.
And she was sitting in the front row
looking at like,
is it,
that's it.
Like you're just going to say that and
that just ends.
No.
Now you're this objects.
You don't know.
I'm of magical fictional Jewish Zombie.
Can't come back retarded.
Is that what you're saying?
Fuck off.
She's in the God squad she couldn't
handle it allows people in the God squad
cut in and all that stuff,
so it might not even be the God squad.
It might just be in her very narrow view
of the world down syndrome.
Is that unacceptable subject or
religious?
Anything religion.
Like I've had people say,
well,
hey man,
as long as you don't talk about politics
or religion,
like,
well that's ridiculous.
Those are two things you should
absolutely fucking talk about it every
chance you get because the one of the
reasons why both of those dumb,
retarded fucking things are still around
and the same state they've always been
around is because dummies like you don't
talk about it because you've locked it
in this ideology box and tucked it away
somewhere where you just talk about the
Lakers and the fucking lawn and how long
you think this drought's going to last.
You don't want to talk about the fact
that you're getting fucked and then
you're being surrounded by children who
believe in magic.
Yeah.
Surface stuff,
I mean people are,
people are a little scared about that.
I mean,
I feel like in comedy,
nothing's off the table.
Nothing's off the table.
It's only,
might not be right.
It might not be funny,
but even like patrice o'neal,
the late great patrice o'neil had a
really good point once where he was
like,
if someone goes on stage and offends
you,
they say something to offend you.
Or if someone goes on stage and and
makes you laugh.
Both of those things come from the same
place.
They're both trying to make you laugh,
but it doesn't always work.
You know,
like the ideas that eventually become
great bits.
There's been nights I had,
I had some bits that they eventually
became like closing bits,
like bits that I had to close on because
I couldn't follow them.
They were just too good for me.
They were like,
all my other bits weren't as strong as
them,
but at one point in time they would bomb
and that like when they were first
developing almost like,
how the fuck am I going to get this to
work?
It's just too weird.
It's too fucked up.
It's too controversial.
It's too.
It doesn't.
It's not connecting with people.
Whatever the reason was and almost every
bit sort of starts out in an embryonic
stage.
What it eventually becomes when it's a
finished product and if that is an.
If it's a bit that's controversial and
it starts out in its embryonic stage,
you're like,
nick,
sap jacked stop dog.
Like you're missing the whole entire
point of stand up and you can't be here
because you're a part.
As an audience member,
every audience member is not just there.
You're not just seeing a show.
When you stand up,
you're in part of the creative process
because the bits come alive in front of
the crowd.
They evolve and change in front of the
crowd and that's how they become
something that eventually gets on
television becomes a special until that,
until it happens,
you're in as much as the comic is,
you're,
you're in on it.
We need you.
I give it.
If it for the audience,
no jokes would ever come out,
right.
They just.
You wouldn't really exactly know the
best way to do any of them.
You have to do them in front of people.
Yeah.
How do you feel that Seinfeld,
Jerry Seinfeld's up.
He's a very funny standup.
I mean he's a very good comic.
He's not,
he's not my kind of stand up,
you know?
I prefer standups.
We don't have any restrictions.
I don't like standups that only.
You don't use any swear words and don't
talk about sex.
They don't talk about anything profound.
Everything is like real simple.
Straight across like losing socks in the
dryer type shit.
I think he's a brilliant.
It just not how I prefer like a bill
burr or a Louis ck or jody is like,
that's my.
Because I go see Joey Diaz.
I'd see it.
There's nothing that's off the table.
I'm seeing chaos,
you know?
And at the end of this show you're
fucking holding your body laughing and
you're like,
I can't believe he doing.
He does his bit about eating and girls
eating the girl's pussy from behind a
sticking your nose in her ass.
Like a pigeon.
Like who?
Like you got to do the pigeon and he
does this.
Like I'm not doing it any justice.
I'm totally fucking up though.
You're like,
that's not even funny.
This is the funniest guy ever.
Got to see it,
but you need his body and with his
voice,
everything and it has to do with,
you know,
what was set up before that and where
we're got to.
He has this bit about the fucking
Liberace Hbo movie with Matt Damon and
I'm Kirk Douglas.
Michael Douglas is one of the funniest
bits I've ever seen in my life to a
point where I'm holding my body to keep
everything from breaking from laughing
too hard.
I like so.
I mean,
I like old strains of standup.
The thing I totally hear you in terms of
the limitations that that Seinfeld gives
himself.
There's no profanity.
A doesn't necessarily tell you a huge
amount about himself.
It's kind of abstract stuff.
I love words.
I'm a huge fan of words.
I love etymology.
I like studying woods,
the origin of words,
all that kind of stuff.
He is a fantastic wordsmith and also
he's very,
very specific.
Like he will,
he will omit the wood,
the if he doesn't need it because he
examines the entire sentence.
I love the dedication to that.
I also love the free form element of,
you know,
what he was doing,
just anger coming at you or Eddie Izzard
is very kind of like just school of
thought went all over the place.
The thing that I love about Seinfeld
might be the limitations that he gives
himself,
but also that idea of the choices that
I'm making.
I've made specifically for this joke to
work as correctly as I think.
And he's a,
he's a professor of comedy,
right?
I mean,
he knows comedy,
knows the history of comedy.
Who knows what's funny.
He knows what's not funny and uh,
there is something very safe about him
and I could bring my parents to see him
and he is old school.
But for me,
the fact that Seinfeld lives in this
world of Joey Diaz is and
bill burrs and Louis ck makes him almost
like the last of a dying breed,
you know,
and I do have a lot of respect.
Well,
gap again is very clean,
although he's not the kind of wordsmith
that does.
Seinfeld is A.
Brian Regan is also very clean and very,
very funny,
you know,
but I hear you.
I mean he's a master at economy of
words,
that's for sure.
He,
there's,
there's definitely a rhythm to learning,
like when you know,
when to leave words in,
when to add more words,
when to have a pause,
when to have no pause and there's an art
to that sort of creation of the bits.
He's definitely a master at that moment
as well.
She,
she knows woods too short.
It's very specific words and you know,
she can be a little,
a little frisky it a little noisy,
but obviously that's very disarming when
you know you're kind of an attractive
lady to get up and do that stuff.
I think she's.
I think she's brilliant and
unfortunately it is a very male as a
society is a very male dominated job in
the sense that I feel like if Sarah was
a guy,
there's a chance she could be a little
bigger than most.
She is nailed.
Some would argue the opposite.
Some would argue that female comics are
judged on a curve and that the best
comics,
if you look at like the best female
comics that are alive today and compare
them just bit for bit for the best male
comics,
you wouldn't really have them in the
same category.
You think she can throw down with Louis
Ck?
I feel like Sarah Sarah was brilliant.
She.
Well,
I mean I,
it's weird like I don't like seeing,
you know,
even though I said Joey Diaz is the best
in the world because I think he just
makes me laugh the hardest because
that's like my style of comedy.
I love that crazy chaotic style,
but I don't take he out of the equation.
I don't think there's a best.
But I've seen Sarah.
Sarah was at the store two weeks ago and
she was fucking fantastic.
Just smashing,
just fantastic.
But I've seen,
I've seen birds without.
Do you know Duncan Trussell?
Yep.
Duncan drops.
Even Duncan trussell just stand up and
doug stanhope destroyed.
It's all about,
you know,
if they're in their groove,
if there,
you know,
and there were always recycling material
so you catch them two years from now,
it's going to be a totally different
set,
a totally different point of view,
totally different place in their life.
Totally different perspective.
And I think,
you know,
as far as personal taste,
it kind of ebbs and flows depending on
where that person is at any point in
their life.
Yeah.
I saw doug stanhope well and so the,
the cody stood,
I was fucking bent over.
Double laughing so hard.
I him and then there's a guy I've only
seen once.
I didn't even know if he's on the silk
anymore.
He's called Dove Davidoff.
Yeah,
definitely.
With office around still.
That guy killed me one night and he's,
he's just cool as fuck man.
Fucked up leather jacket,
shaved his head,
look Kinda like a little bit of a g and
his material was just excellent.
You know,
it's light status on any given night,
you know,
I think also coming from England and
having,
excuse me,
having that backdrop of Monte python and
Derek
and clive and stuff,
the playfulness of words is something
that I appreciate.
Like do you know money pythen came out
with a vinyl record as a double groove
in it for the stones.
So you put on,
let's say side B,
but it hits on the second groove,
so you hit the exact same record,
but then the last sketch is different.
So then you're like,
fuck,
I love that sketch.
Not heard that before.
I must have been too stoned or too
fucked up.
You put it on again,
but it doesn't hit the second group.
It hits the first group.
So you get to the end of the record,
the sketch has gone.
You're like,
wait a minute,
if I smoke then you put it on again,
but it's back.
And monty python put that in for the 19
sixties audience.
They're listening like that Shit I love,
you know,
love that stuff.
Yeah.
Monty Python,
they were definitely groundbreaking.
Insane,
insane.
They did some pretty,
pretty incredible shit.
Yeah.
And it's still,
a lot of it still holds up,
you know.
Totally.
I mean,
you know,
everyone talks about the parrot sketch
periscope just fine.
But for me,
like the argument sketches,
one of my favorites,
there's one called travel agent,
which is insane.
There's,
you know,
the fish dance,
the fish tanks.
No to people.
I think it's definitely Michael Pailin.
Could be Graham Chapman stood on the end
of a pretty high canal.
One guy has one guy has two little fish,
like kinda big sardines are about that
big.
And he skips over to the,
uh,
skips over to Michael Pailin,
slaps me in the face a couple times,
skips back,
skips over to Michael Baden and slaps me
in the face a couple times with these
fish.
It's skips back and then the other guy
and then he finished and he stands stale
near the guy,
pulls out a fucking huge trout and just
takes them out and throws him in the
canal.
It's like completely silenced.
Done to music.
I've seen that.
I've seen so a Naca can stupid,
you know.
How long have you been living in
America?
Uh,
I moved to La in 2003,
so a while,
uh,
first moved to the back of my managers,
God.
And she had like a granny flat,
not were there any more.
So there was no toilet in,
there was no TV,
there was no toilet,
no toilets.
Where did you go to the toilet?
So what she would do.
So she worked over at her house,
which was also her office.
She would leave the back door open,
but she would lock the bathroom from the
inside.
So at nighttime I could go open the back
door,
go use the bathroom,
but I couldn't enter the house because
it'd been locked from the inside.
Uh,
I had no phone and no.
Oh,
so the first 18 months in La was just a
fucking joke to we just trapped.
Yeah.
And she would come and knock on my door
and go,
hey,
I have an audition at 1115 and it'd be
like 10.
And I go,
okay,
someone gave me a ride to go,
no.
I go,
okay,
we're going to have to cancel that
because I don't have a car and I
couldn't get to Santa Monica.
And that went on for awhile and then
eventually she was like,
maybe buy a car and I get a phone.
I was like,
yeah,
okay,
I'll do that.
And then it started to kind of shift
around a little bit.
So when you came over,
you were just known as an actor?
Yeah,
I had done a couple of TV shows in
England,
a little bit of theater in England,
started to do some English films and was
doing a TV show in France for England.
When I got the role on load the rings
when it did load the rings.
Uh,
and as we're coming towards the end of
principal photography,
which is almost two years,
the onset publicist is medical Claire
Raskin think she's married now,
so she has a different name.
She said to me,
what you gonna do after this we're going
to do when we wrap in December.
It was like,
oh no,
go back to Manchester,
wait for it to come out a year later.
And she said if I was you,
I'd go to La,
get jumped on this.
Like go take some means,
get a manager,
get an agent like,
okay,
cool.
Good advice.
Went back to Manchester for low,
but Manchester had amazing.
Say Manchester's,
you know,
if la is London,
Manchester is New York,
it's industrial.
It's a bit rough or been.
Most Times people say,
oh,
I can throw big football town foreign
place to do stand up.
Yeah.
That rockers.
And they drink and they like to fight
you a lot of fights.
I saw a lot of fights there.
I'm got to have your shit together,
you know.
So.
So went back to Manchester was bored.
I mean Manchester has a lot of great
elements to it.
There's not a huge amount of work for an
act today.
You can do some soap opera is like
coronation street or something.
Shit.
What's coronations true?
Incarnates street is the longest running
soap opera in England.
I think it's been running for four
years.
Oh yeah.
Uh,
is there any original cast members?
Is a guy called Bill Roche who was in
the first ever episode and he's been in
it for edges.
It's called Barlow in the show and it's
a very boring,
very pedestrian,
a slice of northern life and the way
that you,
the way that they combat that in England
is to have a show called east enders,
which is about London life and
eastenders is like drugs and crack
confide in markets and you know,
everyone gets their hands dirty and
yeah,
like snatch serialized snatch and then
carnation street is about,
you know,
obviously we brought Ge have lost me,
brought you or what's a budget,
like a budgerigar,
like a canary or you know,
the casket,
open tray and can't get a cat down.
And then they call the fire brigade and
the fire brigade turned up.
I'm one of the people who's in the fire
brigade,
happens to be the ex lover of the person
who's got the cat and they get together
and they go have a pint together and
it's very just like a low hum.
Very northern,
but it's a little,
I think derogatory towards London people
because it paints them to be two
dimensional,
you know,
they all were flat caps and all of
football.
Me and bit simple and you know,
I don't really know.
I'm talking about all of that.
Newspaper was a bit scary or what news,
you know,
so I was always a little offended by a
carnation street.
Uh,
but that was the option when you,
Manchester,
if you're an actor,
be incarnations to you.
It wasn't really my vibe.
So I came to La and uh,
was still am really good friends with
larger would so hung out with logic for
probably a month or so just hanging out
and go to Disneyland and Magic Mountain
and do nothing.
Mann's Chinese theater.
Huge deal for me.
Huge.
Like when I was growing up the whole put
your hands in the Clark Gable hand thing
or see how small bay gribbles feet where
the,
that's a huge deal for me.
That's old school Hollywood.
So I did all that and then moved to my
manager's place,
uh,
and you know,
just kind of fucked up for a year and
then got my shit together and start
going to the gym and started feeling a
bit better about stuff and had a couple
of auditions that I got clothes on and
then ended up getting an audition for
last and then,
you know,
kind of that's all she wrote.
Yeah,
I think you kind of have to think about
the,
the enormity of rings was like,
it was such a big job to do and coming
down the other side of it,
you have to have a little bit of time to
kind of take a breath.
And I think that was different for a
love of the people.
You know,
Vigo went off and rode horses for a year
and you know,
Orlando stayed working very quickly and
billy got enrolled.
The rode horses,
like no acting,
just rode horses.
I think for the light.
The first year after law,
the rings,
he was very much into just being on his
own riding horses.
He's like one of those Daniel Day Lewis
characters isn't a totally.
He was so good in the fucking the
apocalypse movie.
What does that movie,
the road?
The road.
I couldn't even watch it.
Oh,
I got to the point where he's teaching
his son how to shoot himself in the
mouth.
I was like that.
We're good.
Yeah.
It's active and have you seen and
promises,
but he plays the Russian guy with 10:11.
Fantastic.
Has the naked fight in the steam room.
He's ballsy.
He's a very ballsy act and he's a great
guy.
Did you guys live in New Zealand when
you were doing that?
Yeah,
two years.
For two years.
Just under two years.
What does that,
what is that like New Zealand?
I,
you know,
I was dumb enough to assume that New
Zealand would have the weather the
Australia has because it's close to it
on the map,
but it's actually not close to a
geographically.
It's a long way away and certainly much
more southern geographically then
Australia,
so he kind of has an English weather
sunny days,
but generally,
you know,
showers and when they call it Windy
Wellington,
because,
you know,
every year some old woman will get blown
down on the street and you know,
it'd be a huge issue there.
It's a very safe country in terms of
going out and doing your thing.
They have a great respect for our,
you know,
everyone's,
everyone's inked,
everyone's called.
It ain't.
I've never seen so many tattoos on young
people in my life,
which they go over that more of a tribal
thing,
but certainly it's a rite of passage.
When you reach 18 or 20 or 21,
you'll get a tattoo.
They love our.
Everyone's,
everyone's a sculptor.
Big Surfing community goes acute.
Um,
they like to drink like English people,
which didn't necessarily do me any
favors.
We had countryside is so beautiful.
Beautiful.
That's why they filmed it there,
right?
Yeah.
PDX also also Kiwi.
So he's from,
he's from there.
So he wants to keep all of his movies on
the island of New Zealand.
On the islands of New Zealand,
because it brings a lot industry in the.
I don't think he would've done it if he
knew it was outside of his wheel house,
but you can.
There's nowhere else to make the Lord of
the rings.
Fucking sceneries so spectacular.
The shy exists.
You can go to the shy green rolling
hills sheep everywhere.
Cows.
Beautiful.
Yeah.
It's a strange place New Zealand because
it's covered with all these animals to.
There's so many wild animals that were
brought in there.
Like apparently there was no mammals.
They're like in the 16 hundreds or
whatever the fuck it was when people
started arriving.
Yeah.
And they have a huge issue with that.
They have a huge issue with,
uh,
you know,
animals being brought into the very
strict and customs also,
you know,
millions of years ago you had birds
flying over New Zealand going,
wow,
that place looks rad.
Locust trees everywhere and there's no
humans.
I'm going to land.
Which they did.
And then over the course of a few more
million years and they then lost the
ability to fly because they didn't need
it because no natural predators to hold
these flightless birds walking around
doing their thing.
Then they accidentally bring in things
like possums and rats and stuff and cats
and these animals can't believe their
luck.
But like there's all these flightless
bird,
the carbon climate tree and one of these
birds Kakapo's Kias,
Kiwis,
there'll flightless they'll.
I mean the Kakapo is a parrot,
one of the largest parents in the world.
The mail.
We'll build a little depression in a u
shaped valley.
So he'll build 11 amplify,
which will be a u shape valley in that
valley.
He'll build a depression and he'll sit
in that depression and make a deep,
guttural base like noise for his female
to hear him and the female will walk
over.
But it takes place over the course of a
few days and any animal can hear that.
So the rats and the caps and the possums
would just follow the sound and the male
won't move.
It'll just sit there and they just kill
them.
They just kill them and eat,
so then now being present now being
protected in certain parts of New
Zealand because these polar animals have
been fucked over by with one
Australia's had similar issues and one
of the things that Australians had an
issue with was the proliferation of
rabbits.
Rabbits had gotten to Australia and they
just bread like a motherfucker and
spread across the entire country and
along the way they had to figure out how
to mitigate the issue of these rabbits
and the overpopulation.
So they brought in foxes and then the
Fox has got out of control and then they
brought in feral cats.
Feral cats and foxes are like one of the
biggest issues in all of Australia.
They just have an overwhelming amount of
them and they still haven't put a dent
in the rabbit population.
No,
no.
I mean anytime human beings try and get
involved with the nature of things,
they make a huge mess of it.
I mean there's A.
There's a classic story in Hawaii where
I can't remember what the animal was.
I used to know,
but they brill in an animal to bring
down the populations of another animal,
but the animal is Diane.
All the other animals nocturnal.
So they never meet each other.
They just smell each other.
Like I know he's a rat.
Is Subway is borrow,
you know.
So that's hilarious.
It's scary.
I mean,
you know,
I think humans,
well,
I don't think humans are easily my least
favorite animal on the planet.
I don't have a huge amount of hope for
them as a species.
I'm pretty ashamed to retailers and Oh
kimmy would dong dude.
But you're nice.
I'm nice when we're talking about the
individual that's tangential,
I mean as a species,
but you know,
we,
uh,
a mess and we're breeding out of control
and for some reason we,
we place a huge amount of importance on
human life because our brains are
developed to the point where we think
that we're special.
But if you were to take humans off this
planet and have a look at it in 200
years,
it would be a vibrantly green blue
planet living in balance with itself.
If you had to take right,
but you wouldn't want to live there.
Well yeah.
He wouldn't be able to tell anybody.
That'd be no restaurants and they know
movies.
Whatever.
Get Mad.
You would have never worked.
Never worked,
but I know computers.
I would live in the plains live,
get you get it and you'd eaten within an
hour they'd find you and they'd fucking
cut you down,
but you still live in.
But you live in balance with that,
with that will,
you know if you'd state worms or an all
spiders,
old Beatles off the planet,
we would be dead in a hundred years.
You know,
I'm lucky enough to do this show and
every so often we find ourselves in the
real wilderness way.
You've taken a car to a river and a
river to a boat and then walk to someone
else and then taking another boat for
three hours down river and you're
heading to this forest jungle light
location and I'll see humans on the
river's edge fishing or playing kids,
little six,
seven,
eight year old kids.
And I think those fuckers know so much
that we'll never know.
They know when the rains come in,
they know when the Predator is nearby.
They have incredible night vision.
They have hearing that we can only
imagine they have the ability to climb a
tree,
like we can't all heal themselves with a
fruit or with a plan.
And I,
I admire that much more than whoever the
whatever the fuck Kanye does.
Anyone like not just county.
I'm not picking on county,
but like I know the bronze.
Incredible.
He's an incredible athlete.
I have a lot of respect for him and
Steph curry isn't an amazing basketball
player.
They can't contend with the ability that
these children have these light indigo
child.
Right.
But much like your agent told you back
in the day,
they lived different lives.
You can't compare Lebron to them and if
you put coby Brian on that island making
some snap,
easy put coby Brian on that island,
he would probably starve to death.
He put them on the court with them.
They wouldn't score a single point.
Oh yes.
It's like we're.
We're all in these different paths.
Yes.
Hosts for courses,
but my,
my retort to that would be,
you know,
the the correct way to live on this
planet would be the way that they're
doing it and all the way coby is doing
it.
Who knows how coby lives his life.
He is an extraordinary athlete,
but in terms of excess and unpolished,
in terms of the excess of,
let's say Los Angeles,
the waste,
the portion size,
the pollution,
the traffic,
we're not getting it right.
We've,
we've got it wrong.
We don't seem inclined necessarily to it
in the western world because we're like,
well,
yeah,
but we can all eat.
We live in warm houses.
We get DIRECTV.
Like I'm just chilling.
Like intuit really hits the fan and the
tsunami comes in.
We're good.
The other people,
those Africans,
they've kind of fucked it up and the
people in Southeast Asia,
they fucked it up in South America is a
mess.
But in la you like,
same way we did it.
We succeeded or not succeeded,
but not living in balance with our
planet.
We are killing our planet.
It is on its way and it might not happen
in our lifetime and I know certain
people have said this for generations.
You have all these scientists saying it
might not happen in my lifetime,
but it was certainly happened in the
next and I'm part of that was that those
people representing that comment as
well,
but I do believe that we're at that
tipping point of like,
what are we?
What are we doing?
Why are we here?
We're not here to make cash.
We can't be because I mean it's.
It's about moving from being a human
species that made some mistakes and
realize the limitations of our planet to
living as a human species that has the
potential to go forward into our future.
At the moment,
there is no future for human beings.
It's a.
it's a ticking clock.
We need to take that clock out of the
scenario to be a successful species
because Andy did it.
These did it,
wounds did it,
and which are my favorite animal by the
way,
live in extremely condensed societies.
There's no murder,
there's no rape.
They look after their kids.
They made their forest healthier.
They leave no carbon footprint.
They make the planet bear.
I can't talk.
They don't make movies.
Music is bullshit.
They may make me have a conversation
with them.
You want to beat your head up against a
rock.
If you wanted to fuck one,
you'd be something wrong with you.
People are way better than ads.
I think that what we're doing is
definitely tragic.
If you look at the consequences that
human society has on the environment
itself,
but if you look at the potential that
human minds and human creativity and
ingenuity half and you look at what
we've been able to accomplish with raw
materials and what we've been able to
build in this incredible world.
Just the ability to do this kind of a
show where you're broadcasting something
right now,
it's flying through the air into
people's phones because people in their
car that are listening to this in real
time.
I just think that what we need to do is
put some of that ingenuity on figuring
out how to be more renewable and figure
out how to way to be more sustainable,
but I don't think that's outside of the
realm of possibility by any stretch of
the imagination.
I just think it's hard because people
live in the moment and they don't feel
the consequences of their actions until
they're too late and I think that's an
issue that people have to recognize the
consequences globally of the human race
and what this,
this thirst for innovation and expansion
and overpopulation,
what what is the impact on it.
But there's been a lot of talk and a lot
of a lot of thought and a lot of
planning and preparing for an eventual
world where we don't have waste.
I think just even the concept of waste
is just about not
thinking things all the way through and
that a lot of what is waste is really
just an alternate source of energy that
needs to figure out how to be used or we
need to figure out how to use it.
But I'm a huge fan of people.
They're my favorite animal.
Unless you at least favorite animal on
the planet,
you're allowed to have your opinion and
then you have seen people totally
entitled to that.
People are all my favorite people.
Yes.
Uh,
you know,
there are some very,
very smart minds out there and obviously
the most impressive thing would you
rather hang out with them or a panda I
would rather go with can really the
hottest chick in the world who's super
smart.
Would you rather hang out with her?
A squirrel.
I mean,
I've hung out with hot chicks before.
I feel like I've got.
You've got it down,
but you don't know the squirrel and you
only need to get to know that I've got
feed him and nut and figure out what is
it?
Do you shit.
You eat nuts.
What else do you ponder the universe?
Do you realize they were alone and
infinity?
There is a mystery about those animals
that I don't,
I don't
field of mystery as much with human
beings.
Yeah.
And,
and,
and you know,
there are,
there have been some incredibly profound
leaps in technology with some very,
very smart people on this planet and we
are doing the best that we can do.
I would argue that all of those
technological breakthroughs and all of
those concepts that we have and all of
those ways that we can talk about being
impressive as a species because we
cannot avoid.
It comes from a very human angle.
We're looking at it in a human conundrum
because we're in our brain was saying,
well that's fine.
You know,
humans can be Dicks,
but think about what we've done.
We went to the fucking moon and you
know,
we know what the dark side of Mars looks
like and we put robots on Mars and we
can create music that was made in an
orchestra based on scratches in a record
group like that.
That shit is insane.
It doesn't matter.
None of that stuff match.
It's not why we're here and it doesn't,
it doesn't do anything for the larger
concept of this universe and this
planet.
It does something for us as a species.
Selfishly,
we're amazing what we did.
We created this thing and you know we
went to the moon ends.
Don't care that you went to the moon.
Well,
the universe doesn't care of ants exist.
I mean,
if the universe doesn't have any feeling
for this planet,
this planet will disappear.
This,
this star will eventually run out of gas
and burn out and Supernova and all the
planets in orbit will be unsustainable
for any kind of life that we understand
and the universe won't give a fuck.
You know why?
Because it's infinite and somewhere out
there there's a billion fucking earths
in a billion solar systems that are
absolutely exactly the same as ours and
it doesn't care,
so it doesn't matter whether you're an
aunt or a person,
but to say that it doesn't matter that
there's someone put those grooves after
spending all this time talking about how
great monty Python r that's,
but it's not just for you.
It's for all the people that experienced
that and the what.
What humans can do that these animals
can't do is spread these experiences as
art.
Whether it's Louis Ck standup or Sarah
Silvermans,
standup or Monty Python's jokes or Janis
music,
what he can't say that that's nothing
because what that has done is elevate
the emotions of every single human being
that's experienced that and you could
say that human beings aren't important,
but then in that case and nothing is
important,
life is not important.
The ocean is not important.
Not really in a greater spectrum of the
universe.
This infinite thing that we exist in,
none of that is statistically important,
but to us for an entity that is
experiences that you're way more
important to me than a squirrel.
I'll just tell you right now,
way more than aunt.
If I had an anime and if I crushed that
aunt,
if I could get a giggle out of you at
smash that animal,
you weren't getting gigs.
Cry For the would cry for an aunt.
Well,
I wouldn't necessarily cry,
but if you had an end on you and you
were like,
I'm going to crush this.
How do you feel about it?
I would go into,
go into a long chicken.
You were eating chicken.
He.
I was eating chicken.
I mean,
it happens,
you know,
it doesn't happen.
I go out,
I killed them.
That's true.
I go out my way to try and live in
balance and be nice to the university as
best as I can because it makes me feel
bad.
It makes me feel that my life is in more
balance.
If I,
if I do that,
you know,
I'm actually working in flow with the
universe and I agree.
I don't necessarily think that the
universe has a bias one way or the
other.
If we were to play around with the idea
of the universe sitting down with a pad
and a piece of paper and they drew a
line in it and they went in on one side,
humans on the other side and they.
They weighed up the pros and cons and
it's with every time they win,
every time.
Joe,
what do you mean by the pros and cons to
that too?
You know,
the universe is having a conversation
with Jimmy Hendrix and Jimmy Hendrix
says,
okay,
you tell me,
which is the most impressive animal to
you.
If you were to compare humans with ants,
I believe that the universe of say
there's no contest.
These animals live in complete balance
with the planet and they do all the
right things.
They take care of their kids.
They don't fuck with other animals
unless they need to.
The the right amount of food,
they create almost no waste.
Meanwhile,
you've got this,
blow it over intelligent.
Eight days running around going,
we invented the world.
We can do whatever we want with it were
abusive towards the planet that we live
on.
I don't think the universe would slap
around a little bit.
I don't know.
I mean ultimately I don't know if the
universe is an entity that really
contemplates these issues,
but if it was,
I mean if you really were examining the
life of human beings in comparison to
the life of everything else on this
planet,
you would have to assume first of all,
that there's just so much inspiring
potential for creativity that comes out
of this one weird monkey that makes
mouth noises and expresses itself
through facial expressions and and,
and written language.
There's is a very,
very bizarre creature that human beings
are,
and I would say if I was completely
objective and had no connection
whatsoever to human beings,
I would say that fucking thing is way
more impressive than ants.
That thing is flying through the air and
metal tubes on a daily basis all across
the world.
That thing is sending video through the
sky into a fucking phone that slips into
his pockets.
That thing is driving on this hard
surface that it's laid out all over the
world.
These internal combustion engines are
powering these metal boxes.
They pulled the metal out of the ground
and forged it into the form of metal
boxes.
Then they've covered these wheels with
rubber and a fucking explosion,
a controlled explosion inside this iron
cast iron block is forcing this car
around.
They stop in these places where they
pull out this fueled that they've taken
fossil fuel from around the world and
tankers and pipelines and they've,
they've,
they've processed it.
It is gasoline that they can then pump
into this car.
They paid for it with a credit card.
Money is numbers that are on a computer
somewhere.
They have paper that represents this
money.
No one understands.
It's a fucking insanely complex world.
Insanely complex.
If you.
If you're looking at the universe,
it turned me.
If the universe is looking,
you know,
at at life on earth in terms of what's
more impressive,
Jesus fucking Christ.
There's nothing more impressive than
people that disagree and also that also
that fueled by the ways is killing the
planet and the universe.
Potentially.
It might.
My concept of the university universe,
how's the gas having to cough up some of
that shit that is being created on
earth.
Right?
Oh,
don't get too close to that.
You know?
I mean it's not good for us and it
eventually,
but I think if you look at it in
perspective of like how long human
beings have been here.
Yeah,
we've met a massive things like really
quickly,
but also the amount of innovation that
has occurred in our lifetimes in the
industrialized world lifetime over the
course of x amount of hundreds of years.
It's fucking staggering.
It's no wonder they haven't caught up to
what they're doing and figured out how
to mitigate all the issues that they've
created by making internal combustion
engines and airplanes and pollution.
Well,
airplanes can only create so much
pollution and that's the real
global warming is fucking airplanes and
the world actually is it changes the
temperature of the earth.
When when September 11th rolled around,
they stopped flying over the United
States.
It altered the temperature of the earth
in a significant statistically
measurable.
I mean cows farting causes a huge house
gases,
but in my mind as an atheist,
my idea of the universe is probably a
little closer to a little a statute that
we have something living in complete
balance with the universe,
which I think the universe would respect
a little bit more in an end than they
would in a human,
but if you tell him about something
impressive,
which all those things are impressive,
that's certainly comes from a human
bias.
How do we equate things that impresses,
oh,
the fact that we can drive cars that is
impressive for humans.
Elephants watches go by and they think
that's impressive.
A Jaguar,
let's say,
can hunt completely silently in the
dark,
make not one noise and catch the
creature that is looking for with
complete and utter economy and sit down,
eat that creature and then sleep for two
or three days.
That for me is more impressive than
hawkings mind or then some theory that
Einstein came up with their living in
balance and flow with the universe and
the doing it in such a way that this
creature right here,
the is also about balancing flow goes.
You're fucking radical.
Oh,
I don't know if Buddha says you're
fucking radical to a Jaguar,
but I think Jaguars are obviously
incredibly impressive and spectacular
and I'm not arguing against Jaguars,
but someone was arguing against vision.
Goggle can lead some food out for that
stupid Jaguar and shoot it in the head
and turn it into a jockstrap if they
wanted to live in flow with that planet.
Well,
what's in flow with this poor little
antelope getting killed by this Jaguar,
which jumps around it well,
so you decide.
So you decide.
Decide to some.
Some gallon of Jaguar Thong.
I now she's sitting out there on her
pores where their headphones on so she
doesn't blow her here off while she
shoots at 300 win mag a Jaguar was going
after a piece of meat.
It bums me out so hard when you see
these beautiful women on twitter,
the opposing with deadlines and dead
rhinos and elephants just like,
well,
you doing this is a very weird thing.
It's a very weird thing that people want
to fly over and shoot like giraffes and
all these different things,
but then when you get into the
conservation aspect of it,
it gets very cloudy.
It's not as simple as,
you know,
people are doing cruel things and
killing these animals.
Then posing them and taking pictures.
The amount of money that's generated by
these people doing that is substantially
more than any other conservation effort
that's out there.
It gets real weird because like this
rhino thing,
I had the guy on Corey Knowlton that
killed that black rhino and you know,
I wanted to find out like what?
Why did he do it?
Where?
Where's his head at?
You know what?
First of all,
that Rhino Fed,
you know,
who knows how many villagers,
I mean they,
they,
they had all the images of them cutting
up that Ryan on feeding all these
villagers that Rhino was also,
they needed to kill that rhino because
the population is very small of the
rhinos.
Net Rhino is killing other male rhinos.
It was a non breeding older male and it
was a very aggressive and killed females
killed males and in order to keep the
population healthy,
they had to eliminate that rhino.
They were trying to figure out how to do
it and this guy paying all that money to
fly over there and kill that Rhino is
actually better counterintuitively
better for the overall population of
those rhinos.
Also,
the $350,000
pays for Rangers.
It stops poaching.
You know,
one of the interesting things they're
doing now to stop poaching is they've
come out with three d printing of rhino
horns.
They're going to make artificial rhino
horns and flood the market and Asia.
Apparently these are virtually
indistinguishable from wild rhino horns.
They actually share Rhino Dna.
They make them a Keratin and they're
going to three d print these rhino horns
and just follow the in Asia.
It is brilliant,
but it's.
It's crazy that they need to do this
mate.
Poaching is way more of an issue for
Rhino death and in in any of these
exotic animals than hunting is a lot of
places that we go.
They discolor the whole,
which doesn't cause any grief to the
rhino itself.
They'll color the on orange or red or
yellow so that it loses the value ground
for the medicinal market.
Like you said,
it's made a character is the same
material that makes up fingers,
fingernails,
and heres the thing.
Bite your fingernails.
If you think you're going to kill
cancer,
bite your fingers.
You're speaking logically about things
that are just totally based in
superstitious.
I mean,
they get Viagra.
You Fuck,
you don't have to eat a Rhino Horn to
get your dick hard.
This is nonsense.
It doesn't work either.
That doesn't mean it's not like you eat
red meat.
It's crazy that these things are going
extinct because if it would be one
thing,
if you ate rhino horns and it really did
make your Dick hard as a rock and then
you could fuck all night for days,
but it doesn't,
right?
It doesn't even work,
but yet people are still killing them
for that very reason and I've had this
conversation with people a lot where
where I say,
let's say like let you were just saying,
let's say for the sake of argument,
it does work.
It does work.
That does not give us the right to kill
the animal,
to the point of extinction,
not.
Well.
It doesn't make any sense because
there's other things that it does.
It's one thing that if you.
If Rhino Horns made people super
geniuses and cured cancer,
then you'd be like,
okay,
we have to figure it out.
We'd have to figure out a way to breed
more rhinos.
We don't want to make rhinos going
extinct because they're essentially the
fountain of of of Wisdom.
If you kill them off,
then you lose this one opportunity to
figure out how this one animal developed
as property that is so greatly aids.
It'd be pretty ironic if if rhino horns
made people the ultimate human being,
but yet we're killing them off to try to
become the ultimate human being and
robbing ourselves of this one source.
But again,
you know that's a.
that's a very,
very strong human angle.
You know the,
the Rhino Ollie animals that exist on
our planet,
a fair game to be explored and had to
look at to see how they benefit us,
but how about how they benefit the
world?
You know what I mean?
The The majesty of an elephant's hole
and is based around the fact that an
elephant's Tusk is based on the fact
that it's attached to an elephant,
not the fact that you can cut it off and
put it on your mental peace rosal value.
Then we look at things from this human
angle as opposed to this planetary
universe type angle,
which some of us do,
but again,
with the rhino thing,
the conservationists that are trying to
protect the rhinos,
they all agree that you have to kill the
aggressive non breeding older males in
order to keep the population healthy.
Yes.
So like this guy going over there and
killing this rhino,
it's very.
The whole thing is very cloudy because
it's very counterintuitive.
Right.
Have you seen Louis Thoreau's
documentary on African Safaris?
Yeah.
Fascinating.
Because all of these animals that he.
When he went to those South African
hunting camps,
all those animals were on the verge of
extinction just 20 years ago and now
they're flourishing,
but they're flourishing and these camps
where you can hunt them.
Right.
Ken Hunting,
it's so weird.
It's.
There's a lot of places that he's not
allowed to go because of that,
because of a few things that louise
done,
like he's,
he,
you know,
he's obviously quite a controversial
documentary and it shouldn't be.
He's up.
He's amazing.
He's fantastic.
Nothing controversial about what he does
in my opinion.
He's just honest and thorough and,
and brilliant.
I mean,
I think what he did with that hunting
camp,
it really exposed how bizarre that whole
world is.
This show called the bizarro world or
something.
Louis Ck is bizarre adventure.
So bizarre.
It's not lucy,
Kate's luther,
luther,
um,
I forgot what it's called,
what the name of.
I don't think he can go to South Africa
at the moment because of upsetting some
people in South Africa about something,
you know?
Was it because of that or were there
different,
different thing?
Super.
Well,
I know a scientology is doing a
documentary on him.
Oh,
well yeah,
because he's doing a documentary on
them.
So they decided to do a documentary on
him and he said,
watch.
Yeah,
well I want to watch both of them
actually want to watch what kind of
crazy shit they have to say about him.
Like what they do nutty thing.
Have they concocted,
they do free.
I think it's free brunch or free lunch
on a Saturday near where I live and you
see people going in there full,
you know,
from a personality test.
Eleven 30 to 1:00
and people would come up and be like,
are you enjoying the chicken?
Yeah,
you want to come into this little tiny
room with me and answer a few questions
like,
fuck,
I hope all the homeless people go and
get free food often,
but shit like that gives me the willies.
Organized religion in general gives me
the willies.
Well,
they're one of the most bizarre ones
because they were founded by the most
prolific science fiction author the
world has ever known.
You know the idea that,
well,
he lied and made up a bunch of shit
except this.
This is all trip.
Well,
he's the statements where you said,
my next,
my next mission was to try and come up
with a religion to do.
And he did it.
Oh yeah.
I mean,
not just statement.
His ex wife spoke in great detail about
his plans in order to create some sort
of religion,
really profit off of it.
I mean,
he spent a good deal of his life living
in a boat,
hiding from the irs,
you know,
because before they were tax exempt or
tax free status before they had that
status,
they were,
you know,
he was,
he was.
He owed money because they were a cult.
Then they were taking money from their
members and thought,
oh,
thanks fucking madness.
Yeah,
it is crazy.
But the Louis Theroux thing is a.
for anybody who has like a hard line
stance on this whole African hunting
thing,
just take a look at that and you'll
probably not going to change your
opinion,
but it'll give you an idea of the
complexities and the,
the,
the weirdness involved in this whole
thing of these animals.
Literally we're on the verge of
extinction with the one you've seen the
documentary.
The old guy at the end when louise like
badgering him,
he gets asked him and he goes,
you don't understand.
Africa is fucked.
It's fucked.
The only way these fucking animals are
going to survive is if you've got to
give them value.
You've got to make them more.
That's
bizarre.
I gave them a monetary value to protect
them.
Yeah.
It's very strange.
Your show.
I'm a is wild things,
wild things with Dominic Monaghan.
What do,
what do you do in the show?
There's a BBC show and it was at BBC
America for a while.
It's now travel channel.
I go around the world,
try to change people's ideas about
animals that most people are scared of
and try and evoke a little bit of
curiosity and kill fear in whether we'll
ever scares you.
Whether you scared of little.
Yeah.
All we had food you've never eaten or
animals or people of different color or
people of different ideas about life.
I,
uh,
I get a lot of travel and I love
animals.
So what had happened with me was
whenever I had like two or three weeks
off,
uh,
I would always take a trip on my own
unless it was hanging out with my girl
and the trip on my own would usually be
pick an animal around the world and go
and find the animal.
But to make the two or three weeks
spread out a little bit,
instead of going directly to the source,
I would land in the capital city and
spend two or three days in the capital
c,
go into restaurants,
hanging out,
hanging out in human communities and
just asking them like,
hey,
where would I go and see a weld shop?
Do you guys know about the wheelchair?
I've seen it around here,
where would it go?
How would I take transport,
do I take a train?
All that kind of stuff.
And then gradually made my way down.
Then for the last week,
try and do that thing.
So my agents knew about this and they
were,
they were constantly seen photos of my
adventures and stuff.
And My um,
non acting agent kind of said to me,
you know,
this is a show dom,
like,
this is a show what you do,
no one does that thing that you do,
like,
you should meet some producers.
So I was like,
alright,
I'll meet some producers.
So I sat down with different people,
ended up sitting down with a guy from
Canada,
runs a production company called cream
and he said,
what's the show?
And I pitched him a trip that I took to
find orangutans,
that trip that I took to find the whale
shark trip that I took to find the King
Cobra.
And he was like,
cool,
do you have a ideas?
And I was like,
I have 808 ideas.
And he went,
all right,
come up with eight ideas and we'll come
back in two weeks time and write the
show.
And came down first episodes about ants
because it's my favorite animal.
And we went to Ecuador to find the army.
And my plan was to lie down in a carpet
of Armenians and what they call it,
uh,
drove varmints and,
and know what it feels like to have
this,
you know,
$20 million ends walking around on top
of you.
And will they,
will they go into your ears and your
eyes and your mouth and your nostrils
and canicula grown human being and all
that they can.
And they can be.
You'd have to be tempted.
You'd have to be tethered you as a,
as an able bodied human being.
No,
you just run away.
Well,
it depends on the type of and not really
dance can kill you.
Now know you get a bunch of them.
I'm the authority and NS.
You'd have a bunch of them climb on top
of you.
You wouldn't get killed.
Well,
you're talking about hundred of them are
very difficult.
Bullet answer.
Extremely taut bulletins.
Have the highest pain threshold of any
insect sting in the world.
Uh,
it's right at number six.
Number one is go to sweat bee,
which is the equivalent of a tasting
white wine vinegar.
The bulletin is described as walking on
hot coals with a nail in your foot,
so it's extremely painful.
Blends living relatively small
communities for since maybe 24.
Ebola ends in a,
in a huge group.
If you were to piss off a community of
bulletins,
the most amount that would be on you
would probably be,
let's say for the sake of argument 50,
which is outside the realms of
possibility,
but let's say 50,
51 and kill you physically.
It would be painful,
but it's not like debilitatingly
painful.
You would probably want to go to
hospital to have them give you morphine
so that you could go over the next three
days,
but it's not like 50 rattlesnakes.
Buyer's not going to kill you.
It's not an acute.
So,
so we did the,
we did the,
an episode in Ecuador.
Um,
they ended up not allowing me to lie
down in a carpet events because they
said it was too dangerous,
but I ended up putting my naked handouts
too dangerous.
How so?
Well,
they just said,
yeah,
how are we going to get them all off
here?
How are we going to get home with the
rest of the day?
You're going to have 300,000
ants on your light.
We're never going to be able to get the
stings out of you for you to be on TV.
My friend Brian Cowen,
he stayed in Bolivia for awhile.
He was going to be some sort of a bug
scientist.
Whatever the fuck you would call that.
What's the entomologist entomologists?
And um,
he was studying for it and was staying
in these,
uh,
they had these huts where they were
elevated off the floor of the jungle and
they would put Turpentine on the posts
of the huts to keep the ants from
crawling up into your.
Because once they find you,
once they decide that you're a target,
like you're fucked.
Yeah.
Especially if you're,
you.
If you can't move.
Like I said,
if you,
if you had two broken legs,
you're in trouble with bullet.
The great thing about blends,
and you'll see this in these
communities,
in the local indigenous communities.
When the aunts moved through that
village,
they'll just go off for a day and they
just let the ants clear out all the
scorpions.
Oldest bide his oldest son and bs,
all the bullshit spring,
clean my house,
follow me on Yoga.
Ah,
that's interesting.
So that's a balance.
Yeah,
it's a beautiful thing.
That is pretty fascinating.
So I'm kind of interested in the concept
of fear,
you know,
just as a rule,
I think that word is divisive and
negative potentially and it doesn't do
us any favors.
It doesn't move us forward as a,
as an animal.
And I kind of reject it as a concept.
I think things are dangerous,
but the idea of fear makes you clumsy.
May she made the wrong decisions,
makes you do things incorrectly.
So what are some of the more archetypal
fares on the planet?
Our heights and snakes and spiders and
planes and we try to show people those
things in a slightly more positive light
so that you can sit comfortably at home
and start to change the way your brain
chemistry works with those animals.
I mean,
obviously you know that like,
let's say for the sake of argument,
you are scared of spiders,
if you hear the word spider,
spider will take you to negative things
that happened in your life associated
with spiders,
inner circle that you can go off and
it's feeding that negativity.
But if you now put a positive story in
there where you saw a spider with a
friend that you were in love with and
then you went off and had food that you
really liked,
your starting to change that pathway.
And if you just replace the negative
with the positive,
you will then feel differently about
spiders and that's what I'm attempting
to do with the show.
So your motivation is not to celebrate
these animals.
It's rather than mitigate fear.
But it's a bit of both.
I mean,
obviously we show the animals in,
in the light that I like to show them,
which is positive,
beautiful,
uh,
fascinated and profoundly.
Yeah.
Fascinating.
What's the word I was looking for?
Um,
where they're able to.
I'll find the witness I can,
but I feel like I feel like certain
animals are able to actually move out of
a,
a description.
You can't define them there,
the other worldly that magical in some
way.
Uh,
so we do do that.
But uh,
you know,
I like to show people that at first a
wild animal,
the first thing of wild animals going to
do is going to try and get away from you
and then not initially going bite you.
The vast majority of wild animals out
there.
As soon as they a human bounce.
So then you or I have to then juggle the
idea of a wild animal saying,
I'm not into this.
I'm going to get away.
And me trying to impose on them,
if you hang out for a little bit,
not going to hurt you and I'm going to
do anything.
Just give me two minutes of your time.
I can achieve what I want to achieve.
You can be on your way and you can see
that palpably with a change in the
animal's body language.
You can see,
I can see when a spider is okay with it.
I can see when his sculpins okay with
this snake any animal down with.
I'm like,
oh,
it's okay.
No,
you can come closer.
You can sit down.
You can chill because it's animal gets
it now,
but at first the wild animals like,
I'm wild.
I'm going to kill him.
What are you saying?
Like a wild animal gets it.
When they see they say work out the day
they pick up on its energy,
right?
They pick up on the change in energy.
Let's say we just did an episode in Sri
Lanka with the Indian Cobra,
Monica called Cobra.
What are the most iconic cobras or if no
snakes in the world with those two
little glasses on the back of his head,
the one that the snake charmers work
with.
So I pull like a six foot Indian Cobra,
have a stack of wood in the back of
someone's house and the first thing that
God wants to do is get away.
So I'm holding onto it by its tail and
it's trying to get wet and it's trying
to get away and is trying to get away
and intellectualize is in its snaky
brain.
Oh,
I can't get away.
Why can't I get away?
So it turns around and looks at my hand.
Other reason why I can't get ways this
guy's hand,
so now I'm going to deal with his hands
so it tries to bite me,
tries to bite me,
bite me because I know how to hold onto
his neck and low.
Let it bite me.
If I ride out that storm,
which usually takes about two to three
minutes,
the snake again and it snaky brain
thinks this isn't working or the normal
ways that this works for me and animals
got hold of me.
I try and buy it.
Let's go.
I'm free.
That's not working,
and now I'm getting exhausted because
I'm buying a nugget and anything for it.
Maybe I'll just relax.
As soon as the animal relaxes,
I then chill.
I then release a little bit of tension
on his tail,
move a little closer to sit down with it
again and it snaky brain is like,
oh,
I'm being fed something positive.
Now,
if there's no tension on my tail,
I can move a little freer and there's an
exchange of energy with a snake now.
Thanks.
All right.
I'm not going to be aggressive because
that's not working for me.
All this animal that's in front of me,
we chill for a little bit and talk about
how beautiful it is.
Talked about all the amazing things
about it and then let it go and the
snake won't remember that.
The snakes not going to name.
Then see a human a few days later and go
positive experience.
This is cool because their brain doesn't
work like that.
Just doesn't benefit snake to have those
memories to hang onto because they don't
generally run into humans.
Our member and maybe the audience will
remember it.
Maybe they'll feel differently about
animals.
So this show really kind of came out of
[inaudible] came about and sort of an
organic manner like this is something
that you were doing anyway for no reason
other than.
Because you enjoy being around these
animals and you have the freedom to
travel and see things that intrigued
you.
Right?
That's pretty fucking cool.
Yeah.
I'm,
you know,
I'm obsessed.
It could have been a show about a few
different things.
I'm obsessed by a bunch of different
things.
I love Manchester United.
This could have very easily been a show
about me going around the world watching
major soccer rivalries around the world,
Andy in street food and meeting people
and every so often seen animals.
I could have done that.
It could have been about street food.
I Love Street food.
We could have done a whole episode about
street food with a little bit of
football and a little bit of animals.
It just so happens that you know with,
if you create a TV show,
the backdrop of animals,
it's an evergreen show,
right?
I mean,
people want to watch shows about animals
in 10 years time this,
they're gonna want to watch an episode
about Vietnam.
Those animals are still gonna exist and
they're still going to be like,
oh,
well I'll watch this.
It's 10 years old,
but he's still doing all the universal
things that were do and he's interested
in the world.
He's interested in Vietnam.
He goes to see the capital city,
hangs out with animals,
so it was the easiest sale to build it
around animals.
But ultimately it's,
I mean,
you know,
I'm getting paid to go on holiday.
Really.
That sounds amazing.
It's cool,
man.
It's really cool.
You love animals.
You obviously have this deep affection
for them,
but yet you eat them.
I do eat some.
I've been vegetarian for the most part
this,
this year.
Um,
and every so often I'll eat a piece of
fish and when I was in South Africa I
felt kind of weak with needing proteins.
So a steak.
I ate this big hunk chicken today
because I felt like I was kinda low on
energy and they want to come in here and
be like,
Hey,
what's happening?
So I ate something to give me a little
bit of fuel.
But um,
I would say,
uh,
I don't know.
I probably meet once every two or three
months,
something like I'm not the biggest dude
in the world.
So for me to,
for me to get,
for me to feel full on vegetables and
fruit is fine for the most part,
but every so often my system is like,
I need flesh and today I was like,
I need flush,
but you like animals as much if
not more than you liked people
undoubtedly.
But imagine if you talk to someone and
they say,
well I only kill people like once every
couple weeks,
every couple of weeks I feel like I need
to murder.
No,
I hear you.
That's a valid point.
And um,
I am working on it.
I made a new year's resolution at the
end of last year where I said to my
family,
like,
I think I'm going to go vegetarian.
And they all laughed at me because they
were like,
you eat meat and fish and you like duck
and you eat goose and all this kind of
stuff.
And I was like,
oh,
I think I'll be okay.
And I've struggled a little bad times
this year with not eating meat because I
need the energy.
And the show that I do is very sapping
of your energy.
You're in very hot countries were up at
sunrise.
We finished at sunset,
chasing after animals,
putting myself in harm's way with
dangerous animals,
and just every so often I'm like,
I gotta I feel it to feel like I need
some vegetarians will call bullshit on
that,
you know,
they'll say like,
that's ridiculous.
We're just not doing a good job of
monitoring the amount of protein that
you,
your diet takes in Keenwah,
hemp seeds,
whatever you need.
I mean,
I believe is Tofu is tricky because it's
processed,
you know,
pro.
Were you dealing with Tofu?
You're dealing with very much a human
created thing,
right?
I mean,
I believe as animals,
we're omnivores,
right?
What grazes certain things.
So,
um,
I think there's times where your body
might need a little bit,
but I'm,
I'm open to the idea of someone saying I
can organize you a diet that has no meat
and you can maintain your weight.
We were talking about this before we
started the show.
Like I use,
I usually coast around about 1:50.
If I drop five pounds,
I look like I'm.
I'm suffering from some disease where
you have very unique darter
requirements.
It seems like because of your metabolism
scenes.
Her Nana's.
Yeah.
I need to know your history of doing
this from time you were a child or just
you know what the warrior diet is.
You ever heard of that?
Yeah,
it's a the idea that you have one huge
meal a day because that's how you know,
people ate a long time ago.
They would try to find food that would
get it and then when they would feast at
night and so there's a lot of people
that believe that that's a really good
way to manage your weight,
to not eat anything at all during the
day and then you eat at night.
I tried it for a little while just to
see.
I mean I didn't try because I was
serious about it.
Just like what is that?
Even something that makes sense and you
can get used to it.
You can get used to not eating all day,
but I don't think you have the same
amount of energy you have it,
but that was the other thing they used
to say that breakfast is the most
important meal.
They've totally abandoned that.
What is the most important?
There is no meals,
you know,
there's no most important meal.
The idea was that if you don't have a
healthy breakfast,
he won't,
you know,
you won't feel good throughout the day.
But I oftentimes don't have breakfast.
So I oftentimes do what I,
I,
I call earning my breakfast while I
don't eat until I work out and then,
you know,
it's also because I like to put my body
in situations where it has to work hard
where it doesn't,
doesn't want to,
you know,
like if I,
if I don't have food in my body,
like you're like,
you don't,
you can't,
it's harder to push as much energy out.
It's harder to,
to have the,
the amount of.
But then you have to focus more and then
you have to force yourself into it.
You know?
So I put myself in,
I put myself in weird situations like
that just to make my body function.
You liked that battle a little bit.
I lost that battle too.
I think it is.
Why is why every year or so I stopped
myself from having certain things.
My New Year's resolution is usually
stopped.
It never stopped.
You kind of have added sugar.
You can have that.
It's so you can have bread,
you can have alcohol,
you can have meat.
This year though,
I've been cheating.
Um,
but I mean,
you,
you obviously don't suffer from the same
thing that I saw from my.
My thing is putting on muscle,
you know,
like I'll go to the gym and train as
hard as I can for,
you know,
the size down that uh,
and then,
you know,
I don't get as big as I would like
unless I'm pounding food and that's
just,
it's pretty stressful on my system,
you know?
Yeah.
It sounds you're,
you're a very unique situation when it
comes to that.
But you know,
you could have eggs and eggs if you get
them free range from healthy chickens,
there's no negative impact.
They make an egg every day.
I have 22 chickens at home,
so I eat a lot of eggs are shit and my
chickens are like my pets.
So like I'm having food that's created
by pets,
you know,
and I feed them healthy food and the
eggs are dark orange and they're filled
with coleen and all sorts of healthy
protein and they're really good for you.
You know,
you can get around killing an animal to
eat them.
Right?
But the thing about being a vegetarian
or being a Vegan is animals don't play
by that rule themselves.
They're constantly killing each other.
Like you were talking about the,
uh,
the Jaguar killing the antelope and that
that's natural.
Well,
the reason why human beings are here is
100 percent because of hunting.
If we weren't,
if we'd never figured out hunting,
we've never figured out killing how to
eat animals.
We,
we probably doubled our brain size of
never doubled over a period of 2 million
years.
We've never figured out agriculture,
we would never figured it out
civilizations and we wouldn't just
wouldn't be in this position to debate
veganism if it wasn't for hunting in the
first place.
So one of the more ironic things,
I mean we are omnivores,
we do eat meat and we always have a
meeting.
They did say it's a beautiful moral
choice to try to leave the smallest
carbon footprint to try to leave the
smallest footprint as far as animal
suffering and.
But the reality is the wild itself is
just fucking vicious and mean.
And they,
they don't give a fuck about each other.
No.
It is fascinating that we are so hell
bent on saving animals that don't save
each other.
Sure.
I mean,
I,
you know,
I'm lucky enough to go into the jungle a
lot and a lot of people that I tell it
to is like,
Oh man,
you go into the jungle.
That must be incredible.
It's so blossoming with,
with life and all these,
all these new things in eggs and you
know,
creatures everywhere.
And I'm like,
well there is an element of that to the
jungle.
But ultimately the jungle is a place of
death,
so it was a place of dark s,
a swollen water,
sudden death.
Well,
it's a cycle,
right?
It's a,
it's a.
it's a constant continuing.
Continuing reviving cycle is like things
or reading things which are eating
things which are getting eaten by things
and it's just constant swirling.
And one of my favorite documentaries is
documentary on the Harpy Eagle and it's
sees heartbeat eagles.
Oh,
they're fantastic.
These fucking flying dinosaurs that are
swooping sloss and monkeys off of these
trees.
It's just an amazing,
amazing documentary and I'm just the
idea that different things in different
parts of the world have evolved to find
their niche.
They have evolved to find the way that
they survive the best.
And this giant crazy flying raptor that
just swoops in.
I believe it's the biggest ego in the
world is yeah,
they swooped down and just snatch
monkeys at a trees and kill them and eat
them.
And just what a bizarre niche.
Like what a bizarre specialty those
monkey communities think about ego and
getting the kids to get in that light.
Right.
There is a monster that lives in this
guy and this thing will end use if you
see something like a big shadow that
comes to log,
that is the dragon,
that is the gateway to don't have that
as much in our world.
I mean we watch game of thrones so we
think that dragons exist and stuff.
But in a,
in the other animal communities,
like the insect world,
insects and my favorite animal that is
fucking brutal.
Gladiatorial daily life with these
creatures really fucking heavy.
Um,
yeah.
The life of the wild is very heavy.
It's very strange.
I was a moose hunting in British
Columbia this last fall and when we're
up there we came across a calf that had
been recently killed by wolves,
took some pictures of it and put it on
my instagram feed.
And it was a because it was just
stripped down to the bump,
but it was,
was bizarre.
Was like if you have never seen
something like that before,
it's like being there like,
well what this just happened.
Like this happened two hours ago.
Like there was blood and there was hair
everywhere.
And most of the main had been eaten and
were like this,
this is the real world that these things
live in.
This is it's baby.
The Moose that were out there hunting,
some of it's babies got captured by a
pack of wolves and they tore it apart
and we're,
we're,
it's,
it's contradictory that you would find
something appalling and beautiful at the
same time.
But it is both.
It's both of those things.
Sure.
Because we're so conditioned by streets
and phones and electricity and houses
and buildings that when you were exposed
to this totally different lifestyle,
this totally different environment,
like the wild,
the actual real wild.
It's this jolt of,
Oh yeah,
this jolt of wow.
There's like,
there's just a toe.
This is a completely different variable
series of variables that you're dealing
with.
So simplistically,
beautiful night.
I was in Kenya probably eight or nine
years ago and I saw as Zebra Fall Cbre
Fall,
uh,
that was being hounded by two
hygienists.
The mum had gone and they saw it like it
was,
it was,
it was trying to navigate his way around
a big tree.
While these hyenas would just fucking
minute and they had broken or it had
broken one of his back legs compound
fracture like this,
so it was hopping around on three legs
and there was two heinous,
so it would go to the left Hyena,
Hyena,
and the hyenas,
which knew at some point that we're
going to chow down on this thing.
We're really just fucking me.
That it would come over and they would
buy it.
It would fall over,
it would get up again.
That chase it.
They'd hit it so the leg,
they try and bite the broken leg off.
They will like fucking with it.
They weren't trying to eat it for a good
half an hour or so,
and I was really.
I was in mixed company and I was taking
a lot of pitches to this thing thinking
this is fucked up.
This is how,
in fact,
the last few moments of this creature's
life is going to be the car that I was
in.
The people were like,
okay,
can we go now?
Like we don't want to see that.
And we left and I was talking that night
with the people that,
that I was with and they were like,
oh,
that's disgusting that we,
that we see this.
And I was like,
this is what's real.
This is nature.
This is life.
You know,
I,
a few weeks ago,
me and my friends in the middle of the
night when we're walking around Griffith
Park and we've seen fucking owl.
And we saw some coyotes run along the
track and stuff.
And then I went home and I have a few
snakes at home and I started passing
around snakes.
When people check this,
check this one out,
I've got my scoping out and torrential,
uh,
one of my friends was like,
oh,
this is a normal Saturday night with say
with old dms creatures and stuff.
And I stopped her and I was like,
fleur,
this is actually normal.
This shit that we were doing earlier on
where we're all showing each other
photos on our iphone and watching TV and
put in a DVD on and playing fee for an a
playstation.
That's a construct that has been created
to make us feel okay about life and keep
a stupid so that the bosses can do what
they want.
This is real.
We're supposed to know the name of every
snake was supposedly in the name of
every tree in the forest.
We've lost that ability and that's what
I'm trying to get back to.
Is it normal?
I mean,
I think that playstations or about as
normal as beehives.
It's something really procreate.
People create things and they create
things.
Construction,
buildings,
cars.
They create things all over the world.
I think all behaviors natural.
I really do.
And I think even the most bizarre fucked
up human behavior is natural.
We are as we're natural.
Well,
yeah,
we of course were natural.
We're part of the animal kingdom.
We are as a,
as a creature and natural create,
uh,
the natural thing created by bees would
be a wild hive.
And honey,
the natural thing created by humans
would be a child.
A painting is a slightly abstract
version of creation style creation,
but it's much more abstract than awhile.
Beehive and a baby.
So there's nothing natural about
buildings,
but yet human beings construct
them without any interaction with each
other all over the world and they'd be
like a,
a shelter to keep the rain off,
use natural,
but like that's where it starts to trade
center and then they figured out solar
power and then they figured out
electricity and then they figured out
Wifi.
Then they figured out that it seems
natural to me.
It doesn't seem like it should be
because it's not wild because
independent of human beings,
it doesn't exist,
but independent of bees.
Bee Hives don't exist.
I think he is as bizarre as our antics
and our creations are.
I think ultimately everything that
happens is,
is natural.
Yes.
I would agree with differences in being
that we can debate whether or not we
should be doing it or whether in the
consequences are worth the effort that
the toxifying,
the oceans,
the sky's the pollution.
That picture that I showed you of Mexico
City have fucked up.
The pollution is in Mexico.
There are creatures out there that
debate.
Yeah,
there are.
We just.
We're not tuned into that vibration.
There are creatures that as far as we're
concerned,
when we watch them silently communicate
with each other,
it's not silent for them.
There is something,
whether it's old double or something
that they sent,
so something that they understand that
they do,
we're just not in tune with the idea,
you know,
and and these things that we create
naturally,
let's say for the sake of argument,
a skyscraper or a jumbo jet.
Yes,
I agree.
That is natural because we exist and we
create it.
That's a.
that's a natural process,
but those things that we're now creating
a large,
expanded huge versions of boys natural.
The trade senate isn't a natural
building and natural building might
house 10 people.
I don't know how many people housed,
lived in,
worked in the trade center.
Thousands,
right to enough thousand.
3,000
people were.
Yeah.
That to me feels slightly unnatural.
A jumbo jet that can take 500 people
from one place to the other feels a
little unnatural.
Maybe a plane that can take eight people
feels a little bit more natural agent.
I mean,
I don't know,
swollen.
We've everything,
but that's natural.
That's what people do.
I mean,
there's a reason why Mexico City exists
is the same time that Los Angeles exists
at the same time that New York City
exists is because if you leave people
alone,
you don't kill them off.
You don't kill them off with disease or
war.
They overpopulate and they develop these
nationally intrusive cities.
Yes,
it's natural for us.
It's natural for us as a species to look
around and go,
yes,
deli is completely swollen with people,
but that's the natural,
uh,
you know,
journey that the,
that the country of India is going to go
on and create this.
See,
I don't necessarily think if you take
out this human bias that,
that is natural for a species to,
that we're not supposed to read
rampantly out of control.
We're supposed to take care of the air
and the planet and the food and do that
in balance and naturally with a species.
Well,
the reason why human beings are
overpopulating is because we figured out
how to get the fuck away from predators.
No reason why we wanted to fuck and make
as many people as possible as.
Because naturally we got eaten mean the
Jaguar.
The key kills the antelope also kills
people.
True
that that was a big part of the problem
in a grass hut.
It's really hard to fight those fuckers
off.
Absolutely it was.
It's the reason why we left the forest.
We're not in that window in that
scenario anymore,
so we're developing this new style of
living and we have to figure out a way
to deal with the consequences of all
this waste that we produce and also deal
with the fact that people have this very
bizarre diffusion of responsibility
thing going on when there's a thousand
people that are doing something and that
something is fucking everything up.
It feels different than if one person is
doing something and something is fucking
things up,
then you feel responsible.
But if you're a part of a city that's
polluting the world,
it doesn't seem like it's your fault.
It seems like somebody else out there
be fixing it.
Yeah,
I know.
So the very.
I mean,
I think empathy's one of the most
dangerous words on the planet,
they very apathetic idea of,
well,
what difference can I make a plastic
bowl and just forget about it.
You're like,
well,
obviously if everyone flood that way it
would be a major issue.
Well,
I have a lot of friends who smoke
unfortunately because I know a lot of
comedians and I cigarettes.
Yeah.
And I see them throw them on the ground
all the time.
They throw them in the ground,
step on him.
My two,
two of my friends the other day did it
and I,
you know,
I don't want to just be that guy,
correct people every time that happened.
So I just avoid it.
But fuck,
it's so depressing the fact that people
are just so comfortable with throwing a
cigarette on the ground,
stepping on it,
and then it's out of their mind.
Yeah.
I'm going to step away from the mic for
a second.
That's trash.
It's trash.
Like that's what I want to say when that
happens,
there's a complete disconnect and I
think it comes.
And this is another,
you know,
pull,
um,
comment on cigarette smokers.
I think it comes from the fat that they
smoke,
they smoke,
smell,
they get to the end of it and they're
like,
fuck,
that's a day habits.
It's fucking disgusting.
They throw it down.
They had done with it.
So it's not that problem.
ISO,
they're abusing their own bodies so they
don't mind abusing the environment.
Right.
I know.
So you say a lot of times people driving
on roads or freeways and the idea behind
that is,
I know this is bad for me.
I know it's dirty.
I don't want to step it out and leave it
in my car.
I'm just going to throw it into the
planet.
Dude,
I've seen
different Prius's throw cigarettes out
the window of my favorite things.
Trying to keep up,
keep a running tab of Prius's,
throwing cigarettes out the window.
Anything it feels,
do anything.
It looks bizarre now when people smoked
cigarettes,
like I was born in [inaudible] 76 until
the probably early two thousands.
Seeing people smoking cigarettes didn't
really matter to me.
I'd been so exposed to it that I was
just.
I didn't even have a comment about.
I was just like,
oh,
there it is now,
and I see someone pull out a box,
pull out a cigarette,
put it in the mouth in light.
I like watching like,
what are you doing?
What's going on?
Do you not know what's happening with
this thing that you're just about to
inhale it?
This is going to slowly poison you,
but the thrill of it or the fun of it or
the James Dean thing where they just
want to be cool.
Yeah.
The danger of.
I mean I,
I grew up thinking about all that stuff.
It looks cool for James Deane to smoke
it and the Beatles grew up smoking and
then in the Second World War they gave
them out as part of your rations so you
can understand how soldiers came back
being addicted to cigarettes because
they're scared of death that are around
death that bought out their mind.
They get 10 cigarettes a week.
They're all gonna smoke cigarettes,
but I mean,
you know,
the level of education certainly in most
of western Europe and in this country is
to such an extent that when I see a
smoke I'm just like,
what are you doing?
Well,
it's one of those weird contradictions.
So I know,
I know very intelligent people smoke
too,
which is very shocking.
Like when you know someone and they're
brilliant and then they,
they can't stop smoking cigarettes.
So like wow,
have you could figure out a way to
balance this whole thing out better.
You'd be so much healthier but they
don't self self abuse.
He knows the self abuse things.
An interesting thing,
but I mean everyone's on their own
journey.
So you just kinda gotta let them.
Yes,
and I think everyone has advice,
but sometimes you just say that to
someone,
just let them know how you feel about
it.
It'll maybe shift their perspective and
they'll have this new found way of
living whole.
Yeah,
Dom's right.
You know,
I think it was fucking weird.
Like I just do it.
I don't think about doing it.
Yeah,
I was,
I was a lot more fucking,
you know,
opinion a,
it's not that I don't have strong
opinions now,
but I,
I kind of keep them a little bit more to
myself in my twenties I thought that it
was just a human thing to be able to
kind of spit venom at people when you
felt like doing that.
Now I kind of like grown up a little
bit.
I don't do as much,
but unless I was dating someone who I
was in love with and they were smoking,
which I would never do,
I found that really attractive.
Then I feel like I'm in a position or my
family,
but like a friend,
I just feel like they'd be like,
well,
fuck you down.
Yeah,
well I don't have Akila go fuck
yourself.
Who are you?
You know God.
It's true,
but you don't.
To kill all day every day and think
about those cigarette smokers is man,
they wake up in the morning,
it's a cup of coffee and a cigarette.
They liked that fucker and that's how
everything gets started.
That eight hours of downtime with no
cigarette is fucking with them when they
wake up in the morning.
Yeah.
Which is a whole system throughout the
night going,
okay,
let's get this toxin out.
Let's send all these messages to the
brain that this is bad and we'll deal
with it,
and then they wake up in the morning.
They're like,
oh,
I feel so bad.
I need a cigarette.
To me.
I read this booklet,
said the craving for a cigarette is not
necessarily the craving for a cigarette.
It's the craving to stop the bad feeling
of the cigarette by replacing it with
the adrenaline that your body creates by
putting the poison inside you again so
you feel shitty because you smoked the
cigarette and what you need to make that
shitty feeling go away is to expose
yourself to another jolt of the poison.
So your system goes,
okay,
let's deal with this adrenaline.
Throw all those painkillers in there and
then 20 minutes later you get it again
and then 20 minutes later did you read
that book called something like how to
quit smoking or five steps to quit
smoking.
My trainer played around with smoking
cigarettes while and I was like,
dude,
you might train econ smoke,
and he called him.
I had him.
I didn't change his,
his language as to how we refer to them.
He called them smoky treats.
I was like,
Yukon call cigarette smells.
Sounds like something you give a dog and
you know he's,
he's,
he's little positive affirmation.
I'm just gonna.
Have a little smoky treat and to give
myself a smoker tree.
I was like,
no,
you're killing yourself.
And then he read this book and it was
the reason why he quit and I was like,
let me read it.
I don't smoke but I want to read it,
and that was the thing that I took home
me.
It was this idea that it's not the fact
that the cigarette makes you feel good
or you love the feeling or it's five
minutes of downtime.
It's the fact that that concentrated
inhalation of poison is taking away from
the shit you feeling that you're getting
from the longterm effects of that
poison.
I don't know about all that man.
I don't know exactly the way it's been
explained to me by addiction experts are
that when you have an addiction,
like everyone talks about the cigarettes
calmed them down and the way it was
explained to me,
he was like,
cigarettes don't calm you down.
What they do is they feed your addiction
so you have this addiction.
You're stressed out because your body is
craving this thing that it's attached
to.
You have some sort of at a molecular
level,
you have this bizarre attachment to this
substance that you've been pumping into
your body so that your anxiety ramps up,
your body needs it,
and then when you get it,
oh see,
like cigarettes relaxed,
but no,
no,
no.
You're addicted to cigarettes.
And that feeding,
that addiction calms the craving.
Calms the screaming of the addiction for
a brief amount of time,
and then it asks for it again.
So the idea that cigarettes calm,
you know,
they don't really,
you're your extra amped up because of
the fact that you're addicted to
cigarettes.
Yeah.
I was very lucky.
I grew up with a with a mom who's a
nurse,
so my mom,
my mom exposed me to two things which,
which stopped me from smoking
cigarettes.
I mean,
that's not to say that when I was 17,
18 and one of my best friends walked
outside to smoke a cigarette,
I didn't go,
oh,
let me try it and cut it up.
And was like,
Eh,
yeah,
that's okay.
You know,
I've danced with that devil,
but my mum did two things for me.
The first one was she told me about
people in the hospitals that she was
working out there had to have legs
amputated,
hands amputated,
arms amputated due to complications with
smoking cigarettes.
So I was like,
okay,
that's fucking heavy.
And then the other one was,
she printed out a list of which we've
all seen by now the ingredients of a
process of cigarette,
which is like,
you know,
fucking cyanide and whole foods and
like,
Holy Shit,
you know?
Yeah.
Like you said,
hundreds if not thousands of things that
are a direct fight against health and
your system.
And I was like,
I don't,
I don't want to do this.
Did you see
either Russell Crowe movie the insider?
Oh yeah.
The one that was all about the
scientists that worked with the tobacco
companies to make cigarettes more toxic
or more addictive rather.
Fascinating.
Apparently based on reality too,
right?
Yeah.
I watched a inside out over the weekend,
you know,
this new great watch it with my kids.
Watch it yesterday.
So I did a review.
I do this thing on twitter called at the
flicks,
which is like if I,
if I watch a film that has had an effect
on me,
I do a little blurb about,
about what I like about it on a,
on a word press word press account.
And I thought it was a really interested
in movie for a lot of different reasons.
One of the major ones is that the way
that it's being touted and sold in La is
to deal with these very cartoony light
characters that live in this girl's
brain.
You know,
Lewis Black,
his anger,
and he's all red.
And then amy poehler is joy and she's
sweet.
And then sadness.
Who's like overweight and has,
you know,
blue heron needs her adenoids taken out,
but it's from,
from where I was saying it is a common
on the first time a human being has
exposed themselves to depression and
what it can do at a molecular level to
that person and the journey you have to
go on.
So like the beast or all their little
relationships with these emotions and
stuff.
But the a story was this really dark
story of a girl moving from where she
moved from Minnesota,
Minnesota to San Francisco.
She lost a friend.
She wasn't in the hockey team anymore.
She had a slightly different
relationship with their parents.
School wasn't going where she ended up
trying to be a runaway and I thought,
I thought it was brilliant at first and
foremost,
but if it did not feel like a kids movie
to me and if it was,
it was a bitter pill to swallow because
when I was a kid up until the age of.
I went to the edge of 15.
I really had no concept of depression.
I didn't know I existed.
I was just a happy go lucky kid.
That was sad when I got less sweets than
my brother,
but happier when I did and for the most
part I was just coasting on the second
till you started dating church.
Someone just slamming a lot of what
happened?
What do you mean you want a kiss?
My best mate.
Fuck.
I was like,
Holy Shit.
I didn't realize it could wear it like a
cloak,
you know?
My whole thing was sadness was just like
that.
I felt the stairs.
I scraped my knee.
I'm sad.
Oh,
I feel bad.
I'm going to bed,
wake up in the morning.
My default setting was happiness and
then girls and stuff.
It became like,
oh man.
I'm like,
I've been sad for a week and it was
depression and that thing in that inside
out movie.
I mean I cried like a fucking baby.
Do you remember the short film before
it?
Lava with the two volcanoes was in bits
where you really.
I was crying.
I went on a date.
I was on a day.
Oh,
so embarrassed.
You're crying on Jesus Christ and she
didn't.
She didn't really know.
I mean she's.
Yeah,
she didn't know.
She knew your crying.
I wasn't weeping.
How long had you been dating her living?
Dating for a few weeks.
So it's pretty recent.
Like she's facing probably ready to
bail.
She was crying and she's a girl.
That's fine.
She was crying at the lava thing too.
You're both broken,
broken and fucked up and like.
What did you think?
Did you see was great.
Did your kids respond to the stuff in
her head and did they respond to the
other stuff?
Oh yeah.
They respond to the whole thing.
They loved it.
We are.
We even went to the bookstore afterwards
and we bought some books on it because
there was a,
they have books inside out books or
they're kind of like into depth about
all the different things and the impacts
of emotions,
how you need the sadness and how the
sadness can help you change your mind
and make decisions.
Yes,
there was.
There was one thing which they changed
the very less that they put into the
script.
Not put into the Strip that last minute,
but but involved in the story.
The last minute that I was,
I was gonna write a scathing review
about that particular thing because you
know the whole thing about coal
memories.
All the core memories were happy.
My thing was going to be not all your
coal memories happy some of your
memories,
a dark and heavy and they define who you
are as a person to the positive,
but they did that at the end cause
sadness Takota those coal Mary's and
they kind of found the balance of like,
some are good,
some are bad.
One of the only things that I wasn't
crazy about and I thought it was
potentially a little darkness,
a little dark,
was that when the emotions were
navigating their way back to the kind of
brain area,
they walked through the subconscious and
the subconscious was scary and dark and
mysterious and black and potentially
things would jump out at you.
And my subconscious isn't all like that.
Some of my subconscious is a tiger's
drinking cups of tea with sources and
asking me how I am and I'm in different
galaxies.
Spinning around having fun,
so I do have doc elements to my
subconscious,
but I thought it was a little dangerous
to tell little kids anything that lives
in the catechumens of your mind is
potentially dangerous.
It was like,
well,
some of that could be a poem that's
amazing.
Or a song that you wrote or painting,
which is beautiful.
Like that was my only issue.
Right?
I thought the three d abstract thing was
fantastic.
Fuck.
When they there,
they sort of lost their shape.
That was really bizarre.
They just ended up becoming shapes.
One was like a big star rolling around
so well done.
Such a well done movie and really like
you said,
a movie that even though it was a
child's movie,
it really adults could appreciate it.
I felt like it was more.
I felt like it will work on a love adult
levels that I wrote in this review.
I was like say thank you for the fact
that your kids under the age of 10 might
not necessarily pick up on some of the
heavier themes of this movie.
You will at some point reach a point in
your life,
wet sadness will smack you in the mouth
and you have to deal with it like maybe
a 10 year old isn't ready for that yet,
but your 12 year old might be okay with
it because they're going through some
changes too.
I thought it was brilliant.
I've spent a lot of time wondering what
those things are there for like is there
a reason why depression exists?
Is there a reason why sadness or joy
euphoria,
do they serve some sort of evolutionary
re?
There's.
Is there some.
Is there a reason why they exist that we
just have to sort of manage,
but I mean is it really the reason why
people have gotten so far because we're
not just totally content with everything
the way it is and there's always going
to be jealousy.
There's always going to be like we were
talking about the actors looking at
other people going,
why is this?
Because they've reached some point of
success and it's never enough and
there's some new thing that eludes them.
Some new thing that they wish they could
have that then thing would be better and
by his thing fucked up and I don't do
them.
What's wrong?
It's almost like these are motivating
energies.
These are motivating elements.
Motivated.
I mean and the depression thing when you
get.
When you first start dating,
it's like it's almost like burning your
hand on a hot stove,
like letting you know like you're
dealing with something really fucking
powerful here and this horrible feeling
that you have right now when it's not
working out.
Understand this and understand the
consequences of getting involved in a
relationship now because it's not so
easy to just jumping in with someone.
It's not so easy and you learn so much
from those fucking early relationships
because it was the pain.
Like I had a manipulative girlfriend in
high school.
Not Her fault.
She's a nice girl.
Yeah,
she is lovely.
Actually.
She was very nice girl,
but she had a single single parent or
mom was quite large and didn't like men
and there was a lot of lot of education
going on that was probably not so
beneficial in trying to get into
pennies.
So she didn't live there.
Yeah,
I got in there,
but she got in mind to girls.
She's dirty little girl.
But point being was that that
manipulation that I experienced from her
very on very early on,
it made me realize like,
oh,
okay,
this can happen to like shit that
doesn't happen with my friends can
happen with a girl and then all of a
sudden we'll take your.
So I had developed this intense zero
bullshit policy.
So when I got older and I became a man,
when,
when a woman would try to manipulate me
in any way,
I would start laughing.
I'd go,
that's adorable.
But that's not going to have.
Fortunately I have other options and so,
uh,
this is not going to work out anymore.
So take care of.
But if I hadn't gone through that,
I mean I have friends that are fucking
perpetual victims and they get
manipulated by women over and over and
over again because they're weak and I
think there's a certain amount of women,
whether they appreciate it or whether
they rather,
whether they honest about or not almost
can't help manipulating men who are easy
to manipulate.
It's like you,
you can play them like,
fucking let me play up.
Ding,
Ding.
You just want to hit the tunes.
It's,
it's.
And I think there's something,
there's something natural in that.
There's a,
a natural predatory response to weakness
in certain ways.
And I kind of feel like that's all mine,
all that Shit's in place like that.
It's,
it's almost like to ensure momentum,
to ensure entropy,
to ensure that energy keeps moving.
And there's no stagnant,
mean if you stay stagnant,
you will get depressed.
If you,
if you don't evolve and don't succeed,
you will feel like shit.
If you know,
if you get dumped,
you know you're going to feel horrible,
you better figure out how to not get
dumped,
you know?
Just just handle it.
I mean,
if it goes,
grown up with a mom who she admires,
who is also manipulative to her dad,
she also then she may potentially fall
into that pit bull trap of doing that to
other guys.
I mean,
you know,
as,
as a creature,
as a by allegedly,
like you said earlier on,
we have taken ourselves out of the
equation of how do we solve the
conundrum of staying warm at night,
being protected from predators where we
get our food from.
We've sold all that as a creature.
So our brain is now giving yourself the
opportunity to expand mold than the
physical.
You know,
most people don't necessarily go to the
gym and hit the ways.
A lot of people,
you know,
read and get an education stuff.
So from an evolutionary point of view,
the thing that is expanding more than
anything else is our brain.
Now that's positive and to a detriment I
feel because we do overthink things and
we do guys have into a situation,
is this right?
Should this be happening?
To me?
I think that in this you have to look at
it as the same coin.
Just flipped over in a different way.
If you have a great birthday and you get
all the gifts that you want and you got
a great piece of birthday cake and all
your friends showed up,
that's beautiful and you experienced it
and you loved it and you told her your
friends about it and you relive it with
your friends and it was one of those
days that you always think about when
you go to sleep at night because it will
help you go to sleep.
You need to understand that the day when
none of your friends showed up for your
birthday pie and you and your parents
go,
your gift that you didn't really want.
It's the same thing.
You're just viewing it in a different
way.
You're viewing that thing is like,
oh,
this thing is bad.
This thing is good.
It's just your life.
There's those things just happen.
You know,
and you have to have the balance of
those two things.
So what I tried to do when I was
younger,
I would suffer from her lot and I,
I am prone to depression.
So I try and keep myself in a positive
headspace,
but a great way for me to attack
depression when I see it comment is to
say,
this is natural,
this is normal peaks and troughs are a
way for you to understand the journey
that you're in and you can't if you're.
If you're getting overly high about
something that's as dangerous as getting
overly low about something,
it's the bit in the middle.
There is the balance.
That makes sense.
So if you get overly high,
there's a price to pay at the end of
this ride.
That has to be.
If you get too drunk,
you're gonna get hangover,
right?
Right.
That hung over.
It's almost worth it to experience the
great buzz.
Those great moments.
It's like those great moments that you
have when you're drunk.
Boy,
you fucking pay for him for a couple of
days,
but they're almost worth it.
That is almost at the time,
is
the balance I've been in.
I've been in situations in my life where
I've thought I've.
I've sat around on my own and thought,
I think the worst is going to happen in
this situation that I'm in with this
girl or this business scenario or this
day that I'm going to have tomorrow.
I think the worst is going to happen.
My ultimate nightmare that I can
envisage is going to happen and it's
happened and I have to be okay with the
fact that it's happened and it's never
quite as crushingly bad as you make it
in your mind.
You know,
I've been in like,
I've been in a city,
I've been in situations where to go
where I'm like,
I know we'll break it up.
I just don't want it to fuck that guy
and she fucks that guy.
And I'm like,
okay,
it happened
and you survive it.
You know?
And that's,
that's the,
that's one of the lessons is like you'll
get through it.
Well that's a real problem for people
who don't ever get through that and they
don't realize that it's not gonna be the
end of the world.
I got lucky.
I'm not the girl that I talked about,
but another girl that I did in high
school who was,
I don't like to say slut,
but there's no other word for.
She would fuck anybody.
She just,
she was a maniac.
She was just poor girl.
She went to Catholic school.
They made her,
they fucked her head up.
They fucked her head up.
They made,
they made her,
you know,
just the forbidden fruit.
Right,
right,
right.
Well,
and also I think she was hormonally very
advanced.
She,
uh,
she was very woman,
like at the age of like 17.
Everybody was like cheezits mess,
but she fucked everybody I knew.
So like when I was in love with her at
one point in time,
I'm sure whatever you would call in love
with.
So I got used to that at an early age.
He used to disappointing disappointment.
It's brutal.
Yeah,
it can be.
But it's fascinating to me that you say
that you didn't experience any
depression at all into your 15,
but then you say that depression is
something that you're prone to.
Yeah.
Um,
I think,
I think I am prone to it.
but you never experienced it until you
hit your till you started dating,
didn't know what it was.
It didn't really know the concept of it.
Like I said,
sadness.
For me it was like scraping my and then
I got,
but it was very temporary.
So it's not like you had this sort of
existential angst that was dragging you
down.
What is the point?
You know?
I think,
I think because I didn't know that
existed when it hit me for the first
time,
I had absolutely no defense against it
because I never.
I'd never seen it before.
I suddenly walked around call corner and
there's a saber tooth tiger in front of
me.
I was like,
Holy Shit,
that's terrifying.
And it just enveloped me and then my
defenses had not been built through.
My formative child is to go through
elements of sadness.
Like I said,
my foundation and my family,
my parents were together.
They never fought.
They got on well.
I had a good relationship with my
brother.
I was.
I did okay at school.
I never had those real major challenges
apart from the fact that I knew I was
enacted and I was like,
what the fuck am I doing in trying to be
an actuary?
Manchester is never going to happen.
I'm never going to be an actor.
I had banks but it wasn't like a painful
physical mental and so it was just
something that I was dealing with.
So I don't think I had the full issued
to deal with it the first time and I'm a
huge fan of women and I also probably
punched a little bit above my weight
when I was younger because I was the
smallest kid at school about super
mouthy and no one could ever tell me to
shut up.
So I was always trying to go for the
ultimate girl and every so often the
ultimate bill gill to be like,
all right,
I'll entertain you for a week.
And I'd be like,
I found it.
And then she'd be like,
fuck you.
I'm going to jog.
Like,
ah fuck.
I can't even compete with the joke,
you know?
So I think I didn't get myself pitfalls
until the point where my parents had
kind of said,
it's all,
you now,
you know,
15,
16.
They were like,
okay,
go,
go find out who you're going to be.
And at that point I,
I got a little,
you know,
exposed to some sadness and stuff.
But,
um,
I also,
I just think it's part of life,
you know,
I have this,
on twitter,
I'm constantly,
not constantly,
but if anyone ever says to me,
hey,
you know,
I've been struggling with this or you
know,
this is getting me down,
or I had a rough day or I've had a rough
week.
I just,
you know,
I'm,
I'm sick with this or whatever.
And the way that I respond,
the way that I always respond to it is
like,
you know,
this,
this will improve.
And you will get to a point where you're
able to look back and say,
oh,
that was a dark period in my life.
Otherwise it's gonna all be dark and
then you're going to die.
Which is a horrible way to live your
life.
And sometimes it does happen,
but you got to be hopeful about it.
Um,
but uh,
you know,
the,
the way that you make sense,
like I said earlier on of your life,
is to know,
oh,
here's a dark place is a light place.
Here's a dark place,
here's a light place.
And the sweet spot is in the middle.
You know,
it's,
there's a great line in the office that
Ricky Gervais' show.
I think he ends the entire show by
saying life is a series of peaks and
troughs and you don't know you're in it.
You don't know you're in a trough until
you had enough to a peak and you don't
know any peak until you're coming down
the hill.
And that is true of life,
right?
Like,
I don't want my life to be incredibly
hectically happy all the time.
I think I would burn out.
And obviously you don't want your life
to be incredibly darkly heavily sad
because that's going to kill you too.
I want it to just be cruising.
I just want to cruise with balance.
Balance is a huge word for me.
I don't usually appreciate it.
I don't usually appreciate the sun
because I'm used to it.
I don't usually appreciate civilization
traffic because I'm used to it because
it's become what it is,
but I spent a week on Prince of Wales
Island in Alaska and it rained every day
constantly all day and we're camping.
So we were in these tents and we're
soaking wet and it was.
So we had these,
uh,
helmets or a brother.
I'm a headlights on,
you know,
there's a strap on,
you turn the light on so you can walk
around at night and not fall.
And I turned it on inside my tent and
there was this,
it was,
it was like,
it was raining inside the tent because
it was just missed.
It was water mist everywhere.
It was just,
it was so wet and just,
just weird.
You're just constantly drenched.
I had a great time.
It wasn't a terrible thing,
but my point is when I came back to La
and it was sunny and it was just
beautiful and just driving around,
I called my friend and I go,
dude,
I fucking feel fantastic.
And it was nothing unusual going on.
It was,
I mean it was great stuff.
I was doing a podcast,
we're going to do standup at night.
Everything was normal,
but the contrast to being in that
miserable fucking rain soaked island for
five days,
like all of a sudden now I appreciated
it and I was like,
oh,
I needed that.
I needed that balance.
Like sometimes you need to camp to
appreciate a house,
show the perspective of the whole thing.
I have my own issues with that light.
I mean festivals way.
Hoffman is way too hot.
I mean born in Germany,
brought up in Manchester until I was 18.
A hot sunny day
in either one of those countries is
probably a e three e four,
so a big one.
Oh dude,
that's it.
That's a day when like people take days
off work and they go by and get drunk in
England.
You know what I mean?
That's a day of work.
Was January here,
but like you know,
91,
92 degrees.
I can't analyze it now.
Like oh that's nothing.
That's 100 right now.
I'm sure at least,
right.
It's probably 100 to 110 on a bad day.
Yeah,
so that's nothing compared to Vegas.
Vegas is brutal,
so there's that.
But also the the major issue that I have
in la,
which is something that I'm constantly
exploring with my friends is
unfortunately the culture for the most
part is a little jaded.
You know,
a lot of people come into La Tech as
much money as they can out of it and
then leave and it's been depleted
spiritually and of its soul.
You know,
if it's community,
you go to places like Barcelona or or
Berlin or Wellington or Sydney where
people are feeding that.
See,
I get the impression that La for the
most part,
has things been ripped out of it,
taken out of it like the foundations
have been taken out of it because of the
perspective issue though,
but the way you're viewing it,
it could very well be,
but I also think that one of the
archetypes or characters of La,
the the social walking down sunset
boulevard or the cool guy that wears a
white dress shoe,
a white dress shirt and a cowboy hat on
a Friday night.
Their reaction to see as that archetype.
I know the guys that are in the
standard,
you know the guys in the rooftop bars
and standard.
We go there after the company.
Source of great.
Damn it.
Yeah.
It's good food and I like the people in
the tanks and stuff.
That's where kids are.
You have the standard explain that and
you go to check in at the reservations
or the desk.
There's a woman that is in her underwear
that is in like a fish tank,
an aquarium that's essentially.
She's reading a book and she's not
allowed to interact with you so she
doesn't look at you.
She just lives around this aquarium and
like reads your book and is in her
underwear and it's so fucking variably,
aesthetically beautiful.
Invariably teaching the people,
checking into the hotel.
Something very weird about hotel,
but anyway,
so,
so those archetypes,
their reaction to seeing something
genuinely impressive,
let's say for the sake of argument,
it's an animal that we've never seen
before,
a crossing sunset boulevard and when it
gets to the junction of traffic going
one way and traffic going in another
way,
it sits in a yoga position and creates
this fucking eclipse of bright hot
sunlight.
Their reaction to that,
if you're doing the cool la thing is to
go cool.
Not to be like,
holy fucking shit.
My life just ended.
That is the most awesome thing I've seen
in my life.
The required reaction in La is to go
awesome.
Those people that are trying to fit in.
Honestly,
I think that La has so many people and
so many people that are trying to it and
that's a part
of the problem is it's so many people
are not doing what they want to do here
and they're trying to and they in there,
so there's a,
a giant population of trying,
you know,
but there's also a lot of great artists
here.
There's a lot of great painters here.
There's a lot of great musicians here.
There's a lot of great comics here.
I think as far as standup comedy goes,
is the greatest spot on the planet
earth.
I don't think there's anything even
close.
New York is probably second place,
but man,
it's tough to fuck with La and I think
like as far as architecture and as far
as our,
like there's a lot of contribution of
restaurants.
There's a lot of great shit in the
street in downtown and there's so many
people that want to be one of those
musicians that want to be one of those
artists that want to be one of those
comedians.
I want to be one of those actors that
want to be one of those,
anything that's important and so they're
trying to be that person and you're
around them all the time.
They're the ones who are going to go.
Cool.
Yeah.
There's the fakers yeah,
there's a lot of fakers you also move
into in what I would assume to be for
you,
at least quite a healthy community of
comics that will know each other to have
known each other for 20 years that hang
out on illness clubs on sunset and you
have a nice little perculating community
of people traveling in Java now.
Everyone says hello.
I don't have that.
I'm the recluse,
you know,
so I don't hang out with actors buddy.
I don't have any active friends.
Well that's.
I mean I'm like I'm friends with people
that I've worked with full,
but in terms of hanging out like Elijah
and I are super tight.
I don't necessarily hang out with him
that much apart from little gnomes,
Orlando and had to say in the United
States,
but they have that kind of recluse too
and it's me going out on sunset and
certainly certainly me going out on the
sunset with Elijah or Orlando Old Bailey
is a fucking.
Who's billy?
Billy Boyd who I was in load the rings
with.
Played the other hub at the Scottish.
Right.
Okay.
Yeah.
That is a fucking zoo.
I have no interest in is why those guys
are reclusive because when you get to an
Elijah Wood's status in life,
it's.
It's impossible to be normal.
It's very hard to go to a restaurant
without being this side show everywhere
he goes,
people must stare at them,
so that's why I got like that becomes a
recluse in the animal in the zoo.
And what I love about being a home for
me is I can control the music.
I don't have to listen to shit music.
I can.
I don't have to pay for the alcohol upon
the thing that I bought into,
like start off to upscale the payment of
the alcohol.
I can watch any movie that I want,
I can.
I can bring in anyone that I won't,
but when I'm in a boss scenario,
as I'm sure you've experienced over
years,
people feel like they can come up to you
a little bit and then you add alcohol
into that equation.
I mean,
I've had people in Bob's.
When I'm with my buds,
someone will come over with a shot of
whatever.
Let's say a shot of Jack Daniels.
I'll come over and be like,
dude,
and they'll play on me.
No,
no,
no.
I got your shop.
I'm like,
oh,
okay.
I'm drinking vodka.
Oh,
I'm drinking Tequila.
I don't want it,
dude.
I got your shot.
You're going to a shot.
Yeah.
I don't drink Jack Daniels.
If you want to give me a shot,
Tequila,
I'll drink that.
Well,
maybe I'm just not gonna drink.
Anyway.
I'm
with my friends.
I'm just gonna do my thing.
They'll get pissy and Moni because I'm
not drinking their shop.
First of all,
I didn't ask you to come off to me
second and you to buy me a drink.
Thirdly,
you're interrupting friends who all know
each other and you're a complete
stranger.
I've had people put their hands on me in
boss,
like put their arms around me and try
and walk me over to their friends
without asking my permission to get your
fucking hands off me.
I'm not.
I don't come from where you go.
People that know you from television or
know you from the movies.
They think they know and so they also
think in some weird way that you owe
them something.
You're Charlie from last?
No,
come on.
Come on over a table.
I want my friends to meet you.
I loved your show.
Okay,
that's great.
I was in Vegas once and I had a mouthful
of food.
I'm cutting this steak and I'm putting
it in my mouth and this woman goes,
I'm from Canada.
Come over to our table.
We have friends from Canada that wants
to meet you.
I go,
you fucking crazy bitch.
You do want to see me eating with 20
other people.
I'm just going to come over to your
group of fucking friends and put on a
clown hair,
give you jasmine,
and then when I said I'm eating right
now,
I said,
when I'm leaving,
if I leave and I've run into you guys,
I'd be happy to say hi,
but right now I'm,
I'm eating dinner with some friends and
she looked at me like I was the biggest
piece of shit.
I wasn't mean to her.
It wasn't,
but it's that same thing,
but I've also had great experiences in
bars where I've run into great people
and I feel like when you put yourself in
those positions where you could be
uncomfortable sometimes those
uncomfortable positions,
I'll have fantastic conversations with
some random dude who makes cabinets or
some shit like that or some,
some guy who,
you know,
whatever.
I'm making my own vodka,
you know,
want to try it.
Oh,
okay.
How'd you get into that?
And then you have these conversations
with people.
As long as the people are cool,
but it's like you can't get cleared off
of people.
Here it goes again with that fucking
statement.
I keep saying,
I don't know where I got that from,
but it pop it in my head.
It doesn't have anything to do with
homosexual studies in general,
and please don't hate to get angry.
It's more the exact definition of the
word,
which means Kuli Kuli enough when you
get people put you off like that,
you can get put off to people,
but I don't want to be that guy so I
don't hide a go out.
I go to bars and I will occasionally run
into drunk retards,
but for the most part I feel like if you
put that out there that you're just a
normal person.
Just how you might know who I am,
but I'm fucking.
I swear to God I'm normal.
Most of the time you run into people
kind of accept that vibe.
Like you were talking about the Cobra
kind of recognizing exactly what you are
and figuring it out after awhile.
If you put out that vibe like you can't
be fucked with or you know,
everybody's annoying to you,
then people find you and,
and you know,
and I don't,
I don't,
you know,
look,
for me it's just the Boston area walking
around on the streets and stuff and not
90,
I would say 90 percent of the
interactions that they have,
maybe even 95 percent of the
interactions that I have a positive in a
bar because it adds alcohol,
that a completely different scenario and
I,
I don't,
I don't come into bonds with my,
with my backup.
I'm usually having fun with my friends.
One of the phrases that I use a lot in
terms of animals and humans is comment
me correctly.
You have to come at me correctly if
you're coming
at me aggressively,
dude,
I bought your Tequila.
It's go dude.
And it'd be like to go away,
you're going to run into that.
I just happens all the time.
You must get insulated because you know
you're associated with cage fighting and
you're a big deal sometimes the opposite
people.
And because of that,
people want to fuck with me or people
want to talk to me weird or the,
you know,
they want to hold onto me.
They don't want to feel my body around
my neck that grabbed my shoulder.
If you're a big dude,
you're a big dude.
People get weird.
There's just a certain amount of weird
people you're going to run into and they
probably don't even know why they're
acting the way they're acting.
When they do,
they're probably feel like,
what the fuck is wrong with me?
Yeah,
exactly.
It was almost like an out of body
experience.
Floopy around you.
Charlie shrink my boobs.
And they would,
they would,
they would do.
Let's say they met there and randomly.
Oh their uncle randomly on the street,
they would do stuff that would,
they would never do it.
I've had people scream and the Annapolis
Shit fucking,
you would never do that.
It'd be like you'd go over and say hello
to him.
Yes,
it's true.
But you find that with fires,
obviously.
I mean,
I don't know how many fires you know
fucked with.
Oh yeah,
I've seen it.
Yeah,
I've seen them get fucked with,
it's ridiculous,
you know,
just some people are just drunk and they
also,
they don't like the idea that they feel
intimidated by this guy being around
them and they want to like put that guy
in his place,
you know,
I don't want to.
And there's also people that are just
completely delusional.
Like I've run into so many guys who want
to tell me how if they fought in the
UFC,
they would kill everybody.
Right.
But they can't do it right now because
they're busy with some other shit.
I could take so many fucking people tell
me that bro.
My mentality,
they,
uh,
they all have the same thing.
Like I don't quit man.
He'd have to kill me.
And you're not gonna you know,
like it's so many dummies out there.
It's just there's a certain amount of
people out there that have nine volt
brains and there's not a goddamn thing
done.
No,
not in the books.
They can read.
Not enough life experiences.
They just have shit genetics.
Yeah.
And that,
that,
that's real.
We've been taught that everyone is born
on an even playing field and it's about
you to find yourself.
Know there's some people that are ditch
diggers and there's not a goddamn thing
you can do about it and it sucks.
It sucks if you're one of them.
Survival of the fittest.
Sometimes ditch diggers have smart kids,
but sometimes they don't know.
My best friend who's a smart guy,
he's a firefighter in Manchester.
He and I went backwards and forwards for
a long time on the fact that he thought
that he could take Rhonda Rousey.
She will break both big.
Is He?
Oh,
he's like,
Yo.
Size because he know how to fight.
He was a tough guy at school and like
those dickheads that you see in the
street,
he's like,
yeah,
but I'm gonna let gill punched me in the
face and it's old.
I'm like,
no,
run around.
He's not going to punch you in the face.
She's going to put you in a choke hold
or she's going to put you into
submission where she breaks both in
rounds and then she stands on her face.
She can tap grown men who are
professional fighters.
I've seen it.
Yeah.
You know,
if you just eat,
you just don't know.
There's a level of talent and ability
that some people have that it sort of
supersedes the sexual.
Totally.
The,
the,
the ideas that we have,
the classifications of,
you know,
man can't beat up a woman or a woman.
Can't be the man rather.
Yeah.
They know they can.
There's just as other girls,
cris Cyborg.
She,
she'd beat the fuck out of most man,
you know,
and,
and do it in a,
in a very manly way.
And,
and Rousey's technique is so strong that
you can't fuck her judo spectacular.
And her arm bars are amongst the best
I've ever seen in any weight class with
men,
women,
anybody.
She has.
She's phenomenal.
One of the scariest dudes for me,
I think he's been injured for a little
bit,
but I saw him.
You,
you come and tell you on this fight,
and it was truly terrifying to watch was
Rory Macdonald.
Oh,
rory.
Rory Macdonald owned some English guy
where he broke his cheek and broke his
nose.
And I mills.
Yeah,
I watched it,
I couldn't believe what I was saying and
I rewound it and the reason why he went
off like that is he got cool.
Roman Donald got caught by something and
you said it,
you were like,
well,
we got caught.
He got caught.
He tied the guy out,
put it on the floor and was like,
fuck this nonsense and destroyed his
face and he's got like a terminator vibe
going on with man.
He's just like calling.
He knows.
Yeah,
he goes dead.
You're dead because you want to judge
CNPS boys.
Yes.
Yeah,
he's trained on there for us,
a hobby and Montreal.
He was phenomenal.
He.
Is he injured?
Is that.
No,
he's fighting for the title.
July 11th.
Good Fan in Vegas.
Woohoo.
That's the undercard of the Joseph
Connor Mcgregor fight.
He's fighting Robbie lawler.
Who's the champion right now.
It's a wild fight and good luck to him
and it's great fun.
What about jsps?
He done hopefully,
uh,
you know me,
I have a different stance and the rest
of the UFC,
I think they'd want them to come back
because he's worth a lot of money.
I think he's had enough,
yeah,
I think he's in his thirties and he took
a tremendous amount of punishment and
his career and did the greatest thing
you could ever do.
He won the title,
defended it a bunch of times,
in my opinion,
is the greatest welterweight and history
and it's not going to get any better
from here.
You know,
he's taken over 800 shots to the head in
competition in the UFC.
I think it was like 880 something that
counted as one and that's just in
training.
I mean that's just in fighting,
not training.
Yeah.
I mean one of the saddest things I've
ever seen in UFC is when you spoke to I
think after his fight and he was like a
little rattled and he was like,
I'm going to take a break for a little
bit.
And you were like,
are you retiring?
And he was like,
I don't know,
I need to step back.
And I looked at this guy that was caught
like a Greek God and I thought he's
about to cry right there,
like he's done.
And the pressure on him to come back,
I think he's really unfair because like
the most precious thing for him to hang
onto now is his mind.
And he was like,
he was just about to lose it.
Well,
you know,
he's had some memory issues.
You know,
we,
I had him on the podcast he was talking
about he didn't know whether or not he's
been.
It had been abducted by aliens because
he would have these moments in his life
where all of a sudden
he was at home and he didn't know how he
got there.
And I was like,
Whoa,
that's not aliens.
Like these are,
these are probably issues that you're
developing from trauma.
But in his mind there,
it's almost alien.
It's like something's wrong.
And you know that when you start talking
like that and you.
I mean,
it's not like he's talking like that and
he has no history whatsoever of being
hit and no history whatsoever of any
sort of brain injury.
You know,
you're talking about a guy who's just
fucking job is to break people's brains,
you know,
and he's training with other trained
killers and they're hitting each other
on a regular basis.
You can't,
there's a point of no return,
no return in fighting and you got to
realize where that point is and it's
very hard for fighters to recognize that
they need someone to help them and talk
to them about it.
But George is one of the rare few that
did it on his own terms while he was on
top as a champion retired.
I applaud him for that.
I think he's amazing.
Yeah,
I think he's fantastic and he seems to
have come from a foundation of supple
and obviously it doesn't come from this
country and it feels like he has a nice
kind of backbone.
But yes,
plenty of money to.
He made a lot.
I made millions and millions of dollars.
He made more money than anybody,
so hopefully he'll be fine.
You know,
one of the things that happens in the
football community in the soccer
community in England is that these very
talented,
very elite sports stars that have no
idea how to do their own washing or do
their own groceries or write a check,
get taken care of for probably 15 years
and get spout the other side when
they're 35,
huge amount of depression in retired
football players because they,
now they're in the scrappy at 35 and
they look around and go,
I have this incredible talent which is
now no longer needed and I couldn't
functioning society in a way that most
people do.
So they're in no man's land and node.
Do you find that with.
Oh yeah,
it's even worse because they're brain
damaged.
A lot of them.
I mean there's a certain amount of brain
damage almost every fighter has by the
time they reach 35.
And uh,
I mean we get,
we experienced that with all sorts of
athletes in America with its football
players,
basketball players.
It's a crazy thing because most people,
they have the highest earning potential
when they're older.
You know,
as they get older,
they make more and more money to become
more and more successful and then they
retire with athletes.
It's the make the bulk of your money
when you're young and wild and
irresponsible and impulsive and then
you're supposed to try to hold on to
that gold dust as you get older.
I think we're at a new show on HBO is
about this.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
Little funny,
but we just ran out of time.
Just hit hit the three hour mark.
I love it.
Thank you dot.
That was awesome man.
I really,
really appreciate.
It was a really fun conversation.
You just do this more often.
You're around here,
right?
All right.
Let's do it.
Alright.
Dominic Monaghan,
ladies and gentlemen,
dom's wild things on twitter.
Tweet him,
tell him you love him.
See you.