Three two,
one.
Stir it up,
nick.
We're live.
Hello everyone.
Put the uh,
ear cups on and cheers,
sir.
Oh Man.
Thank you joe.
Thanks for being here,
man.
Yeah.
Thank you for breaking me out here man.
I know we meant to do this before,
but I hope now with all this good energy
between us,
we can do this properly for the Indians.
Yeah,
for sure.
Listen,
man,
to say that you've had a crazy
experience in this life is one of the
most understated things a person could
ever say.
I mean,
where do we begin?
Right?
Let's tell everybody your store.
So you were wrongfully committed of
murder.
You spent 22 years on death row before
you were exonerated by DNA evidence.
Yeah.
Hello everyone.
My name is Nick Harris and I was X.
Joe said,
convicted and sentenced to die for rape
and murder.
I didn't commit at the age of 21 in 1981
of woman named
Mrs. Craig was murdered in Delaware.
I have never met the woman.
I was in prison on unrelated charges and
I stupidly made up a story to try and
get out of those charges.
The police soon feel realized that I was
a liar and they fabricated the charges
around me then so it's ironic than in a
few days you're going to upper darby,
Pennsylvania,
and that's where the murder happened.
Really.
Basically,
and Linda May,
Craig was leaving her job at 4:05 PM on
December 15th,
1981 she's going home.
She gets abducted.
I don't know any of this,
but I tried in desperation to get out of
a lie that this officer put on me.
Fuck,
I got pulled over in a stolen car.
The cop beats me up.
He puts charges on me.
I'm facing life imprisonment and I'm a
junkie because all of my life I was
destroyed by what happened to me.
At the age of seven I had my head beaten
him by a man with a rock in his hand
after he sexually assaulted me and I did
all the stupid things that people can do
in the aftermath.
I kept it a secret and I let it foster
all the anger in me.
I became very aggressive as a child and
I ended up in trouble all the time.
And when I was in prison on these
unrelated charges to the murder,
I stupidly fell into that mindset of
desperation of trying to get out of it.
So the police put a prisoner in the cell
next to me.
He said,
I confess to him,
I was given a three day trial.
I was sentenced to death and put on
death row.
And then stupidly I escaped from prison
in 1985 and ended up on the FBI's most
wanted list to get out.
I was being transported to court and the
sheriffs were being cool.
We have,
first they were talking about what was
going on in Philly.
They were two nice like sixties
[inaudible] 68 67 and we drove five
hours from one of the hardest prisons in
America called Huntington.
And I left there after spending two
years of my first two years in silence.
So if you opened your mouth,
they would come in and beat your head.
And so I was so glad to get in the car
cause my mom was waiting in my lawyer's
office cause they were gonna give me a
review of my trial because they withheld
so much evidence.
So I was eager to go to court and it was
the coldest day of 1985 February 15th we
stop at a gas station and in Exton,
Pennsylvania.
And as I got out of the car,
the officer driving,
pull past the cubicles.
Now we all got out of the car and ran
over to the cubicle together and I went
in to start a peon and an is holding the
door for me and my eyeglasses start
fogging up.
You know what I mean?
Cause you go from the freezing cold to
warm to the cold,
your eyeglasses.
So all I know is I turned around and I
come out and he has the door like that
and I put my head down,
go under his arm and I turned left and
go back to the car.
And the dude smoking a cigarette,
doesn't know that his partner,
when the cubicle,
the pis and as I'm running back to the
duty,
pulls his pistol out and point blank
shoots at me,
Joe like Paul.
And as it went past my face,
I was like,
Oh shit,
I hit the ground,
I ran and he's following me with the
gun.
I could feel it like,
um,
like I was waiting from the blast me,
you know,
cause he thought it overpowered his
partner.
Oh he doesn't know his testimony at
trial was I turned around,
Nick's running at me and my partners
down are gone.
I pulled my gun and he runs and I,
I wasn't going to let a death row
prisoner run.
So I've tried to stop him.
I shot.
So I run around the corner,
I hit the ground,
I ripped all the skin off my hands.
I've run around the corner and I fly
towards this restaurant and there's all
these people innocently eaten dinner and
I'm running right towards the plate
glass window cause he ain't going to
blast me,
you know.
And I ran like I knew he couldn't shoot.
And then I shot around the corner and I
ran down to a gas station.
I tried to steal a car that didn't work.
Then I ran like 400 yards,
400 yards,
and I hid behind the car.
I just escaped from and I was laying in
the weeds behind the gas station,
about 50 yards from a muddy road
screaming,
who was the bigger idiot for letting
this happen?
And I was thinking,
oh my God,
like what am I doing?
What do I do,
Joe?
What?
Like how do I just jump up and say,
wait a minute,
it was a mistake.
You know that he already tried to shoot
me in the face,
right?
So I go high behind the police station.
Next four hours I'll have my God,
I'm Jeanne paid,
chased by a helicopter and he chases me
and he pins me and he chases me.
And I was so fit that I ran for four
hours through the woods without care,
with the branches did to my face or
nothing.
Man,
I blew out both quads.
I did my,
my hamstrings.
I ripped my feet open.
I ran so hard in terror that I didn't
care,
man.
And I got away and I,
I made it all way to Florida and I was
going to lead the country,
you notice?
And I said,
I got to go back.
How did you get to Florida?
I stole a dude's wallet,
New York,
and I got on an airplane and I went down
to Florida and I tried to rob a drug
dealer and I tried to do just,
I was sitting there,
I was so angry.
I was going to kill myself.
I was on,
uh,
I'll never forget this day.
I didn't want my folks to see me in
prison.
Handcuffs no more,
you know,
so I was going by a raft and it's going
to go on the ocean and I was going to
have one last party,
but all the foods that I loved,
then I was going to stab the raft,
wait for the sharks,
have to cut my wrist,
you know,
and then it was going to cap myself and
go.
Then I said,
no,
I'm going back.
So I turned myself back in.
They put me on death row in Florida and
I went back and I faced it,
you know,
say beat me for four minutes,
man.
They broke my face,
broke my back,
crushed me,
man,
tortured me and I thought I'm to get you
back,
you know,
for all the days you made me go in a
cage and beat some other prisoner while
you stood there with a club laughing at
me,
I'm going to get you back.
I'm going to make sure I started being a
loving person again.
So I'm sitting there in 1985 1986 with a
105 years plus the death penalty.
And I decided,
fuck this,
I'm going to be a nice guy.
So I started to learn,
okay,
I suffer from Aphasia.
I had my head beaten him with a rock.
So what is Aphasia?
Aphasia can be identified simply in
people who have stuttering disorder.
Their brain and their of vernacular
abilities are distorted by disruption in
their brain.
Either their brain is functioning too
fast or their mouth is functioning too
fast,
or there's a combination of the two
misfiring and Aphasia can be through
trauma or through genetics.
And Aphasia affected my life so much as
a young person,
I never had the respect to listen to
people because I couldn't function.
I couldn't articulate,
I couldn't speak when I was at trial,
people spoke words that I didn't
understand and it frustrated me.
And when I tried to speak and I
stuttered,
people would be like that.
Uh,
C'mon retard.
When he got to say so after that beaton
where they beat me for four minutes and
he broke my face,
I began practicing speaking to myself.
Every day I learn new words and I taught
myself how to correctly articulate that
word into a sentence beautifully from my
own self and myself every day.
And then I became very,
very good at writing.
I began helping other prisoners.
I became the most dangerous prisoner
that they held because I cared about
other men.
I wrote to their mothers.
I wrote letters to their lawyers.
I gave up opportunities for people to
write books about me so I could help
another innocent man.
I did all those things because that's
how I got back at him for night.
They did to me.
So in 1988 I'm sitting in my cell and I
read about Dna and I knew right then I
could prove my innocence.
So I was the first man in America in
February of 1988 to ask for DNA testing
to prove my innocence.
And he threw away out hot tubs and
material.
And when I discover new evidence,
they destroyed that.
And his woman who came to meet me and
start visiting me fell in love with me
and she believed in me.
So she stood by me and told me that she
would be with me either to the gallows
walk or to the Moma approved medicines.
And for nine years she stood by me,
you know.
And finally we found some evidence that
was testable in 1995 what?
What was the evidence?
It was sperm from the rape and it was
being sent out here to California,
to Dr. Edward Blake.
And it broke open and transport and
spilled.
So Jackie left me,
had nothing left,
and then they put me in a special unit
and it started torturing me.
I keep this part quiet.
I never told a story.
It would ruin what happened if you're a
13 it's now out on Netflix,
but they finally closed down the old
prison I was in for 12 years,
where the average rate of survival is
only five and I was wanting hard as Jews
there and I made it.
They closed the prison down and open up
green county,
Super Max.
And the courts ordered that every
prisoner in Pennsylvania be loud out of
their cell for eight hours.
The administration looked at each other
it fuck that.
Not the crazy cannibals and not to
serial killers,
not the dudes that have been assault and
rape and each other.
So they picked 48 if it us out and they
put us in Pittsburgh and a special
penitentiary setting in which we were in
a sealed unit and they put all these
guards in there.
They weren't allowed to touch other
prisoners because they're so violent and
told them that we're giving you the
craziest of the crazy.
You know,
Buffalo Bill from silence of the land
was a real man,
right?
His name was Gary Hide Nick.
He abducted black women in Philadelphia
and put them in a pit under his house
and fed one of them to the other
survivors because he was building a
master race.
He was my neighbor man,
like so they started torturing us and
doing all this psychological crazy shit
to his word.
They were feeding us to each other like
wolves.
So I kept it all quiet until this year
when,
once again,
misfortune fell on my life and I
released monsters a madman,
the new book that I was going to give
you today,
and I thought,
you know,
I got to tell that story,
you know?
But it's been so hard to come back from
these moments,
Joe.
It's just like I look at what they did
to me and how I went to that moment
where the DNA is gone,
Jackie leaves me.
And so I find that I'm dying from
Hepatitis C that they did learn.
They infected me of it when they broke
my teeth when they beat me.
So I asked to be executed.
I said,
I studied all the world's religions.
I read over 9,000 books.
I did everything in piety.
My mother asked me to do,
I don't want a guy like they'll carter
did with the cards,
come into his cell and taunting them,
you know,
teasing him and listen to a man scream
in agony because the pile in his belly
is killing them.
So I wrote to the courts and I asked to
be executed.
I said,
fuck it man.
I want to die as a man.
I love who can respect himself.
Yeah.
The court intervened in order to DNA
testing that was going to be done on
evidence is spelled
July of 2003 the DNA test come back and
he proved innocent.
How did so the,
the dea evidence spilled and they just
captured it.
Once it spill,
it was in a box with all this evidence.
And Dr. Edward Blake who did the Oj
Simpson trial DNA,
said that there would be challenges to
it if he did the DNA in 1999 1998 and
2003 they had advanced mitochondrial DNA
separation so well that he felt
confident in his results.
So the federal court got involved and
said,
look,
I don't want to have this man executed.
I want the DNA done.
So they did that and it was amazing that
on the day that I called the lawyers,
they revealed the truth to me.
I called his lawyer and I'm like,
what's up?
He goes,
nick,
we got DNA from three separate sources
that prove you're innocent.
I said,
that's amazing,
Mike.
I,
I'm,
I'm really grateful.
He goes,
you know,
we used to tell people you're crazy that
we never believed in you.
I'm really sorry for that.
I'm like,
man,
really?
You want to take away my joy now,
man.
So I was really downcast at the day.
I called my mother,
my brother,
Mikey was having a seizure at her feet
cause he was an alcoholic after he fell
off a roof and he died shortly after.
So
he just went fucking crazy from there.
They take me off death row and they put
me in a psychological cell and they tell
me they can't trust me,
that no human being who has had done to
them what we've done to.
You cannot be angry that we open this
door up and we let you out.
You're going to get us.
So we're going to leave you until the
day they let you out.
We're going to leave you in this cell
because we don't trust you not to kill
us for what we did to you.
What did they do to you?
He to have the thing called gladiator
day,
so to lieutenant will be off on a
Sunday.
And the guards who started to come from
the Philadelphia area were black.
Nadian liked the guards up in the
hillbillies,
beaten on black prisoners.
So a weird thing happened where this
lieutenant came up with an idea,
we'll look,
let's let the prisoners get this
frustration outta you guys buy you pick
out the biggest guy and you pick out
this guy.
So one day I'm sitting there minding my
own business and they open up my cell
and there's four of them were clubs
Europe.
So I got to go in the cage and I got to
go and hurt somebody while they stand
outside.
And if you don't fight,
they're going to come in and they're
going to be worse than you can beat a
man or get beaten by one man.
Yeah.
So they did all this for their
entertainment.
Would they ever punished for this?
Not until after the riot on one of them
testified against the others for the
murder and stuff.
Okay.
I've watched the 11 people commit
suicide.
I've been stabbed,
strangled,
beaten,
senseless.
The cards used to talk because I was a
qs.
If a psychological murder of going out
and stock and his poor woman,
because she looked like my girlfriend,
they said I was never treated like a
prisoner.
I was treated with deference.
The worst word I know in English
dictionary do we I was treated was so
harsh that it was cruel beyond cruel and
yet all I wanted to do was have enough
within me to learn to beautifully
speaks.
It didn't on a date at the executed me.
I could tell them how much I cared about
myself.
Yeah.
I was more important to me than living
because
somehow when you suffer like I've
suffered,
your head cracks open and you have this
hyper sensitivity to life
so that when you touch the human beings,
you never forget the 14 years no one was
allowed to touch you.
You know what?
Fuck this.
I ain't crying no more.
It's all right,
man.
There's nothing wrong with crying.
I just thought about it.
You know what Joe?
I do because I feel better for the whole
shit you shouldn't feel because I look
in your arms and your eyes and I see the
hurt that I'm causing you for doing.
No,
no,
no.
Don't worry about that,
man.
All right,
well this is what I know I'm doing is
trying to imagine what your life has
been like.
Don't you worry about me at all?
I'm harder than life and I'm kinder than
love.
Secretly.
I'm a saint.
It never hurt no one.
I try my best to be played every day and
I've had misfortune and I return
and a very sorry that I sit in this
chair today after it came about.
You see,
I believe in good.
I believe good is going to when Joe and
uh,
I believe that I had again and was three
years again when years ago when I met my
wife,
current wife Laura.
See,
I had a woman in my life before that
used me and left me here in Los Angeles.
I ended up homeless on the streets here
and I was actually living up in this
area on the streets because my good
friend Noah,
lives around here.
Him and Jason took care of me and my bad
times I call it.
So I go back to England,
I meet this woman,
fall in love.
We have a baby and she's born on your
birthday.
And I start to believe in hope again.
I go do a podcast and England with my
good friend Brian from Chew Jordy.
And I start to spread my message again
and I want to get all these young kids
to believe in themselves.
And then one day I put the baby down for
a nap and I get Laura to lay in my arms
because she's sick and we'd get up 20
minutes later and the baby's dead and
I'm coming down the steps with the bed
dead baby.
And um,
you know,
all fucked up again.
And then people are so cruel that in the
village they started,
you know,
maybe the baby was killed by the guy on
death row when all this shit.
And I have a stalker ex wife,
Karen,
who just won't leave me alone,
contacts to police and tells him that I
put out a tweet that I,
and it only happened because my good
friend Anthony Simon Don,
he was in the green room,
told me the day before my daughter died
about have good close friend of his,
they lost a baby that day.
And so when our baby died,
I put out a tweet to saying,
you know,
appreciate the people in your life cause
they're so precious.
And the police came to our house and
humiliated me and wanted to know how I
could tweet about something because my
clock was nine hours off because I was
living on the streets of Los Angeles and
my time was still on la time.
Cause the anthony and I are developing a
major motion picture about my life.
And I told the police,
what are you crazy?
Like why would I so I can't even get a
break on the death of my daughter like
the,
that was the moment that the director of
the film fear of 13 decided to rip me
off for my rights to the film.
Um,
I decided to rip you off how he owed me
50,000 pounds from doing the film.
Fear of 30 decided to rip you off
because he thought you killed your baby.
Now he decided to rip me off and not pay
me my money.
When I asked him I needed money to bury
my daughter.
So I end up in a shouting match with
authored the Moelis,
the billionaire from Boston.
I promised to get on his plane and come
kick his ass over the money.
We're arguing over cause I begged I,
it was crazy.
I ended up,
I'm still confused.
What?
So your child dies,
is it my child dies and everything goes
badly on syndrome.
Yes.
And everybody that I counted on to have
my back,
including director David Sinkton who
promised to pay me for my participation
in the film all then tell me,
well no,
I'm not paying you.
And I'm like,
how can you do this when I need this
money to bury my baby?
Why did he say it wasn't paying?
Cause he said he didn't owe it to me and
all this.
I said,
boy,
are you crazy?
You,
you have a written contract.
So it's the same thing.
You know how that entertainment
businesses,
once they get what they get out of you,
that's it.
So he just said he wasn't going to pay
you what the contract said.
Right.
So author demaurice invested in the film
and he owns most of it.
So I write to author,
I call myself author.
David's not paying me my money,
can you help me?
Cause he owned most of the film by that
point.
So author gets all annoyed at me.
I said,
look man,
my daughter just died.
I blew up at him.
I told them,
send me your private jet or come to
Boston,
we can have a fist fight.
You love to fight and all that shit.
I just lose control.
And then author out of His grace sends
me some money so we could bury the baby.
But it went through all this terrible
shit.
So I started,
I said,
now I'm going back to America.
So I leave England,
I come over here.
I got two daughters with Laura.
We go over here now and the Oregon and
Anthony,
my God,
I meet this amazing man only because of
Muhammad Ali dying.
And now he's going to help me make a
major motion picture about my life.
So I get away from all that trauma of
losing a baby and being humiliated by
people thinking I would do some shit to
a little girl.
And I go back and rebuild everything and
then I try to go to Canada and they
won't let me in as crazy,
so I can't go do my job there.
I lose all.
Don't let you in because you were on
death row for 22 years.
Yeah,
I know you're innocent.
Not only that,
I just came from speaking before the
United Nations sitting next to the
president and current former presidents
of Switzerland and I have a security
clearance from that.
I worked in a high profile job in
England going around speaking over to
governments,
but Canada holds it against me because I
escaped from death row,
so I can't enter the cat.
The country of Canada,
Robin Sharma tried to have me come up
there and speak for him with his
conference and I had the humiliating.
They do it from my home via skype.
It's like,
I'll never stop being punished for what
happened,
you know what I mean?
But I don't care about that.
What really bothered me,
it was that all those things started to
fall me and I started losing hope again.
So I go and I even tried recently just
to have a normal job and give up
everything.
I,
I'm a beautiful speaker in schools and I
go around and try and help people with
their education.
Right?
So I was trying to do that the last year
with a,
a friend of mine named Wayne Sharp from
New Zealand.
He has a company called my verse and he
wants to help children find the correct
path.
Education so important.
We can't get that gone.
I can't,
I just decide I'm going to give up
everything and just go get a normal job.
But that doesn't work.
So I'm sitting there and it's Jamie's
birthday and I'm angry like,
what the fuck?
How could it fall apart again,
sit in,
you contact me after I tweeted and it
all starts again.
I'm back to believe in that.
It doesn't matter how it got in his
chair or it doesn't matter.
That demand proceeding me has everything
and I had nothing.
I still believe in
you this time and I told you now I
messed.
I sent,
yes it fucking Hell Joe,
you're going to change my life.
Doing is,
man,
you could have to do this.
You didn't have to be nice to me.
Yeah
you are.
And for that man,
I'm willing to keep going.
Cool.
I can't,
I mean I don't think anybody can imagine
what it's like to spend 22 years on
death row for something you didn't do.
I'm wanting you to go back to the night
that you got arrested and tell us cause
you,
you kind of,
there's some tissue right?
Besides you if you want it.
Yeah,
I'm good.
I'm daughter crying.
Okay,
go ahead bro.
It's just the night you were,
how old were you were (202) 012-0120 I
turned 21 before he sentenced me to
death.
I'm 20 years old.
I'm a Philly kid and I'm high on meth
and the music's blasting drive into
chester,
Pennsylvania and the stolen car and
everything in my life is just chaos.
I'm fighting with my two brothers all
the time and no one has respect for me.
I was ugly and it's two o'clock in the
morning.
I just came from a bar.
I go through a stop sign and the next
thing I know,
I saw the lights,
I pull over and beating and my head's
out of control and I'm sitting there
gripped with fear.
I took a beat and Philly in December 4th
of that same year in which they ripped
all my teeth up.
Oh.
Would a blackjack.
So I was really scared,
you know,
I was like,
don't move.
Don't run.
Don't do nothing stupid.
You took a beating from cops earlier?
Yeah.
You know,
Philly cops put me in my place because I
ran my mouth.
So,
okay,
there I am sitting there and the next
thing I know,
bam on the window,
Bam.
And he rips open the door and uh,
attract from bad company was playing
really loud and he,
I can't hear any or make focus of what
he's saying,
you know,
and then exiting or no,
boom,
right up out of the car.
And he's got me on the duckhorn and his
name is Benny,
right.
And he's six foot four and he's gotten
me pressed against the top of the car
and he's holding me down and I can't
breathe.
So I start resisting.
I popped his arm off and the adrenaline
goes,
boom,
here comes the beast out of me cause
it's six two and that age I was crazy
tough man.
I was like off the charts and so I
pushed him back.
I remembered that and he couldn't
believe it.
He pulled out his stick and raised it up
and I just snatched it out of his and
chucked it away.
I was looking at him like,
I was like,
that's Zombie guy.
And he went furious many,
pulled out the pistol and I seen it
coming and I grabbed his hand and I
pushed down and I had my arms out
stretched and the gun whoop boom,
down into the ground like that.
I looked at him and he put the gun up
there and he's dead.
Motha fucking Wuss.
He puts me in a car.
I'm sitting in the backseat,
I'm freaking out.
You know,
he gets in the car and he's,
he's like jumping back and forth from
the front seat.
Then he waits and he looks at me in the
mirror and he grabs the mic and he's
going like shots fired officers.
This shots fired.
He looks at me one more last time he
goes,
help,
help.
It could still going on and like,
um,
I'm like,
what?
Like what?
What's going on?
Dude tells them when they get there,
the backup officers get there.
He's like,
he tried to kill me.
He's got my gun and I got it back from
him.
I'm like,
no,
this is going south.
They jacked me up,
take me out of the car,
beat me down,
take me to jail.
Now I'm charged with attempted murder
and kidnapping of a police officer.
I'm 20 years old and I meet skipped
Dimatteo public defender who didn't
tells me I'm facing life imprisonment
and that's it,
and they're going to put me into
security wing because my bail is gonna
be so high.
I looked at him,
I said,
what do you mean man?
I was just trying home a minister one
car,
like he said,
no man,
you ain't never going home.
So I broke down and I went through detox
with note no help,
you know.
So three days I'm in a cell with nothing
but this newspaper.
And as the headline on the newspaper,
Mrs Craig's murder,
and it starts taunting me,
taunting me,
it's hot.
Somehow in my head,
I came up with this crazy mantra.
If I knew something about something that
big up,
you can let me go about this lie.
I didn't try to kill nobody.
I was sitting on my bed and the guard
was walking by and he goes,
what's wrong with you?
And I started telling him what was going
through my head,
the whole story.
And that was it,
Joe.
Oh my God.
He ran down the block.
He rented a sergeant's office.
They got me to the warden.
The warden's now been told to say,
you're telling them what's going on in
your head.
So I repeated it.
You had,
you had a plan to tell him a story,
to tell them a lie.
And when that officer responded because
he heard the story,
I didn't have any idea what the impact
of my words were.
I was so stupid.
Oh,
you were also going through detox?
Yeah.
And so they take me to the awards office
and he starts praising me.
They take me out of solitary
confinement.
Tell me I'm doing a great job.
What did you tell him?
I told him that a man that I knew in the
area had told me he had done the crime
and that if they let me out,
I would tell them all about it.
And he told me I was helping the
community.
They were taking me out of solitary
confinement and all that.
They told that,
uh,
they spoke to officer,
right and he was going to retract his
charges and only charged me resisting
arrest and they were going to drop the
rest of the charges and everything was
going to be good.
And then three days later they came back
and said,
dude,
you lied.
And the only reason you lied is because
you want to tell us that you did this.
They put me in a room and start doing
all this shot.
They find out that you lied to do did I
made the story up.
A was no longer a drug addict.
And he had an alibi.
So you just tried to pin the story on,
on some other drug addict they do to rob
me a rolled me up in a rogue and tried
to kill me with a three 57 magnum.
So I figured,
I heard the story that he was dead and
figure out he won't even find him
anyway,
you know.
But a 20 year old doesn't have any
concept of,
you know,
complex stuff like this,
especially in the 80s.
Right.
Dude,
they came right back to me and they had
me in a Delaware County district
attorney's office and this detective
Martin told me no certain terms.
I was gone tell him why I killed that
woman.
I wasn't leaving that room.
So for 13 hours they tortured me.
Matt started bringing up my childhood
and all that Shit.
I told him,
man,
I just wanted to blow up my whole world
like a Nasssa.
Oh,
that's good.
So this is my confession consists of,
um,
and I kill anyone.
I never meant to kill anyone.
That's good.
You never meant to kill her.
What are you talking about?
So
I went to trial and I was given a three
day trial for the murder of Mrs. Craig
after the jury found me not guilty of
all my original charges.
So I was really frustrated that a jury
heard the testimony of officer right.
He would later be fired from the force,
uh,
being caught up in a drug gang and
chester,
he was dirty.
Uh,
but they didn't know that at the time.
But a jury found me not guilty.
That prosecutor,
my mental,
when that happened and he decided to
seek the death penalty.
So a month after I was found guilty,
not guilty of all my original charges
that I made the stupid story up.
I,
they gave me a three day murder trial.
That in essence was a joke.
And what they did was they prayed upon
the poor jury and showed them pictures
of the victim and stuff like that,
man.
And they had an inmate who burglarized
the prosecutors home and was facing 20
years come into court and say,
I confessed to him.
That was it.
So the inmates so that you confessed to
him,
Charles Catalina,
they got to got to do that.
Yup.
So I'm sitting there and they dropped a
bomb on me.
I know it's coming.
The jury was so crest at,
they went out to the wagon wheel
restaurant and put their dessert order
on hold while they found me guilty.
And then during the sentencing phase
they had their dessert.
Yeah,
I was 20 years old,
man.
I'm like,
this isn't real man.
I never killed a this woman.
How can this happen?
You know?
And then Yoni mistake I truly think I
made was that I told the judge go to
hell when he sentenced me to death
because he couldn't look me in the face.
Why do you think that's a mistake?
Because he decided to send me to
Huntington prison.
The hardest prison in America at that
time wasn't going to do before that,
I don't know.
But he made sure I went to the place
that they broke.
You see,
Huntington was designed as the prison.
If he raped another inmate,
they sent you there.
It was the first shoe program in
America.
It was the first really what does shoot
program?
A special housing unit or security
housing unit were s level five supermax,
you know,
like Pelican Bay.
And uh,
your punishment was that you weren't
allowed to speak in yourself and if you
got caught speaking in yourself,
they came in with a nurse and they,
after they beat you down,
she jabbed you in the ass with thorazine
and they knocked you off for a week and
you lost your mind.
So it was horrible.
Like I told you the first two years of
my sentence,
every day I kept my mouth shut.
I didn't care what was done around me.
And you weren't allowed to say a God
damn word and a minute and you know,
a lot of talk to other inmates.
Nothing.
I day to sing happy birthday to yourself
like I did.
I paid for that one.
They fucked me up,
Joe.
But I don't care about that.
Look,
I realized I was in a race.
I had to kill off the person that I was.
The person that I initially was upon
entering prison was a deceitful,
lying,
coward,
but know fortitude because no self
respect resided within me
and in utter humbleness,
I took everything that they did to me
and I paid for every window.
I broke everything I stole,
rely at all,
and then I started to love myself.
I figured I ain't get nothing out of
this but misery.
So I'm going out like the dude.
I'm a stand up and not misspeak
beautifully on the daily to execute me.
I'm a walk to that walk,
man.
I'm a Judas.
I didn't kill that woman,
but I damn sure ain't no coward.
I'm going to find out everything I can
about life and then I'm gonna face my
death.
I'm a do.
It was [inaudible] man,
like I had this beautiful,
beautiful speech ready for him too.
I was going to lay it out and just be at
peace because I realized there was
nothing else to do.
I could fight.
I couldn't argue.
It didn't matter because God's in
control of my life and I really believed
that I had a choice,
either be a bitter pill and get sucked
dry by all the misery of mountain me or
get my shit right and start loving
myself.
So I taught myself how to speak and
overcome this,
uh,
Aphasia.
It affected me my whole life and I found
out that I was giving myself
neuro-plasticity healing and I became
very graceful and calm and prison.
I was so serene and so powerful.
How'd you find out you were giving
yourself neuroplasticity healing?
I found that out from Robin Sharma,
Robin Sharma's,
the foremost authority on speaking about
neuroplasticity healing.
And when he found about what I speak
about,
he said,
I am the living embodiment of his
teachings.
That through grace and dignity and
kindness,
I've developed my own charisma that
carries me with confidence.
And that is the description of what he
teaches professionals,
beginners,
everyone to explain neuroplasticity for
people to neuroplasticity is a reward
system within your brain where in your
interactions,
especially with other human beings,
heals you.
So people who suffer from PTSD,
people who have had trauma in their
lives can actually heal themselves by
being meticulously polite.
And I began all of this when I was
released.
My mother sat me down and she said,
Nikki listened to me.
For you to get out of prison and not be
a nice man is a waste of everyone's
time.
Every prayer,
every time someone called me to mother
of monster,
every time a woman's spit in my face,
every thing that I went through is a
waste of time for you not to be a nice
man.
So I want you to promise me one thing
every day I want you to go out and say,
yes ma'am.
Yes sir.
And thank you because I want you to show
respect for who you are and that way
they hurt this family badly.
It's the only thing I ask.
I didn't notice.
She handed me the tool to healing
because neuroplasticity is the self
contrived act of rewarding yourself for
being a nice person.
And my gift over the last 14 years is
that I made myself so amazingly pliable
and gifted at helping others find the
good within them.
That's the reason I'm truly here today.
The thing that I've been able to
accomplish through my writing and
through my efforts is to show people
that you take things personally in life,
you'd be then a full,
because what you've done is you've taken
all the hurts and you've made them to
justify reason why you have to be an
asshole to somebody.
Whereas you keep forgetting that you've
been given a break over and over just to
be here,
man.
Dude,
I've been shot,
stabbed,
strangled,
run over by a car,
hung myself in prison to drug overdoses
and I had accountable trying to murder
me for two solid years.
I know that I could fall at any moment
from my own hand,
but God blessed me.
I believe so much in my purpose in life
that I won't kill myself.
I won't give up and it's only because
I've been tested that I know that it has
to be for a reason.
I had dreams about all this while I was
in death row.
I had the most amazing,
intense dreams because of my suffering
and they play out now.
So what happened?
Did I manage to touch something we're
all chasing.
Where am I in a delusional world?
Because I,
what do you mean by that?
I told people last June,
last year,
I told everybody on facebook something
was going to bag was going to happen and
it did when my daughter broke her elbow.
So I told everybody before it happened
two years ago,
I told my wife Laura,
I was coming back here to meet Anthony.
So I'm on Donnie and go on the good news
network and do a thing with Mei,
Mei Ali,
who's a good friend of mine and I told
him how things would happen and sure
enough,
every time it's played out I,
why did you think something was going to
bad was going to happen when you said
something bad was going to happen,
your daughter broke her arm.
Dude,
I'm in a meeting with a guy named Kevin
and John and I look at them and I say,
I have to,
and I'm on Melrose Boulevard.
My daughter is playing in the playground
a few blocks away and I'm in this
meeting with these men about my film.
I stand up at the table and I say to
them,
I have to go right now.
I run outside and I asked my wife,
Laura,
is she okay?
My daughter fell and broke her elbow and
had to have six pins put into it and
Cedars Sinai,
we have a $63,000 bill did.
It is stuck us with,
but I knew it was going to happen before
it did and I even told people it was
going to happen.
How can I have that touch?
Did you knew that was going to happen
specifically?
I saw the event,
but not in real time so I could make
sense of it,
but I saw the greenery at the park when
we pulled up,
it was the same and I had the flash last
night when I met Stedman Graham.
I had all these moments,
that woman last night pinned the thing
on my collar and she looked just like my
mother and I had this dream because my
mom died on September 9th and 10 years
ago.
I was actually on a flight September 11
for her funeral and it's all crazy how I
saw all these things in my dreams on
death row and they play out and it keeps
happening with witnesses to my life that
are recognizing it with me so I can't
make it up.
Do you know what I mean?
I wish my friend Jason was here.
He's,
he's been able to help me just put this
in context and I'm doing this badly,
but I just think that somehow I went
through an experience so intense that it
is truly cracked open.
Something that has given me a
hypersensitivity to things.
I think that it is allowed me truly to
be humble enough to really give my life
for a purpose and not be ego driven.
Like I have nothing at this moment where
we sit here,
but I am so proud of the fact that that
doesn't never stop me from believing in
good
and you could beat me all day.
You could put in a cage,
you could do whatever you want to me,
but it's up to me that didn't make it
misery.
I'm choosing not to men.
I don't care how much I got a struggle
from this point on or what grace is,
and granted,
I just want one thing to stay true in my
life that I don't lose who I am.
I fought so hard to be this man through
a childhood of a feeling so inadequate
because another man raped me to the
feelings that I was so low of being cast
aside as a condemned human being that
then rise up and go and speak before
governments.
To the point that Kofi Annan told me
that I was one of the finest speakers in
the world to then go and follow that and
stand at the base of the Coliseum where
human beings were put to death for
entertainment and blow 20,000 people
away and have it flawlessly done.
And to recognize that I had it all
within me to do because of one thing
that neuroplasticity came me.
Charisma,
the kind of charisma you exude.
So I don't know where it is that you hit
that point where you decided to really
believe in yourself,
but like you said,
you didn't listen to that shit that
people were telling you.
And once you did that,
you started to contrive all this
beautiful charisma because I didn't even
watch the fight Saturday when you were
talking,
I listened to you and I thought he so
flawless.
It's not even thought of,
but people would never grant you that
you dad to do something in your heart,
something within you made you believe in
this guy,
man was I,
I have not had much resistance at all.
I'm going to be honest with you,
like what you're,
what you're saying about me is very
kind.
I really appreciate it,
but really haven't had much resistance.
Yeah.
But what it is about you that makes you
believe in yourself.
Yeah.
What happened?
Where'd you hit that point?
Well,
I'm pretty sure it came from martial
arts,
from martial arts competition when I was
very young,
pretty sure from the first,
the first,
when neither neither.
Just,
um,
just how difficult it was.
Just,
um,
doing it from 15 to,
uh,
before I was 22,
I stopped somewhere around 22,
but there's just the fact that it was so
difficult that it,
uh,
it taught me hard work,
taught me focus and,
and uh,
I didn't have anything before that
before that I thought it was a loser,
like a really thought it was a loser.
I don't know.
My father,
um,
my Stepdad's a very nice guy,
but there's something about growing up
without a father that is still alive,
that doesn't talk to you.
And you know,
my mom worked all day.
My stepdad worked all day.
There was no one around,
you know,
I just,
uh,
and we moved a lot of,
didn't have any friends.
So I just,
I just,
um,
I never felt like I was worthwhile,
but that's what I wasn't anything like
what you experienced?
Nothing.
But it was enough within you that it was
the point where I needed to prove
myself.
That's what I need.
I wanted to show,
I,
there was something inside me that I
needed to show that it wasn't useless
and the only way I could show that it
wasn't useless was by being good at
things.
And initially it was art.
And then after art it became,
martial arts in the martial arts thing
was more important than art because the
martial arts tested me.
Like art was beautiful because I could
draw things and people would love them.
And then it made me feel good that
people liked my work.
But it was,
there's a big difference between that
and the martial arts.
The martial arts was so difficult to do
and to compete at a,
you know,
a national level,
it was,
um,
every time I did it I was terrified.
But after it was over,
I felt better about myself and I
understood that I could actually be good
at things.
So it was the first thing that I ever
did that gave me a feeling of of value.
So I went from being a loser to being an
extreme winter.
That's brilliant.
But it was just,
it is.
But is your point though,
but you're saying that people like held
me back and that's not really the case.
It wasn't,
you know,
I mean I'm sure people judged me one way
or another because of fear factor,
some of the other things.
But the thing about going through the
martial arts competition and everything,
when I was young,
I don't,
I don't give a fuck how other people
view me.
I don't,
I just do what I like.
I do what I like and I try to be nice.
But that's where your charisma comes
from and where you got that from,
it's still yours,
man.
I admired it.
A lot of people don't have the
confidence to do that,
to shut it off.
That noise,
that thing that makes us all react to
every one else's opinion.
Well I react to it.
I mean,
I,
I'm,
I'm most certainly feel it,
but I just don't,
don't,
I don't let it change the way I,
I go through life.
And,
uh,
I think because of the lessons that I've
learned,
I try to express that as much as
possible for people that haven't gone
through those same lessons.
So I can,
I can,
I can express that information and maybe
people can absorb some of it without
having to go through what I went
through.
I think what you went through is
infinitely more difficult,
more trying.
And I think that your message and your
story can show people that in the worst
possible scenario,
the beginning of your life as a man,
you're wrongfully committed to life in
prison.
You are going to spend the rest of your
life until they execute you on death row
and all the horrors that you've gone
through to come out of that and to come
out of that with a purpose of being a
nice person and learning how to speak
and learning how to speak clearly and
confidently.
Like there's a lesson in that that said,
I mean,
I mean this is almost like at a,
at a religious level.
I mean you talk about someone who's
created a diamond from pressure.
I mean that's what you've done well,
you've done is you've,
you've figured out a way to,
despite all this raging hurricane of
emotion that goes through your mind,
that's caused you to cry when you think
about these things,
you can express yourself in a very clear
way that lets people,
it just at least peer through the window
into what you've experienced in your
life and it,
it,
it can give people a perspective that
there just is very,
very rare that someone gets fucked over
in life as bad as you did.
Very,
very rare and it's even more rare to
come through at the end with a sense of
purpose
everyday of my life.
Someone writes me and tells me they
didn't kill themselves today.
Did you know that every day man,
did he stop drugs?
There's a young man living in my house
named Zach curves is a really good
friend of mine.
He really changed his whole life since
meeting me.
Uh,
even my close friends have told me I've
changed their life and I appreciate it
because I recognize a lot of times it's
the good within then that's resonating
and I'm proud of the fact that I have
sat and listened to the words I kind of
deserve for what I've tried and I'm
going to learn in the future to accept
the graces that you just did to me.
Because in the past I always tried to,
as you see,
diminish it.
I have worked very hard,
Joe.
I have worked very hard to craft,
um,
my work into writing and like your
drawings.
I was so proud of having a number one
bestseller in my first book and I was so
proud of using my talent as a writer to
then articulate what it's like to lose a
baby and my journey through her eyes or
to use,
uh,
this last effort in monsters,
a med men too,
to help people.
It's okay to have a bigger secret than
the one that people know you by and
still live with it.
And then when it's right,
you can share it.
Or I've made a point that I'm done
writing because I've accomplished all my
work as a writer and now I want to do
one thing.
Well,
I want to help young students around the
world take them so seriously with their
education.
I did over 500 of them in schools over
England and Europe and stuff.
I loved it,
man.
I got all these young lads and lasses to
come back to me and show me degrees that
they got when I showed him important are
education was.
And I,
I really thrive in that.
And Yeah,
environment because I think that's where
everything's still is for me.
Somehow.
Like I'm a kid,
you know,
who won't let go of needing to still
chase the good in my life.
And I notice things in the woods and I
know there's a billion things in the
woods,
but I'm still willing to walk that path
and find something meaningful.
And that's what I came here to really
say is that I want to make an impact
with my words,
but not overdo it.
So I don't want to do,
uh,
any other podcast after this one except
for my friend Brian's.
But I wanted to,
the meaningful thing without it having
to be attached to the social media draw
that has hurt my life.
So much
social media draw that has hurt your
life.
How has it hurt you live?
Well,
when my daughter broke her arm and we
put up a go fund me page,
I was viciously attack because people
expect me to have funds but they don't
know,
you know,
things need to have funds because of the
movie and the book.
And I'm not,
I have nothing.
I borrowed money to get here.
Like people don't know that I'm wearing
a shirt from my friend because he funded
me to be here,
you know,
so I'd have food while I was here.
It's like that real,
you know,
so people don't want me to not succeed.
Like I hurt third image of me if I don't
have wealth in addition to being this
person before them.
Well,
I just think people just,
they don't understand,
you know,
the people see someone else's life and
they like to assume the worst and they
like to criticize you whenever they have
an opportunity.
So if they see any vulnerability,
they pounce and you know what you've
gone through is the opposite of what
most people go through.
People have difficult times in their
life but more than difficult times.
You know what they have.
They have long periods where they don't
have anything happen,
where life is boring and life is just a
dull gray and life is just work and
coming home from work and the trials and
tribulations of that and traffic and the
kind of insane experiences that you had
being wrongly convicted and spending 22
years confined in a cage forced to fight
because of vicious psychopath guards
that those kinds of experiences or the
experiences that allowed you to come out
of it.
This very kind,
very open minded person who's trying to
better yourself and wants to see the
best in other people,
the people that go through their life
and this dull state of jealousy and
bitterness and resentment.
And just constantly focused on
themselves as self obsessive culture
that we have.
And one of the things about social media
that's most fucked up is you're looking
at all these other people's lives and
shedding on them and comparing yourself
to them and finding faults in them and
attacking them in the comments section
and attacking what the,
and the people that are doing that,
they're all doing that because they're
in,
they're in agony during a different kind
of agony than you.
But it's an agony of nothing.
I know.
And I looked at it and I thought,
I try to craft a beautiful message on
the social medias so that I don't get
caught up in arguments.
And I always try to show the good dude
in the world.
And that's why I love like the good news
network.
I'll try and deliberately stay away from
things that poisoned my mind cause I
don't want to contribute.
I don't want to get caught up in the
trump era argument or the previous
argument or the new argument.
I want to post meaningful messages of
good because that's my overall message.
So I thought recently maybe I can
contrive three beautiful messages for
twitter,
facebook,
and Instagram,
and I could leave out this wonderful
message and then I can go about my
business of going back into schools and
talking to students because it gets too
chaotic.
Um,
in addition to all the lovely messages
of the,
uh,
wonderful human beings that listened to
me speak,
or they saw the film fear of 13,
read one of my books,
there's also a lot of women out there,
men,
and they'd been harassing me and
bothering me.
And it's put a lot of conflict in my
life and I don't want that harass you
and bothering you.
How a lot of women fall in love because
of the film.
The film made me look very attractive.
What is it about
women and men that are on death row?
There's the one too.
Yeah,
I know.
So to it.
Yeah.
They'll contact me and tell me about
their inmate.
I'm not an inmate,
I'm not a death row prisoner.
I was on death row.
That is a strange obsession that some
women have it.
And it goes to a psychological feature
of women,
uh,
who can fix things with their loan.
So they want me to deceive my wife,
to be with them,
but not be deceitful.
They want me to ignore all the social
chaos I could cause to go and leave a
family to be with them,
but they still want to harass me.
And it was so bad recently,
even on my anniversary,
I had to cut off the people who were
bothering me.
I have a,
uh,
an act of stalker in my life.
Uh,
it's all kinds of crazy.
I've gone through a lot of experiences
where the social media is really tested
me.
So I thought I'm going to try and be
like the dude.
All right,
so they're going to execute me said that
twice the day.
The dude is the guy that knows art.
So this is my last scene.
You mean like from the Big Lebowski?
Kind of like the dude man,
like the dude so seriously.
Jeff Bridges one of my heroes.
What a moment.
You know Chris Pine,
Jeff Bridges,
Ben Foster being interviewed about hell
and high water and a asked Chris Pine,
what do you watch?
And he goes,
oh my God,
I got to tell you about fear of 13.
I've got to tell you,
Nikki Iris,
man,
this dude is the shit.
You know what I mean?
And my phone goes,
yeah,
I had dinner with him.
He so really,
really cool dude man.
Wow.
You need to have Chris on.
He's a really cool dude.
He really introspective and he's deep
like he's a real good conversationalist.
I soak time.
W w what else has he been in?
All these bullies image up.
Oh Dude,
he just a blanket on him.
He just did the one word oprah too.
And he did the one before that with the
Star Trek.
Oh,
that Guy Chris and wonder woman.
Yeah.
It's just as great on telling you,
man,
what are any a to invite me to dinner
and hang out with him.
And even Harvey Weinstein pops in for a
minute.
Holla.
I'm like,
no.
And he's like,
Harvey,
you just produced that documentary.
But the dude that was in jail or
everything hit the fan.
This is before things went tits up.
I know.
I had this real great blessing.
So Alejandro Monte Verde,
uh,
who did the little boy with a Kevin
James,
he has an amazing life story himself.
I mean his,
his family was abducted by the
kidnappers and executed.
This is real drama.
The day I meet this man,
I'm at a red carpet event in La and he
goes home and watches fear of 13,
and he comes back and he tells me,
I'm going to make your movie.
I'm going to help you.
I don't know how,
but God told me there's certain movies
that have to make.
And he's making one right now with Tim
Ballard from the CIA about um,
rescuing children from the sex trades
and stuff.
So he's doing really serious work.
You know what I mean?
So make a feature.
Films that are going to make a feature
film about me called conviction right
now,
it might be changed,
but I got the script and it's fucking
hard,
man to read.
But we have all these a list actors.
And my dream of course was Chris Pine.
Cause I think he's one of the best.
Right?
But I have no say.
But I get this amazing chance to come
out here and meet all these people for
the film being made.
And I realize it's all meant to beam and
like all this crazy stuff.
So maybe if I craft my message right,
I can step back and let people
appreciate the message I had without
distorting it.
Cause I don't want to ruin it.
I don't want to go too far and end up
making a fool of myself when I thought
the right thing to do was teach people
about neuroplasticity and how to make
yourself a really bad ass outside the
ring by being a kind man and how to
rarely make yourself a really nice
person to the family and loved ones by
having the self respect about yourself,
to be patient in life and things like
that.
You know,
and don't ruin it.
So that's what I,
you keep saying don't ruin it.
You know,
when you're talking about social media,
I think one thing to take into
consideration is when you do something
like a go fund me or any,
anytime there's anything controversial,
those are magnets for hate and you might
think that everyone hates you,
but what you're dealing with is a very
small amount of people from a very large
amount of people that,
sir,
if you thinking about the whole
planet,
right,
and all the English speaking people,
you're dealing with hundreds and
hundreds of millions of people that can
achieve so much in what you said.
That's why I'm here now because on my
website,
[inaudible] dot org we organized so
today's listeners can go there and
download copies of my book.
I can get out of destitute times.
I can get my life together.
We did everything we could knowing that
this podcast is reaching a million
people.
So you're right.
I do.
I mean even you like your social media.
What I mean is just the thing is to not
get caught up in the numbers that come
at you that are negative because it's
just a sheer matter of volume,
right?
If you're reaching people through the
Internet,
you're reaching,
who knows how many human beings.
I think one out of a hundred is going to
be the type of person that wants to send
a hateful message because it's easy
because they don't have to look you in
the eyes when they do it.
They don't have to feel any social
consequences.
They don't have to feel your pain when
they insult you or,
or you know,
say awful things,
but you or your family,
they're doing it because they want to
affect you because they're hurting and
they're hurting for a very different
reason than the way you're hurting.
But this is what's wrong with social
media is because human beings are not
meant to communicate that way.
We lose our humanity in this very
shallow form of interaction because all
those parts,
what's what's important about people's
looking them in the eyes,
talking to them,
hugging them,
shaking their hand,
communicating honestly and anytime you
you're missing any of those pieces.
When you communicate dishonesty,
when you don't want to shake someone's
hand,
when you don't want to look them in the
eye,
when you don't want to enter in your
interact with them.
When you don't care about them as a
person,
all those things leave you feeling like
shit and all those.
That's true.
You're right.
The social media is the worst form of it
because it's just text.
You have to interpret it yourself.
You don't know what the fuck is going on
in their life.
You don't know who they are,
but you read that text and you absorb it
personally.
You absorb a personally,
you take it in the worst possible form
and you,
you feel that critique in your chest,
you feel it,
you feel it in your head.
And now I guess I got caught up in this
notion that
I could just copy a normal guy and have
a normal job and people would leave me
alone.
Well,
they would if you weren't on social
media and uh,
I,
I've already entered that form so you
don't have to stay in that form.
But it's true.
But here's the thing.
Even if you do use that form,
you know what you can do.
You just don't interact.
You Sal is,
that's the thing.
That's what I said.
I was on it too.
It's hard for people to understand that
are on the outside.
They're like,
well,
you asked all,
I love you.
I want you to interact with me because I
love you.
You know,
and I want you to recognize that I'm
recognizing you and I appreciate that
from people,
but they have to understand the volume
of people that someone like you is
dealing with.
That's what I tried to convey.
And I try very sincerely,
never to be ignorant to people.
And you know,
it's,
it's fucking mind blowing joke.
Cause I had my mind made up and now I've
realized that I do.
And it all goes back to a conversation.
What were boy Jason Daily?
Me and him were driving along the four
five one day in a film for it.
Fear of 13 is about to come out.
And I told him I didn't want it to come
out and he said,
you don't own that film.
Every kid that's ever had a shitty
childhood owns that film.
Everybody who's got a broken marriage or
a shitty lifers really struggling owns
that film.
If you fuck this up,
I'll never be your friend again man.
And he was right.
I don't own the fear of 13 and I don't
own really anything of it,
but it's message is so beautiful.
I did what I could to tell my story
because we're all living our life as an
experience,
but we can only convey it as a memory.
And I did beautifully for myself and I'm
so proud of the effort I made.
I don't care that the director rob me,
I'll make my way.
I don't care what I went through to this
moment because I truly appreciate the
person who wrote me last night and said,
two weeks ago I was released from a
mental hospital after trying to kill
myself.
And my mom sat me down and made me watch
film now,
and the last two weeks I've been going
to therapy and I'm getting my shit
together.
I don't film Joe and I don't own my
message.
I guess my message is taken on by the
people who love me or not.
You're right.
I'm not going to be bothered by the
negatives.
I had a terrible experience with a
Stalker for 12 years who won't leave me
alone in it cost me and my daughter in a
divorce,
all kinds of crazy stuff.
So it was really affecting me and my
current wife and I didn't like it,
but I think I'm going to actually beat a
dude and just hang around for a little
bit longer and make you proud of me for
what I do from heroin.
Well,
don't worry about me man.
Now everyone that I love as though to
always be on that list,
man,
I really,
that's what you use for motivation and
that's great and there's nothing wrong
with that.
Um,
but I think that what you can do and
what you are doing,
it show that you can,
you can overcome things.
You can overcome horrible things.
Some of the most horrible experiences a
person could ever face.
You can overcome them and you have.
And those messages,
they give people inspiration.
And inspiration is one of the greatest
things you can give a person and her
that you inspiring me today.
I told you since this man ever since we
started communicating,
I told you I meanness.
I even went out of my way today to matt.
Matt rang me,
your producer,
and I wanted to make point right away.
I said,
dude,
I know a lot of people climb right past
you to go to Joe.
I wanted to tell you,
thank you for helping me and my family.
Thank you for helping organize.
I made sure that Jamie got my love when
I came in the room because he organized
my trip and it was so cool.
He got me into the right airport and
everything.
Right.
Because I know that is so important to
that man because a lot of people make
that effort Gel,
and I don't want to be that guy that
misses my chance.
So I'm gonna thank you.
And yes ma'am.
And yes,
sir,
to everyone,
like my mom asked me and make sure never
to overlook people because that's truly
my message.
My kindness makes me able to come back.
My good heart is made better by the fact
that I want to believe in good.
And it's crazy how it's come back to
reward me in so many ways.
Like,
do you remember when Muhammad Ali died?
Yeah.
Well,
I didn't know anthony some on Donnie.
I didn't know his story,
but one day I get contacted by a man
who's seen the fear of 13 and I learned
that he went to university out here and
he became a lawyer because of a promise
to his mother to be a good person.
He goes to the mosque every Friday and
becomes close friends with Mohamad a
Neko to dinner every night with Mei Mei
on Fridays,
you know,
and he become real close.
And he tells me this story how at a
young age,
Mohammed looks him in the face and says,
you're going to be one of the men that
carries my message in life.
And he's like,
I'm 22 what could I possibly have to
offer anyone?
So he goes through this experience and
on the date of Muhammad Ali had approval
from the government patent office for
this bracelet that says within good
there has god.
He called me in England where I was the
time,
and he says,
I have a question for you.
I saw your film.
I learned a lot about you since then.
Why aren't you bitter,
man?
Why are you still willing to believe?
And I said,
my mother never prayed for anything but
good.
She always told me that only good there
was was an was within God.
He said,
are you kidding me?
Hold on.
And he starts sending me this stuff.
I didn't know that earlier that day.
Muhammad Ali's bracelet would be,
you know,
approved by the Pat.
I didn't know any of that,
but it was those words.
You see what I mean about the
synchronicity of all this craziness of
my life.
The next thing he know I'm and in Los
Angeles,
a meeting Alejandro,
he wants to help me make the movie.
I meet all these wonderful people like
Adam and from bottle keeper.
He's such a sweet guide.
They came up with this company on the
beach a couple of years ago and now it's
doing very well for keeping drinks cold
and he's done wonders for me and my
wife.
This man is such a lovely guy that I
wouldn't be in this chair without him.
We're anthony or any of these people.
Right.
And then anthony sets up may,
may Ali,
and he brings me out and we have a pod
cast and he doesn't tell her word about
me beforehand.
Now.
What's crazy was I'm doing this
interview right behind where I used to
sleep on the street and I think I kept a
lot of quiet,
did some of my best work when I was
homeless,
and I do this thing in May,
May,
looks at me and says,
no disrespect to my father Muhammad Ali,
but you're one of the most influential
men I ever met my life.
And within five minutes of meeting you,
I'm already changing things about my
life.
I decided right then,
okay,
then I have to own that man I have to
live at for her man.
Like I can never go back.
I can't go back and be an average,
retarded,
mindless,
angry person.
I can't be caught up in the drama of
everyday stupid shit.
Like I got an owe it to that girl,
you know?
And I have ever since I met her,
she's one of the nicest people in my
life,
man.
I have some amazing friends,
Joe.
I really mean it manna.
And there's so many connections to your
life you wouldn't even know,
dude,
when people found out I was coming to
meet you.
Every one of them said the same.
Pretty much the same thing.
Joe.
Such a nice duty.
So intelligent.
I love listening to them.
I work with educators on a platform
code,
netplus they love your stem procast I
know people up in Waterbury,
Connecticut that teach out of the self
defense class codes.
Practical set defense third right now
going crazy.
Cause you know they know Joe Jesse,
I'm Kazak huskies on the first ballot
tour card.
You know it and they,
these guys are really crazy like Alex
core,
Cortez and all them.
They're like joe is so next level.
I'm saying so are you psych joe showing
you to believe in yourself because he
didn't get there because he had like
been handed this shit.
Like I remember reading stories about
you going to the MMA and just doing it
so he could have drink money man.
Like the get free tickets and go in.
Right.
Yeah,
that's true in it.
Yeah.
When I first started working for the
UFC,
I did the first if not for money.
Right.
I did the first 15 shows for free.
For free.
Yeah.
See what I mean?
Well,
it was probably foolish financially.
My manager didn't think it was a good
idea.
I just didn't care.
I just,
I was enjoying it.
That's what I love.
Like I,
it's what I want to do,
man.
I want to be the dude.
Man
was also struggling company that I
believed in and I wanted to help him.
But what,
what you're saying is interesting
because you have one theme that you keep
repeating,
that you want to do things for other
people.
He keeps saying that like you wanted to
do that from May.
May you wanted to make me proud.
This is a constant theme that you,
you want,
you want to do good for other people.
That's an amazing,
amazing mindset for someone who's been
through everything that you've been
through,
that,
that sentiment,
that and then your gratitude.
That's another very,
very powerful thing.
Gratitude,
love and gratitude are two of the most
incredible expressions and some of the
most influential.
Because when you showed true gratitude
to people and true love to people,
they feel that that affects the way they
interact with the rest of the people
that they're going to experience.
Like if they run into a new person,
just moments after meeting you,
they will be nicer and they will,
they will feel that gratitude and feel
that love.
That's a real,
and that's one thing that we all can do.
You know,
this thought that we're all a powerless
and helpless.
It's of the problems with there's this
society is that the society is so
overwhelming.
We have so much information coming at
us.
And the message is that what's important
is,
you know,
beautiful girls with short skirts and
fast shiny cars and big giant houses and
private jets and diamond rings and
Expensive Watches and all this horse
shit.
And this is what people seek.
They seek that instead of seeking love
and gratitude because it doesn't seem
that that's important,
but that's way more important.
It's everything because that literally
changes the world.
It changes.
It's like,
you know,
I always thought that that expression,
the wings of the butterfly eventually
become a hurricane.
That's fucking stupid cause that doesn't
work that way.
A butterfly just generates a very small
amount of wind and they're small and it
doesn't really work that way,
but the idea behind it,
what what it,
what it,
what it represents as a metaphor is that
you literally buy your one person that
lives amongst 300 plus million people in
this country,
one person with love and gratitude and
inspiration,
especially the way you can express
yourself that affects people you come in
contact with and that in turn affects
the people they come in contact with and
that literally can change the world and
actually could change the world.
That's real necessity,
man.
That's what I'm good at.
I know it.
I've helped so many people heal their
lives when I've interacted with them and
tense time.
I've made it.
Let me stop you because this is one
thing that you said to me before the
podcast and you said it again during the
podcast.
The only want to do this one podcast,
you don't want to say anymore.
And I want to ask you why.
Because if you have this powerful
message,
the more people you reach and the more
you express yourself with this message,
you're not going to cheap.
And your message,
well you're going to do is you're going
to get it out to more and more people.
And the more people that you can get out
your words and the way you express
yourself,
that's going to affect people.
It's going to affect people in a very,
very positive way.
Okay?
But the other side of that,
and no one can appreciate is that I'm
failed.
I haven't been able to get anything
going.
I tried to start upon,
no,
no.
Let me,
let me stop you.
Let me stop you.
You're not failed.
First of all,
you've only been out of jail for 13
years.
That's fucking crazy.
You were in jail for 22 years on death
row.
There's not a whole lot of people get
through that experience and can tie
their own fucking shoes after they're
done.
You know,
you,
you're,
you have every right in the world to be
shell shocked and incapacitated.
You're not,
it's hard to get things going that the
world does not open its doors for you
and success does not come easy.
It doesn't work that way.
Okay?
So for you to say you failed,
you haven't failed.
You've already written books.
You've already have a,
a documentary made about you.
You're in,
in the process of making a feature
length film about your life.
That's not a failure.
No,
I just failed getting the platforms
together that I need and I guess
failing,
it's just,
it doesn't always work out right the
first time.
It's not,
it's not a failure.
You're not a failure.
Okay?
Then here's the deal for you,
sir.
Prove your words right to me and come on
when I get my shit together.
You come on my podcast.
When we finished the conversation,
later on,
I would do that,
but even if I didn't,
doesn't matter.
You can do anything,
but wow,
I just want to showed you,
you yourself,
this idea that you're,
you've failed is crazy.
It's you.
You have not failed.
If you've done things.
First of all,
everyone does things that don't succeed
and then you recalibrate and you adjust
and you try again.
No one succeeds and wins the world
championship in their first fight.
No one writes a book and without
learning English and without practicing
essays,
that becomes the greatest book the
world's ever written,
read,
written,
whatever you,
you,
you take time and you learn.
This is what life is about.
Life is about this process and through
that process you find yourself through
the difficult tasks that you undertake,
maybe adjust and you become better.
You said he started a podcast and you
feel well,
how long did you do it for?
I didn't never got off the ground.
No one believes in me.
And then I know,
I'm just saying,
first of all,
the podcasts are easy,
man.
What that phone you have right there?
I'm sure that phone has a audio recorder
I've done by living my $11 phone
probably does.
Oh,
they all do.
Every phone does.
That's not $11 madness or regular
android phone.
Right?
A good phone.
It's one of these wafer these me.
And look,
if you had this phone fucking 10 years
ago that people think you are a wizard.
Yeah,
man,
if he were in the fifth century,
of course.
Yeah.
Well that phone I'm sure has,
you know you're kicking me into this,
right,
and I'm going to have to respond because
of the way I've always been wired.
I'm going to do this.
Then I can do anything.
No,
listen,
I am all right.
You need never again encouraged me,
sir.
Okay.
If I go around doing that for others,
I have been rough on myself because I
thought I'd have a platform and
accomplish the things that I wanted to
and I felt really shitty that I wasn't
able to take care and provide for my
family.
And that's the heart of it really was
the struggle and that side.
I wouldn't give a shit about fame.
I've had the most amazing experiences of
my life,
man.
One of my first interviews was the
village voice and the woman learns me at
the end,
Jennifer Gonnerman's,
she says,
man,
you know you're living one of the
greatest stories ever told man,
this ain't no joke.
And every time she's told me that words
in my head,
I realized comes with a hell of a ride
in a price.
So if I've got to own it,
I got to own all of it.
I keep telling people to own it when you
do well.
So maybe I needed to bounce back and
this is the day I stepped forward and
start kicking ass again.
And maybe that will get me out of those
tearful that I've had to go through.
What do you have every right to have a
struggle?
I mean if anybody has any right to,
to,
to have difficult emotions and a
difficulty expressing those emotions.
It's you.
I,
and I understand how you could dwell on
things not succeeding the way you
anticipated one of them too.
But he just kind of keep going,
man.
You know,
I'm such a honest person.
I could never come on here and fake it.
You know,
I could never do that for you man.
I thought that would be so insincere.
So I just came down here and I decided I
was,
cause it was poured out.
Honestly we did.
And I feel like the best thing about it
is like jelly.
Like you're so like me in so many ways
on the,
on the download,
like you just,
he's just want good.
Like you just want to have a purposeful
message that you want to share and
that's what I thought was really cool.
I had a really cool experience last
year.
I went to East Germany to speak before
company and I met all these Lebanese
refugees after meeting navy seals.
The dude's on the plane love me man.
I built them up for being part of our
military system.
I made them really respect and honor
themselves.
Then I was on the streets of Berlin
hanging out with these Lebanese refugees
and I made them feel so good about this
fact that they still believed in each
other.
So I have some magical ability to go
around and touch different groups and my
message resonates with people who've
been in the military or have been
through trauma or not been through
trauma.
And I have a gift.
I know it and I've spoken in some of the
most prestigious places and one of them
is still to this day,
one of the highest honors.
I spoke at St John's church in London
where a ticket on the Vietnamese monk
who marched with Martin Luther King in
Selma,
Alabama spoke,
and he used to be my pen pal on death
row.
He was the first man that gave me
respect when I was on death row and he
questioned why I didn't have respect a
lot like you're doing for me today.
And he taught me to look at myself
differently.
So I went through a whole one year
period of my experiences before I could
speak at that church.
And when I did,
I was absolutely flawless because I knew
that my friend was there and he was
guiding me.
And somewhere within me I have some
magical ability.
I don't know where it comes from,
but I have an order to skill.
And once I'm past these dark days,
I'm sure I can lay it down well so that
I can carry a message beautifully to
educational fields purposefully into the
corporate fields or wherever I want to
go and I love it that I do have a
winning hand and I have a gift behind it
that was earned,
not control yourself.
How to do this.
I mean think about what you were saying
earlier about learning how to speak so
that you could speak at your own
execution.
That's why it's a powerful motivating
force.
Yes sir.
And to learn all of the world's
religions so that you understood what it
means to speak.
Do you know in the Sanskrit religion,
a lot of the words are used as
descriptive forms of things.
So chair isn't the object,
it's the feeling of sitting.
So you have a responsibility and not
only in the words that you choose to
speak,
but in a manner that you deliver them
and the vibrations within you that you
carrying leash share with another person
because there is a receptor within us
all to the truth and it resonates and it
rises within us.
And so I found that powerful ability to
talk to myself in that manner so that I
could love myself and I would stand in
the wouldn'to of my cell and talk to
myself or quote beautiful texts and I
loved reading the Prophet I Kahleel
Goubran.
I read it over 20 times because I
thought his message was so powerful
because he lost his entire family while
he wrote this book over a three year
journey and although I might have come
back from the ashes like pg Carnahan and
the man who beat would be king from
Roger Kipling,
I still feel like I have a valid message
motivating me to go forward.
And my idea from this wine on is I want
to go home to Laura and the kids and
regroup,
get myself together and I know a lot of
people are going to contact me because
of your grace to have me on your show
and what I plan to do over the next
couple of years,
Joe,
is I want to show myself not just user
that I'm right.
Being a kind man.
Being a goodhearted man,
being meticulously polite doesn't mean
you're a loser.
It doesn't mean you're a full and if
people take advantage of you,
it's down to you to take it as an insult
or rise the fuck up about the insult and
just move past it.
The reason I'm not bitter is because I
didn't take it personal when they broke
my teeth and put me in death row and
tortured me.
I didn't take it personal because right
now there are 2 million people
incarcerated in this country.
I didn't take it personal because 150
other men got off of death row.
That's why I'm able to function because
I don't take life personally,
but I'd take love personally.
I take it so personally to,
I'm willing to love myself.
A lot of people can't do that.
Do you know how hard it is to get a
woman to look at herself without looking
at a fall they can't stand?
Do you know how hard it is to get a man?
To be honest with his emotions,
thinking that he's weak?
If he does,
I would rather have tears on my face
walking down the street and frustration.
Then just rip on somebody and hurt
somebody.
That's the kind of caliber of level of
humanity I want to find them myself.
And I think we all do.
And I think the message,
like you said,
has been distorted by the social media
so badly that we need more talking.
And I would all,
I would dream of having a late night
talk and
play some of my calls,
music and talk to people,
just average people and just open it up.
Like I want to just share what's good
about me because my mother was right.
Wouldn't have just been a terrible waste
of time if I got out of jail and I was
just another asshole on the street,
it would,
you know,
one of the things that keeps coming up
is you are longing for community.
And this is something that I've been
thinking about a lot lately because I
think one of the things that people are
constantly searching for in this world
is happiness,
right?
So one thing that people don't have that
they wish they had that comes up over
and over again.
It's a reoccurring theme and one of the
things that's also a big part of this
life that we are all are living right
now is this very recent disconnect
between our neighbors,
our friends,
by commuting to work and it's being
stuck in this stuffy environment where
you can express yourself normally and
this is the majority of your life,
the majority of your time.
And then we wonder why we're sad and we
don't spend enough time together with
friends.
Here's,
here's when you aren't sad.
When you're having fun with your friends
because that's what human beings are
meant to do.
There's some,
they're meant to work together to do
something together like something
meaningful core of your healing.
It's meant we're meant to have community
or meant to have friends and we're meant
to laugh.
We'll meant to share experiences were
meant to care for each other and when
that's not happening in your life,
you feel like shit.
What you're doing is spreading the
fingers of your community.
You're spreading the branches of your
community by,
by expressing yourself and helping other
people,
by expressing yourself and inspiring
other people by sending your message out
there.
This is a type of community for people
that are longing for community.
You're connecting with people,
people that are longing to feel a
connection.
And this is,
this is something that's missing.
Is this something that's greatly missing
in our society?
And you,
you understand it more than most because
your time that they forced you to be
separate from community that they did.
They gave you the opposite of community.
If you communicated,
they beat you up,
they gave you the opposite of the
community.
They locked you in a cage,
didn't let you mingle with other people,
and then the people that were around
you,
you didn't want to mingle with them.
Horrific people that are just the worst
examples of a life gone wrong and you're
surrounded with them.
You still emerged.
And that just,
that alone gives people hope.
And that hope is something that
everybody needs is a good person on
death row.
To the point that,
uh,
a man named Tom Lowenstein wanted to
write a book about me and I turned them
on to water oh,
Grad,
who's still sitting on death row.
And I asked them to write the book about
Walter.
And then CNN death row stories wanted to
me and have Susan's
friend and narrate my story.
Two and a half years ago,
I told him again,
water still on death row,
man,
do for him.
Now what's Walter Store that Walter was?
Walter,
oh,
grab was convicted of killing a little
girl and put her in a TV box,
but he didn't do it.
And he had the misfortune of having his
brother attacked in his house and nearly
murdered and being brought in for that
investigation.
And then simply asked by detective,
hey,
there's a girl killed on your street.
Did you know anything about it?
He goes,
yeah,
I know about it.
Next thing you know,
he's facing death row.
So a jury finds him not guilty,
but before the sabotage of one juror,
he ends up on death row.
When the SEC sabotage of one juror,
he voted not guilty.
And then he'd products out during the
vault.
Dare,
I lied,
I lied.
He's a,
he's guilty.
So they declare a mistrial.
Get the guy,
they called him on senior to come in and
say that now he confessed to him,
they have a second trial.
So they put all their on death row and I
meet him and everybody's abusing shit
out of him.
So
I did the unnatural thing.
I stood up for him for all the bullies
and I told the two men that were abusing
them if they put their hands on him
again,
I was going to get involved.
And I started helping Walter with his
lawyers.
And ever since I got out of prison,
I kept my word to stick by them and
fight for him.
So I gave up opportunities,
could have changed my life.
And now death row stories is back and
they're going to do my story.
And Walter is still on death row right
now.
Yeah.
And he's innocent.
And what can be done to help walter
contact Tom Wolfe and ask him why the
innocence projects and the and integrity
units won't take up his case.
There's no evidence.
And uh,
it was clearly,
I mean when you see the show on a death
row stories,
it's just laid out so clear.
I was a little disappointed they didn't
mention me that I turned them on to
Walter Myself.
Selfless sac was overlooked but that was
just my ego.
But I always am like that and that's
what I love.
I know that they were despicable joe and
the acts that a lot of men did word
spectacle,
but if I let that stop me from loving
any of them than I was going to be
nothing.
So yeah,
a lot of them were really messed up man.
But the ones that needed it,
I set aside everything and still cared
about men.
So spell out Walter's name for
[inaudible],
g R.
O D.
O.
Grodd Walter.
Oh Greg was convicted of putting a
little girl in a box and Philadelphia,
we need to get Kim Kardashian on the
case.
Yeah man.
Cause this is she's,
she's getting people released from
prison.
Kim,
if you want to get someone a,
uh,
a pardon.
It's Walter.
This man has suffered enormously.
People prison.
Is he in?
He's in Greene County,
Super Maxim and pence,
Pennsylvania.
I fought for my other friend Walt,
Ernie Simmons.
He got out here the trials of Walter Al
Grod,
shocking murder,
so-called confessions and notorious
snitch to send a man to death row.
Tom Lowenstein came to me while I was
still on death row in 2002 and he said,
nick,
my God,
your story,
I want to write a book about you.
And I said,
you,
that's brilliant.
But how about the guy sitting next to
me?
It doesn't have lawyers or DNA or
anybody to help him.
How about helping him?
He goes,
are you crazy?
You're given up an opportunity.
I said,
dude,
it ain't like that.
I love this man.
He has no lawyers like I do.
So that's the pattern.
That's who I am.
So I didn't take credit for it,
but I really did try to help another man
because I felt like I would be so
disappointing if I just took and took
and took for myself
and you know,
I'm actually grateful I didn't go on
your podcast two years ago.
I was a homeless person without a family
and now I got the two amazing girls,
Sara and Bethany and my wife Laura.
These two English girls get the dream
life change.
They get to move from Somerset,
England out here to Oregon and my little
girl gets on a yellow school bus show.
She goes the bus every day.
She's in school.
They,
they like,
I'm in the community.
I got all these wonderful friends up in
Oregon,
like Donnie Hobbs and these guys that
are my personal friends now.
I built my community again,
like I got all these cool people up
there that love me.
I,
my wife's right now in Salem with her
friend carly,
and they're opening up a new shop up
there and all this stuff.
So I really did it despite not having
anything.
I did exactly what you said.
I went and overcame the debt probation
and found community and built my tribe.
Look,
I know a lot of people s a struggle to
have people in their life that aren't
causing conflict.
It's you is allowing it,
man,
go out and find new people to be around.
Cause a lot of people want you if you're
a nice person.
It's just hard for me
people to find those people sometimes
and that's where they lose hope.
You know,
people that don't and one of the things
they did it,
they don't know where to get started,
right?
They don't know how to,
how to get their life going,
how to get moving,
how to feel good,
how to get success.
There's so many different things.
And um,
to those people I say just do something.
The more things you do,
the more things you can do.
Do something,
do anything.
Whether it's commit to walking around
the block 10 times a night with whether
it's a committing to writing your life
story
and you knew it stops a lot of people is
their self imagery.
Right?
[inaudible] I,
I was convicted of a rape and murder,
and in everyone's eyes,
I was a psychologically deranged person.
I had to live with that stigma everyday.
Right?
Then when I got out,
everybody thought I must be crazy as
fuck because I spent 8,057 days in
solitary confinement being tortured.
So there's no way I could be saying,
right,
right.
Their perspective had no effect on me
because by that time I'd given myself
enough education to know the difference
between what was done to me and who I
am.
And this is the problem with a lot of
people.
They fail to stop doing this thing where
I am this or I am that and this is the
problem.
So I really have never cared about the
perspective of anyone in the negative
except for when they got it wrong,
from my intent to do good with them.
And then it just became a battle of my
own ego.
So I realized that the truth is,
as long as I know I'm doing right and
I'm doing good,
it isn't going to matter about their
perspective because the same person who
thought I was a rapist,
scumbag murderer now thinks I'm one of
the most eloquent speakers they met in
their life.
Their perspective about me changed,
but mine surely shouldn't,
but it did.
And that's what a lot of people suffer
from.
They let that negative comment make them
feel like they have to overcome it or
have to live with it.
And I'll tell you what,
Joe,
I really never expected this,
but for the first time in my life from
conducting an interview throughout the
whole process,
I've been reevaluating who I am and what
I'm saying.
It's like a fucking slap in the face,
man.
Like I came in here,
the drag world with my emotions,
carrying him on my sleeves and all the
stress.
I haven't slept well for days.
I haven't taken care of us.
That's bullshit.
I didn't do well in articulating and you
gave me a wake up call that I have never
had before.
In any experience,
you can go back and look through the
history of the many experiences of ahead
of interviews and I've done some
outstanding ones.
I've never had a personal experience
where throughout the course of speaking
of another man,
I started to reevaluate everything I
held firmly to,
and I promise you I'm going to go and
think a whole lot about this and get my
shit together because I do owe it to
allow to people to be one bad ass
motherfucker with a hell of a message to
yourself.
Damn straight,
man.
I'm going to do that.
I really am an so if you want me to come
and speak before your corporate
functions,
if we're a high school or university,
I do that better than anyone.
In fact,
I'm fine.
One of the finest speakers on the
planet,
and I learned it because I watched Bruce
springsteen.
You remember that speech he gave at the
Oscars for Philadelphia?
No,
I never watched the Oscars.
Dude,
get that up.
My God.
Bruce springsteen is one of the finest
speakers.
No,
but just the image.
But dude gave one of the most profound
speeches I ever waste.
Beautiful Girl.
He made the nexus point between music
and imagery.
So poignant that I was blown away by it.
So much so that when we made the
documentary fear of 13,
that's all I'd kept imagining when I
spoke was the imagery we would be
lended.
And I love the fact that I worked very
hard to bring the whole audience into my
cell one time to spend with me my story
in a way that no one ever did before and
I fucking rocked it.
That's awesome.
Yeah,
I liked that.
I liked the fact that I know I have
talent in that field.
I don't want to boast,
but I have a gift and it King uh,
light years ahead of me.
When I watched,
I had 400 students in ealing enraptured
at a conference.
My friend at educator named Emma Dopson
set this whole thing up.
So go there,
you could hear a pin drop because all
along,
somewhere along the way,
an energy clicks in and I can hold a
room in palm of my hand.
I've had some amazing experiences with
it.
I don't know how to stay at,
but that cult of personality lure of
being on the stage and talking to people
is powerful man.
And I can see why Tony Robbins and
everybody gets up in nine eight Dudette
I'm not a life coach.
I can't coach no one's life.
But I can tell you about your life and
ma in ways that would make you really
invigorated to want to make a better
life for yourself,
but no one could truly be your life
coach.
You got to do that shit yourself.
And I love it.
I love it that I understood those
moments because one of the coolest
things was I used to go to the globe
theater.
Anybody did understand Shakespeare
understands the globe.
Theater is the center of the world for
Shakespeare.
They would perform titus andronicus and
then after which Cleopatra would come
out on stage and introduced me to the
Carl.
Now I had eight minutes,
10 minutes tops to do this thing and in
eight to 10 minutes I had a crowd who
had been spanning for three hours long
play crying,
putting money in a bucket for what I
said to them and did it flawlessly every
time.
And I did it for a whole summer in
London.
It was the most amazing experience to
stand there and look out over this vista
of London after you did this amazing
thing where people never expect that you
and you are nothing to do with the
theater.
You are just a human rights charity
chosen by the theater to come out and
speak.
And I,
I realized that that moment I had a
gift.
If I could get people who have been
standing for three hours watching a play
to have wet tears in her eyes,
putting money,
shoving it into a bucket for me than I
knew I had some ability to finally
speak.
I was no longer an aphasia effected,
destroyed,
distorted mine,
addled by drugs and used beyond belief
to distortions of like I was so screwed
up to come back to do that.
I knew I was,
do you know I wrote this whole book in
only three days.
Wow.
200 and I have a gift Joe.
Like seriously,
like I wrote and I have witnesses.
I wrote the whole book in two and a half
days man.
Cause it was in me.
This story monsters med mum was so
powerful that when I met Laura,
my wife,
I told her,
I said,
you know what?
I'm a finally do it man.
I'm gonna get this out.
And it,
it just came out for two and a half
days.
I barely slept,
ate,
did anything.
All I did was make love to my wife on a
break or right.
And I mean poured it out and I poured
out the whole book and I've realized
that was needed to move on.
And it's,
it's the best book I ever wrote my life.
And I'm so proud that it's my last one
because I don't have to worry about no
more stories.
I did the thing that was great.
All right,
so this one changed.
This is really fear of 13 my countdown
to execution,
it went through hell.
It got canceled.
It's now fear of 13 then I wrote the
kindness approach.
I did one called my journey through her
eyes.
I didn't bring a copy as you,
wait a minute.
Do you not want to write?
Like why?
Why do you say that?
I hope it doesn't because I crafted my
series of books that create and
captivate my whole entire message.
Right?
And I want to leave it pure.
I don't want to then go on and make up a
falsifications of things that didn't
happen.
So all these are nonfiction.
All these are nonfiction.
All these events are true and points in
my life and I think that's the best
thing to do.
Stay true to who I am.
I was going to tell one story called,
that's enough for me as a fictionalized
writer just to show everybody my talent
because people in the past that said,
wow,
you can write anything.
So I was going to do that,
but I've held back because I thought I
want to leave it.
Cool.
I want to leave it like,
this is my series of work.
My work is I wrote to prison books and I
wrote two books that will guide people
in life,
how not to be screwed up or bitter.
And I want to leave that as my message.
I want to go and do other things,
but those are my books and I'm proud of
the work I did.
I got it out of my system.
I'm a published author.
I can go down in history.
Is that right?
I'm cool with that.
I don't really want to then push it and
think that I can then lower people into
reading more works than I'd can try
because that's not really fair to them.
Do you know what I mean?
I,
I want to keep it that way.
I think that's one of the things I want
to try and stay true to.
Now,
speaking as my love now,
negative,
someone wants to hire you to speak,
where would they go?
Nick Harris.
Dot Org.
So it's really simple.
Um,
everyone on the podcast can easily find
me on the other social medias.
But I have,
like I said,
my really close friends,
Adam,
uh,
Callahan and his wife just had a baby so
that everyone in my website,
[inaudible] dot org and a lot of people
can reach me for functions like that.
But I really love the fact that I have a
chance to also with this my vs.
Dot com to go ahead and go into schools.
And there's a really cool thing,
you know,
this x generation times three men,
they're like so computer savvy,
right?
So much so that you actually are
starting a trend.
There's no longer 15 minutes of fame.
There's the five second video clip of
fame now and has been reduced.
It's just like everything's five
seconds,
you know what I mean?
It's no longer,
so everything in the education field is
coming to us faster and faster.
So we need to use the analytics of
something like my verse to go ahead and
get a child to figure out who they can
go and be in their careers and then
follow that correct path.
You can't just throw it against the wall
anymore,
Joe.
You have to really work hard to get
children to feel good about being a taxi
driver,
a painter.
You know,
it's not no shame to be a a person who
goes out and does a simple manual job,
if that makes you happy as a human
being,
you should be able to do that without
the stigma,
right?
But the school's not going to tell you
that.
You know,
they're going to tell you you could be
anything,
but why wouldn't you want to find out
what would make you happy in life and be
that right?
That makes sense to me.
So not going to learn that from school.
Now learn that from people,
from people,
and you'll learn that from,
from online more than anything today.
And that's why I want to be involved in
the educational field.
I think that's my greatest gift of
someone who went to prison,
who hadn't ever read a book,
who accomplished the things that he did.
Then can share how the purpose of my
education was.
So did I,
was able to process life enough to
handle it.
To give myself enough separation to
realize who I was as a human being is
not the sum total of my misery and that
I could then help others structured
their lives through politeness to go and
get a good education.
And I love that fact that I worked so
hard through all these different things
to not lose that message.
Men.
And it really does work for a lot of
young people.
They find that there's self restrict,
uh,
respect really does grow when someone
gives them just a small little bit of a
break.
Man,
they're so honest.
I love,
I love it.
I'll never tire of it in that one regard
because I've touched so many young
people's lives.
Man.
That's beautiful.
That's a great message.
And uh,
thanks for being here man.
I really appreciate it.
I'm glad we did this.
Yeah,
me too.
I really do.
Can I give a quick shot at this?
So I got some good friends of mine.
I'd,
I really messed up on Alex Ortiz and uh,
I like these young dudes,
these fighters joke,
they're all mad about you.
And I like it.
What do you think about the Bella tour
anyway?
I love it.
Yeah,
we'll need more.
We need more organizations like that,
but I think Bella tours doing a great
job.
Yeah.
Jesse Casa Kosky.
He's gonna fight this Mofo bear.
And I like the fact that his father
teaches that coon Tao with that prison
style of martial arts.
I don't know what that is.
Oh,
well it's the old style.
It's like,
um,
it isn't like the martial arts that most
people would know because it's derived
from the Filipino prison systems.
It's like really pure solves of quick
attacks and stuff like that.
So as soon as in the boxing,
but now I like it that like dudes,
I've got Mike Campbell and all these
guys have been really supportive to me
and everyone,
like I said,
that knew I was coming on here.
I just want to tell them if I forgot who
you are.
Thank you all for being so supportive.
And I really want to say thank you to my
wife for being so therefore me lately,
and I'm really grateful that we've
learned in this wonderful lesson that I
might belong to you,
sweetheart,
but I also have some good left to do and
I'm gonna try and do both well,
and I'm very grateful to everyone.
Listen,
especially to you,
Mister broken.
You're really nice young man.
Thanks man.
I'm grateful to you as well.
Now I'd mean that Joe and I know you're
going to do,
he said on a nice young man like you're
my grandma.
You're a nice young man.
A even better.
I'm your sexy granddad.
Give me some love,
boy.
Thank you.
Go and have a good day.
Or we want to love your round the world
by,
by Martin Mooc.
How man.
Bye Bye.
Bye Bye everybody.