Oh, I won't. That means we're on. So I'm,
I'm multitasking Greg Proops that's
what kind of podcast or I am.
I love that monkey noise though.
Cause that to me alerts me to
many things are happening at once.
The jungle is full of activity.
That's how you got to look at it.
You really have to look at it that way.
It's like you got to make a positive out
of it. Always. The natives are restless,
you know, we think it's cute. But in
reality if you heard that fucking noise,
he'd be terrified.
If you're out there in the jungle and
you hear it might be some mother fucker
ready to jump on you bite your
dick or it's me. That's creepy.
Right before you buy it is creepy. If it
was just you in the woods, I'd be like,
oh, what's up dude? Yeah,
that'd be the end of it. If
it was a monkey in the woods,
man, he'd be fighting for your
fucking life. Monkeys are terrifying.
And I was in Barbados once and
they have green monkeys. Yes.
To call it green monkey. Ja,
they threw shit. You know,
my wife and I were like walking through
the parking lot of the hotel and all of
a sudden a giant branch falls
next to us and I'm like, really?
And you look up and they're
like, yeah, fuck you.
I know you don't care how much
you, they're kind of Douchey. Yeah.
They killed a guy in India recently,
a mayor of a town. It was a,
I don't know what happened, but he got
swarmed by monkeys and they killed him.
Like that can happen. And in Gibraltar,
the apes are attacking people to Christ.
Greg Proops. You know, it's like
that movie James Franco was riot man.
James Franco's always right.
Well the gym,
so I could be wrong about just James
Franco was always right. Uh, you could,
how about you fucking make James
Franco's are always right.com. Thank.
Go to squarespace.com make your own
website for it. Set up an online store.
Started selling. James Franco
was always right. Tee shirts.
It's no disrespect to James Franco.
This is not parody.
This is just saying that this is not a
parody. We're not being assholes here.
We like you. I just, you know that
fucking movie man, while he was right,
the apes are taking over. I watched
the staying on, uh, uh, I don't know.
I think it was PBS where they,
they was showing baboons and Africa.
People were just simply tried
to go to the supermarket,
but baboons new now gotten hip to the
jive that there was food to be had at the
parking lot and they were just rolling
people for their bags of groceries,
kicking their ass and take a minute to
think scarier than about them because
they're like a tiger mixed with a
monkey or whatever. Horrible teeth.
They'll jump on you.
They fight in packs and they organized
their like highly intelligent dogs.
Like they get up on too and like,
it's just mortifying.
You're watching like a lady
with two grocery bags and
about the and just fucking,
and you're like, I would, I
would never stop screaming.
And that's what it feels like to go
to John's instead of Vaughn's. Yeah.
Been there. [inaudible] they don't
have, we can't afford an age remorse.
Like, oh, they have no problem
killing you mean anything to them?
Like our idea of like what's
fair and what's not fair,
what we expect and don't expect. It's
thrown out the window with wild animals,
especially wild animals
that get too used to people.
That's why they have a real problem
with like bears that live in and start
tacking the garbage. Then they, that
becomes a source of food. Like period.
They don't ever quit and then they run
into people and all kinds of crazy shit
can happen,
especially if they have kids.
It's not that Boone morality that him to
just informs everything in nature that
I protest most vehemently. Very
smart to God. Three Smart Fox.
How about the meatball? The bear was
it who was going into houses? Uh,
and like he found me. Paul's in the
freezer. They're like our key in me.
Paulson was just like eating
them and sitting in the hot
tub and shit. Holy Shit.
No.
People come home and find bears on their
couch watching TV and stuff with their
weed. You know, like there's really, it's
like you say though, they, they don't,
it's a pattern to them. You know
what I mean? They know Tuesday,
Tuesday night there's going to be pizzas.
I'm coming down and I'm
meeting them or not.
It doesn't even matter if it's Tuesday,
it's,
they're going to keep checking your
house over and over and over again.
If they find out that there was garbage
there, once it becomes a source of food,
right.
And they have to shoot him,
it gets real or they have to take on and
bring them to zoos. Squares my soccer.
Worse commercial ever, but
yet the best, uh, anyway,
that's squarespace.com is an
awesome place to build a website.
Really is very bad ass, easy
design. Ah, you could try it
out. If you don't like it,
you just tell them to go fuck themselves.
You don't even have to give
your credit card information.
Once you decide you like it, you say, Hey,
I can make a bad ass
fucking website on my own.
Then you enter in your credit
card information. It's super
easy to do. You can, um,
have it set up so that
it goes live as a store.
You can make your own store like super
easy. You can make websites super easy.
It's, it used to be like a very
difficult task to make a website,
but it's not anymore.
Uh,
so go to squarespace.com
and check that shit out.
Actually turned my mom onto it because
she wanted to make a website for her
flower company on this side. Like
she just, you know, she's retired,
but she has like the,
you know,
once in a while she'll do this flower
arrangement thing and I told her to go
here and she's actually making one
and it seems pretty easy for her.
So that's crazy.
Yeah. Oh, go ahead and please,
I was going to ask the name of your
mother's flower company and flat bolt. Oh,
nice.
So Mary and me,
my mom and my ex fiance's mom and
they have a flower company together.
Wow. They're going to get, they're
going to get offers now. I know
people want to go judge squad squad roses.
What town do they live in?
Tell Him Jesus Christ. Columbus, Ohio,
a murder throwing your mother did in
Columbus, Ohio, every couple of weeks.
But only two women who run a small
florist shop can solve this crime.
Someone climbed over this Rose Bush.
This rose was firstly snapped.
I told my trainer to use
squarespace.com keeps saying like,
I need her website or need to get
a website built. I'm like, bitch,
go to squarespace.com.
That's an easy thing to say to people
that would say they need a website.
Like just do it. You can do it
yourself is super easy. Yeah.
Yeah. So really like to say
that to something that you,
this is for the first time, like ever
and the Internet history, uh, use the co,
the offer code Joe and the number
10 for the month of October,
and you'll get 10% off your
first purchase on new accounts,
including monthly and actual plans.
And we're also block brought to you by
law to you today by hulu.com now with
Hulu plus. This is our first,
uh, Hulu, uh, commercial.
Apparently Hulu is pretty fucking bad
ass. I've heard about it for years. Um,
people, uh, you know, watch
different shows on it.
I never exactly knew what it did though,
until uh,
I started paying attention recently and
lets you watch thousands of hit shows
you can, you have Hulu plus, right?
Yeah, I have it on my Xbox. Do
you use it? Uh, you know, I, I,
I've had it for a while and it's one of
the things I always forget that I have
and because it's not that expensive. So
like when you pay for it, you're like,
it's one of those, Oh, I forgot
I, I subscribed to this. Oh,
I should watch it sometime. But
when I do, I usually just watch.
I should let a family guys,
when I just want to sit there and watch a,
I have family. I'm really
stupid. I just like, you know,
South Park family guy and
a couple other things.
When you get Outta here, you don't
want no thinking. Yeah. I don't know.
I don't understand that.
You're not watching the four,
the three tenors or whatever it is,
or Celtic woman ever.
Sarah Brightman what are those things?
Those are all the PBSC DVDs they offer.
When you flipped by,
you know,
the PBS channels where people go to the
Cerritos Arts Center to see a thing,
right. It's always the, it's
always a classical music.
There's some group with four good looking
dudes and they're called Il something.
Someone will write you, I'm
sure if you, uh, and then, uh,
the Celtic woman has like five hot looking
Irish girls who wear long dresses and
they go, Yep, Yep. And
you know, single Celtic.
And then there's Sarah Brightman who was
Andrew Lloyd Webber's a wife years ago.
Does this like mystical, which
deal? But in theaters, you know,
so like it's for regular people, it's
not for witches. Wow. And you know,
she hung the moon comes
up and shit and I'm like,
Sarah Brightman after midnight
or whatever. And it's like,
she was a musical comedy star basically.
He found the shtick doing like kind of
Demi Golf music for people who don't
really like classical. You know what
I mean? It's like you're not smooth.
Jazz is for people who
don't actually liked jazz,
they just want something in the
background and it's got a saxophone in it.
Then went to sedate them. You
know, like they don't want to fuck,
they don't want jazz.
They didn't wanna listen to Charlie
Parker who still have a heart attack.
The smooth jazz can push you to accelerate
into traffic as new jobs every day.
It will suck the zest out of life.
Yeah.
When you hear him smooth jazz version
of like a Michael Jackson Song from 1978
[inaudible] you'll be like, this isn't
making it happen as much as it might.
How often do people get to
listen to music at work?
I think if they let you have the radio on,
uh,
it's probably one of those commercial,
a crappy stations or top 40 shit where
they can guarantee no one's going to say
something screwy. Or if everyone
agrees and everyone's the same age,
I'm guessing like an oldies station
like k or if there's something to,
it was just going to be sunny
and share all day or whatever.
When I went back anyway,
they had a CD,
it
was like an hour long
and it just repeated.
I hate for like six months at a time would
get, oh we get a new CD and then they,
we're like, oh, on this top,
something that lives inside me like an
Armadillo and is waiting to burst out the
music at the lax airport in every single
restaurant there are bar hard rock in
the morning and stuff like
journey and shit. And I mean,
when I say hard rock on me and
like classic, you know, I mean,
can we take it down a notch?
And then Christmas carols start,
sometimes the Christmas was killed.
Channel come on accidentally at lax and
just be on for a while and you're like,
what the fuck? And they'll
go, it's on a computer or
whatever. And you're like, wow,
that's kind of unacceptable
since we're trapped,
it's kind of fucked up to
play something that's sucks.
Like if you walked in and
there's some thrash metal,
yeah,
I would be like, oh, come on
Dick. Right. This is a donut shop.
But if I went to a skateboard shop
and it was like 8:00 PM would accept,
we go to Abercrombie and Fitch and he,
we walk in there and it's so loud and
you just want to look at sweaters or
something and it's like when they hit
you with that fucking stinky, the air,
what kind of weirdness
that where they,
they don't accept the way reality smells.
They must spray some chemicals in your
face that you know are not good for you
and pumps shitty music in your ears
that really, really gay thoughts.
It's fucking shaving down hairless
dude's all sleek and slim and I'm in love
with this but on Hulu you can,
there's this show called Chicago fire
and I'm in love with this girl right here
and she just started following me on
Twitter. Her name's Laura and German.
Laura German. That has nothing to
do. We're just talking about, yeah,
Hulu because he didn't see her stalker
and a that shows on who? The CDC.
That's cool. If you want to
watch the show with her though,
because you can go back a season and
you could watch the whole season,
like the first season and there
is limited commercials on it,
but I think it's only seven 99.
Yeah,
it's seven, seven, nine nine a month.
You could stream as many TV shows and
movies you want whenever you want. Um,
it's great way to, to access.
Also, they have new content too.
They have Hulu originals, originals,
Hulu originals are doing now.
The awesome starring Snl Seth Meyers and
a moon boy starring Chris O'Dowd from
bridesmaids.
So they're starting to do their own
content just like sorta like Netflix is
doing, which is pretty bad ass. I
love that people are doing that.
I love seeing this new progression.
You know,
I haven't watched that Netflix show with
Kevin Spacey, House of Wizard, his carts.
I heard it's fucking incredible. Yeah,
I keep hearing it's fucking incredible.
There was an English version. It was
really good. Now he's a bad motherfucker.
Anyway. Um, Hulu plus
go there, check it out.
Laura German by all kinds of shit.
She thinks the world of you, man.
Go to Hulu plus.com forward. Slash.
Rogen. Yeah. She's in love with and to
anyways. This is a good show. If you
like fires like I don't watch much.
You like fires. No Book of
matches. This show rules.
If you're inspired by the ancient
elements, it's, it's really cool.
I actually don't want to shows. I got
into this. It's good. It's like er,
but in fact about fires. What's
it called again? A Chicago fire.
Its second season right now. Just started.
It's Microstar. That's my buddy. Yeah,
it's a big guy right there.
He was on a show called hardball with me,
sweetheart of a guy who was in
Goodfellows gets A's in a thousand movie.
The bodyguard.
He played the guy that Kevin
Costner gotten the craziest
fight and the bodyguard
and super, Super Nice Guy. One of the
nicest guys I've ever met and hold on,
I was sitting there. Yeah, that's the guy
from sticking to the city right there.
You know the one guy that [inaudible] how
would you know Josh? You have a penis.
What's wrong with that statement?
Miss Charlotte Guy.
I liked Charlotte too. Yeah. Anyway,
go to Hulu Plus Hulu plus Ford.
Slash I mean that's,
I said, where is she? You
know, I dunno. Whatever. Free
trial. There's a free trial.
Hulu does Hulu plus.com
forward slash Rogen.
You can get an extended free trial
and they know that we sent to you.
So go to Hulu plus.com forward slash.
Rogen.
This is probably the most
disorganized commercial ever,
but I think we got a lot of solid
entertainment in there and that's what's
really important.
Um,
we were also brought to you by [inaudible]
dot com if you go to o n n I t use a
code name, Rogan, and you will save
10% off any and all supplements. Greg,
you need to go there and get you swollen.
Get yourself some kettlebells. Uh,
I'll have them brought to
you, man, I haven't sent to
you. You just say the word,
I'll hook you up.
It's how it's battle stations and
my arms battle station down Uga.
We sell all kinds of, uh,
strength and fitness equipment,
including kettle bells, battle ropes,
weight, vast, all that kind of shit.
And as I said,
you use the code name Rogan,
and you'll save 10% off any
and all supplements. That's it.
Boom. Done. Hit The music,
Brian.
Good Joe.
Well,
good experience Joe Rogan podcast.
My night all day.
Good. Google the Mowgli.
Greg Proops. Holla. Hey Baby.
What's going on brother? Uh, everything.
I can't even begin to stop it a camp
again now everything's going on,
Eh, it's, it's a nice day today.
I'm excited to be out here.
I don't get to woodland hills is,
can I say where we're broadcasting from?
Is it an undisclosed location? Undisclosed
location. But you fucked that up,
so wow.
You get real specific Tarzana
area and uh, so, uh, yeah,
no, it's nice to be on
earth with you, man.
It's nice to be on earth with you as well.
All rotating around the smartest man in
the world podcast. That's the one that,
that guy's name, the guy couldn't
get the name right. Yeah, no. Right.
It's a hard one man in the room. It's
difficult to remember. Yeah. The smartest
guy in the room. Yeah.
That one. Cause there was,
I think a documentary of that and Ron
that was called the smartest guys in the
room. Yeah. Yeah. You don't want to be
connected to that creepy shit. Now I down,
I watched that documentary. That
wasn't it again. Very strange. Yeah.
It only makes sense though, you
know, I don't understand finances,
but the corruption of finances
only makes sense to me.
So a movie like Enron or it turns out
the bunch of dudes just fucking robbed
everybody blind.
Yeah,
I guess that's what you rolling
brownouts they get crazy. Yeah.
They try to figure out more ways to make
money. But that's always the way it is.
If you allow people to make
the insane amounts of money.
And I'm not saying you shouldn't,
I'm not, I'm not, you know,
I'm not necessarily a
socialistic in any way,
but if you allow people to get
to that billion, trillion, that,
that fucking insane amount
of influence level. Woo.
That's slippery. That gets really
crazy. We'll look at the world. I mean,
that's what's going on right now. That's
why the government is closed and shit.
Exactly. It's why the government's
close. It's why there's war.
It's all these big groups
because as individuals,
because you imagine if
the world consisted,
is only individuals where there was only
like a few people on the planet and you
know, Russia was like, listen,
we're going to go into Afghanistan
and we're going to take your shit.
And Afghanistan was like one guy and he's
like, what are you talking about man?
And Russia was like one guy, like, why
are you here? Like what are you doing man?
You got your spot. I got my
spot. What the fuck's going on?
Because I want your spot too, man.
But because there's so many people,
then there becomes this weird diffusion
of responsibility where we can somehow
or another, even in this day and age still
justify all the crazy shit that we do.
You mean like sending bombs around the
world by remote control all that? Yeah,
absolutely. That's really
freaky. You know, there's,
there's some numbers you know,
that, uh, are very disputed about,
we were talking about on the podcast,
like some sources say that 98% of the
people that are killed are civilians and
then other people are saying,
well,
the reality is that the census
is there are not that good.
It's not that easy to tell how many
people were killed. They'll exaggerate.
There's a lot of lying going on.
There's a lot of, a lot of, um,
misinformation that comes back and forth
from both sides. But like either way,
even if it's not 98%, he, how about it?
Let's make it 2% 2% innocent.
It's pretty fucked up.
And the other 98%, what exactly
are they guilty of? You know,
what exactly are you doing where you
think it's okay to launch missiles through
the air? It's like some shit that
we don't exactly know. You know, we,
we assume they're really,
really bad guys.
We have to take off this earth because
they're involved in terror plots. Okay.
I believe that, you know, it's
possible that that could be going on.
It could be going on, but
shit, that's a crazy way to go.
And if a bunch of people are
near you, tough shit. Yeah.
I think for them it's a more
economical way than sending an army.
And it also plays to all the defense
contractors because kind of shit they have
to use for that's most high tech
and most expensive. And it can,
it's just like everything else in
life. It's like just how the, you know,
the early days of Samurai,
I didn't want to adopt the gun and
it was proved very costly. Like the,
we were always moving forward, especially
with weapons and these, it's inevitable.
Didn't you see Malala said to Obama
yesterday when you say that she said the
Predator drones are creating terrorism.
Yeah, I would imagine there were the,
our terror, the terror from
the sky, absolute terror.
There's many definitions of terror
and won a state operated terror.
And that's what that is.
Yeah. And it's, there's this,
that the idea that it's somehow or another
protecting us. I get that, you know,
I get that and I want to believe that.
I really do.
It's a huge violation of
the Geneva Convention.
If anyone cares about the
Geneva convention anymore,
it says explicitly you mustn't
kill innocent children. Yeah.
They're not trying to, I guess, you know,
I don't know what the fuck is really
going on. Obviously I'm not there,
but the idea of it as just
a complete objective person,
like looking at it from the outside,
it's so science fictiony it's so,
or William.
It's so weird.
It seems like something from a horror
movie like from like 20 years ago,
a horror movie about the future, but
it's just like the terminator, right?
I mean it's not happening here. Pinpoint,
but he could, shit, man, that's,
technology starts to evolve.
People are going to want revenge for
things that have been done to their
communities and that's
where it gets fucking crazy.
They're actually talking about launching
blimps and to the air to protect from
missile attacks.
Oh God.
Like World War One when they'd put a
bunch of blimps up to fog the Yankees.
Christ. Yeah. Wow. You hear all
this crazy talk and you're like,
Jesus Christ. How about everybody
just work this shit out?
Do people really want to take those kinds
of risks and kill that many people and
isn't it possible you guys can just settle
the fuck down and everybody just talk
things through? Mm. Not Currently,
but it might happen one day.
Right. There's been, uh,
some years of peace in the last 500 years.
What about a couple of 25 30 years?
I don't know if there really has been,
have there ever in the world,
not in the world.
I've mean,
I've read statistics like
that and different magazines
where they'll say like in
the last 500 years there's
been cumulative 20 something.
I don't know how they pieced
together the years of peace within.
That means one whole year in a row or
with a part of a year and two weeks here
and two weeks there.
It doesn't seem like there's been
peace ever since I've been alive. Yeah.
I don't think there's ever been piece.
If you, you're thinking about worldwide.
I grew up with Vietnam. Yeah. I mean,
even if you just kind of America
because after Vietnam then, well, yeah,
worldwide it was V it never stops.
Well,
there's always been some creepy shit
going on. Even when we weren't at war.
I mean,
and we learned about the Oliver North
trial and the Sandinistas in Nicaragua and
all that shit back when Reagan was in
office and we didn't really know what was
going on until that was coming out. Yeah,
and also there we were involved you,
we were involved
in all sorts of military shit.
Even when we weren't officially at war.
Like though I'm getting pain and they
gotta get paid and they got to get paid
off. That was a drug. Drugs
and money. Drugs too, for sure.
And most likely drugs right now.
And people don't want to admit that,
but it is so obvious.
It's ridiculous.
They have poppy fields everywhere.
They increased the amount
of heroin they grow,
the u s invaded and increase that.
Yeah,
I mean I get it. I'm not saying you
shouldn't make money selling heroin.
Wasn't it the same thing in Vietnam
with the Golden Triangle though? Yes.
Basically it her one profit making
organism. No one wants to believe that.
And that's a problem.
The problem is that a lot of people
are averse to disturbing information.
They don't want to believe it.
They don't want to believe that at
the highest levels of government.
Some of them must be selling some shit.
If you the government and you knew like
it's almost like a public safety thing
to have the government sell in the coke
and them being the big dealers rather
than some crazy guy, at least
the government, you know,
they probably have some fucking rules
as to how they're going to deal with a,
their competitors and how they're
going to handle things. I wonder,
I mean it's,
well that brings me to the metal,
the medical marijuana question because
having just been in Canadia and and Jan
van and a Washington,
you know,
on the one hand I'm all for
them being able to sell pot,
but on the other hand you're getting
the government involved and that, oh,
it's a little frightening to me.
Unless you can get the government
high and then get them involved,
then it would work out.
That really is the only hope.
I know that sounds so stupid,
but the only hope for this culture that
we have right now is that people get
high and take another look and go,
wait a minute, what are we doing?
Get. I somehow get get high through
yoga if you don't want to smoke weed,
but if you do want to smoke weed,
the best thing to do is to smoke weed.
Don't fuck around. Dive right in and don't
be a bitch. Take a look at this thing.
This thing is crazy.
This is a crazy,
crazy world that doesn't make any sense
to anybody and no one stops and goes,
hold up.
Why do we keep doing it this way?
Why are we keep doing this?
Why are we keep doing the same shit?
It's been fucking up our ancestors.
Why? What do we deal with in detail?
I don't want to kill you. You don't need
to kill me. Let's talk this man shit out.
That's the thing.
I've never had any anything against any
of the countries we've been at war with
in my entire lifetime at
never thought to myself,
God dammit fucking Iraq.
What was, you know,
it never really affected us personally.
No.
Except people who lost friends
and loved ones of course.
And that will actually went over
there. But yeah, it was too easy.
It's too easy starting these things.
I mean stunning them.
You know what's too easy
when you don't feel anything,
you know when you're over
here, we don't, it's,
it's a human being as used to accepting
the risks and rewards in its own
environment. The other shit outside
your environment is just so fake.
It's so abstract. It's so hard to wrap
your head around the Great Wall of China.
There's people on the Great Wall of China,
right?
And they're walking around and what,
what are you talking about?
Like that's going on right now on the
other part of the world. It doesn't seem,
I don't feel that here.
So when bombs are dropping in Afghanistan
and Iraq war in Pakistan through
drones,
it feels like nothing over here.
It feels just like someone
walking the Great Wall of China.
If we're too detached, we don't,
we're not getting the impact.
If we were in the community,
would see the fear and talk to him.
They were terrified and talk to people,
lost loved ones because these bad guys
are camping out in the same town as you.
It's terrifying. Terrifying
Shit. I think we are,
we're just so far away from it.
We're getting the information,
but we're so far away. It
just doesn't seem real. Now.
There's a huge disconnect and I think
in the public discourse and even bigger
disconnect because of that,
I think people have it feelings and
people have emotions so people know what's
going on. But I think that that,
that emotional disconnect as a,
as a huge Malays that's gotten worse,
I think in the last few years.
I think you're right.
I think the economic pressure on top of
it and the disconnection and the fact
that it's become clear that the
really, really wealthy, you know,
it's going to be this way.
They're not really willing to budge
on it for the moment. And uh, yeah.
And there's only one way to stop that.
You have to put a cap on how
much money someone can have.
And that just doesn't seem right
either. Well, no, we can't do that.
That's like saying you have to
have all the guns back tomorrow.
That's not going to happen either.
Yeah, that's it. That's it.
That's even less possibly
out because you know,
I think it would be easier almost to put
a cap on how much money you can make as
long as it was just a preposterous cap.
I'm not even,
I'm not even adverse
to people making money.
I would simply like them to pay their
fair share of the fucking, you know,
rent on that raggedy
motherfucker that's so big to me.
I really wished that I
trusted where it all went,
but I think it's very
important to me to pay up.
Like there was a time when I was a kid,
why didn't pay taxes for like shit,
it was like a year or something like
that. Yeah. I didn't pay taxes for you.
I was just broke.
It was just too broke.
And then when I got some money then
I've got an account and paid all my back
taxes. I just was, I was barely
getting by as a comedian.
But I felt like such a loser. I felt
like, like when I wasn't paying my taxes,
I felt like a scrounge. I felt like
if you in the principle of taxes,
I'm not saying that they go to the right
use and I'm not saying that I agree
with it, but with with its
decisions that our government makes.
But I think that I've,
I very much agree with the idea of
everyone contributing to the community.
And I think that if it
was managed really nicely,
if it was a really like healthy
police force filled with nice,
who are
just trying to help out. And the same
thing with governors, the governors,
if they were really
healthy and nice people,
we're just trying to really expand
the community and not be influenced by
special interest groups that want them
to allow certain poisons to be stored in
her holes in the ground and shit.
If they weren't influenced by that,
then I would feel even better about it.
I would really be happy about my
contribution to our community.
I think it's super important to pay taxes
on turning you down to that, you know?
No, I'm fine with, did you turn yourself
down? I think I did. I think it is too,
but I think it's like you said,
there's just too much coopting going
on in the system. And uh, I mean,
well it's too big. The, the,
the problem I have is that the richest
people want to keep talking about John
and government and stopping government
because governments evil cause
governments this big boondoggle
that people are sponging off of,
but they're the ones sponging off
of it and then they don't give any,
they don't pay any taxes because they
avoid it and you think, well fuck you.
You're not giving in and
you're not helping out on
the other end and you want to
take away poor people's allotments and
poor people aren't taking all the money
away. Like if everybody that was a
giant corporation paid their taxes,
there'd be plenty of money
floating around. Yeah.
But the problem is it's not
just how much money comes in.
The real problem then becomes what happens
with that money. Who's handling this?
Who's, who's setting up organizations?
Yeah, honey. Exactly. I mean,
that's where our real problem gets what,
$600 billion a year or something.
Oh Shit. They just go, I'll
take that pitch. Yeah. They
get the right thing. Yeah.
They just backhand us and then us
getting across the floor on her ass,
try to start a little health care and
everybody has a fucking heart attack all
up in this place. I am so ignorant
when it comes to this Obama care thing.
I tried to pay attention to it
and I tried to read up on it,
but my add kicked in hard.
Yeah. It's perplexing. It's,
there's two issues. One, the one that's
really weird is that it's already a law.
Yes. Correct. Okay. So the
Supreme Court, so what the fuck,
what are these guys doing? Like how
can you like resist a law? Well,
and that's not the way to resist a law.
That sounds like you think that
your ideas are more important. Well,
let me give you a, uh, a bad analogy.
And the 1870s after the civil war,
that was a big election between
Tilden and Hayes. And, uh,
it got thrown like the Gore Bush one,
right? It was a lot of chick cannery,
a lot of jiggery pokery and a lot of vote
fucking rolling and dad people on the
rolls and shit. And rather than
throw it to the Supreme Court,
they put a three man panel together
who put it down in Hayes favor. Well,
children was more of a
reformer in Hayes wasn't.
And so Jim crow was allowed to
flourish after his administration.
Jim Crow was against the law of the land
because those laws had been put in the
constitution.
Even black men got the right to vote that
they were no longer property when they
were no longer slaves. All of those
things are laws. So it's like, well,
they did it anyway.
They made bathroom segregated and
restaurant segregated on the country
segregated. And they just fucking
did it. And like right now,
they don't want the affordable healthcare
act. They don't want whatever Obama,
they're unhappy with
whatever the agenda is.
They're simply stopping
it because they can, uh,
constituted not constitutionally that,
you know, organizationally within the,
the rules of order, they're
allowed to pull this shit. And uh,
I think it's the same thing.
There was no point it ruined the
country then that Jim crow got in.
Cause if they'd kept it
the way it was supposed to,
there was lots of black congress people
after the civil war in the south and
they were all republicans cause
that was the party of abolition.
And then that turned,
and so they that weren't having that after
there was a dozen of them, looks like,
let's not have that anymore.
She had many black men speaking
their mind from Alabama. And so they,
uh, you know, went back to
miscegenation laws, Jim Crow woman.
And I feel like this is the same
thing in a very poor metaphorical way.
Like the Trayvon Martin case was a
case of a person standing their ground.
And you know,
like those laws,
those laws are an extension of the
slave patrols when you didn't want black
people wandering around at night
and they simply weren't allowed to.
And men gathered and rode
around and fucking rounded
them up and shit like that.
That's where those laws came from.
If it's from the same time period after
the civil war and during the civil war,
before the civil war, the ancient ancient
law, then it's a, it's as it's as,
it's as old fashioned as white guys
having a fucking whiskey after work, uh,
on the plantation. And I was under
the impression that this stand,
your ground law was fairly recent. It
is. I'm just saying the antecedent to it,
the, what precedes it is, uh,
uh, hundreds of years have,
let's make sure the undesirable people
aren't in our neighborhood after dark.
And by doing that, you've extended
it technically, as you know,
that jury ruled the way
they were told to rule.
They didn't go out of their way to find
George Zimmerman innocent whenever they,
the judge said,
you've got to go by the letter of this
law and underneath all the Pr, you know,
blah, blah, blah. I'm not a
lawyer, nor do I play one on TV.
I'm just an asshole with a big opinion.
There's like almost every case.
There's so much involved in it.
For an outsider like you or I to
say that we know what happened.
I always think that's so crazy and no
one knows what happened on the night.
And when I do know,
I do know that it probably wouldn't
have happened with a different kind of
person.
Like if there's certain people she'd
be sure there's certain people that can
handle things socially,
altercations and then certain people who
are really poor communicators and they
cause a lot of like a lot of issues
communicating with people and then their
arguments and sue that might
not necessarily have had
to and might not have if
some cool dude who's like
the security patrol guy.
What's going on man? Everything cool.
Just got some skittles. I'm going, yeah,
that's it. Like nice,
friendly, you know, maybe it,
maybe this dude had been fucked with too
times by too many dickheads asking him
questions and he was like, yeah, fuck
you. And he had built up, you know,
did you see the Kanye West Jimmy
Kimmel interview? I did not.
It was pretty interesting. And Kanye
West was super honest about it. You know,
they have this big Twitter fight. And one
of the things Kanye West said was like,
all these people were attacking him.
And so he had built up and then he'd
just exploded on the one person that he
actually knew that it was totally,
you know,
it's this disproportionate reaction that,
but it was just the same kind of thing.
It was just build up that does,
didn't have an outlet and then boom.
Then it just goes all into that. Yeah.
Now, and I think you're right that,
uh, George Zimmerman was riding around,
probably spoiling a little bit for fight,
and he was clearly huffy about guys in
the neighborhood and shit. And you know,
I mean,
in the end it could also could be,
he's just a neighborhood watch guy and
he's trying to do his thing and there's a
lot of shady people in the neighborhood
that's also possible. Could be,
he could be, that's been a black
community for a hundred years.
But I'm saying there's still
a lot of criminals still.
A lot of kids should just not saying just
because it's a black community doesn't
mean it's crime Britain. No,
but the big thing is that he,
there was a lot of breakins and that area,
right. So he was, yeah. Yeah. And He'd,
he'd had run INS with guys before. I
think that thing is, that's even more,
you know, over arching than his, you know,
reaction on the night to
fucking shoot somebody was as a,
which is horrible and tragic,
but uh, it's like what,
what it did in a,
in a,
in almost a Rodney king or Oj waiting
the country to really be like a
thunderclap that just fucked
everybody over. And you know, again,
pointing out the inequity
that there's two sets of laws,
one for the underclass and one for
everybody else and that, you know,
nothing's fair and,
and the racial divide and it,
it's just something that I
thought it was really destructive,
like as an emotional. Also
the media of course, you know,
amped it up to insane levels,
but it's true.
And it's also something we're fighting
through. I think even with this shutdown,
I think is a, if you'll
look at the teams, you know,
there's a racial element
to this that's undeniable,
that carries through in everything
since this country was born. Well,
do you think that if he was some white
trash kid that was in the neighborhood,
some, uh, angry white dude
with like love and hate,
tattooed on his knuckles
and Zimmerman shot him,
do think they're same thing
would've happened? I don't know.
I think he might've been acquitted
still because of the, of the law,
the letter of that law.
It,
he was in his defense and I'm not a
Zimmerman apologist. And I, as I said,
I'll be super clear. Um, I was not
there. I don't know what happened.
I would not say I know what happened.
I don't know.
I do know that Zimmerman's
face was fucked up.
And I do know he had cuts in the back
of his head from his head being bounced
off the ground. So he was
getting his ass kicked. And I,
I've gotten my ass kicked before.
It's a terrifying fee. Atis. And, um,
if he was getting his ass kicked and
this guy was in danger of hurting
him, that's the whole, the whole
reason the law exists. Yes.
You should be able to defend yourself
with a gun because without a gun,
you're at the mercy of this asshole's
beating the shit out of you. Right.
I'm not saying that he
didn't instigate the fight.
He's going to sit and take the gray
area comes with what proceeded. Sure.
Fracas he could die there. That's
make no mistake about it. Yeah.
It's pretty easy for someone to die in
a street fight. Oh hell yeah. It is.
Especially with concrete is going to say,
as soon as your head hits the fucking
streets, super easy to get knocked out.
Super easy to fall down, smash your
head and never be the same again.
Like it's really scary scenario.
So if you are a fighting this kid
who's like in better shape than you,
he's kicking your fucking ass. Like you're
in danger of dying. Like that's real.
Like your life is
essentially in his hands.
He might punch a few times when you're
out and walk away or he might stomp you
to death. He could do that if he
wants to. It's up to him and he's,
he's so enraged that you're in a physical
altercation with your bodies where
you're fighting for your life to the
point where you have to pull a gun out.
Well,
I think that the pointless,
like he's not a policeman and he
challenged to this guy and you know,
do we know that? See, I don't know
what exactly. So that's the problem.
So I'm not,
I'm not making any,
there wasn't a police
call and all that jazz,
unless that didn't happen according to
the, the police call definitely happened.
But what's interesting about the police
call that happened was that they edited
it. They asked you what does he look
like? And he said he's a black guy.
But when they played it on the air,
they edited it.
So they cut out the woman we Lorraine's
question. So they changed it.
Here's this guy looks suspicious,
he's a black guy.
So they edited out the question.
They made it look like he was
pointing out that he's a black guy.
He thinks about it. The media was never
said July did all of a sudden they were,
they, no, no one's going to support
it again for a couple of weeks.
No one's innocent in this. No
one's innocent in this. Of course,
the number one tragedies
that this guy lost his life.
I try to tell young men if they would,
if anyone who's willing to listen,
if foleyed conflict at
all costs at all costs,
there's no need to fight people.
I was at the beach this weekend and this
guy was giving me the finger is older
dude, I'm sure you know, I don't
think he knew who I was or had any,
uh, idea that, uh, Sherry,
wasn't it disgruntled lesson?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
I don't think he had any idea.
You know,
that I was a nice person
and that I could have, uh,
talked to him through this and
everything could have been fine,
but there was a bunch of kids playing.
It was my friend's kids.
And my kids and they were playing
here, this a cove area. And um,
this guy had set up his, uh, his,
his blanket there on a public beach,
but there's people all over the place and
these kids wanted to play in this cove
area.
And so this guy got so pissed off.
We came here for a little peace and
quiet and we didn't want to be, you know,
people right on top of us. And I just
smiled at the guy, didn't say anything,
I just smiled the guy. I'm like,
yeah, it was so ridiculous.
There's no way I'm going
even to argue with you.
You're the public beach and little kids
are playing to this fucking people all
over the place, man. Just cause people
came near you. Cause you don't have this,
you don't own the spot next to your spot.
You don't have like a specific amount
of room and the guy gives me the finger
and I'm like, you're so crazy.
Like you're, you're like in,
you're engaging someone you
didn't know nothing about.
You don't know anything about me.
I could be a real mean guy
and I could just decide, oh,
you just gave me an excuse to beat the
fuck out of you and there's nothing you
can do about it.
I'm just going to grab you and start
smacking you around and you're going to be
terrified.
And you gave me the green light,
you gave me the finger and why
don't you give me the finger bitch?
There's a lot of nutty people like that
out there. So I, I saw this guy do this.
I'm like,
wow.
Have you never experienced like a really
crazy person before you like inviting
crazy people into your life?
Is that what you're doing? Yes.
Like people who would do
that with driving too.
They play games and cut people off
and hit the brakes. I dated a girl,
he used to do that. She was great, great
person. But she's very competitive.
When it came to driving,
she got ultra competitive with people
and if people tried to cut her off,
she would go into oncoming traffic and
cut in front of them with me in the car.
And I was like, listen, you gotta
listen to me. You are going to get hurt.
You're going to hurt me.
You're going to hurt them because
they got in front of your con.
They made you go to your place two
seconds later. This is crazy. But yeah,
they did a douchey move.
They suck at driving.
Do you don't have to speed in front
of oncoming traffic and cut them off.
You know you have to let them know, fuck
them. You don't have to take, you know,
I'm like, okay, you're, you
can't, you can't be serious.
Like this is a nutty
way of approaching life.
Like you're going to make
an enemy of a crazy person.
You're going to do with
danger everywhere you go,
you're going to do it in
the wrong spot. You, you.
There's a broad spectrum of people you
can and can't piss off and if you piss
off the wrong people, you, you're
in serious fucking danger. Oh yeah.
That's the thing that
drives me crazy that La,
I mean you're talking about
this guy in the beach and stuff,
people that thing that I think people in
general are now I sit in la except when
they're behind the wheel really wears
down on my soul here because there's no
other city in the country where people
treat you the way they do it in La.
I think we're panicking. I think
everybody Oughta, there's, yeah,
there's so much traffic
that people just panicking.
They're just fucking trying to get home
quicker and cut in front of people and I
just take it out of my job madness.
If I pull out of my drive,
I yesterday at dude on Sunday I
go to my wife watched this guy,
he's going to try to pass
me coming around the riot.
I'm just coming out of the driveway and
he yup, speed it up, fucking one around,
made it inches, you know, death defying
Ben Hur fucking bullshit. And I'm like,
then we were right behind him
at the light and you're like,
well you're fucking 40 centimeters ahead.
And they did.
He got a big w out of that one.
People drive cars the way they live life,
but that's what I mean.
It's like it reflects on
everything. Yeah, you're strong.
Can you open these?
What are those mints?
I know it's just like having an actress
on this shift. Thank you brother.
Would you like a then you
guys, we've got one over.
Thank you.
Yeah, I'm in delicious.
What'd you like him then?
I'm going to open it up meant to laugh
at me and my inability to open this.
Joe will attest that these this weekend.
Exactly. Those things are tricky.
Or are you good at jars it?
You know what doctor fuck off my ass is
what I'm good at. You know what? I'm too,
yeah. The jar that I struggle with
and I'm like, this is ridiculous.
Like what if I was some Old Lady?
I wanted to get a pickle,
but I'm never opening this. I'm going
to have to open this with a hammer.
Like if I was an old lady and I got
to one that I'm serious. Pickle jars.
Like you can't open them
bitches. No. Right, right. Yeah.
You know,
that's why they have those tools,
those little rubber
things you put on the top.
That's like grip it better and stuff.
I use the a kitchen sink gloves,
but even then sometimes, wow, that's
a good call. Yeah, that's good.
You get a good grip. Yeah,
you need a grip, but it just
seems like a silly thing.
Like you're, you're making these so
hard to open. Yeah. Like it's almost,
you need tools. On the other
hand, in the Zombie apocalypse,
you'll be able to swan end to any charge
food store and really live off that
ship for awhile.
The Zombie apocalypse is already happened.
Have you seen this crocodile drug
that these, uh, it came from?
Russia crop could deal. They're calling
you and stuff like that. It's um,
it's a supplement for heroin for people
who don't have heroin or they just want
to try this when they're
the sick of killing himself
with heroin and it actually
rots Skinaway. Wow. Like
literally giant chunks of flesh,
exposed bone and all these
people that are taking it.
It's here in Los Angeles now too. Yeah,
I've heard. It's insane. It's insane.
It's highest clowns. I think it's deal.
I've only seen it written. I haven't,
I know vice has a documentary on it,
but I didn't watch it.
It's so depressing man. Oh my God.
Last time I was here it was bath salts.
That's right. But this one, when that
dude eight, that dude's face. Yeah, right.
Wasn't it?
Around that same time,
it turned out to be just weed
and he just had the munchies.
That's what they said it was weed.
But the problem with that is of course
you know that we'd stays in your system
for many,
many weeks.
That's why fighters take like five
weeks off and they still get popped now
because you know the,
the weed just shows up in your system.
It's really hard to get
wheat out of your system.
So like he probably wasn't really high.
He probably just had gotten high.
And the thing about it's testing them
for bath salts is there is no test for
bass off. That's the big trek. So
when they say that there was nothing,
the only thing that we found
in his system was marijuana.
They're not saying he wasn't
on bath salts, they're just,
they're not admitting that they
don't have a test for the fucking,
these crazy drugs that
people just keep inventing.
They don't have tests for them.
So then saying,
well he was high on marijuana and there's
new drugs in like basically every week
there's new drugs cause
there's just people tinkering.
It's got so tired of people trying to
pretend that that was actually what
happened. The guy who got high
and eight, this dude's face. No,
that's some silly shit.
Yeah it was.
But this croc deal or whatever,
it is the latest,
greatest and the most disturbing
by far. That's wild. It's really,
I'll show you some pictures. You
want to see some veterans? No. Okay.
I'm really sensitive and a us can eat
some barbecue lighter. So I was to,
it won't hurt you. You're, you're old and
wise enough to know. It doesn't matter.
It would just be able to separate and
enjoy your ribs. Just dig right in.
It really does look like some walking
dead shit though. Really is like,
people just have giant chunks rotted
away from their skin and they're still
alive. Somehow. Jesus fucking quite high.
It makes you want to do that too.
That's so good that you're like, Shit.
First it falls off and you're like,
okay, I'm still getting more. Yes.
A couple more. Yeah. And how long does it
take before it makes your skin fall off?
Does it get,
does it happen right away?
And that's why everybody has their
skin fall off. Or is it like,
do you have to be a real asshole and stick
with this fucking drug for six months?
You know,
waiting for it to rot your skin away.
People are just so self destructive.
And now what the fuck is that Greg?
Proof? I don't know about him.
I'm sitting right here and I can
hear you. Yeah. What is that? Uh,
I mean, like you say that thing. What did
she say about La? People are panicked.
I think there's too many of us.
And I think when you look at
rat population density studies,
uh,
I listened to some
online talk by a police.
If it was a art bell was
talking to Terrence Mckenna
and they were talking about
a population density studies they did
on rats and that at a certain point in
time you get enough rats in the room,
rats start doing crazy shit like that.
You have one or two rats in the room.
Everybody's cool.
You have a hundred rats in the room.
Things get a little sketch.
When you pay 5,000 rats, they start
eating each other. They started one of,
some of them will hide in
the corners and just nod.
They like mimic human
crazy behave. Right, right.
I think we're not supposed to wear,
I don't think we're designed,
I think we're improving,
but I don't think we're necessarily
designed to be around this many fucking
people and it is pretty dense
that, yeah, especially Los Angeles.
Even in Los Angeles,
a little more spread out than like
say New York or something. Yes,
it's definitely more spread
out to New York. Look.
And the thing about Los Angeles,
most people that if you live in a house,
you probably have like a yard, you know?
And you know people that have a yard.
It's something that's a nice thing to
have. Yeah, it is. It's a privilege.
You don't get that in New York,
New York City. Good fucking luck.
You might get a little terrace.
Yeah. If you're rich or flower box,
you've got a little flower box. You just,
it's concrete everywhere. Fuck that.
Well, it's interesting
though. There's a lot to,
there's a lot of benefit to New
York. It's, it's weird, but it's,
you're basically on a buzz all the time
because like it or not the p the people
around you influenced the way you feel.
The energy that you have in New
York is like this move in town.
There's so much going on. There's so
many people. You just go, all right,
here we go. And almost like
Popsie up a notch. And you know,
I think there's something to that. I
think there's something to, to the, the,
the juice that you get from
being around that many people,
but it's not for everybody. No, it isn't.
But you do you feel like something's
going on and you might be missing it. Yes.
Uh, I liked that too. I like San Francisco
that get, well, one, I'm from there,
but in the daytime you can be around
people if you want. And then like,
I always find that there's
always unbelievable empty,
quiet spaces no matter where
you go in San Francisco,
even in the middle of the day or
night or Friday night, it's never,
it's never as bustling as New York. Well,
it's an unusually smart town. I mean,
I think New York is kind of
unusually smart a lot of ways too.
There's MS obviously a lot of dumb people
all over the land, but there's the,
the high pockets of smart people that
you can meet at the museum in New York or
you can meet and a million different
places in San Francisco.
I mean,
that is literally the tech tech
capital of this country. Yeah.
The brightest minds from
Google and apple and other,
all in that northern California area.
So if you thought about that and just,
just that as a city,
like that's what,
that's gotta be one of the
best congestion's of minds
that we have little g she
San Francisco, it's impossible
to not be, you know,
it's impossible to not be.
If you been Uber successful with
a bunch of different companies,
a lot of really smart people.
It's just,
I think it's probably the
smartest spot in the country.
The concentration is certainly an intense,
I feel it when I performed there.
Oh yeah, you do because people
will know what's going on. Yeah.
They just seem more, they seemed
really tuned in. You know,
I did one of my specials, my,
uh, 2006 shiny happy Jihad.
They did it at Cobbs and uh, so
one of my favorite ones, I just,
I just always felt like San
Francisco audiences have just,
there's something about them, you know,
they're just like one notch smarter.
Certainly my favorite Krug's I've
always loved them just one notch.
I think that La Crowds, it depends on
what you play can be really amazing.
You can get one notch smarter
here too. And you, by the way,
you get one notch smarter and Columbus,
Ohio is if they come to see you, you know,
if the people know you.
But I just always found that collect
coming up that like they almost demanded
more too. I think. So. I mean I, I came
from San Francisco from the old days,
you know, from the 80s. And uh,
there was a lot of really crazy Craig's
common and if you were hacky in any way,
that was kind of frowned upon and it
was really important to keep pushing the
conceptual law envelope and stuff
like that if we were famous for never
succeeding in La,
you know,
on stage because the ideas
are too abstruse and stuff.
And then of course now everyone that
I know in La is from San Francisco.
Well don't you think that comedy is just
so evolved so much since then? You know,
the, the, uh, the public's perception of
comedy as well because of the Internet.
I think people are just a way blue
broader palate also is fueled by the club
scene then and it's not as much anymore.
Yeah. They do have a way broader pallet.
Yeah. The scene was all about the club
scene. Now it's still is Kinda, yeah.
I mean there's still spots like,
you know,
the seller in New York that
just draws people to it,
of the Improv and Hollywood draws people
to it. The comedy store, of course,
you know, there's always going to
be that. But I think that the, the,
the ability to promote on the Internet
is the thing that changed comedy the most
over the last few years.
Absolutely.
And it's allowed us the luxury of taking
back the means of production. Yeah.
Removing a lot of middlemen that
we're not, uh, it turns out necessary.
And it also allows Greg Proops
to be Greg Proops. Like,
you can do your podcast and no one
gives you a hard time about anything.
You make all the decisions. It's not even
a compromise necessary. Like now, Greg,
I was thinking today because it's
president's Day, right? Like,
maybe you just do this thing
about presidents and like,
hey fuck head, you know,
like what did you go make
your own podcast. Okay.
I everybody has ideas that they want
to stick in your face and they might be
good ideas but I don't want to land now.
And that's the thing that's so great
about this is the under, like you said,
just the unbelievable self
determination for freedom.
And I take responsibility for
it. If the show sucks, I'm like,
that one wasn't as good or you know,
I'll try to do it better.
And I listened to him back and think,
well, that could, uh, that could have,
I'm a little more, it's just so
effortless, you know? I mean,
without being effortless,
look, it always requires, like,
I always feel like podcasts,
the most important things that
I'd just be paying attention to.
What the fuck's going on in the world.
As long as you're paying attention to
what's going on in the world is always
going to be something to talk about.
Oh,
I live in the most bizarre time ever
and we're the most like content rich
comedians ever everyday.
Some insane new stories that you
can't fucking believe is real, but is,
you know about a clam and a penis and a
fucking, who knows? You know what I mean?
There's like, there's always
some new fucking insane story.
It's like you never run out of
comedy. It's impossible today. No.
And that's what someone said,
Jay,
like as I do mind by myself and they go
[inaudible] you run out of material and
it's like, really not
today. Nah, not anymore.
I'll have to do is go on the Internet
and write a paper and do this and talk to
people. And there's
5,000 things. Do you, um,
infiltrate other communities
that you don't agree with?
Do you ever like go to like
really conservative websites
are either forums and I
do, and I'll go to a lunch
tray. I think you'd have to,
I was just reading,
speaking of infiltrating,
there was an interview and I think it
was New York magazine with a Antonin
Scalia and they asked him the
question and what did you,
what do you read in the morning
and shit? And he said, uh,
I read the Washington Times and the
Wall Street Journal, and the guy goes,
you don't read the post. And he
goes, I used to read the post,
but I found that
everything was too liberal.
And then he went and the guy wants, so no
New York Times at all. And he was like,
no, I never read the New York Times. And
I thought, okay, look, I'm a comedian.
I have no responsibility to the public.
I'm not holding a secured
position where I'm adjudicating on fucking
matters of grave national importance
every day of my life and writing opinions
and being a deciding vote on a fucking
panel of nine people who were
hand chosen by psychopaths.
And yet I have the capital loss city of
taste to fucking watch Fox News every
once in a while. And I don't go on,
I got, you know, like you just go,
like you can't read the New York Times
because it upsets you too much and you're
a justice. Like how narrow is your
fucking purview? You know what I mean?
Like why don't you say, I don't
believe anything out, you know?
And then he talks about how he
believes in the devil and whatnot.
And you're like, we're getting kind
of weird here with the justice. Like,
I mean, who is that? He believed
Janine Scalia. Oh no, he didn't. Yeah,
he health guilt. You could go online and
look up the interview when you read it.
It was just, but I like to
think of what's, fuck you
man. I read, I w I read Fox.
I'll read, cause I read news stories on
my show and I'll say this is from this,
you know, and obviously I read a lot from
the Guardian or Truthout or whatever,
you know,
but I'll also go,
this is from Fox News or this is from
CNN or this is from a right wing,
the Wall Street Journal.
I read a piece from the Wall
Street Journal about the
fucking former head of the,
uh, Shearson Lehman and shit.
And I, because Richard Fault,
someone said he's a survivor. And I
said, he's a fucking criminal. You know,
he started a new company on Wall Street
and all we're supposed to feel sorry for
him that he's so brave that he
weathered the 2008 collapse.
Like you engineered it.
Even people in the financial community
blamed him for it was like, well,
well they can a survivor that's a quote,
you know,
paint things and a beautiful of
course. But I mean, Scalia said that.
And so when you asked me do I
infiltrate it? It's like, no. Do I,
do I watch a steady diet of Fox News?
No.
Do I read right when you
just to all the time, no.
Do I try to read stuff from all over
the world from different points of view?
Yeah. Yeah. That's why Greg,
cause it's interesting,
you don't have to agree
with everything you read.
And I always say this
to people about comedy.
Do people that come and see you and don't
like your politics and then get up in
a huff and fuck off. I always think you're
not sophisticated, not sophisticated.
And I don't mean that in like a smart or
like you went to college way. I mean, uh,
there are people who have no education
who can understand a whole bunch of ideas
at once and see the humor of, you know
what I mean? Well, there's some people,
there's lines you cannot cross.
Their pea brains won't allow it.
But that's what I mean, like come
back to subject. That's off limits.
Mostly.
I find that if you are disagreeing,
I remember last year or two years
ago when the election was going,
I did a joke in Eugene or Portland.
Oh No. One of the places in Oregon,
it wasn't in Eugene, which is wicked
liberal, but it was a clown with law.
I don't know where the fuck I was in
Oregon. It was a city in Oregon. And uh,
I said something,
I said that the Republican nominees aren't
just the worst group of nominees I've
ever seen from the Republican
Party in my lifetime there,
the Reus Group of people I've
ever seen in a room, you know,
and started to go through them.
And when it was Herman Cain and Newt
Gingrich and someone in the backyard, no,
it was like, no, you don't
get to veto jokes. And a guy,
I'm not kidding.
A Guy wrote me the other day on my email.
Like I take email from people and
I read it, I don't know his answer,
but any road I was at your show
in Chicago and it was podcast.
So my podcast is not advertised
as a standup show. It says
podcast, you know, like,
and therefore there's a
different thing that's happening.
It's a lot more real and you
know, unless you know, and uh,
he wrote me and he said,
ah,
I didn't spend this 20 bucks or
whatever to hear your fucking politics.
And I didn't think it was very funny.
And anyone that would like to
show it'd be a halfwit and shit.
So normally I would just block
him, you know, but I thought,
I'm going to write him back
and I realize you're hostile.
Tone is not conducive to
discourse and understand this,
you chose to come in the room and you
pay it if you'd asked for a refund of the
time, that's another matter. And I go,
and by the way, after the show's over,
you don't get to email the artist and
ask for your money back because you
disagreed with them.
You take your chances,
whether you go to see a symphony or a
movie or a fucking whatever it is you're
going to go see, man, when
you go to Jack in the box,
you might not like them sausages,
but you don't get to fucking
write me after and tell me
you want your money back.
And then say everyone that liked it was
a moron when he was the only one who
didn't like it. You know? And it's
like, I don't understand that. Well,
there's always going to be
people that can't wrap their head around
the idea that there's different people
and different people like different stuff.
Yeah. And if you don't like something,
it's okay.
If there were other people enjoying it,
well then you know that's for them.
It's not for you.
But the anger like letter like I didn't,
I don't like your politics on all
our fucking, that wasn't very funny.
And the people are assholes. And just
sending that letter, you're an asshole.
[inaudible] mean you might want to
tell one of your friends like that.
I didn't have a good time. He's talking
all this liberal shit. I, Trayvon Martins,
by the way, the not yet. The
night I did it was uh, uh,
the 50th anniversary of the march on
Washington for jobs and freedom and I
played a clip of Martin Luther King
speech, the part I have a dream and shit.
You know,
cause I didn't think that crowd had
heard it before because a lot of young
people who haven't heard it. Exactly.
And everybody listened really intently.
And I thought this is
what you objected to.
You objected to the biggest cry for
peace in the last fucking 50 years.
What were the other controversial points
that were discussed in the pocket? Oh,
I think there was a vote rigging. Uh, I,
I assert and I will stand by this,
that voter fraud in this
country is nonexistent in
the way that the media would
make you wish that it existed.
Pete poor people are not pitching up
in their millions to polling places and
trying to fob off bad idea or
whatever. And then, you know,
like a lot of states have Jen,
this whole voter id thing and people,
why shouldn't you have to show Id
let me hit you to something. Um,
about 10 to 15% of this
country has no money at all.
And those people don't have bank accounts,
phones, televisions, computers or ideas.
Yeah, they're ad hoc doing that
shit. They don't just have it.
And like for instance, I was on a
show in a conservative lady said,
why shouldn't people have show ids?
And I said,
my mother who passed away this year was
94. I said, my mother doesn't have an ID.
She's voted in every election
since Roosevelt's first one.
Are you going to deny her the vote?
What do you do? How do you go?
You don't have to,
if you're on the voter roll,
you come up and you say your name and
they've stayed on the role and I'm Greg
Proops. Yeah, but they,
you're not correct groups and you
don't know who's doing it. Do you check
that?
[inaudible] Woodland Hills.
Greg Proops cut that part out. It's
too late. It's live. Oh Shit. Fuck,
I'm sorry. Uh, anyways, the and
a woman said there was a plate,
a case in Illinois and shit. My,
my point is governments in actress,
restrictive voter laws.
That's what's going on with voter fraud.
Making students not be allowed to vote
that are in North Carolina college
students not letting them
use their student Id to vote.
When you're living for two or three
years and you are an out of state student
living in North Carolina, you will now
not be able to use your voter id. You see,
that's a restrictive law. If you're
over 18 and you're registered to vote,
no matter what state you're in, ought to
be able to vote in the place that you,
you know, that's just one
example, but I'm in like,
that's all bunch of liberal
Hooley is made of Liberal Hawaii.
I live on a bale of Hay
made of Hooey for people.
Need to think about less putting less
money in your grill. Exactly, man.
And more money in your ID collected.
We're going to let the cast of winter
bone vote, then I want to vote.
That's all I'm saying.
At a certain point in time,
it wasn't everyone gonna need id though.
It seems like it almost seems like
they're going to jail. I agree with you.
And they do and everything that everything
that we possess has a code in it and
it can, your wallet and everything in
your wallet can be read from you know,
miles away. Yeah. Yeah. And,
and all that shy because of the ID chips
that are in everything. And I'm like, Oh,
and your phone is on all the time.
We know this is just obvious shit now,
but my phone is a tracking
device. Right, right. But I,
I'm telling you that people who, who
live day to day, uh, for instance,
if you see homeless people,
which you do in Los Angeles,
they don't have a cell phone and an
ID card. And you know what I mean?
Like that the idea that everyone has
a computer is a real white people
middleclass idea around the
world of the 5 billion of us.
I guarantee you it's not that many.
It's not the majority of people with a
computer because there's lots of other
countries like unless you think every
single human in Africa has a computer,
if you know what I'm saying. I mean
like most by now, if they don't,
I'd like them to subscribe to your thing.
I'm selling on my podcast.
It's pretty fascinating when you think
about how vast the differences between
the people in the poorest parts of the
world and the people in the richest parts
of the world,
and the difference in what life is
and from the jump with no, you know,
you didn't do anything wrong. They just
got the worst hand of cards ever wound
up in an incredibly poor country and
no one has shoes or something terrible
happened.
Like you're a middle class person
living in Syria or Iraq or whatever,
and all of a sudden the shit hits the
fan and now you have to move to a camp
cause your neighborhood got
blown to shit and fuck. You know,
there's a lot of different, speaking
of which can I plug my comedy special?
Oh hell on this. Delightful, upbeat note.
We were talking about people around
the world possessing computers.
If you do possess one,
you can download my comments.
If you're listening to this
and you don't have something,
what could you do it on a phone?
Can you download it on a phone?
I expect your kid. Yes. Then you
can even get it on your phone.
I'm just going to sit on your phone,
put it on your friend's phone
and then sit behind them.
If you're listening to this,
it's impossible that you don't have
access to Greg Proops comedy special.
You can get it.
It's a chill.com/groups or uh,
Greg proops.com and a,
I think it's 509 I think it's for 80 now.
I think it goes up to five
99 when it comes down.
I shot it lie that Musso and
Frank's, you know that joint. Oh,
that place in Hollywood. Oh,
that what an amazing idea.
I didn't even know they did
shows that they down with.
My manager came to me and said, I've
got it loose. Hose is perfect for you.
And I was like, it is
perfect for me. So I say,
I say a bunch of quotes from
all the riders that drank
there, like Bukovsky said,
never get up before noon.
And uh, uh, what does it,
Faulkner said a time.
Time is a time his dad,
as long as it's being clicked
off by a little wheels,
only when the clock stops does
time come alive. And I said,
Moose says is where the clock stops and
time comes alive because it's always the
past though. It feels like it, it looks
like it. You get that Vibe, you know?
And that place has been
around for a long time.
[inaudible] it's such a beautiful place.
Yeah.
I love those old Hollywood joints.
Like Dan to those places are amazing
cause it feels like when you go to them
that you're, you're like entering
into like, uh, like a time machine.
You're going to a place that hasn't
changed much and so many years,
not even the menu of the smell bread,
they give you celery and shit.
You know what I'm saying? Like so good
stuff. Celery food is incredible too.
They have the best taken Hollywood
cause they don't fuck around. No, no.
It's really just steak and
know what they're doing.
They know exactly how to cook it. Yeah.
And they always get the best meat.
Like they've been around forever.
They have these relationships.
Probably would butchers that go back to
the twenties oh everybody wears jackets,
man. It's insane. It's good. Yeah.
Those old joints are fucking amazing.
There was so much fun to do it there
and we had a who sat down. It's no,
I saddled it for a little bit of it. Oh
yeah. Preview. Keep showing the preview.
Well done. Yeah. Yeah man. Yeah.
I had a little table that I could
sit out and drank if I want it to.
But you walked around on the floor of
the restaurant? Yeah. And I had a band,
CML jazz band behind man. Shit. What a
great idea. It was great fun. The areas.
What an original idea. Congratulations
man. It looks really nice.
They shot at really beautiful,
beautiful idea. I love it. Wow.
We just had a light and a
couple of cameras and uh,
some smoke and we did on Sunday afternoon
and everybody could drink and uh,
people will a drink. That's awesome.
How many shows did you do? One or two?
I did one with no hax why? I did like
two little things from another angle.
And that was that we struck like I
did an hour and then it was over.
So there was no,
he know there was no doing that Joko
or no fixing that or know anything.
Yeah. Alyssa, I believe me. I had a drink
and I just fucking kept him, you know,
did it? Yeah, there's a lot
of like really great comics.
If you watch the specials,
you never got them at full bore because
he got like this sort of awkward version
of them.
Like the perfect example is a one
of Bill Hicks biggest specials.
He did it in London and
there was a huge crowd. Oh,
the one where it rides over the bridge
and it's on fire. Yeah, he's got like a
Voodoo child rather, uh,
Jimi Hendrix. Uh, and he, uh,
he's got a cowboy hat on holding. He
feels stiff to me. I mean, he's staging,
he feels like, you know, hey,
you got one shot at doing this
big special in this giant place.
He rides through hoops of fire into
the stage. I mean, it's pretty,
it was something along those lines,
right. It was something like that.
It was like that. He does come over the
London Bridge on a horse. I remember that.
That's hilarious.
No,
my friend Chris Bull directed that and
that was his whole concept form your,
this warrior poet and you're accountable
and we're going to do this and they're
not, but I agree with you. It
puts a lot on, I much prefer to,
Oh God,
it's going to ever show me myself.
I'm going to wear a fucking Jawa outfit.
Oh yeah.
Um, I much preferred being able to just
stand on the floor of this restaurant.
You have a drink like, and it didn't feel
that pressure patch and I, it was all,
you know,
friends and people have friends,
friends that sounds like you could drink.
It was Sunday afternoon and
everybody had a couple drinks.
If there's so many of those little
cool spots like that in Hollywood,
you know the government is,
the comedy store of course is one of them.
The rainbow, the Rainbow
God, that place is so weird.
That's like going back into it and
talking video or something. Man, that is,
and those people still go there
today? Yeah, it's their spot. Oh yeah,
the rainbow. That's so funny. I
forget what I was doing up there.
I was going to some show business
thing and I went in the rainbow too,
like how the beer and used the bathroom.
The food's good there too.
I did comedy there. These
are really, is it upstairs?
It's in the round where you have
to just kind of walk around.
There's people all around you. That's
hilarious. I did one bar on Hollywood.
Was the red something or another that
used to be on sunset? What was it?
The Rand Red Room. No, no.
They just closed that place.
It was a weird place. It was like you're,
you are doing red, red rock. Yeah.
It was like you were doing comedy
in somebody's attic change.
They just really felt like an attic.
They just reopened it.
And I guess they made that top part
bigger cause it's now it's a piano bar or
something weird like that. Holy Cow.
That's when you know comedies failed.
We lost to a piano bar.
Howl at the moon when it's the
two Julian [inaudible] guys.
So Greg Proops stop it.
Hey that shit.
Well that's one of the beautiful
things about the attitude in Texas.
Prov Addison, Texas. It's
right next door to it. Yep.
So dudes would come out of there, you'd
be lit up and you're like, come on man,
let's go play some fucking piano.
Woo.
And then people would be singing back
and forth and dueling Pittsburgh.
It's in a mall. The other bar
there is the hell with the men.
I think the last time I played there,
I got an email.
You get denied or late cause you got
to do the radio the next day and like
there's nothing around but that.
So I went there and had a
few drinks and get lit up.
Oh yeah. Because after you're there
for a while, you're just like,
who sadder did people that are here or
me because I'm here and I had to do this,
you know, one man. Nothing sad about
it. Just get it to be wherever you are.
There you be. Well, I was, I had a few
drinks. So you're at Howl at the moon,
taking an experience, having a
little alcohol, little person dipper,
some jams that I hadn't heard in a while.
There you go.
Little awesome old Leonard Skinner
do something like that. Yeah. Yeah.
Those places are despicable.
They should be stopped. It's,
it's kind of a weird, I don't
understand. Like, well, I mean, yeah,
I don't know that they're fine. It's fun,
right? It's fun for people. I get it.
The people want to have fun it.
But as I always say on my show,
I'm sure to shit on something you
love, so, but you know what man?
Like it's like you said, it's good
to see all kinds of stuff. And I,
I personally like some country western,
you know,
even silly stuff like Toby Keith.
Yeah. I like some Toby Keith songs.
I think they're good. You know, I don't,
I know they're silly lyrics. I don't care.
I think they're good. It's
doesn't bother me. I enjoy it.
I enjoy a lot of shit.
I can put myself in a lot of different
mindsets for a Goof, you know?
Did you get my, at least in city yet?
Oh Dude. It's the best Jagger ever done.
Bangers. Bangers, bangers. No,
I heard it's doing really well though.
Don't ask me how. I know her care.
Britney Spears isn't it? And I'm
the music, but she's in it. Yeah.
She does a song with her. Wow. It's really
cool. You really doubling down. Yeah.
That's about a journey's
greatest hits whizzes.
I highly recommend that to
journey's greatest hits.
Do Journey has some strong songs.
A lot of people don't want a minute.
It's a lot of people
don't want to admit it,
but journey had some fucking strong
songs that if you're by yourself,
you'd get pretty excited if it came on
the radio. No one doesn't admit it yet.
That fucking just a small town scow.
Yeah.
Dominated the world.
So much so that I was in
Nashville like a year ago.
And you know how there's that,
what's the name of the main drag in
national where all the country bars are?
Whatever. And uh, uh, you know,
we were drinking up and down the street
after the show and we went to a country
bar where it was like country open Mike.
So there was the sexy dude who had the
leather vest and he sang the Charlie
Daniels and wanting to,
you just leave this long haired contract
ball, right. And then every, you know,
every type of open Mike country.
And then there was a band that got up.
Then this girl got up this blonde girl
and she fucking sang journey and you're
like, we're in Nashville.
And the place lit up man. And
I was like, Shit. She went,
he's Jeff for small town square out
of the whole place. Like fucking
thought, you know, fuck
yeah. Yeah. Who's crying now?
That's a great song. That's
a great fucking song. If
you by yourself, you will,
you will get very excited
when that song comes on.
If you run a bunch of checks that
you, you know, if they know you,
you're going to let them know
the enjoy a little journey. Yeah.
That's when my new guilty pleasure
events people judge you on.
Yeah. Oh yeah, they do judge you
like my friend Joey, Joey Diaz,
he gets really mad at Eddie Bravo
for Eddie Bravo loving kiss.
And I've told them a mug. I'm
sorry dude. I love some case. Yeah,
you're fucking 45 years old, Joe Robbing
Mother fucking listening to that Shit.
Fuck you.
Listen to that shit.
You're telling me it's one of the
greatest albums of all time. Suck my Dick.
And he'll just, he just goes off. You
can't enjoy, you cannot end. Never.
No one ever said it was the greatest
album of all time. No, no, no.
You can't enjoy it. You can. I
want to rock and roll all night is
magnum magnum opus. Yeah.
Yeah. That's a fucking great.
So Detroit rock city is
a fucking great sunshine.
I saw them a long time ago and uh, in
the 70s and the night hours died and uh,
that was pretty weird. How old
were you? 16. 17 I think. Um,
that he died on my sister's
birthday. And uh, Elvis did. Yeah,
everybody died that year, wasn't it? 77.
Because I think being an Chaplin died that
year too. Big Year real business. Yeah.
Wow. Yeah. But I went to see kiss,
I've told this story before, but the,
at the end,
Dave and screaming all night and they
spit blood and they spit fire and they're
on platforms like grain
elevators and shit. And you know,
they did all their numbers and they did
Detroit Bucks and I sold a joint to a 10
year old and yeah, fuck you
man. And gangster back. Oh Dude.
I that's why, that's how I roll. And uh,
we drove up from San Carlos
to the cow palace in, uh,
I remember at the end of the show,
gene Simmons goes
badly and then they did gel.
That might be the worst.
She's him and compression the world
has ever known. I can't do him.
Maybe it was Paul to someone's
house, a divorce. Well those screens,
everything they would say, maybe
it was Paul then, cause Paul does.
That's probably Paul. And anyways, they
played jailhouse rock but like kids,
so it was like, oh, Whoa, oh,
you
know. Right. You know, like they
didn't like pep up the beat.
And I remember turning to my friend in
the depths of my drunkenness and weed
drank like a jug. And those days you used
to bring plastic jugs full of odd kit.
Right. It could a plastic jug in
and if it had lemonade, you know,
we didn't have sports bottles, we
had plastic jugs. Remember? Yeah.
I remember those. And
um, so like, uh, yeah,
even in the depths of my
degradation at that point,
having sold weed to a child and was
pretty drunk, I, uh, turned him in.
And why are they playing chess rock?
Yeah. And then the next morning,
of course Elvis dies at 44 or whatever.
It would have been pretty bad ass if
they did it like in a totally different
musical styles.
Right. Then their own, yeah. Yeah.
If they did it like, well, two Pi,
they really did it. I liked the
ability to shut up. Wow. No,
no. They did kiss. It was
like God offender. If,
if that works with Joe House wrong,
don't, don't, don't, don't, don't,
that's another good song. Yeah.
Fuck you Joey Diaz. How dare
you. They're not the best crowd.
Listen man,
I don't think there is the best group,
but I think there's sometimes where kisses
the best group cause that's what you
want to hear at that moment.
That might be chill sometimes I just like,
I'm looking through my iPod and I'm like,
Yay, let's listen to a little of this.
And then there's sometimes it's the
stones and then sometimes it's something
else.
We'll play a little group called
Whitesnake doing here I go again.
I've told the story many times but I'll
tell it again. I was in a car accident.
This was when I was 21.
I had this girlfriend is 25,
but she's telling me what to do.
She was so hot though. Um, but we,
we got in a car accident and um,
I was pulling out the stuff from my
car cause he had it towed my car away.
Some dude ran the light
and smashed into me
and she made me throw out my Whitesnake.
She was like,
why do you still have this throw
this way? And I was like, what?
Hey Rocco.
And then tiny kitchen put
your thing in your face.
She was my drug dealer though.
Really? Well she had pussy. Yeah,
that was my drug dealer. Yeah. She
was my drug dealer when I was 21 plus.
He was the gray, the greatest
drug of all time. I did.
It took me a while to understand
like why we want bound up in these
relationships where people would just
like be completely unreasonable and we
wouldn't get along at
all. And I realized, Oh,
I'm like a druggy druggy for putting,
there's something at the end of this.
This is like,
this is not like a relationship where you,
this is the type of person or the
person that you want to be with.
This is the person you can tolerate
because you guys like to fuck each other.
Yeah. It's not healthy. It's
not a good way to go about it.
Well, it's short term, not the long game.
The long game
to avoid argument at all costs.
Greg proof.
Nah Man. And it's something that
you never learned. That's horrible.
Stay off the Moore's.
Yep.
Stick to the road now she
kept it dealt with. It's a,
the point is why I have to
feel like I'm right. You don't.
If you didn't then real all
relationships would be smooth sailing
sometimes. Sometimes people just
have fucking hormonal swings.
Sometimes people just have weird
career paths and their life,
like it's weird dating someone who's going
through a real rough spot in a career.
Like I never realized how women get so
much more emotional about like work kind
of stuff. Then my guy friends
did like when I was dating,
I was dating this girl and she was having
a hard time whether a her job and you
know she, her career was
kind of in shambles and she,
the way she was looking
at it was so emotional.
It cry and this isn't working
and what am I going to do?
Whereas if it was one of my guy
friends, they'd be like, dude,
I'm getting fucking fire. Right?
Like this sucks. I think I'm a,
I'm thinking about doing this. I might
be doing that. And my uncle knows this.
I told him, I told my brother and he told
me, you know, there's, there's a plan,
there's some shit in motion, there's
get going. Whereas like for some women,
the struggle of like dealing with like
personal failures are dealing with um,
work type failures,
tapper,
super impactful.
And I think that's a weird thing for guys
to wrap their heads around it. And, and,
and I'm not discounting the fact that a
lot of guys have a lot of like big time
emotional connections with
things that go wrong at work too.
But I've never seen it
from my guy friends.
Like I had seen it from
girls that I dated.
Well, if you want to come to
my house, I'll cry in front of
my career.
I try to limit it to the car, you know,
it's your podcast doing well. Yeah.
Thank you. It's a great podcast. Thank
you very much. Really Fun and very unique
to explain to people how you do it
because you do it differently than pretty
much anyone.
Well, I don't use humor
in mind per se. Uh,
I invite people to waste up to two hours
of their life listening to me talk and
drone on and on about
should I have no business.
I sit in front of a live crowd and uh,
and just spiel basically for the
first like half hour, 45 minutes.
And then I kind of get to the second part,
which is the boring preachy part and
that's when it's about the news and the
government and whatever.
And I often have the Bible
of the Constitution Handy
and I'll read little parts
of it out just to make sure people are
down with the letter of the law. And um,
how do people react to that?
Do you find the,
you're getting mostly people who know
what you're doing and know what to expect
or do you get a lot of people that are
kind of surprised because they thought it
was like a comedy podcast or they thought
you were just going to do stand up?
Well, that's so interesting that other
guy that was saying that's silly,
right? Like, I think at the beginning, um,
the people that didn't like it listened
to it once and that was it for them.
You know what I mean? Like, Eh, you know,
the first couple of months I did it,
I think all the people who thought I
was the cute funny one from who's line,
like he's going to be that way and then,
oh wait,
he's poisoned about this and he thinks
about this and he cares about that and I
don't want to dot.
I think they just appeared early.
And what I've found is sometimes
I think as an interminable leak,
you know, just a Sufi
desert, devoid of humor.
Just my opinion for ever and ever is the
part that people really liked because I
think people want you to beat yourself,
like you said.
And that's really the closest
to being myself as a comedian,
that I've ever been
even more than stand up,
which I always thought was the most direct
way I think the podcast is, you know,
cause it's from the heart
and I don't think about what,
I mean I put some stuff together,
but I don't write anything, you know?
And then whatever stories I tell,
it's like on the night,
I think it's something that something
spurred onto me or usually it's about
where I am or what time I was there before
or something that happened that day.
Or, you know, like you said, there's
always something to talk about.
And so that's how I kind of do it. And
then I take questions at the end, uh,
on the road. I always take questions
at the end and we just hash it around.
And some, there's been a couple
of that. The, the public, uh,
the public that the people who listened
to it sort of came up with, like,
I never started it,
but someone said, well,
who's your all time baseball team
of Roman emperors be? Or whatever.
So I made one up, right. And then
the next time someone goes, well,
who would the king and Queens of England
Bay, who had your chief justices be?
He would the president's be who
had the greatest women in history.
So I have all these different teams that
we've done over the years and I just
make them up in the
moment. I don't, you know,
sometimes I fuck him up cause you know,
I'm high and I'm trying to think
of a whole bunch of shit at once.
And I mean I remember in London my,
they said kings and Queens of England
and I went through it and my English
friends up came up to me. We went,
wow, I thought you're going to,
I was worried about you there. And
I'm like, fuck you. I know. No,
I know enough kings and Queens of England
to make a baseball team out of them.
You know, you're supposedly, it's
supposed to be funny, you know,
like the Roman emperor when I remember
it because I said a calendula behind the
plate because he can
handle balls and you know,
but there's more salient ones than that.
Can you do?
But I didn't make that up.
And then I talk about Negro Leagues and
Satchel Paige a lot and that became the
thing on the show.
Like people who hate baseball,
hate sports and don't even know what the
Negro Leagues are. Write me now and go,
it's interesting when you talk about
it, because I liked the talk. You know,
you know when you're passionate about,
you know when you like something
and you imbue that with enthusiasm,
not like hashing through that same bit
that you've done 4,000 times in the clubs
and you're just like, oh fuck,
here's the closer, you know,
there's none of that feeling to that.
What we're going to ask me, I'm sorry,
I don't know nothing.
I just wondered if you could do Bob
the builder in an erotic situation. No,
I wouldn't do that, but
a, I loved Bob too much,
but I would say that Wendy was
exactly like Bob, but with earrings,
let me just put it that way.
I think that we're lesbians.
That's weird that you did that.
I never, never knew you did that.
That's a huge franchise.
Do you get it?
Was Bob the builder cartoon for a Stop
Action Animation for children under four?
Basically, it's, I think two to two
and three year olds. Really? Yeah,
my nieces and nephews and he,
he lives in, uh, England and,
uh, the production, I haven't
done it for a few years, but
he used to do it. And, uh,
I was the American voice,
the North American voice,
Canada and America. And, uh,
it, it's, uh, it's supposed to teach you
to reuse and recycle and shit like that.
Oh, there he is. He wears a
little belt and whatnot. And uh,
look at you because you're so
adorable. Bob. The builder.
Can we build it Bob the builder? Yes,
we can. And then like, he would go,
uh, English when he lived
in a caravan and drank tea,
but in the American when he lives in
a trailer and drinks coffee. So, wow.
We had to translate it into American
and it would be like, you know,
they were going to build a road
somewhere and there was a bird's nest.
So what do we do about the bird?
You know they're little,
little short vignettes and there was a
couple of feature films too that were
kind of funny like Westerns and stuff and,
and all those characters have names.
They're all called like scape and muck
and whatnot and Mackay and never been
adequately scrambler you ever been at a
place like ordering something and a kid
go mr you Bob the builder and they always
pant like that right before they say
it to you, they're going to say, I can't
believe I heard your voice. I know,
but parents too,
parents will be watching this.
Parents will be watching Bob the boat
with their kids and all of a sudden they
tweet really,
really cause on my,
on my show it's smoke dope and drink
and you know, take drugs and do that.
And then they like, but then I don't
think it's that big of a dichotomy.
I mean it's for little kids,
why shouldn't I be a role model for
two year olds is swollen like speedy,
skip that one, let's call it once
again, it's, you know, little kids,
little kids cause someone's going to
pull, those are toxins. Shit like,
you know,
like cute.
I loved it because we would fly to
London and recorded in Soho and we would
order out. And I always, Scott Curry or
Chinese food, I mean like I love the Gig.
It was such,
there's a bar Italia on Dean street out.
Go there and have an espresso before
and then I'd go over and record.
And it was like, it was fun. It
was just fun. And the voices,
this voice show the storable
apart and went into the audition.
If I've told this before,
I'm sorry,
I went to the audition in London and I
was reading and I did all these funny
voices, you know, Oh,
this and that whatnot.
And a English person comes on over
the, you know, inner common cause,
uh, Greg, could you, uh, would it be
all right if you're just a jewel voice?
And I said, are you insinuating I
have a car 10 place? And uh, she went,
well, what did you try it one time?
So I went like, Oh, good for you,
Andy recycled. And then they
were like, perfect. Loved it.
They gave me the job right there. Wow.
That's never happened to me before.
Since with any job and do it in your
own voice the way I'm speaking to you.
It would Joe Rogan. Well, you're a
famous, you live out here in this place.
It's so nice here in Sunflower Valley.
You're famous enough comedian that I'm
sure they know exactly what you talked
like when they brought you in. I
think that was it. I said, listen,
let's be perfect, Greg.
Being Greg proven, I
spent 10 minutes doing other
ways at them going like, oh,
this isn't working out until one of them
came on and said they go, would you
like to do it in the studio? And I went,
ah yeah, I would. That'd be
really fun. So I ran out right
siding called my voice agent in London
and wet like fucking call them back right
now. You know what I mean though,
right. Let them think about it.
Don't let them get a Canadian. And I would
love to do voices. That was a fun one.
That lasted about three or
four years till they sold.
And this is what happens in show business.
This is a lot of Canadians on here
out there. It was hell yeah. Oh yeah.
Oh happy Canadian thanksgiving
by the way. Thank you. Oh,
powerful Canadian thanksgiving.
It is a very powerful and uh,
interchangeable Columbus Day of it.
Only because sometimes this is
the 12 sometimes it's Jane. Oh,
so today is or isn't. It is, it is,
but you know how this one's fluid,
like President Day, you know kids don't
get that off school anymore. No, no.
Funny when we were talking about it today,
like yeah,
cause they realize Columbus was
kind of a mass murderer. Right?
No holidays changed more in ethos from
the time we were a little to now. Well,
like Santa Claus didn't become a fucking
housebreaking know sexual violator.
Yeah,
you're right.
Like first it was Columbus discovered
America with those Santa Maria and the
Pinto Nina. And then it was, oh,
he never really got to America.
He was in The Bahamas or some shit.
And then it got to,
he's a murderer and just dashing babies'
heads on rocks and you hear the stories
of the year and they would force
people to get, bring them back gold.
And they would have to bring whatever
they weighed and gold every week.
And if they didn't, they'd cut
one of their arms off. Oh yeah.
So they do it to a couple people.
They cut their arm off
and everyone's screaming.
And so the rest of them just scramble
and go and get that gold. Like they,
they there. Do you remember the last
time I was on, we talked about Columbus,
cause you called them the new
original gangster. He really was.
Well I think everybody was gangster back
then. You know, the crown couldn't, yeah.
Wait,
it was when he got back after the
first one, it took a long time.
The other guy who hated him,
it was also co captain or the expedition
died for much to his good fortune.
He was in another boat. He
was in the Nina and uh, oh,
so Columbus got back after much ado.
Yeah.
You've got your Portugal almost crashed,
landed the whole fucking enchilada.
When he finally got to
Ferdinand and Isabella,
he had enough stuff with them from
that first journey. And by the way,
he left like 40 guys there.
Cause th the Santa Maria ran a
ground and it was fucking scuppered.
So he just left a bunch of fucking
guys in the Caribbean and they died.
They got in fights with the Indians
and died when he got back to Spain and
finally, finally got to a friend in
front of the king and Queen. He had a co,
you know, eight, 10 Indians
and some parrot and some
goals and some native shit.
And they went, you know,
their minds are blown.
No one knew there was
another world right now.
I mean people knew
there was another world,
but they didn't know that you
could go find a new one like that.
Like he came back with people from
another place who spoke Arawak and had
fucking monkeys. What the fuck
is this? Here's a bunch of men,
10 times more money,
a bunch more boats.
The second expedition was hugely funded
and he went up with horses, cannons,
the whole fucking Enchilada.
Wow.
The first one was like when you send
your friend to fucking Home Depot, you,
here's my car, don't use
the blinker. You know,
he barely made it there
and back on the first one.
And yes he did do all those
horrible things to the Indians.
He was had no notion of them as people.
He was a strict Catholic. He believed that
he'd been singled out by God. That too,
just the idea of custody,
those arms off cause they didn't bring
enough gold and doing it in front of
their family knew that if he didn't
produce precious goods for the Spanish
crown, that he wasn't going
to keep getting funded.
When he went back and that was the driving
to keep going and pushing through to
Asia was what he was after to find
China cause he knew there'd be ivory and
pearls and all that shite total. But look
what he look at it on the other hand,
within 20 or 30 years at Columbus,
now they're in Mexico.
And within another hundred years of that,
the largest silver mine in the world,
that giant mountain of silver,
that all of the silver of Asia for 400
years came from because of the Spanish
trade routes between China and shit.
They reduced a mountain of silver in
Mexico and some in South America too.
And you use the Indians to fucking do
it on the mountain of silver. I mean,
there's a book called 1493,
uh,
Charles Mann. Well, well, using Columbus
is the line of demarcation for everything.
There's a book called 1491 and a
book called 1492. And the vehicle,
because he's the first contact,
you know,
between west and east or between, between
the Americas and you and the old world.
And, uh, on his boat he had, he
was Italian. He had Portuguese.
If there was some Spanish there,
some genuine,
it's probably a couple of donations. Uh,
by the time Cortez, when Cortez came over,
which is what, 30 years after, there
was women conquistadores on his boat,
women concaves dead.
There was about two or three conquistador
has in his book why they don't tell
you all the fun stuff, kind of game of
Thrones. Exactly. Big giant warrior.
Imagine what a bad acid or you had to
beat a beyond that fucking mission and
Cortez burn the boats and took
a vote with everybody and said,
you want to go back or not? And
they were like, he goes, okay,
this is how it's gonna go. We know
where the capital of the [inaudible],
this is our mission and let's look.
And they got all the Indians along
the way and that's how they did it.
And they burned the boats.
They couldn't go back. Yeah.
But according to one book
I read by Bernal Diaz,
who was the last survivor of that mission,
he landed up in like Honduras or whatever,
the little ranch when he was old.
He writes the forward,
I'm old and I'm blind now,
but I'm going to tell you what the fuck
happened when on the mission with Cortez
and he'd been on a previous one with
another conquistador and then he says he
didn't just say we're burning
the boats. We took a vote. Whoa.
Captain General Cortez said to the boys,
parrot is you can go back to Cuba where
they were living or you can go back to
Spain where you got nothing horsch gold
and fucking glory in to notate lawn and
you may die and they may eat.
You eat your heart out.
Such an ability to take risks back then.
It's pretty extraordinary.
I mean the genocide and the Indians
is of course the disgusting part.
But I mean the Aztecs did have a
organized army and you know, it wasn't,
it wasn't a hundred Spanish guys.
They had tens of thousands
of Indians in their army.
When they finally laid the big battle out,
Columbus on the other hand just Kinda
maraud around the Caribbean and tried to
get these poor fucking Indians
who had no gold to give him gold.
And he was in the wrong country, man.
You know America's where gold as well.
Didn't they give him something at some
point in time they gave him a little
baubles but those bottles would come
from the mainland or child across the
Caribbean or from South America where
there was stuff and that they didn't have
any gold there. So they were weighing
little earrings and nose rings and Shit.
And He'd be like,
that was it though.
Total focus and they couldn't understand
it cause they're giving him chicks and
food and like, what else
do you want? We don't have,
we don't have fucking the gold.
And why is the Goldson wouldn't you?
It's not important to us.
They were like,
and he just went as soon as he saw any
gold. That was the end of that. We have,
how do they have this?
Obviously they have that one account from
Cortez you were talking about from one
of the people that,
oh there's loads of accounts of
Cortez cause there's friars that row.
How do they have these accounts?
Oh,
Columbus wrote a diary and a guy's
on the ship wrote diaries and a,
there's a famous a priest who was the
sort of the conscience of the new world
who decried the genocide against
the Indians from the very beginning.
And the Spanish kept meticulous records
and there's a giant library in Seville
called the library of the indies
where all of the Caucasians are doors.
Fucking documents are collated and
captain. So there's, that's awesome.
Are Legal Society. So you brought a priest
with you, you bought a notary with you,
you brought lawyers with you, you brought
generals with you, you brought a doctor,
you wrote shit down. You fucking,
when you took over a town,
you wrote a sign and
posted a crucifix sense.
So how much did you agree to the Indians
who can't understand you that you are
taking over their town and the
name of the King of Spain and Chin?
How much bullshit, all of that.
I mean, you know, so when the,
when they would tell their
version of the events,
how much of it was bullshit
histories all spinning, isn't it?
I don't think all of it's bullshit
because there's a lot of real,
also Indians wrote accounts later
who learns within a generation.
Obviously there's Mexicans,
which are the marriage of
Indians and Spanish. Right.
And uh,
within a generation,
all of the Aztec Nobles of which there
were lots and all the nobles in Mexico
from the Indian tribes married into rich,
you know, married into Spanish family.
So they were raised as rich people who
spoke Spanish now and they were able to
tell their stories as well.
There's a lot of first person
accounts by the explorers.
Cabeza de Vaca kept a diary and I mean is,
is great because it's so self serving,
you know,
o nit whole portions of the journey and
he doesn't mention some of the ratty
shitty did and the radish shit was all
ratted out by priests. Right? Yeah.
And then later expeditions
within by the second expedition,
guys were mutinying on and,
and,
and fucking going back to Spain
and ratting on and then vet.
He was a terrible and competent
fucking commander and that he had,
once they got on land, he was useless
and he didn't know how to handle it.
The Indians and there was always in her
violence with the cruise killing each
other and choosing sides and hiding on
different parts of the island from each
other and not doing
what he asked him to do.
He was a terrible commander on the sea.
The greatest thing you can
say about Columbus's, he's
an extraordinary navigator.
He knew that there was going to
be a trade wind and he caught it.
Having had some of that knowledge,
he knew that if he went down and got it,
he could come and get one back and I
think he guessed that he surmised that or
he knew from other sailors and shit that
you wouldn't actually get lost in die.
You could come back to
Europe from wherever you were
going in Asia and he didn't
have a a telescope.
This is previous to the telescope,
so he is dead reckoning and evidently
was terrible with instruments.
Like he had an astro lab and he had a
sextant but he couldn't fucking use them
very well.
So all of his reckonings in the book,
Andy kept two separate notebooks.
One with his navigational charts and
another with fake ones in case anybody
caught him cause he didn't want anybody
copying is root cause he thought he was
going to have the monopoly on going to
the new world. And so within of course,
20 years, within, within four years,
there's a whole bunch of other Spanish
vessels coming over and you know,
within 10 years it's all over.
There's growing lever.
So when he first starts writing it down,
you said he's writing,
he's not using instruments. He,
he could, he had instruments what?
They're crappy,
they didn't have any idea of longitude.
Right. Latitude was kind
of a free flowing affair.
If you had shit you could focus on
like stars or bodies of, you know,
islands or whatever
that you could navigate,
which is why those mounts of the
world always seems so small from them.
Um,
so he had to reckon by currents and
winds and the color of the water,
how the water,
the salinity of the water tasted.
They had a rope with thumbs on it,
marked in knots and that take soundings
to see how fucking deep the sea was.
And all of a sudden when they got near
and the crew was having a heart attack,
cause they'd been out for a couple months
and it's true. The crew was like, hey,
we're going to die. And he said,
calm the fuck down. And the next day,
uh,
clearly something a human had made,
like a carved paddle hit the boat
and they pulled it out than what,
you know,
there's something over there.
And then the next day a bunch of
branches and shit. And then birds.
And when there's birds and branches,
there's fucking islands.
And they knew then the men started to
get hip to the fact that he wasn't wrong,
that there was something over there.
And then of course see he said whoever
sees the island first gets a prize and
the guy in the middle of the night saw
the lights and he said when they got up
in the day,
I saw him last night
do shouted his crew never loved him.
What lights did he see?
Fires to? Indians were
burning. Oh Wow. Fascinating.
I know, right. That's amazing.
It's really weird to think
of their gear navies.
No rifles on the first expedition.
Maybe a couple,
not rifles like Arca buses that you lit
a fuse and put it in a breach and you
know you gotta pack it down, pack it
down with the ball, low crossbows,
a few costs. Suppose that was considered
real high tech to have those with you.
That was a big deal to have like an
organized group of Cross Bowman because an
organized group across group Bowman
could wipe out lots of people out.
Whatever's accurate.
Yeah,
the armor thing never worked out for
them with all the conquistadores.
Within a few weeks they'd all fucking
started wearing the Indians armor because
it was too hot,
too much stuff.
They were metal and metal rots
in the jungle and shit and this,
so the Indians had fabulous cotton
textiles that made, made, you know,
so Columbus is
his journals.
They were all his own way
of measuring the salinity,
his own way of measuring
the color of the water.
So he would just describe
that like that's how he knew
she had been at sea
since he was a teenager.
Genewiz tended to go to ca cause they
were slave traders and there was always a
tradition of slavery in Genoa,
which is why he didn't
perceive the Indians is people
as much as his first thing
he wrote back was like, I think we found
a bunch of slaves here, you know? Wow,
we can use these people to build stuff.
And then of course their temperament was
not that way and he didn't manage any
of the situations.
Right.
And he betrayed everybody and that's
why it all went so horribly shitting.
All those Indians are dead.
There's no Caribbean Indians.
It's just weird when you stop and think
about what a short amount of time ago
that was. Oh my God. So
short days, it was 500 years.
Seems like a long time for one person.
But once you've been alive for a little
while and like you're in your forties
and you start looking and going,
you know that didn't take that long.
It seemed like he moved pretty quick.
How many of these are left?
How many of them do you get in the life?
My mother was 94 when she passed away.
That five of those born in 1919
yeah. Five lives. Birth to death.
And you're dealing with like the most
horrible atrocities that you know we have
like on record,
there was no chat lines when my mother
was born. There was no, it's so weird.
Ads are growing up in Columbus,
Ohio because that's named
after Christopher Columbus.
And there's all these
fucking statues everywhere.
Like just like celebrating this man and
you grew up in school celebrating the
sky and it's just weird now like reading
what we looked at the men and not at
any other reality. Keep talking. Should
we? Oh, okay. We can adjourn if you like.
I know. Right? And if you go to Seville,
there's a giant statue of him. Uh,
and there's one in Barcelona to,
you're looking out over the scene.
And then the statue in Seville is in the
cathedral and he's being carried in a
litter,
you know,
by four Indians from different tribes
and they're wearing their Indian garb.
And he's in a big brass.
But I are like that.
And his foot is rubbed completely
shiny cause it's good luck to rub.
Columbus's put in,
Seville was on a river and every year
when the fleet would come back to treasure
fleet from the new world,
they'd be ladened down like almost to
the water line with fucking gold and
precious goods and people and stuff.
And they'd come up the river and there
was a chain across the river and Sybil
and they'd pull the chain out and,
and it sail up the river.
And that was a big event every year
because when the treasure fleet came back,
it was like, and of course Spanish
people got none of that money.
It's just the crown.
And then what did they do?
Wage war against the French in the hall,
the Dutch and the English for fucking
300 years and blew all the money.
Did you see that,
uh, document that documentary
about Sunset Boulevard?
No. You should really see, are we
still trying to get the director?
We're working on that. The history of
sunset. It's real interesting. Oh yeah.
How old are they used
to have one like street,
like dirt road going down the street.
And that's really,
that's a really cool movie. I recommend.
I'd like to I think make a map.
Well I know I saw another
one that was about like,
you know that its heyday in the 60s and
all that jazz when it was go go joints
and Zeros.
You watched a documentary on Ciro's?
Well it included sue us and then it had
the riots and you know Jim Morrison and
whiskey in the hall,
you know like a groovy that's right.
Their whiskies on sunset.
Yeah.
What a fucking street facing rain that
to be across the street from the store
before the House of Blues used
to be a hotel, I believe. Yeah.
I just drove by it today.
But then there's that high at that's
next stored to the comedy store or that's
two doors down.
And if you remember the newly sergeant
pepper's lonely hearts club band,
let Peter Frampton they stay in that
hotel cause they come out of that inosine.
Really? Yeah. The one
with the Skybar no, no.
The one on the other side of the street
on the comedy store style though.
Right back a tiny.
What does that,
what's the hotel kind of that
standard is a standard, uh,
our, is that what it is? Something
like something like that.
It's for some fancy Schmancy, very
nice hotel. But the um, that's on,
that's that area like out has
an insane look. That view.
That's what that is. Yeah. Well there's,
there's so many spots like that on that,
those hotels there,
they all have little pools and
scenes at the pool and all that jazz.
You weren't in a,
where are you in San Francisco
when that guy jumped off the roof?
That was before your time, right?
Wait, before you talked to the Hyatt,
the who was protesting during
the Jay Leno days. Oh golly. The,
the comedy store. And the Improv,
I guess comics were like picketing.
They were on like, oh Golly, day back.
What was that? That was like, wait,
that wasn't a seven Letterman when
let him, it was a standout. Oh,
was it really that far? Yeah, that's
right. Well, they, um, they, uh, you know,
that's like kind of a famous spot,
right?
Just trying to get any money for science.
Yeah.
It's a weird thing that they're working
for free and Hollywood and we still do,
I still do shows for free all the time.
Yeah.
Well I think it's important to
work out a lot. So, you know,
doing those free shows, it's good.
Let's you fuck around guilt free,
try out new shit.
And like,
sometimes I'll go up and
I'll intentionally put myself
in like a little bit of a
hole by just starting out with
an idea that's kind of half ass,
like panic my way into figuring
the way through the bit. You know,
I wouldn't do that in a regular show,
but uh, one of those. Yeah. Yeah.
One of those just show up shows.
Those are, um, they're interesting.
They're good but good to fuck
around. Free range chicken. Yeah.
That's the other good thing about La man.
There's an amazing community comedians
out here, but think about that.
Just the sheer volume of clubs
and comedians and the breadth,
like every type of Canadian, oh, he
got to these other towns and you know,
you go everywhere and I'll work in
a place in God's will be like, oh,
I don't know if I were to move to Atlanta.
I'm like,
he advised that if he got to
a place on a Tuesday night,
you're following fucking patent
and Sarah Silverman and shit.
Like he didn't just walk into it.
You know I got your game.
Your game has to get you came together.
If I want him to shut someone down,
I would love to have a Greg
Proops announcement like
that would be an incredible
service that you could
provide. Be advised, like the
way you would phrase things,
if you continue this down,
the road of altercation with my
client results will be catastrophic.
I think you'll find the uncertain times.
I advise.
Great caution in that regard.
Now you can't just a
swan up here and I mean,
I think the only important
thing in La is like,
I remember reading it
in a magazine years ago,
a guy like said the three important
things about being in La. He's like, no,
why you're here. What's the
number one wine? He goes,
if you're here to sleep with people,
then that's what you're here for. Yeah,
I'm fucking bullshit me and tell me a
riding it thing. Right? If you're writing,
write that thing. There is a lot
of that, right? Well that's the,
he said the reason why you're here,
do you, the reason why you're here.
And then the second one was returned
your fucking calls, which I thought was,
those are two good pieces. I mean
if people go to lunch, go to la,
but a little bit like a teach come to
be an actor, teach, come to be a comic.
Did you come to write it then? You know,
not that you can't do them all at once,
but if you're going to say you're a comic,
you got to go out and work
every night and be, do comedy,
you have to be seen and
doing in my opinion.
You say you want to be a comment until
you make a living doing comedy and then
you say I'm a comic. Yeah cause there's
a lot of comics out there and I get it.
You're still a comedian.
I guess you are still a complex sort of.
There's a lot of guys who actually
never graduated from open mic.
I don't want to mention any names but
they're really funny guys. They just,
I guess those are the,
that gets my argument.
My argument just fell apart because
they got yourself stuck comics. Yeah.
Well the whole goal was
to make a living on it.
When you first start to make money at it,
you can't believe that
you're getting any money.
And then when you start to make a living
at it, which chicken takes a long time.
I think it took care of
not just starting now.
That's what's weird to me cause I
took advantage of the web. You know,
as a comedy, you know, we're
selling our special on the web.
We do our fucking shows on the web.
This wasn't available to us, man.
And the promotion and the ability,
the ability to be you on your podcast.
Like we were talking about
that before we even started,
like no one would really
let you do that. No, no one.
I would just say great proves just
here's the, you know, two hours.
This kit it right, right here. We
won't say anything. We'll fucking,
everything you do, love it or hate it will
be positive and you fucking high five.
You know, now that someone's
always going to have enough.
I know that was never going
to happen in the old ship is,
and so I kind of like this,
uh,
what you should do guys do sort of like
an odd couple shows since you've been
emailing back and forth with that dude,
get that dude on the podcast with you
and he gets to sit next to you and go,
yeah,
well here's a bunch of fucking bunch of
bullshit.
It's a bunch of liberal bullshit.
I didn't call me to hear liberal
bullshit. All right. Right.
And just keep me honest the whole time.
The king, what the fuck is this bullshit?
It's a good idea. It could
be like sort of, you know,
like some sort of a top art type thing.
He likes red meat.
It'd be a good battle, Greg.
It's keen law, each other.
Men's Dicks. Do you, um,
uh, read, uh, any, uh,
you have like a regular
reader of history books?
Is that how you know so much about
Columbus or you just fascinated by that?
Well,
I read a bunch of Columbus books.
There's one called the four
of wages by Larry Bird drawn.
Then there's Columbus's own version.
I was playing in Bloomington,
Indiana at that nice a comedy club
there. And uh, I haven't been,
there was a bookstore in Bloomington.
Bloomington's God the attic. Okay.
And uh,
in the bookstore I found Columbus as the
four voyages and I'd already read this
other guy's book and this was
Columbus as account and if,
and his son Bartella Mayo and then
someone else too. So I thought, well,
I'll read it as account and see
what the fuck him, you know,
to get another source.
And then right now I'm reading a book
about Da Vinci painting the last supper
and stuff like that. It
was pretty, you know,
these people don't seem like people,
you know,
like you say you are
disconnected from the reality of,
but then when you think like,
uh, it's set in this book,
like Davinci would write like notes like
uh, got a German kid work and for me,
you know,
like it is notebook.
How'd you go to the store? I needed
to buy socks or whatever. You're like,
it makes it more, and the Davinci didn't
spend all this time making masterpieces.
He designed sets and costumes for loads.
You know,
they're always having events in pageants.
He was in a royal court,
so he did a lot of that.
He invented like stage such that opened
up and there'd be freaky shit inside
everybody. Oh my God.
Like he did special thugs.
He was unbelievably brilliant and
sketched all the time, period.
A book with them all the time.
So you don't always have the notebook.
That's why there's so much of his stuff
left. Cause he wrote so many notebooks.
Yeah. And when you start thinking about
the people that have though of that day,
the Leonardo Davinci's, the
Michelangelo's, the great,
great artists of the past.
It's hard to wrap your head around
what their life must've been life.
No medicine, you know, they
have nothing. Barely nothing.
No. The band. And he had some saws.
If your fucking leg studio is pretty
big though, it wasn't really. Yeah.
The one he had an uh,
Milan was pretty big because his patron
gave him like a used calsl they weren't
using anymore. So he had a nice big
space and a few guys working for him.
And I share a little Italian kid that
stole all the time and would buy candy
with the money stolen shit. Oh yeah. I
like, it becomes a little more human,
you know,
and that he's just gay basically.
He's just gay kid one really says anything
like Leonardo as queer and apparently
really good looking and amazingly
strong could bend a horseshoe.
This is the last thing you want a
gay guy who could bend a horse shoe.
Just devastatingly handsome, strongest,
a better artist in you, funnier than you.
Better musician than he played the
lion's gay. That's the balance.
Gay and the dental. He, he was real witty
guy who lived hundreds of years ago.
Well talk,
he's so famous still because he was
the life of the goddamn renaissance,
you know.
Oh I'm sure.
Well I mean you talk about
bad motherfuckers who've
named have carried through
the ages. Leonardo,
Stephanie Nardo, Davinci.
I mean he did so many
amazing illustrations.
Some the human body and its ideas of,
you know,
his ideas of how to sculpt things and how
to draw things and how to space things
was so advanced and brilliant.
It is ridable like placement
of the images and his work.
There's so there's like, you know, when
they do studies of, of works of art,
like what is appealing
about certain pieces of art?
It's so difficult to
like count the tangibles.
Like what is it as a sense of symmetry?
Is it the depth of perception of,
of distance and space? What is it
about this piece? It's so remarkable,
remarkable and striking.
And because it's not necessarily
always the subject matters,
how the subject matter's displayed and
there's so many variables. It could be,
it could look so different. So weird. So,
so when a guy comes along like Leonardo
Davinci and you look at his stuff and
you go, fuck God damn, this
dude nail it. He just nailed it.
He spent all his time studying motion and,
and visual effects that he has no
books filled with how the water looks,
when it's misty, how the water looks,
when it's rough, how the water looks,
when it's a tempest, when there's
a storm, when it's calm, when like
he felt like artists should walk
around and watch people all the time.
He had insane notebooks of every kind
of movement of every kind of person of
every and the physiognomy ones. I just
saw when I was in Scotland, they had,
and then a museum there when I was at
Edinburgh and we went and saw all of his
physiological notebooks and there
was all these uh, anatomists.
Now talking about this is
more advanced than what we do.
Look at the perspective
on how each of the hands,
he had corpses and he just spent days
and weeks and months and years fucking
studying out the tendons worked and
drawing these intricate and unbelievably
anatomically correct from
shaded perspectives, you know,
from many perspectives,
not just, you know,
just so that he could have almost
like a database visual. Yeah.
His visual cognition.
It's just like far past any,
but I think it was because
he made a study of every,
which is why I think he determined that
you could make machines that will fly in.
I don't think it was great leaps of
imagination. He studied birds, you know,
and he studied everything. Like he was
a, they didn't call it science then,
but you know, as a scientist. Yeah.
That's the thing is that he wasn't really
bogged down by an a title so much as
he would be today.
Being an art.
I mean it's hard to be an artist and an
inventor today unless you're like Kanye
West.
He can do
both. Oh, and a holy figure. The
smaller spiritual leader from my,
my thing here, people, the props
people, the proofs or so per person.
Do you guys call each other the
pupil Lupus Pruett balloons.
We watched Prue Lu, uh,
wheat for proofs. Um,
and our slogan is don't look back.
Something might be proofing on.
Is that your a theme? It is our thing.
Sorry, I'm still hurting at that ground.
Zero. That cassette away way
back in 1988 tonic. So sad.
She was hot as fuck.
Super Hot.
Damn.
Well that was when she got in front of
them and print a crotch in his face while
he was driving. That was the part of the
video. Like someone's gonna get hurt.
It's all fun and games when someone's
got their skip and your face,
until women just looked different back
then with the crazy hair and the men had
the crazy hair too crazy
hit both crazy hair.
Remember she was on a Jaguar?
Oh yeah.
Flipping around the jailer
and unforgettable and
doing the splits and shit.
I know what it means to walk along.
Yeah. There's a lonely road or something
like that. Just dreams, but not,
there's the music of that era that
was like what happened to America?
What happened to the world?
What happened to the
consciousness of the human beings?
Is it because they were
denied psychedelics?
I really wonder because if you look at
the difference between the music in the
1970s from 1970 to the music of the
1980s there's some weird sort of a,
like a detached gets more Koki
and less, less jugging. Yeah,
and it's this weird detachment,
but from, from real, you know,
if you go back to this day,
like listen to Voodoo child,
listen to the live version of
it, how organic it, it's insane.
It's insane how good fucking song is.
It's insane how good that guitar solo is.
It like hurts your brain but then go
and listen to some shit from the 80s you
know,
that was like really popular back then
that you might've liked and you'll be
like,
what the fuck was wrong with these people?
Like she'll look at the movies they made.
You'll look at,
look at the movies they made,
some of the movies they made in the 80s
and then go back and think about some of
the shit they made in the sixties and
seventies and it still holds up today.
Like the hustler,
you know,
things that reflect the human condition
instead of weird science. There's some,
there were some amazing
Gainey's feeds back then.
There were some amazing like who's
afraid of Virginia Woolf still holds up.
Oh yeah. It still holds
up. Well writing, you know,
writing and characters. Right,
but why did that go away?
Why didn't that get better? Everything
gets better. If you look at today's era,
if you look at like from if you go back
to like father knows best and then you
look at today with like say like
homeland or the game of Thrones,
the writing has gotten so much better.
The shows we've gotten so much better.
There's such an incredible like evolution
of culture that's so blatantly obvious
on, on television. Yeah. So why
doesn't that exist for what happens?
Where's that blip?
That weirdness from from the 70s to
the eighties to the nineties and two
thousands they like finally like rock
the shit back straight and got Jesus,
what the fuck are we doing? And now
they're making all this amazing shit.
But they were making amazing shit. They
were making the twilight zone. They were,
they had really original interest in
programming in twilight zone is fucking
brilliant to this day. Scifi plays
repeats and I set it, set it on my Dvr,
wants just thinking this would be fun.
Something to watch one night and
I'm bored and I'm just hooked.
Watching walling after the, I watched
three, four in a row. They're amazing.
They're so good. They all have three
writing is so good and they're concise.
Captain Kirk, when William Shatner was,
when he was going through that, uh,
the machine that tells you your future.
Yeah. Oh my God. That's a good episode.
I love that show. Burgess Meredith. Oh,
that one survives the end of the world.
Don't forget. Oh my God. It's
incredible. I don't even want to give us,
can you say,
spoiler alert on a twilight zone
from 1963 he can because I find that,
I think I talk about things
on my show that I think, well,
everybody knows this and then he
[inaudible]. Everybody doesn't know.
Everybody's frame of
reference is different than
people at different ages and
they didn't grow up with that.
Sell peep.
There's people out there listening
right now who are like twilight tone.
What does this show you speak of?
They don't even know about the movies.
This purchase Meredith you speak of are
just married and just married man. Yeah,
he, yeah. Spoiler alert. He played a guy
that really wanted books. Just be alone.
I can't tell you anymore.
[inaudible] you anymore.
The other great. William Schachter.
One man on the plane. Yeah.
Fuck. That was crazy. The
fucking outfit is so bad.
It's just terrible. So bad. Yes.
Tara, we played it on the podcast.
We showed the clip of the monster, the
monster, like a monkey with a helmet on.
Kind of. It's a furry, yeah, he's a furry.
It really does the of for if you
haven't seen it, Brian Polo Shit up man.
On the wing of the plane. William
Shatner. Twilight zone. Just images.
Yeah. Incredible. But just
the, the sheer originality.
Like they were on to something and then
you know, later you got the fall guy.
Like what happened? They get sued. He
got, you know, some stupid shit, man.
Older girls,
some good show.
Magnum Pi was a good cognitive cop drama.
He sort of had a message and you know,
he was a guy like searching for truth.
Look at this fucking thing.
Ah,
look how bad that thing is.
There's some other images, Bri,
where it's actually on the plane where
you get a whole body. Oh, it's us do.
There it is to the left over.
That is, oh my God, that's stupid.
Yeah.
Why was it a furry?
That is the least scary thing that's ever
been a scary part was just that you'd
be looking at your,
I think that the jet plane experience
was so sexy and exciting in the early
sixties so like, oh my God,
there's a monster on the way.
Well that was actually a propeller plane.
Oh, is it? Yeah. That's a propeller plane.
The guy actually puts his fingers in
the propeller and gets it and hurts his
finger and he's like, stop it. Oh,
he's so nice. He said that. Yes.
He was like poking at the, uh, the, the
helicopter blade propeller assignments.
You know, that's not the same amount on
that. I am the same animal. That's you.
That's me. Cute little dog. That's a
little crippled Lebanon. Yeah. Well what,
I mean I just wonder what happened that,
that weird cultural blip.
The eighties essentially it's the
eighties where it seems like things just,
it really does feel like there was
like a slide, like, like, oh, like,
like the culture got rocked and for
like a decade and how to recover.
And then through the nineties is like
biggie getting its feet back under it and
you start seeing like really good
comedy and a lot of good things start
happening and then boom, it's bad. I
don't know. I liked the A's, but yeah,
I know what you're saying.
It wasn't the deepest decade of all Tom,
although in the 70s everybody kept
calling it the me decade and that we were
really shallow and I kind of
enjoyed the 70 shares. Yeah,
well the eighties were a big coke era.
You're definitely right about that.
I wasn't that cookie
then, but yes, it was.
And I think everything was
informed by that. Yeah.
And also there's the rise
of like capitalist heroes,
which I always hated Gordon Gekko
types. Yeah. And the whole Reagan thing,
and I dunno, I just, I never dragged
out part. You've always, well,
you're from San Francisco and you're
super liberal, man. Yeah. No matter what,
you'll always be super liberal.
That's true. This is, I'm
waiting for the tweeters.
He had a true off, you
know, I didn't tune in.
I didn't pay no money to gene in and
listen to this for free to hear proofs
jockeys fucking fruity bag shit.
Well your points of view are all based
on, you know, a pretty,
very pretty reasonable ethical
standard and your ideas are all,
you know, very progressive, open minded.
I didn't, you're not a ridiculous person.
I've known you for a long time.
You're,
you're very well thought out and all the
things that you say when there's some
people though that also pulled opinion
similar to yours that need to be
throttled.
I couldn't agree more there on my team
and I don't want them on my team and
that's why I don't like my team and
that's why I try to stay on my own team
because I'd act ya this George Carlin said
I'm on the sidelines. You know, there's
no doubt there's some annoying as
fuck people on the right as well.
But something makes me really upset
when I find like really aggressive
progressive people like
overly aggressive progressive,
the point of like causing like arguments
that are totally unnecessary and
feeling completely in
the right for doing it.
It's like really loud and Barky
version of progressive ideology.
It's like,
well, also I like, I like a
little more open minded as to let,
she liked to be the overriding notion,
not my way.
Right in your way and strong.
Like I would have smoking in bars.
I don't see that as wrong.
It's a health issue.
You say that because you smoke and I
think you enjoy it and I am all for
personal choice. I'm all for, you
should be allowed to have a bar.
That's what I say.
What I meant was I would have bars with
smoking and then bars without smoking.
I think the devil could do that. Would
you or were you allowed to do that before?
Were you allowed to say no smoking in your
establishment before the laws changed?
I remember a comedy club. Oh, and
they witness who came in on the road.
Let's, nevermind this. Looking at
you a million different issues of uh,
but this,
the legal age of drinking,
if he can vote when you're 18 then
why is it 21 to drink and would
you be able to go to war when you're
seven? Thank you. And you, you can't,
you kill some money,
but you can't like figure out whether or
not this is ego that's ego or this has
beneficial that he should be informed.
I think eventually, hopefully,
and I've said this to Ad Nauseum,
I think we're going to be
able to vote on the Internet.
We're going to see a radically different
version of what people want and don't
want. And that's the only way this country
has ever really going to be at peace.
That's the only way people are
ever going to really be at peace.
We need like a council of elders,
a council of wise men that
that sort of display th they,
they get on television and with no
vested interest educate people on what's
wrong with the system and how the world
works and what direction they advise
that we act.
Then the people just vote on everything
that fucking happens and everybody gets
to do it on your fucking phone and yes,
there's gonna be some disastrous results.
Miley Cyrus would probably be the first
president, but we'll work that shit out.
We'll figure out what's not fuckers like
that. They're always going to be that.
But we'll figure that out eventually.
And with the education and the access
to information that's also available
because of this,
I don't think we really completely
wrapped her head around the impact.
The Internet has honest. No.
We look at the stuff from like,
I'm watch this documentary searching
for sugar man. Yeah, I saw it.
It really interesting.
Right. And I just started it.
It was only a 40 minute plane ride
from San Francisco this weekend,
but when I was listening, which
has happened, Brian would just to,
what happened, one of the lights
is was making some noises.
Oh, okay. That was, yeah,
those weird, it's the one under
the table here near me. Yeah.
But what was fascinating
was watching that, that V,
I mean it's a real time machine.
When you look at the footage of the use
and that film of like driving around
Detroit in the 1970s beautifully,
beautifully shot,
but you get this sense of this,
this weirdness of that time,
you know that just be,
and then you just stop and think about
the life that we're living right now and
how fucking weird that's going to be from
people in the future when they try to
digest like these were the
first motherfuckers to have
the Internet, right? The,
the whole world as the Internet now we're
so used to it cause it's been here for
500 years,
but back then the world went upside down.
The government started falling, people
started getting access to information.
Religion started declining and
previously never before reported numbers.
But the point where there's
real legitimate scientific
studies that say within
the next hundred years,
there may not be any religion.
Like it may be like a really rare thing.
Like that's how crazy the world is moving.
That's how fast it's moving and
that's how much things are changing.
They're just changing in front of our
eyes to the point where it's, it's,
it's just a normal part of everyday life.
Hey, I don't know, Google it. You boop,
boop, tweet me. Oh my God, I've got to
retweet that. It's crazy story. Bam,
and then everybody else does it.
Then you've got millions of people
that are doing it to each other,
sending it and sending
it and sending that that,
that new distribution of information that
can't be underestimated that that's on
a world changer. It's a world changer.
We didn't have it 10 years ago. No,
10 years ago fit 10 native,
but it wasn't as like this,
this is, this is so beneficial.
20 years ago. No Way. Not at all.
There's a lot of cons online for sure,
but you can find some really cool pockets
of people online to some really Nice,
interesting, friendly people.
There's a gang of message boards.
There's a gang of, of people that
you can connect to on Twitter,
so really unique time, like is it the
amount of people that you interact with?
I think that it's more people kind of
availed themselves of what a tool it is.
You can learn a lot off your
computer or your phone or you can,
but people don't ease it for that.
They just go on Facebook or,
yeah, so a lot of that.
Well, that's so easy.
I need my own personal porn blocker
when someone comes over my house and I
have to show them something. My Youtube,
I have to type Y o u t very quickly
because it wants to go to [inaudible].
You know how like I predict at least
it's huge is and not something else and
that's, yeah, you suck my cock.
Oh yeah. I like it in jail.
You Ooh,
I like it up my butt.
This whenever you want end to
end. Right now. We can keep going.
We can do whatever we want. I could
go, there's no reason you can go.
You can leave or you could
go. You could talk. No,
I probably should go pretty soon. You
should leave pretty early. We can stop.
We've been doing like couple hours. I
got a couple of hours, right? Yeah. Well,
you don't want a cine that even it's too,
I've been two hours, about two hours,
two hours and almost 15 minutes. Yeah,
that's a nice long length for podcasts.
I was enjoyable.
We did with the last thing I ever want
it to be is not enjoyable anymore.
So like when your time is up, but when
you look at career clock and you go, hmm,
I gotta be somewhere.
We just have to look at them.
We just have became a man
and a bestowed your, your,
your beautiful wisdom upon us.
Thanks for having me again.
Thank you for letting me annually come
back and talk about Columbus ad nauseum.
You can come back anytime you want and
talk about the same shit over and over
again and I don't give a
fuck. I appreciate it. Joe.
Your show is very
intellectually engaging and a,
I don't think there's anything like it,
uh,
of all the shows because uh,
you know,
you're willing to explore any
and all areas and uh, and uh,
and take on a lot of different
philosophies in this. Yeah,
there's no question and answer. It's
fantastic. It's just a free flowing
well, there's so much out there in the
world. I think at this point in time,
there's so many different things to think
about in so many different subjects to
cover and so many different
fascinating things to discuss.
And as long as you discuss it like
that, you know of you, you, you just,
you just look at things objectively
and openly and you try not to have any
personal biases going into them and
try to look at every different angle.
The world is a fascinating, fascinating,
fascinating place. There's just, it's,
I think we're in this weird boiling time.
It's like never before seen
summation. I feel panicked and I
feel uh, chased and I feel, you know,
yeah. I think everybody does
that right now is a real weird
feeling in the air.
Yeah. I worry about the everything
across the board from the ocean,
right to the, the melting and the
polar ice caps. I worry about the,
the threat of war. I worry about drone
attacks. I worry about nuclear disasters.
There's so much that can go wrong, but
yet it's still so exciting. Oh, of course.
There's the amazing time to be alive.
We're so lucky.
There's always the sun in the man, you
know? There's so much shit going on, man.
There's so much awesome comedy going on.
There's so many funny people and great
movies and there's just so much great
music and like the,
I think our culture right now this time
were people like anybody can just enter
into the fray, write a blog, make
some music, put it up online.
She made people share it, right? The show
us, show us your comedy, put it up online.
People share it. I mean this, this times,
it's never been anything like this.
The rules are off. That's
the best part. Yeah.
The rules are off and it's being used
in [inaudible] ways in some sometimes,
but overall the, I think that's
going to settle down. I really do.
I have faith in people.
I might be unwarranted faith.
I have faith in people based in what
I've seen from, from friends, their,
you know,
their emotional and physical growth
and what I've seen from more emotional
obviously, but, and when
I've seen from our culture,
I think that's one of the weird things
about who we are right now is the fact
that we're in the middle of all this
chaos and all this war and all this,
all the, all the racism and sexism and
all this devastating shit that we have.
On top of that,
we also have information that's flowing
like a raging river and no one can stop
including the government.
No one can stop it.
And people were organizing things and
there's some attempts that morning,
you know, like there's some occupy
Wall Street things that like,
it's a great idea and they're
focusing on this area,
but we're not exactly sure what happens.
But then there's anonymous that
goes after people. And then there's,
there's bitcoin guy who they
just, uh, they just, uh,
arrested who was running that
um, uh, Silk Road, Silk Road.
He lost all his bitcoins, right?
They took all his bitcoin.
Bitcoin's just went out of business.
Get coins went out of business too.
I think so.
I think it's the whole thing she does.
I think that was my croquet mallet
collection. These things to me,
I would like like the medical marijuana
of 1994 it's like once you open up the
door to that, give it 10 years
and watch what the fuck you guy.
You're going to have something crazy
10 years later after that 2013 what did
they have? Yeah, it fucking
madness. The streets of Los Angeles.
Every way you look as a fucking pot store.
Everywhere you look is a billboard with
a doctor that's willing to prescribe
[inaudible] for anything.
My favorite ones on a Melrose,
I've been doing this for eight plus years.
It says
the doctor I'd been giving out
prescriptions for potheads.
That's so fun, isn't it? It's fantastic.
Yeah. No, you're right man. You're right.
I think that's the exciting
part of being alive.
Cause then I get through the news and
Shit on my shit and then people could go.
It's so depressing Greg. There's
no future. And I'm like, oh,
there's loads of future.
And I always feel like the editing is
the hidden element or not so hidden. Um,
young people of today don't have the
same mindset. So in 20 years time,
all of what we think is real and what's
happening isn't happening anymore.
And I think that's exciting too.
They don't give a shit about gay marriage
or any of these sticky issues that
were still hung up on. Nah, like
shutting the government down.
The government of 2040 is
the same. Government is today
and dead without a doubt.
Yeah. I mean there's some
people I'm sure in [inaudible],
but there's less and less dummies now.
I think as people realizing
that there's this,
there's an impact for the douchey sexism
or homophobia or whatever it is that
they're doing, there's an impact.
That impact hurts other people.
When you say concrete things to people,
it affects them.
When you have an attitude about people,
it affects them and then other people
affect you, they show displeasure of you,
and then you sort of get a balance.
I think that's what the,
the distribution of information does.
It allows people to even
things out a little bit easier.
And I think it also
ultimately as he ultimately,
it's going to make me feel
more kind because right now
they're able to do things
with without warrior the consequences
because they can do things anonymously
like you Facebook and
things along those lines.
I don't know how much
longer that's going to last.
It doesn't seem like it's
going to last that much longer.
It seems like eventually people
are gonna know who you are.
If you're posting things and then people
are going to be able to comment if they
know who you are,
they're going to be able to go.
Why did you say that to that guy? That
was fucking unbelievably douchey. Like,
hey man, the way you handled
that as wrong, or hey,
I really liked the way you
handled that. Or Hey, you know,
I really loved how you diffuse
that situation. You know,
and then we're going to get a lot more
feedback from a lot more different people.
Yeah, we're in for some
strange times. Greg proof.
It's a strange ride.
Let's burn one and see what happens.
Du Du du, Du du Greg
Proops. Thank you very much.
The smartest in the world podcast.
You can get it on iTunes as your website,
Greg proops.com
if you got it,
Greg [inaudible] dot com you can download
it there and you can get my native
video on October 22nd.
You can preorder it.
I will. I'm looking forward to that.
I'm going to watch that. I can't wait.
You're a very funny comedian and uh,
I'm glad you do both things.
I'm glad you do your, you don't set any
boundaries for yourself. I like that.
That's what you want to do and I love that
you do that. Thank you. That's awesome.
So, um, go support Greg Proops,
you fucking savages and a support
squarespace.com if you're looking for a
website,
make your own bitch.
Use the code word Joe 10 and save 10%
off your first purchase on new accounts
you freaks.
And thanks all sorts of
hulu.com now with Hulu plus,
you can watch your favorite
shows any time, anywhere.
Original exclusive content
and including Hulu originals,
the awesomes starting SNL,
Seth Meyers and Moon Boys' starring
Chris O'Dowd from bridesmaids.
So it's only seven 99 a month.
Go get it.
Hulu plus.com/rogan forward
slash don't ever backslash pitch.
Okay, let's shits rude. All right,
we'll see you guys very soon. Brian,
you got anything?
Yeah. October 31st we're having a
huge Halloween show in San Diego
to be spooky, Spooky American
comedy co in San Diego, California.
I should do that place. That place is
awesome. Justin's amazing. There we go.
We're going to be there with
Tony Hinchcliffe, Sam Tripoli,
and also talking to a bunch of
special guests, including some Jew.
Oh, that Ari guy. Um, Wednesday night
I'm at the Ice House. Wednesday night,
10:00 PM show at the Ice House. Me, uh,
probably Tommy buns and we're going
to call a bunch of other people.
You want to go?
Sure.
Hey, go on a cleanse day, partly the
chin, uh, west Hollywood to my pocket.
So, uh, Steven Pressfield tomorrow
we'll see you. Good luck. God bless.
And Jihad.