Young Jamie [inaudible].
Merry Christmas motherfuckers.
Brendan sharp with the Gucci Shoes on.
How dare you,
how dare you,
and he's got cammo with Polka dots.
I want to suggest for you,
it says blind on one shoe and love on
the other.
Oh Lord.
How dare you even leave just for you.
The shows you did much soccer.
He liked those shoes.
The shoes I wore just for you.
It's a little bit of romance,
a little bit of my style camera with
Polka dots on it.
The Day George Michael Died.
It's like a good,
it's good jacket to have on.
What did he die of?
He'd had a heart attack apparently.
Yeah,
that one was hard for me.
Really fucking love that guy.
That song freedom.
That's what fucking jam.
That song has like four parts.
People don't understand that there's
like,
I think it's four,
but there's every part is just amazing.
That's a great fucking song.
I'm a little too.
I wish I could play it be we.
We'll definitely get kicked off of
youtube if we play it and we put it on
Youtube.
But there's,
there's that video that they made with
all those supermodels.
So Christy Turlington and all those,
all those,
uh,
Naomi Campbell and all those different
supermodels in their all wandered around
and there's,
they're singing the song,
they're like lip sync and hence the
video.
Yeah,
it's fucking amazing.
Yeah.
I just know they'd wake me up before he
coco that's in zoo lander.
He had some ridiculous songs,
you know,
I think freedom is the only one I ever
like.
I didn't like,
you know,
like wake me up before we go,
go,
come on.
That's a terrible,
there's the video.
It's awesome.
Did you like,
I want your sex.
I'm not mad at it wasn't a fan of that.
It sounds like these are fucking shot.
The kids.
Awesome.
He's so good on his knees with a
undercover cop or something like that
and,
and no one gave a shit like no one gave
me.
She was loud about good.
Who Cares?
So wait a minute,
here's my problem with that.
What the fuck did the undercover cop say
to get him on his knees and suck his
Dick Restroom?
No.
How did it start off?
It wasn't like,
Hey,
I bought those lakers.
No,
he was probably like,
Hey,
you want you to dick suck.
I'll suck your Dick.
You suck mine.
Like he probably said something probably
don't say Suck Dick.
They probably got code word code words
Woodward's right.
You want some sausage,
Bro?
What'd they say?
We're looking for Bro.
I looked for some friendship.
Friendship.
Great.
I got some friendship boy.
Yeah.
Do you remember when that,
um,
that Sam,
was he a senator or congressman or some
shit?
That guy was an anti gay
crusader.
We always,
my favorite dudes got caught in a
bathroom stall in like Minneapolis and
he was doing that foot tapping thing.
They have like a code Morse code for
gay.
He tap your feet four times and dudes
and let you into the stall and you suck
each other off.
Larry's grades are in the dude's right.
Kind of dudes are into dudes when these
kinds of dudes are in dudes.
Yeah.
But I think if I think it generally,
what did you watch modern family.
You ever watch?
No.
Do they have,
it's a few families and have a gay
family.
Uh,
they have two dudes and they adopt,
they adopted a girl.
She's an Asian girl.
But those guys,
there's been a couple episodes where
this is on ABC modern family where uh,
the gay couple at some college boys move
in next door and then one of the guys is
like hanging out with them and he feels
like he's in college again and he's
partying with them and he kind of has a
crush on one of the guys,
like the main guy and his husband.
It's like you gotta crush blank they're
talking about and he's like,
like,
no,
I don't have a crush.
But like it's obvious that he does and
it's okay.
That's fine.
No,
I know.
But if it was a heterosexual couple,
no,
that would never be a situation like
that.
Oh,
they've done that before.
Take a pilot,
a couple.
I had a crush on someone's wife for
sure.
For sure.
A hot neighbor moves in.
Right.
But it is like where the guys like
admitting that he has a crush on the
neighbor's wife,
like latently,
is that what you're saying?
No,
it's more like a,
you can tell there's,
there's a heterosexual couple in the
Sitcom and a bunch of girls move in next
door and then the guys hanging out with
the girls and he has a crush on one of
the girls and it's okay with this wife.
She thinks it's kind of cute.
That's weird.
Right?
That would never happen.
I'm confused.
Is the husband,
I never,
never watched the show.
So help me out.
Is the husband gay?
I don't know what you're saying.
That's a gay couple.
So it came up a gay cop and a young and
a young college kids move in next door
and one of the guys,
one of the gay couples crushing on the
guys that were one of the guys that
moved in next door and it's kind of a
cutesy crush.
Oh Wow.
And they're really blatant about it.
Like he comes over and there's like
these moments of like he's being
flustered and I have nothing against
that.
But I'm just saying you would never see
that in a heterosexual couple on ABC now
on ABC.
Well I think some hardcore stuff right
there.
I think even though a lot,
what does that mean?
Well,
a lot of times gay couples will take
like traditional sort of almost husband
and wife type roles.
Like it's really common for sure.
One of the,
one of the guys makes all the money and
the other guy sorta stays at home and
maybe they even adopted kid and he like
raises like a mom.
Like yeah,
like it's so,
but I think ultimately we still accept
that gay guys are guys and the guys are
just going to be different.
The same as like two girls becoming
lesbian.
They're not going,
I mean it's like people aren't asexual
if they're gay,
you know?
So people becoming lesbians,
they would probably have a different
attitude about monogamy than people
becoming gay.
I would just imagine.
Yeah.
It seems like overall lesbians are like,
they're,
they're letting love in,
they're monogamous.
It seems that when it seems like gay
dudes are like open about not being
monogamous and Nicola [inaudible] I
don't know too much.
I don't know too many lesbians that
where I've gone deep into their life.
More monogamous.
It seems like generally lesbians or more
girly and monogamous love.
I feel like super weird about asking
that kind of shit to a lesbian,
like a gay dude.
I could ask a gay dude,
they're like,
Justin Martindale.
I could ask that dude anything.
Generally wilder ride,
they're like,
yeah,
guys are like guys and girls are like
girls,
whether they're lesbians or gay dudes.
You right.
That's what the girls like a super like
masculine,
like,
like a male.
Uh,
butchy gay girls generally still don't
feel comfortable asking him.
Like,
you know,
like how it works.
They might get offended.
There's not lesbians meeting each other
and bathrooms.
It's not girls doing that.
Right.
Generally it's usually these,
they push each other into a stall and
they started making out the heterosexual
world.
What percentage of strip clubs in the
United States are for men?
Well,
there's a lot more [inaudible].
There's like one chippendale's,
the county shit.
You got to do some research and if
they're only open on,
you know,
you gotta make your reservations and
shit the fucking like,
it's a different experience.
Like when girls go to see men strip,
they scream,
they scream and they throw money in the
air,
they get crazy and they'll rub their
face on the dude's dicks.
Like girls at Bachelorette parties,
they go,
fucking ma'am.
Is it because they don't go as much?
Like as often,
you know,
in the agreement they could go off on
bachelor parties and they're not.
Yeah,
they're not going to say shit.
It's like what happens at the
Bachelorette party stays there.
Right.
I had a friend of mine who I used to do
taekwondo with that was a male stripper,
two friends of mine actually.
One was his young Puerto Rican kid and
the other one,
this is older white dude and the older
bite to it was a really nice guy and
very smart guy,
but he was like over the top.
Strange Big Jack.
Was He shredded though?
Jack Black Belt.
Black Belt martial artist.
He was a big Jack Dude,
you know,
but he was telling me,
he was like,
these women,
they go fucking crazy.
Like it gets really scratching column
and she just sucking tech daughter
friends.
The girls who were getting married,
we just suck his dick in front of their
friends,
cut to the guys strip club to dudes by
himself in the quarter,
all quiet as flushing fucking strip
clubs when it was dead as fuck.
I worked those Saturday day shifts,
that shit is,
you open up at 11 and there's one girl
and no dude's this weight.
You're looking at the security cameras
to see and then one guy walks in,
boom knee sit there and he's,
it's Saturday and one 15 girl.
She's fucking in Shitty Shit and I'm
sitting there playing depeche mode and
shit.
It was dark big.
My friends like,
dude,
you're so lucky you were in a strip
club,
just origins going on and I'm like,
dude,
you get me a job,
I'll just pick up cokes.
Larry said,
man,
you're so lucky.
I'm like,
ah.
But then ended up moving up and getting
good shifts.
You just wait for the Nike Jan?
Yeah.
When you first get in,
you got the worst shifts.
Saturday day,
Monday day,
Saturday day darkness,
just dead.
There's a UFC fighter is a stripper for
awhile.
Crunchyroll Detroit superstar.
Yeah.
He's over in Japan now.
He's fighting for a rising.
Oh,
that's right.
Yeah.
He's over there now.
He was American ripper.
He's a funny dude,
man.
He's got a hilarious mustache now to
follow his instagram.
It's awesome,
but it's just him shooting things.
He's a fucking sadness.
He used to fight in UFC.
Yeah.
Dan cruickshank probably run through
more rounds of ammunition than anyone in
this entire town in a year.
Fuck yeah,
he's crazy.
He's out there shooting shit constantly
does instagram.
It's all just him gunning things down.
He's a wild motherfucker dude.
He's fun to watch fight.
He's a good fighter.
He know.
He was getting more and more comfortable
with keeping fight standing and is when
he became more and more comfortable
keeping fight standing.
Then you get to see how good his
kickboxing skill is.
He's a really good kickboxer.
Really good.
I know I say kickboxing mean is boxing.
She'll at least the traditional martial
arts basically,
right?
Like what was his,
uh,
his original background,
karate or taekwondo.
It,
it's really,
really good man.
Really good kicker.
And so like,
you know,
when a guy like that makes that
transition hilarious.
Jack Jacked with a candy cane Roos Dick,
let that go back to that Jamie.
It's fucking,
you be like,
look at us.
Look at the first one you see.
The first one you see is if you click on
that video,
it's Darrin cruickshank just fucking
going crazy with a machine gun.
He's just fucking shooting things
constantly,
man.
This dude,
oh dude.
If the fucking shit goes down,
go to Darin crookshanks house and ask if
you can get it.
He's a fucking look at another video
looking at,
he's got a picture of all these Japanese
girls staring at his package lasering in
on his dick like agenda is what they're
doing.
Then he's killing it out there.
Whoa.
I mean that's a hilarious picture
though.
He's a funny dude,
man.
And I don't see,
I don't think the UFC figured out how
to,
how to recognize that.
You know what I'm saying?
Like how many dudes that you see fight
or like kind of almost like the on the
outside it's like the bland,
like everyone's the same because you
don't get to know them.
You don't get to know like all their
weirdness.
So you know,
if it's differently,
it's flat,
it's flat.
So you need a story but on a reason why
to tune into the fight crunch has a
great story.
He's a great story man.
Do you think some people,
um,
had wore certain shorts and you
recognize them by their shorts,
like with soccer,
rob,
but he had the warrant,
the flames and now,
now that,
uh,
everybody's going to reebok,
it takes away some,
a little value if what you're saying is
correct.
If it said adding personality adds value
to the fighters,
which adds value to the show.
Correct.
Hundred percent.
So actually letting them and encouraging
them and letting them get a rash,
guards and shit.
You want to win.
You want to be the fight of the waiters
or rash guard.
Fuck yeah,
it's not a problem in women's mma.
I don't see why it would be a problem.
And men's MMA.
Tell him,
show me the logic there.
They,
they should encourage fighters to,
uh,
where different Shit Melvin can imagine
spots.
I know that would grip.
Oh Shit.
Girls.
Girls are wearing rash guards.
Yeah.
I mean that's rash guard.
We'll fucking help your grappling for
sure.
It's a big factor.
Yeah.
Uh,
why they don't allow,
I mean,
they just haven't really thought about
it.
No one's actually just sat them down.
It's all the best.
Melvin manhoef when he fought k one,
he wore them gladiator type art and
cloudy.
Yeah.
Do you ever he,
he started,
started wearing those things,
you know,
start,
it started that we stumbled Mcdonald.
I'll go you one better.
Alexis Arguayo.
No,
not a wreck.
Stark whale.
A Dennis Alexia.
Alexia used to fight it.
A grass skirt straight up.
A straight up Hawaiian grass skirt.
Mcdonald had like straight spartan.
How bout,
how bout Shinay Yucky when he was
wearing them yellow tie to the rainbow.
He was known for a statue.
Couldn't wait to see what's new about
collarbone and look that scary to watch
that
shit allow that.
They shouldn't encourage that.
They're not cleaning product.
Dell had those blue shorts,
the iceman shorts,
the pink ones.
That's the personality.
If they wear uniforms,
they don't want to look more like every
other league though.
But it's a man on man.
It's personality on personality.
It's one,
one dude.
So his personnel,
just one dude,
that person,
even if it's for dudes,
all their personalities,
you know,
once you get to know him,
they become important,
you know?
So the more you understand everybody in
this case just to fighters,
I also think that making it,
I mean if you want to have a company
that sponsors it,
that the two aren't mutually exclusive.
It's not like a company can't sponsor it
and still have dope shorts that are
different for each fighter.
We have someone design their own stuff.
You don't have to have,
you know,
the same like you have read and I have
blue,
like why correct.
It doesn't matter.
Everybody knows you're you.
Like what?
Who are we confused?
Like do we,
who's the Red Guy?
The right guy on top?
Who's the blue?
The WHO's winning?
Well,
I just feel like it takes away from the
sport when you make everyone looked the
same like in the nfl or something like
that total because what people buy into
and fighting and it's true with box and
it's true with mma.
They want to know why they should watch
the fight.
Cause you can put a fight on access tv
if you don't know the fight.
If you know nothing about them,
they don't get,
they get the ratings.
But he loves cowboy.
Yeah,
exactly.
His,
his story,
his story.
We know,
you know we know John Jones story now
because this has been going through all
this crazy shit and we know cyborg story
and it could take to kick this thing off
whether you want to talk about or not
and you let me know.
But with Amanda Nunez,
imagine just put yourself in her shoes
right now.
Imagine having the biggest fight of your
life ever and the the,
the fight.
Everyone's looking for a specialty or
female fighter because you get so much
notoriety.
You get all the camera's pointed at you
people,
you finally get to hear your story and
she has a great story and then he can't
do interviews.
There's none of that.
There's no promotion.
We're not going to show your videos,
can't do interviews.
There should be no open workouts.
Imagine being her right now.
Like what the fuck?
Well,
the good news is she can concentrate on
the fight and just constant.
The the would always do that.
I understand that and the good news for
Rhonda is that she can also just
concentrate and the fight,
but she doesn't have to do any of these
interviews.
I liked that,
but I don't like is,
I feel like we have to respect what a
champion is and it doesn't matter if
you're the most famous person,
you're still the champion.
And we,
we are the champion of a giant
organization like the UFC.
And how about she's the first openly gay
women's MMA champion ever or amazing
stolen champion.
I'm a champion.
There's never been an openly gay mma
champion and she's fucking bad ass.
It's not like she doesn't have a
highlight reel and it's not like she's
grabbing a hold of these girls and just
sort of winning by staying on top and do
nothing.
So there's no highlights you can pull.
Oh,
she knocks girls out
and choke them unconscious.
She's very good.
So it's exciting.
It's an exciting technical match up.
It's an exciting story with Ronda coming
back after being out for over a year.
There's so much exciting shit,
but to concentrate only on one person to
sell it.
I understand that that person is huge.
I understand that person's the biggest
person.
She's probably right up there with
connor.
I would go.
They both go back and forth.
What do you think conor is bigger?
That's not an argument.
I would,
um,
I would agree with you.
I would,
I would lean towards that.
My point is let's,
with one victory,
she could get launched right into that,
that place again,
I think it's a weird thing,
man.
It's like you're,
you're a super talented person who's
also this giant personality figure.
It's,
it's,
it's more than just a fighter,
right?
It becomes his personality figure,
especially for common like that,
that his whole shit talking and
marketing and he sends out a tweet to
sell the fight.
Part of being a fighter is selling the
fight.
See what you want about floyd
mayweather.
There's not an interviewer camera heat
in it looked towards to sell that
Pacquiao fight cause in the end it helps
the company helps.
It puts more money in your pocket,
it helps sponsorship everything.
You can't say anything about floyd
unless you were one of those girls.
You smacked that well,
but it's part of the Gig.
You,
you've got to sell the fight.
So for me,
and I think Rhonda is the favorite in
this matchup,
but she has to create these scenarios
where it's me against the world.
It's me against you.
Sure she's creating and this,
and this is a big marketing push.
This is like,
you know,
this is the new owners of the UFC and
this is this and this is the really
banjo,
but this is this really a cinematic
thing that we're missing the boat on.
What would definitely mention the boat,
the numbers will prove it.
I bet you we'll definitely miss the boat
on promoting Amanda,
that that for a fact,
but you don't think it was like a pretty
exciting promo piece.
I saw that Promo piece that got me fired
up.
I think the good thing is that it's like
it's really exciting.
Very well done.
Cool thing.
You gift,
it's a garage door.
You think this fight has as much promos?
Say UFC two oh five in New York.
No,
no I don't.
Or The conor fight cause I didn't know
because no one's doing interviews.
Yeah,
no I 100% completely agree with you to
that point but part of me likes,
I want to see what happens when the pay
per view numbers come out because part
of me likes that the fighters aren't
going to be bothered.
I don't think you need to bother them as
much as they get bothered.
I think when connor was,
was pissed off about it when all those
pissed off button will always different
fighters who were doing these crazy
tours are pissed off about this
promotion thing.
The,
the idea about it as you trying to get
the word out to as many people as
possible,
but I don't know if like that the price
that they pay and being distracted from
their training.
I don't know if it's 100% worth it.
You're talking about a world tour where
he's like,
dude,
come on,
I'm coming off the loss.
Nate Diaz is a tough fight for me.
One 70 I need everything
I can do to,
to get this fight and get my mind right
with Rhonda helps.
Do you think that it helps these,
these big promo tours?
Um,
yes and no.
I,
you know,
I don't know if you need to go all
around the frickin world and promote it,
but there needs to be some sort of,
um,
publicity done.
The for,
for Rhonda especially,
I think her as a role model for females.
You can't get kicked in the face,
take your ball and go home.
We want our champ to be like connor or
someone where they go,
I want back in there,
man.
Gimme gimme the fuck back in there.
I need this.
I think that it's cool that obviously
Rhonda doesn't want all that shit.
She's as famous as you can be.
She doesn't want that.
And someone just said,
okay,
you know,
they'd let her just have her piece and
focus on the fight.
I personally don't really watch
interviews.
I don't watch that press,
so I don't even know how important it
is.
All I care about is that fight.
That's it.
Once the fight happens,
give me a little prod you a little
promo.
Give me a little our promo.
It doesn't have to be like,
you know anything fancy.
We're balls deep in it though.
For the casual fan.
My Dad's a casual fan.
He has no idea she was fighting this
Friday.
I don't know.
So for the casual fan,
that's where I would think that it would
make a big difference.
People will watch espn and well that
that's who buys paper views Joe,
because to get that,
to get that 60 $70 and here casual fan,
they need to be sold on.
It sounds like,
it sounds like you own a piece of the
UFC right now.
You're making good points.
Making very good points.
I'm just being fun.
No,
no,
I hear you that well,
but you are making very good points.
My,
my issue is in,
in Ron can do her thing,
but you can't,
it's a conflict of interest.
Here's my,
here's my cousin called me Gregor.
Right.
Cause conor goes,
dude,
I'll fly to New York and do a press
conference,
but I'm not going to vegas.
Cool.
You're not fighting.
Right.
Ronnie goes,
I'm not doing shit.
He goes,
cool.
Different different owners now.
Okay.
Different owners,
however different approach.
I mean it's a different business and in
the amount of things are changing.
They're changing the change.
Joe,
but also wme who owns the UFC manages
Ronda Rousey.
Yeah.
They don't manage conor mcgregor.
Right.
So there's a conflict of interest there.
Well,
um,
it depends because it's just a business
decision.
The only people that should be upset or
probably the other people,
what cody garbrandt and dominick Cruz
aren't restricted from doing any
interviews.
Right.
They're doing everything they can to
sell the fight.
That's a problem.
It's good.
They're going to sell them for me.
That's for fuck's sake.
I for Fox steep in it for short balls
deep.
The casual fans going,
I'm not buying,
I'm not spend $70 for those small guys.
Now to me it's the number one five.
You know,
to me it's the number one flight on the
card.
I love cody is my number one fight
rendered wants his promos.
No,
he's right.
He's right.
No,
no,
no.
What I what?
I wasn't added to the UFC to keep
growing and uh,
it,
it comes with the territory you got to
sell yourself.
But do you offer the fighters?
I'll don't you think that they're
respecting their wishes like Rhonda just
wanting to be left alone.
She is the exact reason why she's famous
as she is.
Okay
though.
Wait a minute,
but you don't have to only do press
while you were in camp like that media
exists after the fights,
which is easy for,
for everybody just talk after the
fights.
But during the training and preparation,
it's a giant distraction is going to
take a lot of time.
It did a decision if someone's as rich
and as famous as Rhonda is a decision to
favor performance over finances.
So like maybe she'll make less money but
she thinks that she'll be more focused
on a performance would be better.
I love that.
I love that decision.
I think really well when you're a really
wealthy,
successful athlete like her,
you can do whatever the fuck you want.
That's what I think.
I think when you get to a point where
you get to decide whether you're going
to focus on making more money and
possibly being less focused and
distracted and maybe tired or even maybe
get sick cause you're doing a lot of
traveling versus only dedicate yourself
to training.
He do all the fucking videos you want.
Put all the promos you want.
I'm not doing shit for the next eight
weeks.
So then where's that?
Who's going to sell the fight?
If everyone has that mentality,
does that,
is that the rule now?
You know what I'm saying?
No,
I don't know what you're saying because
the old way is not the only way.
You could do both ways.
You could do whatever way you want.
They can go side.
They could decide that they're a little
promo pieces that they could put
together without interviews are enough.
They could fly.
I might be wrong.
You know what,
they could just fly to her for two days
interview or at our training camp.
That's what they did for telling me.
And then they take off.
Tony was in big,
big,
really never left big bear.
They came to him.
It was no big deal.
It's,
look,
she definitely could do that.
Or she could say,
no,
I just want to completely focus and
let's see how this works.
Her thing is,
is that she thinks the media backstabbed
her and that's why she won't do an
interview like they turned on and when
she lost,
she's a very emotional person.
It's one of the reasons,
one of the reasons why she's so good.
I agree.
But she's a very emotional,
to me it sounded like my voice was
cracking up.
I swear it roadmap the Cryo or some
conversation,
Doug.
Um,
but,
but to me it's,
if you're a a Rhonda Fan,
like when you break the site down,
there's an that there's a huge x factor.
What frame of mind is Rhonda?
If she won't even face interview.
Okay.
Maybe.
Or maybe that's,
yeah,
maybe she's the most folks she's ever
been or maybe she just can't deal with
the question.
The Fra after the last fight.
We don't know.
Well yeah,
you,
it's,
she's the only one who knows,
you know,
or like you said,
famous is fuck lives in a mansion a lot
about Amanda.
Oh yeah.
What about little for her?
She should absolutely be able to do as
many interviews she won,
but she might not want to either.
She might want to say,
hey,
good.
I'm going to focus entirely on fighting
Ronda to look.
This might be better.
It might be better this way.
It's just like we were talking about
weight cutting before.
It might be better if people didn't
fucking cut way.
Look up.
God damn good.
Kelvin gaslin looked against Tim
Kennedy.
Look up.
Goddamn good.
Donald cerrone looks Donald's walking
around like 176 pounds.
He's not cutting shit and he looks
fucking amazing.
He's head kick in Matt Brown,
you know he's,
he's running through every book.
Tony doesn't cut that much either.
Yeah,
connor,
55 pounds.
Those guys,
man,
they have an advantage.
That's a big acid vantage.
Wait,
wait,
cut.
Yes,
I agree hugely,
but I think the way cut like the,
I think there's benefits to it.
Ultimately.
Obviously you're going to be bitter when
you get inside the octagon,
but the performance hit that your body
takes.
Its super arguable at a certain level.
There's a point of diminishing returns
that a lot of these guys pass through,
but then there's a few fucking examples.
Like Damien Maia,
Damien Maia cuts a lot of weight and
he's just rushing people.
Anthony Johnson and Johnson's cutting
that much weight at two oh five bro.
I think he might be 10 15 pounds.
No Sir.
You're really good at two 22 two eight
guys.
I think he looks really happy as Ken,
who's my offense as much.
For a big guy like that though,
for saying he's,
I mean,
20 pounds,
20 pounds is different when you're a
heavyweight for light heavyweight.
But he's,
he's,
he's lean too.
That's true.
He's jacked.
Who's who's doing in March?
A flight and Damien Maia,
I don't know man.
I think they're waiting to see the
shadows.
Woodley Woodley.
If Woodley and wonderboy,
you have a rematch.
Woodley's campaigning for a fight with
Nick Diaz,
which I would love to see Woodley get
fucking paid too.
I like,
I like what he's doing.
I liked it.
He's trying to get paid.
She is just the big names to make money.
I want to see it happen.
I like,
I like his initiative.
I like it.
You know,
people are like,
oh,
you're just trying to get paid,
bro.
Yeah.
Yes.
By the way,
those are all fucking amazing fights.
Like what are you talking about?
You don't want to see him versus GSP.
Yes.
Tell people to lose your number.
Tell them right now.
Lose your number if you don't want to
see that fight.
He wouldn't want to see that fight.
That's the sport though.
You want the biggest name possible with
the highest pay day because either way
you're probably getting punched in the
face.
Hey,
but also I want to see the runnable
wonderboy rematch.
I want to see that too.
I do but I'm not upset with any of the
other seds or GSP.
I honestly,
I'm even on it.
I'm even on Diaz GSP or the wonderboy
rematch.
I won't be mad at you and wonder boys
up.
Bad motherfucker dude.
And when he was in that guillotine and
didn't and it looked like his head was
literally going to be body,
I don't know man.
He Ha maybe his neck is so small.
That's what tyler was saying that his
neck is so small you got to like really
squeeze it.
Someone else was saying that too.
Like his neck is so small.
Maybe he can like make more room because
it's harder to get a really tight
squeeze on it cause Woodley had some big
ass arms make up for it.
Woodley also said that he's got a little
head so his head could pop out easier.
That makes sense.
Right?
A small head myself.
It's an advantage not will not when you
get punched in the face,
if you've got some crazy alex caceres do
that has gotta be an advantage to the
guy hanging on for real.
Right?
Yeah.
I mean to Alex.
Cause if you get Alex because Sarah's in
a canteen,
like there's a lot of shit he's got to
go through on a shit.
It's not like my head was like,
Whoa,
whoa.
Remember having uh,
they had homeboy and um,
Kenna shave his beard.
Oh that's right.
A meal.
A meal mic.
You got a powerful beer cause it was
called himself a meal.
Meek forever.
And then just the day before the fight,
he told everybody was Mac.
They're like,
all right man.
All right dude.
Cool.
Whatever you want.
Do you have to ease that I bought just
make one a mother fucker.
Jesus Christ.
Why is everybody having,
why do we have to keep the dumb way of
spelling shit that our ancestors who
came over on rafts,
they understand that you just can't make
some shit.
You can't?
No,
you can't.
Well,
you definitely to ease.
Is he all right?
It's not.
It's just not.
We got rules.
Motherfucker rules.
Okay.
We got rules for sounds rules man.
I remember Roy being so pissed when he's
fighting kimball,
he want him to cut his beard.
He's like,
get the new advantage.
What if we get ahold of his neck?
The commission was like,
well I don't,
it's Kimbo slice when I kinda this
fucking beard.
What do you want us to do man?
So sad.
I know the personality wars,
you know,
personality wars versus a,
I mean look,
he is Kimbo slice not beard is huge.
You know the idea originally was that
some hundred the beard protected you
this ridiculous.
That doesn't make any sense unless you
have like some crazy Rastafari and wow
fucking dreadlocked out beard.
Like if you could have like a thick
roped up,
dragged,
locked out beard,
Caribbean Shit.
Yeah.
I think then you can make the argument,
but who,
what,
what kind of a human is capable of
growing the same kind of facial hair
that you grow on your head.
Does anybody ever grown?
Jamie looked this up.
Tapes.
Anybody ever grown like a legit tait
fletcher?
A little bit.
Right,
but he needs to like roll that shit up
and braid it.
He does now take those.
Yeah,
braids it sometimes he's like that
refereed to as that really long.
Oh that's true.
Just the referee the other night during
a Mike Beltrani Mike,
he's awesome.
Yeah.
Mike has,
that's right.
Mike has like ponytails cause he has
picked face face pigtails.
Mike's a cool guy.
He's great guy.
Very good referee to one of the coolest
guys I know.
Super,
super good dude.
Super good dude.
And he pulls out mustache off being that
cool.
He's the only one.
Everybody started growing that much cash
flow going to be like slow the fuck
down.
Stood his background.
It would make sense.
He's a good dude man.
No fee fund mma they lost and they can
cut it because you could use that to
choke him.
Uh,
yeah,
I guess you could.
Yeah.
Or he can choke you with it.
You know,
if he gets on top of you get to Zeke eal
with that.
Go ahead and quiz up Brown.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So I wonder how he rolls that.
He do,
you know,
does he rolled that up?
He's a brown belt and he's huge.
[inaudible] sec guys.
Big fucking deal.
He's not five,
nine,
no giant dude sons.
Even bigger.
Does he put it in like,
um,
like a chin been like a man bun thing?
You'd have to ask,
you'd have to put like a thing over it.
Yeah,
maybe in underneath the chin,
but then again that would kind of get in
the way.
I would imagine the braids like could be
avoided just like other kinds of braids
and there's Rondo biting his braids.
Well that was actually,
it looks like.
Okay.
Yeah.
So he just sorta ties at the bottom of
it and like little rubber bands and
shit.
Great referee.
That guy's on top of his shit.
Does a lot of good ones,
man.
This is a good time for MMA.
There's a lot of like super experienced
guys that are just,
uh,
it's so important when you're watching a
fight,
when you think like a fight could be
stopped and then,
you know,
and then the guy gets through it.
Fighters Millet too.
When you're in the back luck,
I mean they go,
Hey,
I'm be a ref tonight.
There are certain guys you buy shit.
I like who refereed a wonderboy and um,
tyron,
herb dean,
right.
What a great job or mccarthy.
Pretty sure it's herb though.
Those guys didn't on get out of credit,
you know?
Yeah.
They know the fighters,
you know,
and they know that w how tough these
guys are in the can be in those spots
everywhere.
Everyone's got the classic fuckups as a
referee.
I don't remember any by big John
McCarthy.
You don't remember Marilla Bustamante
tapping out Matt Lindland twice.
Oh,
that's right,
that's right.
Morale booster.
Madelyn in an arm bar tabs.
He let go and he said I didn't tap.
And then marilla got him again the next
round with a good team.
That wasn't a fuck up.
That was like the dude ghost tapped or
something.
You know,
he lied,
tapped and he said you didn't tap.
Yeah,
but that's not that big fight is a
championship fight.
But,
but looking back,
thank God.
Oh standardly Yada.
Denmark.
Leon's a great job in that fight.
Great job.
Great job in that fight.
Yeah.
He's great.
He's great to,
Dan's a really good guy too.
And fucking giant.
He's,
he's a gorilla.
Stir guy.
Gives me a hug.
I'm,
I feel like he's my daddy.
Me To sit on the fucking lap.
But another really good referee,
you know,
who's another real,
real good referee that,
uh,
Josh Rosenthal,
very good.
Hellier I hope.
Prison.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
He's out.
He was awesome.
Very good referee.
He got caught up in some sort of pot
thing like plants and shit on his house.
Not good,
whatever.
But he's out now and he,
I guess he's refereeing again for other
organizations,
but he was very good.
I don't remember him ever fucking up and
really smart guy.
When he comes to mma,
knows a lot of his Jujitsu brown belt,
I think under a,
who's the under the,
under Cesar Gracie?
I think so.
But he's a legit,
one of the important,
they train like Mccarthy's rolling all
the time so they know what positions to
look for.
Transitions.
It's kind of funny how those northern
California guys are known as like real
hard style Jujitsu guys.
Like how Caesar and you know when you,
when you start talking about like those
northern California Jujitsu schools,
how fun is always had a reputation of
like if you go like a of frowning upon
tapping,
you tapped in front of house.
That was the story.
It can be totally blown out of
proportion,
but US training down,
um,
with Jacques,
we heard,
we heard the crazy stories about how if
that,
that he looked down on tapping like you
gotta you gotta escape.
Don't tap.
How about Dave [inaudible],
he's another one other than my mother
fucker from the north of California.
There's like that heart.
He came from that same camp that
hardstyle.
It could be a total myth though.
You know what?
I mean,
that's what we thought that we thought,
man,
those guys are so tough,
but don't you break my heart?
Don't like people have like a feel to
them.
Like you hear like,
Oh,
this guy's a half black buddy.
Go,
Ooh.
Like that's,
that's,
that's uh,
like one of those black bolts we'd go
over.
It was guys probably a psap beyond my
shit.
Yeah.
He's a black belt is like,
these are super aggressive style,
right?
Dave Camereo,
Dan Camereo,
like when you hear Hickson here,
if someone's a hixon black belt,
you go,
Ooh,
hundred percent.
Whoa,
okay on this guy's legit as fuck.
You know,
100% legit it,
there's no sh there's no,
like,
she hits it,
especially when they're hixon black
belts.
They're really game too.
Oh yeah.
Like at the Gracie Academy of the,
a lot of Hixon guys go up there.
I mean,
they are game,
the chrome chrome's kicks and he said
he's a cut above the elite.
Like Hixon is,
everyone says when they rolled hixon or
you know,
back in the day that they were just
completely immobilized and dismantle,
everyone has their hixon story.
And you look at chrome,
chrome,
very few Jujitsu players like crone.
Crone got a serious full guard,
serious guilt guillotine and his full
guard attacks.
You don't see that that much in
grappling and the more someone with a
full guard that's dangerous.
Crohn's got that Crohn's,
Crohn's or a little bit different than
your average elite.
You should see his workouts.
When I was doing a,
a grappling competition chromos on at
two so I trained with him for like a
week at a school in Culver City there.
Dude,
they would do these two,
two and a half hour workouts.
His Cardio was insane.
What kind of shit was he doing?
He would do this crazy warm up,
crazy warm up and we go over position,
position,
position and then it was like a king of
the hill.
We'd match up and however long it took
until someone got submitted,
then the two guys would be at the end.
Then the rest of the map with stare and
watch those two guys at the end.
Jesus Christ.
It was intense.
Super intense.
Wow.
And he does a lot of like nutty
gymnastic shit too.
Does that he does the breathing thing
like his dad and at the end,
crone and I were going against each
other probably 15,
20 minutes straight.
And they caught me an armbar.
Wow.
He's a,
he's not,
he's tiny,
tiny.
He says what's wrong with all monsters?
And then with my big ass,
it was just arm bar and he's always
training with nick and nate and he's
training with animals for for a while
now.
It's been a while.
It's been a month and it's looking like
a strike is coming together.
Yeah.
He's looking,
he's a special dude.
Yeah.
Very,
very special dude in special genes.
Their son,
special jeans.
Handsome Fella.
Handsome little fellas structure with
off space.
Yes.
Just like it's poplar,
right?
Yeah.
Uh,
but also he's just a good dude to be
around.
Yeah.
Like you feel like you're around a
Samurai.
Very good dude.
Yeah.
Well he's legit as fuck,
man.
I mean,
it's a,
he's the rare exception to show me the
man,
the son of a great man.
Great man.
He's the rare exception.
He has the mentality because you look at
guys like,
uh,
who though Chavez Jr.
You look at these guys who come from
that kind of pedigree,
it usually doesn't correlate.
Yeah,
they're usually like kind of soft or
they're missing a few things there.
The discipline was not just not there.
It just didn't quite have the same
discipline as his dad,
but he was still talented.
Like to party though,
don't you?
Not like that.
I think our parking's yeah,
for sure man.
For sure.
Because I'm that Jon Jones party,
there's partying and then there's John
Jones bar.
Well,
you know,
he's the son of like one of the
greatest,
if not the greatest with Mexican boxing
champion of all time.
Julio Cesar Chavez is a legend.
When he fought Meldrick Taylor,
remember that fight man?
Meldrick Taylor was lightning limpic
gold medalist during the heyday,
the mark Braelin heyday.
Remember those guys to that whole crew
of Olympic gold medals.
Pernell whitaker and Meldrick Taylor was
just lightning.
So just hit dude.
These ridiculous combinations.
Chavez just kept slugging away bobbing
and weaving and rip it to the body and
slugging away.
Cause you ever see his fights outdoor
and Mexico?
Yeah,
I've seen most of them.
They're just like,
it's like a fucking call a [inaudible]
Algun o in Mexico,
but back to the Meldrick Taylor fight.
Let me,
this is what I remember.
This is what I remember.
Controversy in the first fight.
The end of the round,
it looks,
it looks like Meldrick Taylor was
winning.
He was,
he was stealing the fight and then at
the end Chavez last round was fucking
him up,
had him against the ropes and the ref
stopped it.
But that was only like two seconds left.
Richard Steele,
right?
Did it go down like that?
Yup.
Two seconds left to the 12th round and
he stopped the fight and he stopped the
fight because Malik went down hard and
he got up and he was fucking out of it
and still looked in his eyes and he
waved him off.
He said he would do it again too.
He said,
it doesn't matter if it's only two
seconds off in the fight.
He goes,
I know this guy is not fit to fight
anymore.
He was like,
he got stopped.
He got him up.
He looked at his eyes and Mel Giotto was
looking at him and he asked him some
questions and Taylor wasn't answering
him and he's like,
fuck this.
A lot of that in box elder cause beaten
him the whole fight,
but in his credit,
Richard steals credit.
Myalgic tail was never the same again.
Never the same after that fight.
He was right.
He was done.
He just was right in front of him
touching him,
looking him in the eye.
Let's see it.
This is Cesar Chavez,
Kaos Meldrick Taylor and this was a
fight where meldrick speed and footwork
who he was just,
he was ahead.
It was a head on the scorecard.
He was getting the better of him in the
beginning of the fight that that ref
stop not fight in your hair.
Freddie Roach talked about,
he goes,
I wish my corner would have tossed in
the towel or the referee would have
jumped in way sooner and a lot of my
fights.
Yeah,
well for,
it's very loud.
He took a lot of punishment,
but if you asked him back then,
if they,
he wanted them to stop the fight,
he might've said,
no.
Look how good Chavez was.
Mike God,
he was so good with his angles.
He was our hero did.
He was so good.
Sorry.
Here.
How's the greatest Mexican boxer of all
time?
For sure.
Right.
It was better than now where you could
learn so much watching his test.
The greatest thing he throws in the
thing he throws,
he's like short and perfect.
That was our chuck Norris.
It was a bad,
how to fuck comparing Chuck Norris.
She was a bad motherfucker.
I was a huge Chavez fan when he fought
Greg Haugen.
He was the guy that said,
uh,
yeah,
he has got a,
cause.
He was like a g tech drive is all his
opponents were taxi cab drivers.
That's right.
His son has skills.
He just doesn't have that it factor.
He's just not this guy.
This guy's a different guy.
This guy,
the first of all,
his son is a winger bombs,
you know,
and he's a,
he's a hard striker.
His son can fucking caissons.
No doubt.
He's a big boy.
He's a Chavez,
was a different kind of fighter.
He was a much more volume fighter and
would throw perfect technique punches
and would never run out of fucking gas.
Saint Lucie on you for 12 rounds
throwing bombs on you and just never
letting up talking about it.
Have you seen his interviews?
Now?
He's fine.
Pretty legit.
Well,
I don't speak Spanish.
There it is.
You heard some here.
It's with that right.
Look at it.
Take to the body.
Look at that left Hook,
man.
Come on,
let's get turn.
And he turns him around and with that
right hand,
perfect right hand.
God,
look Meldrick Taylor's down and the
referees counting him.
He's eight,
seven,
six,
five,
four.
These are you okay?
You okay?
And he has no idea where he is.
He won't respond.
Mel Gto doesn't know where he is.
So Richard's still stops the fight.
That is a correct call.
Great job.
We got mad.
You're crazy.
They're crazy.
Cause they thought he was gonna win the
fight.
That fight was over,
man.
If they let him hit him again,
he might've died,
obviously not make me.
You never know.
It'd be,
I shouldn't have said that,
but you know what I'm saying?
Like that's,
that's what that comes from.
It comes from when a guy's done.
There's a boss who just died not just a
few months ago in Australia,
professional boxer.
I like the fact that they're trying to,
like,
if you listen to hbo commentary,
like guys will be like hanging in there
in the fight and you'll heal.
Max Kellerman say they could very
reasonably make the case for stopping
this fight.
And I'm like,
thank you.
I know,
right?
Thanks.
Before you can never ever heard that.
I've never heard that.
Even the NFL,
there's the guy who got rocked Dick,
man,
I hope he doesn't come back.
Hope he's all right to put them in the
concussion protocol.
Who was that dude that just quit on a,
did he quit on Golovkin?
No.
Lowman Chanko no,
no,
no.
Uh,
check again.
Sergei Luma Chang.
He was even really getting rocked out.
Like he was just out class and he's
like,
fuck this.
I'm not winning.
I,
whatever you wrote him on defeated.
I'm just fucking done.
You're talking about homeboy,
Kell Brook.
Yes.
He was getting,
he was getting,
couldn't see out of his eye and his corn
was like,
no,
we was fine.
Golovkin yes,
yeah,
yeah.
But to fight,
well,
the Kell Brook fight,
um,
was a little bit controversial.
The Loma Chanko fight was much more
controversial,
right.
Where most people were like,
this is ridiculous.
Yeah.
Because he really was thinking,
yeah,
neglect.
He just quit.
And Nicholas Walters was undefeated
before this,
but he had,
he had taken some time off apparently.
And that was supposed to be like a big
test for limit Chenko and then even Max
Kellerman,
he goes in the ring and he goes,
you know,
just,
just as a box in kind of sore,
usually go out on your shield,
like you really weren't getting hit.
And he goes,
no,
there was a,
there's a left hand in that and that
wobbled me.
And he's like,
well,
we can't,
like,
can you give us the time round anything?
He's like,
no,
but I,
I was hurt,
man.
That's why I stopped.
And even,
you know,
Mac telling me see how many boxes of
matches,
it's like he's the fucking Joe Rogan of
box.
And he was like,
dude,
like this,
this is going to hurt your career man.
So they're saying all those years he put
into finally establish himself and get
this fight and then you quit and then
there's really no damage.
He just,
it was like mighty mouse just all
around.
He didn't know what to do.
He had no answer and just like,
I can't fucking,
I'm just going to get embarrassed.
I think he was getting hit a little bit
more than that.
I agree with you.
But I think Loma Chanko was really
laying into him.
Was it?
Well what Brown did they stop at seven
seventh round to fight the round before
that.
So it was at the end of the seventh how
does that work?
Or is it the beginning of the seventh he
doesn't come out to his corner.
So it a 77 answer the bell,
right?
For the seventh so it was the six round
Loma Chanko was just putting it to a
man.
It was just really getting on him and I
think he,
he saw the end,
I was like,
dude,
he's like,
I can't even hit this guy.
I didn't have a problem with it.
I was like,
yeah,
you're definitely never beating him as
a,
as a fighter.
And most other other fighters will go,
fuck that guy.
Didn't have a fighter's heart that he
shouldn't be in there.
Yeah.
I think,
I think both arguments could be made.
I agree.
But I think,
uh,
I would lean more towards yours because
like you never know.
Like,
look,
Chavez is getting outclassed earlier in
that fight with Meldrick Taylor and he
never gave up.
He kept chipping away and people will
define you based on how quickly you're
willing to give up.
But I think the skill level,
you know,
do you know who learned lemme?
Chenko is dude is from outer space.
He's an alien.
He's a bad rush.
Motherfucker.
Russia,
he says he should fight Russia.
Oh wait.
Triple H.
No,
no,
no.
You can thinking triple g trying to go
off.
Oh,
sorry.
Lemme Chanko is actually maybe more,
it's more technical.
It's more skilled for sure.
Pull up Aloma Chanko a highlights,
but joe,
to your sale low,
but chain,
to your point,
most skilled boxer in the world does no
publicity.
This is the video viewers.
Well,
he's 125 pounds like you were saying,
but look at this.
Look at these fucking,
the footwork on this tickles.
His angles are so filthy,
so hard for people to hit him clean.
He's just just so technical.
Like he just pushes
dudes around looking.
I mean he's,
he's laying it to this dude.
And you're ready for this.
Seven.
Five,
yes.
Seven fights.
Seven pro fights.
It just has so many amateur b,
six in one,
but wall.
Look,
walters hit him a couple of times there.
I see.
That's where I could see your argument
much more.
I mean,
it's not like walters didn't
occasionally connect.
It's just for sure.
Loma Chanko is connecting more than him
walks up to him to make a decision to
just opt out to look at that.
Come on,
man.
This,
you can't say he's not getting hit.
He's getting fucking hit.
Right.
Right there.
He got hurt right there.
He's holding onto the glove.
Lemme Chanko is all over him here,
man.
I mean it makes sense.
He was a medal winner.
He sees the end man.
He's gold medal winner twice.
Yes.
Two Separate Olympics,
right?
Yup.
He sees the end.
What do you mean he's cute?
Keeps getting fucked up.
That's why Walter is quit.
You know his corn.
Look at them in there in the corner.
Dude,
he's fucked up.
He's fucked that he's also broke
mentally too.
He's like,
I'm not,
I can't compete with this guy.
Yeah,
and I just,
I see everybody's point,
but I see,
I see his point too.
At the end he looked like he was getting
fucked.
I wish you could've gotten into a
frickin Bernard Hopkins.
There was last week.
We haven't talked about that right out
of the hat.
Oh yeah.
You're a hall of fame at 51 check this
out out of the F.
Have you seen this?
Here's one thing I haven't seen out of
the ring.
Boxing needs boxing me to do something
boxing needs and do something about that
ring thing that's not,
that should never be able to happen.
Where a guy can fall through the rings,
the ropes,
and here you're talking about a guy
who's been fighting for 23 something
years.
How long has hopkins been fighting and
he can still fall through the ropes like
you shouldn't have ropes.
You should have some sort of a mesh
inside the ropes.
This is Joe Smith.
Jr is ropes are now loose.
Bernard Hopkins who falls through the
ropes,
Jesus Christ and lands on his fucking
head and Smith is a bad motherfucker.
Dude.
This is a goal.
This was a dangerous fight.
Smith also has arms that look like a,
like a popeye.
Bad Guy,
arms heavyweight.
They're like too long.
No long arms are like too long for his
body.
Get him here dude.
He Fuck Bernard Hopkins Up.
It was rough like this.
Look at it and be fall time and do
something.
And that was the end of the fire right
there.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He fell on his fucking head.
This is the worst part.
Bernard kept going.
He pushed me out the ring and they
showed the replay.
Then that Max in the locker room.
He goes,
what do you think happened was I got
pushed.
Man's do little shit.
He just landed on his fucking head.
That is a real clown.
Right?
But no,
it's a real fight.
He was just,
Smith was winning.
No,
Joe Smith was winning the fight up until
that moment.
And then he knocked him through the
ropes with an Abrie much.
I don't know,
man.
I don't think,
I think Hopkins has done cause that's
dangerous.
The way felt like that she fell and
landed on his fucking head man.
And no wonder why he's,
he's,
you can't hold him accountable for
anything he's saying right now.
That guy clearly landed on his fucking
head after taking some really solid
shots.
You guys know the rule on that.
If he get knocked out of the ring?
No.
22nd,
22nd.
Yeah.
To jump back
in.
Why,
why did he have ropes?
Look,
man,
that's why don't have a mesh in between
those ropes where that can't fucking
happen.
But this guy never happen.
But it does happen.
It's happened before it happened in,
um,
uh,
what's his name?
Uh,
Ray Mercer fight.
Remember when Tommy,
Tommy Morrison got tangled up in the
ropes,
his arms went through the ropes.
You guys have fallen out of the ropes
before he's fallen out of the road.
This isn't the first time a huge fall.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
The camera man should be fired or beat
when he went backstage.
I think people can fall through the
ropes.
It just doesn't happen that often.
But when you get tagged like he did and
he stepped on his foot to Yo,
dude,
he got,
he was getting lit up.
Go back on a 79 just calm.
Talk about that.
No,
I didn't even see it unless I'm
retarded.
Look,
look,
look at this.
Boom,
boom,
boom.
No,
he didn't start charging.
I'm retarded.
I thought he stepped on this.
It's hard to pay attention to everything
in there,
but that was a vicious fucking
combination and the reason why he went
through the ropes is because his legs
were gone.
They gave out when his butt was down and
then he got clipped again and his body
just went limp.
He also went through the ropes because
that left fucking hook from Rhode Island
land.
It's not a pushover fascination.
Not The way you want to go.
I'm telling you the worst part about
that was him fallen on his fucking head.
None of it's,
that's horrible.
That's horrible.
How do they not have pads down there?
How do they not have some sort of a
like,
you know that's possible.
Why?
If people fight on a platform,
that's a bad at anything.
I didn't have pads down.
That's what they should do.
They should absolutely have like judo
crash pads.
How hard would that be?
You know,
have that shit as a buffer in between
the tables.
Have everybody pushed back a little bit
like fuck the fact that that can happen
to a guy like hopkins has been fighting
as long as he is scary,
right?
Yeah.
He asked to be done now,
man,
because that was his doors damage he's
ever taken.
Yeah.
He said he's done.
He was thinking that he's never been
stopped.
That exchange was awful.
Not just for the punches because he
still takes a great fucking punch.
He might've went down from the punches
and got up and even survive the round.
True,
but landed on your head like that is no
Bueno.
Boom.
That's scary to watch him.
And he got a died there for sure.
Damn as twice I brought that up.
So extreme punished.
He couldn't stop being so extreme.
But it's not that you guys care deeply
about fighters.
You'd love them.
Well 51 year old fallen out of the ring
on concrete on his head and he's like,
God,
he's on Mount Rushmore for boxing.
I think you gotta give him credit for
taking that fight because that guy,
he's crazy.
What the fuck?
He thought he saw something in him that
he might be able to exploit and he was
wrong.
How much money did he get for that
fight?
$7 72 like,
like 5 million or something like that.
I Dunno.
Cause you want me to a million.
1 million.
I wonder if he has a deal with HBO.
Golden boy productions to right.
And he's a part of golden boy.
So he's a promoter and he got 1 million.
It's worth though.
He may falls.
Not if you've guy like,
but you made him a million to is a lot
of money,
you'll be fine.
But he already has millions.
Yes.
You know,
Bernard is a wealthy guy still.
Even if it doesn't matter if he has 10
million,
if he made a million for that fight,
him falling on his head like that,
but not if he's never the same again
Eddie,
if your brain trauma or $1 million,
that's like saying people would line up,
say you've never done,
never had any brain trauma.
Huh?
Um,
I mean,
so no you haven't.
It leads to severe depression that
sometimes people never get out of.
There's all sorts of real huge issues
with your hormonal system.
Like you're essentially compromising the
quality of your life forever.
I play peewee or certain circumstances.
Does that count 100% no,
that was not Arizona with helmets,
but I know people that have been Kao
that were essentially never the same
again,
$800,000
he made one not that is,
um,
it was worth,
it was worth it.
I wonder if that's the whole purse
because that might be just like dad paid
for the fights.
A lot of money,
dude,
come on.
It might have got a percentage of,
you know the promotion because he's the
guy.
That's true.
It's a Monterey.
Even 2 million.
A guy like Bernard Hopkins is not worth
it.
The problem is the way landed.
It wasn't just the punches that he took
because he's so skilled.
He's good at like moving.
Wish he was definitely going out.
Okay.
That left hook,
his legs were going out.
He got clipped,
he got hit with hammers.
He was going out using shots before that
too.
But if he went down in the middle of the
ring,
we might be thinking,
you know,
like maybe he could survive the round or
maybe the referee is going to stop the
fight.
He definitely wouldn't have taken that.
The real issue was his whole body was
limp when he fell.
He just went right through stuff to
watch.
That's awful,
man.
Just put some netting in it,
Make it so that can happen.
You know?
But you remember how the Old School
Valley Tuto days used to have a net in
the bottom rope.
Yeah,
it's pretty cool.
That was pretty dope.
Not,
it doesn't have to be that ridiculous
like that.
Cause that was like the vans outside the
ring.
Like wwe,
it seems like those ropes were a little
loose too.
We could fall out.
Ropes were definitely loose.
Yeah,
that's not good.
That's a huge issue.
That might've been something that
Bernard liked so he can move,
you know like Bernard is really good at
like moving away from Shit and if he's
contained up against like a hard rope,
he doesn't have that ability to drill in
this stuff.
True.
And you know like the best fighters who
are really good at like utilizing the
ropes would like lean back away from
punches on the ropes.
And again it's golden boy promotions.
So I'm sure he had some say in that.
That's good point.
The kid is a killer.
Well he also thought his last fight,
he fought a cofa live,
like he's taken on two killers in a row.
Cova live.
Did you really think you're going to
beat that guy?
I mean that's why we love Bernard
Hopkins.
But God,
that's just shows you where a champion,
that guy is that he took those two
fight,
that he decided to take the crusher and
then this kid who is a relative unknown
to most people,
but super super.
Who's got one?
One?
Yeah,
he's super fucking name huge.
He's huge.
And he throws bombs.
Well I don't get it though,
cause it was a great job at Hbo.
Right?
Doing commentating.
He's 51 what else do you need to do?
And Roy Jones is the same.
Roy Jones a flight,
a Turkey,
fine on some weird like live streaming.
Just get wax in the next week.
I think Roy Jones owes a lot of money in
taxes.
I think that's what's going on.
That's what I had read that he owed
millions of dollars in taxes from when
he was champ.
Maybe he got bad financial advice.
I don't know what the instances were,
but uh,
that's why he does it.
Yeah,
that's a bummer.
I'm pretty sure that's what's going on.
It's hard to balance because it's like,
why are you fighting this random Russian
and he's in Russia now.
Like a lot.
Like he's a Russian citizen.
What?
Yeah.
Roy Jones Jr is a Russian citizen.
He lives in Florida too though.
Yeah.
Might as well be Russia.
They can have it.
No,
I'm kidding.
My sister lives there.
Let's just do that on site.
Hurl families there.
It's just weird yet I do is fight.
Yeah.
Um,
Kovalev is,
uh,
he's fucking district.
He's out of Florida too.
He's been trained.
He actually didn't he train up here for
the last one?
I think he did.
I think he trained in Oxnard.
Roy Jones Jr officially becomes Russian
citizen with Moscow passport ceremony.
Wow.
And that crazy.
You know what man?
He's probably just enjoying his life
over there.
Having a good time.
True.
It's just hard to see.
Oh,
you've got to accept who he is now and
not think of who he is now versus who he
used to be.
Impossible.
Yeah.
That's what it really is.
Because one of the things that like
disturbed me,
this guy sounds so fucked up,
disturb me about his last knockout loss
was how his body looked.
I was looking at his body and I was
like,
this is,
this is Roy Jones Jr.
He looked like shit.
He looked like he was not fit and it's
not,
it's not an age thing because Bernard
looked really fit when he fought Joe
Smith Jr Bernard look very fit.
He didn't look like he did when he was
30 no,
but he looked very fit and he looked in
shape,
you know,
but like when we were looking at Chavez,
Chavez never looked [inaudible].
He never looked like Melvin manhoef.
You know Julio Cesar Chavez was like
fairly smooth.
It wasn't like this Jack Dude.
Yeah,
but it's still murder guys.
So I feel like what we saw with Roy
though was different thing.
It's like this can't,
he can't be working out like harsh,
just shown up and talking to Murk.
These guys such so skilled and it's been
doing it for so long,
he probably feels like he's got a
certain amount of boxes.
You see that knockout wasn't good.
And another guy,
he fought,
he fought a fucking killer.
He fought a straight up killer.
See the UFC would never allow that.
Like say like if [inaudible] wanted to
come back.
No Sir.
Well done.
Well that's one of the benefits of Dana
being your friend.
You know,
like Dana does,
doesn't want to have,
he just does not want to be a part of
that.
And he's like,
I care about him.
I don't want him fighting again.
And he's right.
I don't think they'd let any of those
old timers come back to him.
Well that's the,
you know,
the problem is you can't tell someone
what they can and can't do.
Right.
They're grown ass man.
But you also have to realize at a
certain point in time,
like fight that that ego that a fighter
has and it's hard to say who's who's
right
and who's wrong because like they said
that about Bernard Hopkins when he
fought Kelly Pavlik with fuck Kelly
Pavlik they said he was done.
That was such the exception,
just such the exemption by alien.
But because he was that exception,
we got to watch some crazy fights.
But think of now,
but think about the other exceptions
that it never worked out.
Well,
the difference is also Bernard had never
been knocked out before.
True.
And he's a really skillful,
technically like really difficult to
hit,
but it also would diminish the,
your product,
like the UFC would never have like
coleman come back or Don Frye,
I think of Joe Montana came back to
shall pass.
What about that?
That was like that spice huge.
Yeah,
that was huge.
But you know that fight was,
it's a man.
It's like at a certain,
you don't want to see a certain amount
of deterioration from your champs.
I don't want to see Jerry Rice catching
passes right now.
There's fucking bad knees.
All dudes fight.
Oh Dude,
why not let them fire all?
We're so worried about their distance.
They want to fight.
Let them fight.
You remember when Ray Mercer fought
Larry Holmes?
Bitch,
your ass boxes face off like God damn
lie homes was like 46 or some shit.
Then we're not going to let you find out
how old Larry Holmes was when he fought
ray mercer.
And this is after Mike Tyson and marked
them.
So Mike Tyson burped him and then Mike
Tyson went to jail and then he was like,
as long as that mother fuckers in jail,
I'm boxing.
Fuck.
What's that?
He was honest.
He fuck the Kings in jail.
They case the line.
Yeah,
I'm coming out.
Well it was all here.
Everyone had when they fought Mike Tyson
in those early days I would have loved
to have seen Larry Holmes in his prime
fight.
Mike Tyson.
Now we've got marlene,
Psalm 42 oh that's not that bad.
That's it.
That's a different 42 though.
That's not like a 42 in 2016 that's in
1992 42 zero new Mexican supplements.
So totally different.
Yeah,
that's totally different deal set.
A 42 year olds.
Heck crazy.
We don't even think about,
cause I homes gotta be in his late
sixties or some shit.
Well I think he retired when he was like
51 or something like that.
I think he had like a fight like in his
fifties but uh,
Larry Holmes in his prime,
like the Larry Holmes,
it fucked up Muhammad Ali.
He would give anyone a run for their
money here.
He helped big day where that was the end
of Muhammad Ali.
100%.
You're definitely right.
I still,
when you talk about like a vintage or
you talked about fucking George Foreman,
those guys are so big man.
But you look at like Larry's body here.
This is not the same body that he had.
Like when he fought Ali,
he was doughy or,
and he had like a little bit of a,
well actually it doesn't look bad right
here,
man doesn't look bad right here.
This looks like the Larry Holmes that
fought Mike Tyson,
which was like hangs down.
Ooh,
you look good man.
One,
two,
but little slower than he was when he
was young.
Ray Mercer was always a fucking murderer
though,
man.
He was scary dude.
Ray Mercer
started late in his career,
wasn't he a military guy?
He started in thirties,
Olympic gold medalist and boxing and uh,
we did it from the army.
He's a bad motherfucker dude.
And he hit hard.
But Larry Holmes,
once the Fight War on got that Jab,
whenever I think back to these fights,
those,
I always think those guys hit so much
harder than guys now.
Well,
um,
they were knockout artists and,
and knock out artist like ray mercer.
He could be a knockout RC in any
generation,
but Larry Holmes,
he would give fucking anybody today a
run for their money.
Anybody?
Anthony,
Joshua,
he would fuck up a lot of these guys.
Ben Klitschko,
Larry Holmes,
like go to Larry Holmes,
a beat Muhammad Ali because you're,
you're here.
You're watching Larry Holmes.
It's like 42 years old in 1992,
which is like 80 today.
85 no trt and no vitamins.
No,
didn't know nothing about Kido Watch.
Go full screen and then just go to like
the middle of the fight,
man.
Dude,
I went with ordinary home for the
holidays.
So the cow,
good.
Larry Holmes.
Look back here,
man.
I'll look at his movement.
Yeah,
way,
way leaner,
way faster.
And look at his head movement.
Nasty Fucking Jab.
That's a different Muhammad Ali though.
Yeah,
it is different.
Muhammad Ali and it's a different Larry
Holmes till this is Larry Holmes who was
a punisher like look at he's,
he's angry with that chat was like,
it makes a mean face when he's popping
them with it.
Larry Holmes was a bad motherfucker
dude.
And he fought smart too.
I mean he respected Ali and just what
systematically beat him down and it was
hard to watch because Ali was way past
his prime way past his punch.
A bummer man.
It was a huge bummer to watch because we
were absolutely sure that Ali was
getting fucked up.
There was no going on.
Yeah.
There was no denying it towards,
you know,
the remaining rounds of the fight.
I forget how long it went,
you know,
the best body and box and vault time.
You ready for this evander holyfield.
Oh yeah.
It's a good argument.
Jacked.
Yeah,
he's about as Jack did you get tough.
Fuck.
He was one of the first guys to like
legitimately put on muscle and move up
to the heavyweight division to remember
when he was a cruiserweight champion.
Remember when he fought dwight cow?
We do commander Holyfield at
cruiserweight fought Dwight Mohammed cow
who was five seven the Camden buzzsaw
off five 795 pounds.
It's bus saw.
What a great,
yeah dude,
he did.
That dude was an animal.
He was built so weird and he went up to
heavyweight after that.
Any fucked a lot of guys at five seven
Dwight Kawi.
I'm pretty sure he's five seven.
I'm not,
I'm,
I don't,
I don't believe I'm exaggerating that.
I think he was literally an inch shorter
than me and he was fighting as a light
motherfucking heavyweight and a
heavyweight and cruise cruiserweight is
really where it started.
One 95 but he was at tank.
He's was like this fucking jacked up
looking who some are Paul Harris looking
dude look like God job.
Yeah,
but,
but I,
I,
you know,
I don't know if it was supplements back
then,
I think five,
six years,
five six that was wrong.
That is a short one.
90 but wa watch him fight,
man.
It was just so weird because he was a
dangerous big powerful guy.
Look at Vendor Holyfield Ben,
that's the lien of Ander.
Holyfield coming out of the Olympics.
Hunt yelling at him.
Yeah,
it's a different evander.
This was skinny young evander,
but look at coffee man.
Just just this tank of a dude short and
throws these looping over hand shots and
you're always punching down on and look
at the size difference man and just hard
as nails.
A hard as nails.
Dude,
don't ball.
Just like fucking give a fuck.
He's like,
I'm not here to Slang Dick.
I'm going to sling some leather.
Look at his socks,
the lesson,
1990 sweat socks.
They were killing it back then.
Cow.
We had a totally different approach
because he was so short for that
division.
When you watched him fight,
it was like confusing.
It's like,
I ain't never seen this before.
Like holy field was be like two feet
taller than him at points because cow.
We also fought crouched,
so he had moved in tight guard crouched
Tyson style.
No,
he had his own thing.
Mad.
A lot of bobbing and weaving.
He didn't have the same sort of
combination,
ruthless punching style that Tyson did.
Tyson could just fuck you up with one
shot and he knew it.
[inaudible] was like a Mauler.
He would maul you like that right there.
But he's fighting guys way bigger than
him.
You know Tyson was probably like five 11
right?
Wasn't it?
Somewhere on there.
I thought.
Still Short.
Still Short,
but a different,
oh,
holyfield connected and drops him.
Holyfield I mean,
that's what I'm saying.
Motherfucker.
Remember his fight with Burke Cooper?
Another one?
No,
I don't.
Oh my goodness.
I really os burt cooper like on the
verge of superstardom and him and
Holyfield Godo Wiz are with our son
Evander Holyfield.
I mean just,
he was awesome.
Past go to holyfield versus Burt Cooper
dropping some boxing knowledge on you
motherfuckers done.
I should know about mma.
Yeah,
I was huge.
Eddie Bravo and I both,
man,
we were huge boxing fans.
While you're still,
he's still,
I love it.
I can't get [inaudible].
We stopped him,
look at that and he stopped him.
Been talking about boxing for an hour.
Poli field,
man in his prime,
Dan,
I dropped.
That was the second time they fought
Jamie.
That's the second time.
That was when Kylie was older.
See if you can find the first one.
The first one was the revenge fight
because in the first fight they went to
war and a cow.
We and Evander Holyfield went to war,
but cow,
we wound up losing the decision and it
was like a big fight for a vendor.
So that was the second one.
What is this?
I thought I clicked too quick.
It's Tim Fighting George Foreman.
George Foreman versus cow.
We how ridiculous is that?
So George Foreman,
fod.
Kali.
Kali was five six.
George Foreman's fucking hands were a
foot wide.
That's ridiculous.
No thought he fought at 50 didn't me.
Oh yeah,
you won the title at 46 you know what to
say?
Former hardest hitter of all time.
I believe it.
Remember that Michael's prime,
that you're forming fire.
Look at it.
So this is the first Gulf war with one
punch.
This was when Kylie was younger and this
was a really close fight.
This is the different fight.
The second fight of was just on a
totally different level and [inaudible]
was older,
but [inaudible] he used to,
whereas his waist,
his pants rather as his belt,
way the fuck up high.
The straps of his shorts were like way
above his belly button.
He looks like the blue guy or the green
debt from Monsters Inc.
Yeah,
this is just the whole body then.
There's not a lot to hit now and this
little fire hydrant,
but this is like holy fields first big
test.
But see if you can go to,
uh,
that other fight that we're talking
about.
Lean holyfield his man there.
He's so skinny.
What was the other five?
Burke Cooper go holyfield burke coover
holyfield burke hoover was crazy war and
this is like 1991,
I think.
And Burke Cooper was a bad mother fucker
smoking burt that go go deep into the
fight here.
Young Jamie.
What kind of,
Oh,
okay.
Eventually Kill Them.
More rocked up here.
Son Per Cooper was a savage man.
He knocked motherfuckers out too.
He's a vicious power puncher and this
was like a sort of a make or break fight
for him because a lot of people thought
that burke crew like Burke Cooper could
fuck it crack.
And a lot of people thought that Burke
Cooper had a shot at being like one of
the top guys and this,
this was the fight that separated these
two guys.
Just an awesome fight,
man.
GRC,
some Jessia vantage crib in Atlanta.
It's not really a house.
It's more like a,
I would tell her your campus like a
college straight up fucking giant
university from the dus suggest like USC
or some shit in Atlanta.
Yeah,
like a hundred room mantra.
When are you just doing balls?
He went balls out.
That's how,
um,
uh,
Ron White described Larry the cable
guy's place.
That's who it was.
He said,
Larry,
the cable guy's house looks like a
university.
Really?
And he's like not Phoenix University.
Did I say oh was the case?
I'm sure that's where I came from guys
too though.
Yeah,
I'm sure both of those guys live in
fucking giant mansions.
Larry the cable guy's a funny dude,
man,
is he?
Yeah,
he's a nice guy too,
man.
I used to hang with that guy in the
Montreal comedy festival before anybody
knew who he was and he was funny back
there.
He's a good dude,
man.
He was doing that.
Larry the cable guy thing on a radio
show in Florida.
It was like a character that he did and
then cause he'd have his regular stamp
and then that was just a bit that you do
it late I think.
I'm not exactly sure the origins of it,
but I think he started out doing radio
and then from radio he started taking it
to the stage,
but his real name,
this visit videos of him as Dan Whitney
doing standup.
Damn.
Yeah.
I didn't realize how big it was.
I think I wasn't making fun of him and I
was like,
cause that guy is still alive.
I think we're on this showing
you like what?
Boom,
Nebraska sold out fucking arenas,
arenas and shit.
Josh Wolfe took a picture of himself
opening up for Larry,
the cable guy in a football arena that
was sold out.
God,
God in the south,
dude,
shut your mouth shut.
Shut your mouth.
Mouth.
You got think man Nascar and fucking
redneck joke.
This is what you've got to think.
There are 300 in who knows how many
millions in this country and you go down
South Larry,
the cable guy can get millions of people
to see him.
He might be able to do a million person
show.
How the fuck,
not sky's the limit.
If you had a million seat arena,
he's selling it.
And Larry,
the cable guy might sell out a fucking
million seat arena.
And that's not a bullshit.
That's not bullshit.
What is that about?
Can you explain that?
It's a funny dude,
but he also represents them.
He's like a very good joke writer.
He's south.
Well it's,
he also represents them like he's doing
like redneck sort of Shayne's third
democrats.
This is the voice and it's really well
written.
It's funny shit.
You know,
he's,
and he's a good dude.
He's a genuinely good dude.
And,
and him and Jeff,
Jeff Fox,
Jeff foxworthy.
It was like the captain of that ship.
Yeah.
And then those other guys and Ron White
and he brought ron white in apparently.
Um,
and Ron White was,
you know,
doing well.
I mean,
everybody knew who he was.
I knew who he was.
Everybody knew like he was a,
a well respected headliners clubs,
but people didn't really know how
fucking funny he was until Jeff
Foxworthy put them in front of
everybody.
He's a great guy to then corrections.
They're super dirty.
Southern Guy.
Ron White's pretty dirty.
Ron White has this whole bit about,
um,
how when he was in the navy stationed in
Hawaii,
he kept,
he was getting his dick sucked by
hookers and you'd know they were girls.
They were boys.
He thought that there were girls the
whole time until like years later,
he was watching some show about during
the 1970s when he was there,
all these transvestite hookers that were
operating in this one block that he used
to go like every day to get my dentist.
He's like,
I got my dick sucked by about 150.
Dude,
he's talking about it last week on the
podcast.
If you haven't heard the Ron White
podcasts,
listen to that shit.
He's a genius.
He's a brilliant story teller.
He's from stand up,
stand up and he's such a good dude.
So He's,
he's uh,
um,
the blue country guy.
Yeah,
he's a dirty country guy for sure,
but there's college.
Those guys,
you know what man,
it's just I think um,
with when it comes to like what we think
of as country,
like we think of as the south,
you know,
I think people who live in cities are
very prejudiced of it.
I don't think it's the same thing today
as it was 20 years ago.
Everybody knows things now,
man.
Everybody understands things way better
now than they ever did before.
Like if you lived in like a West
Virginia in the 1970s,
you probably,
if you lived in a real rural coal mining
community or something like that,
like,
man,
good luck getting any sort of access
to any information other than what's
right in front of you in your town.
But now,
now you've got a phone and everybody
cell tells you something.
You can just check your phone and go,
well that's not really true.
You know,
I just googled it and Stephen Hawkins
says that this,
Ooh and you will these kids,
they can be way more informed today than
they were back then.
So I think when people think of the
rural south as being like that,
I think that was a part of a problem
with this last election.
I think a lot of people thought like
that.
There's certain people that live in
certain places that are just stupid,
you know,
the,
the red states and then the,
these people are ignorant who'd say,
and they proved it with the election.
Like the problem with even saying that
is people don't like when certain people
talk shit about them,
they don't like it.
Right.
It makes them feel bad.
If you make fun of people live in West
Virginia,
like I just did people in West Virginia
to get pissed off right there.
It's not the state,
not the same people anymore.
Like our ideas of these like spots of
the country where they don't have
information.
We've got to let go of that idea.
Like there's depth there.
Definitely like leaning more right in
some places than left.
And that makes sense.
But there's still a ton of fucking
people that get it in these places that
didn't exist just 20 years ago.
Well yeah cause it,
especially to your point,
because the smartphones,
like everyone thinks,
I'm like,
Oh hey,
like what's going on out there?
But they're fucking,
it's easy.
Like you said,
don't even bring up Google or whatever,
any news.
Like my dad and I,
my dad's in town,
we know argument and he's up against
some point and I was like,
oh cool.
Just went on my phone was like,
nope,
wrong.
And end up discussion.
So I don't know what you want to do.
Well people just have these ideas in
their head and they've had them for a
long time.
And uh,
you know,
if you live in a rural community and you
don't have the internet,
you could just stick with those ideas
and those ideas will be transferred onto
your kids and transfer it onto their
kids.
And it's,
you're fucked.
You're fucked.
If you live in a tough spot like that,
if you live in a bad place filled with
dumb people and there's no new stuff
coming in,
you got to get the fuck out and you
don't even know how you're going to get
out.
Or if you're,
if you just don't have access like North
Korea and they just have no fucking clue
what's cause.
See what they were making them do for
North Korea with Kim Jong rooms making
them do on Christmas.
No,
he makes people worship the mother of
the revolution.
The his grandmother who was the wife of
the first dictator of North Korea who
she died of mysterious causes and like
1949 and so like he is so anti
Christmas.
This guy,
he literally is like,
he's like a character and a Dr Seuss
wavy ticky so anti Christmas,
she's like the grinch.
So they have to celebrate his dead.
They have to celebrate his grandmother,
the mother of the revolution,
the fullest.
Crazy.
You estimate 18 Korean cities disappear
during that war.
Look at that and that's why he,
I mean 18 cities disappeared.
What do you mean the war
on the Korean war between bombed 18
cities in the North Korea?
Yes.
And then the hole,
that's when the regime started.
Well,
the Korean War,
um,
when did that end?
Uh,
fifties in the 50s.
Some June does a weird war,
right?
Like people don't really talk about that
one too.
We're talking about the,
but they did,
it was,
I was watching a documentary about,
uh,
how doctors,
they're allowed to go into,
um,
everyone's Korean and fix people's eyes.
They give them like a month and these
doctors from China,
they come in and they do the cataract
surgery and his assistant snuck in.
She was a journalist.
She posed as an assistant just to get
in,
just to get some footage of on the
inside.
So it was about,
you know,
it is fucking weird.
And North Korea,
it's weird as fuck.
And that guy is crazy as fuck.
But at the top of that documentary,
that was not pro North Korea,
it was,
it was anti North Korea.
But at the very top of it,
when she's breaking down with the
documentaries about it,
she,
she mentioned how 18 cities evaporated
in the war.
It's war son.
Exactly.
No wonder there's so much hate for the
fucking dus.
What their issue is,
their issue was their dictator is
ruthless and is dominating them with
fear.
He bases it on that,
but that doesn't make any sense.
He's doing it against his own people.
What he's doing is imprisoning his
entire country.
I agree with that bombing 18 cities.
It's fucking disgusting.
But think about that.
So just as bad,
like it's almost like you could
understand it was an abused child.
You know what I mean?
18 sit q man's,
but he's fucking country out there.
If there was a country out there that
firebombed 18 of our major cities,
why would we feel about that country?
You would be,
you'd be fucking lynched if you said
anything pro that country.
It would be that kind of church.
I go to bed.
You Bet.
That's like Holocaust type shit.
You bring up that shit.
You'd be fucking bed.
You'd just keep that shit to yourself.
Well,
that's what you ever talked to someone
who has,
who's Armenian,
who's spoken to an Armenian genocide
denier.
There's a lot of like that Armenian
genocide is a very rarely discussed
holocaust.
I mean not,
not the Holocaust,
but you know,
in terms of the use the word to describe
an atrocity,
it was a terrible thing.
And there's deniers of that.
And when you find an Armenian and you
talked to him about people that deny the
Armenian genocide,
I remember manny,
I'm gim Berean.
He won a fight and I was interviewing
them after the fight and he was
dedicating to fight the fight to the
Armenian genocide to the victim.
So the Armenian genocide.
Okay.
And I remember thinking,
wow,
like when was the last time you even
heard about that?
Nobody ever talks about that.
Never,
never.
It never gets discussed.
I think Shirley and people died and I'm
pretty sure it,
La has the biggest,
um,
Armenian population population that it,
right?
Pretty sure.
Hell yeah.
You go to Glendale.
Wow.
Okay.
The United States drop 635 tons of bombs
in Korea,
not counting 32,557
tons of napalm compared to 503 tons in
the entire Pacific theater in World War
II.
At least 50% of 18 out of the north,
22 major cities were obliterated.
Holy Shit.
Right?
Was that right?
Yeah,
you're 100% right.
I mean this is the Internet.
Are we in the library?
Did you get that from library.com?
Um,
that is terrifying.
Look at the images up there.
Napalm bomb that you kind of look at
that in Joan will or whenever the book,
his name is as crazy as fuck for sure.
But he caught you kind of understand
when someone's really crazy and they've
been abused and tortured as a child.
You,
you kind of like,
I understand what you're saying,
but um,
I can't,
I guess the argument would be that if
they didn't do it,
what was the war over?
The war was over communism.
Right?
So the what happened at the end of the
war,
was it the two different countries?
They became North End,
South Korea.
How's that?
I don't know the details of when was,
I know it's probably fucked up the out
when will North Korea was a founded
because this was,
this is like the takeover.
18 different cities destroyed out of
him.
I knew he does.
They say 20 to 22.
When was uh,
uh,
South Korea and one was North Korea
formed.
And when,
when did it become like north and South
Korea?
Do you know?
In the 50 sometimes.
So before that it was just all Korea.
I'm not sure.
I don't know that much about why do I
not know this?
All I know is we fire bombed 18 other
cities.
Man.
That's devastating shit.
Yeah.
We talk about all these different,
uh,
well I think again,
back then,
man,
you,
you never look in North Korea has a
history.
1945.
Oh,
the partition of Korea at the end of
World War II.
Interesting.
The creation of the communist aligned
Democratic People's Republic of Korea.
Okay.
Kim Il Song in 1950 the Korean War broke
out so they broke off in 1945 and water
to be Communist.
Five years later we were going to war
with them.
Man.
I don't know the history of it.
I'd be talking shit if I said I,
I had an opinion on it,
but it sounds pretty sure I'm pretty,
I'm guessing that we,
we shouldn't have been up in there
fucking mass.
That's less.
We were worried that he was going to
become another Hitler and that it was
going to become a just a further
extension of World War II.
It was going to move on Maria,
history of world war two that is like we
don't really know the history of World
War Two.
There's that mainstream history and then
there's the real shit.
Well,
you know,
world war one to both of them are just
like world war one is very bizarre man.
When you go back and listen to Dan
Carlin talk about World War One and you
realize how recent that was,
where most of these guys were walking
everywhere,
walking everywhere with guns,
you're like,
what?
Like,
yeah,
that's what they did.
They walked,
they walked with guns there,
walked across countries,
braveheart with guns.
It is ridiculous when you realize like
that was a hundred years ago.
You go holy Shit.
Like what has happened and now instead
of just,
you know,
50 years after that,
less less than 50 years after that there
napalming entire cities wiping out whole
cities like the,
the ability that where it used to be at
like cannons and shit,
the Ed to move and push him closer and
closer to people.
The difference between that and being
able to drop shit out planes on people's
heads,
drones now,
not even crazy guys.
They got a con just she took continental
ballistic missiles,
missiles that are pointed at Russia and
Russia's got him pointed at us and we
just go,
yeah,
yeah.
That's where like the fucking Hatfield's
and the Mccoy's just stand at the barrel
of Martin,
Sam Moore and Ralph Lauren.
Ralph sheep dog and the Coyote.
Yeah,
old school reference morning Ralph
Lauren,
Ralph,
they would punch in and they beat the
fuck the sheepdog.
Beat the fuck out of the coyote all day
long.
At the end they would punch out and
leave through that reus around there.
What was the,
a rooster is racist as fuck if you're
not bro,
come here,
boy.
Fuck corn.
Corn was racist.
What's your racist?
Yeah,
if you listen to how I say it,
I said come here boy.
And he kept doing that,
but he was talking to chickens.
Now he would say some racist shit.
He was talking to chickens though,
Bro.
That,
but the way he wasn't even talking to
people.
Racist.
Racist doesn't count with animals.
It doesn't.
We're all racist.
We prefer squirrels over rats.
You see a rather nice rat.
You see a squirrel.
You don't mind your kid playing on the
grass was grown on a tree near it.
I see.
I like her at,
yeah,
but if you saw a squirrel,
all right.
If your kid was in the,
in the grass,
having a good time playing around with a
ball and then like a hundred yards away,
there was a tree with a squirrel kind of
school.
Fuck.
Any kind of squirrel.
The big bushy tail.
Cute little fellow.
Got a nut.
Yeah,
there's no problems.
There's no problems.
Right?
If he was like 50 feet from Uk,
would you freak out?
And I wouldn't be comfortable it and
went to anything.
He wouldn't care nothing to babies.
But that was a rat.
50 feet from your kid,
you'd freak the fuck out,
right?
Yeah.
Well cause rats are sisters because
you're raised with that rat was clean.
What if that route was trying to better
the rack community?
Would that,
what does that rat was a leader with
their rat was the one rat trying to
elevate the other rats.
They need to be eating garbage and
cannibalize each other to be better.
We need to build homes.
We need to establish communities.
We need to teach people about rat traps.
I like,
I like rats.
What am I supposed to survive on?
On rats and roaches.
But if we did that would fuck the,
the economy up when you all these
assholes that want to kill coyotes.
Man,
if there wasn't for coyotes,
we'd have roaches or rats.
Least everywhere.
Rats.
Fuck.
Yeah,
they do.
That's like the main diet.
Their main dies like rats and rabbits.
Chili's,
a bunch of coyotes to New York.
Man,
they're already there.
Coyotes.
Coyotes aren't like the city though.
The cities are in the city.
Dude,
coyotes are in every city in the
country.
I just got done reading this book on
him.
Coyote America.
Jamie wrote a whole book on Cody's crazy
book,
man by a guest that's coming on soon.
Coyote turned up in middle village,
Queens and April 27 there's generally
seen as a freak.
It's inch in it,
but it wasn't even the first sighting of
2015 there's many coyotes that live in
mass in um,
uh,
central park.
There's Kylie's it live in Queens.
Yeah.
They live all over Manhattan.
Well,
they're going where the food's at,
right?
They go everywhere.
They're all over the country.
There are small wolf that lives in every
single city,
every single state,
all over the country and do we kit,
we really don't kill him.
We can't have tried to kill him.
They did.
The biggest mass effort to eradicate a
species ever was on coyotes and wolves.
First Forrest Wolves,
which was successful.
And then coyotes.
Not only does it not work,
it has the opposite effect.
When you hear coyote screaming,
they're,
they're doing,
we'll call.
They're just like,
who's here?
Who's here?
Oh No.
Yeah,
they're trying to find out who's in
attendance right after the attendance
calls over if ones missing or two's
missing up.
So they think someone's dead or gone.
The female has more babies.
So the female will go from having four
puppies to having 10 or 15 and then they
also stretched the range out there.
Different than wolves in that wolves
have to operate in packs.
Coyotes can operate as a singular or
impacts.
Now,
what was a,
okay roll call and then,
oh,
someone was really attendance.
And then what happens?
The Mama starts making more babies.
They're missing.
So if someone's missing,
say if they have a pack,
the pack is like eight coyotes,
but one coyote gets jacked by a mountain
lion.
They yell out.
And when they find out that that kid is
missing,
the females say we need to make more
babies and it's like to keep their
species alive,
they produce more offspring.
So they'll go from having,
so they have sex ups?
No,
no,
no.
Their pups or larger groups.
So from four pups to having like 10 to
13 it's like the body produces more
babies.
Yeah.
So the smarter than the wolves.
Oh yeah dude,
they're just smaller.
Did there,
they're fucking ridiculously smart.
They're,
they're sneaky and they're smart enough
to know to not attack humans.
Yeah.
We'd leave them alone if we don't attack
them.
You don't,
you don't hear a lot of coyote attacks
on dogs and shit around.
It's cause they don't attack.
They just happen.
Not Be,
be scared if they weren't as good as
humans at attack,
that'd be gone.
This professor that,
uh,
I've got coming on the floor,
the podcast,
Dan Flores,
who wrote that book,
Coyote America,
what he said is that coyotes when like
the,
the like a couple of hundred years ago,
like they were only in the west coast
and as people push them away,
they started establishing new
territories like us making cities and
going after them,
made them spread out across the whole
country.
She's us like an,
it's,
there's people that don't understand
this.
Like he got approached by this one
because people know he's a coyote
expert.
You got approached by these people that
were doing this coyote a rescue mission.
Like we're here to save the coyotes,
the coyotes doing great.
Like you're here to save it,
save it from what they're everywhere.
Like they literally have populated
quietly and sneakily the entire country
and the efforts,
all efforts to eradicate them failed
when they let me have it.
See when they have male wolves,
they can cyanide like a horse.
They take a horse and they'll shoot a
male wolf and then they take his balls
and his dick and they rub is sent in his
glands all over this,
this animal so that the other wolves
recognize that he's been there.
So they think it's safe to eat.
So they start eating this horse that's
been cyanide and then they would all die
and so they would pop.
They would,
they would attack these packs of wolves
that way they would shoot the mail,
they would take his sand,
put on this meat,
take a horse,
shoot the horse,
injecting with cyanide immediately.
So it went through his entire nervous
system where it's not just our
circulation system.
And so all the meat would be poisoned.
And they did that.
And they eradicated walls throughout the
entire west coast until they brought him
back into yellowstone in the 1990s there
were like virtually
actually gone.
But yes.
Animal too.
I was reading the article that they're,
they're thinking about building a bridge
over the four oh five and I didn't know
this.
There's fucking mountain lines.
Oh,
you can't depend,
you can't it.
But someone hit one in a car because
they're trying to crossover,
trying to cross the four oh five well
that problem.
And they want to build a little ramp
during almost a land.
Um,
they're in like a land island,
like around the Malibu area.
Yeah.
That's what they're trying to do.
Just to keep the big monsters live.
Yeah.
One of them killed 11 alpacas in a goat
in Malibu.
Just a couple of weeks ago,
they put a depredation order on it.
They were going to kill it,
but this lady who owned the farm got so
much hate mail after they said they were
going to kill the mountain line,
that she changed her mind.
She didn't want to kill it because
mental mind doing mountain land shit
cause she has a farm up there.
That's her living.
It's making these Alpacas and this thing
jacked 11 which you sign up for a lady
in a way.
Right.
But if it's killing your food and
killing your,
your you're living.
That's why you make a living is by
selling.
Alpacas are doing,
I don't know what the fuck is an Alpaca.
It's like what the fuck's hustle
hustling llamas when Alan can do with
them,
rent them to rich kids' birthday
parties.
The fuck do you do with a Lama in Malibu
Llamas just sweating their asses off.
There was a dude who own the common
connection that had llamas,
had llamas living in his yard.
Alpaca is a speech they spit to.
They split like a motherfucker.
Yeah,
it's a species of South American
Kamlish.
It's a camel.
It resembles a small Lama in appearance.
There are two breeds of Alpaca.
Wow.
So anyway,
this lion in one day,
Jack,
Jack 11 of these things and just left
him there and
they're big.
Oh,
didn't eat it.
Just kill.
He just had a good old time killing
them.
Yeah.
You got to get rid of that one.
Is there a problem with wolves and
hunters hunters or did they,
they certainly would.
I had a friend who was cornered by
wolves.
They tried to take his elk and he wound
up,
they went up killing I think two or
three wolves.
I think they killed three,
I would have told us the story again.
He had one friend with a rifle and him
with a bow.
He killed two of them with a bow and the
guy with them killed one of them with a
rifle and they were surrounding them and
they were trying to get the elk away
from him.
They had shot him.
They fucked up.
They didn't know that.
They were like in the wolves' Den.
It was like that fucking the gray movie.
Like they shot this elk like right near
the wolves' den and the wolves like,
yeah,
we'll take that dude.
Natural Shit.
Yeah.
And they surrounded these dudes and uh,
started rushing them.
Like really?
It's a crazy car.
Three storing.
And then the other ones took off.
They were like,
fuck this.
The gun I think probably scare them.
They're like,
oh this,
these mother fuckers have guns.
And they did their call.
They did their attendance called,
and they were surrounding them,
but they were,
the wolves must've realized,
Oh shit,
they killed two of us.
I think there's two that are gone.
And then the killed a third and then
like that's it now.
He said he was,
he had the Alpha male in his sight and
he had his bow drawn back and the wolf
took off running.
And when the wolf took off running,
the rest of the pack went to,
they were like,
fuck this.
They're lucky they had a gun and not
just those bones.
So the patch.
So lucky.
Not only that lucky,
it's not just one dude with a bow and
arrow.
Like if you didn't have that guy with a
fun with them
would have been fucked.
You know what's strange is killer whales
have no problem killing other dolphins
and other whales.
They go after and hunt them.
How come they don't go after humans like
that?
Oh,
they have have they only videos but only
in seaworld?
Forget about seaworld.
No,
he had on my regular one ocean when the
wild,
I've never heard of that.
I grabbed a lady and she said,
see Ya Zinc.
No,
no,
no shaming it have a story that happened
in seaworld.
No,
no.
I'm positive.
This is in the ocean.
He grabbed the lady or the guy by the
leg and just fucking kills off.
Kills Him.
Takes off.
But one of the,
how often know how many reports are
there of killer whales attacking humans?
I mean is there do this almost none.
They go after dolphins and other way it
was like getting shit.
They have fun.
Great whites too.
Yeah,
they have no fun.
They have fun with it.
They go after they're mammals.
So why wouldn't the,
oh no,
humans are they that smart to know
offense to man,
they like coyotes.
Are they like how it is like,
you know what?
If we fuck with humans,
they're going to come after us do.
Are they smart enough to know not to
fuck with us or are they being,
is it like a spiritual thing?
What is it?
There's a bogus story
that I read online that I repeated on
the podcast for.
I looked it up,
but the book,
the book is that I'm pretty sure Adam
Carolla told me or some of them I don't,
I don't remember where I got it from,
but the bogus story was that before,
I don't think Adam Kroll believes this,
by the way,
before World War Two they used to attack
us,
but then once a,
they used to do target practice with
them from planes.
Killer whale stopped us.
Turned out
to not be a true story at all.
But that's what a killer story.
What a great story it'd be if it was
true.
It sounds like some place you used to
fuck with us and they're like,
oh,
check this out.
And they're like,
yeah,
we'll help you guys fall in the water.
Pull you out.
Just please stop.
Stop that.
Yeah,
we could work together.
Yeah.
Killer whales are gnarly,
man.
What's up with that?
The gnarliest or maybe if you found out
you see that there's a big cover.
I've seen it kill humans all the time.
I think it's a guy in a,
in a,
in a pond.
In the tank.
The exception,
like obviously seal hunt people,
but grab this fucking lady by the ankle
was like,
ew,
I don't know about that man.
I never heard that.
I'd like to see.
Just see that at the library.
What do you get your news?
Where do you get your hands,
Bro?
Hey Bro.
Kellen sent me that.
Is there a youtube video about it?
Yes or no?
Yeah.
Killer.
I found one fake one.
I see one from seaworld.
There's one where uh,
a Japanese whaling crew was eaten alive
by killer whales.
Thanks.
Cake.
That's not a video.
It just says like a story.
What was the story?
Japanese crew was eaten alive by killer
whales.
That's one of those fucking fake news
stories.
You hear that fake news thing about up
Pakistan was like there literally were
like ready to go to war with,
uh,
what was the,
I tweeted earlier today,
someone believes some fake news story.
I'm not believing this store.
There's other news things on there like,
so it's a fake news story about fake
news jacking off for it.
But no,
no,
no.
That was nail from the same site.
Now this is not from Sam,
but the one that I tweeted earlier
today,
I saw that that was a fake news story.
I'll pull that up.
Right,
right.
That was about,
but it was on cnn about a fake news
story.
Right.
And then they bought into it or about,
someone bought into it with this story
about the war of the potential for war
wasn't fake,
wasn't gonna stay administer issues just
popped up.
I put it up there warning.
It's real after being tricked by fake
news.
Right.
But that's what I was talking about.
Yeah.
So that's real,
right?
That's not fake news.
The ultimate trolling.
That's that dude.
When they're talking about fake news
site,
that's the fake shit.
This shit.
Okay,
well either way.
Either way.
Whoever,
whoever wrote fake news that they put
what?
First of all,
shitty being tricked by fake news site.
They keep putting that out there cause
they're gonna censor real shit and it's
going to be government state run.
They're going China style did they
already doing?
I'm trying to scroll up for a second.
You anything you want in China?
No doubt.
And I'm sorry down.
You got to train.
Anybody go to China.
But guess what?
You can't watch regular youtube.
Why don't they have a space between
Pakistans and defense minister?
This is fucking CNN.
How about you put a goddamn space in
between your words is the Shitty Lazy
Editors,
early men.
What does it Jamie?
This is the telegraph.co.
Dot.
UK.
Oh,
okay.
This one is,
so what's the CNN one?
There was a cnn one that I tweeted.
This was not exactly what a tween,
but either way it's the whole thing is
very bizarre.
Homeboy got
trolled and was about to sit down.
It's like a war.
We'll take you to war.
Bitch is right here.
Yeah.
There's a CNN article duped by fake news
story.
Pakistani mini administer threatens
nuclear war with Israel.
What they're trying to do is put out,
uh,
at scare people with fake news sites so
that they could go in there and have a
reason,
a sensor and everyone's going to go,
yeah,
fuck thick new sites.
Let's fucking sensor.
Okay,
you don't get emotional.
Let's just communicate.
Anytime we see something like that in
quotes that go fake new sec,
tricked by fake news,
people are going to go,
yes,
it's fake on facebook and see that chip.
It's honey dick.
Why Honey Dick in your face?
Right?
But here's the thing.
Well,
who's making these fake news sites and
it wouldn't it be in the best interest
of the government to make fake news
sites of their own?
So they all have a reason to not have
fake news sites around.
But do you think they could literally
stop people from putting stuff out on
the Internet?
I mean,
if that's the ultimate goal,
now what they're doing is they're going
to censor the top,
uh,
alternative media,
new sites that going after them.
That's the target.
This is a big trick saying like CNN,
no,
no.
Like breitbart or,
yeah,
like drudge,
infowars wars.
They're putting out the real shit,
but they got control the media.
So they're saying,
oh,
that's fake news.
So that creating a fake news problem
that isn't there so that that can go in
and sensor the real shit.
It's a fucking trick.
If you see it on CNN,
I called it every headline being tricked
by fake news.
They're getting everyone going.
Yeah.
Thick,
new sucks.
Fuck that.
You know?
Then they're going,
yeah,
it does.
Right?
Look,
here's another fake news site,
and people are being tricked and doing
all this crazy shit and walking into
pizza places with fucking machine guns.
They yell it,
Stop Fake News.
What are we gonna to do?
Let's just sign it.
Boom.
They're going to,
they're going China style.
They're gonna.
They're going to censor.
The Internet isn't going to work.
They're going to blacklist you.
If you're a new site that's credible and
you're fucking with the agenda,
boom,
they're going to go,
hey,
that's fake,
dude,
you're off.
That's what there were in the middle of
that.
Right now we're being assaulted with
people being tricked by fake news.
When have you been tricked by fucking
fake and offices?
They're not tricking me.
You settle down.
Anybody can be tricked by fake news for
sure.
They can be and if the the,
the question is who's actually doing it?
Is the government doing it so they can
crack down on alternative controls
saying like Wiki leaks or anybody that's
putting out stuff that doesn't agree
with her agenda or is there a real
issue?
There's a real issue and that,
that's what I say.
I say I say there's bulk.
Correct.
I say the government for sure would
benefit from there being less sources of
news and more that they can control and
being able to put the wraps on someone
like Edward Snowden and not allow that
to happen.
For sure.
They would definitely benefit from that,
but there's also a bunch of people
writing some fake articles and they'd do
it for profit.
They do it for clicks is there was one
shut up.
He was,
yes.
He interviewed him and he was doing some
don't.
Wow Eddie,
please just be BHP
rational.
We've talking about stuff.
We're not disagreeing with you.
They'll say you.
We're saying it's all the above.
Like I'm saying that people get paid to
write fake news.
I'm saying they get money from ad
clicks.
They can make 10 $13,000
a month.
They interviewed this dude who did it
and he started getting out of control
with it.
He did it to troll Republican people and
then you realize how much ad sends he
can make from doing that and he's making
a fucking sizeable chunk of money,
so there's those guys,
but then there's also for sure there
would be government agencies that would
almost be,
it would be their responsibility to
control information.
Like if you wanted to control
information,
one of the best ways to do it would be
put out disinformation cloud.
The story that's subterfuge.
That's been going on in the CIA and the
NSA and this been going on and all of
these like secretive intelligence
community groups,
they do that forever.
They like if you,
if you pay attention to what we
absolutely know about how they engage
with the enemy,
they use every tactic.
They don't not use deception.
They don't not use propaganda.
The the 450 million plus they spent on
those fake terrorist videos to know it,
but they also had in their mind a
legitimate reason for doing it.
That's what they say.
Because you're right,
you're right.
It could be,
but Eddie,
but it could be both.
See their,
their legitimate reason is they have a
real player.
This is how you watch those videos or
it's in a real player.
When you click into a real player,
it,
it checks your Ip.
It knows your Ip,
so could figure out where you're coming
from so they can pocket.
If they could target pockets of people
in certain terrorist rich parts of the
world where they knew that there was a
bunch of uh,
isis people or what have you.
If they put out some recruitment video
and they can find that there's a lot of
people that are watching it in certain
areas,
they can sort of in their mind
triangulate where these terrorists could
be loved.
Idea.
It's the same I was reading Howard.
It's both end.
It's both.
It,
that's the cover story,
right?
But that,
but it is bold.
Isis does exist.
There are bad people in the world.
There are terrorist in the world.
Kim John Owen is a real guy.
He is.
He is a dictator over his entire
country.
There's a bunch of people in Isis that
have fucking billions of dollars that
are getting this money from is what I'm
talking about.
They exist,
of course,
oil families.
There's a lot of those,
a lot of sources,
a lot of motherfuckers.
And when you see who they're being
funded by,
you know like you ain't going to fall
for that cover story.
That's all bullshit that they,
I don't think you're right.
I think it's both.
That's what I think.
I think everybody's going after it.
They're trying to stop by Esis,
man.
There's nobody trying to stop by isis
that are encouraging it.
They're not.
They love it.
They need it.
I don't know if that's the case.
What does it say in case you didn't
know?
The United States funds and arms,
terrorist groups like al Qaeda and Isis
when it needs them to disrupt a country.
This is doctor Jill Stein who was
running for president.
She said this the day of Christmas.
She doesn't give a fuck.
That bitch is roots thankless.
Woke as fuck.
She's,
whoa.
That's what I'm talking about.
Doctors chills when you know this and it
makes sense.
You could follow the,
you're like,
okay,
totally
makes sense.
A criminals is,
oh yeah,
it makes sense.
Criminals do this kind of shit.
Well,
you should always,
always be suspected.
The people running the show,
they're criminals through.
So you never,
you never go,
oh,
you know,
if someone tells you,
uh,
someone's obsessed with like,
let's say,
you know,
some famous killer,
I don't know,
uh,
like John Gadi or whatever,
some criminal or whoever and he's
obsessed with them and he knows a lot of
shit about this murder,
that murder,
this racket,
that racket.
This is this criminal activity.
Uh,
when,
if he told you,
yeah,
you,
you know what other murder he was
involved in and you talk about it,
no dude's going to say,
uh,
now how do you know that's true?
How do you know that's true?
Where's the evidence that you probably
going to go?
You take his word for it.
This guy's,
this guy's a criminal.
He's fucked up all this other shit.
And then he tells you about some new
shit.
He fucked up.
You're probably like a,
like a normal God go.
Yeah.
Even if he's wrong.
I mean,
he's still a criminal,
but probably I haven't looked into it,
but it's like that when,
when you,
when you could follow the money so
easily and you just see the racket and
you're just like,
oh man,
anytime cns is attacking fake news,
they're creating a fake news problem.
And I didn't follow what you were saying
there until you got to know what you're
talking about.
You're talking about,
uh,
the,
the government's reason for,
for paying a UK publicity from $500
million to make fake isis and al Qaeda
videos.
To me,
$500,000
or 500 million,
those 450,
to me,
I don't want to be in the wrong about
that.
You know,
we need wrong 500,000.
Let's say it's 500 million.
That's thought it was 450 million.
So when you see,
when you see that,
let's say you just saw that quote and
you believed it.
Let's say she's right.
Okay.
Just pretend she's right.
Who,
whatever.
That,
that chick,
that Jill Jill Stein,
she's talking about,
andy is also funding the mujahideen,
which we were pretty open about when
they were there willing.
That is,
that's what became the Islamic terrorist
of today.
But that's what we,
none of the funding tennis customer
Russians,
let me finish real quick,
when you see a statement like that and
there's many people saying that,
but there's a man,
there's one,
just,
just say that's true what she just said.
And then you find out that the
government paid $500 million to make
fake isis videos,
the funding numb and then they're making
fake isis videos.
Sounds like they want to blow that shit
up.
You know?
So when you see the cover story,
when the government says the criminal
says the criminal says,
ah,
what we were doing is we were making cds
and we were like dispersing them and
then so that people would get them and
then they would play them.
And you know,
you know,
we,
we did only a terrorist would play that
cd,
so then we could track their ip address.
To me that's like some serious horse
shit.
No,
but we do it the same with like in the
drug industry.
If they catch a drug dealer they they
flip him or use him for some to get to
the bigger play there,
which is the drug kingpin.
Right,
so same thing with this.
They might,
they might fund those ridiculous videos.
You sounded like that the are criminal
but no Eddie,
the problem is you think there's only
one way to this.
I think there's a like a,
a lack of nuance in the,
the,
the idea of this.
I think it's both.
I think for sure the government is going
to make some fake shit.
I mean they told us they were going to
do it to fight the war on crime or in
the fight.
The war on terror.
They told us they were going to do that.
They told us they were going to do it.
They do it in plain sight.
Then of course,
of course go along for sure 100% but
also there's also people that are in
charge of making sure it's not like
everybody who is in the CIA or the FBI
or any of these organizations is like a
part of some gigantic said that,
when did I say that?
But never said okay.
Only but the people.
But the idea that the,
all the rest of them would know that
it's bullshit and that would go along
with it.
I don't think that's the case.
I think what they're trying to do is
figure out ways where they could locate
terrorists if they figured out a way
they could located terrorist.
And it's through Ip checking of people
who watched terrorist recruitment
videos.
I don't think that's a bad idea.
It might not get everybody and it might
not even work,
but it's not a bad idea.
They're doing a decent job.
Have you seen now just switch subjects a
little bit,
but how have you seen on a second?
Just don't,
don't you think that there's a w there,
there's gotta be some way.
If there are legitimate terrorists in
the world and you're trying to find
them,
he's gotta be some way to find them.
That's a good way to find them.
I Ip addresses,
if they're clicking on those videos,
funding them,
why would they try to find them really
who's going yet?
He is at the same people.
That's my point.
Is it the same people that pitch,
but that does,
that's one person.
Eddie,
this is the same people that are in
charge of making these videos to try to
find these people.
Are they the same people that are also
completely aware that they're funding
them or is there a bunch of different
factions all working together and each
one of them doesn't completely be honest
with the other?
Yeah,
I could see that.
Definitely most of the CIA,
most of the FBI,
good,
honest,
hardworking people.
It's just people keep people in certain
spots there.
I mean,
they're funding Isis.
That's just one quote.
There's many,
many quotes,
but let's just say that was true,
that quote that with that chick said,
that's true.
Okay.
We're funding CIC,
presidential candidate Jill Stein.
She's not the first one to say that,
but anyways,
right.
Let's just say what she,
that statement is true.
If it's true on Christmas,
if it's true,
if they're funding Isis,
yes.
There's probably a low level people
saying,
hey,
how are we going to stop isis?
But the overall agenda is not to stop
it.
The overall they're funding it.
Why they going to stop it?
They want to blow it up.
The funding it.
You'd put two and two together though.
Crip.
First of all,
the criminals at the top.
We know that.
Everybody knows.
Everybody know that,
so we we,
we got to treat them like a detective
would like your average bullshit as
detective would go this criminal,
the no one would ever know detective
would ever look at a criminal.
God.
There's no way he would do that.
He doesn't have the time to do.
He does not that smart.
He doesn't have the smarts that he's so
unorganized.
This guy would,
this guy,
he,
no detective would say that.
It'd be like,
you know what?
You're fucking criminal.
Let's look.
Maybe you are innocent.
Maybe you are,
but God damn,
look at the money trail,
look at all this circumstantial
evidence.
It's just damn,
you know,
look at it.
And then the hardcore evidence documents
and Shit,
if you ask isis,
they're not going to tell you they're
winning.
Like they're getting fucked up.
Who knows what they're saying?
They're funding them and they have
control of the media.
Who fucking knows what the fuck is going
on?
Who really knows?
Nobody knows what the fuck's going to
see how isis used to use twitter and
certain things.
So as they would get,
you know,
followers to see stuff and organize
plans.
Will twitter has a,
someone who's just 24,
seven,
Merck's those accounts where he can't
have them anymore.
Now that use telegraph,
you know what that is or they can send
a,
uh,
it's a,
you can organize a private chat room so
he can whatever,
they have us code words.
All those isis followers go there and
then they ha they logged in and they
somehow some guy got into it cause you
have to prove everyone in the secret
chat rooms and it says what they want to
do.
And they'll say,
uh,
just crazy example in milwaukee.
How many guys do,
they'll say,
how many guys do we have?
And there's seven,
but we have these guns.
These guns were going to hit up this,
oh I scouted,
I did this.
So they're going to,
the guy owns telegraph going,
what the fuck man,
stop these accounts.
And he's like,
ah,
you know,
I created so everyone can use it,
man.
These high level security I create for
that and this dude just get in fucking
reamed for it.
Does he not have the abilities and
Russian?
He does have the Barista.
He's in Russia.
But what happens is these accounts go up
and then after you're done there they
their race forever.
That's why people use them.
Wow.
Interesting.
Israeli hackers have said this.
It's crazy time,
dude.
It's a crazy time.
Cause you,
yeah.
And then he,
his point,
he goes,
I didn't create a fucking telegram for
Isis,
but just like anything,
we create some good,
it's bad.
People follow.
I can't control any,
what was that guy that he kept telling
me about?
Was it Gary Vanerchuck?
Is that the guy?
Yeah,
I saw an interview with him,
man in that he was talking about people,
I'm using phones and this lady goes,
isn't it terrible what we're doing to
these young people using phones?
And he was like,
look,
this is you.
You're looking at human evolution.
We're not doing anything.
These people,
this is like,
this is what people are doing and you
know,
just step back and look at what's
happening.
And he was saying that because we're
just going to be looking in the future
back at this time,
like this is the good old days before
virtual reality for sure.
It seems to me that all these things are
competing together,
that taking over,
taking over various aspects of the
world,
controlling global resources like oil
and things along those lines.
And they are windmills now that assigns
a fucking seven 47.
Have you seen these gigantic windmills
that they're putting together trying to
figure out how to dominate the
production of electricity and oil and
gas and keep money flowing and all the
while we're getting drawn deeper and
deeper into this electronic world.
Like we've got some weird shit going on
in our future folks.
Weird Matrix style shit.
Did you see in Dubai?
They're already,
they're building it now that we're those
tubes so you can get from Dubai to
wherever in like 30 minutes.
Hyperloops uh,
Elon Musk is the one that came up with
it,
but uh,
in Dubai,
the the first ones to actually fund it
and raise the money and they're building
it now.
That's scary.
That's a plane on the ground on now,
son jumping a tube and just imagine the
feeling of going 500 miles an hour,
500 mile an hour,
a hyperloop train.
That's not that fast.
It takes you from Abu Dhabi to Dubai in
12 minutes with Smith's son.
That's amazing.
They're saying if they do it right in
America,
you can be able to live in la,
work in New York every day.
Oh my God.
Fuck all that.
Jumping in that first.
You're going to be in that too.
For what?
At least 500 miles an hour.
It's going to five hours.
No,
no.
That star that's just started to fuck
you on must saying like 1200 miles an
hour is what there is.
What they're planning 500 miles an hour
aside to think what like a plane flies.
I don't think it's any faster than a
plane.
I can go underground.
That's true.
Yeah,
so 500 miles an hour in a plane,
but it takes you five hours.
This is across the country for five
hours.
It's,
it's inevitable.
They're going to do it.
It's going to be five hours now it's 12
miles,
1200 miles an hour.
That's probably two and a half,
two and a half hours to get tenured.
A long time to do a long time.
Go.
Going to fast.
Comfortable too.
When you can walk around this tube,
maybe it's uh,
how big is this tube?
Is it worse?
This smell,
people's farts in a tube going 500 miles
now on the ground or in a tube going 500
miles an hour in the sky.
The Sky,
the plan.
How often do you just say fuck it,
I cannot hold these motherfuckers.
You let him so fucking,
that shit is so rude.
Cause most of the time you hold it in
right most of the time and try to time
it.
You got a bathroom,
you gotta do right?
He's got damn good.
Nailed it man.
You ever just said,
fuck it,
I'm just going to go for it and
whatever.
I'm just gonna keep my eyes closed.
Put your eye shades on the tender
asleep.
They just let them go.
Dudes do that to me all the time.
This guy decided to just go for it.
I'm like,
I don't know.
It could either be this guy or that guy
that recycled air,
just fucking your world up.
It's gotta be like a suction thing in
your and the seat.
So like a little button you press and it
soaks.
It does help.
That shit does help a lot.
They say,
oh it's pretty good.
It was probably for the farts.
For the fights.
Probably broad.
You have a fucking fat wherever in a
restaurant.
Do you have a fan blowing on you?
It blows.
That's hard.
Yeah.
They need to fix that problem and claim
for the farts and they never talked
about it.
Mark fans for 500% or you know what?
Back when people used to smoke on
planes,
that's when they had them remember that
these to smoke
on planes and then it got to the point
where you could only smoke in the back.
So they had a smoking section.
Yeah,
I used to fly back then.
He was crazy.
You would?
I would be in those sections man.
Cause I was,
I would be,
that's where he could buy tickets.
People just like,
they would say the only tickets that are
available,
the smoking section and it would cost
less.
You go into that fucking smoking
section,
just sit down people around your light
and home in a two.
Meanwhile you come on the whole craze
smoking cessation point though.
Yeah.
Dice clay used to have a little bit
about it.
We're in a fucking toe.
Don't have to go back to everybody's
breathing the same fucking hell bit
about a man.
It was fucking hilarious.
Yeah,
it has a weird time when people used to
go to smoke everywhere in restaurants,
in Bar,
everywhere you went,
you would see people smoking movie
theaters.
Now I love that.
We tell you not to smoke in movie
theaters where people would do it all
the time.
People get mad at him.
Hey man,
put it out.
That was one of those laws that was at,
that's what I mean.
The government work.
Totally Shit.
Well,
you know what was a good law?
You know why?
Because people were filing lawsuits.
A lot of people that worked inside
restaurants and bars,
they were getting cancer,
lung cancer from secondhand smoke.
Imagine if your job was to be a waitress
and you got to go to this fucking bar
everyday people go,
oh,
gives you shoot booger.
Well,
it's a good job.
Why should you be subject to being
poisoned at a good job?
Like you have to like,
it's a crazy,
it's not like drinking.
If you're drinking and I'm not drinking,
I'm right next to you.
I don't suffer anything.
Yeah.
But if you're smoking right next to me,
and especially if you work in a place
where everybody's smoking,
man,
you're going to die.
Strip club baby.
I never got him to cigarettes.
You guys are flipped with cigarettes.
No,
but I've had them before.
Go on stage before with Tony
Hinchcliffe.
I've taken a smacks snacks.
He does.
Yeah.
They fire you up dude.
It's like a,
it gives you,
it's a stimulant.
It's,
it's a,
it's very much like a nootropic really
very,
very bad for your body for sure.
But stimulant in itself,
like tobacco is a stimulant for sure.
100%.
I'll give you,
um,
if you could chew,
I think it would probably be the better
move.
Like Donald gave me some of those chew
when I was here and I was like,
whoa.
Like this stuff fires you up,
gets you kind of like buzz.
Yeah,
yeah,
for sure.
That's what that was.
Smoked cigars,
Bro.
I don't know me from trying to load so
that down and trying to cut way back on
the Bros.
But occasionally they sneak through the
broan is if they ruined bro by con con.
Anybody who's an asshole,
bro.
Come on Bro.
He's a bro,
you know.
But um,
yeah man,
for sure.
Like there's a,
there's no doubt about it.
It's,
it's a definite stimulant.
Like if you smoke a cigar,
you get a buzz.
You don't see a lot of smokers these
days though.
They're smart.
People are smartening up.
Well,
you hang out with athletes.
I hang out with zero athletes.
There you hang out with comedians that
don't smoke.
Yeah.
Comedians don't smoke these days way
less.
Way less.
It used to be almost everybody.
Swiss deleah doesn't even drink.
Yeah.
Well he never
drank,
drank or smoked.
There's a lot of guys who don't drink.
Um,
but back in the day,
man,
most guys smoked like are used to smoke
dunkin used to smog.
Joe Use a small red bands still smokes
now.
No,
I never smoked.
no athlete.
Yeah,
I was,
well,
I was healthy.
I was still working out.
Yeah.
Like all the time I was doing standup in
the beginning,
I was kickboxing then like got to
Jujitsu.
I did Jujitsu straight through.
Like I never,
I never didn't actually say you can't
smoke cigarettes and do Jujitsu,
but you're going to get taught,
you're going to miss a lot.
And it's tough.
I mean,
you're,
you're not just working out,
you're playing a game of death and if
you tap out because you fucking gas out
that you got tapped out and then never
feels that good.
That's what Jujitsu is.
So,
uh,
people get obsessed with it.
So,
so much.
You guys,
why Joe Schilling is a crazy example.
He's crazy.
He smokes.
Joe Schilling is a worldclass kickboxer
and he smoked smoking all the time.
Hello?
Pack a day.
Wow.
That's amazing.
They say smokes a pack a day.
Not In Kansas coming back,
but I think he was up to that.
Yeah.
Not In quippy.
Little while did it again.
It needs to get on them.
Robot dicks suck on one of them.
Robot decks,
those,
uh,
those vaporizers.
Bill strawberry clouds.
They do smell nice too.
I don't mind if people do that.
I don't think it gives you the buzz that
a cigarette though though.
I think cigarette gives you a very
specific buzz.
I think it was just chemicals,
all that thick smoke.
There's a fucking,
if Eddie wants to come back and talk
more theories on conspiracies,
which is always wonderful.
Those fantastic.
He's so mad.
We barely talked about the UFC.
Everybody's so mad right now.
Zero option.
They're a shit what we do and it's what
we do.
We're all like,
yeah,
UFC capacity.
So much fun.
We saw the time but um,
they did the FDA approved like 500 plus
chemicals and to put them in a
cigarette.
So all designed to make you more and
more addicted to.
But did you know,
cigarettes a never been less popular and
uh,
my generation they think is going to be
the final kind of strongly get rid of
smoking.
Cause now it's just,
it's more of a healthier kind of vibe
now with millennials and stuff like
that.
So smoking is,
you're fucked.
Like really?
No one's doing it.
I wonder if too,
we'll carry on.
They need more of those dudes that get
their jar removed.
See Lung cancer,
because we're up here,
we're in California.
If we're down south in Georgia or some
shit like that it,
but that she went left and right to the
point he had like a hidden camera and
you put it on the chew section of a
store on a fucking choose locked Pelican
calm.
Chewies shoot.
People who Chew Chewies I dunno.
You could,
you could do,
do what?
Do Your chewy like have a club.
Yeah.
You don't think they called tooheys?
That's going to work?
No.
Oh well,
um,
we were talking about the smoke.
You can chew and like Donald has
fantastic cardio and he chews or dips.
Was it a different,
she'll dip,
dip,
dip paired the same thing.
But the shoe was like,
remember those old school baseball
players look like?
Yeah,
they have
that shit like Lenny Dykstra.
Yeah.
You know,
it's really crazy,
man.
That is probably very similar to what it
feels like when you're chewing cocoa
leaves.
But the coca leaves are illegal.
Like when those guys in Peru,
they take those coca leaves and they put
them in the side of their mouth and they
chew on them and they showed them all
the time.
And you get,
you also get actual vitamins from the
flavonoids,
I guess.
God Damn Cell.
Look at that guy.
That many.
Yeah,
that's cat Jamie.
That's the wrong stuff.
You want to coca leaves that,
that's God.
That's a stimulant or a,
a narcotic rather.
That cat stuff is very much like a,
not a narcotic.
It's like meth.
Dan's us.
Yeah.
It makes it crazy.
They do a lot of crazy shit on it,
but this stuff is a coca leaves.
They take it and they pack their mouth
with it and they chew on it and it has
an effect,
a stimulant effect.
It's similar to a cup of coffee.
I've never done it,
but I have had,
um,
a tea that was made out of it as a
Matteto [inaudible] tea.
Crunk no,
but I couldn't shut the fuck up,
which is always a problem already.
It was like,
are awesome depending on what your job
is.
No,
it wasn't.
Coke was,
I wasn't jacked.
I don't know.
I've never done cuts.
Work coat comes from,
right?
Yes,
exactly.
But it's chewing the leaves versus the
processed soup.
It's like the difference between getting
your sugar from eating an orange versus
eating like a couple of tablespoons of
like real processed sugar.
What?
Like your body's like,
what the fuck is this?
Like where the hell is this shit coming
from body doesn't know what the fuck you
do with like a spoon of sugar.
It's like Whoa,
why is this alone?
Where's,
where's all the fiber?
Where's the fucking vitamins?
This is just shit.
What did you do?
You crazy assholes.
That's what cocaine is and that's why I
can fuck with fruit.
Cause the fiber,
right?
Cause they breaks down different and
that's why I think these people that
chew these cocoa leaves,
they get a totally different experience
than someone who does coke.
I need to try it though.
I never chewed the leaves.
You'd be done with two popular to those
should be legal bro.
It should be 100% legal.
It's illegal.
The pride.
You can't even have those leaves.
The problem is you could take those
leaves,
you can process it into cocaine,
which by the way is an actual ingredient
and cocacola still cocaine is still,
yes.
Yes it is.
They take coca leaves,
they processed the coca leaves and they
make medical cocaine with it.
And the same plant that does this,
the same processing place it does this
ships the flavors of it to Coca Cola.
So it's one of the main flavors they
use.
Got Coca Cola and Pepsi Cola are two
totally different tasting things I've
enclosed.
And one of the reasons why they taste
different is coca cola used to have
cocaine in it and now it's flavored by
coca leaves.
Google that coke is so much better than
Pepsi Cooler that they still look at
this,
look at this.
To this day dude,
coca extractions is,
it's got cocaine free leaves are sold to
Coca Cola.
Exactly.
So they take these cocoa leaves,
the factory processes them,
turns him into medical cocaine and the
rest of the shit that's processed
without cocaine in it is shipped to Coca
Cola flavor knowledge.
Hey,
the medical cocaine when it's medical
lidacain um,
which is uh,
one of the things that they use.
It's like the gay cousin of cocaine they
use it for,
doesn't get you high but it numbs you
up.
Damn.
Um,
yeah.
It's um,
we took a lot of Coca Cola.
They must be making a lot of medical
cocaine man.
Oh yeah.
They must be making ridiculous amounts
of it.
I wonder how much the actual flavor they
get out of the leaves versus actual
cocaine.
It's probably taken a lot of leaves to
get cocaine's last time you had like a
nice ice cold Coke Cola.
I don't drink.
It's terrible.
I had a diet coke last night though.
Well that's even worse.
That's even worse.
That shit is rarely do.
But it said fuck it.
It's Christmas dude.
I did too.
And I had a regular coke,
regular coke.
That shit is delicious.
So good barbecue.
Come on.
I'd wake up in the middle of the night
and run down to the 24 hour liquor store
and get a couple cans of coke and just
like down in one drink.
I had a drink hold cans in one drink.
How was obsessed with sodas?
Man,
think about how much sugar,
how much sugar in my throat.
I'm addicted to that one.
I just want the constant burn when it's
cold too.
Ooh,
that's nice.
That's nice.
Pace the same.
It does not taste the same out of those
fucking fountains.
You better stop calling that call.
Look at that show your Goddamn Liar.
That is not the same formula.
You get to be out of Pfoa at 100% gotta
be out of a can or a bottle or a bottle
or that Mexican bottle with that cane
sugar.
But that green bottle,
no,
the ones that you get at certain stores,
Coca Cola Green cause that's how you
know having a pure cane sugar.
Oh,
green green's a different kind of is.
They don't know what the fuck you're
talking about.
Again,
Nicola [inaudible] worlds are attacking
people.
Speaking to Paige vanzant,
Michelle waterson.
Not to be confused with Michelle
Waterman.
Ron Waterman,
a coca cola life cane sugar and Stevia
bullshit.
Is this a new one?
To put Stevia?
Stevia is a good move.
But cane sugar and Stevia,
they put like a little,
a little dab of Stevia and a bucket of
sugar.
Get that poison on my fucking face.
People know Z.
Do you,
have you ever tried that?
Oh,
look at that.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
We have some here.
We have saw.
I love that stuff.
They sent me a bunch of it.
Not even paying me to say it.
And we drag it on air,
didn't we?
I Dunno.
What is it?
It's soda flavored with Stevia.
They make an energy drink.
It's good.
Stevie's good man.
I like it.
It doesn't fuck with you.
I like to put it in coffee.
Doesn't,
doesn't fuck with your blood sugar
levels.
Tastes better.
I agree.
He's,
no,
it doesn't seem to have any negatives.
I mean,
I don't know what it's like if you abuse
it,
but I think he had a hundred oranges.
Your body's going to feel like shit.
I'll let you know.
Cause I abuse the shit out.
Yeah.
According to Dan Quinn now it's a,
yeah,
that guy is on the ball.
So let's talk about I'm dominick Cruz
and cody garbrandt man.
Uh,
yeah,
two hours into the podcast people are
like,
fuck,
it's,
it's a boxing.
It's a Coke Cola.
But this is what happens when you have a
producer or like,
you know,
engineer or a rather,
uh,
executive.
Uh,
you look at the,
we'll get the money line code.
He's not that big of an underdog.
Well,
cody's fucking dangerous.
Super Dangerous.
Here's the question.
Like,
is he ever faced anybody that moves the
way dominic does?
And we've seen with so many guys that
they have a really hard time hitting
dominic.
He's a really hard time to hit.
Okay,
so dominic is a two to one favorite,
correct?
You know,
which is a,
I'd say that's,
well,
cody's one 75,
so the real,
the real spread is only 35 cents on a
dollar a dollar bet.
Not,
not crazy.
No.
That's swear.
She got good.
Dominic is what they're banking on.
I think.
You know,
cody hasn't Mizzou.
[inaudible] is best win,
which was his last fight.
So that's what got him this title shot.
Here's something bank on him landing on
Dominic.
Here's something that people aren't
talking about.
Linacre and Tj dillashaw is on the same
card.
That's a crazy fucking fight.
Linacre scary.
Lineker super scary.
He's terrifying.
Building that little monkey.
He's built like a chimpanzee dude.
He like like a a pounder.
And when I say a little racist,
ladies and gentlemen,
I call myself a month 35.
Just want to specify Linacre wasn't any
one 25.
Yes,
he was one 25.
You wouldn't make the way that he has.
He has a real talent and he has real
power at that was scary.
Scary guy.
Hemmer cody's the hardest hitters.
That latter one fight.
[inaudible]
a different kind of hit her though.
I think cody is lightning fast and like
beautiful combinations and beautiful
footwork,
better technique.
The angles that he cut when he knocked
out.
Um,
uh,
Thomas,
I made up when he knocked out Thomas
Almeda like Amanda was undefeated,
very scary and he cut some serious
fucking angles and drop some bombs on
him.
I was like,
whoa.
Cody's back speed of entry.
His uncle was alternative Olympic boxer.
His Dad was a boxer and they just put
this little ball of hate and to him,
but he's a ridiculous wrestler to his
kind of knockout power is a different
kind of knockout power.
Then Linacre Linacre is almost like a
guy that is 20 or 30 pounds bigger than
him.
It's weird like he hits guides and you
see them like,
oh,
like he's hitting you on the arms with
these bombs and he takes a shot
extremely well.
Like when he fought a Francisco,
um,
when you,
when you watched the,
the combination of those two guys
unloaded in the first round,
you're like,
Jesus Christ.
Francisco Rivera is a bad motherfucker,
a very good striker.
And he just decided to go to war with
Linacre and Leonard who was just
dropping bombs on them and you go,
Jesus,
he can do this even at one 35 maybe be
even better at one 35.
I and I,
and I love to watch linacre fight.
I don't think in for right now,
I don't think could be championed with
his,
with that style of fighting.
Don't and only boxing watch what
happens.
Watch what happens when Tj,
cause it's easy to game plan for Tj and
Dwayne lug width and go,
all right,
this is what we do and you're gonna see
him.
Angles makes it it up.
I'm excited about it because I think tj
spectacularly talented,
no doubt,
and Tj has amazing footwork and all
that,
the Duane system.
But Leonard has got something special.
Man,
I'm,
I've,
I've very rarely seen a guy at his
weight class that hits people the way he
does.
It's a very,
it's an almost like good,
he's doing a different thing.
Yeah.
It's different kind of months or those
fights are very similar where cody
garbrandt just needs one to win the
fight.
Linacre needs one to win the fight.
Dominic Cruz footwork's ridiculous.
Tj dillashaw is footwork.
Ridiculous.
But you've got to think,
you know,
Tj Kol Hanan Barao twice dropped him in
the first round with a straight right
hand.
It's not like Tj doesn't have power and
Tj hooker power,
he doesn't have the same kind of power,
but he's got way more options as far as
movement,
you know?
So it's going to be very interesting to
see how you have this movement came and
remember that fight only three routes,
which hurts.
I finished Tj,
tj because he's got to survive the
storm.
Yeah,
Tj because tj moves so good man is hard.
Like in the brow fight you saw it like
right away,
browse.
Got that like linear style presses for
five rounds though,
right of that footwork's gonna that's
gonna be hard to follow.
If you're that straight forward pressure
fighter for championship rounds,
you're like Jesus Christ and starts
wearing on you and then tj takes over.
That's interesting.
That's a good point.
I think Tj uh,
is,
is definitely in a tricky situation
because he wanted that rematch,
wanted that title fight.
He was really close in the first fight
with dominick Cruz.
It was a real close person.
You just told me they were like,
you won that fight.
I think Dana even agreed was like,
you won that fight man.
It's a very close fight,
no doubt about it.
Well,
whoever you believe won that fight and
then dominic goes on and beat Shariah
and beat them handily.
And now dominick is stepping in to fight
him and he's got a,
he's,
he's a fighting cody and he's got a
really tough fight on that,
on that same card and a really tough
fight where if he loses that fight,
fuck man back in the line.
This is,
and this is a guy with that is missed
wait a couple of times and Linacre is
like kind of tricky in that situation
where he's Ms.
Wade if at featherweight or I miss wait
rather at a flyweight yeah a couple of
times.
And it hasn't he Ms.
Wade at Bantam weight to one.
Yeah.
So this is a guy that's going to come
and biggest fuck is very dangerous.
Hit super hard.
Like in a creepy way.
Creepy hard almost.
So almost like a,
it's almost like a heavyweight fight for
Tj cause you make one mistake in lineker
lands,
it's over.
You're fighting dom,
you make some mistakes and get lit up.
He's not going to end your night show,
pull up linacre versus Macdonald.
Macdonald is a fucking straight killer.
That kid's a bad motherfuckers.
Yet the patient has had some injuries.
Yeah.
I had some injuries lost to Uriah.
Uriah mauled him.
That was the big one.
When you're I in Merch,
dumb cause that he finally came back and
then you at Merck dumb,
he went away.
It was one over your eyes.
Finest performances.
You're right.
Cracked him with a right hand,
got ahold of that neck and just put the
full uriah on them as far as his,
uh,
his key,
a teen that mounted guillotine just
fucking,
but it's almost like the one 35
tournament cause you have,
you know,
you have a cody and dom,
they have Tj Linacre.
The loser's going to fight the loser
winner's gonna fight the way.
Yeah,
let's watch,
check out that if you could to find that
fine.
Linacre versus Michael McDonald.
Kao I had it but it didn't pull up it
wrong.
Fifer oh these sons of bitches areas.
So like Michael McDonald,
like real classical style,
real good at punching power.
Not built like a scary guy,
but a vicious knockout artists like one
of those guys where the body really sort
of,
uh,
is uh,
is very deceptive.
And remember he was like top,
top prospect.
He was a big,
big prospect to see Uriah or Hanan Barao
first he lost a hand and Barao.
Right,
and then he came back and fought uriah.
Wasn't that the case?
How tall is linker?
He's short.
He's short,
but he's about the same height as dwight
cow.
Five says.
I don't know.
I don't,
they don't think he is.
Honestly.
I think he's five four.
He's a small little dude.
He's a small guy but hits like a fucking
mack truck.
Almost creepy in his power man.
Like and in so confident in it too.
But again,
to the point where I don't think he's
going to be champ.
You look at a guy like John Dotson who
just outworked them and I thought he
lost that fight.
Granted they gave it to Lynika.
Yeah,
well it was close enough.
I mean,
oh look,
look,
he heard him there.
Look,
You could see Mike McDowell steps back
and it's like,
oh Jesus.
There's a feeling that guys get when he
connects on them when you see it in
their eyes.
So like,
Holy Shit,
this is a different thing here.
It's a,
it's a,
that's not snowflake.
That's not snowflake move.
Yeah,
no.
And he's,
he's also got a ridiculous Chin when he
foot,
when he stood in front of Rivera,
it's going like this,
like,
come on.
They were just banging it out.
And Rivera fun but rare flattens people.
So as you watch like Linacre walk them
down here,
you're looking at this kid who's just
got unique power.
Well,
like really unique.
And even a guy like,
oh,
look at that.
Boom.
Michael McDonald recognize he goes down
there,
I look,
he goes down again,
boom,
boom.
And linacre just stands in front of
them,
bites on his mouthpiece and fucking
malls on Mcdonald.
Landed one deal and Linacre ate it like
a tic TAC.
And he's moving forward.
Boom,
take home.
And he rocks him again.
And he's just undeniably confidence in
his ability to walk you down and smash.
You.
See what you can't do as loan back yet
and get your back against the kids.
You gotta move,
man.
See I've heard him again times more,
10 times more,
100% but the question is,
is there going to be exchanges were
dillashaw is inside of his range and
we'll one of these things land and once
one of those things do land,
we'll dillashaw continue to engage the
same way like boom,
boom,
boom.
Or will it be over right lands.
But tj takes a good shot and has never
been a guy to stand in front of you like
this and Oh look at that.
And we see his head gets snapped out.
What [inaudible] talking about.
It's very rare that anybody has that
kind of destroying power.
Remember that?
Remember Tj can wrestle too,
so if they're getting close he'll take
his ass down.
The difference between him and Dotson at
one 35 and I liked Dotson at 35 I think
he's better at 35 then 25 I just think
he just kills himself too much to make
that weight.
Like when you fought GAM Berrien is
dotson can sneak in on you and your son
too.
And when they fought,
did they fight at 35 or 25 when it came
bands and,
and uh,
and Linacre fought does at 25.
Is it 100% of the 25?
Yeah.
Is it,
you might be right.
I don't think that's the right weight
class for dots.
And I think Dodson we'd be at both guys.
I think both guys were way better off
without destroying themselves.
Those are fun fights man.
And then on the pre the fs one prelims
are stacked.
You got Neil magni versa.
What's that catch weight?
One 36 and a half wait or no?
So it must've been like a last minute
decision to,
to have that fight.
So That's interesting that Dodson and
him went to war and linear one that
decision.
Yes,
I 35,
but I thought,
um,
you talked about some one.
Yeah.
Um,
here's the other thing about Tj.
You got to think how long has tj really
been with Duane Ludwig and he continues
to get better with Duane Ludwig?
It's only been a few years.
So in the last couple of years,
like we,
you know,
we will do,
we've seen,
we've seen the two big fights with Hana
barrao where he marked him,
right,
which are the all time career highlight
performances.
Right.
Joe especially the second one that Joe
Soto fight,
which was an interesting fight because
taking a real tough guy on a real short
notice today,
none day,
one day during the way in trying to make
weight falls asleep and bangs his head
on the wall because he cut too much
weight.
Joe Soto steps in.
And so tj makes that adjustment,
wins that fight coming back,
beats the shit out of Barao and the
rematch like really dominated him in the
rematch.
Those are like,
you know,
real highlight reel finishes,
all three of those fights.
So then,
uh,
he goes from that,
the really close lost to Dominick Cruz
and then beats a sun sal.
Like he took a chance with a sun sal.
A sense.
Yeah.
He beat us on site,
look better in the sun south fight.
Then he did in the first time they
fought.
So he's showing improvement just in that
fight.
You just got to wonder what this is
going to look like,
what linacre versus him is going to look
like.
Very,
very interesting fight.
Great.
Matchups fuck yeah.
That one particular,
what do you think about cody and
Dominic?
Do you think the code he's going to be
able to,
like when you look at cody move and you
see his success against guys like to
Gawky against guys like Thomas Almeda
and then you see what dominic does to
people.
He's in front of you.
He's not.
He's,
he's shuffling stances.
He's off to the side.
He's got his hands down.
He's moving in this really fucking weird
way.
That's real tough to emulate.
I love cody,
but the x factor,
here's,
we haven't really seen them.
Faith top competition.
Mizzou [inaudible].
He's older.
He got merck before from Dominic.
Ben.
He gets murked by cody.
We saw promise in Almeda.
We saw him fight a really promising God.
Again,
young guy,
not level of dominick Cruz
or we haven't seen with the movement.
Right?
The thing that I like about cody,
so damn game,
I was talking to a lance palmer at team
alpha male and they're like,
we've never seen theme like it,
like fight week.
If he sees someone and he needs to work
on this,
but he's just young and hungry.
He goes,
if he sees someone from the other camp,
he tries to fight them in the hallway.
He's just like this pit bull man and
he's just so god competitive.
They're like,
wait,
we have to have a coach with them at all
times,
author.
He won't leave.
He won't leave the gym.
If you see someone else from the camp
tries and fight some,
but don't think that that's a waste of
energy.
100% he's young.
He's young.
It could be an exaggeration though.
Could be for sure.
You have had a problem with one dude
once.
We're sure Friday bravo now a sudden
talking.
Reasonable now taught now.
Now talking common sense.
That sounds like fake news.
Let's go over the rest of the car and
popped the whole card.
Jamie.
The big thing on this is,
um,
can cody Land Kenny?
But Kenny,
keep up for again,
five.
It's five rounds.
It's five fucking rounds,
man.
Do you think about anything about these
guys?
They're both real good man.
They're both real good,
good ground fighters to Louis Mocha and
Ray Borg.
That should be a very interesting fight.
Fun Fight.
This card.
It sucks.
Cause how about Canaan?
Verdo [inaudible] the guy that pulled
out on a,
he was supposed to be fighting,
um,
uh,
Ian and pull down on real short notice.
Remember that smoke?
It was fun to watch or got hurt.
He's really both fun to watch as small.
Got For an American Russian or actually
from the eastern bloc?
No,
he's American American.
He's like,
yeah.
Where's Louis [inaudible]?
I Dunno where Louis is from.
It.
What sucks is cane for doom off.
That'd be fun.
Hawaii.
Oh,
he's Hawaiian.
That's right.
Dot.
Last Samurai.
That's why it's Da.
That's right.
His Dad's probably rushing them.
Sao Dare you come on.
Small gun.
Is that a,
is that a Russian name?
Hell yeah.
You go back to that on man.
I don't know anything.
Smoker,
smoker.
What is that?
Uh,
when you say it like that,
that on slide done it smoke a bro.
Um,
whereas where's,
what's his ethnicity?
It just might be Hawaiian dude.
He might just be straight Hawaiian.
Get on Brazil.
And his nickname is a wiki page.
Does he have a weed smoke?
You might be a mad stoner and he's
Hawaiian is fuck yeah,
he looks pretty fucking Hawaiians are
killing it,
huh?
Holloway.
Oh yeah,
man.
Well that's a crazy island.
When you're stuck on an island with
dudes and you got a problem with them,
you can't just fucking drive away.
Like that's a completely different
mindset.
You can't drive way.
Got It.
I'll live in an island.
You're hanging out together on a
volcano.
It doesn't say anything about his
ethnicity.
He's Hawaiian,
Bro.
That's why this shit,
man.
Let's go to the uh,
Amanda Nunez.
Ronda rousey fight.
If you got to put some money down,
what do you,
what do you think,
man?
Who the fuck knows?
I love saying who the fuck knows because
you,
we haven't seen Ronda fight in over a
year.
We don't need your head.
They're looking at her body.
She's in insane shape.
There's a pictures of her online
throwing punches and you look at her
back,
you're like,
yeah,
oh,
leash and seen him.
She's down.
She's down to fight.
Wake.
Wait already apparently you know,
I think losing to someone like Holly
Holm the way she did and to be tired and
get beat up and the whole deal like look
at her back there,
which was punching the speed bag.
Jesus,
that's,
that's ridiculous.
Damn.
So if you think about the way she lost
that fight and how she looked
physically,
she didn't look nothing like this.
Like not even close.
Like she's got all these videos of her
running up hills and all this different
stuff.
She looks like way more fit.
She got tired in the fight with holly
and that was a big factor is also
getting hit was a big factor.
Getting stunned right away and but
really solid conditioning will allow you
to recover better than not being in such
good shape.
Especially when you get hit in the Ed.
It's a,
a big factor with the guys that are
super,
super fit is how they bounce back.
You know,
like,
um,
Neil Magni is a good example.
You can stun that guy in the first
round,
but he's so fit.
He bounces back for her to that,
that holly fight.
You should,
the one thing that Ron,
she always comes to fight.
She's always in shape.
She takes that,
you know,
personal,
it takes it,
it Kinda upon herself.
She did not have the same sort of
dedication towards that fight with holly
that she's got towards this fight.
Physically it doesn't let us think.
We know physically.
You can say that,
but we don't know cause she'd been
shooting movies.
She won't do Prescott.
Right.
You know what I'm saying?
So we don't know.
She could take her down her judo and not
try to strike with,
they're just clinch up.
Do that judo trip.
Take her down.
Anybody's in danger of that arm bar.
That's what she's so god,
she's going to mandan and this could
easily get caught in that arm bar.
Wouldn't shock.
Here's a question for age.
He's got to drag her down.
Here's a question.
Where do you guys,
do you think she has the coaching to
make changes where she just doesn't pull
forward on a man Nunez and get punched
in the face course she's going to
become,
of course she's going to take her time.
Of course she's not going to go out
there reckless.
She's going to take your time.
That's how she came round around Shit
anyways,
and it seems like common sense.
Don't fucking get crazy.
Get in there.
Just fucking get the blood going.
That's not her.
Eddie.
She didn't get to man.
That's a guy named Mike Tyson.
Gay Sound Outside and Jab and do.
She might try to overwhelm arm,
but she's not stupid.
She's going to learn from mistakes.
They just fight a cleaner fight.
More movement,
more head movement.
The surgery,
she's had knee surgery since then.
She could take Amanda down.
I think she can take cat cat cats in
Ghana had a real hard first round and
the first round Amanda Nunez is beaten
the shit out of her cat Nunez.
[inaudible]
Nunez.
Cat Cat came back and stop new needs.
That's either I got her on the back for
a cardio.
If,
if Rhonda,
again,
it's tough because what makes Rhonda
great is there's this flurry,
there's the exchange.
Next thing you know you're f she fucking
hip toss you and you're an armbar.
Right.
And that's the thing.
She's not really going to sit on
outside.
Be patient.
That's not her.
But if she can like if it's a dog fight,
I think Rhonda,
I ended up catching a fourth or fifth
round cause Amanda,
she starts off like a tidal wave and
we've seen it in her losses.
She kind of slows down.
She just does.
Yeah.
Well it's going to be interesting to see
if American top team has been able to do
something to mitigate that.
If they've,
who knows what kind of strength
conditioning program she's under now.
The only problem,
I see it quite as quick.
If Rhonda takes her down and ends up on
top,
she might have a hard time passing
Amanda Nunez Guard and we'll see.
Like Rhonda is not,
she's not known for guard passing,
so that could be a problem.
Maybe she'd shake Craig scrambles Eddie.
That's her thing,
but it's a letter to him to get up.
If she can get her on her back,
how will she,
she deal with passing the guard.
She really doesn't.
She goes to it and then she's going to
transition from there.
You got to deal with it.
With a black belt in Jujitsu,
you're going to have to deal with the
guard pass.
It's nine to really does submit anybody.
It's not a fee.
Rhonda could get on top of her that
well.
She is a black male shape.
She submitted me.
She tape.
She's a black belt in Jujitsu and a
chair after mcmahon too.
She battered both of them and submit
both their asses and then different
submission that she submits.
Her Mcmahon.
She submitted a cat.
Definitely have submitted Misha.
I got beat her up.
No,
not cat.
I'm sorry.
She submitted me Hsa.
She submitted Nisha,
that whole thing.
She did the same thing to Sarah McMahon.
I think she cracked her and then and
then put her away with a choke.
The one pretty sure the one thing she
has over Rhonda in this fight,
it's power.
She has vicious power.
Striking.
And I say that's it.
I'd say that if Rhonda does come at her
full clip like that,
it's a very risky proposition.
She can crack so fucking hard.
But if Rhonda feels like she can get
closer to that,
here we go.
He's not shocking,
man.
Punch.
Right?
She's not scary.
Oh yeah.
No,
she's talking about Amanda.
Amanda Nunez.
So she's working girls.
Only one shot.
She's dropping them.
And Shanna Blazer.
No,
she's marking girls.
Yeah,
she needed,
Amanda does clench a punch as hard as
any fucking woman in that division.
She might be the hardest women puncher
in the 135 she's the hardest one.
And punched her outside of Cyborg.
We'll sidewalks.
Not One 35 just saying females in
general.
She's the hardest punch outs.
Sideboards of difference.
You want to see her fight.
Watch this in my mind.
Stays the same.
Do you see the fight with me?
I agree.
Did you see her fight with me Sha Amanda
Nunez?
Nisha?
I,
yes,
but I forgot all about,
uh,
Amanda knew this.
Stopping Misha.
She beat her up.
She wanted to know.
Okay.
What about the Sarah McMahon fight?
I don't know.
200 go before that.
Because before that is when she was beat
her up on the feet.
Yeah,
I was there.
She's got a nasty jab to match.
He steps in.
I'm going to distance to boom,
boom.
Good scramble.
The question is like,
is she going to,
there's a big difference between dealing
with Rhonda and dealing with Misha.
Look,
this is a mauling man.
She beat the brakes off of her.
Amanda.
It's just putting it to me.
Should tape and you just,
she just has long ass punches too and
then she gets her back.
This size sounds out,
if Rhonda is in the right frame of mind,
I think she does Russia and like she
usually does,
probably eats a shot,
but then she gets inside,
gets thrown under hook,
takes her for a ride and submits in the
first round.
God,
I hope nobody tests positive for
anything to so many people to in pop.
How about sideboard?
Yeah,
yeah.
Game.
Oh No,
no matter what.
It's for game fucking over men.
Now everyone's goes told Ya fucking told
Ya.
I just borrow.
No.
Lactone is what they're saying it is.
So Berona lactones a dht inhibitor,
which is a derivative of testosterone.
Dihydrotestosterone I used to rub that
shit on my head.
Excuse me.
I was trying to keep my hair from
falling out because of testosterone.
Yeah,
yeah.
If you have the gene for it,
dihydrotestosterone is what?
Both of you beautiful heads of hair.
Don't have that as my,
come on dude,
come on.
My hair is falling out like it's fine.
No,
almost 50.
His hair's beautiful.
Thanks man.
Thank you.
[inaudible] dead.
[inaudible] dead wasteland.
When I was a kid or when I was in my,
um,
I guess I was probably in my twenties,
I would,
uh,
rub this spirono lock Tane on my fucking
scalp because it's a dht inhibitor and
it inhibits dht.
So when people take steroids or a woman
takes steroids or a man who has that
gene where the hair falls out,
and if a man has that gene and he takes
steroids is probably even worse.
But if you rub that spironolactone on,
it has a dht inhibiting effect.
And I think if you take it orally,
it also,
um,
it acts as a diuretic.
And,
um,
there's also,
uh,
some uses as a masking agent.
There's a whole bunch of different uses
of this,
like as a diuretic.
It also has benefits as a masking agent
and it also mitigates the effects of,
uh,
of taking steroids in females.
So there's a lot of stuff going on,
red flags with that stuff.
But the one on her side that she says it
is,
is that it's a,
it's used as a diuretic,
which appears to be true.
That'd be great.
She has a rise in and fights Gabi Garcia
think about that.
But what she said,
she had some issues with their friends
and their friends.
She had some pet issues with birth
control pills and then she was bloated
because of birth control pills.
So a doctor prescribed this to her off
season,
which is to try to deal with a look.
I don't know,
I ain't never cut that kind of weight
before.
But if you watch that outside the lines
piece on her,
uh,
with the weight cutting,
have you ever seen it?
I've seen it in and it's horrific.
Commissioner was like,
I would never approve her to fight like
sheet.
That's terrific.
How she's fighting at one three,
five should be illegal.
Well,
one 40 she never got 20 to 35 40 even
when 40 you got to watch it,
Eddie.
It's,
it's insane.
Terrifying.
It's insane.
She's the way she should be able to do
that around the fight and that's why
she's saying she turned down those two
title fights because I was given a shit.
I'm like,
who turns down title fights?
Even though they made the division for,
she's saying,
I destroyed my body.
I'm having depression.
I'm having a horrible issues.
My Body's just not ready to fight like I
need to march.
Well,
when you talk to people,
we talked to people that have caught
like ridiculous amounts of weight like
that,
and then all of a sudden the body just
goes,
which just if something goes wrong and
your body doesn't want to lose any
weight anymore,
your kidneys start aching.
You get kidney stones.
It could be some serious side effects.
Cutting back highway two goats.
Shit,
man,
it's so dangerous.
You're,
you're literally getting to the door of
death 24 hours before you enter into a
cage fight.
It's the craziest thing that we allow
people to do an MMA and it's essentially
in a lot of ways it's sanctioned,
cheating,
true sanction,
cheating.
He's trying to get out of them classes
and then you've got to have a way to
enforce them.
What's,
what's your,
what's your idea?
I think there's gotta be a way to get
guys to fight people that are their size
without having the same rigid wait
structure where you have like one 55 and
one 70 and one 85 any solutions?
No,
I don't.
I think there's gotta be a way to check
hydration levels and camp and there's
gotta be a way you're going to have to
blow the whole thing up though.
Like champions won't be the champions in
the same way class anymore.
But if you've got Chris Weidman to fight
at his natural weight and another guy to
fight at his you and how you determine
that,
you would have to find out what a guy
ways when he's in shape and fit.
And you would have to do this whole
transition over a period of time.
When that went along,
comes in,
that's when they're going to cut.
No,
you don't allow,
you don't allow him to,
there would also be like 20 belts.
I'm in good shape.
But you do the same thing that you do
with Usada.
You'd randomly test their hydration
levels.
You randomly test their weight.
So if they're healthy and they're in
camp,
there's no way they're gonna keep that
weight off the entire camp.
It's impossible,
but you can't.
As long as it's close.
It's like when cowboy cuts five pounds,
that's normal.
Like when you see cowboy,
you don't go,
you don't go.
There's no way.
This dude is one 70 you look at him,
you go,
yeah,
he looks like he's one seven.
That's his real weight.
When you look at Damien Maia,
you like,
there's no fucking way he's won 70 he's
200 pounds.
When you look at like rick story,
he's giant that like there's,
there's some guys that cut the weight
and then put it back on in a big way.
Johnny Hendricks in his prime.
Johnny Hendricks says prime would be
Jack modified when he was Merkin,
John Fitch and Marvin Capelin and those
guys.
So random wayins random.
So for sure they're not going to be
cutting the exactly what?
No,
they couldn't.
And then whatever you weigh in at they,
they let you cut five pounds of you need
to or something like that.
Something along those lines.
You give a person like a five pound
buffer.
Yeah,
it's super messy.
But yeah,
it does get messy.
But you also,
I think you,
you,
you causing part of the problem with
Wayans by having these very specific
weight classes,
like one 55 one 70 so then the problem
would be determining who is a champion
and what do you call that champion?
You have a Builtin area because you know
you,
you'd say welterweight or middleweight
or light heavyweight.
Well you're not saying is the 155 pound
champ.
The names are kind of silly.
Like why is welterweight one 70 and MMA
but one 47 and boxing heavyweight boxing
has been around forever.
Why do we have different names or
different weight classes for the same
sport?
But it doesn't matter.
It's still everybody knows what a
lightheaded off that.
Yeah,
it's still crazy.
My point is instead have like
lightweight middleweight have all these
different names but have people actually
way that like for a guy who's won 70
have an actual hundred 70 pound man,
that's some crazy dude who gets to two
like like rumble Johnson is just too,
how about this?
How about that?
That would work,
but how hard would it be in the,
you know,
the random testing and all that shit and
then the five pounds,
one of the guys,
six pounds.
What you could do is that the two,
the 48 hours before the weigh in,
you're under control.
You have,
you have to have like you're in a hotel.
Oh really?
You can't do any extreme weight cutting?
No.
Weird back check in on Tuesday.
I don't again,
Burt's gone to the commission on,
on what the fuck to do now,
but they used to do as soon as you land,
you don't check anything.
You go to the room and they weigh you
and if you're like 40 pounds,
40 pounds over there,
you know they're on your man.
Yeah.
It makes sense.
Yeah,
that's it makes sense.
That's it.
Yeah.
You'd have to do enough to where you all
the time and when they're all,
yeah,
they're all over it and you're weighing
in every day.
If you're red flag,
then they'll tell Dana,
hey,
bad,
good example guys.
But they don't,
they don't because the guy still miss
cause like,
Hey Kelvin's 30 pounds over weight and
like,
all right,
well he's made it before.
Yeah.
You can't still can't have that,
which you got to have is someone who
doesn't allow anybody to fight 30 pounds
over what they actually weigh in that
it's not legal like Weidman cut,
I want to say 37 pounds and three day
Yoda.
Yeah.
When he fought Leo Machida,
there's gotta be an official way in a
few times.
Yeah.
Like they all got to throw your shit out
camp.
They do that in Abu Dhabi because it's a
two day tournament and you got to wait
if you make it to the Sunday,
if you went a couple of matches and you
get it to the semifinals and finals,
you got to weigh in again.
Who did send fight when he cut all that
way it was it Damien Maia?
No,
it wasn't a,
it was in Abu Dhabi and he's cutting
weight on the plane.
Remind hose and I would dobby so he did.
Was it,
who did he fight?
He fight [inaudible] no,
it wasn't.
No,
it wasn't [inaudible] it was in Abu
Dhabi.
I remember I thought he,
he was Damien Maia Boyz days and that
was on Fox wasn't it?
I find it uh,
two immunos on that card.
So was that Abu Dhabi when Bj Penn
fought Frankie Edgar?
It must've been cause the other Aboud
Dobby card was when Anderson fought
Damien Maia.
Right.
Those are the two that I went to.
I don't think if the Fox card,
no,
you might.
I think you're right.
What do you think about the new rules
that a big John McCarthy?
Do you see that video?
No,
no,
no.
You replay.
I didn't watch it.
He didn't watch your MMA encyclopedia.
How could you not watch the new unified
rules?
The Big John McCarthy posted,
you watched it,
right?
Yeah,
it was Damien Maia basically bought a
stand up fight against Damien Maia and
it was on Fox.
It was the second card on Fox and he cut
short amount of weight in a law or a
law.
A lot of weight in a short amount of 22
pounds in 10 days.
Insane.
Like she too shy like you do.
You get to death's door and then he's so
it tough.
Yeah.
You can't do that.
I still want,
you know when fighters are against the
cage and they put their hand on the mat
so they don't get kneed in the face.
Can't do that no more.
That's all.
You gotta have all four,
uh,
you have have both hands?
No,
they haven't had that starfish in 2017.
Yeah,
it's a great rule.
Hell yeah.
It's a little,
I mean,
did they,
did they talk about I or anything like
that?
I don't think so.
They did talk about a clavicle grabs
grabbing the collar.
That used to be illegal.
You could do that.
I remember hearing the guy say that he
could do that.
Oh,
just so many in the collarbone.
Please do try that.
Please do.
Please try to like,
I just kicked him in the knee.
The column on those,
the dumbest like you really think it's
that easy.
Yeah.
Just going to get someone on their
collar bone,
I think collapses,
right?
Yeah.
Dudes,
they think they could just kick you in
the knee and then they're going to have
like a mobile icu.
To your way point.
A guy who could really benefit from that
as Chris Weidman,
he met light heavyweight.
He should be a light heavyweight,
I feel like.
Yeah,
for sure.
Well,
Jon Jones should be a heavyweight then
you know,
John Jones fought Dan Henderson that
grappling match.
He was 238 pounds.
I mean he murked cheeses,
so wheezes.
What a beautiful takedown.
She's takedown.
Yup.
Oh my God,
I love it.
He shot in and Gary,
Tony and hit that very same takedown but
unsuccessfully on his opponent.
Kim.
Yeah.
And grappling match right after that I
think is going to go to light
heavyweight.
John is so big for light heavyweight
man.
He's so fucking physically talented too.
What is it?
It's a,
it's a fake single and then you kind of
like duck under the clinch.
Yup.
Is that what that was?
And the way John did it was just,
it was so glorious.
We watch how quickly he covered ground.
You realize like how fucking talented he
is.
I don't even think it's up on the
Internet either.
I think it is.
You can watch it and go watch.
You could watch the uh,
the take down and you can watch the
finish.
I don't think you watched the whole
fight and now are they going to do John
Verse jail now because John got on the
mic.
I was like,
yeah,
I want to fight you chill.
And I think they are going to probably
do something like a tail will go in
there and get smooshed for the hx.
John is just too big and too good.
He's so talented,
man.
He's winning Jujitsu tournaments like as
a goof.
He stepping into them and and grapple
with people and strangling.
Go with like a gary tone tonin with
they'll re,
yeah.
Let me tell you something man.
What John said when he was on my podcast
goes,
I fell in love with Jujitsu because I'm
obsessed with it.
He goes,
I'm training all the time.
no,
I'm not going to be standing in front of
people trade anymore.
He goes,
fuck that.
He's like,
I wouldn't be taking people down,
choking the shit out of him.
He said,
yeah,
yeah.
It was hilarious.
It was like just he,
he's so talented as a grappler,
you can do whatever you like.
It's on some other planet.
It was a nice pass to,
he took them down and then it was a nice
pass.
That arm triangle was John Jones might
be pulling guard on people,
an arm bar.
He Guardian Daniel,
come on Daniel after he was beaten him
up,
but he,
he might be pulling guard on people,
an arm bar on him in the future.
He's also a guy who,
who could do and even to a bay level,
beat the light heavyweight champion
heavyweight champ.
And he could do that.
You can get so much more notoriety than
connor could it like dobby absolute as
well.
Maybe he might do we look Humana?
There's,
you occasionally get a guy that's just
so incredibly talented.
You Go,
well,
it's really all about focus.
It's about foot.
Like if you watch him,
watch him,
you've seen it.
The Dan Henderson match.
But Dan Henderson's totally undersize is
not,
they're not nearly in the same way
class,
but it's really not going all out.
He was busy,
but it's effortless.
I mean,
you,
you watch how he does,
he like,
what do you mean Dan Henderson was going
light?
I just think Dan was nice match.
It was competition.
Watch this here.
Here it goes.
Because this is a suspended UFC fighter.
Jon Jones,
what does it say?
Fought Dan Henderson at underground
event and uh,
John started off on his knees and just
crawled forward and he see Dan like
putting his hand on his head and John
[inaudible] John is like,
he's like unstoppable.
The waste closing in on so strong.
He's,
what I'm saying is like the ways moving
in on them,
it's almost like unavoidable.
It's like this is going to be a mauling,
you know this is not going to be like
what he did with jail sign and when he
grabbed shale and took them down and
just slammed on the ground.
So their size and compete with John.
Like look at the guys that have given
him issues like Gustafson,
he says same size.
Those are the only time he really has
issued.
He toward gave him some issues.
[inaudible] hard bar I think got dealt
with.
He submitted veto us.
He did.
Yes he did.
But when Vito caught him in that arm
bar,
that was like really the first time we'd
seen him ever in trouble inside the ox
human they think,
yeah,
I'll get out of here.
This is mostly John just pushing them up
against the cage and they let him go.
Oh,
he threw a jab at him.
What the fuck is that about?
We didn't really throw a jab like he
pretended he was going to do a spinning
elbow.
Oh,
he's just clowning around.
I think rockhold wants to do it to Jon
Jones was rockhold.
That's right.
Rockhold did say that.
Let's see the tape.
Well how long did the match go?
I don't remember,
but it did take down was the ridiculous
thing.
I'll see if you could find that in
there.
See now this is worth it,
Eddie,
just to make money
cause you're not no head trauma if you
lose it's whatever.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
This is a totally different thing.
I really wished that this pay,
there it is.
Woo Boom,
gets him down and riding side control.
I really wished that this was a viable
option in terms of like financial
success.
I really wished that there was a a way,
I think,
I think your event has the best chance
of doing it.
I really do.
I think if your event,
when people watch it and get behind it
has a real possibility because it's
fucking exciting as shit and people will
pay money to see it.
Especially when line at Vegas.
Caliber of these guys are doing and
flying to Vegas tomorrow,
meeting with a UFC fight pass.
They want to,
they got great numbers.
Ebi 10 they said the numbers were
staggering and they want us to get
behind and go crazy.
It's the
best thing about Eddie.
Look at this.
This is totally possible.
You could be the Don King of chokes.
Oh look at this.
Let me get this top fucking jokes.
Look at this.
Just you and Eddie.
You were saying that you are,
oftentimes we'll stay in the mountain
that you don't three quarter mount
butter amount.
You stayed.
Do you ever say in full amount?
Full amount to only because the rise of
leg lockers,
deadly leg,
leg,
leg lockers that hit a leg lock
transition when they're mounted,
so if you let them get their hips up.
I always stay in three core.
I don't even,
the only time I'm doing a full amount is
if I'm in sky dive,
if I got my hips down and my ankles
crossed and then I'm hunting for an
under hook,
but I'll never just sit there and
regular amount because everybody now
has,
has got that mount escape to leg locks
that you got.
It could just turn everything around.
It could be over.
So Sean,
the hips and get soaked.
Also those ridiculously flexible guys
that get those legs and play like
Eddie's dexterity,
your dexterity.
It's always been my main escape too is
using my flexibility when someone mounts
it.
Right.
And that takes me into leg locks and at
that used to be the only he'll hook.
I had in my game was off being mounted
and then I would use a hail Mary escape,
see cups in the armpits,
cross my feet in front of her stomach,
over hook a leg and then take them right
to just good old fashion outside.
He'll hook that.
Uh,
that was my number one escape and that's
just too dangerous now,
not now.
Guys have taken that escape and added a
thousand more leg lock transitions off
it and at that I actually had a guy come
to my gym maybe four or five years ago
for a purple belt from Hen Zos and he
was super flex by walk onto the Mat and
he sitting there walking to class,
he's got both legs behind his head.
I don't know who this guy is.
He said,
he said,
Oh,
I'm at,
so I'm like,
how you doing?
He's just like looking at me.
He just wanted,
he wanted to show me how flexible,
it was way more flexible than I am,
way more.
I can't cross my feet behind my head and
we rolled and I mounted him quite
easily,
but I didn't know it was a trick.
He let me mount them and then its
flexibility and I was low,
I was super low,
but he would grab his feet and just put
it in the little crack and inch by inch
you with a stick his foot in B,
I'm laying flat on him and then he would
get through,
boom,
right into a leg lock and he tapped me.
I'm like,
Holy Shit.
So we went again and I mounted him
again.
I said,
I shared amount of them.
You know,
there's some guys like you just don't
fucking mouth these guys.
You take him to the truck.
So I mounted him and I was super tight,
just clinching time and he just grabbed
his foot and just put it right there.
Just would hold it right in the,
in between our rib cages and he couldn't
get in initially,
but inch pan she would just get,
he would just pull this flynn,
it was like he was jail breaking,
uh,
to that mount escape.
Wow.
That's just crazy.
You got tapped me again and I thought
from that point on I go,
hmm,
I can ever,
uh,
I can't,
I always got to make sure that I roll
with people and assume everyone can do
that,
doesn't and have that kind of ridiculous
flexibility,
dexterity.
You gotta assume everyone's that
good.
So at that point,
it altered my mouth a lot.
Like with the arm triangles,
I just stay in the mount.
So you just assume you have to assume
that everybody's at the death level.
That why not?
Because if it works on them that it
works on everybody.
To me up with it.
What was crazy when Eddie and I were
doing that on an invitational thing,
they were telling us that there's like
14 year olds mto tour homeschooled just
to be dedicated to Jujitsu.
No,
those nine year old real,
those nine year olds.
I was like,
what the fuck is going on?
Yeah.
Two nine year olds doing ankle locks.
Fucking all your shit.
You know what we were talking before the
podcast started,
we were talking about physical freaks
like that big gorilla Shane car.
When and how when,
uh,
I watched Jane Carlin role with people.
It's like,
what is the point of this?
This is preposterous.
Shankar Shankar.
We walked into a mall Easton's Jujitsu
gym and I didn't know who he was for a
second.
I'm obviously,
I knew who he was.
I'd commentated his fights,
but for a second I looked up from the
mat and I saw him walk in and my tests
on a person that's a gorilla.
That's some shaved shuttle out from the
ECZEMA.
Yeah.
It doesn't even look like a real human
and he would roll with people and it
would be preposterous.
It's a waste of your time.
I remember I trained because Jane would
have had another job and he'd have an
injury.
So you'd gone for like four months,
not train Jujitsu twice a day.
So,
so I'm,
I can't wait cause he's like a big
brother and I can't wait till I get to
know more role this full up.
He would come in off his nine to five,
set his lunchbox down,
put on his fucking weird shit.
Basketball shorts,
baggy tee shirt.
I'm like,
you've been rolling.
yeah man,
let's go and you just fucking destroy
me.
I'm like,
dude,
why don't you do more Jitsu?
Like why I can,
I'm just fucking gorilla.
Strongest as strong.
But wouldn't you love to see a guy like
him fall in love with it?
And then when the Monday owls,
like how crazy would that be?
How crazy would it be to watch Shane car
when,
when Abu Dhabi with his wrestling
background,
if he won,
if he dedicated,
dedicated himself to submissions,
like just pure submissions.
Like what a freak athlete is.
Months and choke,
you know,
cause he's bigger than months and he
would pop your head off.
It took out it,
you know what the problem is though,
man.
He's got just that PR posture,
his punching power and he's like,
why would I not have my best thing?
Yeah.
Like his punching power was just
ridiculous.
It's too much work.
Why don't I just jam that guy in the
face and attending nef dog.
I mean it's gotta be,
it's gotta feel way better to knock
someone out to drop someone than to tap
him out.
Go into Shane Carwyn Kaos Frank Mir,
cause that was one of the darkest one
frank mirs corner.
They're gone.
A chill frank rounds almost over.
Just chill and it pishing off.
He looks at the corner and it just
fucking ends.
Frank made it right there.
That's what he does.
His is going,
you're good,
fine frank.
Just let him get the under hook.
Don't give him head control.
You're just chill.
It's almost the end.
The round.
Then shame.
It's like,
what are you talking about?
I can knock the dude up.
I need this much space.
Yeah.
Douche came over.
They were ridiculous.
Uppercuts,
just horrific dishes that he's,
he's an interesting example of mayor
wants to do Ebi.
I know he does.
Yeah,
it's great idea.
He'd be like,
he's an awesome,
awesome as mission Fabi Silver Dome as
well.
Wants to do combat Jujitsu,
the combat Jujitsu version of Eba,
which is going to be the next show.
Ebi Eleven's gonna have a regular 16
man,
uh,
regular Ebi rules,
welter weights,
and within it a four man combat duty in
March.
We nailed down the date tomorrow.
Let me know when it comes up.
There's going to be Jujitsu,
Jujitsu with pumps,
right.
Would come and I would go to it and
catch it with you.
No,
no,
no.
Slap.
He moved,
but not slap the slap part.
But you know,
if you've ever thought about competing
in Jiu Jitsu part,
uh,
he's been too busy with podcast.
I'm too busy with podcast shows and
stuff.
Comedy,
you know,
family gun standups hard enough.
You know like it's so challenging man.
I appreciate that.
But you know when you did have that
grappling match and metamorris a Cyborg
and everybody got mad at you and you
understand why everybody got mad at you
[inaudible] percent,
you'd be even more mad if you know how
much money I meant you did engage him.
He did engage him and engage him on the
ground.
You gave Cyborg chances and he couldn't
do shit with you.
And I watched it.
I was like,
wow,
like I understand you being cautious
because you have to fight in the UFC and
you didn't want to get your legs torn
up.
Cause cyborgs.
That tornado guard is and he's a
ridiculously strong dude.
Ridiculous.
He's a bad motherfucker.
I mean Cyborg is a killer.
And but you did,
you did an all Phi as a tax.
I mean I understand that you went pretty
straight defense but it did work.
You know,
it's interesting cause he,
he was engaging with you.
You work locked up with him in the
garden.
He wasn't able to do anything with you.
I was like,
hmm,
I wonder how you would do if you like
really dedicated yourself like an
competed in some sort of an event.
Like you want the truth.
I just don't care.
That's all you need to say.
Too busy with other things like that.
That part,
that part of my life,
like I love watching this thing and I
love commentating on it,
but to dead cause you really got to
dedicate to keep it.
You know how it is.
You really got to dedicate and be all
in.
Like all Cyborg is doing is shooting
Jujitsu seminars and videos and rolling
every day when you just don't care when
you put metreon and asleep.
I remember thinking like,
who's got a fucking serious doris?
Like you have a serious Doris when you
clamp that thing out on a mitre.
And I was like,
Ooh,
ow,
this is,
and then he was out and I was like,
that's a serious fucking darce choke.
Yeah.
That was my shit,
man.
I love,
I love Jujitsu,
but it's just,
yeah,
it's not,
and I'm not in that lane anymore.
It's not like the,
there's not big money in submission only
or I should be fun.
Maybe you know,
for the winter,
the winter has pretty good money.
I mean Gary Turner is made thousands and
thousands of dollars and Eddie Cummings
and the $100,000
this year.
They're making money if you win.
But um,
overall,
you know,
you,
um,
there's right now there's no money for
it,
but still still the guys that are in it,
the guys at the top there training fool
on the fucking all the time.
I feel like your event,
has it changed your,
your event has
the,
the possibility to change that.
I really do.
You've got the event.
I really did it.
Hopefully,
you know,
Ebi 10 was pretty fucking Damn Chris.
So crazy to watch man.
And you got little girls competing,
which is amazing to watch girls that are
like,
how old are the youngest girls?
You there?
The UFC didn't want to have any of that
anymore.
So really I'm no more minors,
no more,
no more.
Uh,
under age two,
man,
was that because of the girl that got,
he'll hooked in her leg,
possibly soul snaps.
Rob Her heel.
The snap.
Yeah,
I remember that.
Yeah.
She had her acl blowout.
I love children do Jujitsu.
F that's the cutest shit.
It's more to my glove.
It shows you where the sports APP
conundrum.
Come on.
Grace got drunk.
She is really amazing.
Who's Oak?
What's her name?
Cora Hora sac.
Have you seen this Korean girl?
She had the big old check.
Why isn't it possible to maybe have a
youth version of the same thing and to
have like just call it something else
and don't do it on bypass?
That is possible.
It seems like there might be an option
to do other stuff as well.
I mean,
unless you have some sort of exclusive
thing,
which I don't want to grow it.
I,
I really liked that pop one.
Or do you want to give kids the chance
to compete?
He had people loved watching grace.
People loved it.
That was my favorite.
She got bigger roars than anybody.
Oh yeah man.
Tremendous roars.
People fucking love watching grace.
But you know,
there's other shows she just,
she's going to do,
um,
show the arc finishers,
which is a sub only show Ebi rules on
the East Coast.
She's going to do that and she's got a
big fight.
It's like a super fight coming up.
Cora just fought in the honored and the
table.
So there's these other,
uh,
submission only tournaments out there
using ebi rules when they have a
platform.
And,
you know,
the UFC did,
I didn't even want to fight them on it,
you know,
they like,
okay,
no minors,
no big deal,
you know,
uh,
eventually we'll,
we'll see the return of grace
eventually,
eventually can imagine,
you know,
three or four years later and when she's
18 and we bring her back and that's
going to be crazy.
It's going to be like the guns and roses
were union.
Yeah.
Jujitsu.
Interesting.
It's just interesting to see it because
I think it's a,
it's the safer alternative for the
athletes,
especially athletes.
They really just want to develop the Jiu
Jitsu skills.
You can get immersed in Jujitsu.
They don't want to have to,
in order to be a professional,
have to compete as an MMA fighter.
Yeah.
Well,
competition is so high at Uga in
Jujitsu,
right?
Oh yeah.
And so far,
every Jujitsu event has failed.
They've all failed.
All of them.
Uh,
and Ebi,
you know,
we're not out of the woods.
There's no big giant pile of money.
No one's making money except for the
winters.
You know,
we're just,
it's a passion project.
100%.
And who knows,
maybe we don't survive.
But apparently we got really good
reviews at the UFC fight pass for Ebi
10,
which you could still watch right now.
You watch the replay was amazing.
I watch and Geo Martinez and Eddie
Cummings go out at that.
That was one of the most epic Jujitsu
matches of all time.
If you guys don't survive,
everyone's fun,
everyone's fine.
We're going to try it.
You know,
we're going to do our best.
Yeah.
You Guy know you'd being humble and
everything like that,
but,
and I don't,
I,
you just never know.
No,
no events have made it so far.
that's the main,
any markers.
The rule sucked ass.
Go back to the card.
Good.
See if [inaudible] is there any fights
that we missed on this UFC card?
I don't know how there's all these
ready.
Don't worry about that.
No,
no,
no.
You've got the perfect rule set.
Let's go back to this just to see if
there's anything else that Hendrix,
oh,
that's right.
That's right.
That's what I wanted to talk about,
dude.
You know,
you got to wonder where Johnny Hendricks
head is at.
When you heard the way he trained for
his last fight.
You know,
he was saying that he was the only
training like a few days a week and it
wasn't really that steak house.
It wasn't really trained in every day
and that his wife really got them geared
up to,
to train for this fight.
But the problem with that is like Neil
Magnese's,
I don't fucking roll man.
I mean,
he's had some tough fights and some good
fights and he beat hector mother fucking
Lombard by stoppage,
you know?
That's right.
He'd be any beat Kelvin.
And he beat Lombard when Lombard was
putting it to them in the first round
was really close fights where it was
like,
man,
this might get stopped.
And Damien Maia eight his ass for lunch.
Like coby has issued the way Damien Maia
put that smushed down on him.
I was like,
whilst a bad matchup stud,
next level Jujitsu batch,
Damien Monster,
this thing.
Very interesting.
First of all,
you got to get a hold of Woodley.
Second of all,
you've got to get him to the ground.
Good luck with both of those things.
Yeah,
good luck.
Both of those fucking hammered into
another dementia.
It's a fun,
fun,
fun to Whitley and Woodley's showed him
that wonderboy fight that he can hammer
you went to a dimension in the fourth
round,
correct.
He could still like deep into the
fucking championship rounds,
can still hammering you out of this
fucking zone flag for money.
We'll tell you what Jujitsu might make
Woodley a little cautious.
100 [inaudible] probably not gonna throw
any leg kicks or anything,
but try to knock his ass out,
but we don't.
You think that Woodley's wrestling and
his physical size and strength and he's
taking Breslin bubbly,
strong [inaudible] no taken down
restaurant.
The rest of the juicy when Damien Maia
took down chill Sonin people forget that
it the man with the inverted triangle,
the mount that lateral dropped double
over Hook laterals dropped him.
Yeah.
It's vintage Damien mind.
He got ahold of them and uh,
those is frank Mir versus car went.
This is horrific.
No.
Oh,
okay.
Don't worry about it.
That game.
Yeah.
It's probably only on fight pass.
If you go to UFC fight pass and we have
a account or is it just my account?
Is it on?
Yeah,
we don't have to see it.
But anyway,
it was a Merch gigging marketing.
What we were talking about the
difference between a guy who's like a
super tactical,
really high level guy and then there's a
point of diminishing returns where it
doesn't work on somebody and that's the
point of shame.
Carwyn like you should like,
like almost like,
there's like a physical limit of almost
all technique that you hit a wall when
someone gets just so stupid strong that
they can,
as long
as he's skilled and he is skilled on top
of that,
he's aware of what's going on.
He's like a Rashad Evans blackbelt like
Rashad,
it's not going to submit you off his
back.
But his knowledge and his defense is
insane.
There's just different,
you know,
like he doesn't have what's going on
with Rashad.
Like what happened after that?
Tim Kennedy fight,
they pulled them out of the Tim Kennedy
fight.
They pulled him out and then he was
supposed to fight again.
Right.
Pull them out again.
I don't know.
He tried to fight Kennedy again,
but this time in Toronto and Toronto
pulled them out too.
I know.
So New York City pulled them out and
then Toronto pulled them out and uh,
he says it's a preexisting condition.
He said he's something he's always had,
but who knows,
man,
I don't want to hear that.
What do you think about that Kevin?
Gasol them fight Jesus.
Right.
Okay.
No,
no,
no.
But against a Tim Kennedy,
first of all.
Oh yeah.
That's another example of a guy who
wasn't cutting any weight and look
fucking amazing.
But then he wants to go back and talk to
your boy.
Why is you want to go back down to 70
because those guys have to cut weight.
Those guys are cutting weight and
getting down to one 85 and they're
gigantic guys like Hector Lombard and he
doesn't want to have to fight one of
those guys.
Okay,
but you gotta make weight a seventies I
understand what you're saying.
And I think there's a middle ground
there.
I think seven days to harvest made one
70 many times.
It's missed it the last time.
But this last time he says he was on the
new dieticians a regimen and it didn't
work out.
Didn't work out.
You have dolce originally?
Yes,
I think so.
Did you just not want to pay the money?
I don't know exactly what went down
between that.
He's just gotta be personally more
disciplined if he's just personally more
discipline with his dye.
It's on him.
Yeah.
It doesn't matter.
The dietitian,
you know,
especially him cutting weight and how
he's been doing for so long,
you know,
commodity.
Let me ask you this.
The fucking handle moves and shit make,
he'll accept 85,
I think one.
That's what I'm saying.
I think he's fine there,
but he's fighting veit doorbell.
Four nights that he's going to buy.
You Tore Belford 85.
Yo Dude,
that's a,
that's a rumble.
Yeah,
it seems Brazil.
Oh,
what does that mean exactly?
What are you trying to start his coach?
You don't know.
What does that mean?
You throw in Brazil is a different
animal for sure.
Why isn't there no,
you cited there.
What are you trying to say?
What are you trying to save?
Show,
say anything.
What I'm saying?
There's something that I say he down
there.
This is the last chance for romance for
Vituro too.
It's a great,
it's the perfect fight for Canelo saucy,
perfect fight name.
Put the mits to him.
Musashi,
put them into v Tour and I think Kelvin
is a better mover then Musashi Musashi
has more weapons,
like loose aussies are way better
kicker.
Uh,
but what Calvin does,
man with his footwork and that like real
light on his feet,
moving in with that Right Man Jab Rafael
Cordeiro has got,
I mean his,
his,
his striking look,
super professional,
so good and,
and ridiculous combinations and speed
and fluidity.
That's what keeps going forward.
Keeps going,
keeps going forward.
So game,
gas,
shame game.
It's gas tanks retarded.
It's just so good.
He's so strong.
Fear Zero fear,
Great Chin.
Who's demeanors and saying yes and you
know,
was real comfortable when tim was
mauling him.
Like Tim got ahold of him early in that
first round and really
put out a lot of effort that seatbelt
got his back.
Really was mauling him with size and
power.
But Tim gas himself out doing that.
Tim Look terrible in that flight.
Did I love Tim more than anyone in this
world?
Tim,
what about me?
You love him more than me.
It's a tossup.
He'd be fighting for my freedom from my
fridge.
I'm still interesting.
But uh,
tim looked rough in that fight.
It was a terrible performance for him,
but him,
nobody fucking handled themselves better
after loss.
Then that guy,
what did he say?
Fucking owns up to it.
The guy kicked my ass.
He's a better fighter than me.
It was very embarrassing.
Picture him going to the hospital at
well that sucked.
Yeah.
Eyes face.
Totally jacked tip Kennedy took a
picture of herself jacked in the
hospital.
I think I s uh,
outlook on on losses,
losses or ou.
When you're in someone's corner and
you're dealing with someone,
man,
it's like,
it's hard.
It's hard to,
all you can say is like there's nothing
that says you can't win them all,
bro.
You got caught.
Anybody can get cut.
But there's a difference between like
what we were saying,
like a guy like Tim Kennedy took that
loss and like how hard Rhonda took her
loss to Holly Holm.
Yeah,
there's a,
you know,
a giant difference.
Complete opposite.
And that's the business of being a
fighter.
This game's easy when your merch in
everyone,
everyone's every media outlets telling
me how good you are.
Like yeah,
this is fucking great.
Then you take one on the chin,
you lose.
Most fighters come back and go,
all right,
I got merch.
But watch this fight.
You'll see what's up.
I'm a real fighter.
That's why tim or you eat Kelvin's had
his loss.
Is everyone that many.
Then Connor,
you know he came back,
he was already talking shit after that
fight.
He was like in a fuckhead.
I fucked up,
but I'll be back.
Took it like a man and didn't talk about
a staph infection.
By the way,
a lot of people,
when we found out about us sat staph
infection because of my fucking big
mouth,
but he had a staph infection two weeks
out of that first nate diaz fight.
He was taking antibiotics.
That's the word might be.
I don't think it's bullshit.
I haven't heard it directly from his
mouth,
but I heard it from a very reliable
sources.
Do you hear what his camp is doing?
What are they doing?
His coach is requiring every fight on
his team to have their brain scan.
Fuck yeah,
John Kavanagh.
Fuck yeah.
Right.
Powerful move.
Smart Guy,
man.
Fuck yeah.
This is a crazy sport.
You know,
and no one wants to tell people when
they can and can't do it,
but someone should be watching out for
them because that fucking same ego that
makes you want to be a champion can also
get you real confused as to when you are
physically compromised,
which brings us to the fight that was
pulled off this card,
Cain Velasquez versus fabrizio for doom.
The rematch,
which everybody was looking forward to
and a cane did that meeting with that,
uh,
that,
whatever that meant.
A association.
Yes.
The Fighters Association and said that
he's going to have to have a surgery
after this fight.
And they went,
what?
Why don't you step that he fucked up
you.
They like,
you can't say you need a surgery before
you have a major fight.
First of all,
that that's going to fuck with the
betting lines.
There's a disaster there that's going to
fuck with the insurance if something
happens to you.
And then afterwards they say,
Oh,
you know,
you,
you told us that you are already hurt.
We're not paying for this.
Like do you,
do you get paid?
Um,
for like when you're in training camp
and you get to a fight and you have to
pull out because the injury,
you don't get nothing.
Right?
What do you get?
Uh,
nothing.
Nothing.
So you've got nothing.
So if he chose to fight with that
injury,
he said he was gonna be 100%.
He's going to have a cortisone
injection.
And the doctors disagree.
The Nevada State Athletic Commission
disagreed that uh,
Bob Bennett Guy,
he doesn't fucking play any games,
man.
He's like,
you can't say something like that.
And then finally long to do that.
I fucked up.
He fucked up emotional when I called
Linacre a little monkey earlier.
I fucked up.
See came fucked up.
You just talk,
you say things,
you know,
I was going to say,
well that's kind of racist,
but I call myself a monkey though.
I just,
it sounds sounds worse than it really
is.
It's not racist.
It's not the last person racist.
But the point is with when it comes to
Cain is that it was a giant error and
that error pulled him off of this card
and now he's going to have to fight.
He's going to have to get surgery and
then he'd have to fight whoever the fuck
has left and it's,
you're talking about more months out and
then even more examination next time and
it's going to cost him a shit load of
money.
A ton of money went through the entire
camp.
He was a week out and they pull them
from it.
And then he was saying,
I don't know what this is about.
I'm,
I'm 100% good to go.
I've been told I've been cleared.
So he was tweeting that he had been told
that he was cleared right before they
pull them.
I thought,
you know,
I think you give the guy a physical
examination in terms of his movement.
Like what can you do?
Like,
how do you,
how do you tell a guy business wise,
business wise,
you can look in his bag back some since
I ask the as you can't cause the UFC
goes man,
you have a bulging disk,
you can of course on the shot and then
if you get punched in the face by doing
where he gets a guilty and you're
paralyzed,
you assumed the fuck out us cause we let
your true business,
you just can't do that.
No deny.
I don't think it falls on.
Kay came knows better.
The people around this association
shouldn't have let them do that.
Well first of all they should have known
about first the bjorn revenue thing is
very weird.
Like I was reading what John Fitch had
written that John Fitch rather than an
interview said that he was very
disturbed by all this because there's a
class action lawsuit.
And what they're saying is that if the
class action lawsuit is dropped like
that they could form this,
uh,
this union.
And if they all agreed to abandon the
class action lawsuit,
it would,
it would like help the strength and form
the union.
And John Fitch was like,
what?
Like,
so you're saying that the UFC would
accept you as a union if you abandoned
the class action lawsuit that we'd been
chasing down for two years now without
picking any sides.
Like if you're on the side of the
fighters,
not picking any sides,
you just have to look at that and go,
well what benefit would it be for the
people that are not in this to accept
that the class action lawsuit is
dropped?
This all sounds like someone's trying to
get some money because there's no one's
doing this for free.
That's what everybody has to realize
when it comes to like these agencies and
there's like three different competing
ones that are stepping in.
Right?
There's the associate,
the two big ones.
There's associations as the union.
Yeah.
Well ultimately I think we all want the
same
thing.
We all want fighters to be compensated
fairly.
Want them to make a lot of money because
it's a short window of time and it's an
awesome sport to watch.
Right?
Correct.
So you got wonder,
does this help that?
Does this help them?
Does it do any of these organizations?
They haven't yet because if they can't
even get together and organize and
they're going to fight right,
then no one's going to take you serious.
There's three different leaders,
three different ones,
and they all want different things.
And then you've got to wonder whose
agenda's over here?
Whose agenda's over here?
What it has to come.
It can't come from businessman,
can't come from another promoter.
How's it come from the fighters,
the fighters.
You know what I'm saying?
You know,
and I'm not saying current fighters
because they need to fight and then they
need to have someone speak for them
who's been there.
But you can't have these business guys
with other hidden agendas trying to get
things done.
Or,
or in a b,
orange case,
he has this weird jealousy with Dana and
let's see them destroyed.
Well,
we can't have that.
Why are you speaking for us?
What are you doing?
You don't have the respect of the
fighters.
What the fuck are you doing?
And notice he's taking a seat back
because everyone,
when everyone saw him speaking,
they were like,
we're out man.
Like he was going old school bell tour
when he was running things over there
and a King Mo was pissed off at him and
King Mo most of this day calls him a
Dick Rider all the time.
It's not good when you've got a guy like
king mo who's a very respected guy who
has horrible things to say about you.
And I talked to association.
I went,
what are you guys doing?
Like,
yeah,
you have one way to make an impression
and you do this.
You put your best foot forward with this
guy.
And they're like,
well,
I don't know the dude.
Do you know him?
I know of fighters who have dealt with
them.
I never thought for Bella tour.
So I know inside the fighter circle that
people have dealt with them for managing
and stuff like that.
But I him personally,
I was looking at all the tweets and all
the negative stuff.
I think you can take a very positive
angle about improving the life and the
conditions of these fighters without
attacking people.
Yeah,
there's no,
there's no reason to attack.
And it's also see what you want about
Dana White.
It's not his job to make sure you guys
get your shit together and formed the
association.
He's like,
I'm a businessman.
I put on fights.
If you guys want to do that,
cool.
Get your shit together and then bring it
and then let's figure something out.
But if you guys are fighting with each
other,
you don't even acknowledge,
you know what else is interesting about
this,
uh,
the $4 billion that you know,
is that they had to pay to buy the EOC
and there's a lot of debt.
I wonder how,
how do you,
I don't understand business.
I'm,
I'm a dummy.
I don't,
I don't have any business background,
but how much money do you have to make
to pay off $4 billion?
Like if you buy a house and your house
is like 3 million bucks,
like damn,
we like doing,
get some daunting 30 year payments.
Now imagine a thousand times that plus a
billion because that's what it is,
but thousand million billion is,
and that's why they're going and doing
these budget cuts saying,
how can we save money here and how can
we grow it?
So then you see all of a sudden you see
the women 140 pound division,
you're seeing these into 45,
one 45.
You've seen these interim belts.
You're seeing ways to,
you know,
make up the money.
Well,
that's a really sad thing about the
cyborg thing because cyborgs extremely
marketable at 145 pounds.
And they make the decision for her.
Yeah.
They made the division for her and not
just marketable,
but very controversial,
very controversial,
very.
I mean,
she's scary.
She,
she merck's women,
she goes after them and it takes them
down,
destroys him,
smashes people.
She's in her thirties.
I think she's 34,
35 cause she,
that'll I think so.
Pull up three 30 on June 32 31.
Okay,
I'm wrong.
Um,
so,
uh,
31,
it's in her prime,
you know,
in her prime and for her to be the
champion at one 45 this she could be,
she could,
the problem is she's going to be an
under even more screwed.
She's so fucking mad and there's never
been someone who fucking need to pass
the test so bad in their life than her
because the number one knock on her was
you've test pause before.
That's the only reason why you're
competing.
That's what you're knocking people out.
But fell off that train was like,
no,
she's so skilled.
She deserves it.
Put marketing dollars behind her.
They're like fine,
cool.
Here's your division.
Boom test positive but put,
put yourself in or is it possible that
she really did deal with some crazy
weight cutting backlash where her body's
just like fucked up and it's retaining
water in some weird way and our hormones
are all fucked up cause she got on the
birth control pill.
I believe that it's possible that a
doctor did prescribe her this to try to
mitigate that.
And then the doctor told her that you
could take this out of competition.
You can't take it into in competition
because it is a diuretic,
right?
Yeah.
So a diuretic,
if you are swollen and all those things
do seem to make sense.
I mean,
just trying to be done.
I don't wanna I don't wanna see any
skeptical hippo face.
I'm not,
I'm,
I'm with you on this July.
No,
I actually believe her story.
Have you seen skeptical snake?
I,
yeah,
I sent septal.
I blew up skeptical snake.
So send me that.
What?
I have to post this.
Where did you find it?
And the guy goes just for you.
Shall I see you're skeptical hippo and I
raise you a super skeptical snake.
Yeah.
This is fucking snake.
I might've seen on your instagram.
So skeptical.
Have you seen any daddy?
No.
It should be.
This should be your,
your mascot.
Whenever you watch CNN,
this should pop up.
This is a new meme.
This is a new media is fake news.
So no pizza needs to be the main news
site like in his fucking,
oh look at you wrote,
look at you rail,
pull it aside.
My face,
when I watch a UFC promo these days,
I see you're skeptical lip and raise you
a super skeptical state.
That's exact where for everybody at Bro,
that's because they're not showing
Amanda Nunes.
It is kind of fucked up,
but it's also,
you know,
like someone pointed out like when
you're watching these promos,
their movies now it's like this little
film.
It's not like training footage.
People talking about it like this really
slickly produced movie thing.
The story is fucking great.
Oh,
Amanda Nunez.
The story's great.
Yeah.
First openly gay world champion.
Fricking Brazilian.
I mean knock out a highlight reel,
highlight reels,
smack her fucking work.
Like she's the devil and then,
and then we,
they don't show any Rhonda Kaos.
It's like that.
Just like men in black where they just
won't,
he's a [inaudible] and erase that from
your memory.
They'll just many that,
plenty of that video going around on its
own.
Everybody knows what happened.
It's not something you needed to
discuss.
I think they could have done it in that
video and then show him the workout to
the return and it might be even more
dramatic shown are crying,
showing her building back up,
picking up the pieces again.
I mean that,
that,
I mean,
if you wanted to go deep,
you could,
that's going to be in the movie,
right?
If you have a Rhonda Rousey life story
movie that's gotta be in the movie
course a hundred percent if she comes
back and wins,
I mean,
that's exactly what you're gonna see.
You're gonna see all the pain Ronda
Rousey today right now.
I mean,
she is who she is right now.
What's going on right now is because
what happened with Holly Holm,
you know this is her comeback does,
is it,
can she pull off the comeback?
I mean,
the only reason you ain't gotta come
back against who?
Like I said,
the average Fan's gone come back against
who she has been the favorite in every
fight she's ever been,
had a complete blackout of Amanda Nunez.
Like they haven't showed shit at all
just now.
There's very little footage that they're
showing in these problems.
They're showing Nunez.
Stop watching boxing as to put it back
on fucking,
yeah,
cause I don't see an fs one.
Where on boxing that work.
I'll like that.
Joe tweeted them know I tweeted a big
wall like while I was watching it at
home,
I was watching,
I was actually in a hotel room.
I was watching that UFC on Fox where
Michelle waterson beat paige vanzant and
I was watching.
I'm like this is so bizarre.
They're not showing the champion to show
in this giant Promo and it's all Rhonda.
Which makes some sense because Rhonda is
huge.
You want to let everybody know that
she's coming back,
but don't you want to let everybody know
that she's coming back against a killer
against you want everybody to know that
she's coming back to fight the champion.
Joe,
just just from a business aspect,
what in some weird world in mma,
what if Amanda Nunez Mercer in the first
year she has look,
no one knows it.
Yes.
Is one of them.
One of them you see in her face,
she just see her face.
But like most of the pieces about
Rhonda,
but there's a few of these,
right?
There's a few different ones.
Do you know?
Do you know what I'm saying?
Joe?
What happened that she makes Ronnie
there?
They showed,
they showed her head kick somebody
else's trailer,
Bro.
This isn't created shit.
That's okay.
You don't have to,
it's going be a lot longer than an
actual promo too.
Like how long has that video right
there?
Those two minutes?
Yeah.
Do you see what I'm saying?
Angela?
What happens if some weird,
some weird MMA world?
Amanda,
I heard this weird at all and then we're
going,
do you think that's weird?
Not at all.
No.
It's real dangerous place is acting like
they're putting all their chips in this
basket where if Amanda Nunez does her
thing and it happens,
people go,
who the fuck?
Just one.
But Rhonda is a thousand times more
popular.
Popular Than Amanda Nunez.
Hundred percent a hundred percent where
the money's coming from money yet,
but every,
okay,
you've already established she runs it,
but hold on.
You're already the Ron is finding what
you want everybody to know.
She's fighting a killer.
Who she fighting.
That's what we're tuned in in it.
You will see the matchup,
what selling it as if the whole thing
that you're seeing is her coming back.
Yeah,
but I'm saying in some,
in business 101 what happened if that
other person wins and we don't know shit
about her.
You have to say channel.
This is it.
Yeah.
There's just not much of it.
You see a bunch of different,
if she wins then they'll blow her up.
There's still timing.
We have a deadline.
If she willing can fight Ronda Rousey
once this one manage maybe or amy,
if Rhonda gets work twice,
there's no room.
Who knows?
But at least you know that's the girl
that beat I met.
She'll be just like Holly Holm,
instantly huge and on,
on fucking Ellyn and all that shit.
Holly's in an interesting place to write
cause she was instantly huge.
And then she loses two in a row
straight.
Yeah.
And she loses to,
to like two completely different styles.
She gets choked out by Meesha against a
better grappler.
And then she gets a check the lot by
volunteership Chenko and Mount John.
Tina just,
I would like to see that promo if it's
possible.
Jamie at the UFC,
one of the on the UFC.
Youtube.
I know it's youtube but there's no real
bro.
It's not real.
It's your library tube.
So here's her like in the top of her
feet.
Your promos from arm bar people too.
You get them from CNN.
We all know that.
Smashing people.
So this is uh,
is this the same one as the cartoons is
a different one.
This is the holly fires holly.
So this is going to show it at the end
of November.
What happened there?
They'd all show show it.
They cut.
Oh they go black and then you see holly
winning.
Wow.
See what she,
what she likes skeptical snake.
Well you got to like go down more in
your face has to be done on morning
planning actually.
Like you see he's up,
right?
Cause progression of the mouse and the
progression of the belt.
You see the progression of the belt.
But you don't see her getting head
kicked.
That's crazy.
Why would you not show the highlight?
Wow.
What what you're doing is you're showing
preferential treatment for one athlete
without a doubt.
And the idea is that the ability and the
fame that she's reached you,
you show preferential treatment because
she's different.
She's special,
She's doing massive star.
She has a massive star.
That's the,
that's the girl that's going to put this
the asses in the seats right there,
man.
She's got busier than conor though.
I think you're right.
But as far as women go,
she is the,
the corner of the timeout.
The fighters.
I'm talking about fighters division.
It's not even close.
No,
not even close.
There's no one like there's no one like,
but just cause connor sells more tickets
doesn't mean she's,
they have multiple stores,
multiple elite stars.
And here you see Amanda doing some
workouts just lifting some weights or
girlfriend's a straw weight in the UFC.
Is She?
Yeah.
World Bantamweight champion.
Amanda Nunez.
And then you see some highlights.
So this one is showing more.
So this is a different one than the one.
The one that they see on tv where they
roll up the garage door and you see her
hitting the pads pop up and that's it.
Up.
Up,
up.
Yeah.
By,
by Matt please.
Good though.
It looks good doing that.
Very interesting man.
Who the fuck knows who the fuck knows?
I just know you're going to be watching.
Everyone's going to be watching.
Yeah.
That's going to be crazy man.
Crazy nuts going to be crazy.
I think it would be surprised by the
ratings.
You don't think anybody is watching?
No,
I'm not saying that somebody haters.
no,
no.
I'm not a hater on the promotional game.
Stan.
I understand what you're saying.
I don't think you're gonna see the same
numbers of the conor fight or is there
any other books that are coming up that
we should be aware of?
Any other big fights without what else
is happening on the feature about Tony
Khabib is that are going to have not
happen.
Signed.
It's that you're talking about for the
interim title.
I mean that's not happening easily wants
money,
but here's my question.
How the fuck do you have an interim
champion that quick?
What is,
what's,
what's going on with that?
How do you,
what's what sells?
That's what gets people to tune in as
belts.
Okay.
And so because of the fact that you're
guaranteeing will also,
if you have a beep fight,
conor in Russia and Habib has the belt,
Jesus Christ,
we need to rush and destroy.
He is the Russian destroys the only one.
He is it.
He's on Rafi that he's a smasher.
But what a big opportunity for Tony,
if Tony Ferguson could steal that
thunder.
And if you see when Michael Johnson
clipped him and hurt him,
that was the first time we ever saw him.
Her true.
But Michael Johnson just does not have
the same grappling ability of the Tony
Ferguson has.
No,
it's a different animals.
And also Tony Ferguson is a different
kind of stryker too.
He's,
he's much more awkward in his movement
is like,
he's a real hard time.
Get what?
They're both real good.
Michael Johnson's a very good striker.
I mean when you knocked it knocked out
dust employee that both real good.
But the big difference is the amount of
grappling ability,
Tony's grappling abilities.
Did you see Tony's tweet or did he say
he goes,
I'm down except the fight.
He goes off.
So he could be be you cause could be
called them out.
Cause where's the fight?
And Tony,
Tony said,
dude,
you made your deal and you're making
bank.
I'm not scared of anyone.
I just want to get paid what I'm worth,
man.
I'm down to take the fight.
Interesting.
I need to renegotiate my contract.
You know what Tony said in between round
one and round two,
you know he lost that first round.
Rafael Design Joe's,
he Atlanta took some good shots and you
know we ran into the cage and you don't
know exactly what's going on through his
head.
And he and his striking coach Anthony's
like telling and some shit.
And before I got to say anything,
he looks at me,
goes,
coach,
I'm going to break his leg.
I'm going to kick the inside of it.
You know when he started getting it.
Okay,
perfect.
That's what I want to hear.
He's like,
he's such a barbarian.
That's what he had to say is,
I'm going to pose a monster.
So she kept beating DC Khabib looking at
Dana murking.
That dude gone,
oh,
Micah Johnson going on.
Give me a title shot man.
Just whooping his ass.
Gonna look different
on the ground.
It'll look different on the ground is a
cubby.
Make no mistake about it.
He's a fucking bear on the ground.
The grappler,
but excellent.
Michael Johnson was making a lot of uh,
key errors on the ground.
Yeah,
he was,
uh,
he was [inaudible] to fix with that
crucifix.
He was giving it to you was hurt.
He was hurt.
Did you see,
could be versus a dose Angeles though,
until just answers a legit black belt.
He mauled him.
He'll be mad.
Not to say that again.
Mocking mauled him on the ground molded
me in a weird way where you watching him
just smush a guy who is a Brazilian Jiu
Jitsu black belt.
Like he's handling it like a blue belt
or a purple bag costing around.
Like,
I think he's grappling is as good as
I've ever seen inside the octagon.
He might not be the same submission
stylists that a Damien Maia is,
but it's pure ability to control guys,
take them down,
grapple them and maul them.
Is unprecedented.
Is MMA grappling.
I agree.
Look at this.
When he gets a hold of you,
it's,
it's so fucking undeniable,
like this kind of shit.
Like he gets a hold of you at bear hugs
you and just like,
bitch,
you're going down,
you are going to the fucking ground and
he holds you there and he beats the fuck
out of you when he has you there.
Well he's,
the rusher is insane.
Insane and positioning.
His positioning is pressure.
His strength is Damien Maia without the
submissions and mortar.
Yeah.
Ground and pound.
Damien patrol,
but better take downs.
Better takedowns way better.
Yeah.
Mine's taking everyone down is very good
at one,
seven very wrestlers and everything.
No doubt about it.
But you've got to give the edge to,
they're gonna come in off and the
takedowns yeah.
Yeah,
I think so.
I give the edge normally commit off over
everybody except Ben [inaudible].
Ben Asked her.
It was like the only guy that you just
go,
okay,
what the fuck?
That's a fun fun.
Oh Bet dude.
Ben Asked Grin.
I feel like Ben's bigger,
but you know Ben is a 170 of course,
but he probably could make one 55 of the
fuck no,
they could could beep.
They do catch weight when 61 thing that
[inaudible] didn't have the tone he's
going to bring into this,
this college wrestling.
Tony is a really good rustler is going
to be a lot harder to take tony down
than it is dos Anjos tell he's just a
different,
he's a,
he's like a harder mindset.
He's a scary fucking dude and more
athletic.
Whether he wins or whether he loses.
Tony is a scary fucking guy to be in
there with.
Very scary.
Not that Dosantos isn't,
but I think that Tony is like one notch
scarier.
Remember this is dos Anjos like in his
prime to prime.
Honestly it was,
this was before he started making his
real serious run.
He got molly wop tier and then Habib got
injured and then they'll sign.
Just came back and he also started
working with nick.
Curse on that was a big,
a big uh,
factor and his improvement cause his
strength and conditioning got way better
after this fight cause he realized like,
Holy Shit,
I can't keep this fucking vanilla beast
yeti thing.
His pressures,
pressures can rush Russian destroyer
man.
There's just these Dagestan people,
That heart,
that part of the world is tough and
dudes are on
another level when it comes to like
tenacity and aggression.
He's also been doing it since he's a
kid.
He's a world champion.
You know,
Sambo that end.
Russians aren't regular white people.
All right?
We've established the same man was the
American white,
Russian,
white dear friend.
Their genetics are fucking,
there's are powerful people man.
And it's the,
I mean you think about all the guys who
came out of Russia that had been like
ridiculous world champion caliber
fighters like [inaudible] system to Mary
memory.
You have of change skin.
Yes.
Jesus Christ.
He was,
he remembered when he fought to get the
Francisco Bueno tote is a straight
fucking dosantos is hanging in there
with him for a while.
But we get that [inaudible] that take
down.
Come on son.
Monsters wrestling actual beer.
Yeah.
When he's a little kid like the
grappling a bear.
Eddie pull up Igov of Chan Chan for
Francisco Bueno.
Kao [inaudible] will,
you should throw those casting punches.
You know what I'm talking about?
Where we throw hammers?
He would throw like Igor Volv chinch
just give it a chance.
Shan Skin.
Do you know how to spell it?
Eddie?
How do you evolve?
Chin Chin.
[inaudible] c h a can.
There it is.
Just go with one of those all the chant
and then write mma.
Nothing
put equally.
Okay.
There he is.
[inaudible] versus Francisco Bueno.
Francisco Bueno.
And in the,
uh,
it's one of the,
like the most vicious chaos ever washed
this shit.
You never seen this before.
[inaudible] was another guy who was like
maybe five,
eight,
five,
nine at the most and was fighting
heavyweights and just,
he looked like a guy who had longer
arms,
but they saw the ends off.
Do you remember ego hit the chancellor.
Is he before your time?
Before I got really Yo Dude,
look at that.
I mean that was an early Russian
destroy.
Oh yeah.
One of the scary dad bod look at the sky
size of his fucking thighs.
Dude.
Those were ridiculous thighs.
Like his whole body was just like,
like this compact just explosive
machine.
What do you think are rising?
You think?
I love it.
We need more.
Yeah,
we need,
we need ride,
right?
We need to all that.
We need a bunch of organizations like
that to emerge.
Did you see he thinks back.
Yeah,
it's good.
He's filling in for Shane.
I'm so sad the chains out,
but I'm happy to see that he is doing it
again.
And I saw pictures of him with Roy at a
probably cause it [inaudible] lesnar
marijuana rarely.
Unless we're like steamrolled him
knocked him over and yeah,
that was his last five years ago.
10 years ago.
Long ass time.
Yeah.
And then he got Mirko Cro cop or smell
the wall.
Who is a crawling,
fighting.
He's fighting and rising,
right.
Grown is fine.
Caligiuri Ooh,
that's a real
fight right there.
It's a real fight.
He's a little old,
but still such mma wise.
That's a first line test for chrome.
Yeah,
for sure.
Yeah.
We'll say,
yeah,
real test,
right?
Yeah.
That's a good fighter.
He gets back.
It's over though.
So you know they're doing it.
Took the champion and be crowned.
They're doing those fights over three
days,
so he when fight the next night.
That's so crazy.
Who's doing that?
Rising tournaments.
Yeah.
That's so crazy.
Weight heavy weight.
That was in the tournament.
Mola Wall.
King Mo.
That crazy dude that fuck that.
Amir Alica Bari.
Who's,
have you seen that guy?
Yes.
He's terrifying.
Then Keith Herring.
Yeah.
He's fighting it Aka,
right.
He's training out of Aka,
yeah,
Thailand with a Mike Switch.
They tagged me.
The picture of him,
him in that whole guy.
Even the whole kit in the UFC,
Simone Hawk.
So I'll pull aly.
Yes.
So and uh,
politely.
And Mike Swicker holman back and he's
like,
ah.
I'm like bout to unleash the beast.
Not,
oh gosh.
Jesus Christ.
Fuck this dude is scary.
I think rise is awesome.
I think it's important.
I think heritage areas.
Jeez,
it's a big boy.
He looks like Gabriel Gonzaga and Shane.
Carmen had a kid and ridonculous
wrestling just a big ass this showing
you.
I remember that.
He's been training for a while,
right?
He's doing rising.
He's in this tournament.
What's his name?
Amir.
I love Ali.
Barie.
Barie Ali Akbari.
They showed him hidden myth.
Powerful and not,
not too good with the striking.
Is He Russian?
He's right there on that border.
No Sir.
He's not rushed.
And what does his national,
uh,
he's Iranian.
Izzy.
He's Muslim is fuck,
here we go here.
Yeah.
Iranian.
Oh Shit.
A lot of strong wrestlers come out of
Iran,
you know,
iron,
sheik,
his things Greco,
which doesn't always translate to mma,
but who's more synonymous with
wrestling?
And I ran in the iron sheik.
None.
Maybe.
Nobody ever did you ever see that?
I gave him a ride to the airport once
and video tape and put it on Youtube.
I've never seen that.
No shake.
It's like seven parts iron,
sheik and Denny loaner where we're,
um,
cause he,
he,
his manager would take 'em you'd give
him 200 bucks and you could hang out
with the iron sheik and his hotel and
just fucking shoot the shit with them.
And so Dan,
he says,
dude,
you want to go hang out with the iron
sheik?
I said,
fuck yes.
So we went in,
it turns out we were late and he needed,
he was going to the airport in late.
He goes,
you want to,
you want to just take us to the airport?
And we're like,
AH,
fuck yeah.
We got him trapped in the car,
gets out mother fucker.
That's him there.
How old is he there?
He's a pretty old guy.
Holy Shit.
Wow.
Yeah.
He,
um,
he came on stage with me at that pot
club in Toronto.
He came on stage,
he was in the audience and I brought him
up on stage.
You're damn right.
Joe Rogan knows what these toughest
sport in all of Olympics,
freestyle Greco.
If people want to shop tonight.
Oh fuck yeah.
Everybody knows that the iron sheik is,
I showed him that I named a move after
him.
I had my book with me and I go,
look,
I called the move the iron sheik.
Ah,
that's amazing.
He's,
he's hurting man.
His whole body's all fucked up from all
those years of pro wrestling,
everything that too,
but I mean,
his knees are junk on.
His hips are gone back,
Scott.
And he's like,
go get fucked up man.
Fuck yeah,
they do,
man.
Nobody,
I don't think people appreciate the
beating those guys take on their box or
schedule though.
Obviously rehearsing all that stuff in
reality behind the scenes.
He was the baddest dude and he was a
real,
uh,
Olympia has an Olympic gold medal and
restless.
So it was Kurt Angle and uh,
and backstage he was the fucking man.
Everybody knew that he was running the
fucking show.
He,
well,
he was a definite like real wrestler.
Yeah,
for sure.
Yeah.
There's a few of those guys that get
into pro wrestling.
They're like Kurt Angle,
but a real legitimate gold medalist and
the shit went down.
They fuck you up for rail?
Yeah.
Well it's uh,
you know,
like how about brock?
I give this shit went down.
Who's,
who's beaten brock.
Good luck.
Good luck though.
You guys came Alaska.
I see.
Yeah.
Became cause they went to three people
on the planet.
But yeah,
and also Kane at two 40.
You know when brock is at two 65,
when,
when brock is not under any sort of
guidelines or restrictions,
he tends to be larger.
That's more con about it.
Yeah.
Wow.
Look at that.
The audio audience.
She Damn,
he was Jack.
Oh,
he was super jacked back in the day and
powerful mustache.
Yeah,
he was a thick dude.
He also used to use those Iranian clubs.
Those look at the fucking swango other
things.
We'll get the fucking thighs on that
dude.
Jesus Christ.
I mean,
he's just like one thick mother.
Bleaks powerful,
thick ass.
Powerful dude.
But I'm watch,
see if you could find a Irenie.
I,
um,
Indian club workout.
Have you seen the documentary on the
iron sheik?
No.
There's a documentary on him and it just
got released like maybe a year or two
ago.
He said it's awesome.
They're always sad though.
Like the Jake,
the snake one's a bummer.
See those clubs is a great,
it's a great documentary.
Sad though and Shit.
This whole story,
um,
you know,
it's not,
you're not going to start crying and he
does this,
this is,
these clubs meet that check this shit
out.
These clubs that he's using,
these are like traditional Indian clubs
that they used to use to,
to work out.
They would do these things called shield
casts that is fucking very hard to hell.
Yeah.
And the way he's doing.
And he's like,
yeah,
yeah.
Those things around like they're
nothing.
Those are fucking difficult to swing
around.
And I do that work out with a 25 pound
club.
It's that like,
it's that hard to do now.
He's a legit badness.
Yeah.
25 pounds.
Seems like it's nothing that like,
it seems like,
what the fuck is that though?
That he called them Persian clubs.
That's what we called it,
Hershey and clubs.
They,
well they used him in Persia as well and
uh,
I ran.
But the,
those were uh,
like an old school strength and
conditioning piece of equipment and you
would get other people to try to do it
and they just couldn't do it.
Like some of them they would do matter
would,
they would use like these big thick
pieces of heavy wood with a handle on
the bottom.
And that was what the originally are
made out of.
But now a lot of guys make them out of
steel now.
Like this Guy Jack White boy taking the
challenge.
Oh he's doing it to Paul Paul.
Goddammit.
Precious Paul,
Precious Paul's going forward and back,
which is legit.
But the real way to do it is what's
called a shield cast where you take your
right hand and you go towards your left
shoulder behind your back and then you
control,
you bring it down in front of you and
control.
Do we have any of those here?
We don't have any of those.
We have the macy's,
but we don't have a club.
It's a fucking awesome exercise for
stroke.
Shoulder strength.
Your shoulders,
beverly.
Yeah,
good.
What you do,
they can't go with like really heavy
mates right off the bat,
but obviously precious Poe,
he's getting Jack now.
Seconds later he was like,
I do stupid.
Fuck whoever you ellis.
Chest precious pays us a man.
And just knowing that that iron sheik
knows I'm alive.
I mean,
I mean it's pretty dope.
Can you still pay him $200 to chill and
stuff for now?
400 bucks now.
Is it 405 now?
It's fine.
Fuck you.
Keep talking.
It's going to get more.
Yeah,
we put him in the car for like an hour.
It just picking his brain,
make them leave messages.
He was down.
He wasn't [inaudible] ride to the
airport.
We see live,
I think somewhere in Minnesota,
maybe cold out there as fuck if you got
a bad hip.
There's some wwe guys killing it.
Like Jesse Ventura's killing it.
He was a big time.
He's had some injuries to man.
A lot of those guys are all busted up
from that dude.
Jesse Ventura is like 100% wheat
activists now.
He just wrote a book on,
I had him on.
Oh Shit.
Yeah,
he was great.
He's all about the weed movement or some
shit and he uses weed for,
he's got a bunch of ailments and his
wife has some ailments too,
you know,
and she's using weed for it.
You know,
he sued the American stamp guy and one
American sniper.
Yeah.
Chris Kyle.
Cause calcs.
Crew.
Cal said he beat him up,
kind of punked him in a bar.
And he was like,
that fucking never happen.
And sued him.
Yeah,
he's um,
actually said he was going to consider
running for president if Donald Trump
won.
That's what he said on the podcast.
I wonder if he's still going to do it.
Talking to her seventies now.
He's in his seventies yeah.
And that's,
that's a hard,
just Donald Trump.
Yeah,
it's true.
Yeah.
It's all very interesting,
man.
All okay.
Any of the fights we need to talk about?
Is that it?
Did we get them all pulled up?
Brandon Thatch.
Oh,
who's he fighting isn't fun a while.
He's fighting up a price.
Who's Nico?
Nico Price.
Nico.
How's that doing your,
you're friends with him,
right?
Yeah.
Friends with him.
I talked to at least or bowl and this
morning about him,
he said it's the cause that just thing
has always been dedication.
He sits the most dedicated.
He's ever been to a fight.
So that's usually scary.
Well,
he's a super,
super talented guy.
Great.
Oh,
and Tim means is finding Alex Oliveira.
Ooh,
there's a sleeper dude.
How come nobody brought that up?
What else?
Stunned.
Done verse Safa Dean.
But hold on,
let's look at this fucking fight.
Tammy's is a bad mother fucker and so is
all of era.
All the air is big though.
Didn't he have a hard time making one 70
in his last fight?
Yeah.
W was,
it was this last fight is when he got
murked by cowboy.
The real cowboy because he goes by
cowboy to know he,
I feel like he fought Alex.
Right.
And he won,
knocked the guy out,
but he was way overweight.
He's huge,
like way overweight.
Like for some reason he,
I mean,
I want to say he was several pounds
overweight.
Right.
That's a fun fight.
Yeah.
Garcia versus Mike pyle.
Mike pile still hanging in.
God talked about can we,
he's the dirty bird.
He's a bad motherfucker to really
skillful.
Very smart guy when it comes to is not
young and then they are cute.
No,
he's in his forties but he's in the
Larry Holmes forties and like a legit
forties with Usada,
you know,
legit forties Terex,
half a dean and Don Young Kim.
That's interesting to them.
Guns been up for a minute.
Yup.
He has in him versus terrick.
Safa Dean is very interesting.
When was the last time stun gun was in?
When was the last time Dung Young Kim
was fighting.
What was his last fight?
If you had to guess.
It wasn't the Woodley [inaudible]
woodley stopped him probably because
he's taken a long,
let's see what it does it say there.
Is it Woodley?
Nope.
Last fight.
He Won.
Who did he fight there?
Dominic water shit.
Ohh.
Burke.
Dominic waters and Josh Berkman.
Okay.
And then he lost to Woodley.
So he's still decay owed him two years
since 2015.
Yeah.
Hmm.
John Hathaway,
what happened to him?
He was dealing with some injuries I
think had a lot of potash.
Yeah.
A lot of attention and under uh,
under a appreciated grappling ability
for a big guy from the UK.
English fellow.
That's right.
But he uh,
he had some injuries I believe.
And did he have like some sort of an
allergy or something to like maybe a
food allergy or something like that that
he was dealing with?
It's like,
no,
you don't see some kind of medical
issue.
Something that's a bummer.
Yeah,
man.
Hard ass sport.
Um,
is that it?
Is that it for that card?
Anything else coming up that we need to
talk about before we get the fuck up out
this bitch?
Sure.
How many articles do you think we wrote
for the MMA media today?
A fake mma new site.
They need to stop.
They're all fake.
They have a lot of fake ones.
People make up shit.
I walked out and it's almost like a
blur.
I don't remember.
I said I read some shit.
I'm like,
Oh damn.
I was just talking to my friends.
Oh you kidding me?
I never watched that shit.
All that shit though.
Those videos pop up like randomly I'm
watching something else and that shit
pops up and I'm like,
I don't want to watch that bullshit.
Well,
on my show I do fan questions.
Like when you said this shit to Rogan,
like I said that,
listen,
that's what that was a problem with.
Like people like getting upset.
It's something that people's three
people say,
whether you're just,
we're all racing world's Darton in with
shit and talking shit and we're all high
and were being ridiculous.
When you,
when you do stuff like that,
like you're going to say some shit that
you probably shouldn't have said,
but you can't pretend that it is
anything we thought out.
Like a lot of it is a completely off the
cuff and if you don't like that,
that's fine.
But if you do like it,
there's only one way to do it folks.
You've got to do it off the cuff like
that and you gotta get a crack,
some eggs.
If you want to make an Omelet.
It's true.
We'll make some omelets [inaudible]
stones all day.
By the way.
Brian counts not,
it's not that he's not here because we
don't love him.
He's busy.
He's a on vacation.
That's all.
Cause people would go,
you go to cooking Kellen out?
No,
not at all.
But if he was here we would definitely
have made fun of them and we definitely
would have got called bullies.
So that's uh,
that's also made some facts up.
It's just what we do.
And we love him.
He's a crazy boy.
He's so fun fellow.
So he's out there on vacation.
He'll be back for the next one.
So,
uh,
we'll try to do one soon.
Um,
there's some other ones coming up,
um,
that I'm not doing,
you know,
I know for sure we'll have to do that.
And if a one saunders is coming up
against,
um,
uh,
court mcgee,
then is that January 15th,
Sunday,
January 15th and Phoenix,
I'll be there cornering.
So that's the Bj Penn card.
What is it?
January what?
1415 oh,
it's a Sunday night.
Oh,
interesting.
Be Fun.
Oh Man,
man,
I man,
I was doing no conspiracy theories.
That one.
Next one.
I'll try and have them drive.
Brian saying,
why doesn't piece you just punch him
with the right hand.
I'll tell you what,
Bj's fundamentals are just off.
Yeah.
What does it mean to just hit him with
the right hand?
All right folks.
That's it.
I'm a fighter and the kid t fat k.com.
Edgy Bra.
Eddie Bravo on twitter.
Eddie Bravo 10 on instagram.
Brendan Schaub on Instagram,
10th planet J j.com
we're in Seattle,
Portland and Vancouver January.
I'm next EBI is on March.
We're aiming for March 5th amy for it,
but old ones which you do want to watch
are all available on fight pass.
Go there and check out the last one with
a Geo Martinez,
Eddie,
Eddie Cummings.
Cause he's someone that Armbar God damn.
And a,
it's just so many epic matches and it
give you,
if you're a fight fan in particular,
give you a real appreciation of high
level grappling and getting to see all
these submissions.
And it's just awesome format.
That edge.
It has a invented.
Ah,
all right.
We'll be back tomorrow with a,
um,
Zach leary.
Exactly.
Or Timothy leary's son can be here.
All right,
we'll see you.
Bye.