Five four, three, two,
one boom.
And we're live with my friend Justin
wren in the house and one of the baddest
motherfuckers on the planet.
Rafael Lovato. Absolutely. Dude,
I'm bummed that you're,
I'm happy that you're doing well,
but I'm bombing you fighting for Bella
tour. Oh, I really am, man. I want wanna.
I want to come and take your fights.
I know for a fact that Bella
tour right now is like, is high.
It's a higher level than it's ever been
before. Right? I mean, you look at,
they've got Moose Saucy,
you, Rory Macdonald, uh,
Lima, uh, you know Paul
Daley Machida. I mean,
it's fucking high level now,
man.
It's like Bella tour is very
close to comparable still.
I would love to see you over [inaudible]
yeah, well we'll see what happens,
but right now I'm really happy
where I'm at. How old are you now?
I'm 35 and you didn't start MMA until
you were like 31 32 31 house for four
years ago. Yeah, 2014 was my first fight.
Were you doing a lot of MMA training
before that? Because when you're,
you were for people that don't know,
you're one of the most
accomplished Brazilian Jiu
Jitsu black belts in the world.
And when you're competing as a
Brazilian Jujitsu martial artist,
were you training striking when you
training other things as well? Well,
uh, you know, that's a kind of my
life story I guess. Um, you know,
my father is a lifetime martial artist
and so I had a whole martial arts upgrade
upbringing. Well before I ever
found out about Brazilian Jujitsu.
My father was a g condo instructor.
And so growing up, um, you know,
the main thing that we were training
at when I was a child was, uh,
the g condo system,
which was basically mixed martial arts
before mixed martial arts. You know,
Bruce Lee's philosophy was way ahead of
his time. He believed in, uh, you know,
learning from all the arts and creating
your own personal system of self defense,
um, that involves, you know,
each range of combat. And so,
you know, I grew up doing several
different forms of martial arts. Um, uh,
boxing moy, Thai Eskrima Wing
Chung Pin Joc, see lot, I mean,
you name it,
I've probably done it.
And when my father discovered
Brazilian Jujitsu, uh,
I was an early teenager,
like around 12 years old.
He learned about Brazilian Jujitsu in one
of the g Cuando instructor conferences
that takes place in California.
They brought in the Gracies. Um,
they had, you know, they did
like shootfighting fighting
and different sort of,
you know, martial arts and that
included grappling. Uh, but it was very,
you know,
rough and not near the technique
that Brazilians you two has a,
so whenever he first started
learning Brazilian Jujitsu,
he fell in love with it.
My Dad's a smaller guy, uh, at that time
he was probably like 140 550 pounds.
And so it was perfect for him and he fell
in love with it and he comes home and
he telling me about Brazilian Jujitsu
and teaching me what he learned. Um,
and we lived in Oklahoma and then start
to conference was in California at that
time. Basically the only Jujitsu was in
California, maybe a little bit in Florida.
And then Henson was in New York.
So everything was as far as possible from
us because we were right there in the
middle of the country. And you know, he
fell in love with Brazilian Jiu Jitsu.
And so he started making trips to
California to learn Brazilian Jiu Jitsu.
And I was just a teenager. I'm a young
kid, so, you know, I was already, uh,
doing some boxing at the time, uh, as
competing in amateur boxing. And I'm,
I'm used to training with adults and once
I started learning Brazilian Jujitsu,
you know,
I fell in love with it right away because
that gave me something that I could do
where I could be competitive
with the adults right away.
You know, it was a long,
lanky kid. Um, and the
guards just, you know,
felt natural to me and just being
on the ground. I really loved it.
And I love that the,
the technique of Brazilian Jujitsu,
how technical it was and
the science of it. Um,
so I fell in love with it
right away and I mean, uh, we,
we sacrificed a lot to learn
Jujitsu. Being an Oklahoma, um,
always traveled, uh, to learn. The first
time I went to Brazil, I was 16 years old.
It was in 1999, uh, to, to train and
compete in the world championships.
And, you know, we just never stopped.
And we became the first American father
and son, Brazilian Jujitsu, black belts.
Uh, but you know, going
back to your question,
the full spectrum of martial arts
was always in my blood. Um, you know,
even as a Jujitsu competitor,
you know,
someone that found his passion in Jujitsu,
I still considered myself a martial
artist first and foremost, not just, uh,
a Jujitsu practitioner. And so it was
always in the plans to one day do MMA.
Um, but I really wanted to go as far
as I could. And in Brazilian Jujitsu.
You know,
I was there when Bj Penn won the world
championships in 2000 and I watched him
win. And I said, you know, man,
I really want to be the next
American to to win the worlds.
That immediately became like my, my
big life goal, my first life goal. And,
um, and I achieved that in
2007. But, you know, like,
we all saw Bj go to MMA after he won.
He never even did another tournament.
You know, that was the only tournament
he ever did as a black belt.
What's the worlds and he won and then,
and then switch to MMA.
And so I really want it to
be an American, you know, um,
just kind of representing
for us in Brazilian Jujitsu,
I'm competing at that high level and
winning as much as possible and kind of,
you know, at that time it
wasn't like today the world's,
we're still in Brazil. Uh,
uh, the sport was just dominated by
Brazilians and pretty much still is today.
But you know,
now we've,
we've come a long way and I just want
it to be that forced to show everyone
like, hey, we can do it. You know what I
mean? We're, uh, you know, it's possible,
you know, because at that time it was,
it was a whole nother scene. You know,
the world's in Brazil at the end of the,
at the tournament,
you're lucky if you had a handful
of nob resilience on the podium,
had all the belts, you know,
including blue, purple,
Brown, I mean, all the belts,
let alone black belt.
And so I stayed in the sport to
really try to get a second goal.
That was the main thing
that was keeping me in it,
to win a second goal that the
world's has a black belt. Uh,
I ended up medaling eight times,
never got that second gold. But, uh,
towards the end I was just like, you
know, it's time to switch. You know,
I really felt like, um,
in the Mei was calling me,
Jiu Jitsu was getting a little
too comfortable. Um, you know,
and I had been fighting too comfortable.
Yeah.
Like it wasn't motivating me and inspired
me the same way that it was in the
beginning. You know, it kind of lost
a little bit of that hunger, uh,
just because I had been at the, the
that level for so long and I've already,
you know, competed against the best guys
in my generation so many times. And,
uh, you know, it didn't take a
lot for me to get ready. You know,
I was kind of just used to it,
you know,
it's the same tournaments the same season,
year after year, and it was just, yeah,
same guys.
Uh,
it just stopped bringing out the fire now
every now and then I felt it, you know,
especially when I went back to
compete in Brazil, uh, you know,
the world's switch to the u s and
in 2007 the year that I want it.
And so I,
I stopped having that thing to,
to push me to go to Brazil to compete.
Um,
and so I went back a couple of times to
compete in the Brazilian nationals and I
had really good performances there.
I ended up winning the absolute
in 2013 in Brazil. Uh, the,
the all way class division,
uh,
became the first non Brazilian to
ever win a major absolute title.
And I did an in Brazil, that was a day
I was extremely inspired, you know, uh,
competing in Brazil
brought that out of me,
but I just didn't feel that
way all the time, you know, uh,
just got too used to it. And so I just
felt like it was calling me, you know,
I knew one day I was going to do it.
I had to have one fight
just as a martial artist.
I had to do at least one before
it was all said and done.
And I really just kind of took it
as a one fight basis, you know,
like I knew I needed to do it once
and you know, uh, the time felt right.
Like, okay, let's, let's go, let's
switch back in, uh, to, you know,
kind of tapping into who I was as a
martial artist though the training that I
had as a kid, as a child, um,
under my father under the
g condo system. And, um,
and I did one fight and
I enjoyed it and I said,
I got to do more and I've got to do
at least one more the whole time.
When you were doing Jujitsu,
where you training kickboxing at all when
you're doing any wrestling? Like, well,
always, uh, did wrestling, you know, to
supplement, supplement, Brazilian Jujitsu,
the Gnocchi, competitions, ADCC,
things like that. Um, you know,
and I just believed in training
everything to judo as well. Um,
like what about practicing ground and
pound and all the other things in MMA?
Well, whenever I was
younger, uh, my father,
he had some fighters that he was training
and so I trained a lot with them.
And then whenever I took over the academy,
um,
we had a couple guys that were
fighting then as well, uh,
one of which went to the UFC. And so
I was sparring with these guys, um,
helping them get ready.
And in 2008,
I met who is now my main MMA coach.
He's my Moy Thai instructor. Uh,
his name is Mauricio Amado. Uh,
his nickname is Vail. He, his
brothers of Andre Dda. Um,
and they are both shoot box. Is
that what you were encouraged? Tiva?
You've done camps? Yes, exactly.
That's where DDA lifts his brother
and a DDS to fight in pride. Uh,
k one A. I think he did. Yeah. K One. Um,
he did a dream. I believe he
did some Emily as well. Uh,
but he's more of a of a
kickboxing. Yeah. Striker. Um,
and I, I met Matty Uco and, uh, I,
I really fell in love with his style of
Muay Thai and I had some guys fighting
at that time. What's the difference
in his style? Well, it's,
it's totally designed
for MMA. Um, you know,
it's not Moitai for Moitai, you know, uh,
they call it their system evolution.
Sound time basically means evolution,
you know,
and it's evolved into this system
that is designed for MMA. You know,
you're, you're not just
turning, striking for striking,
you're doing striking to set up
takedowns or defend take downs and,
um, it was just a, you know,
an incredible system. Justin,
whenever we fought last year, he got
to train with mighty UCO, um, and,
and experience it for himself and special.
Yeah.
And Maddie's steel himself is just
an amazing martial artist. Uh,
you know, the, the, the passion that he
has is you can't get them to stop. Yeah.
Will you train with a lot of guys? Like
what was different for you? I mean,
I think the way that they,
they move and see the punches coming in
and the blocks are different and the,
the movement, I mean, just so much
movement, movement, movement, um,
and then highlight silo to compensate
for the fact that you're using smaller
gloves, like a different
way of protecting yourself.
How would you explain that
just, well, yeah, I mean the,
the offense and defense is
so intertwined. Um, you know,
you do everything on both
sides. Um, and it's all,
you know, very powerful as well.
It's designed for, uh, you know,
inflicting as much damage as possible.
And for me it was so good because they
can work with me as a Jiu Jitsu guy much
different because they don't have to worry
about someone trying to take me down,
you know, I can pretty much throw
whatever, whatever's possible,
everything in the kitchen sink and for
the most part you're happy if someone
takes you down. Yeah.
That's okay. It's okay. And,
and then also I have the threat being
able to threaten someone with a takedown,
which opens up a lot of striking
as well. And so the, the,
the way they have this system design,
you know,
is just for me and Manny sue us a
person has just an incredible guy that I
really fell in love with. And uh, honestly
if it wasn't for him, I wouldn't be,
I wouldn't be doing MMA.
He just made me feel like I had the
right person in place, the family, um,
to, to go into it and made confidently
and, and enjoy it. You know what I mean?
Cause I, in the beginning I wasn't
sure how much I was going to,
how much I was going to
like the whole process.
You've been working with him
for what, 10 years? Yeah,
we've been training together 10 years.
Yes.
And so I was bringing him out
to help my guys get ready.
There were the guys that were fighting
MMA and at the same time always training
with him. It wasn't my focus then, but,
uh, I, I love to cross train, you know,
and just the movement,
you know,
I love the movement and keeping my
body guessing, doing different things.
And um, and so when I decided,
okay, let's go all in on MMA,
he was the obvious person to call.
And since then he,
he basically spends half
the year in Oklahoma with me
and lives with me and I go
to Brazil to train with
DDA and his team there. Um,
what made you decide to
do that? Like, I mean,
that's a big commitment to try to go all
the way to Brazil for your camps. Well,
how many camps are you done now? Uh,
nine. Yeah, I've had nine fights.
Basically every fight. Um, well how
much time do you spend on that? Uh,
at least two weeks. Um,
sometimes a little more.
There's been a couple times a little less,
but right around two weeks.
This next time if you fight
a gay garden was saucy,
you might spend three or four weeks. Yeah,
I'm thinking probably a month, month. Um,
you know, it's just kind of full
circle for me, you know, like I said,
I went to Brazil first time, uh, 16
years old going to Rio to train Jujitsu,
compete in the world championships.
Did your dad go down there with
you whenever you were 16. Actually,
my dad has never gone to Brazil. He, you
know, he's not a flyer. He doesn't fly.
He does not like to fly. When he was
going to California, he was driving,
driving glaucoma. Yup. 12 over 20 hours.
Drove to your last fight and the Boise,
Idaho, that signers along the
way, three hours, he knows.
And he used to be in the air force
and that's kind of why he had a bad
experience for me. And
uh, he, he lived in Spain.
He was stationed there when
he was in the air force. Um,
but you can get them to
fly. It's a bit of work. Uh,
it's going to take a little bit of a,
some drugs and maybe a drink or
two to come down. But, um, yeah,
he, he would, uh, W I mean we did
road trips on my spring break,
Christmas break from Oklahoma all the
way to California to train. Um, so he's,
he has not made a trip to Brazil yet,
but I think it's coming soon. He's, uh,
he took a long break from,
from, uh, from flying. And, uh,
in 2009, he had a heart
attack. Uh, unfortunately,
but he bounced back and since then he's
kind of reformatted his life a little
bit. And, uh,
and one of the things that he put
his mind to do coming back was the,
the, uh, the famous
walk, uh, in Spain. Uh,
got it left my mind right now. They
made a movie about it before. Um,
and that pushed him to two minutes walk.
Yeah. Well I had, I can't remember it.
Right. Um, yeah. You know, where you
walk, like you walk to hike? Yes. Yes.
It's a long walk. I feel so bad that
I can't remember the name. Um, yeah,
it's like a six week walk and,
and you ended up at a special cathedral.
The Camino, the Camino
de Santiago. Yes. Uh,
in the Santiago is the Cathedral.
There it is, that picture of there.
So he did that. Um, and so he had, of
course, he had to fly to Spain to do it.
And so flying to Spain to
walk six week. Yes, yes.
They're specially trained
for it and you know, and he,
that was one of the maybe
train to walk six weeks it,
well you weren't a backpack.
And so every day he would backpack,
backpack through.
Um,
they have special hostels that you
would stay in on the walk. I mean,
there's a lot of people
that do it. Uh, you know,
you're not going to be by herself.
There's people doing it all
your mountain trail in Georgia.
What is that called again?
Appalachian trail, you know,
it goes all the way up to Maine.
Had a friend that just did that six
months was so proud of him for doing that.
But, and so he started flying again. And
I think you'll be going to Brazil soon,
but you and your dad to me
or something really special,
like you embody the heart
of a true martial artist.
You live it as a lifestyle and for you
even in for him to be supporting you,
you know,
you coming out of the wound basically
starting martial arts and then how he
supporting you as a 16 year
old going down to Brazil.
And how long did you stay there whenever
you're 16 to weeks? Little over. Yeah,
I mean it, yeah. My, my, my
parents, both my parents, uh,
just have given me incredible
support. My mom, I mean,
my dad is a full on martial
artists mean, you know, uh, lived,
he follows his passion, his martial
artist, musician, he plays the Oregon, uh,
just a very unique individual.
Um, and, uh, you know,
he opened a martial arts school and my
mom given us incredible support and,
you know,
I just basically followed his footsteps
and whenever I started to commit myself
to, you know, going all in, they've
always been behind me. And, um, I mean,
I,
I the,
the timing of it is just very special
because he was inspired by Bruce Lee and
that's what pushed him to, you
know, fall that she can do a system.
And so I got to come in in that, uh,
which is a very, you know, unique, uh,
style.
When I was a child,
I was training with Danny and Maisano
Richard Steal some of the most incredible
martial artist that I've ever lived.
That's very fortunate.
And then I was at the special
age of a teenager, you know,
when Brazilian just to first started
making its way to the u s and I had the
support of them say, yeah,
you're going to go to Brazil,
you're going to compete in the world's.
And I got to see Jujitsu, you know,
very early on.
Uh,
the first world championships was
in [inaudible] 96 and I competed in
[inaudible] 99. And so I got to
experience Brazilian Jujitsu, uh,
almost its roots,
um,
in Brazil and see what it's
become today. Um, you know,
worldwide, such a big sport. And
now I'm also fighting in the May,
so it's really cool.
My whole martial arts genic shooter
box is known for some of the roughest
sparring ever. And there was an
old school the way they, you do it.
Do they still spar like that? Because
it used to be just gym wars. I mean,
and the, the criticism was
that a lot of these guys were,
they were damaging themselves so badly
and training that they were limiting
their careers. Yeah, I would
say they learned from that. Um,
a little bit, a little bit, but, uh, it's,
it's definitely, it's definitely hardcore,
um, go down and could achieve. Uh,
and that's one of the reasons that it,
that I like it so much.
It gets me out of my comfort zone.
And you feel that energy every day,
you know,
you wake up and you kind of
have to process what you're
about to go to, you know,
when the professional
training every morning. Um,
but how often did you spar down there?
There is some version of sparring almost
every day, basically every day. Um,
but it, it, it's a different
aspect. You might be boxing only.
There's a Moitai only day
there's a MMA sparring. There's,
you know, grappling with ground and
pound and wall wall work. You know, um,
it's,
it's interesting because there's so many
different philosophies when it comes to
how often you should spar.
There is, um, you know,
and there are definitely days where
I have to kind of speak up and say,
you know what, I'm gonna, I'm gonna
pull back just a little bit today. Uh,
just depending on what my body feels,
a,
I try to listen to that
as much as possible. Um,
there aren't you sparring partners with
like Vander Lee down? They're still, yeah,
yeah. Fuck all that. Yeah. Actually this
spar Vandelay you just
fight him, right? Uh,
this scar right here is happening, could
achieve with sparring, with Vandelay. Um,
you know, you, you get more comfortable
with it and the guys are awesome.
I mean the, they are definitely my MMA
family. That's just the way they do it.
It's not them, it's not a personal
thing. It's not trying to hurt you. No.
Not going to hurt each other. They sing
and dance and you know, hug and, you know,
I mean, afterwards, everyone's so happy.
You make it through it and
you celebrate it. You know,
it's the craziest story I heard was,
um,
shogun and Vandelay we're arguing
over the price of a pit bull puppy.
And so they decided to
fight and if Vandelay one,
then he would get the puppy for free.
And if shogun one vendor would have
to pay him what he wanted and Vandelay
knocked shogun out.
I'm training and it was a laughing when
he woke them up holding the puppy. Wow.
Like what the fuck? Yeah. And they're
really good friends. Yep. Yeah.
It's a little different while somebody
needs to talk to them about traumatic
brain injuries. Right. Yeah. I
think one of the things that they,
the worst things they were doing there,
they were sparring full on like day,
like two days a day before
the fight that was sparring.
Right. The day before they weigh
ends, they're sparring. So yeah,
there's some really funny
cool stories. They, they have,
well I guess you get used to it.
So there's that, but you also,
you leave a lot of your Chin in,
in the gym, you know what I mean?
There's just only so much punishment
of body can take. Yeah. Don't,
don't take it wrong. I mean
that is controlled now, but yes.
But I would say it's still more hardcore
than the average place for sure. It's,
I mean that's the,
it is so open in terms of how people
decide to structure their camps.
Some people have very little sparring.
Like cowboy was telling me,
he doesn't hear Harley's bars at all.
I mean he does just technical
work and pad work. He's like,
I already know how to fight. He wasn't
used to be completely the opposite though,
right? Yeah. I used to spar, spar,
spar, spar. I know switched it up,
but that's when he started
doing much better. He said,
he said it really made a big difference
because he was going into fights damaged
because you know he's such a,
he's so hardcore himself.
That sparring with him ultimately must
become more hardcore cause he's such a
fucking wild man.
Seller did something similar as a thing.
I think Tony Ferguson was just
no sparring. Yep. Tony had no,
no sparring in preparation
for his last fight. That's,
that's when I saw him in the post fight
interview and what makes sense about
that with him though is that he was
coming off in in catastrophic knee injury.
I mean he literally tore his ligament
off the bone and had to have it put back
on and then six months later he
was fighting. That's incredible.
This is not a whole lot of human beings
like that guy. Yeah. He's a real freak.
That level of grit determination to come
back from that injury and to perform
like he did. Yeah. That was my
favorite fight of the night. Yeah.
I really enjoyed it. I was bummed out.
The pedes hurt his hand because it isn't,
it hasn't stopped going forward. No,
he doesn't mean he never gets tired.
That's the crazy thing about Tony,
you know in Eddie Bravo does his camps
with him up in big bear and he says it's
nuts man. Every they do hill sprints,
everybody else is exhausted and,
and Tony's just lapping
them this running back up.
I mean he's just never added gas.
He,
he'll work out six hours hard a day.
And on top of that what
he does is he gets there,
they rent a house and then
he builds his own gym.
So they'll have like a
house that they rent.
He'll Matt up the living room and then
he'll go outside. I'll put up a wing,
Chung dummy, don't hang
heavy bags. He does it all.
I'm so used to do the week
check. Wts Yeah, man mean he,
he actually use wing Chung
and the fight with Pettis,
he trapped his hand and
hit him with an elbow once.
And I remember watching it going like,
Holy Shit.
He just use wind chunk inside
the cage. Like it works. Like,
if you really know your shit,
he trapped his hand and then came right
over the top with an album and I went
look at that shit cause he's always
practicing it. Yeah. You know,
he's always practicing Kung Fu,
but he's a very, very unusual guy.
Like there's all this talk about a Connor
rematch because financially that would
be a fantastic fight, right? Financially.
But when you look at what happened,
that was a dominant victory.
I mean there was one round where
Connor did pretty good the third round.
Other than that could be just
sort of dominated him. Yeah.
I mean dropped him in the second,
beat the fucking shit out of him in the
fourth and the third was around where
Connor did pretty good because
most of it was standing up.
I think he won that round. Right?
That was at the first round.
Can Be you've ever lost?
Yeah, I think there was. Yeah.
But I mean it wasn't the one it like
rotting away. It wasn't like that.
He blasted him in the body, had him
hurt and there was nothing like that.
It was just the edge. [inaudible]
it's hard to make. I mean,
I guess you could say that's the same
thing that's sort of happened in the Nate
Diaz fight and, and Connor came back and
won the rematch. So this is the argument.
The argument is Connor was Rusty's
out of the cage for two years.
He gets back in, let's do a read. And
then financially, Jesus Christ me,
it was the biggest fight of all time.
They're saying is above 2.4
million pay per view buys,
which is fucking bananas.
Yeah, that's, that's huge.
So if it's bigger than that,
and then they,
if they could talk people into a rematch,
I get it, but I don't want to see that.
I want to see Tony. I want to see
Tony Dirty. Yeah, he's earned it.
And that could be the suspension.
Let them give a little money to somebody.
What's the wha I might take on
in life for him. You know, this,
that the whole thing is fucked. It's not
professional. Right. It shouldn't happen.
But neither should people
be fucking scream and shit
at him while he's fighting.
You know? And, and I guess that
was going on the entire time.
He was apparently having,
like Dylan Dennis was in the,
in Connor's corner was screaming shit.
It could be while the fight was going on,
which I guess gets annoying.
Yeah. You said the new angle. Uh,
there's a new angle of video where
it could bebes Russian manager, um,
as,
as Connor is tapping,
he comes right behind Dennis and slaps
him on the back like three or four times.
I did see that. Yeah. Kind of instigating
something. Yeah, there's that.
And then someone said, could be a,
that Connor swung first, which is true,
but could be,
but already gone over the cage and
someone's going to guide has coming at him
and Connor swung at him, but I think it
was already chaos at that point. Yeah.
You know,
it's all very unfortunate,
but what happened really not,
no one got hurt
in any point of view down there. I
mean, did you, did you feel at all like,
oh man, this rights coming towards me or
anything like that? Did it spread around?
I am so fucking dumb. I'm so used to beat
the shit out of each other. It's like,
oh, now they're beating the shit
out of each other over here.
Feel it didn't feel any more dangerous.
I was hoping the chairs wouldn't start
flying and then it wouldn't get too crazy.
And I was really,
really,
really hoping that someone wouldn't do
something stupid and hurt someone to the
point where they would get kicked
out of the USC or suspended.
But that might be the case with that one
gentleman. What is his name? [inaudible].
What is his name? My fucking, I should
check my Instagram because it's,
it's filled with free.
Zoomba oh,
that's what the gentleman's name? Yeah.
Compared to like a training partner.
That's the guy that got fired. Yeah.
I, I'm talking about his fight with,
uh,
artists was supposed to be with Artem
and not a bad idea to cancel that fight
because it's so close to this and
obviously it's going to be so,
so charged up. Let me find homeboys. Yeah.
They just moved argument to fight
Michael Johnson, I think. Ooh. Hm. Uh,
there'll be good for, yeah, that'd
be a real good fight. Yeah. Um, yes.
You Baria they call. Yeah, seat save zoo.
But this shit's all of my Instagram. You
crazy Russians. I see what you're doing.
This like all my mentions,
the zoo Baria Aye.
Aye Co I can't pronounce his last name.
T. U. K. H. U. G. O. V. Good luck.
Good luck with that one.
Jon. Anik can pronounce it.
He prowls as it flawlessly for his
bar is a very good fighter too.
It's very unfortunate.
I hope they can work everything out.
He was supporting his brother.
He felt like there was a fight going on.
He was showing his loyalty. I get it.
There should have been more security.
They should have been better. They should
have talked to these guys beforehand.
They should have stopped all this
fucking nonsense beforehand. It's,
it's bad for the sport. It's bad for
the image. It's bad for them. It's,
it's just, you know, there's no, nothing
good about it. But to Khabib's point,
there's nothing good about Connor throw
on that Dolly at the bus. That was worse.
That was worse. Yeah. I mean,
somebody should get really fucked up.
Fights killed because people got cut,
right? Yeah. I mean, um, you know,
I mean it chaos. I got pulled from his
fight. He had a big cut on his head.
He's still dealing with injuries I
think from that. Really? Yeah, yeah,
yeah. I saw him that one of
the Bella Tours, um, in, uh,
Chicago, uh, there and he
was like, man, I still, uh,
dealing with like flash concussions or
something like that. And I dunno, it was,
it was really serious for him, for
him. I think he took the worst of it.
How did he get a concussion from
it? Don't quote me 100%. All right.
I know he had glass in his eye and I
just know that he was still dealing with
residual effects. Residual effects
for me, I'm torn because I,
I was at a conference,
it was called like the summit of greatness
and we had a bunch of people that
came over.
There was like 13 different people that
came over to our AIRBNB had a blast. Um,
there was some incredible people
there. Um, there's a guy that,
that I think you need to
know if his name's nick,
Saint Agnes Dasso and he's a guy that, uh,
that is incredibly inspirational to me.
I've gotten to know him and
he's got only one arm, no legs.
He's got one finger on one hand,
but he,
the way that he's overcome adversity
in his life. Incredible Dude. Um,
he first started with skateboarding
with one arm and doing handstands on the
skateboard. Well after that
he started doing, uh, um,
bowling and then from there he
had a little bit of an arm on,
on his left arm, sorry. Yeah,
his right arm and he wanted to wrestle,
but his parents said that he had this,
uh,
his bone was growing faster than his
skin and so on, on one of his arms.
It has like a, uh, a problem with
it. And so he wanted to wrestle,
but they said if he landed on that part
of his arm that the bone would stick
through,
it would stick through and like stabbing
to the mat and that there's no way he
could wrestle.
And he looked at his mom and dad and he
thought about it for months and he said,
mom and dad, what if we just cut it
off? Oh Jesus. And they're like, what?
And Nick says, what if you just cut off
my arm? Can, can I wrestle then you know,
my other arms gal and uh, they said, nick,
you're being pretty extreme here was,
and I call it cutting off, let's
call it an amputation and a, and no,
you can't do that.
Well,
he just kept pushing the issue there
is right there and his Instagram,
so was wound up getting it
cut off. Yup. So right there,
it used to be five or six
inches longer than that.
And he went and got it lasered off. And
what he says is that he wants a, so yeah,
buddies with the rock. Um, he's a
bodybuilder too. He just wrote a book.
It's available on Amazon. Um, I think
it's called like from victim to victor.
Yeah, I mean that, that tire flip it
on his Instagram. It's wild if, if,
if you want to pull that up. But it's,
um, he's a really inspirational guy to me.
And, uh, he like literally, so,
uh, on that top left picture, um,
he calls that on his other arm, he calls
that his potato, that's what he calls it.
Um, but he had to have five or six
inches cut off so that he could wrestle.
And a really inspirational guy to me.
He's been like,
end my let's podcasts and lose housing.
Um,
his stories there are
incredibly inspirational and
thought the Neil melanzane
story was crazy. What's
that? Yeah, he, uh,
he broke his toe real bad and uh,
they were saying you couldn't roll for
six months. He had to put in his plant.
He said, how would you just cut it off?
Wow. And they said, okay. So they did it.
You know what you've seen?
Neil Mylanta is a giant gorilla for sure.
I didn't know he did that. He says,
cut my toe off. You just go, okay,
we'll just cut you off. I've
got to train somebody. So we,
it then it's so cut off so you could
keep training. And so nick and him,
they've got some screws loose,
but they're committed.
How committed are you that you want to
achieve this goal, this dream, his dream.
He grew up in New Jersey.
He was like,
I want to be a wrestler and so I'm
going to, I'm going to do this, um,
incredibly inspirational guy.
So him and 12 other guys came over to
our airbnb and we watched the fights and
it was controversies Khabib and we loved
watching everything that night and then
whenever that happened.
Um,
so I'm torn on it because I
love those guys as fighters.
I absolutely love them as fighters.
Um,
and then whenever that happened is
just something that in me, I don't,
I don't know if I was embarrassed
where if I was disappointed,
but they were introducing some guys,
uh,
Steve Weatherford who played for the New
York giants, He came over for like a,
he played for the giants for like 10
or 12 years, um, lives in San Diego,
great guy,
but he's not a big MMA fan.
So I was explaining everything to them
and when that happened is just pretty
disappointing. Then I
spoke at, um, at, uh,
anti bullying coalition in Tulsa.
And I went there and there was a girl
there that, uh, she looked real sweet,
real quiet, introverted, um,
and she worked with mental
health and everything was alley.
All of a sudden she found out I was an
MMA fighter and she said, oh my gosh,
you know, my husband's a
huge MMA fan. I'm not at all.
I never really even sat down
and watched it with him.
But then he decided to take me to the
t mobile arena for the first fight was
Conor, Khabib and uh, she was in there.
She said she loved it before that
Michelle Waterson was an incredible
inspiration to her,
her saying that she wants to be the first
mom to be a UFC champion. She said it,
the night was going great. And then
whenever that happened, she said it was,
it literally scared her because fight
started popping off to the right over
leftover behind her. She's going to
pour, poured out into the arena. Um,
and so that was her first introduction
to May. So I was a little tough to see,
but at the same time, I get it.
Like those emotions are flaring.
And you were talking
about it too, and, uh,
kind of your perspective of
martial artists and, yeah,
I mean, same thing that,
that you were feeling. Just, you know,
that little bit of kind of sadness
and disappointment of, you know, the,
the biggest event, the most
views, the most people watching.
And that's the last thing that they
see. That's what they, you know,
go to bed thinking about and feeling
about. And, and I just, you know,
I don't think, uh, even
Keven Connor, it could be,
that's not who they are as martial
artists, you know, uh, sure.
All the emotions were flying and they,
you know, they have a history and,
and it's hard to let that
go, but I, I just don't,
I don't feel like that's
even who they really are.
You see in all their other
fights, uh, they, they respect
their opponents, you know,
she can,
um, I mean, look, Connors,
that's what he does. Yeah.
He Talk Shit to people and fucks
with their head. I mean it's,
it's a giant part of his game and I know
that that was part of the strategy of
him throwing that Dolly at the bus.
That shit's way out of line. I mean,
throwing a Dolly at the bus. That's not
what a martial artist does. When you,
when you,
if you stop and think about what we
value about martial arts and turns of
teaching children honor when we were
respect and discipline and the things,
when we think of as a classical martial
artists like Leo to Machida or something
like that, bowing to their
opponent, that is not, this is,
this is theatrical, this is
hype. But in all fairness,
the UFC used that to sell that fight.
I mean that was a big part
of their promotional campaign
was seeing Connor throw
the Dolly at the bus and the screaming
and yelling, you know, you're setting,
you're setting an exam.
There's something going on outside
of the actual content itself.
There's all this extra credit,
curricular violence, right?
There's throwing a dollar at a
bus shattering in the window.
All these guys running and screaming,
get off the bus,
and then they're promoting this,
they're showing this,
and then everyone's shocked.
Then it escalates after the fight itself.
You know, one of the, in some ways,
one of the more interesting moments of
the fight was Khabib on top of Connor
beating the shit out of him going, let's
talk now. Have you seen that video? Yeah.
That's fucking terrifying. It's
like, come on, let's talk. Bam.
And he's just slamming. I am told him
he's got to do that before the fight too.
Yeah. I mean, yeah, we're going to talk.
We're going to talk when I'm on top of
you and you're tired and I'm beating the
fuck out of you. That's what we're going
to talk. And that's what he did. You know,
this is all not what could be does,
right?
This is outside of his,
his,
if you look at his standard behavior,
he's very respectful. I mean,
he's never had an incident
like this ever in a fight.
All of his fights before that,
or him shaking his opponent's hand,
doing the standard stare down standard
stuff, talking about his skill set.
And what he's going to do and is,
no disrespect, there's no insults.
There's none of this. That's what I
mean about Khabib. Yeah, but not Connor.
I mean this is a, but, but here's
the other thing. On the other side,
it makes it fun. I'm very torn because
all the shit that he talked to, Josie,
Aldo, look, that was a big factor.
And Josie Aldo charging at him losing
his composure face first and getting clip
at that left hand.
That's a big factor is the emotional
anx that he had gone through from months
and months on the road with this
guy. The middle of warfare. Yeah.
That mental warfare is a real thing.
It just didn't work with be,
but it had the opposite effect.
And with Khabib, he's like,
I can't wait to get my fucking
hands on you. It wasn't,
I can't believe this guy's saying
these things to me with Khabib bid,
but it ramped up the violence to the
point where he was letting you know, like,
Hey, this is real to me. Like if you,
if you want to act thuggish and we'll
just keep going, we'll just, I'll you,
I'll keep taking it. Like he didn't
want to stop after Connor tapped,
like he was holding onto him and he's
letting them know, hey motherfucker,
like this is real. This is not just
shit talking. Connor was saying to him,
this is just business. It's just
business. And he's like, let's talk now.
Let's talk now. Like he, he's
like, this is not business to him.
So to him fights, I mean this is
what he said in the press conference.
It should be, this is a respect
sport and this should just,
sports should be about two men expressing
themselves to the best of their
physical ability inside of the cage,
just doing their best against
the best fighters in the world.
And that should speak for itself and
that they should have respect and honor
outside of it. I wish you would've had
the chance to say that, you know? Yeah.
We didn't have a chance.
The sad part was him letting the emotions
take over what he felt and instead of
just getting the belt tied on and kind
of killing them with kindness at the end
and saying that and having that chance
to put that in everyone's minds.
And he did in the post fight interview.
But I mean how many or the
post fight press conference,
but how many people got a
chance to see that? A lot less.
I mean just a few thousand I'm sure.
And as in comparison to the 2.4 million,
the download, the paper view in the many,
many, many, many more that saw the youtube
clips and Instagram's pips and yeah,
I mean everybody saw it.
It's,
it's unfortunate but it's
also a financial windfall.
Like it's the whole thing.
It's weird because part of what makes
Connor so interesting is that he's so good
at talking shit. He's hilarious
and he knows how to back it up.
But when we saw him fight
Khabib, he just, he fell short.
But it's really that simple
when skill versus skill.
He fell short and the the,
the shit talking led to could be being
v taking it very personal and very
personal at the end and
then pointing at Dillon,
Dennis and jumping off the top of
the cage. The whole thing was just,
it's so fucking crazy.
But the idea that people should be
surprised after Conor throws it,
Dolly at the bus and then still
winds up able to fight. I mean,
what did he do? Paid some money. Did
some, I mean we've got to do some,
some service.
What does he does community service.
I don't even know what he has to do.
I don't either.
If there was something that's where
it's not, yeah, it's Kinda crazy.
Throwing a Dolly is fucking way worse
than punching a guy who punches people for
a living, which is done. Dennis
is a professional fighter.
He's a professional fight. He jumps
out, he takes a swing at them,
they're screaming. He and Dylan is
like, fuck you. And he's like, fuck you.
And there's a bunch of people get involved
and then a bunch of other people jump
in.
The whole thing was nuts.
But the idea that we should be shocked
after him throwing a Dolly at a bus
because Khabib's on the bus.
That should,
those Russians don't
fucking play like that,
Matt.
This is videos afterwards when Dagestan
where they're shooting uzis and AK 47.
So I wrestled there, uh, when I was like
18, um, wrestled there and it was crazy.
They were taking us around everywhere
in g wagons and the ones in front of us
had like armed, uh, I don't know,
machine guns on top of them.
The one behind us are machine guns on top
of them. And then what was it? We were,
we were walking through one of the streets
and there's these big chains that are
in between the road and the sidewalk and
we're walking down the sidewalk and all
of a sudden there's like a laser that
comes over and, uh, and our guys are like,
we gotta go, we gotta go. All of a
sudden a car came up onto the sidewalk,
started driving like they're
going to play us down.
We had to jump into the road
to not get hit. And uh, I,
I don't know why that happened,
but after that we weren't allowed are uh,
the hotel we were in, we
had like balconies to where
we could look out, well,
they had to move our rooms to where
we're inside to where we couldn't have a
balcony and everything else to where the
[inaudible] just because of that threat,
because of the laser that came because
of the truck that came up onto the
sidewalk and tried to run us over.
There was some crazy rumors
that someone got arrested outside
of the, uh, t mobile arena.
See if that's true. If
someone got arrested, a gun
outside the t mobile arena on after
the fight or during the fight,
because it was, there was some
sort of crazy talk about threats.
The problem is you don't know how much
of that's bullshit, you know? I mean,
I probably should have researched
that before we talked about it.
But you see anything bullshit out of,
did they,
they post that
I heard the same thing that I heard.
Yeah. Yeah. Uh, yeah. I think I
heard it on Instagram. But yeah,
they don't play around.
It's a different world, man.
Especially Dagestan that's
all hard part of the country.
Not the Dublin isn't hard,
but it's like that.
They're not known for their,
uh, humor and shit. Dot.
Yeah. Well, I, well, I went into a store,
I went into a store,
like a little market and I was whistling
and dog is done and I didn't know that
that was something disrespectful,
but someone came right up behind me and
just slapped me on the back of the head.
Like, Whoa, hold on. I'd probably
like, it can be just dead. Came up.
And I knew that he was a bad dude,
so I wasn't gonna do anything.
I just didn't know translator
had to come up and say,
you don't whistle in public, you
know, Oh, you're having a good day,
please. Disrespectful. Then I can't
even whistle that good. But, uh,
but I was just kind of
whistling to myself.
I didn't even know I was doing air
guitar. Yeah, that's probably bad.
It's probably that they don't show the
bottom of your feet. Like if you, uh,
that's for sure you can Google that.
But if you are sitting there and you
like cross your legs and you show the
bottom of your foot, that's culturally
really disrespectful to show, um,
the bottoms of your shoes
or the bottom of your feet.
So they just don't play around there.
Um, and then so, so if you have your,
like your foot on top of your thigh
like this, don't do that. Don't do that.
Someone would come and slap your leg and
you make sure your feet are both on the
ground. So just a lot of
cultural stuff, world.
That's why they're so tough. He's
climbing up those mountains. I mean,
it's just jagged mountains.
I remember it was one of the most
beautiful places I've ever been.
I'm just stunning. But just the, the hard
life. Did you see that? A Nike or, sorry,
not Nike, but Reebok video that could
be did. It was, it was awesome. Yeah,
it was awesome. But just seeing that
that's, that's the real life there. It's,
there's a photo of him that he posted
on his Instagram with his father,
him and his father.
He right after the fight,
he did it like to explain like that this,
this what this is about to him.
His honor,
it's not about money.
It's about honor and respect and it's
a photo of him standing with his father
with this incredible mountain range
behind him. Wow. Yeah. It's a,
it's a different part of the world. So
that, that strategy with Connor backfired.
But you think there's a point
where, uh, you know, just,
that's incredible. What a photo
that they should say. Hey,
let's, let's turn the, the talking down
a little bit. How can you, that's what,
that's what got Connor to the dance.
I mean,
it's one of the reasons
why it has escalated.
It has escalated since all do to
then Mayweather bringing in his dad
and the assaults and
different stuff like that.
And then could be going after his
family religion. Anything else? Yeah,
so it's gotten,
it's almost like he has to,
I think you were saying this
got one up on himself. You know,
for me it just kind of felt like,
you know, it wasn't a surprise.
It was kind of like the Karma for the
UFC promoting the bus and you know,
and and letting it just keep
getting deeper and deeper. You know,
say it's the story and it is the story,
but at a certain point if it's something
that was illegal, hurt somebody,
maybe you don't use that.
I was really shocked that they were
using it and promotion. I was like, wow,
I shouldn't be shocked. I thought that
when I saw the promo and I saw the, the,
the,
the Dolly flying at the bus and then
the video from the inside with the glass
shattering, I was like,
okay, I guess I shouldn't be
shocked because it did happen.
You know, it is a part of the
story, but I mean is this,
is this encouraging this like what is,
I mean they're using it to sell the
biggest fight in the history of the sport
turned out to be true. It is the biggest
fight in the history of the sport.
Is that good? That doesn't
seem good. It seems,
it seems from my perspective
it's entertainment versus sport,
right?
When when it comes to sport,
like you would never use that to,
to advertise the Olympics. Right? Right.
They would never have an assault
to advertise the Olympics.
But this is something different. It's
commerce, there's a lot of money involved.
It's a,
it's a huge cultural spectical
it's Conor McGregor who's,
he transcends sport.
He's this superstar in just the
world of just show business.
So it's different but different.
But at the same time, what,
this might be more for the
purest or hardcore MMA fan or,
or martial artists that
competes, but, but what,
what originally drew you to
the martial arts? I mean,
I haven't heard that first hand from you,
but,
but what drew you to the
sport initially? Well, I mean,
like Raphael, I've found out about
Bruce Lee when I was a kid. I mean,
Bruce Lee was the first,
I saw those Bruce Lee movies.
I lived in New Jersey and an apartment
complex. And My, uh, my superintendent,
the apartment complex [inaudible], his
son was my age and I went over his house.
We watching a Bruce Lee movie. I
was like, Holy Shit, look at this.
And they ha he kid had nun chucks and
she had a whacked myself on the back of
head trying to practice doing checks.
But I remember watching that
guy throw kicks and you know,
jumping off of tables and beating the fuck
out of all these dudes are coming out.
And every kid wanted to be Bruce Lee.
Every kid wanted to be Bruce Lee.
And then I took food class and then I
took karate and then I got into taekwondo
and then I got into my time and
all these other different things.
But to me it was just martial
arts was, um, you know, it was,
it was a way to learn how to
fight, first of all, for sure.
But then it was also a way to
test yourself. But it was always,
there was no shit talking back then and
martial arts tournaments, it was node,
there was no trash talking.
Even if there was like little subtle
things that people would say to each other
at the way in under each other's breath,
like I'm gonna fuck you up.
Or something like that was very
quiet and it was very little of that.
Most of it was a bowing,
you know,
shaking hands and then there was the cyst,
the fight,
but there was also no money involved.
It was just fighting, you know?
And I think that when you're dealing
with money and you're dealing with
promotion, let's, let's just
be completely honest, con it,
throwing that Dolly at the bus and Connor
talk and all that shit probably made
that fight twice as big. Maybe you
would've got 1 million pay per view buys.
They want them getting two
and a half million. It's
worth a lot of fucking money.
Think about two and a half million versus
what one extra million people buying
it at whatever the fuck it cost.
What does it cost?
70 bucks or something or is it
64 99 it's a lot of money, man.
Talking about a law, a lot
of money, you know, and then
it's worth more for other fights
because the whole card was so amazing.
It's going to get more people
to is your favorite card?
Favorite moment of the night? It
was a Derrick Lewis, Derrick Lewis,
Tony Derrick Lewis,
Derrick Lewis,
winning by knockout and in a fight where
he said that thing about Derrick Lewis
is he can always just land one punch.
We had just got done saying that like
10 seconds before he lands his fucking
Howitzer on the top of that dude's head.
And then the post fight interview,
we say he takes his shorts off and I'm
standing here, what are you doing man?
It goes, my balls is
hot. I'm like, oh my God.
But I always knew Derek is hilarious.
He's always hilarious.
So I always look forward to
talking to him. But his Instagram,
if you want to know what
Derrick Lewis is about,
you've got to go see his Instagram and
I brought that up and now he's got like,
he's got a million more than a million.
What does he at now?
500 some thousand and just
a couple of days after that.
That's so awesome,
but it's true.
It's fucking Instagram is all motorcycle
accidents do the jumping off roofs and
landed on their heads. It's a false
fucked up Instagram of all time,
but he's just a funny dude,
man.
He's really funny and him and Daniel
Cormier like them promoting a fight is
going to be a breath of fresh air because
like did you see the thing where you
know like Danny was joking around? He
said, he said, he's going to knock me out.
He's like, yeah man, you was
disrespect and Popeye's fried chicken.
Let's play this because it's so funny.
Derrick Lewis told me that he was going
to knock me out right before we walked
Derek music.
What's your issue with Daniel?
I want to know too
this suspect that Popeye's chicken on it.
This is a bad version of it.
I bet
this is all music and stupid editing,
but he's just a funny guy,
man.
He's just a funny guy and he's look,
I mean,
and he joked around about it with DC. He's
like, you at 1.3 million followers now.
That is hilarious.
You just gained a million followers
because I've been following him for years
now. Yeah, I think he gained a
million followers and he, you know,
they were talking about it and he said
to Daniel, you know, uh, Dennis said,
he goes, you want it, you don't really
want to hit me. He goes, no, fuck off.
Fight anybody for money.
It's just classic.
He's just a funny guy and there won't
be any of that do opening nonsense,
but it'll still sell a lot because
it's fun. So a lot of Popeye's too,
it's going to sell a lot and it's
going to sell out of everything,
but it'll definitely sell a lot of
paper views. The real question is,
is he going to be able to deal with
Cormier's wrestling coronaries experiment.
This is the level of fighting
that Columbia is experience
is just significantly
higher.
But Derrick Lewis has unbelievable power.
I mean his power,
his fucking no joke man.
If you look at some of his Kao victories,
he's a brutal puncher. Brutal. He is.
But I think if he and I,
I'm a big Derrick Lewis Fan,
but I think if he fights DC like he fought
Volkov it's going to be a tough night
for him. Um, I know that,
I know that it could go anyway and that
one shot from Derrick Lewis can put DC
out or anyone in the world out.
But I just see dcs wrestling has,
is dirty boxing. I mean
everything. If, if you, if,
if Derrick Lewis is
turning his back to DC,
like he wasn't Volkov and he's
going to close the distance,
he's going to take his back.
He's going to exploit that.
He's going to take them down.
Sure. There's a difference
between six foot seven,
five foot 10 though.
It's true.
There's a giant difference in
size between Volkov and DC.
DC's a real light heavyweight who in my
opinion could fight and Raphael's weight
class. I mean, I think DC
really got his diet in order.
He can be a one 80 to fiber.
It's true, but it can flip over.
Josh Barnett over his head,
all sorts of guys.
There's something about that
that round body tight though.
I mean there really is like
a barrel, the, you know,
the ability to kind of be
ungrabbable you know, and uh,
of course he has the power and he
has the wrestling. So I mean, uh,
he's like a version of feed or you
know. Right. Very similar, very similar.
Seen him knockout Steve Bay with one shot.
Like that was stunning. It's like wow.
And he was saying that he
was doing that in training.
He said he hits way
harder as a heavyweight.
I think just the way he likes to live
his life and how he likes to eat.
He just has more energy as a heavyweight.
He might be a better sound through a whole
life of cutting weight and the entire
life of it. And uh, how to
withdraw from the Olympics.
Because if kidney failure
from weight cutting,
his life should be a movie for sure. I
mean the way the stuff that he's overcome,
this stuff that has happened to them,
the missed opportunities and
wrestling and not miss opportunities.
He was one of the, I mean he's so
great. Yeah. But not being the champion,
that being the world champion up being
the Olympic champion and then coming to
in the life stuff that he's gone through.
Um,
I'm just happy that people like him now
cause you remember he was getting booed
for so long. She was repeating every
time he got booed. I like broke my heart.
It took a while for people to understand
him and now I think that people,
you know,
after people seeing him choke out rumble
Johnson and then seeing him knock out
steep a people are like, oh he's a bad
motherfucker. And he's a really nice guy.
He's a great dude. One of the best
commentators now. He's hilarious. Yeah.
That's also what made him
grow on people as well.
Like you hear him and commentary and
you realize like he's not an EGOMANIAC.
He's a really good guy who
knows a lot about fighting,
knows a lot about wrestling and I'm a man.
I'm so looking forward to John Jones
coming back to John Jones Fighting
Gustafson. That is very
fascinating. Is that going to a,
I know they're going to strip DC, so is
that, is that fight for a title or, yeah,
I guess interim or the real deal. I
think that's the real deal deal. Yeah.
Which is weird,
right?
Like why let the guy be champ champ
if you're not going to let them.
I mean I dunno. It's like, I don't know.
I mean I'm a time,
I'm so torn on all this,
but he's probably going to fight the
winter anyways and then it will be for the
belt. So maybe let them keep the
belt. I mean look, I love the UFC.
Obviously I've been working
for the UFC forever,
but I think there is an obvious conflict
of interest when the promoter is also
responsible for who holds titles
and who gets to fight for titles.
It's weird, you know, I mean,
in every other sport there's like a
sanctioning body that decides this is,
you know,
Rafael Lovato one five fights in a row.
He's the undisputed number one contender.
He will be next in line for the title,
you know, not, oh Logan Paul's.
So 5 million youtube buys these next.
You know what I mean? It's like,
it's weird, like it's,
it's weird that commerce,
I mean it plays a giant part in any sport,
right?
But should it be the
ultimate decider in what,
what happens and what doesn't happen?
Would you ever support the Mohammad
Ali act coming over to MMA?
I don't know exactly how that act
is structured. What does, what does,
what does it say? I don't know a
lot about it, but I know that, um,
I believe the moment of
the fill it up so we can,
we can talk about it from an
educated perspective for sure.
I think that the promoters have to split
50% of the revenue with the fighters,
I think. Is that what it says? I think
so. Um, I think, uh, that is part of it.
They would start doing
that Hollywood arithmetic,
like Hollywood of arithmetic,
like when when a movie comes out.
Do you know how that works?
Dude? It's hilarious.
When they people who have written movies
and produce movies and so and and dealt
with with studios,
they factor in all this other shit
like this is how much my car costs.
This is how much it costs for gas.
This is how much it costs to rent this
building. This is electricity. Oh,
there's no more money leftover.
Okay. Here it says the Ali Act,
many professional boxing safety act
of 1996 specifies that a sanctioning
organization may not receive
any compensation from a
boxing mass match unless it
files its bylaws and a complete
description of its ratings criteria,
policies, and general sanctioning
fee schedule with the FTC.
The further directs the FTC to make this
information available to the public.
A sanctioning organization does not have
to submit this information to the FTC.
However,
it makes the information accessible
through a public website or if you can
translate that. I don't know
what the fuck. I don't know
if I've heard that part,
which I'm not sure that that's
specific. The splitting the revenue. Um,
but then I also think it takes
out of the promoters hands.
What does that center look at?
Where it says law 15 us and what does
that fucking double squiggle shit?
What is that? I'd never seen that thing
before. They ever seen that thing before?
Have you seen it? You've seen it
yet. I mean in this context. Yeah.
I've never seen that thing before.
That's what, that's what the law is.
I mean like a dollar bill thing.
Like that's like, like a law.
That's a symbol for a lot. Have you
seen happen? I think so. There's a,
there's a law that, um, fight for the
forgotten has been looking into, um,
for bullying prevention. Uh, it's
called David's law at a Texas and that,
that same squiggly thing that
didn't even show up on Google.
He just googled it and it didn't show up.
Look at that.
Did Not match any documents.
So, uh, okay. Whatever that is.
I mean, I guess that's a la
thing. I'm, look, I'm always,
I always favor the fighters always because
they have a very short amount of time
to do it. They put the most on the
line. They have the most at risk,
the consequences of their
actions or you know,
in terms of losing in terms of,
um,
just the,
the possibility that get horribly injured
in training and not get compensated.
There's all sorts,
there's a bunch of factors that I
don't feel are fair or just like,
I was very upset when Tony,
when Tony Ferguson got
stripped mean he fell,
he ripped his knee apart and
they stripped him. I mean, look,
I get that there'd be upset that
the fight would happen. Uh, the,
the fight would not happen
and that he would, you know,
someone else would have to take his place.
I understand that.
But stripping them doesn't make any sense.
Like how could you get
stripped for an injury?
It's one thing if he did something to
someone like the John Jones situation
crashing, don't lady's car took off
from the scene. That makes sense.
It's an ethics violation, right? This is
not an ethics thing. He fell, you know,
it's unfortunate promote the fight and
it's tripped over some wires and uh,
it was erroneously stated by many people,
me included,
cause I read it somewhere that
he was wearing sunglasses,
it was not wearing sunglasses inside.
He was just wearing glasses,
just stepped over. So it was just a
freak thing, man. Just a freak thing.
Stepped over some wires and especially
a guy as coordinated. Again,
fucking crazy. Didn't make any sense.
Yeah. Crazy. I mean it's horrible,
but there's no, no one
to say no to that. Right.
It's like how does that work?
How do you decide?
Like how do you decide who
gets stripped and who doesn't?
Who's got an interim title mean?
How many interim titles can you have?
It's just like this.
Yeah,
it's just weird just for the rankings
and the ability to get your shot,
you know,
just that by itself I think deserves
a sanctioning body 100% let alone the
ability for them to get paid
more and be more, you know,
fair across the board and everything.
Well you see how like you,
Sada has completely taken away.
Like the UFC has nothing to say about
you sought a testing and about the
punishment that it implements.
It's completely independent.
So what they do is they come in,
they randomly drug test fighters,
they make sure the fighters give
their whereabouts at all times.
They have to register and log in
and let everybody know wherever,
wherever they are.
And if they violate that you
sought a hands out the punishment.
And we've seen these
punishments and they're strict.
They're very severe and they,
they,
they take away a fighter's ability to
make an a living if they violate any of
their policies or if they test
positive for any supplements.
They've since made a, what I think
is a welcome amendment where, um, if,
if if a fighter,
if it's possible that it's a tainted
supplement or they have a trace amount of
something in, in there, they don't say
anything until after it's resolved.
So instead of like putting the fighter
on blast and putting it out there to the
whole world, hey, this guy
tested positive. Instead of
doing that, they resolve it.
And then smart. Yeah. Which
is the way they should do it,
but still look at a guy like Josh Barnett.
Okay.
Josh Barnett was ultimately exonerated,
but he had to go like two years
where he couldn't make a living.
And when your John is 40 years old,
this, that's fuck two years of spare,
you don't have two years. Yeah,
right. That's fucking crazy. So,
but my point is that is a
completely independent entity,
right? It's outside of the UFC. His
ability to, they don't control that.
They stepped back, they take care
of it. Kindness should be that way.
And when it comes to who gets to fight
for the title, but if a title is a title,
like if it's,
if it's the world championship and you
look at a guy like Tony Ferguson, I think,
I believe he's 11 and one in the UFC,
right?
He's on this crazy win streak. He's
fucking beaten. You look at his,
his like, who's who of who?
He's beaten crazy. Domino's.
Kevin Leisurely. No one else. For him
to fight, he has to fight for you.
Speeding the elites. Oh, the only person
he hasn't beaten is Connor and could be,
those are the two guys. Fuck man. Yeah.
You got to slip. If you looked at
it that way, you'd say he's next.
But if you are mister money bags,
Connor wants a rematch.
Oh, Connor, let's give you
a rematch. Come on to me.
The area where the sport and
entertainment crosses, right.
What do you think about tournament's
coming back to the OCR or,
I mean they haven't done that,
but what do you think about them
doing that for finding out who's going
to fight for the title Bella towards
doing it now? PFLS been doing it.
My Buddy Josh Copeland just made it too.
He was ranked eighth seed came in and
fought two times one night and uh,
and Vinny Mag and nice as well.
Yeah.
And that was a awesome triangle
to beautiful submission.
He's like one of the most
underappreciated guys in MMA, you know,
because one of the few that can
jump guard and you're fuck man,
that guy wrapped his legs around you.
He just had a rocky start
because his striking Rosenthal,
but now it is mean. He's head kicking
people and knocking them out. Did you see,
did you see Josh Copeland's a
knockout, a heavyweight? Uh,
it was one of the best
knockouts, heavyweight in
the long time. No, I didn't.
A lot of time. It's on my Instagram.
If you're able to pull that up, Jamie.
It's a police. It's, um, on my
Instagram and it was awesome.
He got the deepest cut,
one of the deepest cuts
I've ever seen in my life.
He could see a skull and it went, it
went farther than his eyebrow. And uh,
he got cut probably five seconds
before he gets the knockout punch.
And if he wouldn't have got that,
they would have stopped.
It came in ranked eighth seed.
Now he's going into new New York City,
Madison Square Gardens in New Year's Eve,
um, and fighting for $1 million.
How does this work? How does,
what does the million dollars,
what does that mean?
Like there's every weight class when a
million, I believe that they have 10,
they're giving away 10 million.
So at least 10 weight classes. Um,
I think for the women to, they air on
NBC, NBC sports, NBC sports. So it's like,
uh, one of the cable channels.
Right. And then, uh, for Josh, they,
they just fought in New Orleans and he
had a fight, a two round fight first.
And then he followed me around too,
cause they wouldn't allow you then the
state commission wouldn't life height
more than five rounds in one night.
And so the first round or first fight,
um, first part of the tournament was a
two round fight and he had to fight the
number one seed and he beat
him. And then an hour later, uh,
he had to fight again. Here's Josh.
It was just a brutal knockout,
but he got cut right over the eye.
And then right here he just, Oh damn.
Oof Dam. One of the, one of the
best knockouts I've seen in a while.
But it's a ton.
He looks way thicker than when
he was fighting in the UFC.
He's really gotten his nutrition under,
but if you can see that cut or his,
I mean, it was brutal. Um, Bas Rutten was
interviewed afterwards. He's like, Josh,
I can see your skull. Right. That's
a haymaker of a right hand hold.
My Shit was chasing
him. Yup. I mean, yeah,
he looks much better physically than
he did when he was fighting in the UFC.
Yeah. He's been working his butt
off. He's earned it. And uh,
now he gets a fight for $1 million,
which he training down with you
guys in Oklahoma. He, he isn't. Um,
whenever I am in Camp Hill come down
for like two weeks before my fight.
It's a super nice guy. Super Fun guy.
He really seems like a really nice guy.
I've met him before, but I
don't know if you know, he's a,
he's a nine time competitive rocky
mountain oyster eating champion Colorado,
which by the way is bull testicles.
Yup. People that don't know,
he's the only guy I've been with that uh,
we go to.
So have you ever heard of the Big
Texan, the 72 ounce steak? The large,
this is an Amarillo 72 ounce steak.
You'd have to eat in an hour.
You have to pay for it. 72 ounce
steak, huge, large baked potato,
loaded a dinner salad, shrimp
cocktail, huge dinner roll.
You have to drink a 72 ounce soda with
it and man the diets on or does it have
to be a regular side? I don't
know. Yeah, that's preposterous.
The man versus food guy barely
finished it. Barely finished it.
Members of food. Uh, I think
it was like 58 59 minutes,
something like that Josh did in 32
minutes. I think it was the fastest.
That's never been done. Fucking cry.
And then, and then you get this.
So have y'all ever seen the
endless shrimp at red lobster?
So Josh went to red lobster
in the shrimp and uh,
and he asked them what was the most
someone's ever eaten and shrimp and he had
already eaten a bunch of Iga.
He always says,
you don't go to red lobster and not
start off with the cheddar biscuits.
You know,
you have to eat those.
You had like three or four of
those are whole basket of them.
And then the lady said,
I think the most anyone's ever eaten was,
I think it was two 26 226 shrimp
and,
and Josh,
226 like of the like coconut or
fried shrimp, whatever it is.
And Josh is like, there's my mark. That's
what I'm going to do. Um, or that's me,
that's my goal kind of cows.
And the guy told us food stories all
night that he's rolling and he's got like
four or five restaurants.
He's literally not allowed in
public or like it's not a joke. So,
so Josh gets, he gets to like two 50 and
they're like, okay, you broke the record.
And he's like, no, I'm still hungry.
And so he gets to 300 he
gets the 300 300 shrimp.
He ends at 400 and calls,
it goes 400 shrimp and calls it
good to put it on like a cube.
If you have like a box 400 fried
shrimp in it. I don't know.
He smelled like garlic for three days
afterwards then. Then we went to, I dunno,
I'm going into all the stores.
We went into an all,
you can eat crab restaurant
or sorry he did. And uh,
it was all you can eat crab legs and
he's just ordering bucket after bucket
after bucket of, of crab legs. And they
come over and finally said this, sir,
there's gotta be a limit somewhere.
And so they ask you to leave.
I have to ask you to leave so he can eat.
But now he's gotten his diet
under control and everything else.
Whenever it came to grudge,
whenever I got off the ultimate fighter,
he came in at over 350 pounds. I think
it was three 56 or maybe it's three 46,
something like that. I think he
walks around at like two 45 to 50.
He looks a lot slimmer,
but he also looks thicker looking
at shoulders and the chest.
He's been working with Lauren Landau,
who most of the great guy that Brendan
worked with. And I was in Colorado.
It was in Colorado. So he's trained
with elevation and a and m. Oh,
uh, man. Why am I forgetting the main
place that he trains that? Um, but,
uh, Ryan, anyways, uh,
trials, MMA and, uh,
Fort Collins is where it's
training mainly. And uh,
but I'm just so stoked for
million dollar tournament,
Bella Tours doing the million
dollar tournament now. Um,
I think it'd be something, I don't know.
What is 50 cent? Half to do with Bellator?
He's like offering all the championing.
Yeah, he's, he's talking to Khabib now.
What does he do with bell toward,
does he have,
I think he's helping them promote it. Um,
I actually, I'm still, um, where you are.
I'm like, what does he have to
do with this? But he's seeing,
he's promoting his champagne money.
His is on the,
on the canvas and on one of
the cancers on champagne. Yup.
And so he's giving everyone in the
champagne after they win their fights and
stuff like that. And so it's a strange
combination to him. 50 cent and,
and he keeps saying he wants
a fight. People too. Yeah.
What's going on with that? I Dunno,
but if you support and Bella to her,
I don't know. There we go. I'm
not necessarily against it,
but I don't know what's going on.
Do you think he's actually going
to fight someone or is it just,
it seems like it's all just a lot of
fun. Yeah, I think it's fun. It's fun.
It's fun. I think it's for
promotion of this new champagne.
Do you enjoy working for
them? Yes, I do very much.
It seems like a great organization and
everybody that I know that went over
there really.
Yeah, super pro professional. Uh,
everyone's really friendly and a
lot of it is a great guy. Yeah.
A lot of Jujitsu guys on the staff too.
So I like to feel that love.
And it was funny the last
time, um, you know, Changi,
he's always in my corner
and um, uh, you know,
one was in Chicago, a
rich, rich chow who's also,
I hope I said his last
name right. Um, who's also,
I think it might be Joe. He trains
Jujitsu and, and Shawn g was like,
hey, the matchmaker for belts.
Yes. Taken us to Hawaii next. Yeah.
And they've met before. And Johnny's like,
Hey, did you bring your g let's roll.
You know, let's, let's go train. And
we said, oh, no, I don't have Maggie.
I'm too busy. He's got a lot of
things going on. Well in, um,
in Idaho for the last one,
uh,
rich had his key and he was totally ready
for Shawn Gee, this time. And a man,
they ended up training like probably,
I think they did at least two,
maybe three sessions. And each time was
like an hour or over an hour straight.
And, um, you know, uh,
they had a lot of fun and Richard was like
ready for ready for it. And he's like,
how am I [inaudible] next day he's
texted Changi. I'm ready. Let's go again.
You know? Yeah. It's so, so
cool to see him and Solow. Well,
tell everybody who you know,
solve who barrow and Changi or just to
elite Brazilian Jiu Jitsu black belts.
And they're down in San
Diego. Yeah. They're from the
Amazon, from announce. Um,
Saul was a six time world champion.
Uh, he's the older brother, uh,
[inaudible] seven time world champion,
two time absolute world champion.
He's the greatest heavyweight that ever
has ever been in Brazilian Jujitsu. Um,
it's a really cool story.
Uh, I was 19 years old.
I was a brown belt and I competed
in my first professional event.
Uh, it was a nogi pro tournament. Um,
and Ohio is the part of the
Arnold classic event that goes on,
uh, with, uh, the bodybuilding
and all that. They had a,
a Jujitsu competition and they
had a pro Nogi tournament.
It was only three weight classes.
It's like a lightweight,
a middleweight and heavyweight.
And it,
at that time it was like the biggest Nogi
tournament that there was besides for
ADCC. And a lot of the ADCC
champions would do that event, um,
to win the money of course. And then
also just kind of prepare for ATCC, uh,
later in the year. And I
knew Saul, he had, um, uh,
his home base has affiliations,
uh,
associates association schools
where we're at in the beginning, um,
in that area of the country in Ohio.
And he always competed at that tournament,
so to Changi. And so I knew there was
a great chance that, uh, you know,
all we get a chance to face
Solow going into that event.
And I had to send my resume in to, to,
to get accepted into the pro tournament.
And I'll never forget the email
they send me where it was like,
you've been accepted. Congratulation Saul.
He Beto was in your division. Good luck,
you know, and how am I, okay. Uh,
how awesome. I'm already thinking,
how awesome would it be to have a
mattress? Sol, I'm 19 years old.
Saw was already six time world
champion, a legend already. Um,
and so, you know, go to the tournament
and sure enough it was destiny man.
Uh, we're on opposite sides
of the bracket and you know,
he clears out his side, gets
the finals, no problem. Um,
and I find my way to the finals.
I had four matches and actually in the
semifinals I ended up going against one
of his black belts. Um, and it was the
first time I ever faced a black belt.
At that time there wasn't a whole bunch
of Gnocchi opportunities, you know,
where you could be a non black
belt and fight a black belt. Um,
and I was losing on points and
at the end I started coming back.
And I was able to submit,
uh,
his black belt and go to the finals and
his black belt kind of threw a fit and,
um, was pretty disappointed.
Uh, wouldn't shake my hand,
wasn't there when the referee was raised
her hand and I could feel all this
energy because it was kind of,
I think everyone thought they were going
to close it out together, you know?
And uh, and they do that
though. Would they fight it out?
Every tournament is
different. Oh Wow. Yeah.
It probably bowel out and then
they would share the prize money.
There was a substantial
prize money for first place.
I think it was like five grand
and second place was like 1500,
something like that. Uh, it was the
first time I got paid to compete.
Like I w I ever won money.
I was super pumped, but um,
yeah, so, you know,
I'm going into the finals against Saul
and I just beat one of his black belts
and I was just like, whoa. I was
so nervous, so scared, you know?
But it's an absolute legend. Yeah. And
I'm 19, I'm a brown. And it, you know,
it wasn't like today where you see all
these legends and these world champions
all the time. Like at that time
they were all in Brazil, you know,
and so it was hard to see this guy.
He's like,
the only time you saw him as if were in
Brazil and they were still very, like,
they had this mystique about them and you
know, it, it was just a different vibe.
There were way more scary, I guess you
could say, way more intimidating, um,
back then. So I was definitely
super intimidated, but you know,
at the same time I was fired up, you
know, I want to be a world champion.
I get to face, you know, a
legend and, um, let's go.
And so we had a good match.
Uh,
I was able to last for a
good amount of time, but, uh,
he eventually passed my guard, mounted
me and submitted me at the very end. And,
uh, you know, I wasn't disappointed. I
was happy. It was like, man, you know,
this was the first time I got to face
someone like that. And I did my best.
I was able to keep my guard for a while.
So I was, I was proud of that. Um,
but at the same time, you know, he, he
mounted me, tapped me and, and you know,
that's what he was supposed to
do, you know. Um, but he, uh,
he was so nice to me afterwards,
give me a big hug and we talked and um,
and that was kind of that at that moment,
but I felt like I had earned his,
his respect. You know, fast
forward a few months later,
I'm in Brazil and at that time
there was two world tournaments.
There was a second organization,
um, called the CB and, oh,
so there was the CBG J and then there
was a CBG J oh. And they were paying,
there was a world championships
that were paying, um,
Nova Uniao kind of created that event.
They separated,
didn't want to support the original a
world championships and they made their
own world championships and a,
and they were paying and that was the
way they could get a lot of guys to come
over and support that tournament. And
it was big. It was pretty much the same.
It was basically the same thing.
There was only a couple of teams
that didn't support that tournament.
And at the same time,
there was a couple teams that competed
that tournament that didn't support the
original worlds. So depending on
what division you were fought in,
it was either exactly the same
or it was tougher, you know,
especially in the
lightweights because Nova,
Ya'll had all the best lightweights at
that time. And so I'm at that event,
I competed there and Solow
wasn't competing that year.
And so he was very approachable.
He wasn't fighting,
he was just coaching and uh, and I
competed, I was a brown belt still.
And I come over and I say,
what's up to solo? And uh,
oh. He's like, hey my brother,
good to see you. [inaudible] how
you doing? Uh, and he's like,
where are you training? And tell him
where I'm training. He's like, well,
you want to come train with me? So
yeah, I would love to. And he was like,
here's my card. Give me a call on Monday.
I'll come pick you up. Sure enough,
a column. He comes to my
hotel, him and Shawn Gee,
they pick me in a couple of my friends up.
They drive me all the way to Copa Cobana
we were staying in Baja and we go and
train and a man,
like just seeing the way he
interacted with his guys, the energy,
the way I felt there. Um,
you know, at this time there
was, there was a lot of the,
you know,
how do I put it?
Like there was a resilience and
then you're a Gringo, you know. Uh,
it was,
it was hard to go to Brazil and like learn
a lot and have someone really kind of
open up and, and, and help you and
show you and teach you a lot. I mean,
Eddie would know,
I'm sure you've heard the stories.
I remember being in Brazil with Eddie
long time ago, um, at back in the day,
uh, you know, you just, especially if they
felt like you were a threat, you know,
they wouldn't show you a lot because what
a few minutes of fighting one of their
buddies.
But you know what I mean?
And so this was the first time
that I wasn't treated that way.
And you know,
Salo in Sean's,
he really opened up and
was like, you know, um, uh,
bringing me sort of into their family
right away. Do you speak Portuguese?
I'm not a hundred percent fluent,
but I'm pretty good. You know,
I can go to Brazil and,
and do whatever, you know,
I need to do and be on my own and be fine.
Um,
at that time my Portuguese wasn't
as good as what it is today.
Did you take classes or the next year?
Actually,
the year after this in 2004, I
lived in Brazil for four months. Um,
and that's when I really got
pretty good at Portuguese. But, um,
you know, anyways, he was open
to answering my questions.
He was teaching me stuff and,
and we trained,
I trained there all week in between
the time from the first worlds into the
other, the main worlds. Um,
and I just kind of knew,
like immediately, like, man, this
is, this is what I want, you know,
and it was the first time
I ever had someone of that
level be open to helping me
and taking me under his wing.
And so we stayed in touch. Uh,
shortly after that trip to
Brazil, he came out and, uh,
to Oklahoma and taught a
seminar at my dad's school.
That time my dad was running the academy.
Um, my dad loved him right away as well.
Uh, he stayed with my dad and,
um, you know, like once again,
we spend a whole week on the mat together.
He's helping me.
He did an amazing seminar, so it was
just an amazing guy to, uh, just, uh,
you know, he's like an encyclopedia
of Jujitsu and just, you know,
one of the most amazing martial
artist I've ever met. Um, and I mean,
we just never stopped. I just
have his style in a way. They,
him and Changi have that
smashing. Yes. Your game.
It's just such a hard style.
It's, I love that style. I mean,
I love watching it. I love, I love
that. It's just a total control,
you know, and it's just
pressure and you know, I mean,
everybody that I've talked to that's
rolled with him award. Sean's,
she says it's filled out.
You have a building on top of you
and these guys are on. Yeah, exactly.
Two of the greatest carb Gar Plat garp
pastors that have ever existed and there
mountains, they smothered. They make
people tap just from their mount.
So do you brother. It's
suffocating. But I didn't have that.
I was a guard guy. I didn't really a great
combination of those two things. Yeah.
It all came together for me. Uh, but I
mean, this was a time I'm a brown belt,
transitioning into becoming a black belt.
The next year I get my black.
But when we really started training,
like day to day,
that that year I spent four months there.
I trained with Shawn. Did you every day,
you know, um, you know, I'd be, I'd become
a black belt and they're literally just,
I mean destroying me.
You know, they were, uh,
their home base at that
time in the U s was Toledo,
Ohio in the middle of
nowhere. Yes. Toledo.
That's where their affiliates
were. And that area, uh, Michigan,
Ohio down into Virginia.
They had a Philadelphia,
when did they go to San Diego?
It was 2007 2007.
So this is like,
this is like a training
with them down there.
Cause he was down there with them
for the Bj Penn fight with, yeah,
it was before that. It was around the same
time. Oh seven. Oh eight. Really? Yes.
Versus Diego was o seven o eight.
Yeah. Wow Man. I'm confused.
I felt like it was like 2003 or something
like that. Um, it's um, too many fights.
I'm kind of rambling it. Diego Sanchez
was in the ultimate fighter. I like 2005.
Right. Uh, well he was in the
first season, which is all 2005.
December 11th, 2009.
Oh, okay. Yeah. So, uh,
I said, oh, seven, oh eight, it was
probably only doing nine, but um, yeah,
I mean they would just
destroy me with that pressure.
And it was like the exact answer
to my guard because they, you know,
you fight your way inside. So I
couldn't use my length. Right.
And I didn't understand how to frame,
how to protect myself and I just
literally got smothered and you know,
just destroyed, uh, on a daily
basis. And in Toledo, Ohio,
it would just be the three of us,
you know,
they didn't have like a big team and so
I would go there and stay with them and
we would just train for hours every day.
And the bike,
the Airdyne bike would be the evening
training partner. Two guys were out,
the other guy was on the bike.
I got one of those rogue,
a echo bikes out there.
That's the version of the airdyne.
Holy Shit. Is that thing death? Yeah.
It's a lot harder to me to have
solid screaming in your ear.
And how would you do it? Would you
do it sprints or like what do you,
what do you do on that thing?
Uh,
you had to keep a certain pace and
whenever they were in a scramble and going
hard, you had to sprint at the same
time on the bike. Oh Wow. Yeah.
And so you didn't want to be the one
like going too slow and in the middle of
the training solid looks
over and he's like, you know,
yelling at you to pick it
up. You know what I mean? So
you had, you had to push up,
you had to push it and then it was
your turn to go in and you know,
so I'm going back to back between Salo
in Changi and the Airdyne and the air
dyne.
Those were,
those were some good times that's in
the living room or something like that.
Or was that Mark Lehman and stuff?
That was the layman just mats
in the living room at the house.
[inaudible] appreciated guy.
Very much layman's Goddamn
encyclopedia of Brazilian Jiu Jitsu.
I remember he had everything sort of
written out like way back in the day.
Like most people just had moves in their
head. But Layman had things written up,
thinking might've done it on his computer.
Yeah. It was on his computer. Yeah. Uh,
another guy though,
it had a big influence on me is he,
these days he went back home to Wisconsin.
Right.
And I think he might have a
school there now. I think he's,
I know he was doing team
take down, right. Yeah.
He was with hydro twice when Hendrix was
that his best. Yeah. You that's right.
You were there as well. And then
I haven't heard from him. I was,
I was wondering like, yeah, he went back
home. He's had some back issues, you know,
that kept it from training. But I think,
I want to say I heard he is teaching now.
He is back to the teachers teaching and I
think he's also, uh, some of his family.
Either it's a bait and tackle
shop or maybe it's like, uh, uh,
the standing paddle boards or
something like that on a lake.
And I think he's helping with
that business as well too.
So his back from Jujitsu.
Right. I think that's, yeah,
that's where his same number one
injury that fucks people up in Jujitsu.
It is the back right back,
neck, upper back and neck.
Have you had any of those problems?
I used to have some neck issues.
Uh,
you know,
it wasn't ever anything too serious,
but if there was something that kept me
from training for a week or two, it'd be,
becomes my neck would flare up.
Um,
but fortunately my strength conditioning
coach that I've been with now for about
nine years, um, he really changed the
way I trained. I used to think that,
you know, the supplementary like
strength conditioning type stuff.
Like I had to just destroy myself and
lift hard and do all this crazy stuff and
I didn't feel like it was productive and
less, I couldn't walk at the end. Uh,
and then I would go train and get hurt.
You know, I just, I couldn't move.
I was too tight, too sore.
And so my strength and
conditioning coach, Luke Tyree,
um,
he really kind of put me on a different
path and made it a lot more back to the
basics,
pure clean movement and everything.
Just about health and awareness. A lot of,
uh, so what kind of stuff do you do now?
Well, you'd be surprised how little
I do. Um, you know, and I don't,
there are times where we
push it, but I, I don't, uh,
I don't ever leave feeling like I'm
not going to be able to train later.
You know, I actually, a lot of people
do strength conditioning type training,
you know,
later in the day after they've already
done their martial arts training. So they,
you know, don't feel tired when
they do their martial arts training.
The strength conditioning training than
I do actually makes me feel healthier.
It makes me feel kind of awakens
my body. I feel looser. And so I,
I was doing in the morning, um, that's
the way I like to start all my days.
Um, but, uh, you know, we, we
do a lot of kettle bells. Uh,
I've been playing a lot with
the mace lately as well. Um,
I do a lot of Airdyne bike. I'm
on the bike a lot. A sled, rags,
you know, we just pick heavy things up
and moving around, you know, um, uh, the,
you only lift I really do on
a regular basis somewhat, um,
is dead lifts, uh, with the
trap bar so it's safer. Um,
and there was just also a lot of movement,
a lot of mobility involved.
Why is dead lifts safer with a trap bar?
Uh,
cause you're not carrying the weight
in front of you so it's not as much
pressure on your back,
you know. Um, it's, it's,
you're kind of inside of it and so it's
a little more natural to bring it up.
What's that other machine that Luke had
is that you also love, it's the, uh,
the reverse hyper first cyber
things amazing for your back,
isn't it so critical
for decompressing the,
compressing your spine and
then strengthening up all
that area and a real weird
way that's very difficult to
do outside of that machine.
And here's the first one that just
say crawl. Why don't you, you know,
he taught me how to crawl and, you know,
just start crawling for five minutes,
10 minutes, hang, you know, get on the
pullup bar. Hank. You know, we, we,
he would incorporate all these recovery,
uh,
techniques and exercises into my training
and a lot of movement and would be the
first one to say, ah, I know you
want to go this heart today, but no,
you're going to tone it down. How are
you feeling? What's on your schedule?
You know, and really just, you know,
put it to where it fits
nicely into my routine and,
and isn't something that is everything,
you know, that takes it all out of me.
And he kind of opened my eyes to the
movement area, um, of his training.
Um, and that kind of led me into another
person I'm training with now these days.
His name is Cameron Shane, uh, who's, uh,
an innovator when it comes to movement.
Uh, he has, um, uh, a system,
the boot con, a movement system,
and he's an incredible guy. He's in
Florida, in Miami. Um, and he is,
uh, uh, Yoga, you know,
as a, as a Yogi. He,
he's a martial artist first fell in love
with yoga and then created this free
form mobility and movement that you see
guys like ido portal preaching and doing
now. It was a really well known
for his work with Connor. Um,
and I'm really into that as well.
And so I've been working with him now
for a year and I love that movement.
I just love it.
And it's all when Shawn g are also that
they spend a lot of time with Algebra
Hoomana from Genesco naturale
so, yeah, exactly. Exactly.
Yeah. So I, I love Yoga.
I love movement and that's a
big part of my recovery. Um,
and training without impact, you know, um,
and it's kind of implemented into my
strength and conditioning program as well.
So you're conditioning
program used to be just,
was it you on your own or was it someone
else that was like brutalizing you?
A little bit of both.
Um,
and it was just hardcore go full blast
and try to build your strength up and
break your body down. But yes, while
you're doing Brazilian Jujitsu,
it's not really the best
way to do it. Yeah, I was,
I was 100% like going for all the major
tournaments in Brazilian Jujitsu at that
time and I would kill myself
in strength conditioning.
Go to train neck, we get jacked up. Do
you ever fuck around with that iron neck?
Have you used that before? Is that
like a halo? Yeah. Yeah. I've seen it,
but I have one here. You got to try
it. Yeah, it looks easy. I'd love to.
It's one of the best things ever
for strengthening your neck.
And I've heard you talk about it. I love
it. The decompressing on the, the hangs,
you know, those are great as well. Yeah.
More people should be doing that, right?
Yeah, it was great. It hangs from a
chin up bar to where your shoulders,
it's just great to just, uh, so
what you're basically following,
it was just like a, a protocol
where you're not going to failure,
you just strengthening things up and you
probably doing like more workouts but
less time. Yes, exactly. A lot of
people were leaning towards that.
Now I do something every
day, Monday through Friday,
and then Saturday is like a,
a long, hard training
day, uh, in the mornings.
And then Sundays is like a yoga recovery
day. That's the other thing. Luke,
tell me about his active recovery.
You know, I used to think, well,
I need to take a day off, I need a
rest. And I would basically lay around,
you know, and I thought that
was helping and it wasn't,
he was the first one to really give
me the accurate active recovery.
Like go take an hour long walk,
you know, uh, stretch, move,
breathe, do yoga, you know, something
like that. And that helps tremendously to,
um, I, I don't get to a level of soreness
anymore where I feel like I can't do
anything, you know? Whereas
that used to happen to me. Um,
but I was younger and I had
this stubborn mindset and,
and I just thought, well, no,
I got to go, go, go, go. And
you think you're doing well,
you're pushing hard, and you think that
that's really the way to do it. Yeah,
it was just the harder you
push the strong yield cat,
it's just all about overcoming
weakness in your mind. Yeah, exactly.
You had that thing in the
back of your mind where like,
what if the other guy's doing more,
you know, I gotta go hard today.
I've always wondered how many fighters
ruined themselves before they get to the
fight because they just overtrain.
I think it's a real common,
and I think you can get to a level of
spectacular strength and conditioning.
You can get there, but it's not
something you're going to get to.
And in a two month camp,
you know,
and I wonder how many guys are coming
into camp where they're not in the best
shape and you're just pushing it so
hard during camp that by the time those
eight weeks are dumb, they're fucking
worn out man. Yeah. And they take,
they taper off the last week or so,
but it probably isn't enough. Yeah.
It's gotta be a lifestyle. Yeah. 100%
has to be a lifestyle. The way you eat,
your move,
you breathe,
the way you view your training
and you're saying sled drags.
So you're putting a harness on
and dragging the sled behind you.
Are you pushing the sled? Uh,
yeah. I mean both harness, um,
that's maybe around your waist or you
can, you know, hold like a, you know,
some handles and push it, pull it
or are you doing any running at all?
He'll sprint.
Uh,
I don't do like a lot of long distance
extended period of time running, uh,
just hill sprints.
I feel like that's the easiest on my body
and also translates the most into what
I need.
And you decided Justin to go down to
Oklahoma to train with him and you moved
there.
What,
what, what caused that move? Like what
was the motivation behind it? Honestly,
it was a couple of things. Um,
there's some really great people,
my sports agents out of Oklahoma City,
my business manager is
out of Oklahoma City.
I'm an organization we partner
with is out of Oklahoma City. Um,
and then water for, yeah. Yeah,
they're out of there. Um, and then,
uh, Jessica was out of their company
that I'm a spokesperson for it.
But then the thing that was the
deciding factor, my wife and I,
we watched a,
if anyone's got a flow grappling
subscription where you need to go get one,
because they did a documentary on
Rafael and it's called the American. Um,
and it's his life story, his life journey.
And he gets to see how hard he works.
You get to hear all the history.
Um, but then to me it was like,
this guy's like a Modern Day Samurai.
And then whenever I went down and trained
with them, uh, it was suffocating.
And I've trained with Shane Carwyn and
frank mir and Randy couture and all sorts
of big heavyweights that are
known for being so much pressure.
I've never been claustrophobic under any
person in my entire life except Raphael.
And it just feels like,
like you said,
a building or like this building of melted
hot no cheese or blanket that's going
over your face. And she's, she's,
yeah, no, it sounds cheesy saying that,
but it's just like,
it's melted all over you and you can't
get them off and you'd take inch by inch
by inch.
And I have a good wrestling game,
but I wanted to get my Jujitsu there
where every time I take someone down I'm
going to finish them.
And I've done that in
fighting statistically every
flight of taking him to the
ground to finish.
But I wanted to get even more proficient
at that and just seeing the way that he,
he coaches, he teaches.
Um, honestly, like I've,
I've been coached by Cael Sanderson
and kindle cross and Kenny Monday, um,
a Olympic gold medalist and
wrestling, um, fantastic people,
amazing coaches.
Um,
there's something really special and
different about the way he teaches and
coaches, um, that you really
start to grasp everything.
He breaks it down bit by bit,
inch by inch.
I mean the way that he will because
he's an active competitor too.
And he's a great teacher. I mean,
when did you start teaching Raphael?
I mean you were in high school probably,
right? Yeah, yeah, because it was just,
yeah,
my dad and I, uh, in Oklahoma, you know,
I was the most advanced
student there, you know, uh,
and so I started helping my dad teach
when I was like 16, you know, if he,
if he wanted to go travel and train,
I would help teach if you needed a night
off or whatever. Um, I was sort of the,
the next one and I started teaching
adults, uh, right off the bat, you know,
I'm 16 years old and I'm
teaching grown men, but, um, I,
I've been treating
teaching now for almost 20,
and then there's things that I'm doing
and he'll say, turn an inch this way.
I'm just an inch.
And I turned an inch and I hear my,
the guy I'm trained with the,
and it's just a small little
inch of an adjustment. Um,
get your chest up high or get, you know,
finish this way, your chest down low.
I mean, the, and I can
hear him very distinctly.
Um, whenever I'm training,
whenever I'm competing,
whenever I was in my last fight,
um, I can hear everything he's saying
too. And so in a, in a trust it,
so there's this level of trust that,
that, um, I don't know why it's there,
but you're just a fantastic human
being and make some, this guy,
this guy blew me away. He's, he's been
such a blessing in my life and you know,
I was very kind of like skeptical of
him at first, just because, you know,
he's a big guy, heavyweight
MMA fighters like, man,
is how is this going to work? Is he
going to be open to putting on the Geeky?
What is his mindset? Is He,
is he a fighter? Is he a
martial artists? You know,
how's, I just didn't know how it was
going to work, you know? Uh, I'm not, uh,
we don't have a fight team, you know what
I mean? We have a martial arts school.
Um, and so you're always just
a little, you know, when,
when a fighter wants to come and, you
know, how's this going to work? Yeah.
Some of them are a little rough around
the edges that's saying it lightly.
And especially when you
have kids in classes. Right.
But of course don't have anything to do
with fighting. They just want to learn.
Right. And that's the most important
thing. Just learning. Um, and,
and becoming part of the
team, part of the family. Uh,
of course I did my research
on Jocelyn and, you know,
I knew he was an amazing person, but I
just didn't know what he trained, like,
what his energy was like inside
the academy, you know. But, uh,
he was open to putting on the
gate the first conversation
we had. I said, hey man,
you know, I'm gonna, I'm gonna want to
put a g on you. Are you okay with that?
It's so critical for you about the game
for me.
I can't pass on what I,
what,
what I really have to offer,
you know, my passion, my love.
There's no way I'm going to be able to
pass that on to you if you don't put on
the key,
if you don't get inside my head and,
and learn what I have to say and
how I feel about Brazilian Jujitsu.
But what is specifically why the g,
it's just a,
for me that's Jujitsu. Like for
me that is Jujitsu. Nogi is,
Jujitsu is a part of it,
but it's, it's submission,
wrestling, submission, grappling,
you know, uh, the, the beauty
of Jujitsu for me is with the g,
um, the, the inches, the details,
the way you can make a mistake
here and that's your downfall. 10,
12 moves later, you know, minutes
later the way it feels, you know,
the tightness of it, everything.
Jujitsu is, you know, I mean,
I just use my passion. For me, I feel
like whenever I put on the Geeky,
it was tough. I didn't want
to put it on a, but then, um,
whenever I did and it was just tough
because I couldn't power out of stuff.
And then slip out of things. That's
the big factor. Yeah. And so for me,
it's helped expand my knowledge of
every position you have to be for me,
uh, and learn from him. Um,
it's, it's both are technical,
but there's one that seems a little bit
like maybe you expand your knowledge and
then whenever you, um,
take it off, I feel like I,
I feel like I understand the Nogi
positions a little bit better,
a little bit more that more refined, more
refined, more refined. That's the word.
Yeah.
It's like a gallon is a friction because
of the fact that people can grab you.
You have to slow it down,
slow it down and truly understand it.
I feel like before I was
able to muscle out of things,
I was able to slip out of things, is
able to use my weight a lot more. Um,
and I still get to use that
whenever I take the g off.
And whenever I'm in the Geeky,
it's to learn and it's to really expand
my knowledge base base, the depth of it.
That's what it was too.
It's like, you know, uh,
you're not going to fully become part
of the team and the family if you're not
in the classes. You know. And
like I was saying, you know,
I'm going to want you to do
the classes in [inaudible].
98% of my classes are all in the
geek. Um, you know, we take it off.
We, we, we do Gnocchi
afterwards. You know, we have
our sparring or MMA training,
everything else, but I want
you to come to class, you know,
I'm not going to do like a lot of special
treatment just for one individual and
you need to,
you know,
be a part of this family and that is
to put the key on and come to Jujitsu
class.
Um,
he had a lot of other guys
who are professional fighters
come and specifically
come down to train with
you like this. No, no, no.
Oklahoma's not like that sort of hot spot.
You know what I mean?
It's rare for people to come.
And he told me it made sense
that he was going down there.
And then when I saw the results,
as soon as I saw that one fight,
will you a mount of that guy
and got an arm triangle? I
go, well, there you go. Yup.
Yeah.
I mean now you're finishing from the top.
It's not just punching a guy
when you're on top of them.
Now you strangling people. Yeah. And
then he learns like a sponge. I mean, he,
he's,
because of that attitude that he has and
our connection that we made so quickly,
uh, it made it really easy for me. And
I mean, obviously it's a great athlete,
great wrestler. Um, and the fact
that he was open to it, you know,
I mean, I was telling like, Justin,
you've got to play guard. You know,
you're going to start on your back.
Like all these things.
He was accepting of it and then he
just made it so easy to absorb all the
knowledge. And it's just like, you know,
playing a video game with him. It's like,
here's what you're gonna
do, and boom, he did it.
What a wrestler falls in
love with Jujitsu. I mean,
you already have this ability to
manipulate bodies that it sets such a high
level and the strength that
wrestlers have. But so many of them,
for whatever reason, never make that leap.
It's uncomfortable. It's uncomfortable.
Uh, going to your back is not, I mean,
you've been trained your whole life not
to go to your back. And so to do that,
go to guard, um, to have
someone put you in a,
you're not supposed to be getting pinned.
You're supposed to be turning
your back and getting up. Uh, but,
but getting comfortable with your back,
just flat on the Mat,
but then getting into your side because
you understand that you're just gonna
get smashed and smash and smashed if your,
if your shoulders are
flat against the back,
you catch and triangles and doing things.
He's got a good Omoplata man, don't,
yeah. You to have flexibility.
I think I do for having,
he's been working with a strength
conditioning too. I mean, he's kind
of gone all in with
everything. Uh, his, his,
his regimen is kind of becoming mine.
I, I, I'm inspired by it. Um, but yeah,
I've got, I've got a normal plotter.
The triangles, little harder. I got to,
I got small legs where heavyweight
short, short legs, they're thick.
So why? Okay. Okay.
I only wear like a 30 inch inseam or
whatever, 30 inches long or three,
it's either 30 or 32. So instead of, I
think most heavyweights were like 34,
36 different things like that.
So in short, torsos really long,
the doctor told me that, uh, uh,
if I didn't have short legs I'd be
like six foot seven. So yeah. Um,
but yeah, I got short little legs
and just coming in the academy,
it's been really great, you know, um,
I came in and was really wanting
to be coached and I wanted to be,
have a mindset of being coachable and
it just absorbing everything he teaches.
But then on the flip side,
uh,
last year we had like this holiday break
Christmas party and a rough Hale said,
you know, what if we could like transform
a community, uh, with clean water?
And so what if we like set a goal at
reasoning? And what does that cost?
And it was like, man, it's like
$4,200. And he's like, man,
let's set a crowdfunding campaign
and let's, let's do it. And, uh,
hosted a party. Um, and we
were able to raise 14,000,
$400, um, through the academy.
And the, the team just came
around it and said, hey,
we're going to, this is your passion.
You're sharing in our passion.
Like we're going to, we're going to do
something great in the community, um, in,
in the world. And so
that's been great. Um,
Rafael and I are partnering again.
We are getting ready to
launch a nationwide through
fight for the forgotten to
nationwide bullying prevention, a campaign
and curriculum. Uh, I grew up, uh,
getting very heavily,
like really extensively on the podcast
is terrible stories and it made me,
uh, and, and so this last year, um,
I got injured at a shoulder surgery.
I got Mesenchymal stem cells in their
MSC stem cells. I'm getting better. Uh,
hopefully I'll fight, uh, first quarter.
When did you get your shoulders?
So I got it in like late March, um,
labor them. Uh, but it was actually,
yeah, Lieberman, rotator cuff I think,
but my rotator cuff was just fine.
Um, and it's kept me out for a while,
but the whole time I've been, um,
and it was actually after
being on the podcast last time,
I'm talking about bullying. It's
like, how can we make a difference?
And there was such a response from
the Jerry like community saying,
let's do something here that also,
let's make a difference here in the
United States of bullying. How can you,
how can you prevent billing pulling?
What do you think?
I've always said that one of the best
ways is teach people to actually fight.
Yeah. I think that, well,
a lot of bullies are hugely insecure
and if they just learned how to fight,
they wouldn't act like
that. Right. I think,
I think martial arts is going to be a
tool. So what we want to do this year is,
is to get into a hundred
martial arts academies, um,
with a bullying prevention curriculum.
A lot of people don't know that 100,000
kids in the United States alone,
160,000 kids every day. Skip School,
skip school because of bullying.
That's 3 million school days last a year,
or sorry, a month, 3 million school days,
lost a month.
And then I started digging into it because
Oklahoma's become home now and like
28.9% of the students deal with
depression that's debilitating.
That affects them for two weeks or more
school. I mean depression, addiction,
suicides in school, shootings are
all through the roof. And you know,
the suicide rate that you said,
so,
so insane in Oklahoma fit
that says the at risk youth,
um,
behavior survey and they say that 15.4 no,
15.1% of the students are d
dealing with suicidal ideation,
like seriously considering suicide.
And then 7.4 7.4% of the
students had attempted suicide,
attempted it.
I was one of those kids.
I was one of those kids in that seven
out of a hundred kids have attempted
suicide just in Oklahoma
schools. And that, that,
that goes around the country
to around that 6%, 8%.
I was on a bullying prevention summit
in San Antonio with congressmen or US
Representative Will Hurd.
He brought me in to speak with
Maureen Molech and Maureen. Um,
she has a foundation
called David's legacy.
She started it because her son in San
Antonio was getting ridiculed in cyber
bullied relentlessly. You know,
whenever we were growing up,
bullying would end at 3:00 PM.
Right, because you're out of school.
But now it just increases because kids
aren't in school, they aren't in class.
So that's whenever they can really
take off and start bullying. Well,
David had over 300 comments of people,
uh,
that were just brutally
cyberbullying them.
A ton of them are calling for a suicide.
Um, it went on for weeks and weeks.
They moved them from schools.
He attempted suicide and at once or twice,
but his third time, his third
time, you're successful. Um,
and I'm very proud of Maureen. Uh,
very proud of her because she, um,
got a law passed called David's law.
David's law is about cyberbullying. Uh,
we want to see if we can get that
into Oklahoma. What is the law?
So the law basically Maureen's family
was told basically at school, um, they,
the school was good to them.
They were trying to make a difference,
but they're basically saying their hands
were tied, their hands are tied from,
from doing anything about it because it
was an overwhelming response of students.
I mean 300 students, and then it was
off school property and it was online.
So there they said their
hands are tied. Well now, um,
the law basically brings into the fact
that law enforcement and the schools can
get involved off the school campus and
they can look into the cyber bulling and
they can take action against
it. So it basically just
means, hey, this is serious.
Um, and, and, and it's not okay. Um,
and we're going to stand up and
do something about it. Texas, I'm,
I'm proud of Texas. That's my home
state. Um, they passed it 33 to zero.
No one voted against it. Um,
and it's really great. We're,
we're working with a state representative
named Collin. I'm in Oklahoma.
Um, and, uh, a judge, Trevor Pemberton.
And then there's this principal named, uh,
it's kinda sound like a joke. Last week
it was a MMA fighter with a politician.
We went to dinner with a
politician, a judge in a high
school principal, you know,
MMA fighter. What brought us
all together, you know, it was,
it was bullying prevention.
Um, but, uh, debris on Davis,
she's the high school
principal of Edmond North.
It's one of the biggest and one of the
best public schools in Oklahoma. Um,
and in the last nine years of
her working in public schools,
she's been to nine funerals of kids that
have all committed suicide. And, um,
it's,
uh,
it's just on the rise
in such a brutal way.
And one of the things that really touched
my heart and wanted me to get into to
this like, Hey, we've
fight for the forgotten.
We're always going to be
focused on the pygmies.
We're working with even
expanding into the, in Uganda,
we're working with the pygmy king of
the Botswana pygmies and Uganda. Um,
we're looking to do land,
water and food initiatives among them,
but there's kids in our own community
right here that feel forgotten. Um,
and whenever I was a kid sitting
at the lunch table by myself,
getting pelted in the back of the
head with chocolate spit wads, uh,
food fist when kids were pulling up my
shirt and slapping my belly and twist in
my nipples in front of the girls and
acting like they're hitting me with a
harpoon, you know, cause I'm the size
of a whale and all this stuff, you know,
it and telling me,
you should just kill yourself,
telling me you should just kill yourself.
You're worthless. You're nothing. I mean,
I, I felt forgotten, um,
and thought, you know,
I am worthless and I should just kill
myself and dealt with that over and over
and over.
And now the kids are taking action on
that in such a incredible way that we've
got to stand up and do something.
And so we're, we're partnering
and, uh, I'm really excited.
Um, we are hopefully getting
into a hundred martial arts
academies this year, um,
to equip them with bullying
prevention curriculum.
It's called heroes and waiting and you
know, uh, a real inspiration to me.
There's two things.
Um,
there's a ted talk called the psychology
of evil. Oh, I'll text you that link.
It's incredible.
But it's the psychology of evil and
it's by getting with Philip Zimbardo or
something.
Um,
and in there he kind of coins a term
called heroes and waiting Phillips and
Barto. Yeah. And, uh, then you, uh,
you with the audit video that you did
be the hero of your own movie, you know,
be the hero of your own movie. Um, I
love that. I love that, that, that,
that you've spoken out and said that
about people you can be the hero of your
movie.
Well,
he rose in waiting the curriculum that
we developed with century and Maya,
which is the martial arts
industry association. Um,
it's all about teaching kids.
It's, it's bullying prevention, but
it's also character development.
So that is what prevents
bullying. Yeah, absolutely.
The only people that bully or
people with weak characters. Yeah.
And kids that are usually,
there's something wrong at home,
right?
You know a lot of these kids that are
bullies usually getting abused at home or
either by an older brother or by their
dad or cousins or whoever the fuck it is,
it's and then they're taking it out on
someone who they feel is weaker than them.
Right.
This is one of the reasons why I think
martial arts is so important for young
men because I mean we know
from our experience in gyms
when you're dealing with
like high level martial
artists on a regular basis,
like there are some of the nicest,
friendliest fucking people you're ever
going to meet because they don't have any
insecurities. I mean and
whatever insecurities they have,
they get out in the gym to
get out through training.
They get all of their frustrations.
They don't have all this pent up fucked
up energy that a lot of kids have.
Like kids.
Kids are always dealing with existential
angst and their whole life is just this
weird ball of confusion and
hormones and you know the,
the, the whole idea of life
itself is so confusing.
Then anytime they have any sort of
control of or anything, they exercise it.
Whether it's control over another
kid or control over, you know,
throwing a rock through a window or just
they don't know what the fuck they're
doing.
You know they have all this pent up
fucked up energy and pain and I think that
so many of them are just severely lacking
in guidance and discipline and just
those things alone.
Guidance and discipline and also the
lessons that you learned from martial arts
that you can overcome things that you can
get better at things and that when you
feel like quitting and you don't,
you actually grow and learn.
Like your experience is like training
with Shawn g and Solow. Just like that.
It's one of the things in
made you said a champion,
I mean did training with
people that are like,
it all started with my dad and having
that when I was a kid. Gas, you know,
you're so fortunate because of that.
I mean,
and those experiences are what shaped
you into the person that you are today.
And a lot of people don't
get those experiences.
And unfortunately they
act and disgraceful ways.
And this is what we're
talking about earlier.
I mean to bring it all back to what is
martial arts and art is martial arts shit
talking and throwing dollies or is his
martial arts really competing in one of
the most difficult endeavors in
all of all of the world of sports?
Well,
so I came from a wrestling background
and I believe that is without a doubt a
martial art. Yes, it is for sure.
Side of martial arts. And then, um,
in my coaches, one of the most important
martial yeah, absolutely. Absolutely.
In one of the toughest to do. Yeah. One
of the toughest without a doubt. And then,
um, but then coming into Rafales
Gym, uh, I mean academy in school,
it started teaching me like
the martial arts principles.
We didn't really talk about
that so much. Um, in, uh,
in wrestling it teaches you that,
that naturally the hard work cause it,
it thins the flock pretty
quick if you can cut it right.
But then what are the six
blades? So Solow, he, uh,
his logo, uh, it's the star in and
uh, he considers the mineral middle,
the spirit of the Samurai, and then
there's six blades to the star. Um,
and they stand for six different
values. Uh, loyalty, respect,
honor, discipline, attitude and family.
And those are the core principles in
start inside the Children's program at my
academy. Uh, and sort of
just the, there, the uh,
it's a very famous logo. Yes,
it is. And I have right here,
I carry it with me everywhere I am.
Yeah, that's it. But, um, you know,
besides for the, you know,
the, those are the, the,
the core values and then,
you know,
being a forever student and dedicating
your life to learning and bettering
yourself. I mean, these
things that martial arts gives
you. I just, I, you know,
there are certain areas and other sports
that they give you a piece of that,
but nothing is like martial
arts, you know, for me,
everything that I've learned
through martial arts, there's, yeah.
I think what you're saying that there's,
there's other sports that teach
you discipline. Like just me.
If you become a long distance runner,
there's,
there's discipline involved in that.
It's going to build up your character,
but it's not specifically emphasized
the way it is and martial arts.
And so I've been looking into
and researching and we're
partnering with century.
We're partnering with Zebra,
we're partnering with Gameness,
we're partnering with Souplesse.
Uh,
I don't know if you've seen the Bulgarian
bags and the throwing dummies and the
gladiator wall. We're partnering
with them because of Gladiator Wall.
Glad your wall is a,
the wood that is,
you can hang on it and you can do all
sorts of stretching in different bars.
The level almost looks like
a ladder. Actually, Jamie,
if you could pull up fight
for the forgotten.org um,
I've actually got some show in their soup.
Less on there.
We should give a shout out to
the cash APP too. Oh my gosh.
The cash APP is one of
my favorite sponsors,
has done an incredible thing in
donating $5 to fight for the forgotten.
And every time someone signs up and
uses the code word Joe Rogan. Yup.
Which is pretty amazing.
Thousands of dollars from
that. They've built two wells,
more of a more, more coming in January.
We're starting to implement, but, um,
cash app came to me and we were
trying to do a $50,000 fundraiser,
um, to drill a deep, deep well, um,
in Tanzania for the Masai Warriors.
Um, and we're going to do that with water
boys, which is Chris Lungs, a foundation,
Chris long police for
the Philadelphia Eagles.
He won the super bowl doing it his
entire salary. Really great guy,
climbed Mount Kilimanjaro with him and
we were partnering together to help this
village to get 7,500 people clean water.
So it's about $6 per person.
I started posting about that and Gary
Mcmanus from cash app hit me up and was
just like, hey, we want to do
something big with you guys. Um,
and we already had another $50,000 donor
that was being anonymous and cash up
came in and said, hey, we're going
to match that $50,000 match you have.
So Kashyap gives $50,000
if we could raise 50,000.
And so we ended up raising
50,000, $52,625, and then,
uh,
and then it was tripled.
So it came out to being 152,625 and a
cash app gave us $50,000 because they
believe in the mission and vision
of fight for the forgotten.
They believe in you and they believe
in this community. Um, and me and I,
I absolutely love a cash app.
The,
in fact on this crowdfunding
tournament we're doing, um,
on the website fight for
the forgotten.org/heroes,
we're doing a heroes and
waiting crowdfunding tournament.
And so we're inviting you in a hundred
martial arts academies in a hundred
individuals to help us raise $4,200 there.
And so,
yeah,
we're doing it through December 31st
so we're given us quite a bit of time,
but what we're going to be doing is the
crowdfunding tournament is going to fund
a wells.
So we'll transform a community with the
$4,200 and it will equip their martial
arts academy with the bullying
prevention curriculum.
So they don't just amazing
by the way. Yeah. Yeah.
Everything that you could ever ask for
a to help pass that knowledge along and
increase your program, you know, help
your school, bring more kids in a,
make a bigger impact. Um, so not
only are you helping the kids,
but then you're also raising money, uh,
inside the academy to help towards, um,
you know, the fight for
the forgotten. Yeah.
And uh, it's, it's going to
be a thing where, so it's,
there's 12 weeks of Mat chat topics and
I love it because he rose in waiting,
talks about, hey, everyone is a
hero in waiting. And what is a hero?
A hero is someone who sees a need
and takes action immediately.
And so we're teaching the kids that,
hey, guess what? 87% of the time,
whenever you see bullying and you say
something, it can be as easy as, hey,
that's not kind or,
or you include the person that's
being bullied into your group. Hey,
come over here. Um,
within five seconds, uh,
the bullying stops 87% of the time.
All you have to do is say one thing,
87% of them,
almost nine out of 10 times.
You can shut down bullying
whenever you see it happening.
Because here's the problem.
Whenever people think you're,
when you see bullying happening,
a lot of times you might think
you're innocent bystander, but,
but your body language and you being
around and involved in the bully,
seeing that he takes you being
that you're a silent supporter,
so you're not an innocent bystander,
you're now involved when you see it.
And so you're being a silent supporter
if you're not standing up and doing
something about it. And so we're
doing this competition and whoever,
whoever's the top crowdfunding,
uh, team is going to get there.
Jim Renovated by Zebra, they're going
to get $10,000 worth a zebra mats. Um,
century is going to come in
and do $10,000 worth of a gear.
They're going to do gloves, uh,
headgear, sparring equipment, shields,
uh, the Bob the dummy. Um, souplesse is
going to do the, the Bulgarian bag, uh,
throwing dummy and then the top individual
fundraiser is going to get a free
home gym from Zebra and
century gear. Uh, Bella toward,
just let me know last night that whoever
is the top fundraising individual is
going to get flown out
all inclusive, um, to uh,
to the January 26th, the
heavyweight Prix finale, uh,
between [inaudible] Ryan Bader Ryan
Bader Forum at the forum in La.
So you're going to get,
they're going to get three nights of
hotel rooms are going to get their airfare
paid for.
And uh,
so basically what fight for the forgotten
is trying to do is raise $420,000
throughout the rest of the year.
And what we'll be able to do with that
is hopefully drill equivalent to 100
water wells were served
30,000 people minimum.
Hopefully we'll be around 45,000 people
with clean water. And then, um, it, it's,
it's pretty easy if people go
and hit sign up. Um, Jamie,
if you could just hit the
link. It's a, it's sign up. It.
We're trying to make it really fun and
consider, tell people how to get to it.
It's fight for the forgotten.org
forward slash. Heroes.
It's forward slash heroes. And then
here, whenever they go down, um,
you can hit become a fundraiser and
whenever you become a fundraiser,
you can either create a team, which we
did with Lovato's a couple of nights ago.
Um, you can hit join a team.
So if a team's already created,
you can join that team where if you're
an individual martial artist or just
someone that's passionate about the cause,
you can hit start fundraising
as an individual. Awesome. Um,
and then we're going to have a top 10
prizes. Uh, basically like price backs.
The top crowdfunding team is going to
get a championship belt to fight for the
forgotten championship belt.
Two through 10 are going to
get championship trophies.
And then anyone that hits the goal of
$4,200 is going to get a fight for the
forgotten gold metal for hitting
the goal. Um, but the, uh, if,
if you actually click out of
that and then scroll down, Jamie,
you can actually see how it's
kind of started a little bit more,
but there's a already a few teams.
There's four teams now that have
signed up and some of our res,
we haven't announced it yet,
so, um, there's team Lovato
down there, there's, and it,
what it will do is they'll show the top
team so you can track it and make it
competitive so that you can go on there
and make a comment whenever you donate.
Um, but basically I guess
martial arts and more, uh,
I do know them if you click on their page.
Um, it's a guy out of South Carolina,
sorry, North Carolina, Jacksonville. Um,
and he just got hit by the
hurricane brutally. Um,
he can't go back into his home
for another year, a year, a year.
He can't go back into his home. He's
living in the academy. Why a year?
His homeowner's association set,
it's going to be like a year of clean up,
fix everything, fix everything.
That's what it's predicted to be.
But he said at $4,200, he wants
to teach his community. Um,
it says James, right. And, uh, he, he's
wanting to, you know, teach the kids that,
hey,
we're still heroes in waiting.
We can still make a difference in our
community with bullying prevention and
globally with a community
that needs clean water.
And so that's what we're trying to do
is make a difference in both places.
Awesome. Drill the wells and, um,
equip the martial arts academy with
bullying prevention. Beautiful.
And let's wrap this up. Um, just
want to say one more thing. Yeah,
I just wanted to back it up
one more time. You know, uh,
Justin has inspired me so much to,
you know,
get involved in these sorts of
things and, and uh, you know,
I'm happy to have my school involved and
I'm just kind of out there calling out
for all the other juices,
schools,
um, you know, in the country.
Like, I mean, if we just
get two schools per state,
that's a hundred. Um, and
if each one, uh, you know,
reaches the goal of 4,200 than we've
done it. Um, and so, you know, uh,
it's, it's a great cause it
helps the school, uh, the,
the material that they get
a is a very, um, helpful to,
to implement it to their
children's programs,
even comes with marketing material to
help get those kids in the doors. Um,
so it's totally worth it. And then,
you know, uh, it's always great, like,
like he said, you know, when we had the
school Christmas party last year, um,
and it's always great to get everybody
behind something behind a cause. Um,
and you know, to get your whole
school to rally together, you know,
for this cause would be, um, you
know, a great thing for your,
for your teams and your Jujitsu families.
Um, and it's not that hard to do,
you know, it's not that hard
to, to, to hit 4,200. Um,
and if we get a hundred schools to do
it then, then we've done it. So I'm,
I'm here, you know, to, to
support Justin in that. Beautiful.
It's always great to have your
brother and your brother, so,
so happy for what you've
been able to accomplish.
So happy to know you and to be a part
of this and just to spread the word.
That's beautiful. Wow.
Thank you man. This, uh,
it couldn't be done without you and
your help. I mean, honestly, it's a,
it's skyrocket at us, um, to
be able to make the difference.
We want to knock out the water crisis
and to stand up and speak out against
spooling here and what's my honor,
and thank you for being here,
Rafael and kilos of luck to you.
I know you're supposedly next in line
for a shot at the title and Bella Toy
Garden was saucy. Everything looks good.
I can't wait. Thank you. Appreciate it.
Thanks for being here. It was awesome.
All right, we'll see you later folks.
[inaudible].