This was just saying how big our recipes
here,
each other.
Hello.
Welcome to my weekly podcast.
I'm solo will shut the door so nobody
interrupts Shazamm.
I'm back riding totally.
One hundred percent.
So while there to answer your questions,
talk to you.
See what the fuck's going on out there
in the wild world of twitter.
Thank you everybody that tuned into the
show we did yesterday and serious.
Uh,
I did a show for an hour yesterday on
raw dog and I'm going to try to do that
more often because it's fun and uh,
it's just,
uh,
it's fun just to do even for a goof,
but it's a great way to promote gigs and
uh,
you know,
get things cracking.
Not this weekend as in tomorrow and
Saturday and Sunday,
but next weekend,
next Friday.
I'm not exactly sure the date I'll be at
Gotham.
I think it's the 26th.
What's Today's date?
Seven days?
Yeah,
the 26th,
the 26th.
I'll be at Gotham for two shows in New
York City.
I don't get to New York City very often.
I only go there like once every year and
a half,
two years and uh,
it's already almost sold out.
So if you want to get tickets,
you got to hop on that shit.
Now,
a Gotham comedy club in New York City,
you know how to use the Google son.
I would throw up links,
but if you really want to go,
you'll figure it out,
right?
So,
uh,
get any on my podcast.
I will definitely.
Um,
Brian was supposed to beat my lips.
Are very shy today.
Brian was supposed to be here today for
this one,
but he got held in traffic and getting,
getting boned by the irs.
Back taxes.
Pay Your taxes,
bitches.
That's uncle Joe's advice for the day.
Pay Your fucking taxes.
The worst thing is when the irs like
signals you out,
singles you out as a guy who's not
paying taxes,
and then they just crawl up your ass
hole and look around.
The tax laws are so gross.
The whole thing is so gross.
The idea that you have to pay such a
giant percentage of what you make to do
what?
To keep more people arresting people for
buying pot to do what?
To fix the streets.
Is that where the fuck is the money
going?
God Damn it.
Our machine is just too God damn big.
You know when you get to a certain
amount of money,
you get into a 48 percent tax bracket.
You know you have to pay half of what
you make half literally.
That's crazy.
And the crazy thing is the people who
make them more money,
the more money you make,
rather the higher percentage you have to
pay.
So not only do you pay more money just
because you make more money,
which seems,
that seems rational to me,
but the fact that you pay a higher
percent,
that's just like saying,
listen,
we know you got it.
Fuck you.
Give us the money.
I mean it's really that simple.
It doesn't make any sense that someone
who makes more money somehow or another
uses a higher percentage of resources.
That's completely unfair.
It makes no sense,
but people just accept it but just
accept it and they just take it in the
ass and the machine keeps rolling on
there.
Will be no end or will there will go to
a first the twitter to check it out of
the twitter feed that is on the same
page,
which is a ustream.tv
channels slash Joe Rogan Dash live,
which will.
That's where you're at,
and then also go to forums dot Joe
Rogan.net.
That's my website and there's a a forum
up.
They're dedicated to this particular or
rather a thread dedicated to this
particular broadcast and so answer some
questions from there to you mother
fucker.
Pull out of Iran Afghan and you'd save a
fortune.
Yeah.
What is that?
Well,
that's A.
I mean that's a simple way of looking at
it,
right?
CMC dermo 73.
It's a simple way of looking at.
Everybody says pull out,
but why the fuck are we there in the
first place?
Like what is going on?
You know what I mean?
Is it as simple as,
you know,
we're over there because we need to keep
these terrorists from becoming strong.
We need to go and attack them at their
base.
Okay.
If,
if that was what was agreed that that's
the reason why we're there,
but there's a lot of people that say
that doesn't make any sense.
There's a lot of people that say there's
very few Taliban that are actually left
in Afghanistan that we have other
motives and that these motives might be
the natural gas pipeline that runs
through Afghanistan,
which are bloody apparently has been
trying to control for years or they also
very overlooked in a subject that people
like.
They kind of poo poo it and they make it
seem like it's not that big a deal is
the opium market.
Afghanistan produces some 90 something
percent of the entire world's opium.
The entire world's poppy seeds.
The entire world.
Heroin,
more than 90 percent of it is produced
in Afghanistan.
That's fucking crazy,
right?
You hear about that.
You like there's a lot of goddamn money
and heroin.
There's a lot of goddamn money in opium.
I mean if all of it is being produced,
literally almost all of it in this one
place,
like someone's making some fucking money
off that it's not.
The US got in there and they stopped.
Making heroin?
No,
there's more heroin now.
Heroin,
apparently you talked to people.
No.
You know,
I know people will do heroin and they
say there's more heroin and it's easier
to get now.
You know what the fuck man,
what?
What is really going on?
Then you find out that the president of
Afghanistan,
this is absolute fact,
president
of Afghanistan,
his brother was being paid by the CIA
for years,
like our government dollars.
We're going to pay the brother of the
president of Afghanistan whose in the
poppy business.
This guy is involved in the opium trade.
This guy is involved in the heroin trade
and he's an employee of the CIA.
Like really?
Is it that blatant?
Is that obvious?
There's for sure there's a ton of
fucking corruption when it comes to the
higher levels of government,
but I think really selling drugs or
they're really doing it that openly.
It seems ridiculous,
right?
It seems like there's no way that could
be possible.
There's no way it could be that corrupt.
If it was,
we would have heard about it,
but when you start researching the
history of the CIA,
like they've been accused of doing this
for ever,
not just accused of doing this,
but people who don't make any sense like
crazy people and you know,
Internet conspiracy theorists,
but no,
they've been accused of doing it by
people who used to work for the CIA.
They've been accused of doing it by
people who have actually flown in the
drugs.
There's a great case about a guy named
barry seal's from MENA,
Arkansas escapes to driving flying to
Mena,
Arkansas and dropoff big packages of
cocaine.
I think we've talked about this before
or I've talked about this before.
And anyway,
these two kids,
uh,
inadvertently were there when the
cocaine got dropped.
They were,
they witnessed what had happened.
So they took these kids and they
murdered them and they left their bodies
on the train tracks.
And the excuse,
the official excuse at the police used
was that these kids had gotten high and
that they had fallen asleep on the
plane.
Sharks because they were on drugs.
Well,
the mothers of the kids forced
autopsies,
the parents forced ops autopsies,
they didn't want to do autopsies,
but they forced them,
they,
they got them done,
and it turns out that these kids had
been murdered.
They had been stabbed multiple times
before they had been put on these train
tracks.
So then the investigation goes further
and it turns out this guy named Barry
Seal's who is a CIA employee and there's
no documented.
This guy's got a great long history with
the CIA.
There's tons of pictures,
there's tons of documentation on this
guy.
And this guy was flying in drugs from
South America and that's what he did.
He did it for the CIA and right when he
was about to go testify,
the guy gets murdered that gets
assassinated,
uh,
with George Bush's phone number in his
pocket.
Um,
so there's that guy,
there's a,
there's another guy named Michael Rupert
and Michael.
Rupert has a website now and he's got a
bunch of books on the whole situation,
but his story is that he was working for
the lapd.
Uh,
I'm not sure if he worked in narcotics,
but he's involved somehow or another and
some narcotics case and it turns out
that the CIA was involved and the CIA
was protecting these people in the CIA.
He was selling drugs and he,
uh,
went to try to report it.
They squashed everything and he just
went public with everything and it's,
you know,
he gets very little attention.
I mean,
it's really shocking how little
attention to yet.
But uh,
he's a,
he's a fascinating dude.
This Michael Rupert Guy,
he's got a couple of really fascinating
books.
Uh,
I think,
uh,
the end of the Rubicon is one and that's
the one I've read and there's a,
he's got it,
he's got a few other ones,
but basically like going into great
depth and detail,
all of his research on the CIA and their
involvement in drugs.
Why,
why would they do that?
Why would our government do that?
Fucking,
there's a lot of goddamn money on it.
I think they could justify that either.
So much money involved in drugs and
someone's going to make that money.
People are addicted to drugs,
like why don't we make that money in the
least that money's being made by the
good guys.
I mean,
that's like the most idealistic point of
view.
Make sure your kids don't do drugs.
Make sure no one that he loves,
Dude does drugs,
but let's be honest,
there are people out there that are
going to do drugs and if anybody should
make the money,
it should be the good guys.
I can see people falling for that,
but the bottom line is it's all greed.
It's all this nasty,
evil,
greed,
the.
That's the whole reason why some drugs
are legal and some drugs are illegal.
It's because when they make them
illegal,
they can control what you do.
They can.
You can't control things that are really
easy to grow like marijuana.
So one of the main reasons why marijuana
is illegal is because it's so god damn
easy to grow.
He could just plant seeds out in the
field.
It'll grow on its own.
You know,
you don't even need to help it.
I mean,
it's a really hardy plant and I know a
lot of morons that grow pot and when you
know it's an easy thing to do like that
you can't control that,
you know,
they're,
they're not going to be able to control
it.
There's going to be people selling it
left and right.
They're not going to get taxes from that
because people would just get to
exchange cash or whatever the fuck they
going to do with it.
You're not going to be able to wrap
something up the way they get wrap up
oxycontin's or something like that.
You know,
it's very difficult to produce an
Oxycontin,
you know,
they liked that.
They don't like heroin.
Heroin is just like,
what are you doing?
You're growing a plant and then you're
scraping some shit off the plan and
you're selling never stopped.
That's illegal.
We will let you do that,
but we will let you buy these pills that
are basically the same goddamn thing
that just made by a pharmaceutical
company and they process it and they
make this orally adjustable heroin and
that's what Oxycontin is.
I mean,
it literally,
they call it hillbilly heroin.
It's fucking heroin.
It really is heroin.
You're just eating it,
you know,
you're eating it in a pill form,
just like Marinol is thc in a pill form,
but that stuff's supposed to suck.
I've talked to people that say that
principle thc is link one active element
and marijuana,
there's a whole bunch of two way better
to get the actual stuff from the plant.
You know,
I don't know if that's true with heroin.
I've never done heroin.
I've never done marinol either.
I wouldn't do heroin.
I'm scared of anything that's addictive.
But if I was a musician I might consider
it.
I might,
I might just start a little every now
and then,
you know,
write down and wants today and never
again or something.
Try to convince myself that somehow or
another it wouldn't be addicted.
I don't know how it really is
a.
I hear varying reports.
You know,
the problem I have with toe whenever
someone talks about things being
addictive and not being addicted is that
alcohol is addictive.
You know,
people get addicted to alcohol,
but I'm not addicted to it so I don't
get that.
I mean,
I can,
I could,
if,
if someone told me right now I could
never have another beer or another glass
of wine for the rest of my life,
I'd be like,
okay.
I mean I enjoy it.
I like a habit,
a shot every now and then with my
friends just to get fucking crazy or
shot before shows from.
But realistically it's not that
important,
you know,
I don't need it.
It's not really addictive to me,
but to some people it is.
Okay.
Is that the case with heroin?
Is that the case with cigarettes seem to
be the one they've got the most wired
cigarettes seem to be the one they can
addict the most people to,
you know,
because there's a lot of people that
don't get addicted to the normal stuff.
Like there's a lot of people that drink
coffee and they drink it all the time,
but they can just quit and it doesn't
bother them at all.
And there's some people that they,
if they don't have coffee everyday,
they're fucked.
Those people are addicted to caffeine.
When I was writing my blog,
I was writing a monthly blog right
before I recorded my,
um,
my comedy,
uh,
my m spike TV,
comedy special.
I wanted to make sure I kept my brain
like real sharp.
And I said,
well,
the best way to do that is to perform as
much as I can,
but also write as much as I can.
So I forced myself into writing a blog
every day for a whole month.
And um,
when I did that,
you know,
I was drinking a lot of coffee and I was
drinking French press coffee where it's
like,
it's really fucking strong,
you know,
and I make it strong too.
I like it.
I like a strong cup of coffee,
but the problem is I was drinking this
shit like two,
three cups a day and then I did it like
30 days in a row and there's one point
in time where I didn't drink it for a
day and I had a headache and it was
like,
uh,
oh.
Like my brain was getting accustom to
having all these stimulants in it.
And I realized,
okay,
this is not good.
I got to stop that shit lately.
I've been drinking tea.
Brian turned me onto this thing.
This is like this.
You put the tea leaves in there and then
you put the water in there and you can
like,
you don't have to like have a tea bag.
You get like fresh tea leaves,
taste good.
It's just like,
sometimes I need something warm to
drink.
It's like,
it's just like,
like my friend tate,
he says it best.
I said coffee,
coffee's like a warm hug.
But I got addicted to coffee.
But uh,
I mean it was only for like a couple of
days,
a couple days.
I'm not drinking and just drinking water
and everything was back to normal again
luckily.
But this was 30 days in a row,
not 30 years in a row,
you know,
I couldn't imagine that.
But cigarettes seem to be the one that
they've got the most nailed as to how to
just get you fucking hooked,
you know.
Um,
there's a,
an article that I read recently where
they were discussing all the different
additives that the government allows
them to put into cigarettes and there's
599 of them.
How fucking nuts is that?
There's 599 different chemicals and look
at them,
unless you're some sort of a Pharma
chemists sort of a character,
you're not going to have any idea what
the fuck they are and there's 599 of
them in cigarettes.
I'd say it was just supposed to be
fucking tobacco.
Like what the fuck is going on?
What is that?
I mean is it a procedure or are they
preservatives?
Is it,
is it like that Russell Crowe movie,
the insider is all that shit actually
designed to make it more addictive.
It's one of the most damaging things I
think about politicians is that they
never talked about cigarettes.
You know,
they're always wanted.
They always want to talk about the ill,
no bad drugs out there.
And you know,
this terrible thing that can happen if
your kids get involved in drugs,
but nobody wants a banned cigarettes
like nobody ever says that.
And it's because those fucking tobacco
company spent a bankroll.
I spent a fuck load of money.
What else?
Let me go to the questions here.
Is there a lot of questions and they
keep moving fast.
And I'm a rambling motherfucker.
Joe were a different color shirt in the
UFC broadcast.
Next time.
No knit.
I like wearing black shirts and I get
them for free.
I get clothes from affliction for free,
send me some cool shit so that I don't
make fun of them anymore.
I like their stuff.
I like some other stuff.
There's some scully stuff that was just
a little too scully and Flemmi for me.
But uh,
I got a pair that dragon jeans,
they got dope leather jackets too.
And I liked their,
uh,
the Japanese style stuff.
They had all that.
Uh,
I forget the man's name.
A tattoo artist design a bunch of t
shirts for them that were really fucking
cool.
Like right up my alley,
like Tiger Versus Samurai type stuff.
I've got a bunch of those,
I love those.
But apparently that,
that guy,
uh,
he was selling his same designs to a
couple different tee shirt companies.
They had to get rid of them because it's
a,
some sort of a copyright lawsuit and go
on affliction crows are fucking brutal.
Um,
ed hardy is the most brutal to me.
Ed Hardy Shit.
Assassinate John from John and kate plus
eight because that guy single handedly
made ed hardy shirts.
Like dad is just like,
that's the gold stamp bank Douche bag.
Like when that guy started wearing it
everywhere,
like I think ed hardy was probably
paying him a little.
Did they know that,
uh,
that just put the fucking the Douche
label on the Ed Hardy.
Um,
there's a,
a chick that's a one in the morning djs
in Denver,
missy,
and she calls them Douche Capes,
which is the perfect way to describe
them.
Do capes.
Okay.
Glad you guys liked the raw dog show.
That was fun.
That was real fun.
And my coming to Australia anytime soon,
I'll be in Australia next time the UFC
is going to be there.
I really can't over there for
just to,
just to fly over there.
I don't have the time.
It's too long.
Sixteen fucking hours in the air.
I enjoyed the shit out of it though.
I had a great God damn time that's
drawn.
This man,
dude that's going to fight.
Tim Silvia,
Aaron Davis aspect question.
There's this guy who's like one of the,
uh,
he one strong man competition like many
times and he's scheduled to fight.
Tim Sylvia,
who is a former UFC heavyweight
champion.
I'm looking at flight and everybody's
going,
oh,
what's he?
This is a great fight.
Fight like Tim Sylvia can fight like
just kids.
Ray Mercer knocked him out just because
like he's lost to a couple of different
guys like fate or there's a big goddamn
difference between losing the fader and
losing to a guys had one fight and it's
really good at lifting shit.
That guy's gonna get his ass handed to
him if tense it.
Tim Silvia loses that fight.
There's something wrong.
He's got something wrong with him and he
probably shouldn't fight anymore.
I think tim,
Sylvia,
she'll be able to keep that at bay.
I mean,
it all is,
is big and strong.
I mean,
I just cannot see a world where Tim
Silvia doesn't bomb on that guy as is
coming in,
you know?
I mean,
I could be wrong.
He could just get completely overwhelmed
by the power.
But technique is more important than
power and fighting.
And if one guy,
I mean you can hate on Tim Silvia,
all you want.
The guy was the UFC heavyweight champion
and he wasn't because he sucked.
Go Watch his fight with Rigo Rodriguez,
you know,
watch,
watch some of his fights.
Watched when he had kicked trey
tellerman.
He's fucking dangerous man.
Tim Silvia is one of the most underrated
and under look guys.
Yeah,
he got knocked out by Ray Mercer.
But guess what,
Ray Mercer connects on your head like
that.
Everyone's going out.
He definitely fucked up and he
definitely didn't fight smart in that
fight without a doubt,
but you can't write them off just
because of one performance.
He's still accomplished a lot of
dangerous shit.
He's always been a sucker for that
overhand right.
That's what I shouldn't say a soccer,
but he's getting hit and gotten hit with
it before Randy coture dropped him with
it.
That's where Lawsky hit them with and
that's also obviously what ray mercer
had him with.
You know,
he's got a lazy job.
They said it,
but I think that puts an Ascii guy.
It's like,
wow,
you're.
You're jumping into the deep end of the
pool.
So you know,
Tim Silva is not that old.
Tim Silvia has had some tough fights,
but not that much.
No,
I think that's going to be a real tough
fight for that push guy.
I could be wrong.
He might do those running fucking leg
kicks like it did to that other dude.
We're just basically ran out on like a
bowl,
but that other guy comparing him to Tim
Silvia is just ridiculous.
He's smaller.
He's not as nearly as experienced.
He's just a boxer is.
I mean,
there's so many differences between the
first guy who fought and fighting the
UFC heavyweight champ.
That's fucking,
that's pretty crazy.
He might not even get to him because
he's got to fight in between that and
he's got a fight.
Um,
before that.
I think in April he's fighting someone
else and he's going to fight him silly
right after that.
He might not beat that guy that he's
fighting in April.
I mean,
if a guy knows how to fight,
it's a,
just a big goddamn difference between a
guy who's just strong and he's gonna
leave openings.
Man,
you know,
if he leaves open,
someone's
going to catch on and as soon as you got
to catch them,
you can't put muscles in your face.
And you know,
I mean,
I don't know exactly what kind of a
background he has and fighting other
than being super strong,
but it didn't look like much.
He lived real stiff.
You know what I mean?
Once he hits you,
if he gets a hold of you,
starts hitting you,
you're fucked.
But it's all that before he gets a hold
of you.
Stuff that's like,
it's all Herky Jerky,
you know,
all muscle,
no technique,
you know,
it's uh,
I think it's going to be interesting,
but when you're guys that strong last
year,
we'll learn a few techniques,
get them really good.
Fuck.
I mean,
you're talking about a guy that
literally is one of the strongest men to
walk the planet.
You know,
if you could teach that guy to start
guys,
some,
some solid wrestling,
teach that guy like it's just a good
amount,
you know,
just a few moves.
Just teach them how to keep his hands
up,
close the distance,
teach them some take downs and teach
them to get on top of dudes and just
smash their fucking head.
You know,
a guy like that.
If you taught them some shit,
he would only need a few things just
because he's so God damn strong.
A few things.
You'd be able to beat a lot of guys.
But Tim,
Sylvia,
I don't know,
but that's on.
I don't know about that sign.
Let's see what else we got here.
Um,
I watched a video today of a dude who
cut his fucking balls off the dude.
Somebody posted it on my message board
and this guy says something crazy.
Ozzy man or deranged ozzy man,
the thread cut his balls off.
This guy tied a rubber band around his
balls until his balls,
like literally died.
Like they turned like,
like dead and gray.
And then he hacked his balls off with a
knife.
Really?
Um,
do you want to see it?
If you want to see it.
You know what?
I'll throw the link.
I'll just let everybody know that it's
fucking completely disgusting.
There's no way you should really be
watching this,
but if you want to,
I will copy the link posted on twitter
and I'm gonna say do not watch this.
Okay?
I just posted it on twitter.
Don't watch it.
You don't need to unless,
unless someone has done you wrong and
less and less.
Maybe Sandra bullock is out there.
Sandra,
I know that you've had some tough times
recently and I saw recently a online the
photos of this young lady that Jesse
James allegedly has had an affair with.
And,
uh,
you might want to watch the video of the
guy cut his balls off the rest of you
though.
But this is a message to Sandra bullock.
You need to know,
sweetie,
that there's a broad spectrum to human
beings and human behavior.
And it's,
you know,
life isn't what you see at the craft
service table when everyone's kissing
your ass on the set.
There's a lot of crazy shit out there.
And,
uh,
this crazy fucking skank with a tattoo
on her forehead fucked her husband too.
Mad World,
so fucking mad world.
If you look at Sandra bullock and you
looked at Jesse James,
you know,
you'd say,
well,
you know,
he's a rough fucking handsome character
and she's a beautiful woman and they
make a great couple.
Uh,
and then I showed you this freak with
the tattooed on her head,
this,
this crazy place that he's apparently
been banned.
And I said,
well,
we would.
Do you think that he would cheat on her
for her to be like,
what the fuck is that?
Now he's Jesse James,
right?
This guy's a fucking TV star.
He's married to Sandra bullock.
He's not going to fuck this crazy bitch
with a tattoo on her head,
but yeah I did.
And why did he do it?
Because people I fucking deranged people
are crazy.
They can't help themselves.
They,
they're looking for something to fucking
just to blow energy out somehow to what
are they going to do to some drugs,
cheating on their wife,
drive too fast,
get a motorcycle.
What the fuck are they going to do?
You know,
if you read tiger woods,
his stuff and I can't fucking help it.
Some new scan came out with all his
twitters or not.
Not as twitter as his text messages that
he sent to her.
I'm like,
first of all,
what kind of relationship did he have
with these girls that they would want to
put is like,
didn't even.
I was even friends with them.
It seems like these girls like don't
even,
like they didn't even talk to him.
It seems like,
you know,
like it was this,
this thing was just all fucking.
And because of that I think they were
like,
they felt slighted and that's what I'm
getting out of this.
I'm getting that.
They felt slighted,
you know,
that here's this guy with the most
squeaky clean image in the world and
this image is what he used to make a ton
of money and you know,
he's like a super successful guy at the
most lucrative sport in the world and
the sport,
the most connected to money to big
businesses to mean so many.
Like it's so important to be like the
best golfer ever.
I'm like,
God,
it's just such a huge thing like to
market and sell that.
And so here's this guy.
And meanwhile he's just a dirty bitch
just talking about taking it out of
their ass,
stuffing in their mouth.
I'll add those in as texts like this
motherfucker was crazy.
You know,
it's,
it's pretty clear that it's,
it's more than just,
Oh,
you know,
he thought he could get away with it.
Oh,
well,
you know,
he's just a man and men are,
after.
No,
no,
no.
He was deranged.
Alright,
people are crazy.
He was getting a wild thrill from doing
this thing that he wasn't supposed to be
doing.
It was all like naughty,
shitty.
Want to Piss on girls to saying I want
to give you a golden shower,
but the crazy thing is tiger woods or
sending tax.
I want to stuff my cock and your ass.
Now put it in your mouth like,
whoa.
Tiger.
Like,
man,
if you're going to send a text like that
to someone,
you've got to make sure that that person
is your friend saying you can just.
If you're fucking tiger woods,
you can't just go send in text like
that.
The people you know,
you got to go,
Hey,
I'm.
If I sent you a text and it's really
crazy,
will you promise me that you won't sell
this later?
You gotta say something you get just,
just fucking free ball like that.
Tiger,
tiger woods.
Have any fucking friends because I feel
like if he had any friends they were
going to.
What are you doing?
Like you're banging waitresses and
people are watching,
you know,
like you're gonna.
You can take it down a notch,
you know,
get,
get a hooker who has something to lose.
But who has something to lose in
comparison to him though?
Nobody.
If you're a guy like that,
you can never trust anybody,
you know,
if that's what you're doing.
If you're a,
a wild guy that likes to cheat on your
wife and you're a fucking billionaire,
super squeaky clean character,
who the fuck can you trust?
Like that guy?
Man,
I want to predict that he would have to
go somewhere where they didn't know who
he was.
He'd have to go to like Malaysia to
cheap.
Poor Fella.
All right.
What do I think at James?
Tony.
I'm disturbed by James.
Tony is his recent speeches,
you know?
Um.
Oh.
I don't know what's going on with him
physically.
You know?
I don't know.
I guess he wants to fight heavyweight.
I've heard that.
He says he wants to fight Brock Lesnar.
If that's the case,
I think maybe the best thing to do to
get this over with and just give him
brock lesnar.
I mean if Dave James,
Tony Loses to somebody.
The way I look at it as like James,
Tony,
obviously all the respect in the world
as a boxer of all time,
you know,
really one of the craftiest guys to come
along in decades and a guy who really
utilize that old,
like Archie Moore shoulders,
shoulder roll style,
like had a real classic old timers
boxing style,
like real good at like,
like rolling with punches.
Then coming back,
let's just counter right hand is against
John Ruiz.
There's like a youtube clip of him.
Like you see how beautiful his timing
was and like when he just destroyed
evander holyfield in their fight.
Man,
he's a so he's so skillful as a boxer,
very,
very skillful,
but there's so much more to mma than
just boxing.
And I'm not hearing about him going to
American top team.
I'm not hearing about him going to team
quest.
I'm not hearing about him going to,
you know,
to like high level camps to work with
big wrestlers to get.
I tried to take him down because
otherwise I'm hearing him say he's gonna
fight.
Brock Lesnar,
I'm hearing one of two things.
I'm either here and he doesn't give a
fuck,
he's just here to get paid or I'm
hearing he is crazy and he thinks that
he's going to be able to stop brock
lesnar from taking them down by hitting
him with a punch.
The either one is not good because one
of them means he's delusional.
That he doesn't really understand what
this is all about and the other one
means that he's just a guy who was
looking for money.
Either one is not that good.
I don't know.
You know,
Boxing is a tough Goddamn game and when
you've been in it,
as long as James Tony as a,
even though he doesn't take that much
punishment,
you know,
you gotTa,
you gotta realize these guys at a
certain point in time,
you know,
they only have the only have a certain
amount more punches you can take,
you know,
at a certain.
There's a finite number after that
number,
you're fucked.
You know,
and I think that the thing with James
Tony is he has this incredible
confidence in his hands and he really
truly believes that if a guy like brock
was,
tries to take him down,
that he's going to be able to connect in
with those little gloves,
he's going to put them to sleep.
I think it's looks a lot easier than it
is.
That's what I think.
I think if he starts training with high
level guys,
he goes and you know,
work out with,
you know,
a chemo workout with some of my high
level wrestlers and see how easy it is
for those guys that take you down.
You know,
you think you're just going to catch up
with an upper cut.
You can't throw punches the same way
when you're worried about a guy taking
you down.
You don't know.
The timing is not the same.
You can't stand the same way.
If you stand the same way,
they're going to kick your legs out and
they're going to take you down easy.
So you have to change your stance.
So now I have to change your stance as a
boxer.
You have to constantly be thinking about
sprawling,
constantly be thinking about getting
your under hook set.
It's not.
It's not the same sport.
It's not the punching ability that he
asks is a huge plus and it'll
definitely,
if anybody is stupid enough to not try
to take them down and just box with him,
you're going to get your clock cleaned.
You know for sure he's going to hit you
with some precise counter punches.
He's going to take advantage of little
tiny minute openings because really he's
such a high level box or we don't see
that high level striker in the octagon.
He can make God look foolish if somebody
chose some crazy boxer,
you know in the UFC,
a guy who's got good hands chose to try
to stand up,
just stand up with James,
Tony.
He would make them look like a fool.
He really would really demoralized that.
He would talk shit to them.
He was bitch,
bitch,
and he would keep just land and punches
on you.
He will fuck your world up,
but I don't think they're going to do
that.
I think guys are going to do one or two
things.
They're going to kick the living fuck
out of his legs or they're just going to
take them now and I don't think he's
going to mail stop that.
I don't think he's going to stop though.
I don't think,
you know,
if he got like a,
a big Jujitsu guy gets all the women
like,
uh,
like Nepal,
Gabriel,
Gonzaga,
Gonzaga got a hold of Jesus Christ.
He might just start breaking pieces of
them off,
you know?
And if God help him,
if Brock Lesnar wants to take them down,
you can't,
we can't just catch that guy with a
punch.
That's not enough.
Okay.
That's,
that's enough for your average regular
human brock lesnar.
That's,
that's a freak of a man that's like the
high end of the genetic spectrum or you
like,
you know,
you can have a dude who looks like a
kabod crane.
You know,
you could have a dude who looks like,
you know,
like who is olive oil?
And that Popeye movie was that bitches.
No pictures.
I'm so mean shelly.
Something,
another,
whatever her name is real stink of
Lindsay Lohan.
You can have a Lindsay Lohan frame,
you know,
a Paris Hilton,
the frame low skinny body or you have
the high end.
You have brock or some weird instance
where,
you know,
Vikings,
Vikings for generation after generation
and their warrior bloodlines were passed
on and this motherfucker living in the
woods in Minnesota,
you know,
he got the best of the best fucking head
is that big.
You know,
I mean that guy for sure has good
wrestling for short works very hard and
his technique and all that's well and
good,
but at the end of the day,
that motherfucker is a barbarian.
The reason why he so fucking good he is
at direct descendants from ancient giant
warriors from thousands of years ago.
That's that in a regular dude,
man.
You ain't going to just be able to punch
that guy and send him home pack and now
he's going to eat your punch and he's
going to pick you up in the air like
you're a pillow and you're going to feel
so bad.
You're going to feel terrible.
The feeling that you're going to have of
helplessness and hopelessness when that
fucking gorilla grabs a hold of you and
yanks you up in the air and smashes you
and it gets on top of you and starts
those big fucking lunchbox fists.
That's a wrap,
son.
You're done.
Okay.
You're not.
You're not going to jab and shoulder.
Roll your way away from Brock Lesner.
He's gonna.
Fuck you.
He's going to do whatever he wants to
you.
He's going to have you work for him.
You're going to own him.
He's gonna.
Be He's gonna.
Be Your master.
He's going to put a dog collar on you.
He's going to do whatever the fuck you
want.
Do you not understand that?
Like that guy can do whatever he wants
to you.
If we didn't live in this civilized
culture thousands years ago,
everyone that brock lesnar fought would
be chained up in his yard.
They would work for him and they would
just hope and pray that brock doesn't
get angry and decided to fuck you up
today.
You know?
That's,
that's a scary dude,
man.
You know?
Is he the best guy in the world?
I don't know,
he's got to fight door.
He's got to fight chain car.
When you know these guys,
we've got to see what happens.
We got to see what happens with fucking
Cain Velasquez.
Cain Velasquez,
a motherfucker.
Whoa.
That guy's a frighteningly talented.
Frighteningly talented,
and frighteningly dedicated,
you know,
incredible technique to and everything.
He is his punches,
his take downs,
his kicks,
everything is perfect technique.
There's no fluff in his,
in his technique is no fat.
You know,
there's no like,
excess movement like the way he throws
leg kicks,
Goddamn beautiful.
Just perfect technique.
The way throws punches.
Same thing.
Everything is perfect technique.
His endurance is second to none.
You know,
I'm super,
super impressed with Cain Velasquez.
I think he's just,
he's amazing.
You know,
the big question is,
does all that amazing cardio and
technique and,
and,
and the discipline,
does that make up for the great white
warrior?
You know,
does it make up for that big fucking
freak of a monster?
Like Brock Lesnar?
You know,
that's an angry mother fucker dude.
When a dude beat your ass like you did
to Frank Mir and then still get to the
fucking cameras,
start screaming,
he's screaming and spits,
coming out of his mouth and his
mouthpiece has fallen out and you're
like,
what the fuck did you just beat his ass?
And you're still mad.
And then it gets in Frank Mir phase
fucking talking shit.
And like,
whoa.
Like that's.
That is a guy who's got a lot of pent up
shit.
I mean,
when you're 290 fucking plus pounds of
muscle and your bodies covered with
swords,
he's got like swords and skulls and
death.
It's all like axes and swords and
destruction.
It actually says kill them all and his
lower back.
He's got a like a tramp stamp that says,
kill 'em.
All Eem all.
Whoa,
whoa.
Who's that?
Therefore it's a scary fucking dude,
man.
That's a real angry motherfucker.
And it's real interesting to see,
you know,
I would love to.
I really want to see him versus fate or
that is a very,
very intriguing fight to me because they
represent such polar opposites in fate
or you have a guidance,
you know,
relatively small heavyweight.
He's just about six feet tall.
He weighs about 2:30
and he's got a considerable amount of
fat on them.
I mean,
I would say like probably at least 20
pounds of fat.
Like he's got a lot of jiggly fat.
He doesn't try to lose weight at all.
You know,
he just says,
I'm a heavy weight.
This is it.
This is what I weigh.
I'm going to fight as a heavyweight.
You know,
there's a broad contrast between him,
his personality,
he's very stoic.
You,
you never see any expression out of him.
I mean everybody like comments on the
fact that the dude like never seemed
angry,
never makes a mean face.
Never seen it her,
no matter if he's cut or no matter if
he's got the guy hurt and he's finishing
them off,
he's just got this dead expression.
Whereas Brock Lesner is giant.
Dantic has to cut weight to make to 65.
He's a guy who,
you know,
is at the very top of the weight class
and he's a guy who is just flooded with
emotion,
flooded with anger,
flooded with expression.
I mean he wears,
he is one of those no nonsense
motherfuckers.
He wears who he is out on his sleeve,
you know,
and he likes to talk a little shit and
he gets angry at people and he likes to
swear and you know,
I mean he's,
he likes to stick the bird out the
audience and you know,
when they bloom,
fuck you,
you know,
and he's,
he's a totally different dude.
I'd be very curious to see those two
approaches and see which one would
ultimately prevail because it's really
not.
I mean it is fair,
but it's not fair because brock is so
much goddamn bigger.
Brock is a lean to 65 and when he's 65,
he's cutting a little weight to get down
there.
You know,
he'll drop some waterway,
like maybe 10,
15 pounds,
you know,
to get down.
So He's inflated,
you know,
well up to like to 80 by the time he
actually gets into the octagon.
You know,
just solid as a fucking house at two 80,
whereas fader,
you know,
at 2:30,
that's 50 pounds less is not nearly as
solid fader at 2:30
is,
you know,
he's jiggly w,
it doesn't matter if you connect to your
face,
you know he's a bad ass puncher.
His jujitsu is fantastic.
His grappling is fantastic.
He's great off of his back,
but there's a.
that's a big difference man.
You know,
when all things are equal,
and I'm not saying they are skill wise
because I do not believe they are.
I think Faye doors more skillful and has
more options to win the fight,
but progress so fucking big.
He's so much bigger when you're talking
about 50 pounds of bone and muscle 50
fucking pounds.
That's a significant advantage.
And then on top of that you're dealing
with a guy who's this freak athlete,
you know,
it's not just that he's big like big and
lumbering.
Like they've had guys that were big and
lumbering dudes that have fought in mma
before.
They just,
they were never like this motherfucker.
The way brock moves,
he moves like a light guy,
even though he's a giant guy.
He's a freak athlete,
you know,
I mean,
he really is the descendants of some
fucking crazy warrior tribe.
That's why he's got all this,
you know,
angry energy to them.
That's shit's genetic.
A lot of it got to be.
So that's my answer to that question.
Alright.
That was the going off of
the Ustream Shit.
So I don't want to go to the Joe Rogan
Dot net forum.
Yeah.
We'll see what kind of questions we got
up in that bitch.
Got Two pages of questions and a lot of
them were joke questions.
Jokey,
jokey joke.
Bb.
John says,
Hey Joe,
what do you know?
Wow.
Is that a rhetorical question?
I know.
Uh,
Not enough my friend.
No,
not enough.
Nor do any of us.
That is the great unfortunate truth.
Let's see.
How do you feel about the pope knowing
that child sex abuse was going on and he
didn't say anything about it when he was
a priest in Germany?
I think they're all fucking freaks.
I think there's
only one way you can be a guy who
dedicates her entire life to not having
sex.
The only way is you're a sexual deviant.
There's something wrong with you.
I don't believe there's any priest that
aren't really completely fucked up.
I think it's one of the craziest ways
that anyone could ever make,
make a living,
get through life.
It doesn't make any sense to me.
You're a,
you're a fucking priest,
so wait a minute.
Do you get to a different heaven than
the people that get posted and get to
have a good time?
No,
you get to the same heaven,
so by doing what you do,
what everybody has to listen to you and
give you money and you get to fuck the
kids.
Like what is that about?
It doesn't make any sense because it
totally goes against what the idea of
religion should be all about.
Religion should be all about.
It's like God's word to everyone on how
to live your life.
Why did.
How come these guys that spread God's
word,
they don't get to have sex.
What's that about?
Why?
Why do they?
Why are they so fucked up?
I'll tell you why.
Because initially preset too much
goddamn power.
You know,
a long time ago,
priests were allowed to have sex,
but the problem was they were fucking
everyone because those are the guys that
were in charge of God.
Those were the guys that were talking to
God.
Those were the guys that were.
They were at the front of the fucking
God line.
They had the Willy Wonka golden ticket
and they were reading the word of God
and in a village,
you know of several hundred people,
the guy who's the fucking priest who
speaks the word of God and has to
console all these women and you know
maybe these women there with husbands
that are tired of fucking him and this
priest would love to take step in and
take some of that.
What's up?
I'll give you some God knowledge.
Now you give me some head and that shit
was going on left and right.
And that's why priest camp.
Fuck.
The reason why priests aren't a lot of
fuck is because they were fucking
everybody.
So then,
well,
who the hell wants to be present?
You can't fuck.
You know?
Once they told him they couldn't fuck
anymore,
what did they do while they probably
some of them probably kept fucking and
said,
yeah,
I'll stop.
And they kept banging people.
Then they got caught and they probably
got flogged or something terrible like
that.
And so then they really cracked down and
made sure that the priests are not
allowed to have sex anymore.
Well,
once they started doing that,
then the only people that want to be
priests were either gays who could be
with other priests and they just keep it
on the sneak,
sneak and bag each other or pedophiles
because they had access to all these
children.
These children had listened to them.
The overwhelming amount,
I mean just,
it hurts your head to think about how
many fucking kids had been sexually
abused by the Catholic Church.
I mean,
it really hurts your head.
It really hurts to think that all these
people are so blinded by a fucking fairy
tale,
that they're willing to let some
criminal,
some monster fuck their kids after all
these years.
The fact that that is still going on
that is mind boggling.
It is mind boggling that we pay any
attention to this silly caught and no
one can save this.
No politician can say this because for
sure no one's going to vote for you if
you come out and say this is nonsense
and if there is a god for sure.
These are not his words.
This is the word of man.
How the.
I mean if you just analyze religion.
I mean just as.
I mean let's let's say that once upon a
time it was word of the word of God.
Who the fuck knows?
I don't know.
You don't know.
I mean,
if there really is a god,
I always say that I've done things that
were so much crazier than the stories
that people tell about heaven.
When you smoke DMT and you've
communicated and another dimension with
beings that are made out of love and
understanding and they're.
They're super knowledgeable.
They know everything about life and
everything about you.
When you've seen something like that and
someone wants to talk to you and tell
you that they've seen,
you know,
a guy in the cloud with a harp and who
are you to tell him that he's full of
shit.
You're talking about something that
you've actually experienced that I've
actually experienced.
It's way more fucking crazy than angels
with wings and a dude in the clouds with
a big book of who gets in and who
doesn't.
That's way less crazy than the things
that I've actually experienced and this
thing that you actually experienced when
you die.
This dmt to stuff that when you die,
this is what your brain produces when
you're in heavy rem sleep.
This is what your brain produces a
natural part of human neurochemistry and
it lets you see something way crazier
than what these religious people are
talking about.
So who am I to say that there's no god.
There may be.
Maybe there is a fucking village and the
clouds.
Maybe it's all true,
but just studying the actual words.
If you know the the history of how the
Bible was made,
that the ancient ancient Hebrew,
which will be the original Old Testament
was written in the original Bible,
written ancient Hebrew,
was there.
To this day,
they only know three out of four of
those words for this day,
like today,
25 percent of the words in ancient
Hebrew.
They're like,
who the fuck knows?
Not only that there was no numbers in
ancient Hebrew letters doubled as
numbers,
so like the letter a was also the number
one and there was numerical value to
words that is completely lost in the
translation to Greek and Latin.
Like the word law of the word love and
the word of God have the same numerical
value and this numerical value,
the value of these words.
It's like it was very important to the
translation of what you know,
what,
what it was,
what was meant.
All that is missing.
When they translated that and then
eventually to English.
All that's missing,
and then you got the New Testament,
which is just complete wackiness because
constantine who wasn't even a fucking
Christian created this,
and this is just clearly a ploy to try
to control people.
Constantine got together with a bunch of
bishops and they wrote it all out and
there's stuff that they left in and
stuff they stick out.
So the New Testament,
which is literally made hundreds of
years after Christ was supposed to be
dead.
Who the fuck knows what that's all
about?
Who knows?
But only you need to know is the guy
even wrote.
It wasn't even a Christian.
Like right before he died.
He converted unbelieve and you know it
was.
It was very constantine won and he was
an emperor or you want to control people
and that's what it's best at.
It's so good at controlling people that
you'll let pedophiles fuck your kids
because they have the fucking,
the magic fairytale golden ticket.
It's mind boggling.
It's mind boggling that this goofy fuck
in a crazy outfit.
This cult leader gets special treatment.
They'll make fun of the moonies.
They'll make fun of scientologists,
but the fucking pope on TV,
somehow another gets to be national
news,
this crazy fuck who's not allowed to
have sex,
who hangs out with a bunch of crazy Fox
who aren't allowed to have sex and every
rock you fucking pick up.
There's a priest fucking a kid
underneath it.
I mean,
it's just throughout their entire
organization.
There are thousands and thousands and
thousands of cases every fucking year.
New ones pop up every fucking year.
Some new scandal about how they knew
this guy was fucking kids and so they
moved him to New Mexico or some shit.
I mean,
it's really shocking that Catholic
people are even going to church anymore.
It's completely shocking that there's
still people that they trick.
Just the sheer weight of its own
bullshit should have collapsed the
Catholic religion a long fucking time
ago and this is coming from someone who
was raised a Catholic.
I went to Catholic school when I was in
first grade one year I went to Catholic
school and it was such a fucking
horrendous nightmare.
I don't remember second grade,
I don't remember it.
I remember first grade though,
like a motherfucker,
because first grade was the only year
that I was in Catholic school.
I remember this fucking cunt sister Mary
Josephine's is evil,
evil woman who used to tell you that if
you didn't get your homework done,
you have to sit on a nail in the closet
overnight.
She would smack you in the head.
I mean,
it was real shit.
If you cried,
if you were upset about something,
she would make fun of you.
You know,
look at it.
That's why I'm crying.
She was just no compassion,
no love,
no friendship,
no warmth.
It was all evil.
It was all anger and evil and that is
what that relationship is.
It is unnatural.
It's not real.
This relationship to life where you're a
person who's in charge of some nonsense
fairytale and because of that you get to
shit on people and yell at their kids
and hit their fucking kids and treat
them like shit because you somehow or
another are special because you're one
of those people that doesn't fuck and
you have what?
You have more access to God and I know
you don't even have more access.
You're not.
If anything,
it's the craziest,
most ridiculous cult ever and it's still
going on and if that's not a a damning
condemnation of human beings and human
culture today in 2010 with the age of
information with the Internet,
with all this,
that we still have the Catholic religion
that that stupid shit is still around.
It's mind boggling.
Without a doubt.
If there is a god that's not what he
wants.
If there is a god,
what God is is the energy that creates
everything you know.
It might not be a conscious thing or it
might be all conscious things together
as one thing in some sort of a framework
that we can't even recognize because
it's so big.
It's so great that literally,
you know when someone,
some hippie says,
hey,
you are God and God's you would.
If that's true.
What if that really is true?
What if our purpose on this life has
shielded us from that recognition
because we have to go through whatever.
We have to go through it like we're here
for a reason that we're pushing humanity
and human culture and human innovation
forward for reason,
you know,
probably some sort of fucking,
some sort of a technological thing that
we're going to create that's going to
enter us into the new age.
But if that's the case,
he said that we just lacked a perception
to really understand that we're in tune
with anything,
with everything,
with the whole world.
Then that makes sense that everything is
God and that's the feeling that you get
when you do mushrooms.
When you do mushrooms,
you get this feeling of connectedness
that you are attached when you do dmt as
well,
which is very similar to,
to mushrooms in what it is.
Chemically,
what dmt is his dime methyl tryptamine
what mushrooms are cubensis mushrooms is
for Fox for a boxy and,
and dimethyltryptamine.
So they're very closely,
chemically related.
And um,
you have this intense feeling of
connection with everything,
with people you know,
with the friends in your life,
with animals,
with,
with wilderness,
with.
I mean,
that's why they say do mushrooms and go
into nature.
Because when you do,
when you have some mushrooms and you're
laying in a in a,
you know,
I'm in the woods,
in a plot of trees you'll,
you'll like,
you feel like the energy of the trees.
It's like some Avatar type shit like you
really feel like the fucking tree of is
communicating with you.
I think that our,
our main problem as human beings is that
we are in a stage of evolution and we're
in an adolescent stage and we are
certainly passing where we used to be
and our just our potential for evolving
above the basic fight or flight
instincts and our potential for evolving
above just just animal brutality and
anger and jealousy and all these things
that we think that we need in order to
compete and survive.
We have potential to rise above that and
that's what yoga is all about and that's
what meditation is all about in
isolation tanks and people who are a
psychedelic enthusiasts.
What,
that's what that's all about is this,
this struggle up this slippery slope to
get to the top to have just a little
better view of what the world could be.
And I think that that's what,
that's the potential that we have inside
of us.
It's all moving towards that,
you know,
human understanding,
human,
the idea of human enlightenment,
you know,
this,
this quest to get your shit together.
It's all moving away from these
nonsensical animal instincts to
something higher and more evolved and I
think that potential is the only good
thing that human beings have.
It's like we have this potential for one
side or the other.
We have this potential to be like,
you know,
like an evil government that corrupts
citizens or we have this potential to be
a brother.
We have this potential to be a sister.
We have to potentially be someone who
loves you.
Like they love family life.
They love themselves,
you know?
I mean,
I have a buddy that as a kid,
and we were talking about babies
recently and we were just joking around.
He's a comic as well.
Gene Pompa last night at the Improv and
we're just talking about,
and I've had this conversation with
other people too about how it makes you
like so much nicer person.
And I said that like,
man,
if everybody treated everybody the way I
treat my daughter would have fucking
beautiful world we would live in,
would just be a world of warmth and
friendship.
And you know,
if we just had a pill that made you love
everybody the way I love my daughter and
we do have a pill like that.
It's called ecstasy.
But that's,
it's terrible for you.
And the next day you feel like shit and
it hurts your head.
But,
um,
if we figured out a way and maybe we're
going to do that,
I mean maybe that's what the next stage
of evolution really is all about.
Maybe it's an evolution pill,
you know,
maybe,
uh,
you know,
some people will take the evolution
vaccine and some people won't and
they'll shoot your arm with some shit
that lasts six months and it's some
vaccination against stupidity.
Some vaccination against against
nonsense,
against a lack of understanding and
appreciation of the fact that we're here
in this temporary situation as one
gigantic hive,
one super organism,
and that the more love you spread out
in,
the more positive energy you spread out,
the more you get back,
you know,
the more it comes back to affect you and
it goes out and ripples because the
people that you affect,
they affect other people as well and the
more positive you spread out of
literally you can change your world.
You can change the world of the people
that you come in contact with.
You know,
I think that is what human beings are
slowly starting to realize and that may
be what God really is,
what God might be,
is everything.
What it's not is a bunch of dudes in
fucking robes that want to have sex with
your kids.
Okay,
that's not God.
That's nonsense.
And the fact that these fucking
presidential candidates and all these
knuckleheads that want to be world
leaders and they want to guide us
towards,
you know,
the.
They're not guiding us towards anything.
It's business as usual.
There's no evolution whatsoever in the
political process.
There's no evolution whatsoever amongst
these fuckheads that talk.
They are decades and decades behind the
Progressive American culture that the
people that are at the front of the line
of thinking,
these motherfuckers are decades behind.
You know,
this idea of religious freedom.
Yes,
I agree.
you should have the freedom to study
religiously.
You should have the freedom to do
whatever you want.
You don't feed the flying Spaghetti
Monster.
That's your thing.
That's fine.
You know,
but you can't take it seriously like
you,
you can't expect someone who is.
I mean that.
That is the whole idea of the separation
of church and state.
The whole idea is like some sort of a
concede conceding somehow that,
okay,
you're allowed to believe really
ridiculous shit.
How about this?
How about we just leave all the religion
now and all we concentrate on is how
things are run business,
how we treat each other,
what laws we enforce,
how you make sure that people aren't
being victimized.
These fucking politicians and these
newspapers and all these people that,
that really follow all this pope
bullshit.
They just add credence to it because
knuckleheads read about in the news.
So they think it's legitimate.
I had a conversation with someone where
they were saying that,
you know,
that um,
uh,
we were talking about cults and I said,
well,
I was watching a documentary and it's
really fascinating.
Was a documentary on Christianity and
they kept referring it to the cult of
Christianity.
That's how they're referring it to in
this,
you know,
the very scientific documentary.
And this woman was very upset.
She was like,
Christianity is not called.
And I'm like,
why?
How can you say it's not cool?
And she's like,
well,
because first of all,
you don't have a cult that has billions
of people in it.
Yes you do.
But it's just a bigger call.
Like if you ever caught that as three
people,
if you can trick three people,
you can trick 3 million.
Okay?
If you can find three people dumb enough
to believe your wackiness and they let
you fuck them.
And they were purple Nike's because you
tell them that's the sacred color.
If you get three people to do that and
they really believe it,
they're going to get more people to
believe it.
We are all going through this life
completely clueless.
These we are like people in a spaceship
that woke up from hyper sleep and we're
going through the manuals and no one
knows how to run the ship.
That's what we are alike and there's a
few of us that are older that are
pretending to the younger people.
Listen,
don't worry,
we've got this.
Everything's going to be fine.
We're going to have a meeting with
Congress to work on this house and these
people are trying to placate the rest of
us who are just like them and no one
knows what the fuck is going on.
So anybody that steps up and tells you
that they have all the answers,
that God wants this for you and God
wants that.
No,
you don't know.
Those are the enemy.
Anybody that says they have the answers,
they're your enemy.
And anybody who wants your money,
they're your enemy to you.
You know,
give me a fucking show.
All right,
don't just stand there and recite some
stupid Latin Shit and pass around a
basket because you're too lazy to work
for a living.
You Fuck No.
If you,
if you want to be the real messenger,
the word of God,
you wouldn't be asking for money.
Okay?
Stop it.
People would be giving my new because
they love you.
You wouldn't have a fucking basket.
You pass around and make everybody feel
guilty.
Fuck you.
That's,
that's nonsense.
That's silly,
goddamn nonsense.
And until we acknowledge that,
until we acknowledge that that is our
own insecurities that are asking us to
search for an answer to something that's
impossible to answer,
to acknowledge that we're fucked,
we're just spinning.
Our wheels were in the same spot.
We've always been,
you know,
and that that is the problem.
The real problem is everybody wants to
pretend that there's an answer to
something that you cannot answer.
There is no answer.
It is absolutely impossible.
And if,
if there is a god,
it's probably so much more complex than
you could ever possibly wrap your
fucking head around.
And I'll tell you what,
it's not,
uh,
Adam and eve,
okay.
It's not God made to people and you
know,
they fucked and they had kids and the
kids started fucking each other because
that's what Adam and eve is.
There's only two people.
He just one of the.
That's like any child with a simple
grasp of mathematics and five minutes to
think about it,
you'd say,
okay,
I'm going to tell you the story of Adam
and eve.
You tell me what you think is wrong with
that.
They would go,
okay,
if Adam and eve made people,
everybody came from Adam and eve,
everybody the whole world.
Okay.
If Adam and eve made people.
So they had kids and the kids were like,
they were brothers and sisters.
How did they make more people?
There we go.
No,
they fucked each other.
They fucked each other.
The Adam fuck the kids.
And he fucked the kids and the kids
fucked each other.
And that's where people came from.
What?
It's 2010.
No one has any fucking answer.
No one got damaged except maybe
Gangstarr gangstarr has got the answer.
So that's my long answer to a short
question.
Fuck the pope.
Fuck all those dummies.
Fuck anybody that tells you they've got
it wired.
No,
no,
stupid.
No.
You don't have it wired and you got to
get a real job now.
Okay.
It's 2010.
If the whole world got on mushrooms,
the Catholic religion would implode.
Okay.
They would have to go out and start
kidnapping kids to fuck because nobody
would bring their kids to him anymore.
You know,
it's,
it's a corrupt criminal organization of
kid fuckers.
That's what it is.
Do I have any idea how last dance?
No,
those fucks I.
I been trying to not tune in.
I'm going to be on Adam Carolla's
podcast real soon,
I think next week.
Actually.
I'll tell you right now because I'm on
the fucking Internet.
Harlow.
I liked them apples.
I love the Internet.
It's easily my favorite human creation.
I'm so addicted and it's killing my
vision.
I have a hard time reading things when
they're up close now.
Okay.
Let's say had a corolla.
Yes.
Next week.
The 23rd.
So next Tuesday,
the 23rd,
I'll be doing the Adam Carolla podcast.
However,
I don't know exactly what time the
podcast.
I'm a one time,
he puts it up.
So that's my answer to that,
but I'll be doing it next Tuesday,
the 23rd.
All right.
More questions
bad.
Bobby says,
Joe,
I once read,
if they legalized all drugs it could
cost the USA 150,000
good jobs and cops,
lawyers and so forth.
I don't know if it's true,
but I believed the war on drugs is a
makeup make work project.
Forget about if they're getting some
profits and selling them.
I don't know if it's true,
but it sounded right.
Yeah,
there's definitely though.
The war on drugs is definitely look the
between the private prisons and between
a law enforcement.
There's an industry and keeping drugs
illegal and it's not about protecting
you.
You know some drugs.
Yes,
it is.
You know when,
when they go and close down crystal meth
labs.
Yeah.
That's a fucking danger because crystal
meth makes people.
It completely fucks with their judgment.
Makes them insane.
Liquid did the Jesse James.
He fucked that bitch with a tattoo on
her head.
I guarantee that dude was doing meth
when he fucked her.
There's no way he was sober.
You don't fuck chicks with tattoos on
their head when you're sober.
When you see ambition has pray for
sinners tattooed on her fucking
forehead.
You Go,
what?
And she's ugly.
Oh yeah.
Let me stick my Ra Dick Inside.
You know,
that guy was doing drugs and there's
drugs that are bad for you.
Okay.
And Crystal Meth is one of them and said
terrible,
terrible drug,
you know,
is another one.
I mean,
I've seen cocaine turn people into
their,
like they become like,
like roaches.
They become like bugs,
you know that like they don't,
they don't thinking about human and just
trying to get that shit.
I don't like get that shit.
You know?
They literally get black sharp guys.
They turn dead on the inside.
Man.
There's drugs that are terrible for you
and those drugs.
Yeah.
I could see an argument for them being
illegal.
I could see an argument for us doing
something about the people that sell
them because they're,
they're damaging people.
It's dangerous,
but there's other drugs like mushrooms
and pot.
If you get caught with those things,
man,
it doesn't matter.
Those are still illegal drugs.
As a matter of fact,
they're more illegal than heroin.
Do you know that?
Schedule One drugs for the most part are
the drugs that really have like use
schedule one is the most illegal.
Okay?
Schedule One is DMT,
which your own brain produces.
So as Terence Mckenna,
he said,
uh,
everyone's holding.
I mean,
that's really,
really what it is.
You are in production,
in production and in you.
You are in possession of a really
illegal substance.
The number one to schedule one,
dmt a marijuana schedule.
One.
No one's ever died.
Pot ever.
Do you know what?
It can't.
The only way pot is going to kill you is
if you're standing on the wrong side of
the fence.
When one of those Mexican drug
helicopters comes over and pushes a bail
out at clubs you on the fucking head,
that's how you die for pot.
Other than that,
you're not going to die for pot.
You might think you're dying,
but you're just gonna fall asleep.
And you're going to be fine.
No one's fucking died of it ever,
but yet still pot is scheduled.
One mushrooms,
same thing.
I've never heard of anybody dying for
mushrooms.
You can definitely dive.
You eat poison mushrooms,
but poison buffered by the way are
illegal and you could have poisoned
mushrooms all around your backyard and
you can munch on them all day and
fucking die of a heart attack and nobody
gives a shit.
No one's going to have a.
it's not going to be a big inquest.
No one's going to go crazy.
But if you,
if you put psilocybin mushrooms in your
yard and the cops come and find them
growing in your yard,
they will lock you in a fucking cage.
Even though psilocybin mushrooms,
they can make you go crazy if you do too
many of them.
And if you have a weak mental
constitution,
I could see you going crazy for
mushrooms.
Just too much information,
too much realization.
But you could go crazy from anything.
You can go crazy from paint.
You know you could,
you could have pain,
you know,
sniff pain,
blow your fucking brains out.
You can go crazy for anything and
there's a lot,
some people are weak and fragile and
there's uh,
any really extreme experience can fuck
them up.
There's an ant that,
uh,
I think it's called an iron and I forget
the name of the amt,
but this ant bites you and the venom is
so intense and horrify that it's been
described as slamming your arm into a
car door for an hour.
That's what it feels like.
Just slamming your arm.
Imagine what that would feel like.
And it lasts for 24 hours.
What?
So this intense,
insane,
throbbing.
Like literally you're getting ripped
apart,
like someone slamming a door on your arm
and it lasts a whole day and the
experience is so traumatic that some
people when they come out of it,
they are never the same again.
They're just a shell there just so
fucked up.
They could not get through the pain of
one full 24 hour period.
The like there's some shit in the world
that could fuck you up.
Okay.
That's not why marijuana is illegal.
That's not what mushrooms are illegal.
They're illegal because they're trying
to keep you from them.
They don't want,
they don't want a society that is
questioning leadership.
They don't want a society.
And that's the other problem.
The people that are in power,
they're not using these things
throughout human history.
Shamans have been the leaders of tribes
and Shamans have been the ones that the
tribe will go to when the tribe has
troubles and what the Shamans are,
where people who had a lot of experience
and navigating psychedelic dimensions
and in the Amazon,
when you know,
they would all sit around and drink
IOWASCA.
Iowasca is a,
uh,
an herb,
a like a tea that they brew with that,
that produces dmt.
And it's uh,
the,
uh,
ordinarily DMT is not.
You can't drink it because it gets
broken down when you take it in orally.
When you eat it,
it gets broken down by something in your
stomach called monell aiming oxidase and
it's produced in your gut.
And this Iowasca was a way that they
figured out how to extract DMT and Amano
aiming oxidase inhibitor from another
planet.
It's really fucking crazy.
I mean,
they've been doing this for 10,000
years and a place where there's 250,000
plus different species of plants.
They figured out a way to combine two to
make this incredible brew that lets you
communicate with,
with the afterlife and which by the way
is totally illegal.
You know?
I mean,
it's a mess.
You know,
it's,
it's a real fucking mess.
When,
when you start think about what would it
really is because what it really is is
people keeping other people from having
an experience and the reasoning for it.
The reason why is not because they think
that this person,
if they have that experience going to
make life difficult for me,
they're going to come after me.
They're going to hurt my family.
No,
they're doing it because they can profit
off this person not having that
experience.
If I say that something is illegal and I
set forth laws and I say,
if you cross this boundary and you do
this behavior and you,
you know,
you violate my law,
I get to lock you in a cage.
I get to make money from locking you in.
Occasionally that I get to employ people
that will now they have a job and their
job is to go after people that are doing
what I said they couldn't do and get
them and kidnap them and put them in a
cage.
That's what you're having with marijuana
and mushroom bust and stuff like that.
You're.
You're telling someone that you buy your
judgment,
they shouldn't have that experience,
and so you say,
well,
if you're going to make such an extreme
judgment,
that judgment has to be based on facts,
right?
No,
no.
It doesn't have to be based on facts.
Of course it doesn't because of it was
then marijuana would have been legal in
the 19 fifties.
I mean it would've been legal in the
when when they passed the sweeping
schedule One psychedelics act of 1970,
I believe it was.
When they made everything illegal,
they would have.
They would have had to provide some
reasoning for making mushrooms illegal.
Some reasoning for making marijuana
illegal and it would've been scientific
and it would have been medical,
but the problem is every single fucking
medical study that's ever been done
about marijuana shows that it's
relatively harmless.
I mean,
you can ruin your life with anything.
You can ruin your life with
cheeseburgers if you want to.
Like I was talking about like bottles,
you could take a bottle and bottles can
hold a nice delicious drink or you can
take a bottle and you can stuff it up
your ass and throw yourself down a
flight of stairs and bleed to death.
It doesn't mean that bottle should be
illegal.
The real fucking problem is that we are
allowing people to victimize other
people for profit and that's what the
war on drugs is all about and the reason
why the war on drugs works at all is
because the people responsible to cops
and the lawyers,
they're not doing drugs.
If they were doing drugs,
if they were doing the right drugs,
they are doing mushrooms and they were
smoking pot.
There would be nothing.
It would all stop.
They would have to stop.
If you do the correct amount of mushroom
dose,
you would realize that in victimizing
people,
you are victimizing yourself.
You are creating a terrible stream of
Karma.
You are,
you are ruining lives for nothing.
You were ruining lives for something
that doesn't have anything to do with
you and something that's been around in
terms of for marijuana and mushrooms and
Iowasca tens of thousands of years of
human use.
And as I said,
in those indigenous cultures,
the Shaman was the one who made the
decisions.
That's because this is the guy that had
the most experience and these,
these matters of the spirit world.
We don't have that anymore.
Now we have opposite.
We have leaders that if we find out
they're doing mushrooms,
would be shocked.
We would,
we would want them removed from office.
If Obama had a press conference on
Monday and said,
I got together with my wife the other
day.
We did five grams of mushrooms and,
uh,
we went to the mountains and I really
started thinking about our country.
Everybody be like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
That would be the most beautiful thing
that he could ever say if he could say,
I just took something that allowed me to
literally tune into the stream of love.
That is God,
that is the energy of the universe,
that is mother Gaia.
I connected myself to all of that is
loving in the world and I came back with
some revelations and some thoughts about
how we can lead our culture better,
how we can be kinder to the rest of the
world,
how instead of going all these places to
to control the resources and to to to
ruin them.
How about we introduce them to the
spiritual realm?
How about we introduced the whole world
to mushrooms.
How about we approved them in mass
quantities and slowly start to open
people's eyes up to the fact that it's
not a lack of resources that we have in
this country.
It's a gluttonous fucking gigantic group
at the top that are fucking in raping
the world.
It's not that we have not enough
resource to run the life that we we
need.
It's.
We don't have enough resources to run
the life we're living.
We don't have to live like this,
this is all nonsense.
We wrote,
we live a non agriculturally based life.
We live a life where we rely on fossil
fuels and you know,
we rely on petroleum or we don't have
to.
There's many,
many things that can be done with plants
that we're doing right now.
If marijuana was legal,
first of all,
just hemp as for use for oil and use for
textiles and use for,
for you can make houses out of it and
you can,
you can fucking fuel cars with it.
You could build cars with it.
Load is actually made a fucking car with
a um,
uh,
instead of carbon fiber or fiberglass,
they made the fucking shallow out of
hemp.
I mean,
it's all possible.
We just can't live the way we're living
right now and there's no way to
effectively reset civilization better
than psychedelics.
But meanwhile saying that makes you
sound like a retard.
Like I'm listening to my own self and
I'm like,
if I didn't do drugs,
if I had never done mushrooms or
anything like that,
I heard a guy talking like this.
I'm like,
who the fuck is this idiot?
Like what could you pop?
How could you possibly say that you
think you have all the answers?
I don't have the answers,
but I do have a possible door to the
answers and that's what I think.
I think psychedelic experiences are and
these guys that are running for
president,
they will deny that to the end.
They will.
You know,
Obama had this fucking thing recently,
whereas a town hall meeting and he got
all these questions from the Internet
and the number one question,
the number one question was marijuana
legalization and every other issue that
was being discussed that day,
whether it was healthcare or anything
else.
He gave these really well thought out in
depth answers,
but it came to the marijuana question.
It was like,
Whoa,
whoa.
I don't know what that says about this
group here.
They said,
no,
I don't think that's a good idea.
Really.
You don't think that's a good idea?
You don't think it's a good idea to stop
suppressing people.
You don't think it's a good idea to not
jail people for having a fucking
experience,
to not jail people,
for selling a plant,
a naturally growing thing that's never
killed anyone.
You don't think that it's a good idea to
reverse and evil fuck up corrupt law
that is helping people with the worst
Karma ever imprison people for nothing.
Well,
you need some fucking mushrooms and
that's the problem.
We have a whole group of people running
this fucking country and none of them
are doing mushrooms.
I would like to have a talk show.
I.
I've talked about this on stage.
I want to have a talk show where I make
people do mushrooms with me and it
would.
It would be called a do mushrooms with
Joe Rogan and we have on,
you know like people that like me.
You want to know a real truth.
Serum Mushrooms is the best truth serum
you,
you.
Once that fucking wave hits you,
that wave of,
of alien information and the wave of
love and connectivity and when you see
the fiber of the universe all around
you,
you're going to start talking.
And if I could get,
you know,
like Ken Starr and Dick Cheney,
and could you imagine,
could you imagine if those guys like if
people sued them and people,
you know,
uh,
because like,
look,
there's a lot of people that want to
take them to trial for war crimes.
Especially Dick Cheney.
When you think about the fact that Dick
Cheney was the ceo of Halliburton and
then he becomes a vice president of the
United States.
We go to some crazy fucking wars,
or Halliburton gets the contracts and
the wars are all based on totally false
information about weapons of mass
destruction.
There's people that say that Dick Cheney
was at the helm of it.
He was lying.
You could try that motherfucker for wars
against your current crimes against
humanity.
You could try him for that.
And if he was convicted and they said,
here's one thing you can do to get out
of it.
You gotTa,
you gotTa do the let's get,
let's do mushrooms with Joe Rogan show
and you have a guy like that,
like,
uh,
any,
any really fucked up politician George
Bush,
senior George Bush Junior,
you know,
anyone like that.
Sit them down and make them,
do mushrooms.
Make them realize that just because
you've been living this life the same
way as everyone before you,
as your father and all these other
corrupt politicians,
it doesn't mean as justifiable just
because you could find examples all
around you.
People who have done worse and people
were doing the same things.
It doesn't mean that it's supposed to
continue and it's got to this gotta be a
way to stop it.
It doesn't seem to be stopping with the,
the evolution of culture,
it seems to be the same.
You know,
it seems to be the corruption.
It's being exposed more,
but it doesn't seem like it's put a
monkey wrench in it.
Like they're just stopping,
you know,
the,
the financial corruption in this bailout
is staggering.
And if you really want to hurt your
head,
you go and read some of them.
Mike,
Matt,
tie ebs articles about it.
It fucking hurts,
like when you look at the billions and
trillions of dollars and where it's
going and how it's being funded and
these guys are getting bonuses and
they're getting bonuses,
but they don't have any money from the
money came from tax payers,
but they were old.
The bonuses or else they'll quit or
wild.
They fire them.
They're the ones that fuck this thing up
and at first,
but it's staggering.
I mean it's literally our entire
civilization is built on a foundation of
unfixable bullshit.
It's the only way I think to restructure
our society correctly with literally it
would have to be done by someone other
than us because once.
I mean that's what the constitution was
all about.
When there was the birth of America,
the idea of America was that we were
going to have a separation of church and
state that we were going to have people
that could only run it for a few years
and then they would have to leave.
We were going to have the will of the
people and then it was going to be.
We're going to be free from all the
imperialism bullshit that we haven't
deal with in England and in Europe,
but after awhile it just fell into the
same thing.
You know,
people inherently,
if we're left alone and we're just
people the way we are right now,
our evolution,
our cultural and social evolution is so
much lower than the evolution of
technology.
What we're able to do,
we were able to communicate with people
all around the world.
We're flying fucking tubes through the
sky.
We're able to send video through the
air.
You know,
we're able to watch television programs
that are being broadcast from the other
side of the planet.
I mean we have this incredible
technological capabilities,
but socially we're just a bump ahead of
where we were in the fifties.
Just a little,
just a little.
I mean,
it could be argued that were like
slightly behind where we were in the
seventies in comparison to like,
you know,
if you think about it,
like as far as like what kind of access
to information they had back then.
You know,
everybody was all about love and peace
and love.
What?
Why,
why is that?
Why was the sixties the late sixties?
What,
why,
what was the drop off between then in
here,
you know,
strokes to what it is.
When you know all that summer of love,
all that woodstock ship,
they were all on acid.
Okay.
They're all in mushrooms.
They're all in pod.
There were highest fuck.
And they were realizing that this way of
living the life that you know,
leads you to be your dad is not where
it's at when you want.
Your Dad dropped out of a fucking heart
attack at 55 and you scarcely can
remember him laughing three times ever,
you know,
and you go,
what?
I'm supposed to be that guy.
What the fuck is that?
You know?
And then the Vietnam War and all the
disenchantment with our government.
I mean that's what forced people to more
drugs.
That's what forced the culture to change
more.
We need something like that.
We need something like that right now
because the way we're doing it,
we're just spinning our wheels.
When the president wins the Nobel Peace
Prize and then like a week later,
since 30,000
people more into Afghanistan,
you've got to go,
what the fuck?
Really?
You know what the fuck you think this is
a good idea?
Nobody.
After the Vietnam War,
the Vietnam war was a good idea.
Less people are going to think the
Afghanistan war is a good idea because
Afghanistan isn't even really the
fucking country.
I mean it's like it's like one city and
a hundred tribes.
You know,
the way John Mccain describes
Afghanistan,
he said that it's run the same way it
was run when Alexander the Great was
around.
I mean literally you have war and and
they run tribes and in between these
warlords,
you know,
there's a few Taliban like sprinkled in
the hills and you know,
how we find out about these Taliban.
This is where it gets really funny.
We give the warlords Viagara because the
warlords can get it up anymore and you
know,
they want to still be the warlord,
but you know,
they got like there's six wives and
these chicks are like,
sit around.
When are you gonna fuck me and they
can't fuck up.
So they take Viagra now and the soldiers
give them Viagra and they in turn in
turn give them information about the
Taliban.
It's pretty funny.
Shit.
Okay,
let's do it.
How long would the world ignore the
people that are
dying of starvation?
I think Sam Kennison and the best answer
to that,
why don't you people live with the food
is
okay.
Let me see.
Tiger Woods is.
Golly,
I don't know what that means.
Fuck Champs Tony.
Big l recipes.
Oh,
big Al was a rapper that was shot and
killed in Harlem in 1999.
Thank you.
Eternal.
A damaged already almost 7:00.
We've been doing this for an hour and a
half.
Alright.
People don't see anything more
interesting here.
So I'm going to go to back to the
twitter.
I'm going to stay.
Stay with you guys for another half an
hour.
Or someone thinks I can't recognize two
dudes.
Dicks.
I claim early.
I proficient and identifying poor stars
by their dicks.
Some fans might wonder if you're truly
being us because it seems Kinda Gay.
Who's this?
Who's Peter Noise?
Ron.
Jeremy Rocco's.
For Freddy.
I would say the bottom one.
It looks a little like Ron,
Jeremy,
and the top one looks a little like
Rocco.
So Freddie.
But the top one could be the same guy.
In which case I say Bolter Ron.
Jeremy.
My right side.
So sad that I know twitter.
She was on twitter.
God Damn,
I love you too.
Rs for Andrew.
You motherfucker infiltrate the White
House kitchen and mix psychedelics in
the food.
That might not be such a good idea.
Did you hear about what happened in
France?
I'll find the article for you in the
CIA.
The CIA put a LSD in.
They spiked.
I'll put the um,
it's,
it's all over the Internet.
I'm not just one.
I'll put,
uh,
I'll put one up on,
but if you just look up CIA,
France,
lsd in Google,
you will find a many,
many,
many articles about it.
I'll put it up on twitter right now.
Just throw it up on twitter.
Right?
There is some fascinating shit man.
So I don't think that dosing people with
a acid is the answer.
I think,
um,
that's definitely not the way to go.
Um,
I think any psychedelic drugs should be
done if you've got to do it at all with
an understanding of what you're doing
and you're doing it with someone who
knows what they're doing,
who's done it many times before,
and that's what the role of a shaman is
supposed to be.
You know,
what a shaman is supposed to be is
someone who can give you a experience
and help you and guide you through the
experience of,
of literally leaving this world.
I mean,
that's,
that's what psychedelics are all about.
You know what I mean?
Everybody wants,
everybody thinks that,
you know,
to really leave this world,
you're going to get a spaceship and
you've got to go to another planet.
You can leave this world from right
here.
You can leave this world in your own
mind and it's much more possible to me
that the real aliens,
that real alien life,
it's probably way weirder and way more
complicated than we've got it broken
down in the movies with metal ships and
shit like that.
I think it's,
I think it's more of a dimensional
thing.
I think there's,
there's a,
you know,
I mean if you talk to people that know
anything about quantum physics and I
don't understand it,
I don't get it,
but from their claims and supposedly
this is mathematically provable,
there's at least 11 dimensions,
you know,
that's just what we know about.
What does that even mean?
Do you even know what that means?
I'm not sure I do,
but I think that the way I think about
it is that it's,
it's very likely that just this reality
is just the reality that we're tuned
into,
but there's probably an infinite number
of different realities going on at the
same time all around us.
We just can't tune into it.
We just don't literally don't have the
senses for it.
So it might be the alien life is here
right now all the time.
It's just operating on like a different
frequency on the dial.
You know,
like the world is a radio and that we're
97 point one,
but that the aliens are one of nine
point eight and you know,
we just can't do an event.
You know,
who the fuck knows?
But you know,
when you start talking to aliens,
people going to think you're crazy.
If we ever did we ever did fucking find
is God damn.
Would that be a crazy day if they ever
did come down?
But I don't think there would be too
nice to us because we're not so nice to
chimps.
You know,
look at what we do to killer whales.
Man.
You know,
we take fucking killer whales when we
know they're super smart and we don't
care.
We don't give a fuck.
Get the fish texted with getting the
tank do tricks.
You know,
what makes us think that aliens are
going to treat us any differently.
Maybe that maybe that's what all these
alien abduction experience are all
about.
Maybe they're real.
They don't take it seriously at all.
They just think we're crazy pink monkeys
with nuclear weapons and they come down
and they fuck with us and there's a joke
that I do in my act about how if there
are really are aliens,
I believe the earth is the Tiawana of
outer space and I really,
I think that might be accurate.
I might,
this might be just a place to come to
fuck around,
you know,
why would you want to fix us?
So why,
so we can make more is already 6 billion
of us.
You know,
what,
why would you want to make more and you
know,
the last hundred years,
I mean,
how many more people have been born
something like four or five fucking
billion.
I mean it's Ken,
pretty naughty man.
This is motherfuckers gonna get
overcrowded soon.
And why?
Why would they mean if you've got to fix
us?
It would have to be a radical changing.
It would have to be really radical
because socially we're not catching up
to where we are technologically.
Our awareness is not up to what we're
capable of,
what we're capable of blowing up the
whole plan for in.
We're capable of creating black holes
and we're capable of all kinds of shit.
I mean just the.
The nuclear arsenal that North Korea
possesses,
those dummies.
They got one fucking stupid little dude
with glasses.
Makes them shut the lights out at night
to save energy.
Nobody's got any money.
This motherfucker's got to Ghana nuclear
weapons just quarter to launch on people
11.
Oh,
at this guy.
11 dimensions explained.
Says as Y Z ge,
one,
one a watch that and I still won't learn
anymore.
I'll watch it,
but I'll still be like,
I'm not sure really what their science.
Okay.
Couple more questions here and I hear my
daughter's crying.
If aliens didn't exist that says that
everyone who was abducted or saw a Ufo
is crazy.
No,
it doesn't.
Because first of all,
what you have found means unidentified.
Let me tell you something,
man.
People are full of Shit.
You know,
we did a thing.
I used to do a show called game show in
my head.
I did it for CBS and it was a hidden
camera game show and what the show was
was we would,
um,
we would,
uh,
have a contestant and the contestant
would have to convince people to do a
bunch of shit and it would be under a
hidden camera.
And we set up in Hollywood and this
dude,
we had a contestant dress up like a
newscaster,
like a guy worked for channel four news
and he stood there on the street corner
and we had all these cameras pointed on
him when the cameras right on the people
and he would go up to people and say,
can you do me a favor?
I'm in a terrible situation.
We had a situation here earlier and uh,
a Ufo landed.
They had to tell the people on camera
that a Ufo landed and that all these
witnesses had seen it.
But then the witnesses took off.
So I need you to pretend that you
sought.
And every fucking person we asked to do
that did it.
I thought no one was going to do it.
They just stepped right up.
And so tell us about the experience.
And the guy was like,
well,
you know,
I saw the UFO and it was silver lights
were on the edge.
They describe it in detail.
I'm sitting there like,
why people love to be on camera and
people are just generally full shit.
And even if they did see something by
the time that story comes around and
there's cameras on them or they're being
interviewed and they're talking to
reporters,
that story is going to morph in their
memory.
It's going to change.
Who knows what the fuck it was.
It could have been an experimental
government jet.
It could have been a flock of birds at
night.
It could have been a Ufo.
Who the fuck knows who knows what it
really was?
But the people that are talking about
are almost all nuts,
man.
They're almost all looney.
So I think that people see things and
then they blow those things up in their
head.
And as far as the abduction experiences,
all Ufo duction experiences occur while
people are sleeping there,
that they're all a curling like late at
night.
If you look at them,
the bulk of them,
except that people are just completely
insane to think they come and take them,
you know,
during the middle of the day and bring
them back and it seems like there were
only gone for a second,
but really they're gone for days.
There's some loons that will tell you
some stories like that,
but I think that what's going on is it's
dmt related because we know that the
brain produces dmt while a person is in
heavy rem sleep and if you smoked dmt,
the experience that you have is very
much alien.
It's very much like what you would
expect someone to be talking about if
they were brought to another world or
brought a border spaceship.
I mean,
it feels like you're going on to
something you know and who knows what
kind of a,
you know,
a response you would give these Ufo
people if,
if you took them and gave them dmt and
made them smoke dmt and go,
okay,
was that what you saw?
And if they're like,
yeah,
it was back on the ship and go,
okay,
settle down.
Then you know.
Then you know what's going on,
you know what,
what is that?
Are they,
are they really making contact
with entities?
Is it really their brain and their,
their imagination that becomes
supercharged because of this chemical
that floods through it?
And what is imagination exactly?
I mean there's,
you know,
people can poo poo that and say,
oh,
it's just,
you're making things up.
It's hallucinations,
isn't it?
You know,
how do you know that that world is not
just as real as this world just because
this world,
you can bang on it,
make noise.
You know,
you could feel it.
It doesn't mean it's more real.
That just means it's solid.
You know?
It's,
it's very possible that the world of the
imagination,
the world of your mind,
the world of dreams is really a world is
really another dimension.
Do I believe in ghosts?
I'm not scared of him.
I fucking watched those.
Ghost stories are,
what are they scared of?
Fucking ghosts never killed anybody.
You see it or some shit.
It's amazing how many of those goddamn
shows there are there.
Everybody wants to like watch the
paranoia level.
Everybody's obsessed with UFO and
everybody's obsessed with,
you know,
shit that's not necessarily real big
foot like I've always had the killer
whales are way more interesting than
bigfoot.
These super intelligent animals and
asked to actually rescue people that
kill or they killed great white sharks.
They killed dolphins.
They like.
They're ruthless,
crazy,
super intelligent animals.
They play with their dead like seals.
You ever see killer whales,
like throw a clf merits,
Swat them on their tail and send them
flying.
Their fucking ruthless.
And they were super smart.
It's fascinating.
Shit.
All right.
I think a chat roulette,
if you've been on chat with that,
you've probably seen my deck.
Sorry.
No,
I never put my Dick Archer.
That's just roots.
Um,
I think it's funny though.
I haven't done it yet.
I did the other roulette or you just
type.
Just like a,
it's like a one on one personal
messaging like in Brazil was dudes
trying to get laid or you would do.
I would say yes.
And then they would just fucking hang up
on me.
So I started saying I was a chick and I
did a few of those and I put them up on
the,
on the forums and Joe Rogan.net
and it's kind of fun.
Alright.
Did Dan Hardee get to leapfrog top 10
welterweights and get a title shot?
You know,
I don't know.
I mean it's hard to say.
Uh,
I think Dan Hardy's exciting dude talks
a lot of shitty saying all the right
things because he had serious power in
his hands.
It's just whether or not he's going to
be able to deal with that fucking
wrestling game of GSP.
GSP can take you down,
man.
He's such an athlete.
Managed so explosive and it's,
I think it's just really hard for dudes
to avoid that take down and he gets on
top of you and stays on top.
It got to beat your ass.
You know,
the thing is about GSP is will it be a
fight like the Tiago Alvarez fight where
he neutralized elvis but he never really
came close to stopping them?
Or will it be a fight like the Fitch
fighter,
the Bj fight where he just gets on top
of them,
beat the fucking shit out of them,
or will hardy have something up his
sleeve,
you know,
maybe a hardee's takedown defense is
better than we thought it is,
you know,
maybe hardy,
um,
has a strategy for how to counter the
double and how to stop him when he's
coming in or how to,
you know,
take it to him or maybe he's going to
pull guard.
I mean,
where the fuck knows what hard he's
going to do.
I'm,
he's a very,
very smart guy and he's very confident
and it's real confidence.
It's not bullshit.
He really believes that he's going to
clip GSP and he's going to rock them and
he's going to go home with the title.
Who the fuck knows sun?
It's going to be interesting.
Spice bag of ice.
I'll spilled bag of ice.
Says that the 11th dimension is in his
pants.
Wow.
That's built bag of ice was still
around.
I thought it would have abandoned that
twitter by now.
You've got a lot of sticktuitiveness on.
Good for you.
Alright.
Um,
I think that's enough,
right?
So I can 37 slash 11.
That's a perfect time to end.
We are proof that aliens exist.
Perspective.
Okay.
I don't know what you're talking about
now.
You've done too much drugs.
You're,
you're,
you're ruining.
The whole call is done.
Um,
I will look one more time for a good
question on the forums dot Joe
Rogan.net.
And if we cannot find one,
we'll wrap it up.
Bitches.
Did anyone ever wonder why we'll lose
all the grid rappers that have a
significant place in hip hop history?
Rappers,
Tupac,
Biggie,
big l easy.
He one on a big alice.
Easy.
Yeah.
Yet we're stuck with garbage like Nelly
and fucking soldier boy.
Well yeah,
that's interesting.
Um,
I think rappers,
man,
that life,
you know,
the life is all guns and meanwhile
you're Tupac and you got fucking machine
guns tattooed on your body.
It says thug life on your stomach.
You know,
those aren't signs of a,
a long and healthy career.
He was like the first dude to like cover
his body,
his whole body with tattoos too.
They're all doing that now.
It's really crazy.
You know,
little wayne.
I think it's hilarious that little Wayne
said that he's a gangster,
like told Katie Kirk,
I'm a gangsta.
Ms Dot Katie.
Meanwhile he put him in jail.
He immediately put them in protective
custody.
You're a gangster,
made me you and you've got all your
money and your outside,
but the inside world.
No,
you're,
you're a singer,
you're an entertainer.
And it would be awesome with one of
those guys have fucked your face.
Not for everybody.
For them,
for that guy to fuck your face.
He'd be.
I'm not saying that.
I'm looking forward to you getting your
facebook's,
but let's be realistic.
It would happen.
God dammit.
Yeah,
motherfuckers alright when.
Alright.
I think that's it.
There's no more.
I could say I'm a,
like I said,
I'm going to be an Gotham at Gotham
comedy club.
Uh,
next Friday.
Next Friday is the 26th for two shows.
It's almost sold out.
So if you want to get tickets,
you got to jump on that shit right away.
It's,
it'll definitely be sold out by that
day.
Um,
so,
uh,
I'll see you guys then I'll be on opie
and anthony that Friday in the morning
as well.
Looking forward to that.
I'm looking forward to the and that
Saturday the 27th and that should be fun
as fuck and everything else.
It's.
Thank you everybody for tuning in and,
uh,
have kept my promise to keep up this
weekly podcast.
It is now also on.
You could catch it on Itunes,
the audio version.
It's on Itunes,
so check it out.
Thank you guys.
Report.
Thanks for everything and uh,
I really appreciate it.
And,
uh,
I will see you next week.
Next week I will do this home one day.
I will do this Tuesday next week.
So I'll see you guys next Tuesday.
I love you.
That's.