All right,
we're live.
We've been talking about doing this for
a while.
We thought we finally pull it off.
It's about time.
What are you doing in town?
I,
I'm like came here and did a little
surfing off the,
off the plane.
Um,
then I had to do a USC thing where I did
a trained,
um,
Blake Griffin this morning,
this afternoon.
Oh,
okay.
I saw that picture.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
you're doing mixing it up and I may,
he shown me some how to dunk over a car
and I was teaching them how to Western
mass.
When you see a guy like that,
that's like a giant athlete like that,
don't you want to go man,
you will.
Fucking great radio voice.
I've never heard the radio,
the radio voice stand up your fucking
mind.
Now you're like,
now you might like it.
Well,
you know,
we were at dinner,
I'd have the same vote.
Okay,
Gotcha.
They like and next on the stage
yesterday can we to the main stage $14.
Kamikaze is nice and smooth.
What do you see?
Like a dude like that?
Do you want to tell him?
Man,
what the fuck a body to be heavyweight
champion of the world was telling him.
I was like,
you're huge drips.
Like everything about you is just
massive,
but you know,
and we're like,
I'm doing some under overs and some like
wrestling and I think he was kind of
like,
let me like,
I felt like he was limping Armenia.
I was like,
pussy like fucking man.
Give me,
you know what I mean?
Like don't,
don't fucking big brother me right now.
I don't give me the,
the,
Oh,
I'm just a little kid.
So then once I fucking gave him that
talk,
then he stepped it up a little bit.
I was like,
yeah,
don't don't do that to me motherfucker.
I'm a grown ass man.
I'm fucking six foot tall.
I'll fuck you up.
So don't live army right now.
It's funny because you are six foot
tall,
but when you stand next to him and
you're like,
Jesus fucking Christ.
Yeah Dude,
he's 6:10
Jesus Christ.
10 Man.
Yeah,
it was a,
it was funny.
You know,
I was telling him like,
how you're so coordinated on the court
and then you put some fucking gloves on
and you can't,
what the,
what the fuck?
I won one,
two,
I'm going to just go,
like,
come on,
hold different things.
And then um,
he had his management coming to me and
telling me he doesn't want to near kick
and so of course we fucking need a kick
because you can't tell me what you can't
do because he have fucked up knees or
something.
Who knows?
I have no idea,
but he didn't know he did an and he
didn't want to be embarrassed.
Like when you do something that you're
not good at people,
especially cameras.
And so he,
uh,
no,
we did it.
A lot of those guys have fucked up
knees,
right?
Of those photos.
Everybody is fucked up.
No biggie is huge.
That's a giant dude.
Yeah.
If you could teach that guy how to kick
Jesus Christ,
fucking need to do,
could dunk over a car.
So I jumped,
jumped me.
It was fun.
Yeah.
I can only imagine.
I can only imagine,
but those guys,
there's so much more money in the NBA
and you don't have to get your ass
kicked.
That's what I told him.
I said,
hey man,
I need you to go to the NBA and tell
them you guys need enforcers like
hockey.
I'll be there.
I'll be your man.
You know what I'm saying?
So you're telling me you go out to say
Yo Cowboy fucking number 23 keeps
hitting me in the ribs.
You know,
I don't,
I don't like them.
I'll go out there.
I'll just iced the fool right there on
the middle of the court.
And it is weird that hockey is the only
sport where you're allowed to beat
people up in the middle of the game.
Yeah.
My Buddy Scott Parker,
I mean he is the enforcer for the car as
well.
He's retired now,
but I mean that was his job.
So you know,
he would tell me he was like mentally
have to prepare like him and I talk a
lot about just the preparation of
fighting and how he'd get game ready
because he knew he was fighting.
Whoever was the other enforcers or he'd
be ready and it's cool like interacting
with them in that sense,
but yeah,
they like promote it like,
oh,
you're messing with my goalie or all
year.
So they send up the enforce or like it's
just,
it's because it's Canadian.
What a cool job.
It's a great job.
Fuck.
Like you're Joe.
Get Him in here.
You know what I mean?
So it's just funny that no other sport
or any other sport.
If you fight,
you're not just ejected from the game,
you're subject to penalties.
You might get suspended in hockey.
It's a normal thing.
You mean if you're,
if you,
if versus you've played just hold off
and jump need someone's whole face off
in the middle of the game.
That would be huge.
And then they'd be in big trouble.
Do you think it's [inaudible] hockey?
Like did not that stable because you're
on skates.
Like it takes a lot of fucking skate
knowledge to be able to brawl while
you're on skates.
I can barely fucking stand on skates.
I don't know how to ice skate.
No,
I'm terrible at it.
I,
uh,
I did it about two years ago and thought
I was cool to try to do the hockey stop
fucking cocky in Bam asked out on the
fucking eyes and that was,
that was the end of my,
uh,
my hockey dreams.
So I'm fighting him no idea.
So I would imagine if you could teach a
dude like,
dude who's like a figure skater,
teach them some,
like real good kicks.
You could fuck somebody up,
but you're not allowed to do that,
right?
You can't just figure skate.
We'll kick someone's fucking head off.
Juggler die.
No,
no.
Um,
I don't think they can raise either knee
or anything.
They can't bring any scuffs off your
feet down.
What about superman?
Punch wouldn't be effective.
They wouldn't even know that you were
throwing a kick came at him like full,
like,
you know,
thor in the movie.
Troy.
Excuse me.
So like a trick,
like.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Yeah,
it would have to be something.
No one expected half deal.
Yeah,
it,
it's just weird that they don't have
that basketball.
Basketball becomes less and less
popular.
Maybe.
Maybe they would have to bring it in.
So what did you know in hockey?
The enforcers can't wear a face mask.
Kill it.
They can only wear a helmet with no.
With no guard.
It's like a penalty.
If they do.
That's interesting.
So they can't take punishment.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
I mean,
so if one guy had it on and one guy
didn't exactly say it but not have it,
but still lady's grabbing just throttle
punch through the plastic and that's
insane,
right?
Yeah.
It is kind of insane.
Insane.
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
it's a fucked up job.
That's a weird gray area sport,
but I think a lot of it is also because
it's Canadian Canada,
they're just them.
There's more men up there.
I'll give you,
you know what I'm saying?
Sure.
It's like there's a lot of policies in
America.
I mean there's a lot of men in America,
a lot of places and there's a lot of
posts and in Canada I think fistfights
or moral or a normal thing like think
about,
we're back pre biblical and we're in a
political sciences.
Okay.
I'm gonna throw my head in there.
Cool,
okay.
And all of these policies you think so
many women,
us,
Alpha males would have.
We would just go and like I think I'm
gonna take your girl and just beat his
ass.
And the problem with that is you can
never fucking sleep those days man.
Like the old days and shit.
Like you never sleep,
you know,
you would hear footsteps you like all
fucking great.
You look out your window.
There's a thousand dudes coming over the
hill.
I just did.
But those wish a motherfucker would days
the Mongols that fucking just shooting
arrows.
No one has a gun and fucking launching
people on catapults.
Those kind of three big we have,
you know we got,
we don't have,
maybe they just barely came with arrows.
Swords definitely.
But what do they figure out?
Arrows,
like all those,
like the arrows are on the hieroglyphs
right?
So that's like 2000 BC at least because
I think the pyramid is 2,500
BC.
I think they dated that.
So I think if you're talking about when
it was,
the invention of the arrows should
probably know this.
I should know this,
but I have no idea.
I have no idea.
So long ass time ago.
Yeah.
They figured out a few things first.
Right?
They figured out like spears and then
they figured out catapults.
Probably.
That was probably the next boat trip
trebuchet,
right?
Trevor,
what does that trip is not a catapult
trebuchet and though is called a
trebuchet.
Can you google it?
Trebuchet.
I'm saying it wrong.
Should I be Shay?
That was fucking quit google.
That's not bad trebuchet.
That's the original Caterpillar fucking
telling me,
son.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
Even it's even spelled the way you
pronounced it.
Loose lip shade with a mouthful of
school.
What do you got there?
What does that stuff a Copenhagen long
cut.
Wintergreen.
Dangerous for you.
Is that bad for you?
Probably not.
Any more dangerous than marijuana.
Marijuana is not dangerous for you at
all.
How dare you,
sir?
I don't feel like that is either.
Put that stuff does not like chew
people's faces off and shit because
there's one dude who shows up at a
little kid schools to warn them of the
dangers of chewing tobacco in his
missing half his face.
I remember that dude on TV.
Look at bone cancer in his face.
I don't mean to freak you out when I'm
going out with my boots on babies.
So,
uh,
wow.
So face cancer from school.
You're good at face care for school.
I'm gonna.
Call it red bull and tell them,
hey,
I'm gonna.
Be the first guy to jump out of the
astronaut thing you got there.
Don't need to shoot.
I'm just going in head first.
They'll bring it off.
Jesus Christ.
That's my mentality though,
Joey.
Like if I got in a car accident and lost
a leg or an arm,
I'd just,
I'd tell him,
pull the plug right there.
Shoot me.
I'm done.
One leg.
Oh Man.
It'd be tough.
They got some good prosthetics now.
A lot of these guys that come back from
Iraq and Afghanistan,
they do marathons now.
Poor.
Let me credit.
It's incredible.
It's incredible though,
isn't it?
It really is,
man.
But God damn it.
Yeah,
you would.
You'd be,
you were real close.
There's a couple things.
They sequence the gene of the flatworm
recently and they're looking to try to
figure out because of flatworms can
regenerate.
Like he'd cut them in half.
They become two completely different
flatworms.
I think they also have the same
memories,
like if one flatworm knows where the
food is and you cut them in half of the
both halves know where the food is.
So it's very confusing to them because
they're trying to figure out what is
that memory or is that just,
you know,
like lawyers and it's good question.
I think specifically the w,
what they know and the way they know
what they believed that it's a memory,
some type of a memory.
Obviously a crude memory,
but uh,
they think that they're going to be able
to figure out whether the next hundred
years how to replace limbs that you,
you're going to be able to regenerate
it.
The way of frog does or an alligator
does.
Think about that next 100 years.
Think about what,
think about this iphone six year and the
next.
I mean nothing.
Do you remember the flip phone and the
texting?
You were so happy with it too,
you know,
speaking of that,
do you know,
I mean you have kids,
so do you remember when you were 15,
16 years?
Have the call,
like,
hey Mr Rogan.
I'm,
is Sarah there?
Can I talk 9:00?
Phone off?
You know what I mean?
Those days are gone.
Our kids will never have to unless you
know the strong will take,
take their phone.
But do you even have a landline at home?
Yeah,
I got a landline but it's useless.
Never use it.
Okay.
So people like that,
right?
I mean you have a landline just in case,
but uh,
you know,
I have a landline because I live in the
middle of nowhere and that's way I can
get Internet.
There's like a hamster on a wheel and
ever fast he's running it powers up my
wifi and it's terrible.
I can't even to.
You have like one of those satellite
Internet connections.
It's phone line,
bad 56 k?
Yeah.
It's like you can't do anything better.
Um,
if I,
if I wanted to download a podcast,
I'd have to start the download before I
went to bed and maybe by noon the next
day it be done.
Yeah.
I got like 48 hour download movie times,
so I've got to really plan the movie
online for a flight.
Netflix is ridiculous.
Netflix?
No,
we cannot load a Netflix.
They have satellite Internet now.
Nobody know.
You can get it all over the country.
Really?
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
It's like,
just like direct TV,
they just point the dish with the
satellite in the sky and it's not fast
as like a fiber optic,
but it's pretty fast when you look into
this.
Yeah.
You got to get that.
What I got going on is that's not
biblical.
Yeah.
It sounds.
That sounds horrifying.
You like
you live in like a couple of decades
ago.
I am and there's nothing they can do.
They can't lay wires or anything like
that now.
They don't have.
They don't have it out there in my area.
I've tried.
I've tried to look into that satellite
game.
Where are you at now?
Edgewood,
New Mexico,
right on the backside of Santa Fe.
Albuquerque.
And you're there because of Jackson's
because you could be close to Jackson.
Well,
I moved to Albuquerque to help Linda
Garcia with the Roger Ward to fight.
And I never left.
I literally called my grandma,
my grandma she's watching right now
live.
So I'll give a shot.
Um,
I literally showed up for Linda for a
week and then now Greg Osby b is 50
fiver and I never left.
I literally,
I had a house in Colorado.
My grandma took care of everything,
brought all my stuff down and just
drove,
like,
which slowly come visit me and bring
things down.
I never went home.
Wow.
It was wild.
Yeah.
So why was,
I just liked it so much there,
you know?
Uh,
in Colorado I was like kind of the,
at the gyms I was kind of the kid that
no one would put a name on like a.
no one would claim me.
Right.
I was like,
really?
Oh Man.
It was a hard time.
You know,
that's.
And that's what the whole bmf ranch and
like me giving back to people came from
because Oh,
drive here,
go here,
do this.
No one will put their name on me.
Like Dwayne,
I train with him,
but he would never put his name on me,
you know,
none of the gyms would like claiming I
was just,
well I was a fuck up,
you know,
and I,
it was weird.
So it was just your young me crazy.
Yeah.
You know,
and they're like,
this dude,
I can't have this guy fighting for me.
Exactly.
He's just,
he's a loose cannon.
That's crazy.
Too crazy.
So I wanted to.
Greg,
he like took me in and like at that
time,
George and a key to our dean and were
shot.
It was like a family down there was
crazy,
you know,
it was.
All of them were so welcoming and so I
just,
I said,
this is it,
this is where I'm going to make my move.
And so,
so you,
you train there,
but you also built this crazy rent,
bad motherfucker rent,
which is pretty awesome.
I love that you did that.
I love it.
So what made you decide to do that?
I'm like,
I wanted a place where I could ride my
full brother,
shoot my guns and all that.
So I looked at the city limits and land
that I got in Edgewood to buy in
Colorado would have been out of control.
Outrageous.
So,
you know,
I told my grandfather is where I want to
went.
My grandfather said done.
I mean,
on a phone call.
My grandpa said,
done just what you want.
Got It.
Drove down with cash in hand,
bought me the property just slightly,
man.
It was the greatest dude on the planet
So,
uh,
yeah.
And I started training there and him and
my grandma would come down and uh,
you fucking curiosity now.
But uh,
you know,
it just,
it was like a dream for me.
And so now now I'm rooted.
And so did you build out there?
Was there,
was there a structure to there?
There was a house,
right.
And we extended the house,
built the gym,
now I just built dorms.
Which,
if you're going to build anything,
anyone listening,
make sure you get permits because I of
course didn't because I'm a fucking
idiot,
loser.
And a wild.
So I got a big red flag notice on my
door.
Said,
dude,
get your permits done.
Got a picture here.
You want to see it?
Yeah,
I do want to say it.
So what do they do?
Does it delay you any further?
Because it's a cease and assist.
Don't,
don't.
Uh,
well they don't want to.
Oh Jesus.
Yeah.
Well notice the stop.
Stop work.
Bam.
So I had to jump through hoops,
you know,
go hire hiring one.
I had to spend all day.
I had to go to the Santa Fe county and
really like get everything in line,
show my plans,
blah blah blah.
Pay The money and uh,
basically get the ball rolling for the,
for the,
uh,
for the performance.
I got it done now.
So there's places out here,
like if you want to build something in
like Malibu near the ocean,
it takes fucking years and you got to go
through all sorts of red tape and this
corruption and nonsense.
You have to deal with.
Exactly.
So I just felt it and I shouldn't have.
I have a buddy lives in Topanga.
He's under the coastal commission and he
just said,
fuck it.
If they catch me,
they catch me and he just built up,
did all this shit to his house.
It's been a fuck load of money on his
house and just got away with it,
you know,
you can get away with it.
He can with wires hanging out of your
wall,
stop work to get fined and then never
get permits for years.
So I tried to like,
you know,
let people learn from my mistakes.
I'm kind of learning trial by fire,
kind of how I've lived my whole life.
So how many dorms did you build out
there?
Um,
well as of right now it's a glorified
horse.
Stable.
So,
um,
there's no dorms being built because of
the work stoppage.
Stopped a,
just a way to get a permit again.
Yeah.
So now it's a,
it's a horse that because there was a
horse stable underneath,
giant horse,
stable.
And then I built a rooms that I'm
probably going to paint in holding the
archery gear in.
I got a whole bunch of beds that I need
a store and in a couple and I got guys
that come out that'll probably store and
some of those rooms with two beds.
Do you think that this is what's going
to be your transition after you're done
finding that you'll eventually just run
a camp?
I don't know Joe,
I just,
you know,
teaching to me like if you and I were
doing something I could show you
something you had a problem with for me
to like come in and teach a class and be
really hard.
I don't know how that fucking even works
like that.
But you know,
at that time,
what would it be hard about it?
Like maybe getting a curriculum or
something thei thought out like,
okay,
I'm going to teach this,
this and this today.
I don't,
I just don't know.
I see what you're saying.
Maybe if you had somebody that like
Kinda organize it for you and you guys
came in and,
or you know,
have guys like Henry or someone who was
like a,
a,
a coach already work with them like
Winkeljohn and Jackson work together.
Sure,
absolutely.
Yeah,
I mean I have a great,
you know,
Jafari and super direct thing.
One of my great friends and coaches,
you know,
he uh,
he lives out there with me helping me,
who trains all the guys and we got,
you know,
Henry training with the Thai guy.
So we have a good,
you know,
good stable of coaching and just
bringing guys in.
Man.
I,
like I said earlier,
I didn't know how many directions.
So now when people come,
I want to be the guy like they asking
what are you responsible now it's three
bucks.
We don't have a fucking choice.
But before I'd have to be like,
hey,
these guys were no go.
They didn't pay,
they didn't do this,
you know,
just like experiences I've had through
my career.
And what do you do for cutting
weight?
What do you do for this?
What do you believe it was just cool to
be able to answer all the questions for
the upcoming guys,
you know?
Yeah.
Um,
it's got to be a cool thing to be able
to help guys in a way that like,
you wish somebody had helped you,
right?
Absolutely.
Because it's like a,
there's,
there's a real,
an area in the beginning of a fighter's
career,
especially where they don't feel
legitimate and sometimes a guy like you
taking them in and saying,
hey man,
like,
like what you're doing with felder,
right?
You know,
a guy who's a real talented guy,
very talented.
You take them in and then boom,
all of a sudden he's legit as fuck.
You know,
that's what everybody's saying too.
It's like everyone's saying,
oh,
he trains with Donald Shit.
Okay.
You know,
I mean,
that's kind of exactly like that in.
There's a lot of guys that come to when
you come,
I want to be able to put my name on it.
You know what I mean?
He's a worker.
Do you train with you?
Have the coaches work with you?
Because when you say that you're from
our stable,
that's what I want it to be,
you know,
legit roasted you hook up with Henry
Smith.
Um,
do Baltimore man.
We just kind of crossed paths years ago
and root boy.
I said rude boy.
I wish I had an answer for that,
but I don't.
I don't know.
I don't have,
I don't have like that dude though.
He's a great coach to.
Sure.
Absolutely.
Um,
and smooth in the corner.
Like you can tell a lot about a guy and
how he gives instruction in your corner.
Absolutely calm and smooth.
He's like,
can I please get this?
Can I get that?
Thank you very much.
But he also is a very technical is real
technical and his instruction,
like as a guy who watches a lot of
fights,
nothing drives me crazier than when
someone doesn't have advice,
you know,
and they're like,
go get 'em,
go kick his ass.
So that'd be like me cornering Leonard.
But for in the quarter,
like that is kind of tactical advice,
you know,
lenders,
one of my all time favorite guys to
watch because God damn it,
you know,
the,
the firefighter,
a dying breed,
you know,
when,
when Linda was at his,
you know,
talking about retirement with me and
everything.
He,
he's like,
man,
I just wish I could get a fight with
somebody who would just stand there and
fucking throw down with me.
And I'm like,
Leonard Brother,
those days are gone.
These guys that come in and take you
down.
And he's like,
yeah,
but no,
I think this guy gets down with Mike
now,
Leonard,
he's going to take you down,
you know,
so that we'd have to go back and forth
that.
Then the kid would take him down,
you know,
because wrestling and practicing
Breslin.
But that's where the sport's going,
you know,
so well the sports going in this method
that like,
you know,
an order or this,
this place where in order to win you got
to be able to do everything.
It'd be totally unpredictable.
And you,
you've got to be able to fight smart and
not put yourself in danger.
And Leonard was all about just throwing
himself into danger.
Peeling the stickers off the match with
the punches.
Yeah.
He would drive from the back of his
calf.
Loved it.
I mean,
but those are the fights.
I mean the Jens pulver and Lydia Garcia
if I.
Yeah Man.
Why?
Oh,
Leonard had a bunch of wild ones.
So you get a bunch of,
like when it was over you just like
shaking your head like,
God,
what did I just see?
So,
uh,
the craziest thing man,
I,
when I had the incident at whole foods,
I don't know if you heard about it now
when I got punched a blender with
somebody,
punched you.
What?
In the parking lot or sometimes I'll get
it out now,
you know.
So I'm walking across texting on my
phone in a guy lays on the horn and my
girls like,
who is that?
I look up,
I don't know.
She said,
you don't know him?
I said,
no.
We walked to the car,
the car goes and parks like three spots
down from the dude gets up.
He's like,
what's up motherfucker?
And I was like,
like me,
you're talking to me?
And he's like,
yeah bitch.
And I was like,
okay,
and then just smoke me and my,
I blew my glasses on the floor.
Now mind you,
I'm still in trial for the boat race.
It's thing that's going on the boat.
One was you head kicks some dude,
right?
Allegedly some dude got,
I'll get to that story out.
So my girl looked at me and burning
fucking fire is raging out of my ears,
right?
She goes,
no,
no.
Right.
So I'd tell this dude like anybody
would.
Today's your lucky day.
The dude's like,
oh yeah,
mother fucker back.
Right?
And then then he hops up again to hit me
again.
I said,
motherfucker be touched me again.
I'm going to kill you.
Like,
like I can't take two.
I cannot take to Leonard there.
Right?
And so litter goes to hit this dude and
then he's like,
all Bible good doesn't cuss.
And he's like,
frick you,
you know what I mean?
Like he's like,
he's so lucky that guy got so lucky.
He probably thinks he's such a bad ass.
And uh,
we're in,
we just literally got training done
training.
So we're in like training gear.
We,
the whole foods gets shit the drink.
So was like,
you want to be a UFC fighter,
what the blah blah blah blah.
Like God man.
So,
uh,
and I got my car and drove away and
don't know who that guy is.
I have no clue.
Whoever you are,
pitch whoever got lucky as fuck.
Alright.
So anyways,
boat,
rage,
boat raised.
What happened?
We're up at Grand Lake.
Reason I go to grand lakes.
It's freezing cold.
No one goes to grand lake to wakeboard
because it's cold,
cold water,
ice,
grand lake,
Colorado up in the mountains.
Fucking super deep,
freezing cold lake.
But the water's beautiful.
Um,
so this guy lived there,
he seen my boat and he told the police
there and he seen us there the week
before and he called it massaging and
making load my boat because yeah,
as an expensive boat I can take care of
it,
whacked it,
make sure it's clean,
you know,
to,
and he's upset that you take care of
your boat.
I guess that's what the police report
said.
So he,
um,
my buddy mike fishing off the back of
his belt,
off the back of my boat.
The guy comes in,
EU having fun playing.
He has like a ski do jet ski boat and he
uh,
comes feet away and like sprays water,
have a,
he washes my boat up onto the rocks.
Now I got cody Donovan at the time,
was fighting in the UFC.
I'm in three or four of the nine of us.
There was nine of us.
We were camping out for the weekend and
uh,
cody's fight rate like,
fuck,
let's go get him.
The girl settle us down.
We don't.
Right.
So later on,
about an hour and half later we go out,
we'll go wakeboarding.
Well,
with my boat you got to fill the ballast
tanks up so you have to like kind of sit
idle and let the tanks fill.
So while we're sitting there idle and it
takes feel he's down in the area.
So we're like sitting there letting the
tanks fill.
He's like flexing his muscles from the
shores and which one are you want
something bro.
So it gets in his boat and he goes
flying up next to my belt completely.
Let's go to the steering wheel and runs
the front of his boat.
His boat just goes pink and hits my
boat.
And I'm like,
oh my God dude,
what the fuck are you doing?
And he's like,
which one are you?
Pussies wants them shit.
We're like,
what?
So everyone bakers are happening and
blah blah blah blah.
Anyways,
the dude says,
you know what?
Fuck it on the run my boat into your
boat.
He's like wasted drunk chairs off,
flipped a bitch and comes bead lining
for my boat.
Now had this not been the situation
we're in,
I would have congratulated this,
do for the most epic fucking water spray
I've ever seen thrown into another
person's boat because at the last second
he cuts and throws the most massive wave
that just drench is everyone's phone and
just like,
like he hits you like a tidal wave and I
was like,
was fucking pissed.
So I tried boat to the shore and I get
off the boat and I run about 200 yards
down the shore trying to get him to come
to me because my girl stood up and she's
like,
that's fucking it.
And that's all I had to hear when I
hurt,
when she stood up and you know,
she's like,
that's it.
That's it.
You know what I'm saying?
That was it.
That's all I need to know.
Okay.
That's it.
So I tried to get this dude to run to
me.
He does not.
He comes straight from my girl,
gets off his boat,
pointing his finger at her,
you know.
So I just walked right past step in
front of him and I just front teeth
stumbling,
like set them down in the sand,
like chill the fuck out.
A lot of crazy gorilla pounding the dude
in the sand is going through my mind.
I don't always trained myself and the
dude gets up and tries to hit me with
the old sneaker righthand Oh God,
sorry.
I just slipped and I had kicked him
lightly Gel and I say lightly,
very lightly,
like just like a,
like a boom and sit him down and I'm
like,
motherfucker don't even know what the
fuck.
I said he wouldn't get up,
dude won't get up now.
So I literally sit down right next to
him like,
you fucking,
I don't know what to do and I,
I want to just thrilled.
Just ripped his heart out.
Right?
Or to start backhanded him sitting next
to sitting next to him,
shoulder to shoulder.
Little weird.
What a weird dude.
That's the only thing I can in the fit
of rage.
I mean I could,
I could think to do that.
So cody grabs me,
knock enough's enough.
And as soon as I do that,
the kid rolls over,
take out his phone and takes a picture
of me,
take a picture of my boat.
He dials nine slash 11 and I was like,
good call.
I'm on when you fucking idiot.
So the do calls nine slash 11,
call
show up.
I said,
yes,
dude's drunk.
He says,
man,
I'm only junk because this dude
embarrassed me in front of all of my
friends.
So I had to drink to get over what had
just happened.
What?
How'd you embarrass him by cleaning your
boat?
Oh no,
because I had kicked him in front of his
friends.
But that was before that,
the massaging.
And so he,
he had a lot of people with them.
Yeah,
like a big camper.
So we go to court,
we filed the second two year process.
I'm going through all the guys that his
width or are there police statements
match mine that he'd been.
He was talking about us all day.
Two weeks.
You would chase us down.
He wanted a piece of it.
So I mean it,
it all got dropped and dismissed,
but he tried to come up from 50 grand
and it was just unbelievable.
What's amazing,
how nice you were about it mean the
front kick to the chest and head kick.
Yeah,
exactly.
Exactly.
And what I just told you,
there is the same story.
His people told him,
he said,
I'm not exaggerating that didn't I just
haul off and beat him down?
Which I,
I'm thinking I'm maturing in my,
in my water.
You aren't mature.
I am going to tell you that.
It's just amazing how people will try to
sue over things like that.
Like that becomes like the lottery to
them.
Do you know the two guys sued?
The people always ask that came in.
Can you take a picture choking me like
the UFC doesn't want anybody choking
anybody in pictures.
I've been told that I tell them no.
And Matt Hughes were both sued.
The Matthew story is kind of hilarious
because the guy asked Matt he to put
them in a rear naked choke for picture.
So Matt Hughes does.
And then the guy says,
hey look,
I got evidence has got choked me and he
hurt me.
So he tries to sue.
Well they do an investigation on the guy
and find out the guy's a cop.
Then they dig deeper and find out he's a
dirty cop and the dude wants up getting
popped and goes to jail because of that.
And the chocolate Dell one,
I'm pretty sure chuck had to wind up
paying something like three times,
three times,
three times they've been sued them.
And my neighbor,
I'm sued me for what he said that,
um,
my dogs attacked his horse.
Did they know?
Absolutely not.
Some body else's dog did,
but he was a neighbor.
So we said mind to guy just moved in and
his horse ran through the fence.
Well,
if you're any kind of a horse owner at
all,
you can't just move into somewhere and
take the reins up your horse and let him
go.
We have no idea what the perimeter you
need.
You need to take your horse out and walk
the perimeter.
He lets his horse,
the horse runs through the fence.
He said,
and my dogs chased him to the fence.
Um,
it was cheaper for me just to pay the
guy off than to go to court and fight
it.
So it's just unbelievable,
man.
That kind of shit drives me fucking
crazy.
In my old roommate,
me and Leonard Garcia used to live in.
We'd have guys come down for training
camp.
Um,
this lady got as good man after we,
after when I bought this new house,
we moved in.
She then claimed students that we were
subleasing are ran out to our training
partners was $12,000
out of Bayer.
Why 12,000?
Gives a fuck.
I don't understand it.
She must've been hurting for money.
So she was years old.
She owned the house at one point.
Did you ricky?
He used to work for Jackson's Greg
Jackson's guy.
I probably would if I saw him anyway.
So the ladies hurting for money,
right?
She needs to.
She's renting this house,
her house,
the house she's living in.
I get ricky buys her house from her.
I tell her,
hey,
we'll move out now so you can move back
into your house.
Does your foreclosing.
So we,
we make this all work,
right?
I worked with lady I,
she's a realtor.
I use her as my realtor to buy my ranch.
That's how fucking crazy this gets,
right?
So I use her or we do this.
Soon as we get the paperwork done,
she turns around and sues us for
subleasing are ran out.
And my grandma's honestly,
you can vouch for this fucking crazy.
Yeah.
She said that the whole time we were
there,
we were having people come down to
training.
We're,
we're,
we're renting it out to them and making
money off of her property.
Oh,
two.
And of course I got the notices to go to
court.
Why don't show up to court.
So they passed.
Brian could have fought it,
but I did.
And I was like,
yeah,
whatever.
If you do,
that takes forever.
The problem with those things is it's
like these,
uh,
blake,
do you know what a patent troll is?
[inaudible] patent trolls are.
They get patents on things.
They buy up patents and patents and then
they'll sue like a,
uh,
like a company like apple,
like they,
they were going to have to podcasters
for awhile and what they do is they'll,
they went after Adam Carolla for
something,
some,
some sort of sort of patent and they
went after a few other people,
but apple had a wound up paying like 7
million bucks or something like that
because for apple to,
you know,
they have so much fucking money.
It's easier for them to pay off a patent
troll than it is to address it in court
and spent all their resources and you
know,
they might like the UFC is doing this,
you know,
the antitrust lawsuit that like this is
going to cost them $100,
million dollars in legal fees.
But it's either that or pay people off.
They'd rather spend the money.
They'd rather pay the legal fees.
Yeah.
Oh,
because principle for them.
Well,
principle and also sets a precedent.
And you,
if you,
if you start paying out then other
people start coming out of the woodwork.
But what's a weird.
It's a weird world we live in where you
can just sue over shit like that Alpha
brain.
So brain size.
Good for you.
You got that big ass on it.
Package.
Right?
I love it.
I love the picture you sent of you with
the balancing.
How'd you do that?
Man with the balance was good.
But the whole thing done.
It was,
it was suspended.
Did you pull that off?
Because I'm fucking super athletic.
Alpha.
Pam.
Okay.
That's a good answer.
And,
and when we were at elevate,
which is a strength conditioning where
you guys sent a whole bunch of those
masons too.
And uh,
they were like,
you're gonna fucking knock your teeth
down.
And I was like,
well then I'll be at toothless
motherfucker,
but let's do this.
You,
you're constantly doing shit like that.
Right?
Like suddenly wake board in jumping
snowmobiles over the top way.
El Nino,
baby,
come on,
Colorado is going to be unreal this
year.
I cannot wait.
Everybody's hoping for that.
But I don't know if that's real.
I hope so.
They keep saying that though.
The way the temperature of the water at
California is like desperate surfing
with when with nothing this morning and
it was great.
Warm as fuck.
Warm,
super warm.
Yeah.
They have yellowtail they bad yellow
tail all over the coast around Santa
Monica and Malibu,
which is,
you know,
usually you got to go out to fucking
Hawaii and so uh,
they're pretty excited about it.
People think that this is going to
change,
but you know,
trying to guess what Mother Nature's
going to join a few months from now
because back then you could maybe key in
those words.
I have no idea.
I don't know either.
I don't know either,
but they are damn sure on the damn sure
on.
And what do they use?
What kind of Hocus pocus are they using
to figure that out?
Maybe the Mayan calendar.
That didn't work out though.
We're still here three years later.
Here we are.
I was convinced dude,
like way back in 2006.
I was like December 21st 2012.
It's all done.
All done for you on the computer.
Junior crash at 2000,
2000 came around.
I was hiding,
I stayed at home,
stockpiled water,
the whole deal.
I was listening to art bell,
Start Stock,
stockpiling water has stockpiled food.
I need to do the water guys have a.
well you're out.
You're out.
But the problem is the well the well
suck.
Well it's not that good because it will.
Well in Colorado it was really good for
you,
but if you have 20 people come to your
house and take showers.
So yeah,
I had a brand new water heaters and
everything like that.
You gotta well you're out there like are
you on solar?
No,
my wish I need to be billing.
So here's like a giant fucking white
them fucking Christ.
And if some asshole comes and trains at
my house and forgets to turn the heater
off from the gym,
$1,500
overnight.
Oh No.
And then I come into the house fucking
ripping and roaring.
Who the fuck?
And everyone's like wouldn't meet of
course 1500 bucks.
Propane in the winter.
Right.
And the funny thing is that the propane
companies like,
oh you don't want to pay.
We want to bring any more profane.
We don't give a shit.
Oh God.
You got to keep warm.
Yeah.
So yeah.
Fuck that dude.
You should have a fireplace in that gym.
Who's going to stoke it today?
You're the,
you're the stocker.
Go split the wood and stock of wood out
there.
Do you have a forest?
A?
No.
For us,
we got no CACTI.
Can you cook Cacti?
And a fucking not really.
Right?
I wonder if you can get some pot out of
it.
I don't know.
You'd have to have because we are.
We.
Are we on Pedro?
Is that what it is?
The idea.
But uh,
we're in the,
that's where they do it in young guns.
Oh yeah.
Well not only that,
tent rock where they film.
You're under spare road,
asshole.
That's miles down the road from me.
That is where.
Yeah,
yeah.
That's where they,
you know,
this only that's the only.
We're doing that for the last couple
hundred years.
Like everybody thinks that that was like
thousands of years old.
No evidence,
no evidence that they were,
you.
The native Americans were using
paylocity more than a couple hundred
years.
But um,
ha ha,
okay.
Marijuana Pot.
What do they like?
Let's just smoke this shit up.
How does that,
how does that work?
Who's the Guinea pig on that too?
Good question.
Pod.
Like,
oh,
let's just boil some cactus and oops,
now I'm fucking tripping.
So that was cool.
This is real good question.
There's a lot of those things out there
that like how the fuck did they ever
figure that out?
Like math,
math,
like all battery acid now like,
cool.
Let's all grow old medicine.
Oh,
you meth users out there.
Ix Nay boys.
Yucky.
Well there's very good cooks.
That's why,
you know,
breaking bad made a lot of sense.
You know,
he needed a real fucking chemist,
chemist.
But uh,
like the Iowasca one is a crazy one.
They've been using that for like 10,000
years.
You gotta take the leaves of one plant
and.
Yeah.
And they boil it down.
It's a,
it's dmt in a,
in a drinkable form because otherwise
dmt.
The only way you could take it as you
have to.
I've experienced him to eat more real
life.
We want to have an accident.
Uh,
when my guts were hanging out of me,
I remember him with your guts sides
where I got this giant scar.
What is the director director?
Four wheeler,
you know,
and uh,
broke all my ribs and anyway,
that was in the hospital flight,
took the flight for life to the hospital
and I remember laying there and laying
in the garden,
they had me strapped down because I was
a fucking lunatic and I remember tipping
the Gurney over and I had to throw up
and I threw up blood all over this poor
nurse and she did this little weird,
oh God has got blood thrown upon me.
Action.
And then I remembered they sent me back
up and it was like the most peaceful
feeling.
Like everything was just okay.
Like no pain.
Fucking dying was okay.
I stupid as that sounds and crazy.
Like it was just,
it was just okay.
I felt the best I've ever felt in my
life.
Wow.
It was like supernatural man.
It was crazy.
Like I was in so much pain,
like,
so I'm in the Goddamn ambulance and
they're taking me and there's a new guy
in there because my lungs were
punctured,
so this huge needle and the guy's
telling the other guy how to fucking
[inaudible] I guess he punctured her
lung and then your air comes back.
Right.
And the guys like walk in the new guy
through and I was like,
fuck no,
like,
I'm like,
I can't really say fuck no.
But um,
yeah,
I was like,
no,
you don't get the new guy today,
not today,
motherfucker.
So,
but anyway,
fit the Gurney over so much pain and
they write me back up and everything was
just okay.
Like went,
like it's crystally blue haze and I woke
up like two weeks later,
a strangling,
strangling my grandma two weeks later.
So you were in a coma?
Yeah,
well it's like a medical induced.
Yeah.
Wow.
Jeez.
How old were you when this happened?
It was 2006 June,
something in 2006.
My grandmother was fighting in the WEC.
At this time were you.
When did you start fire?
I was nine slash 2009,
so talk about me doing crazy shit that I
probably shouldn't be like it hurt and I
don't want to be able to fight.
I was,
I did this giant kickbox didn't want to
a world title and I won a spot to go
fight in front of the King of Thailand
and I was supposed to leave that weekend
that I went out racing motorcross and
wow.
So Ms Dot that fucking boat,
but a hey,
this,
there's not a lot of money and fight
King of Thailand anyway.
No,
but I mean,
so the kid was,
the only reason I got into fighting was
because a,
I love it was like my favorite thing to
do in the whole world still is.
But I would just see the world.
They'd call me and I was the guy.
They would call you all.
Everyone talks about taking short
notice.
So I was like,
Craig Kelby,
you're crazy.
Like man,
I used to take fights on three days.
Notice I'm taking them a four weeks now
I'm fucking good.
So they'd call me.
I was their guy.
They'd call and be like,
Hey,
we need you in Japan.
Um,
it's Wednesday when you there Saturday.
And I'm like,
let's go.
And I'd go and fucking me and my buddy
Mike Baldwin,
who was like my best friends still to
this day who comes to everyone of my
fights would get off the plane,
hit Rappongi.
I don't know if he is like,
yeah,
the party.
And I remember sometimes I was so hung
over for Wayne's that I'm like trying to
drink gatorade and recruit my brain.
Just marketing,
just to weigh in,
just to square up.
Just a waiting areas.
Yeah.
So those,
I mean in fighting,
which is something that I did to pay for
my trip to go see the world.
So fun.
Those days where I still,
I still live in today,
you know,
finding me.
People make such a big deal.
And I see like,
like felder's a perfect example man.
He,
they take it so serious.
Fighting is not that serious.
Felder takes it too seriously.
Serious man.
So that's one thing I try and teach
these guys like,
man you drink beer,
you fucking alcoholic,
you piece of shit.
That's what I hear all the time.
Yeah.
So what?
I drink beer.
I love.
I like to drink beer.
Cool.
Refreshing.
Budweiser's.
She ain't got that band.
I liked drinking.
I like to have a good time.
But people taste it.
They quit their life.
Right?
Weeks.
They're like,
can't eat that.
Can't do this,
can't go home.
I have this huge fight in mma.
How is it the biggest fight of your
life?
I mean,
it's the same like this dos Anjos fight
coming up January or December 19th.
Orlando,
Florida.
World title.
Biggest fight of my life.
God Damn Right.
I'm a drink.
Beer and fucking have a good time and
probably get there 10 days early and go
wakeboarding and go,
oh my God,
why not?
So you just kinda treat it like it's any
other ordinary life.
Yeah,
because back in the day when I used to
fight,
he'd be on two,
three days notice I had nothing to worry
about.
It's just a fight.
But what do you worry about an incident
happening?
Like the incident that kept you from
going and fighting for the King of
Thailand.
I mean,
that's,
that's the real,
I mean the big thing is to win the
title,
right.
The most guys when they get to your
position,
they kind of start playing it safe.
That's the difference between you and a
lot of these guys because a lot of guys
are wild in the beginning,
but then somewhere along the line they
start realizing the consequences and the
stakes and they start playing it safe.
Yeah.
I just start to play it safe kind of
guy.
Yeah.
I could go.
I could go wakeboarding the week of the
fight and blow my knee out.
Sure.
I'll probably still with a blown knee,
just tape that bitch out.
See what's up.
Just a couple of shots.
Get a couple shots of Jack still getting
cortisone.
There's all sorts of shit they can do
now to sort of help you a little bit.
Short term blown out knees.
Never a good time.
No,
no.
I mean I've had a couple blonde needs,
but how many different he had knee
surgeries other than the stomach?
No,
no surgeries.
Amazing.
Yeah.
In fact,
in front of the,
before the uh,
my last fight,
I'm,
I supposed to get an Mri on my knees and
I had an MRI of my chest because my
fucking ribs are so separated and I made
it very crystal clear to the EFC.
I will go get this MRI,
but regardless of the outcome it comes.
I'm still fighting.
Is that okay with you guys?
And it was long and they said yes.
So I was like,
fine.
They wanted you to get an Mri.
You wanted to get a day.
Wanted me to want to do together.
So you were complaining of some pain
maybe or you're realizing there's
something wrong.
Like my chest was super separated,
like I couldn't even take a bridge pop,
pop,
pop like in my solar plexus.
So uh,
went to Dallas and I went and trained
with some kids in the gym and the dude
through a knee with no Shin Pad and just
crushed me and my solar blacks and like
separated it bad.
So like what fight was this for the law?
Midecky fight.
So real.
Yeah.
The last fight,
I am the one who is supposed to be with
qbe that he pulled out for the third
fucking time,
so that guy gets hurt a lot.
These are all fucked up,
fucked up.
A lot of those guys that are fucking
cane,
right?
A lot of those fucking guys are super
strong mentally.
Just ridiculously aggressive.
Those guys wind up blowing shit out.
Like canes blown out his knees,
bone on his shoulder.
Both shoulders had surgeries on him.
Fuck yeah.
That style of fighting,
especially that intense grappling style,
like you just weighed less injuries and
kickboxing and then stand up striking
like boxing.
How many fucking fights get canceled in
boxing?
It's rare as fuck man.
Fight Mayweather.
He said,
oh,
I can't pull it.
Yeah,
almost.
I don't know.
I can't remember a big fight ever.
I mean it would have to be something
severe and usually it's like doing
during strength and conditioning
training or something,
you know,
or running or something maybe.
But it's very rare that someone pulls
out of a bar or they'd have to break
their hand or something like that,
but it's rare.
But in MMA,
Goddamn,
it's common,
it's fuck,
there's so many weird scrambling
situations that you get involved in,
you know,
within you bring in guys to train with
and sometimes those guys.
That's the other thing that what you
just said to bringing in guys to train
with man.
I think that is one of the biggest
mistakes that guys make is that these
young guys,
they bring into camp.
They don't even know these guys.
These guys tried to make a name look at.
Well,
if you brought me in to train with you,
Joe,
I'm fucking you up,
right?
Yeah.
You want to.
I'm not gonna.
I'm not gonna let you beat me down.
Especially if you're coming into a
champs gap or has a high level guy who's
well respected.
They want to say,
dude,
Donald Cerrone came into blah blah,
blahs
camp and fucked him up.
Oh Shit.
Really?
I mean,
that's what happens.
So you need to,
you got to have your friends.
He had friends.
A lot of guys do it the right way,
like what you're doing at the bad
motherfucker ranch.
All those guys are family,
right?
Yeah,
absolutely.
And speaking of family like failed or
people are like,
Kelly,
you want him to lose like the fuck I do
what his,
him losing due to me.
You can't respond to those people.
You can't get.
I live at six comma line,
Edwin New Mexico and you motherfuckers
won't come.
You can't get it.
What that is,
you're opening yourself up to the
retards of the God and you know you got
your standard.
You're talking about the people that
comment on a youtube video.
I feel the same dumb shit to me.
I'm like,
you are a youtube where they could be
children.
It could be young,
young kids or could be morons supposed a
picture of something like surfing and
people are like,
Connor's going to kill you.
Well Bitch,
first of all he's okay.
I want to just get on there and say all
kinds of shit.
And it's just like you got to pick who
you communicate with.
Like say look like you and I know each
other.
This Jamie,
Jamie,
he's a good dude.
You want to have a conversation with
Jamie?
He's not going to say anything retarded,
but he's right there in front of you.
Now,
if,
if we were just random people talking
around,
you never know.
You might run into a good dude like
Jamie or you might run into some
complete fucking idiot that you would
never talk to him in real life.
But in text they all look the same.
They all look the same.
It all looks the same,
but God can say some shit in a full
sentence and you know,
and pretend that he has a point.
God dammit.
I'm gonna.
Start drinking too.
All we're gonna have to.
You're getting fired.
Are you?
Uh,
are you cracking open a nice cold,
refreshing budweiser?
I am Donald American Budweiser.
I just don't,
I just don't think it's wise to
communicate with people that are just
insulting online.
I don't,
I don't ever go back and forth.
I used to.
Why do you drink that fucking piss
water?
Disgusting beer comments.
I get some bad.
Budweiser is not bad.
And then I reached back and like,
Oh yeah,
they pay me to drink that fucking ice
cold bud.
Budweiser.
I love it.
I like all kinds of different.
We used to be a bud light guy,
but now I'm more of a bud heavy guy,
but I like a Sam Adams.
I like a Guinness.
I like a dark beer,
but I like a budweiser to.
It's like I like water and occasionally
I like whiskey.
So you're talking about start begging
her to snakebite snakebite.
Snakebite is genis half Gannis and then
half an apple like apple lager.
Oh really?
Oh,
snakebite maybe.
No.
What's that shit that we drank?
Black butte porter.
That shit's good.
Good.
There's dark beer.
This dark black.
Who makes that black butte?
Who's the company?
That makes sense.
Google.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Does shoots brewery.
How awesome is Google now?
Because no one can bullshit.
You could have told me 20 years ago,
a year,
the best restaurant in the world.
I'd be like,
Oh,
you are?
I know you won state seven times.
Wrote and took worlds.
Whoa.
How many artists?
Uh,
no you didn't.
No,
you didn't actually.
You've never been wrestled.
How many martial arts guys were like
that though?
All the one that wore the recto rex
condo.
Fucking bad ass pants doing mag flag
American flag pants and shit.
Yeah,
it used to be,
there was a bunch of guys that claim to
be in.
Do you ever know who Rafael Torres.
You ever hear about that guy who was a
guy who was a writer for um,
like one of those online magazines?
Uh,
I think Abu Dhabi news hired him and uh,
he turned out to be a fake black belt
and wound up killing the guy.
Won them killing like he was dating a
girl and she was married.
Some dude killed a dude for the
insurance.
Money got busted the whole deal
craziness,
right in jail now for murder.
But before that he was claiming to be a
black belt,
but he set off a bunch of alarms.
Would go off to Thailand to have these
fucking no holds barred fights and come
back and yeah,
I got them into twister in the first
round.
Everybody was like,
you just learned that like last week,
like it was,
it was real weird.
But one of the things he did that was
hilarious is this dude claim to be in a,
a.
no rules Kuma Tay in the woods.
So he had his friend drop him off.
He brought a big ass duffle bag.
Right,
right.
As big he had his friend drop him off.
He was like,
drop me off and come back again.
Get me a couple of days.
Right.
So his friend dropped him off.
He goes off into the woods and it
shrank.
Comes back in a couple days now he's got
a trophy.
No more,
no more fucking duffle bag with two
trophies and same size as the duffle
bag.
Dude comes back without a scratch on
him.
The camping gear.
I mean,
but that's the kind of shit that people
did.
You know,
they,
they were people who were retarded.
They really would pretend that they were
involved in these no holds barred
contests.
And there were 150.
You know,
I remember the early days like Hixon
gracie there would say 400 and oh sure.
Well you mentioned if you had 400
fucking fights.
God Damn.
You got to fight a lot.
You have to find like every couple of
days for years.
And it sounded like my high school days,
you'd have to win all of them too.
That I did.
Not that I did not.
Yeah.
Well those are important.
Loses the losses are some of the most
important ones.
Right?
Those are the ones that really make you
get back and fucking dig in that burn
you burn yourself.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Absolutely.
To this day,
are there any losses that,
that just fucking that when you get up
in the morning,
you think about that one and it makes
you just want to go run and you know,
more or less.
The guys that talked about the Diaz
fight,
tell me all the time of day will beat
your ass at the nic.
The Diaz brothers have the most
incredible following,
almost almost as credible as the conor
mcgregor following the colts is
unbelievable.
So they,
uh,
they was telling me all the time,
you beat your ass again.
Like,
all right,
well bring his ass on [inaudible].
I'm ready.
Whatever.
What?
You fought nate,
right?
And the Nate Diaz fight like it seemed
like you having a hard time in the first
round.
Like you had a hard time getting
started.
Like that was a fight where like,
that dude talked to a lot of shit to
you,
your boy.
And it seemed as he.
Is he contacting you?
He just said he's still there.
I told him come crashed his mother.
Fuck.
Ah,
where is he?
I don't know.
Oh,
he's texted you right now.
Um,
yeah.
I was like,
you were asking me.
He got in my head and you got me.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And that shit doesn't happen anymore.
No.
And everyone tells me kronars in your
head.
Dishonesty.
So that was a lesson for you.
Super Lesson man.
Yeah,
don't,
don't you mean.
So let's,
let's take it back.
You're talking about rex Condo,
this guy,
right?
Oh,
you see all the movies that people say
don't fight out of anger.
I say that for a reason.
I mean,
so when I got out of anger,
I mean that's,
I was just,
I don't know what the fuck I was doing.
I was just sucked that night and that's
all there is to no excuses.
The motherfucker beat me to just get
caught up in it,
up in the emotions of all the shitty
talking.
He knocked your fucking hat of God.
How dare he can talk some shit.
I'll tell you what you know.
But I as much as he talked,
I,
I like,
like those guys.
I like them too.
I really do.
I mean because there is no front on them
at all.
They are what you see is what you would
like if I were to run into the Diaz
brothers out in the street.
We're fucking throwing down and there's
no question.
I mean that's just who they are.
I mean they're,
you know,
so it's not like they put on this front,
this persona that they're big tub.
No,
that's who they are.
Twenty four slash 24 slash seven and
yeah,
it's awesome to me.
You know,
I think both of them I got nothing but
respect for both.
So when you guys were all retired or
you'll have a drink together and have a
drink with them now I don't have any.
I don't have any animosity or any anger
or hate towards either one of them.
I would definitely hang out with both of
them,
you know,
and it sucks that fucking,
nick is in trouble with this whole
marijuana thing and it was awful.
It's awful.
And it just shows how bad the Nevada
state athletic commission is.
And they were angry because he took the
fifth because he didn't want it.
The fucking guy passed two World Anti
Doping Agency tests to test are blood
tests that way.
More accurate than the fucking urine
test that Nevada state athletic
commission gave him with Quest
Diagnostics,
you know,
and nothing against quest diagnostics.
But that method of testing is not as
accurate.
Right.
So the dude was within the realm.
I mean he was,
he was legally passed and they try to
stay.
They're stealing money from them and
they suspended him for five years.
There are fucking kangaroo court that's
five years.
Ridiculous.
At any job.
I mean if I said,
Joe,
you're off the air for five years,
you're fucking ruined man.
That's five years irrelevant after
almost a year.
And if you're not,
I mean he,
he,
he is one of the names in the sport.
Absolutely.
But I mean five years he's getting older
and he's like 33 or 34.
How old is nick now?
Hold on.
I want to say he's 32 at least.
Right?
So five
years.
He's fucking 37 and he's not doing any
trt.
He's not doing shit,
man.
God bless him.
He's 32.
Yeah,
it was right.
So five years from now it's over man.
When we were kids,
when a boxer like hit his thirties,
you're like,
ah,
he's 32,
33 is almost over.
We knew it was almost over.
Sure.
But then the age of trt came along,
especially with mma,
things got real weird.
Sure.
Things got real strange.
Like you started to see guys like 36,
37,
like vito or having a fucking fights of
his career,
the best fights ever.
You know.
And these guys,
the Diaz brothers,
one thing you've got to say about them
as these fucking dudes take care of
their bodies.
Yes,
they eat healthiest.
Fuck.
Nick's always eating all organic food.
He eats really healthy.
He's constantly shaped constantly.
When if this guy is smoking pot,
he,
he's not,
he's not doing meth.
You know what I'm saying?
I mean,
he's taking care of his body.
It,
it's not like he's doing steroids.
It's not like he's doing something
that's making them freakishly fast or
ridiculously strong.
It's actually the complete opposite.
It's the whole thing is it's so
frustrating,
man,
that these clowns have any power over
people like you.
It drives me crazy.
It drives me crazy that people like you
need these fools that have never been
punched in the face.
They've never been strangled.
They'd never fought a day in their life.
And they're the ones that get to decide
what happens to you.
Well,
they're the ones who get to tell Nick
Diaz he has to sit out for five years
and they have the pencil pushers of
American man.
They're the people that in high school
didn't,
you know,
I feel like those are,
those are the guys that now they have
something to prove now.
Now he's high and mighty,
you know,
and maybe you know,
but,
but there's a lot of pencil pushers that
are good dudes,
you know,
it's a good women.
It's not the problem.
The problem is people in positions of
power that are accustomed to that
position of power and then they treat it
like a fucking king or a queen.
They're tyrants.
That's my buddy Scott Parker.
Was it parked from the avalanche that
he's been over 400 fights.
He just actually ran the dairy dairy.
You marks.
Is that the,
uh,
the forest.
The forest actually you have four sides
because those guys will fight all the
time,
right?
He'll probably like two,
three times a week.
That's huge.
He's,
he's my snowmobile and partner.
Right?
So we,
that's what I'm saying is El Ninos and
pump.
So I don't know if you've ever ridden a
snowmobile,
but you get stuck in like five,
six feet of power and now you're stuck.
A big assemblage come over one hand by
Rad just written me out,
like go get it.
And I'm in there digging me out like an
hour.
And then I'm like,
mother fucking big ass bitch show.
Yeah.
He's a good dude.
Came down,
helped me build the fucking ranch,
managed solid guy solids as it gets.
That's nice man.
It's good to have good friends.
Yes.
Especially ones that can lift a fucking
snowmobiling rack,
pull it out of the world of professional
athletes is short that
it's even more frustrating when someone
gets.
Like,
if you're an accountant and they suspend
you for five years,
you know,
hey,
you could always get a job doing
something else.
Then five years from now you get
reinstated as an accountant.
But when you're an athlete you got this
short window.
I mean,
I think nick started fight when he was
18,
so he's 32 now.
He's got a few years left at Max.
Yeah,
Max Max.
I mean it's conceivable that he could
come back at 37 since he does take care
of his body.
Maybe it's maybe it's a very tough
financially.
What are you doing right?
You're accustomed to a lifestyle in
fighting.
I am at least.
Yeah,
sure.
I'm a super degenerative my money.
Everyone knows.
That's not mean.
What if I were to,
if something happened to me today,
I don't know what would do.
You would have to go on the road and
started doing seminars,
but euro because of your style and
because of Nick's style,
you guys are both really well loved.
Like if something like that happened
with you,
you could go do seminars and make a few
grand every week and maybe,
maybe not in Dublin.
How not to go anywhere.
Thought you could do it.
If you and connor fought and duked it
out,
had an epic contest,
then you could do it.
You know,
I'm just a big stick in the more.
If you beat them a couple times
decisively,
you'd have to beat them to where they
have to just give in.
They'd have to say,
all right,
you had to beat them,
beat them.
But if you're fucking cut down to 1:45,
you torture them.
Fucking connor example.
Man.
I appreciate the fuck out of.
Look at that guy's doing.
He's getting eyes on the sport.
Yeah,
he really pisses me up.
I feel like just tell him when he was in
the fucking president,
but I wanted to rip him so bad.
Of course.
Wanted to kill my own bag.
You know a car and you can blow me like
a cup of hot soup.
You son of a bitch but me like a cup of
hot soup.
You blow on a cup of hot soup.
Is that what it is?
Yeah.
Okay.
Don't.
But if he just blows you like that,
that's why it's confusing.
The vernacular is really odd.
Like blow jobs.
I don't understand where that blow me
like a couple hot soup first time.
First Time.
There you go.
I've never heard that one before.
I've been around.
That's bought.
But the fucking guy.
Look what he said to dos Anjos.
That shit was hilarious.
Like,
you know,
he's like,
if you get a fight with me,
you have made it to your wife honey.
Put It on the fucking red panties.
We made it.
Come on.
I,
I appreciate the fucker.
That shit.
His shit talking game is better than
anybody.
It is.
He's the best ever.
Yeah,
I mean and Nick Diaz is right because
you know like what his anc antics inside
the octagon.
Nick's antics inside the octagon fuck
would a lot of people's heads.
Sure.
Like the first fight with Robbie lawler.
Like I remember there was a first time I
ever saw nick talk shit.
It was the first fight with brock.
He logs Robbie.
It was dangerous.
So Nick,
Nick took that shit talking to def con
five and he got into the octagon and the
first thing he does,
he gets into the octagon.
He looks over at robby goes stockton
motherfucker stockton and he starts
walking around Stockton Mother and rob.
He's like,
what the fuck is he talking about?
That even mean?
Yeah.
Then the entire time the fight is going
on like,
what?
Bitch,
what you gonna do Bitch,
what you gonna do Bitch.
And it hit them all.
Bitch,
I just stung you bitch.
And it'd be popping them and every time
robby lawler didn't talk back to them
but you could clearly see he's not,
he didn't anticipate that,
but I don't.
As far as nick and nate go,
I don't know if that's like a game plan
that there that's just like them.
Like I think if they were on the street
they'd be like,
whoa.
Like that's like real life talk like
that,
what they know.
But it's still a bit like that.
That's,
that's,
that's them,
that's them.
You know what I'm saying is still a
psychological think.
It's an excellent tactic.
And,
and do you think silver?
It fucked Anderson Silva's head up dude.
Somebody laid out on the mat.
Yeah.
He laid down,
got a and get a nap in the greatest
pound for pound fighter in the history
of the sport and he lays down and then
he gets up with his hands out like what
bitch,
what pitched fucking.
And he didn't do any of that leading up
to the fight,
which was even more fucked up because I
don't think Anderson expected it at all.
And then when he was in there talking
shit to him,
you could see Anderson just like moving
around and not doing anything frozen.
And you know,
thinking about like,
look,
bitch and Anderson had never experienced
that before.
Man,
come did he is Anderson is the,
the greatest psychological fall I've
ever seen in my career to witness him go
from the guy who beat Stephan Bonner who
steps his back up against the cage,
drops his hands,
was like,
come on,
go ahead and then moves out of the way
and then decides,
all right,
now I'm gonna attack,
hits bonded with the need of the
stomach,
drops out and then pound them out and
Tkos.
Um,
and then it looks like a guy in the
fucking matrix.
I mean.
And then to go from that confidence to
the two Weidman fights,
man,
they did a number on him.
They did a number on him like I'd never
seen before.
It's,
it's fascinating to see.
It's fascinating to see how a guy could
be almost just unbeatable.
And then Weidman,
after the second fight,
I mean,
you gotta think about the second fight.
Anderson broke his leg,
right?
Sure did.
Well Weidman didn't knock him out.
He broke his leg and he had him hurt bad
first round.
But then after that fight,
Wyden was like,
you know what,
I don't want to find them again.
I want to hurt him.
Like,
Whoa,
just for Anderson to hear that.
It's got to be like,
that's a mind fuck man playing.
I mean you're coming up.
I mean the mind is such a motherfucker.
Like if you could just get your mind to
do what your heart wants to do,
life will be so much easier.
I think there are so many times I'm in
the cage.
Right.
And I don't know if my brain knew what
my heart was trying to say,
but that's what I wanted to do.
You know?
And it's so and then you fuck bro.
I can't even put words on it,
you know?
It's crazy.
Do you do any mental training?
Do you do any meditating or any
visualization?
Fucking ice cold budweiser rather than
talking about,
God dammit,
fucking fight is a fight.
But I probably maybe should.
I mean,
but it's,
it's in this sport.
It's not like.
Gotcha.
I was telling him,
Blake Griffin Day like,
hey man,
you have a bad day.
You fall back,
let your team pick up slack.
If I have a bad day on the worst fighter
in the world,
my twitter feed is just nothing but you
pussy fucking die.
Well,
there's a difference between a guy
losing a basketball game two and getting
shit on by fans.
All you have to stay offline for a
couple of days.
You know when you hit that three pointer
to win the game and you're a fucking
hero again,
back to your backup.
But for a fighter man,
especially because fighting like when a
kid or especially an idiot looks at a
fighter,
they look at something that is so
unattainable,
they might as well be talking to a
Unicorn,
you know,
they might as well have been talking to
a god.
They might as well be talking to someone
who's not even real so they feel like
they can talk shit to you.
Did you say God and something real like
you're not even say since I like it.
Yeah,
that's what I'm saying.
You know like your,
your Apollo and Zeus or something.
You know what I'm saying?
Because like you,
you,
you are not,
they don't relate to you.
And when the rightness thing,
they're sitting there,
they're fucking keyboard getting crazy,
man.
I don't know.
What I just did was I think I might have
deleted something.
I mean the crazy thing about fighting is
if you and I were to go out and fight
right now,
there's no emotion.
There's no thought.
It's just fucking get it right.
But now December 18th,
I have this big tondo to think the
problem.
It's not the fight that bothers me.
Nothing at all.
And I think I speak for all fighters.
I don't know.
I don't give a shit,
but it's,
I got my grandma's sitting ringside,
I got all the people I meet along the
way that you know,
I've met and I've interacted with and
hung out and in their mind when they
talk to people like,
Oh yeah,
I'm going to,
cal was fight.
He going to fuck this dude up.
And I'm like,
you know what I mean?
So,
so like the precedent is so high,
like we need the pressure.
Unbelievable.
So He's talked to those people leading
up to that fight.
You know what you should do.
I don't even know if it's,
if it's talking to them over,
it's just knowing they're there,
knowing that they're there and knowing
that there.
I mean,
if the pressure is unbelievable.
So when you're in that fight and they're
like,
are you ready,
are you ready?
And sometimes you're like,
fuck no,
I'm not kidding.
No,
I'm not ready.
It is never going to be a time when I'm
ready for this.
Oh No,
no,
I'm not sweating.
I'm hooking my heart's pounding in my
chest and,
and they're like being and you're like,
oh shit.
Fake it till you make it and it's time
to,
you know,
it's unbelievable man.
And you gotta go out there and is he
ready?
So that I need to look across to him and
he's like,
he doesn't look ready.
He hit me.
You know what I mean?
Like it's some nights and some of those
times when you're sitting in the corner
and look across and you're like,
second got him,
check,
I could see it.
I broke him.
Got It.
Sometimes you will crush.
He's like,
I don't know.
What is this dude going to come out
really hard and it hurt like it's
[inaudible] so crazy.
Like the Eddie Alvarez fight,
third round come out.
He came out.
I was like,
Whoa,
whoa.
Hey Man.
Slow down.
You know what I mean?
Like,
so it's,
it's,
there's so much mind shit that goes on.
Like I said,
I can get my fucking mind do what my
heart wants to do.
I feel like it can be anyone in the
world,
but the problem is,
is being ready on game day.
Man.
It's so tough.
But listen to me.
Why don't you do any mental preparation.
I tried.
I tried to meet the mental people that
don't fucking do it and that's all Hokey
pokey.
Fucking turn yourself around your cell
phone.
You know,
I feel the mental game is so hard to
grasp because yeah,
Henry Smith and Jafari or calling out
what I should do,
right?
I see what I should do.
Right?
If I don't do it,
you just like frozen,
like a stick in the mud.
But do you think that like,
okay,
like when you,
when you're in the heart of battle.
Okay.
Let me ask you this.
When you're at your best,
like,
like let's say a particularly impressive
fight like the Jim Miller,
Jim Miller fight,
you were on fire.
You just look,
you look so dominant in that fight and
you look so focused and you just,
your combinations,
you're distancing.
Everything was on point when you're in
that zone,
right?
When you like right before you stopped
him,
what,
what is in your mind?
Are you empty or you blank?
I'm going to be a fucking thousand
percent honest with you.
I'm like a video game in a third person.
So I see myself from behind my head
playing myself.
He'll fucking moon and taking my brain
talking.
But that's how I see the fights.
I don't see the fight in me finding use
from like a helicopter view above my
fucking right shoulder and I see it like
when I'm in the zone and I'm so,
you know what I'm talking about,
emotional step back.
And I'd like do this like little hop
hopping that like puts me like.
Then I like go behind fucking dialed in
and it's like deep,
deep,
everything just flows right.
And I see myself out of body is crazy as
fuck.
Sounds right.
From like a third party.
Well I haven't heard it before from
anybody else,
but it doesn't sound crazy because I
think what you're talking about is it's
not you like your outside of you.
So I am.
I'm literally outside of me.
It's like I'm telling that person what
to do from an outside perspective.
So when you're at your best like that,
would you say you've done them?
Fight the entire fight the entire from
bell to bell.
The Donald fight.
I was outside.
I mean there wasn't a,
there wasn't a point we touched.
I remember clear.
They'll seeing myself run across and
touch gloves and he was fucking on dee.
What was the fight before the Dunham
fight?
Dos Anjos.
So do you think that because of the dos
Anjos loss,
like you,
you've got more focused,
more intense and then came out in the
Dunham fight and you were just on fire.
Fuck,
I wish I had an answer for that.
I don't know.
I mean,
I,
I totally underestimated the dust dust.
Sondra.
Sondra stocking will not happen again.
He's,
he's gotten a lot better.
Know that guy works
hard.
I know,
I know.
He's your adversary and you're fighting
them,
but when you're at your best,
would you say that you don't have any
emotions at all?
Zero,
right?
Zero at,
at,
at zero.
Yeah.
And then when you're frustrated and
you're in a bad place,
you're battling your emotions.
Trying to calm them down.
Try and.
Yeah.
It's like I'm,
I'm like trying to find second gear.
Yeah,
you know,
it's like the worst sound in the world.
You know what I mean?
That's what it fucking feels like when
I'm just,
I try to grinding,
grinding,
grinding like cold motherfucker that's.
And he talked to yourself,
you fucking pussy goal and that's what's
going through my mind.
Like,
I'm fat,
can't find it.
I just can't find second gear.
And it,
when you're in that place is the most
frustrating.
The absolute most frustrating man.
There's nothing that means like,
what do,
what do you do?
Well,
do you think that it's possible that
through mental training and through
specific techniques you could get better
at achieving that,
what you would call maybe like a flow
state the same way you got better at
being a fighter?
Like think about your first days of
fighting when you first learned Moitai,
you know,
you weren't like,
I'll tell you when I first saw you,
I saw you when you on the tap out show.
Sure.
Because it was like,
who is this wild motherfucker hanging
out with masks and throwing head kicks.
But the cool thing about you,
what I felt you um,
you sort of,
you were a pr,
the personification of an idea that
Eddie Bravo and I both had.
And that idea was if you get a guy who's
a really good kickboxer but also has a
really good guard,
their fucking super dangerous because
they're not worried about getting taken
down so they throw those kicks freely.
So you,
a lot of your early fights by submission
off your back.
Correct?
Because yeah,
I've just,
well for one of my wrestling was zero.
Right?
So I mean,
it's not like I was like,
oh,
there's kicked freely and defend.
He,
they just take me down.
I mean,
it's fun.
As you were to watch back then when I
first watched you,
are you telling me now?
Is that what's going on here?
No,
no,
no.
If you're a lot better now,
right?
Sure.
You're a lot better now.
So you got better at that.
Do you think that you could get better
the same way with your mind float and
don't you think that you should practice
that though?
I should,
I should.
I want to work on that.
I'm going to work on that.
I think if you had a coach that could
work through about this mind.
Right?
And there's been times when I've been
hitting pads and I fucking go into flow
state.
You're in the zone.
I go into it fucking blah blah,
blah.
I've seen you do it.
I've seen videos of you doing two days
ago by and I don't see it.
Right.
That's how it goes though,
right?
But then sometimes it's like,
dude,
it is like,
it's like a drug man.
I think that state exists in everything.
I think singers experience it.
I think also to basketball players,
all sorts of different athletes
experience that state and it's all about
trying to find that state that state
exists in standup comedy that state
exists in and,
and I think in every,
every thing that's difficult to do,
there's a time we use zone into his own
hand man or zone out.
Yeah,
whatever it is,
but it,
it only comes if you've dotted all your
i's and crossed all your t's.
You have to have no worries at all about
your preparation.
Oh No,
no,
no.
That all has to be absolutely.
Yeah.
You know,
and I think the drinking has any effect
on your physical performance or do you
think that you,
you do it at a level where you're not
fucking with your endurance thing?
I think,
I think people think that cowboy just
drinks fucking 12 pack at night,
but that's like how many beers do you
drink on a,
on a regular basis?
Uh,
with dinner,
a couple.
If I'm out with friends,
a couple,
you know,
we'll put the six pack down,
maybe maybe graduate to a 12 pack,
I don't know.
But uh,
we're engaging and having a good time.
So this is a rare moment.
Do I sit at home and drink alone?
No,
absolutely.
Social drink social drinker.
I hang out with my friends.
I'd have a couple beers.
You know what?
Dinner.
Um,
but a lot of times training,
when you're training,
you're sore,
you come home,
you know,
he wrote up,
you're like,
oh my God,
you want a beer?
Yeah.
Did you put two,
three beers down?
You're like,
oh,
taste so much better.
Yeah,
much better.
Ice Cold Beer after training is one of
the.
Actually it's good for you too because
there's something better.
Chocolate milk.
Well,
it's,
it's up there as long as you don't have
too much of it.
Just like a point of diminishing
returns.
They say that,
uh,
the like,
I guess it's the hops or whatever it is.
It can replenish the glucose and your
body,
you know,
who uh,
was a,
a Glucagon glycogen,
whatever it is,
you know,
who was a big believer in that one of
the best ever boss route and boss route
and never stopped drinking.
He goes,
hey,
I have a drink or two every night.
Well he did eventually because he sort
of developed an issue where,
you know,
he's getting a little crazy with it,
but when he was training,
you know,
he would have a couple of beers at night
and he didn't stop having it.
I mean sometimes I'll drink two,
three,
four nights in a row and I'll go,
I won't have a beer for a week,
two weeks.
I don't know,
you know.
And so here I'm gonna tell you the
problem with drinking.
Okay.
Are you ready for calculating velocity
on drinking?
I've been ready forever.
Alright.
So me and you have a six pack.
We roll over dinner,
six pack leads to a 12 pack and he's
just drinking shots,
leads,
zillow,
staying at two in the morning.
What do you do at two in the morning?
And you chase pussy right?
So now you fucking find a girl,
you go home,
she plays the.
I don't want to give you the pussy game
until 6:00
AM.
I don't want to give you the pussy game.
Sounds rap stuff.
Finally,
finally at six,
7:00
AM you do it.
Your deed fine.
Got Training at 9:30.
I don't make it.
That's where I feel alcohol.
Yes.
But if I have four or five beers,
I go home,
go to sleep.
Is it gonna affect my train mom?
I don't think so.
Not at all.
As long
as you have water,
not dehydrated,
all that jazz.
Yeah.
Do you watch your diet?
You absolutely not.
Well,
floyd mayweather.
Ate burgers 49,
12.
Yeah.
I mean I just,
I eat whatever I want to drink whatever
I want and that's my life.
So you never like,
you don't have like a dolce guy or
something like that.
It monitors your adult Tay Guy.
How dare you,
how?
What's wrong with adults?
You know,
nothing's wrong.
It works great for Rhonda apparently.
But,
um,
does works great for a lot of people.
Right now.
I don't,
I can't have you telling me if you said
cowboy,
calibrate that beer.
You can't eat pizza.
Pizza.
Pizza is like sex,
bad pizza or good beach.
It's still fucking pizza.
Brother does,
but is there a way you could have the
best of both worlds is the way that you
could like figure out how to give your
body the best fuel and maybe I'll give
you a little slight edge on it.
That's going to help.
You know,
supplements will help.
Vitamins,
supplements and vitamins.
Nothing.
Molino 30 to around my friends can,
can definitely preach for me.
I don't,
I don't take,
I don't take shit.
Nothing,
nothing.
No protein powders,
I use it a little bit of medicinal
marijuana on the fucking knee.
The CBD oil.
You know what you should do with the
knees.
Fucking stem cell injections are
incredible.
Man.
I,
he had one.
He had a,
he was that close to surgery at a stem
cell injection in his knee and fixed
them right up the.
Yeah,
I mean I.
Rhonda is apparently thinking about it.
She had her,
one of her judo coaches just had stem
cells done in his name to your steering
me away from medicinal marijuana.
Now I want you to do that to both do
that too.
But don't do it as much as Nick Diaz or.
No.
Do it refuse the urinalysis urine test?
No,
I uh,
I didn't.
I,
uh,
it was like a rub,
like a,
uh,
I was in Colorado.
I got A.
Oh yeah,
they have creams.
Claim is exactly what it was.
It was like a cream,
like a,
I think it was like a 50 to one cbd to
thc.
I got some of that chip and I'm scared
of it,
bro.
I put it on my knee.
I didn't,
I didn't feel.
I didn't.
I mean there wasn't.
No,
there wasn't.
It was only like one percent 50 to one
cbd and very little thc.
Correct.
Oh,
I see.
And do the week of it and my knee felt
great.
Um,
what's one of the best anti
inflammatories nonbelievers?
Well,
so and uh,
but I don't,
I don't,
I mean I don't smoke weed,
I don't shy on people that do,
I don't give a fuck.
You do whatever to help people,
you know,
make no difference to me.
Um,
I just wish I could be on high.
Have you ever been like,
like I used to get high when I was a
kid.
Like fuck,
I'm done being high.
Wish it could be an high right now.
Kind of like if you drink too much and
you're spinning,
you try to put your foot down on the
floor.
Like I wish I could be on fucking drunk
right now.
Same,
same kind of deal.
I wish you know.
Well,
it's like everything,
you know,
a little bit of moderation.
It's good.
Coupled toots,
just a little bit hanging out with the
make a little Kissy
kissy mean.
One of my good friends,
airborne and camp,
that's all he would smoke religiously
every day and when we'd be isolate
Harvard floor.
So I give me,
fuck,
let me hit that thing.
And the next Gen I'm over in the corner.
Fucked out of my mind.
I want to be on higher.
I don't have a tolerance for it.
And you're jumping right into the deep
end of the pool and he had swimming
lessons.
Okay.
To learn how to hold your breath.
Breathe in.
Breathe.
There's a lot of shit that goes into the
kitchen.
I've had a lot of friends who are like,
let me see what the fuss is all about.
I'll go,
okay,
listen to me.
This shit right here.
This glass tips.
Okay.
Smell this.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They use glass glass at the top.
Take a smell of that.
Just smell it.
Smell it.
Just smelled it.
See that?
That's not to be fucked with.
No,
you don't.
No.
That's not to be fucked with.
You could smoke it,
but you gotta be fucking careful.
You'll do this.
This looks like something that I would
find out on Colfax and Colorado,
like,
like a crackhead crackhead's.
Yeah.
Well you got to deal with this.
You handed me this job.
Be like.
I know.
Right?
But usually use paper at the end of it,
but glasses better than paper and it
comes in a fucking bitch and little.
Yeah.
Little spark that bitch up right now.
I will if you want me to.
Do you want some of this?
No,
I'm not going to know.
Okay.
Now Watch.
So Vapor,
Kush,
vapor air.
It is glass tip.
But I do this all the time.
I wouldn't recommend a hit like that for
a third floor.
Me,
that'd be done.
No.
W will confuse people.
It makes you anxious and freak out and
makes you confront all sorts of Shit
that you've been keeping in the back of
your head.
But I can fuck that shit all the time.
So this is my friend.
Okay.
I also want to dig in on us.
So I mean,
I,
I guess I don't,
I don't smoke weed.
I mean I've done it of course.
And um,
we did a backpacking trip with a couple
of buddies of mine and they brought
weeds.
Of course,
of course I smoked it,
you know,
packing,
we'd go hand to hand and I was in charge
of the hands and I was in charge of the
GPS.
So where we're going,
I don't know,
but it was two miles as the crow flies
every,
every fucking time they asked me where I
was gone because we kept moving.
But the spot we're going to stay the
same.
So everywhere we went it was.
So it's two miles as the crow flies.
So miles as the crow flies is such a
fucking mountain turn.
People who have never hiked,
I have no idea what you're talking
about.
Right?
But that's the idea folks,
is that if you go down and then up will,
the distance between those points
straight as a crow would fly is like a
mile,
but you're going like a mile and a half,
two miles,
maybe three if you were still fucking
air taco night where we out.
I said it's two miles as the crow flies
and they'd be like,
you mother fucker.
Dude.
I am amazed at how fucking tired hiking
gets you just fucking 80 pack ruck on
your band.
Yeah,
dude,
trust me.
When you're,
um,
when.
Especially in Colorado.
Yeah.
Well we brought all our rock climbing
gear with us.
Probably 30,
40 pounds of climbing gear,
30 40 pounds of gear,
and you're dealing with altitude.
Fuck,
it's hard,
man.
Where traditional climbers.
So we sat her on anchors.
Oh Shit,
me.
If you're going to do it,
why not?
Well,
I have this to make your.
You're fucking come all the way to a
bed,
right?
That what you do.
You like to make your sphincter like
really fuck that clamp down.
That's the thing.
That's another bucket when you,
when you go to,
when you're hanging out on one day and
you go to set that bolt and you don't
know if you said a good enough because
you're fatigued.
Oh Jesus Christ.
And he had to clip the rope.
Sweaty hands is heron about this.
I had this cat.
Uh,
Alex honnold.
You know who he is.
He's the one of the greatest free
climbers in the world.
You want to talk about setting your
sphincter.
This guy climbed shit that most people
don't even want to climb.
That's him just taking their time shit
with no ropes.
And one time he's halfway up the mount.
When he realized that he forgot his
fucking chalk,
he didn't bring any powder,
so he's halfway up the mountain and I
don't even like to do kettle bells
without powder you at that point.
It's kind of give it a little.
He just kept going.
He's an animal.
I mean this fucking kid.
Look at what he's doing.
Look at this.
Look at this fucking condo now.
Today.
Your Pot fucking committed,
right?
When you're halfway,
you don't just slam down.
So his only option is where's the
commode?
And I gotTa pee bad or right out there.
Go right out the door and take a drink
for fun.
I hear you,
dude.
Yes,
I'll be right up.
Fine without you.
I'm Donald is going to be fighting for
the title in a fuck.
When is it?
December in Orlando,
Florida.
And he's fighting Hafael dos Anjos the
guy who beat Anthony Pettis,
who was,
uh,
one of the baddest motherfuckers in the
sport.
So dos Anjos is a beast.
It's a,
it's a really big fight,
a really important fight.
And it's a fight that as much as he'll
talk about how much he,
uh,
you know,
he doesn't give a fuck and he's having a
good time and everything like that.
This is something he's been working
towards for a long,
long time.
But like while he's peeing,
I could just tell you this,
this is how this guy is all the time.
Like he's not putting on a show.
He's a great guy too.
He's fun to hang out with me and he's
always like this.
He's always friendly.
He's always like,
when you hear about him getting in
fights with people,
like the fact that he barely net kicked
that guy.
If a lot of people said that,
I'd be like,
please,
you fucking teed off on him.
Like I would have probably teed off on
him,
but he really would like a nice Eddie
Bravo or sheffield staring at me.
We went to Sheffield already should
fear.
That's my buddy Mike Maxwell,
but made a bunch of a fear.
Sheffield,
my girlfriend and my girlfriend's last
name Sheffield.
So that.
Oh,
that's very different.
You think about art,
you think about your girlfriend.
Things got weird,
that kind of super fucking weird.
My friend Mike made a bunch of different
pictures of uh,
this is what Joey back there.
We've got to revise the Joey Joey Diaz.
Wondering now which one was he?
That's in the back.
It didn't work out.
These are reduced.
So I just bought some new guns.
Yeah,
I saw a man.
So what is an integrity suppressed 300
win mag.
So,
and then that's where
the suppressor is part of the barrel.
The suppressor for people that don't
know guns as a silencer.
That's it makes it really quiet.
Sounds like a faggot.
And really all you hear is nothing.
So you have a $300,
right?
So it's a motherfucker of a gun.
So much kick.
Um,
so this has very little kick to because
it's zero kick.
So normally if you're gay people they
shoot and the double tap,
right?
Right.
Now you can do whatever you want.
And that's insane.
Insane.
So we're super,
super sonic rounds,
right?
Which is,
it breaks the sound barrier that's in
California,
isn't it?
This gun?
I'm sure.
Fuck,
everything is legal in California.
I have no idea,
but.
So they make sub subsonic ammo again.
All right,
so you don't hear it right?
But we're shooting supersonic animal.
Just to prove a point why all you could
hear is the bulk.
Clinique,
clinique,
clinique insane.
So the guy that came out to my house,
it's a keystone armory plugging them
right now.
But uh,
we'll please do.
They would spit down the barrel because
suppressors aren't made a gun.
How many rounds is that?
Whole?
Thirty two.
My 300 wind bangs,
Banjo Bolt.
Action Rifles.
The same one,
right?
So I'm going to leave it is an,
we were literally shooting it in my
backyard and the guys across the street,
we call them over.
They're like,
dude,
we thought you guys were just using your
nail guns shooting built in house.
That's insane.
It's like clink clink,
clink cookie.
So they have nine millimeter,
45.
And uh,
it sounds like a Pelican.
You can't even,
probably can't even possess them in
California,
which is really weird.
You know,
in Europe,
hunting without a silencer is rude.
Like they all have suppressors because
they don't want to hurt people's ears.
Like they don't like,
it doesn't make sense that you can hunt
with an archery equipment archery setup,
which is totally silent.
It's that bad as Talladega short of
having ever been in Talladega.
Never been telling me about Talladega.
So fun.
Talladega and Daytona.
If you guys are Nascar fans or if you're
not,
you need to go.
Just experience the infield.
You don't want to really like watching.
I like watching,
turning left and then right.
I like a lot of movement in my racing.
I like that formula.
One thing was around a lot.
Listen,
Kevin Harvick is a dear friend of mine,
number four all day.
And uh,
but they have this left turners on the
planet forever.
Nobody left her as we're going here.
Okay.
So I show up to Michigan,
Michigan,
Kevin's racing and I said,
you know what,
how,
how fucking good,
how good can you.
I mean,
how hard could it be?
So I said,
let's go to a gold cart race.
I'll fucking,
I'll run with you.
Right?
So he calls up the nearest go kart
track,
so it will be right there,
will show up.
I said,
wait,
where's the fastest car and fucking bad
ass?
Kevin says,
which ones is the slowest?
This motherfucker was running laps
around me in the fucking gold car and
I'm a go golkar going,
motherfucker.
Like,
I feel like you're not going to beat me
in a go kart
to say I'm a go kart going motherfuck.
Pull over and wait for me to catch up
and fucking catch me again.
It's all about how they.
You know when you're going,
when you're taking those corners and you
hear earlier,
that means you're losing speed.
He just,
I mean,
he just knows how to cut the line.
Getting unbelievable.
Well,
I would,
I would imagine even to be just a guy
who does nascar,
you would have to be one of the top
drivers in the world.
The difference is that I.
I appreciate the shit out of and women,
Danica,
she's hot too.
Crazy.
Razi of racing to ever run is not hot.
How dare you?
How dare you say it loudly and proudly.
Goodness.
You have higher standards of Neisser.
I think she's hot as fuck.
You don't think she's hot?
I don't wanna I don't wanna get into
this.
We don't want to go.
I love her too much.
When you,
when you watch formula one race,
like,
do you feel like that you have a biased
opinion when you're.
When you're accommodating because you
like her so much.
I have a biased towards you too.
Okay.
I do.
Next question to try to suppress this
question.
I tried to suppress it,
but part of being a commentator is like
uriah faber.
I love that dude.
I think you're right.
Favorite is a cool motherfucker.
I love talking to him right when he
fights.
I have to put myself in a place where I
don't think about that.
Tj,
when tj fights,
I have to put myself in a place.
When I'm think about.
I'll tell you what I hate.
I hate.
I love Connor.
Right.
I love that.
So my grandma always tells me a cheap
watches fight.
She used to put it on mute and there's
just a real fight.
She doesn't like me.
No,
no.
She loves you,
but she,
she,
she just likes to be no silence and it's
integrity.
You know?
She should,
you know that they should offer that and
he goes,
you,
Joe are to the fans can weigh the scale.
I know.
I know that it's important for me to.
I try to be as objective about,
but I also have to be honest,
if something's happening and some guys
that you see,
sometimes the judges don't agree with
the fans,
you will,
you,
you are heavy on the scale.
One side but big.
But I probably am better at it than the
judges.
Sure.
There's a real problem and that's an
arrogant thing to say that they're
watch.
You don't.
I don't think this is the Friday just
happened and I obviously I heard about
it sucked.
I heard it,
but it's totally not even remotely
surprised.
I haven't recorded.
I'm going to watch it,
you know,
Bam,
Bam.
Watch on fight pass and Bam,
Bam,
Bam.
Won The fight.
But we've seen that man,
we saw that happens all the time in
Ramsey Mitchum's last fight a lot with
the Henderson and myself first fight.
I feel like I won,
you know,
the third fight that we just had.
I don't fucking know,
man.
It could have got honestly tell you.
I thought he edged you.
So I just studied and it was a very
close fight and it wasn't a.
It wasn't a travesty.
Sure.
This travesty,
and I'm,
I'm not hiding anything.
Benson is one of the fucking best on the
planet and you're one of the best in the
planet.
It was a great fight.
I mean,
it wasn't.
There was,
I mean,
there was no doubt about it.
It was a super high level,
very entertaining fight and is coming
down to help me train for this fight.
That's awesome.
I love that dude.
He's got a great soul.
That's what he told me.
He's like,
hey man,
it's a good one.
They gave me the first one fucking go
get it.
That's what he said to me.
That's beautiful.
I'm glad he did that.
You know,
I,
I'm,
I'm biased towards a lot of guys.
I'm biased towards a Chad Mendez.
I love that dude.
I think he's a great guy.
I mean,
but when they're fighting.
Damn Dude,
I tried to let all that shit slide away.
I try to look at it as objectively as
possible,
so like in the like the Rhonda fight,
if batch beat the fuck out of Rhonda in
that fight,
I would be calling in as if it was one
of the most spectacular moments in mma.
Even though I'm a friend of Ron does and
ass that she looked.
That was damn Leonard Garcia.
Ronda fight.
She just put hit down on her mouthpiece
and fuck that girl up gaming and and did
it like flawlessly.
That fucking righthand she hit her with
and then tagged with the left that she's
going down.
She's not whinging shit.
She's throwing perfect clientele.
Come on.
Those were wingers fight,
but she's throwing clean technique.
Man is for her to winger,
but the way she landed the righthand
that as the girls going down,
she gets with the left,
there's no wind up with that.
Has the bank b bank and been fucking
striking for a few years.
Man is a recent thing because if it
will,
it will.
You know what man,
if you're one of those fucking people
like that girl's got that brain.
If you're one of those fucking people,
she could be the best surfer.
She could be.
She'd find her way.
You know,
if Danica Patrick was the number one
nascar driver,
she'd find a way to get in front of that
bitch.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm sure there's some people out there
that doesn't like that girl doesn't have
any loser in her.
She figures out a way to win when their
whole life.
Her mother is a bad motherfucker too.
Can you say that a mother is a bad
motherfucker.
That motherfucker is used as loosely as
is for Australian or English.
English.
She.
This is a term of endearment.
He's a good con.
I was with these wild,
awesome fisher.
He was just with me today and that's all
he said.
You fucking cunt.
Get chicken.
Chicken or am 3:50
year.
Fucking can't.
What's an rm?
Three Slash 15 ram $3,500.
Crazy,
right?
No.
It's a ram over those.
Over there.
I have a buddy who lives in Australia is
the biggest truck you can get as like a
Toyota Tacoma Tundra or something.
So and so we're at.
We're at a bar in Vegas and they just
tell these guys,
hey,
and I'm like,
if I would say,
hey,
you can't get thrown out of the Bar,
will worlds folks built that?
It's different than a bar made a bar
maid grandma Roger conked out.
She would just.
I mean,
I don't know if she could understand him
and I was like,
what is going on here?
Did you tell him?
That is different for us.
We have civilized folk.
We actually had to turn in the modern
world.
They're living in the fifties over
there.
It's like a John Wayne movie.
Unbelievable.
I love Australia,
man.
I fucking love going there too.
I'm looking forward to Melbourne.
I'd never been to mountain dogs fighting
there is he?
Is He fighting that card?
Fighting other ranch.
I like that dude.
Yes.
Column Logan Strong did call.
Nope.
Wasn't me a bodyguard to the crocodile
hunter.
He was not crazy and we talk about all
the time.
So you want to know even a crazier
fucking story.
So Kyle knows and Jonathan Webb just
signed to the UFC train.
The Jonathan who had been at the ranch
came and trained call for his fight the
entire way.
Kyle,
his opponent got pulled out.
They called Jonathan,
hadn't paid the fight,
so they train for each other the entire
fucking eight weeks.
Oh my God.
Thought each other.
Jesus Christ.
So they have to fight each other.
They did.
It did.
Where did they fight in Australia?
Who won that?
Kyle one.
Wow.
That's hard.
Right?
And Jonathan looked spectacular,
man.
It was unbelievable.
It was crazy.
It was for all of us,
like coaching and internal guys.
It was like,
what?
But Kyle Co tells Jonathan,
you idiot if you don't take the fight.
You know what I mean?
You're be a fight in the UFC.
All you want to do.
So you stupid bitch.
Take the fight.
And that's,
I mean,
that's.
If you had that happen to you other than
Benson.
I mean I fought.
I'm Melvin Gallard.
Yeah.
Oh that's right.
You train with Melbourne very many
years.
So there was some psychological warfare
and that fight too.
Sure.
Because you said that Melvin used to
quit and training like I'm going to make
them quit again.
Yeah,
absolutely.
We're not psychological a lot on your
friend to write on your friend.
They'll get dow,
but the son of his came out and whammer
dampered me,
didn't he?
Yeah,
he left hooks.
Hold up here.
Was that the hardest time you ever been
hit?
I think you said in one of those UFC
countdown things.
That was the hardest thing other than
Lynn or training.
Yeah.
I was wanting to rock on a rope,
so other than that,
but a rope that's hilarious for people
don't know where he talking about.
If you had a rock on the end of a rope,
just swung it.
That's the way limit throws rock and
roll a rock on her rope.
Wow.
I mean,
you know,
it was a great video.
We're a connor.
Love him or hate him is a teaching when
he's coaching this this season of the
ultimate fighter and they're doing these
real specific drills and he said a cool
thing that I think John Kavanagh says.
He said,
this is upgrading your software without
damaging your hardware.
There's two schools of thought.
Right?
Right.
There's that school of thought,
like fight smart,
train smart,
and then there's the school of thought
where you hard ride jet skis over the
top of cliffs the day before you fight.
Well,
we made.
Wait,
let's go fucking swim with sharks.
I mean,
that's,
that's your school thoughts,
sort of a different school of thought.
Very much so.
Yeah.
I,
uh,
how hard training sessions are you
having in camp?
Are you guys going full out?
Sure,
sure.
I mean some days,
some days,
not,
some days.
Not.
So I might,
I may wake up on Tuesday like I'm not
filling it.
I'll go fucking late board.
Just decided not train.
Yeah,
I mean I got all the guys on my coach
right there and they,
they been with me for so long that they
just say,
okay.
So you know,
a lot of people think that that actually
is a smart thing that that's active
recovery.
I'm tired,
I'll call it sold the day.
Do you.
But you like to still do things though?
Oh yeah man.
I mean,
we go rock climbing,
wakeboarding,
right?
But if you think about that,
like,
so you're still working,
you're still moving your body,
right?
You're not taking a day and just
sleeping,
man.
There's been,
I don't know how many days of my life
that have just done nothing but slept.
Look at today's Day.
I got off the plane,
went surfing,
trained.
Oh boy.
Now I'm here.
It was just always moving,
running and a gun in baby.
I love it man.
I love it.
I mean that's just,
that's my,
that's how I'm geared.
I've just had,
I had in my friends have to take breaks.
They tell me all the time,
my cowboy,
I got a week for you after that.
We got,
we got,
we got tagged team somebody else in
because we can't keep this fucking pace.
You're too much.
You go go,
go,
go.
Like there's days that I'll train weight
board all day and come back and train.
Wow.
And just uh,
eh.
But you're enjoying it.
So you're getting a rush the whole time.
So when I look at life right now is I'm
retired now because when I quit making
money and it's time to proper retire,
I'm not going to have any money.
So going to feed you and go scuba
diving,
not scuba diving.
My favorite thing,
I'm going 400 feet.
All you need is a good financial
advisor.
All you need is someone who you trust to
take care of your money and and handle
shit and make sure you always say what?
Say what?
The goddamn money just I stayed at her
trailer hitch.
That's what I'm saying.
But if you just stay being cowboy,
we just need to figure out a way to get
this out that you don't have to work
again a day in your life.
When you're writing,
you're not going to be broke.
You just needed the right guy to steer
you.
You're a fucking.
I got my grandma.
She,
she,
I tell her all the time.
Maybe she's the Gal.
She is perfect.
I can.
I asked her what she said.
Fucking ride it till the wheels burn
off.
Mother.
Motherfucking people know you're out
there.
That's all you need to do the
difference.
I mean,
what you've got what you are.
I'm not blowing.
I'm retired now.
Who are is like what everybody wants out
of their superheroes when 50.
This is lit as fuck.
And I can't wake board running
triathlons with fancy guy.
Like that's what everybody wants.
They want a guy who's just living like a
fucking wild man and going in there,
there's,
there's something appealing to that.
There's something that's called live,
a life worth living,
but there's some appeal to the Spartan
to write something appealing to.
The guy's willing to not have sex.
Shout out all distractions,
put a fucking poster on his wall,
write down goals.
Some Dan Gable type dude who's just
stoic and fucking never ending an
indomitable spirit.
And this guy just doesn't do anything
for his body.
Hey brother,
you want to go?
Fucking weight board wouldn't be the God
man.
I'm fucking in the zone.
And I'm like,
what's the,
the zone we are talking about when
you're behind.
No,
that's not today.
That's,
that's in your fight.
We're discussing fund today and they
don't.
And I said,
well,
alright,
I'm going to go have some fun.
It's a balance,
right?
It's trying to figure out what's the
best way to do it.
What's the best way to do it?
Because like Dan Gable I brought up.
Did you play football?
No,
never played football.
Steered away from that Shit.
Okay.
So you hear,
you hear the guys that are still 35,
40 years old talking about that game,
right?
They had.
Yup.
I think that's what I searched for every
day,
you know,
like fighting is fucking love it and get
six times a year if I'm lucky.
And this year I'm good at one time.
So,
uh,
I think that's why I do the things I do
because it gives me that feeling that
I'm searching for that scared.
What am I doing?
Oh my God.
Feeling where you'd like proven yourself
and you'd like it to be true.
And those are two things that a lot of
people shy away from.
I mean,
know competition.
If you can right now and said you're
better bowhunter me.
I bet we'll set the motherfucker
targeted.
Let's go,
let's do it.
And that's just,
I mean so.
Well that's also the only way you get
good at anything.
People shy away from that.
Just there's only one way you could
surround yourself with bad motherfuckers
are doing exactly what you do and you
force yourself to keep up.
And we inspire each other.
That is the problem in this sport
because I see that in the gym all the
time.
You see it,
the guys sparring day comes or grabbing
day comes.
You see all the guys finding the guy
they know they can be.
They don't go after the guy that kills
them.
Me,
I want you motherfucker.
But I want to.
You want the toughest challenge.
You're the baddest dude you want.
Let's go.
Fuck me,
I want the one that's going to stir you
up inside.
Fucking burn me where you submit me
three times in five minutes.
Not going to happen again because you
know what I mean?
That's how I think.
You fucking fuck me.
I'm calling my coach like I just got
fucked up.
Let's fix this problem.
Right?
So that's,
I mean that I want the guys that pushed
me.
I need those.
I need that in my.
Well,
when you get to the level that you're at
to,
you also realize that those guys that
push you or the reason why you put in
that extra effort that takes you to the
top of your ability and there's that.
There's this,
there's a few guys that we all know that
never quite reached the top of their
ability.
Like you hear about them in the gym,
they're fucking on fire.
They just have the,
you know,
they have,
they have days where they world beaters
and for whatever reason they don't ever
get it together in the moment of crisis
is Jim Heroes,
right?
Absolutely.
It's the sport is an believable man.
It's like you have to be able to go out
there and fight at your best every
single day and you have to execute under
insane pressure.
That's the most admirable quality about
it.
You know,
like sometimes when I look around like
that was one of the craziest things
about Rhonda fight was after she knocked
out bench go hand,
she just strutted around the cage and
looked up at.
Everybody just took it all in stride.
It shifts face,
planted that chick on a straight out of
compton.
Add.
Okay.
I mean she really did.
Which the movie was fucking
unbelievable.
I didn't see the movie.
You haven't seen the movie?
No,
I didn't see them.
Great.
I'm sure it's great.
It's great.
But the fact that she face plant that
are on that and then just walked around
the that moment,
like that moment.
Who the fuck understands that moment?
But her.
Who are you or anybody who experiences
it,
you know the,
the moment where you know,
think of like the Edson Barboza fight we
crack on with that jab and then take his
back like that moment when when your
taps and you stand up and the whole
crowd goes fucking ape shit because it
was chaos up until that moment,
right?
He came out,
guns blazing.
Then you caught him with that Jab.
He went down.
You've got his back and strangle them.
That moment man.
When you were in the,
in the fire.
In that moment,
Barbara has as he blinks,
but in that moment,
about 20 seconds before that moment,
I knew I got him.
How'd you know?
Because he hit me with fucking
everything he had in the kitchen sink.
And when he unloaded Babe Babe,
Babe,
babe being kicked me as hard as he could
and I just stood there and he looked at
his corner is like,
now what?
I was like.
Gotcha.
So,
uh,
so you saw a moment of thinking on a
moment of contemplation.
I got it.
I got you.
He's a talented motherfucker.
Talented.
Absolutely.
That's which kick that he was hitting
Paul felter with was the fastest which
could I've ever seen in my life.
I'd never seen anybody throw it like
that.
Hard and fast.
Like Jesus fucking Christ.
Well,
Mark Henry and ginger.
So it's showing a little bit more than
he could be black.
Like check Congo.
You would've been impressed by that
kick.
That kick was insane.
Right?
He's so fast,
man.
And his coach,
Mark Henry,
that's a guy who's like one of the most
underappreciated guys and this port and
after the fight they came in and said,
man,
we,
we studied Paul to a tee.
We tunes fight.
So serious dude.
He's a wizard.
That guy,
he's the unsung.
He's like a really quiet guy.
He doesn't want a lot of attention,
but I admire the fuck out of the way
that guy coaches Frankie Edgar,
the way that guy like conor and Frankie,
I love Frankie.
Ooh,
I'd love to.
Have you ever seen.
Have you ever seen the guy?
And he goes,
fuck you.
Fuck you.
Fuck your cool air.
That's.
I feel like what happened at the press
conference because Frankie was.
You're welcome.
That was it.
Yeah,
so I felt like the fuck you.
Fuck,
you're cool and fuck you.
That's what would happen because the
ability of level change that he puts his
face to love frank.
Frankie will set a goal.
Got to run a ultra,
ultra marathon with him.
You got to be willing to go to the
depths of your ability and there's a guy
that fought at 55 undersized and won the
fucking title.
Always crazy one.
The title undersized.
He was so much smaller than Bj.
So much smaller than a lot of the guys
he beat had those tough fights with
Henderson mean he's that fight with cub
Swanson.
I was like,
good Lord,
that fucking Pacey puts people.
He's like,
he's taken it to the next level.
When I talk about guys who put paces
like that,
wrestlers break you pace.
Nobody liked Frankie right now in the
sport.
He's,
he's the epitome of that style of
fighting.
Maybe Weidman could show it to in some
fights if he gets the right apartment.
A crazy fight.
Rockhold is a bad motherfucker.
That's a crazy fight.
Rockhold Rocco's.
Jujitsu is nasty man.
The Way He controlled the Ota.
Machida,
I was impressed as fuck.
I was like,
Jesus Christ,
his grounded pound is controlling the
ground.
He,
he beat Leo Machida at every facet of
the game and that was impressive as
fuck.
To me.
That was a high profile fight.
It was a big fight.
I that impressed the fuck out of me,
you know,
I think it's a great fight.
Weidman's a monster man.
What do you think?
Your laughing?
No,
no,
I,
uh,
rock holds a dear friend of mine,
so I love that dude.
I mean,
he's out of cubes.
Camp is the only.
Yeah,
no,
I know.
I like him.
I know about all that.
Great Dude.
Khabib,
you know,
there's always gonna be that thing going
on between y'all.
You guys at the very top,
you know,
stirring the pudding again,
like a guy like Khabib Kinda need that
motherfucker.
That guy.
He's,
he's like a tank,
a propane out there for you.
You know he's going to that gym.
Yeah,
that's the guy because he's so fucking
good.
I mean,
you look at the way he manhandled dos
Anjos.
I'm like,
Jesus Christ.
Habib Nuremberg.
Madoff is a grappling motherfucker.
His,
his wrestling as someone really
appreciates the guy's ability to impose
his game plan.
He impresses the fuck out of me.
Absolutely.
That guys like giant tank,
a propane for cowboy.
That's a crazy way to make a living man.
You've got all these tanks.
Have propane out there.
Anthony Pettis.
That's it.
He's another propane tank.
Oh yeah.
Anthony told me and he's a cowboy.
If you need me to come down and train
you for deciding.
Yes.
I hate that motherfucker.
Haley there.
Wow.
That's a pet is home.
I just hit you up on that.
Wow.
That would be a good thing man.
He can give you some insight.
I love that dude.
So do.
I mean I gained with pedes.
I got nothing back.
I really don't have anything bad to say
about any of the guys up at the top.
You know,
it just.
Well,
you know what man,
ultimately outside of you guys competing
against each other,
you admire what [inaudible] you uniquely
know what it takes to be in the position
that pedis or Hoffeld dos Anjos,
Nate Diaz or you know,
fill in the blank.
All those guys.
You uniquely know what it takes to be an
easy.
It's a very small fraternity of guys at
the elite level and your division 1:55
is just chaos.
Like that whole division.
He's like,
look at it.
It's just killer after killer after
killer.
Absolutely.
There's coming up fucking sharks.
That's a 1:55
is like someone throwing a goat in the
water in South Africa and once in a sea
of sharks get it.
Yeah.
I mean it's.
So,
it's cool to see that you guys,
you know,
reasonably are friendly with each other.
Absolutely.
Considering considering considering you
know anything about your boy Irish,
the Irish mbit coming up to 1:55,
conor mcgregor make negative.
What did you say about him?
About kicking the lucky charms out of
his house?
He came up the one of the develop
bending over and fucking knocked the
lucky charms out his ass.
Don't know how that works.
It's like blowing on a hot soup,
but you knew you wouldn't believe the
uproar of the Irish community I got from
that.
When I said be silent,
I'd be more shocked or respond.
Be like,
I can talk about a Leprechaun.
Right?
Is like you talking to me bad about
Santa Claus,
like I wouldn't like,
oh,
oh you,
you went there like come on.
You know what I mean?
Is their sacred guy.
It's like a Unicorn.
Yeah.
I don't know what it is,
but a Leprechaun is.
It's a weird one,
but it's totally as well.
It is.
Unless you take the right amount of
mushrooms,
you can meet leprechauns.
So I,
I mean,
to me that's where it came from.
Connor is the leprechauns sitting on a
big old tub of gold.
He is not a gold for sure if you think
I'm not going to come out of that pot of
gold.
Why not 35?
I got open arms,
baby.
It would be a fun fight.
I'd love it.
I think he really struggles to make 1:45
and I think with this new law where you
can't use the ivy,
you know when he fought Chad Mendez man
at the way in,
he looked extremely drawn.
His cheeks were sucked in.
His body looked really small.
Like you're Ryan.
Him had some weird little altercation in
the hallway and it wasn't staged,
but you're right is not like he didn't
want to fight in the street with them
right before he's going on Chad who wish
a motherfucker would.
I know you do,
but.
But what you had said was that he's.
He said duty feels really small.
Like he loses a lot of weight.
He loses like close to 30 pounds or 25
pounds.
He gets up to like one,
seven d and the normal in the 70 range.
So 1:55
was worried.
Belongs really,
you know,
that's the probably the healthy weight
class for them and how you feel about
all doing him.
It's wild fight.
It's a wild wildfire,
you know,
I'll tell you,
I tell you what,
man,
I'm Aldo has been jumping,
jumping,
jumping in.
They were jumping from guns.
Did Religion de pree vehicle did.
We're just talking.
That's how it goes.
We're jumping.
This isn't like a radio show.
Kangaroo fucking Australia and con.
Yeah.
Fucking the whole thing,
man.
Budweiser where we'd,
um,
I think if you can come down.
Did you lock the fucking door counts out
there?
Yeah,
I'm going to get it because you have to
right now.
Is it really Jamie?
I'll go again.
I said I'm locked out.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
Tell them we're coming.
Yeah,
don't worry.
I love this dude.
I'll give him a key shit that he's done
a,
he's done podcasts here without me.
It's one of the few guys,
him and branded shop.
They had a fight companion podcast.
But um,
we'll,
we're just saying what the fuck were we
just talking and talking about
leprechauns.
Oh No,
the Aldo fight.
Oh look sexy.
Brian Cowen,
it's just unexpectedly showed up.
We have a big show tonight.
I will.
We were good man.
We'll leave here like,
you know,
half an hour.
So fantastic show.
Can't start without us.
Look at this.
Tomorrow we're doing a.
The Ventura.
What is it?
The Hong Kong.
We're going to be at the Hong Kong and
we've got two shows at 8:00
and 10:00.
I think we're headlining the festival or
something.
There's a Chinese restaurant festival.
Venture.
A comedy festival.
You didn't even know you booked this.
I let him book things.
Not Money now.
They pay US money.
What's going on?
But just thinking about Aldo versus
mcgregor.
We're talking about,
uh,
he asked me what I thought about that
fight.
Yeah.
I,
uh,
I'm curious.
I'm curious about the sexy cow in the
hammer.
Sexy Cowen.
The Hammer.
What do you mean you made the account?
What's the structure?
You're going to hammer nothing of drunk.
It's a little bit.
It's code.
It's just a little boost.
Wait,
I want to know what do you think?
I think I think,
uh,
is in his head.
He might be,
but he might not be all that might be
able to fight like a fucking assassin,
even under all the shit talking.
No one's ever talked to before,
so we don't know.
We don't know how it's going to fight,
but we know that guy hasn't lost in 10
years if he,
if the guy's been beaten,
some of the best guys in the world and
if you look at him when he's on point,
you look at it like his fight with Uriah
for instance.
Some fucking terrifying leg kicks.
Fast Shit.
Yeah.
Fastest Shit.
And his Jujitsu world class,
his Jujitsu is very high level.
You know,
he'd be Brina in regular Jujitsu,
irregular Jujitsu competition.
He's a beast.
He's a.
he's a very good fighter.
That all aspects one of the best ever.
I feel like he's in his head.
I know that trash talk wouldn't work on,
but we were talking about that earlier.
You're coming in too late for this
conversation you're talking about.
He went over to talking about the nate
Diaz fight were jumpers here.
We would travel,
travel,
travel.
I like it to go and it's a great fight
and.
But you gotta also,
I gotta be honest.
Like I look at Aldo and even though all
those been dominant for so long,
it's one of the best fighters.
He's,
he's,
he's had a lot of tough fights.
Those eventually will catch up to you.
It's like the Chad Mendez fight.
The last fight was a really good fight.
It was like a back and forth fight and
Mendez hit him with some fucking bombs.
It was a great back and forth fight and
he tagged Mendez with a big shot at
the end of the first round.
I think the Buzzer rang and then he hit
him like a.
It was a little late,
wasn't agregious,
was a little late and at fuck Mendez up
and Mendez still came back and cracked
them.
It was a back and forth war.
It was a very close fight.
Has although fought anyone who hits as
hard as Mcgregor Co.
Well Chad mendez hits pretty fucking
hard.
Um,
but I think connor may have some special
poWer.
Not like a magic power,
but I think he's one of those guys that
just really as super heavy hand.
It's so aCcurate is very.
he's just very smart man.
The way he fights is very,
very intelligent.
You know,
I was joking around with donald about
his training Methods that he calls it.
Him and john.
Kevin.
I was coast.
They,
they described it as upgrading your
software without damaging your hardware.
So they're doing all these like really
technical drills on hitting specific
points,
but they're not like crushing each other
to just drilling it into the mind and
getting.
And you know,
and donald has more of a wild style
who's out there.
I feel like donald's changed.
I feel like you stand in people's grill
more now.
You just stand right there.
Like you can give a shit.
My two of my favorite comedians in one
fucking room,
I'm like,
people will kill for this situation
right now.
Donald's.
Ronnie was in the crowd when I tape my
comedy central special in denver.
Well,
the first time I met donald,
he came.
I met him the night before.
Then he came and I just saw his hat
going back and forth as he was laughing.
I just saw your hat.
It was the greatest impact after I left
joe.
Joe,
you know what I'm gonna do for you?
What are you gonna do with fucking vct
and you're fucking bathroom in there.
Vct is that shitty cheap tile you got in
there.
The tile on the floor.
On the floor and in the shitty paint
brush,
but this is this like a lease.
I'm going to come in here and fuck.
I'm not going to pull a permit and I'm a
fucking.
Don't just kind of lay a towel.
I might bite the tile to cut it.
That's great.
I'm getting a new spot.
New spot.
It's a spot.
Yeah.
I'm bringing.
I'm never satisfied.
I have real problems.
Never happy with it.
No,
I think that's the same way.
I don't know if I don't know what it.
Is it worse than me.
I'm the worst,
like if I'm always moving,
almost happy with everything.
Unhappy with everything I do.
Yeah.
I'm always that way.
The other bumping with the wolf.
No,
that's a great a werewolf.
Fucking a gorilla.
Exactly.
I got it.
I had a dream.
I wish I knew the dirty will make that.
That's.
I hope you how the moon.
Every time of year in that position
woman,
if you could grab the back of her
shoulders like that.
Either have a whopper of a dick or.
That's a big one.
I had an affair with a girl who was on
the canadian national water polo team.
Oh jesus.
She had a back on her and she had a neck
and she.
But she had a really nice body and she
was really pretty.
And her hands.
Go ahead man.
You're not even drinking the damn her
hands.
But what threw me off with just the
thickness of her fingers as we would
hold hands.
I was like,
whoa.
I feel like I feel like a young lady.
Do you know gabby garcia is so is your
dick look shamelessly tiny in her hands.
Her take was way bigger than mine.
I got a hug on me.
Um,
there was a,
there's a woman named gabby garcia is
still is,
but she used to be overweight and she's
like world jujitsu champion and she used
to try this giant crazy face.
Well she lost all her body fat and then
I guess she might've had some facial
surgery,
but all of a sudden she's a giant hot
chick.
It's real weird.
She's got full six pack,
like pull up gabby guard for.
And I've seen her before.
Listen,
she was,
I don't know what she did,
but whatever she did that took a lot of
fucking work because she like,
became like she went from being a big
giant fat woman who's a beast that hugh
jitsu.
But she was very overweight to be super
slim.
Like she always has these exposed
midriff shirts and she's rocking this
fucking ridiculous six pack.
She's,
she's just 64.
Slaac yeah,
Johnny Cash.
My dog's named johnny can jump in.
We're jumping in.
You spend most your time.
Colorado,
New Mexico,
bUt I go see.
I'm going to see grandma tomorrow.
She's listening in live right now.
Tell her hello?
Hey grandma.
Grandma.
How she gave me,
so I grabbed it.
Comes back today,
so this is what she looks like.
That's what she used to look lIke.
that's impressive as hell as a different
person.
Yeah,
totally.
Looks like a different person.
The neck and the other one.
I don't know if she had facial surgery,
but it seems like she does.
She is.
She is just a true specimen.
Look at that.
That's crazy.
It's weird.
You would.
She's giant too.
I mean she's like six foot four,
like there's a picture of her with fader
and it's like,
holy fuck.
She's so much bigger than.
I'm looking at her now.
See if you find a picture of a gabby
garcia and fate or it's like a real
recent portion.
vandelay silva.
Yeah.
That was when they were on the ultimate
fighter Brazil,
but here's the thing.
It looks like she want him in a corner.
I was only a couple of years ago,
dude.
It wasn't.
That wasn't that long ago.
It was really simple or really similar
or recent.
How many beers have you had?
About a few.
Far right far right.
look at that.
That's her.
Look at her body.
Look at donald.
Yeah,
that's a big growth.
That her boyfriend.
That's fader.
That's fate or dude there,
that federal boyfriend here.
He's looking good flies back.
He's making a comeback.
He's gonna fight in Japan.
The problem is there's no fucking
opponents for them.
I mean there's.
I don't know how the hell else is like
surrogate cart.
I'll fight them.
Surrogate kerataN on time with the kid
and in fact hitting dodgeville and he
picked me.
How much time would you need to fight
fader morrow?
He's amazing.
One hundred percent.
You just walked in right now through the
fucking eight.
Getting fucked by a werewolf on the
ground.
I'll get fuck bait or not a doubt in my
mind.
He.
You just fight him.
I'm scared of russians.
I'll say it right now because of isis
for everything.
I see this new thing with putin.
Putin took $15,
billion dollars from this guy.
Took this guy,
stole this guy's company,
and then the guys exiled in the south of
France and now he's.
He's suing the russian government.
He says,
good luck.
Good luck with this guy.
Took $15,000,000,000.
He was like,
putIn's banker,
putin's right hand man for years and now
this guy is like penniless,
penniless,
and the guy say a billion seconds is 33
years.
The guy says that putin is the most
wealthy man in the world.
He said he has more control over more
money than anyone on the planet.
Like you might not be on paper,
but they're.
They're saying that he might be worth
like 200 billion because Russia is one
crop economy.
It's all oil.
Guess who controls it?
You don't do anything without that.
He's a sako.
How is he doing?
Russians?
Politics has always been that way.
It's always been run by azhar.
It's always been run really by a group
of,
you know,
used to be the pull up bureau,
but for the most part he's just doing
what the old russian model was,
which was get the biggest guns and
killing what I mean,
isn't it a crazy when you see a guy
who's running like essentially a
complete undercover gangster
organisation?
Monarchy.
Yeah.
Dominating entire country.
He,
he apparently,
when they were trying to attract
investment in the nineties,
the problem was american companies,
german companies or french companies
coming in and these gangsters,
these russian guys would come in and go,
hey,
you got to pay us money.
And couple of them said no,
and they just shot him right there in
the office.
So putting inside of this was gonna be a
disaster for any kind of foreign
investment.
So putin said,
alright,
well I know how to deal with this.
We know exactly where they are and when
they were having big guys hanging out
together in their own club houses or
whatever,
he had these spetsnaz guys show up in
their,
in their vans.
They just show up in the middle of the
day,
open up and just killed a shitload of
them,
like 100,
201 day they had a moment of silence.
Apparently before he had his,
uh,
before he had his,
his,
uh,
whatever it was,
you know,
his meeting,
they had a moment of silence for up to
200 citizens that were killed and they
won their business.
And that was the message to anybody who
saId you want to shake that foreign
company.
See what the fuck happens.
They still didn't invest though.
But he's.
He doesn't.
Dogs running a fight on tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
Tonight.
He's a black belt in judo.
However,
I'm hear everything in the hood.
Everyone's from a street.
I hate that expression.
Donald,
if you had to fight straight and who's
not from the street?
I was born in the metal.
Are you?
I wasn't.
I'm not from the street.
Alex.
I'm looking for the silver spoon in my
mouth and just no role.
I'm in.
I'm in the forest.
Who do you want to punch in the face
more than anybody on the planet.
Are you interviewing them around?
My man.
I'm taking.
I'm taking over the guy from wholefoods.
Shitty fucking question questions.
The guy from whole foods.
It was a previous story because it got
punched him foods.
Parking lot.
Fucking late.
He told me that story.
WHat did you.
What made you decide to come over here?
He was texting me.
Oh,
why don't you tell him if you were
texting him,
like be more appealing to have three.
Well,
why don't you use our people in the
world?
He's one of my favorite people.
Do.
He just had a break.
He's making secret text while we're in
the middle of a pop lovers.
He's called.
Come on over this garden.
Said the door's locked in.
I'm locked out.
you want to key you gonna have a kid.
That's right.
Yeah.
Okay.
Just to hang out.
Sure.
Where we'll market.
The people know about the bad ass
werewolf.
Vfl side.
Yeah.
There's pictures of it.
It used to be before I got the pool
table used to be.
The werewolf was the first thing you saw
when you opened the door and I was like,
I need to put a goat cam.
That was the first thing I saw when I
came in.
I was like,
werewolf pool pools day.
Do you play pool?
You musT play.
I do have a pool table in the bar at the
ranch.
Have a bar that I built but you.
I have every alcohol you could ever
believe of,
but because I don't want someone to come
borrow.
yeah.
Kegs,
boxes,
cases.
I don't want to come over and take over
for me this and I don't have it damn
gangster.
This is,
this gets you psychologically because I
know your background,
like how you grew up and you're like,
you're creating like this environment at
that ranch that's not just like a
training environment,
but a place where like,
you're,
you're trying to give these guys
hospitality and bring them into like a
family situation.
Like I'm never in ranch that we're
neverland.
Fuck,
we're a bunch of boys coming to hang out
as much.
Not as much.
Jared is what they're calling it today.
Not as much boy play.
Yeah.
How about turn?
So yeah,
but you know what I'm saying.
It's like because You know your,
your grandparents raIsed you and you
were wild kid and you know,
he didn't feel like you've had like that
thing we were talking earlier about
trainers that wouldn't put their name on
it.
Now you're doing the total opposite of
that.
The total opposite.
Absolutely.
I appreciate that man.
The total opposite and yeah,
if guys calling me like have they can
afford it,
said don't worry about it.
I got you.
Go ahead.
So what do you do that with the ranch
ranch?
Grandpa bought some property.
Happiest moment is life.
Tears almost came to his side during the
podcast builds a place,
doesn't get permits.
Fucks up because he has the bunk bed set
up.
Oh shit.
Now what do we do now?
Sleeping in a barn.
A key propane.
If you keep the propane on it costs 1500
bucks a night.
This is a lot of work.
You're learning all this stuff.
He doesn't have any power out there,
man.
He's getting tanks of flammable liquid.
Any shooting guns everywhere.
The whole thing is ridiculous.
He shows me all these guns.
He's got gun.
Shoot a propane tank with a gun.
It will not blow up.
Is that true?
Absolutely true.
In the movies.
It will not blow up though.
I had a navy seal hammer.
When you throw a grenade it doesn't.
There's no fire.
It just.
You just hear pop and there's no.
Yeah,
just smoke.
Which I was amazed at.
Well,
that's annoying.
What about to chuck norris movies?
Where there was an explosion?
Is chuck norris still the coolest dude
alive or.
No?
I met him and I was more happy than I've
been when I met anybody.
Ever inexpensive manner.
Great job.
First time I was very happy.
Chris.
He can be public anD a bar instead of in
a fucking hotel room with a 14 year old
chuck norris.
Um,
I met him into world combat league
member.
Used to have that kickboxing
organization,
that dome audit,
a bowl bowl.
I met him there and just the fact that
chuck norris knew who I was and gave me
a big hug.
I was like god damn.
And put his boot up to your face.
Black bottom of,
let's say he had crushed things.
Kickboxing fans,
the Texas ranger mother fucking remember
super foot.
Wallace used to have jeans that he
advertised in like the back of comic
books.
Yeah,
we'll chuck norris did to chuck.
Not chuck norris,
I think more than she requested posters
of bad ass shit that you have to think
about if your life is that cool.
Chuck norris,
he's a super nice guy.
Too many.
It was a uh,
yeah,
there was a,
there was a thing,
a banquet for a karate guy who was a
famous karate instructor and he was one
of the truck norris's friends.
So I sat in on the.
They wanted me to sit and like give,
give a speech.
like everybody gave speeches,
like all these old school black belt
guys gave speeches at chuck norris gave
a speech.
I just sat next to cHuck norris and talk
for like an hour and a half.
We just talked about the old days of the
karate tournament and the old days of
kickboxing.
And you know what it was like to hang
out with Bruce Lee.
It was one of the best moments of my
life.
You didn't hit him with any chuck norris
lines like chuck norris doesn't do
pushups.
He pushes the earth away from him.
How many of them?
You know what?
Why not even like an opening line?
I Just knew.
First of all,
how many times do you ever get a chance
to sit and actually right next to chuck
norris in a public setting?
This moment right here,
that's how I feel at this moment right
now.
We feel the same way.
I'm sitting next to him.
It was just me and him talKing,
you know,
just me and chuck norris right next to
each other.
So our.
It was like a little kid I saw missing
in action in the fucking movie theater,
lone wolf,
mcquade.
I was there for all those movies did.
I panicked.
I panicked two times with celebrities
that I felt were really big.
I met opera chino and I was talking to
him and I was like,
just be cool,
be cool,
brian,
be cool.
Don'T spazzed out sometimes.
And are you looking at yourself from a
third person?
Kind of kind of more staring at him.
And I was just like,
he had a bandana on and he looked so
cool and he was 70.
He looks amazing.
He's from New York.
That's a good fucking.
I've never done it before.
That's very good for.
Is that similar?
Like fucking I went like this and I got.
I can't kill myself.
I,
I heard the words coming out of my mouth
and I was like,
brian,
stop,
stop.
You're saying,
hey,
I go,
you know,
it's funny.
I get.
I'll say it again,
don't say it,
and I sent it.
I go,
I just watched scarface was on tv as
left he and he goes,
michael.
I was like,
no.
My face was saying it and then I go.
I looked at him and he went like this.
He goes,
oh boy,
that's what you did.
And he hugged me,
know he shook my hand and he put his
shoulder against my chest.
I was like,
oh,
that's the coolest way to ever do
anything.
And I was like,
see you later.
Then.
Then I need springsteen backstage.
I talked to him for awhile.
I talked to his wife.
I'm a huge bruce springsteen fan.
Six months later with my dad in a
bookstore in Idaho in sun valley,
Idaho.
And I hear his wife say,
hi,
how are you?
I'm and I go,
oh,
patty,
hi.
And she goes,
what are you doing?
And I go,
how's bruce thinking?
I known them when I talked to him for
like an hour.
She goes,
ask him yourself.
He's right here,
and I turned.
He's looking at a book I read called
fiasco.
I remember he had his glasses on and I
go,
how you doing?
and he goes,
I met you.
We talked backstage and all of a sudden
I realized my eyes.
I folded my arms,
but for whatever reason my fucking arms
were really high and my elbows were
pointed right at him and in my mind I
was like,
brian,
please let go of your arms.
Don't do this.
What are you doing?
And I go,
and this is what I did.
I go,
did you ski?
And he goes,
usually we do,
but this year we just let the kids do it
and we're just sitting,
you know.
And I went and I meant to say I fucking
meant to say I've been skiing all day.
My feet are killing me and I'm not going
to ski anymore.
That's what I meant.
Say,
I've been skiing all day.
My boots are shitty.
I don't want to ski anymore.
And instead I went with my fucking arms
like this,
I go,
my feet are killing me.
And he just looked at me and there was a
pause.
I go,
I'll see you guys later,
man.
And I kind of like fucking.
And I've never lived that down.
I juSt felt exactly.
But I'm sure they deal with that shit
all the time.
Just holding myself like that.
Did you just have that same moment right
now?
Like during this podcast?
I feel embarrassed right now.
What you're doing.
I feel embarrassed guys.
Get people wanting to take pictures that
are trembling out of fucking control.
Yeah,
sometimes it happens.
I've had a lot of nervous moments in my
life.
I appreciate nerves to deal,
you know,
I can't help nerves.
The guy with the camera and he's like
capable of fuck people.
Fuck we go,
come on bitch.
What are you going to get?
An iphone son?
Yeah.
I fuck with them.
But I don't you deal with that.
So the greatest domestic disputes that
you ever witnessed in your life is on a
boat ramp.
I don't know if you guys have ever been
on the boat ramp,
but either the wife is driving the boat
and a husband and the pickup and he's
trying to fucking guide.
Ron left.
look.
No,
she trying to snake the trailer down and
he sitting in the boat screaming at her
snake and the trailer down with 30 other
boats are trying to dock.
It's damn.
Oh,
that's interesting though.
Next time I'm there,
I'm gonna.
Go because it is.
You would.
I never thought of that.
Oh,
it's unbelievable.
I just thought the boats were always in
the water.
Somehow been getting.
It's 4:30.
They'd been drinking all day trying to
get the fuck out.
Messaging dispute happens in it is.
It's classic.
They say there and when and realtors,
realtors see a lot of dark shit between
couples as they're looking for houses,
deciding what they want or they can't
afford a fucking house,
but she wants the house.
She always wants it.
Dude.
I had a conversation with my buddy about
this recently who was talking about his
girlfriend hates.
Where's the fucking stripper voice?
She wants a fucking towel up it up.
What does that sound is stripped from
interacting?
This is a.
I know a dude who's fucked and I feel
bad.
He's just bringing it toward dude is
this.
The girl wants him to live over his
means,
you know,
and it gets weird.
You know what she's like,
we need a better house.
I need to.
We need to get a better house and he
can't really afford a better house.
So he's scrambling.
Well,
this a bad place to be.
A woman I know is a realtor.
Said she was.
They were looking at this house that was
like $6 a night in New York city.
What happened for $6,000,000?
just about 1300 square feet.
Something crazy.
Yeah.
No yard.
And her friend had the ranch for 10
million from drawing.
Yeah.
I mean it's crazy.
You can buy like nothing for you know
me.
Well he shoots guns in his yard,
but off the fucking toilet.
That too.
We got to fucking new silencers.
I don't really get them sense rests on
his toilet.
Just looking out the window in case a
straight antelope games,
big games.
I'm a birdman.
Yeah.
Birdman,
birdman,
just any bird,
they insult you with their freedom.
Just poor.
I'm poor.
So she goes.
She was showing them the house and she
said,
I have another place.
It's just a little too,
you know,
it's a little bit out of your price
range and it was $8,000,000
and this girl's friend had a $10,000,000
house and she loved her husband and
went,
how could you fucking do this to us as
in you don't have enough money.
Got in And hale.
And he went.
Instead of going cla later he went,
sorry about that man.
That's how people live sometimes.
Well,
that's people that if they don't have
any other interests other than
materialistic things than you,
that's what you chase.
Yes.
It is a real problem with that in this
fucking city is a real problem with
people that are only chasing that and
they're not looking at the big picture
life.
They're defining themselves by how much
one of their houses cost,
how much you know,
what neighborhood they're in,
what kinD of car they're driving.
all that stuff is them and there's no
other stuff is no.
The looks in a comedy.
There's no society looks at that.
If you show up and you're living in your
school,
kids go to this school and you live in
this area and you drive the range rover,
right?
That's your status.
I think that that term society,
I think that's changing pretty well
because of the internet people like
there's going to be.
There's a bunch of people that don't
think like that and now they can all
agree.
Whereas before what was put out in front
of you was what was on commercials.
What was you saw the hero have in the
movie?
Burt reynolds as a trans.
Am I fucking need a trans am like all
that stuff was the only way we
associated with ideas about items,
but now because the internet,
you'll talk to people that go,
you know what man?
I don't.
I live in a fucking trailer that drive
around in my truck and I just go to
different places and I climb mountains.
that's like that.
Alex.
He lives in a van.
Yeah,
but that's cool too.
And he'll find fans.
The people that admire him because of
that.
I know.
I think that like.
Yeah,
and I think that some people who chase
money,
it has a lot of meaning.
Some people were humiliated by being
poor when they were kids.
Money.
It makes them feel powerful,
safe,
whatever.
But like I was thinking about,
I was trying to isolate of the two times
I'm the most happy,
like the two things that mattereD to me
the most with my friends and getting
better at something.
I thought it was coming with a finger
and you're,
it's coming with a finger up my ass.
Obviously when you check and you see an
extra comma in your bank account,
you're not fucking just tickled pink.
I not really,
but I'm weird that way and he knows that
I'm just so weird.
He drives a fucking shitty car.
Drives this goofy fucking volkswagen
money.
You could have something that you,
you drive,
it's a pleasure,
like you enjoy it and it changes your
transportation to a ride at disneyland.
RIde every.
I like getting better at something and
being a silly goose with my friends and
a finger in my ass.
And if let's say we got to end this man,
we gotta we gotta show on that note.
And on that note,
donald motherfucking cowboy serone.
Thank you sir.
We did this at the same time.
you're in town,
man.
Look at the trifecta.
I'm sitting here and we can take it
wherever we could.
We could probably have about 100 days
easily.
Easily.
We'll,
we'll see how the everyone racks and
fucking love it if they get a couple
hundred youtube comments.
I'm fucking get plenty of comments.
Look,
the most people are gonna.
Love it.
You got to separate.
What does the bible say?
You got to separate the wheat from the
chaff,
the wheat from the chaff.
Yes.
If you don't have a fucking sword,
go and get one sale your cloak and get a
better one to zero with the bible says,
god damn it.
They're selling swords in the bible.
Sell your cloak and gate.
I don't remember that passage so close.
How pious donald is always making the
cross.
I don't know if I'll ever own a cloak.
I might go to the grave with no clothes
on.
A cloak,
man didn't right now I need some dracula
club.
I want to own a lot of land and walk
around in mY cloak.
Yeah,
and I want to and I want to just order
my servants around me.
Coconut,
two straws and some shaved ice pack
llamas.
Oh,
I want to shoot animals in the woods.
I can bring the pack lambos and they'll
pack it out.
That's good.
I want hamsters to feel in my hands.
Please.
I want a few Guinea pigs around the
house just in case I need to eat them
like the people do.
They keep in the kitchen.
They're all scrambled around the kitchen
and grab what I need them.
I want them for petting and pressing
against my.
Janet apparentLy don't miss each other.
They never like where's waldo.
They don't give a fuck about waldo or
the peanuts out.
Yes,
they're good.
They say cancer like that.
Cats could give a fuck about their
owners.
Well,
when their owners die,
cats,
ether faces.
Is that true?
You know that?
Yeah.
Big john Mccarthy was telling me that.
He said,
the worst thing you want to find is a
guy.
Guy's been dead for a couple of days and
he's had cats.
Yeah.
The cats seat your face when you stopped
giving him cat food,
they just started eating you.
Whoa.
The your face your face for a long time
too,
until you get really rotten and you get
really rotten.
You're not there to feed them when
they're hungry.
They don't.
Dog.
Your dog will fucking starve to death.
Most dogs maybe might be a cunt to your
dog.
Your dog might eat youtube,
but most dogs will like sit there and
they'll say,
yeah,
they want to wake up.
I have a fucking toward is that,
but he's gonna live to be 100,
200 years old.
Tourists are man eaters.
Yeah.
If you find the interface and facile
first,
you might wake up and you have no
lasting.
They can cannot get their head.
So far,
just narcolepsy.
Don't eat my ass hole.
I'm fine.
You fucking shitty turtle.
They peak your asshole.
Can't they go a long time without food
to a.
I don't know.
I know.
I'm so.
If I call it to come to the show
tonight.
Fuck yeah,
dude.
Come to the show.
You can come for sure.
Absolutely.
Come.
Can I plug my date this weekend?
I'm going to be at the san jose improv
friday,
saturday,
sunday.
My favorite places in the world.
You know who lives near there?
Luke rockhold.
Donald cerrone,
his favorite person,
not puppies.
And I plug my event.
Hell yes.
Orlando,
Florida.
December 19th.
And fucking new and new champion of the
motherfucking world.
He made me,
but I'll be there.
I'll be there.
I'll be there for my boyfriend.
Going to be their best.
Do you want to do the gig with me the
night before?
December 19th?
Yeah.
What the night before is.
I'm doing again.
Take advantage of Florida now.
And he does come and be the night
before.
Yeah.
It wasn't something.
I'm booking some theater in there on
friday night so we'll do it over there.
Earlier.
What do you get?
Nervous thinking about that date?
Are you ready?
He's been ready.
I wasn't ready.
Bitch.
How dare you?
He's full of skull and budweiser's.
Hurricane smashed him coming.
Donald said,
hey,
right now I wish.
I wish I had a fucking billion dollars
and a huge belt buckle.
So we gotta we gotta end this at 7:00.
We've got a show on fucking coming 19
motherfucker.
and knew you heard them loud.
I'll be.
I'll be rubbing rogan.
I'm recording my underwears bitch.
Motherfucker.
Get him kicking.
We're out folks.
Thank you for tuning in and much love.
See you soon.
Bye bye.
Three hours.