The joe rogan experience
podcast is brought to you by
[inaudible] dot com if you
go to o,
n n I t.com and uh,
it's a mute button. Oh, it's
fucked that up. I'm not a Newbie.
That's the sad part about it. You would
think, see, this is my real laptop,
Ladies and gentlemen.
I don't have like a dedicated work
machine or anything like that.
Did hop into this if an alien
love man. Uh, I love alien ware.
I know I support them.
They make some awesome podcasts.
If you like playing video games, they
do make awesome podcast. Do I say that
may awesome computers
to do your podcast on?
It's fucking shows over
already before 40 even begins.
What is it that your brain sends
out the wrong word sometimes?
Like how did I not know that that was
the wrong word? TDT, h c Heck Nah.
It's not that. Yes, just being stupid.
I think. I don't know. I think it's THC.
I think my brain's not that good.
It's pretty good. We should not,
we should do a Doug Benson not
smoke weed for three months.
And I don't think I'm pair
around you. No, no. Both of us.
I don't think I can be around
you. If I was sober, we
should try it. It'd be weird.
We should do an experience. We should at
least 30 days. Okay, sure. I'm done. Um,
anyway,
on it.com
blah, blah, blah. Go get
some vitamins, bitch. We uh,
we also sell a kettle bells and battle
ropes and all kinds of good stuff.
Beef Jerky, Buffalo Jerky. It's
actually buffalo. I like I said,
it's fucking delicious. It's all the,
everything from onnit.com is essentially,
someone said you should call it a
performance website. Uh, I don't,
I think that sounds g h.
E y you know,
it's the way of saying gay without
being offensive to homosexuals.
Did,
have you ever played pool on on it?
I played pool on Alpha brain. Silly
Bitch. That's intense stuff, right?
She's so silly. This is just silly person.
Brian. Really, they need to understand.
You're like a small child.
I was crying like a child last night.
At the comedy store.
Why would you say I got really drunk
and all these people were like, Hey,
can I buy you a shot? I was like, Oh,
I'm sure. And then I was like, wait,
now I'm wasted. And I gave
away my cat last, you know,
yesterday and it started getting
emotional about my really,
I hate when I get drunk and stoned
and I just tear up like a little bit.
Maybe you need some new mood.
I do need a new mission.
I used to do I need to start
over by some new mood? No,
I'm going to have to buy it.
You know I need to stop growing.
I need some more design. What you
need more frothy loads. Do you think?
Do you have low testosterone?
You probably, I probably totally.
Probably not that good.
It's probably a low but you seem happy.
Maybe if it was, if you got like
all test it up man, you know,
snapping in the slim Jims Shit.
Yeah.
You might be like too intense if
you were like all write it up.
Wifebeater not about a beater
but certainly like a shaker.
He would grab people and shake
them, slap my room. It's commercial.
It's the worst we've ever done.
For sure.
If I was even thinking
about buying some products,
I would say, this is how the
fuck did you bring me this? I'm,
this is what you're calling a commercial.
Uh, w what Alpha brain is folks is, uh,
you know,
what the fuck it is.
You heard this podcast before
while we playing games,
they're vitamins and vitamins and
enhanced cognitive function. Um,
the idea is that there's certain
nutrients that they've isolated that are
particularly helpful for
brain function and uh,
it has a very clear effect for me. Uh,
for some people it doesn't, I don't,
I don't understand how people's brains
work. But, um, I think everyone, you know,
has different sensitivities to various
herbal compounds and different vitamins
and nutrients and you know,
and everybody has different sensitivities
to how your body is set up to now.
Some people's bodies are there,
they're very sensitive and they're,
they're very healthy and they're aware
of like different things having changes
on them. And then other people
just a little numb. They're
not, not quite tuned in.
Um, uh, I don't know what works
on you. Everybody's different,
but if it doesn't work on you,
it's a hundred percent
money back guarantee for the
first 30 pills. Just try it.
No one's trying to sell you
anything that doesn't work.
There's science behind it.
If you go to the Onnit science page,
a lot of the stuff that's in it's at the
various ingredients have been shown in
double blind placebo tests.
I think.
I'm not really even sure if I understand
what that means, but here we go.
What I'm saying is yes. Yeah. What I'm
saying is it's this, there's science.
There's a reason to believe it works to
that. It all makes sense. It's all the,
all the various ones, whether it's
Alpha brain or knew mood, knew mood,
which is a literally a mood
boosting supplement. It's,
it's five HTP and l tryptofan and w
the way it works is five HTP becomes
serotonin in El Tryptofan
becomes five HTP.
So the idea is that it gives you like
sort of a slow release boost and the
nutrients that your brain needs to produce
serotonin. It's all fascinating stuff.
Plus we got kettle bells and battle
ropes and all kinds of other manly shit.
So go get on it. Use a code name, Rogan,
and you will save 10% off any and all
supplements. All right, you freak.
You need to start selling cats.
Her. The ACAT buddy gave it.
We should have like an exchange program.
You don't have to,
you just give them away.
Give them a way to like people like Joey.
Joey will take another cat.
Actually my cat techie now lives on the
Trueblood set the set where they film
Trueblood at [inaudible] House. So
they use it. That's where they film it.
You'll be in prison. Pretty specific.
Yeah, I was gonna find that chat.
Then you're going to be even Saturday.
Oh, well they're not going to want it.
It's the true blood set. Chose say
tonic. It's about vampires and shit. Oh,
that's right.
You don't want that.
My fees for cat's going to be
around negative energy all the time.
Fucking vampires and shit to cue the music
class tries here. This is ridiculous.
Rogan experience.
Joe Rogan podcast by night all day.
May I begin before we
even do this podcast.
May I just say that you are
a bad motherfucker. Yeah,
you can say you are a bad mother fucker.
There are very few people in life where
I've watched him on TV and I've watched
him do stuff and I just went fuck that.
Fuck that.
Like you on that fucking show,
you went through some of the
realist moments ever in television.
Literally survival.
Not That fucking English do two sleeps
in the hotels that jacked your idea.
But the real shit man, when you were,
there's so many times I watch your show.
It just my mouth open.
Like just thinking about what the fuck
must've been going through your head
surviving in the mountain,
not the whole. The whole thing had to
come from that. I mean when I, you know,
when I first uh, sort of offered it
up and call it a network, you know,
they were a little shocked and I
said, no, I'll, I'll actually do it.
They kept thinking, you know, cause no,
they're used to like production company
as just somebody calling and saying,
you know, we'll, we'll set up a camera
and we've got these guys going in.
And I said, no, I'm going to
actually survive. And that's what,
that's what to set it off. Nobody's
done anything like that before. That
dude, that one when you went to
Africa and a hot air balloon,
I've watched that thing like five times
and caught a curdle like hugging myself
while I was watching like what the fuck?
He's got a hot air balloon
and there's lions out there.
Yeah, it actually is, you know, the,
I don't know if this made it on the show
or not, but uh, later on in the show,
when I'm in the memory that that was in
the thorn Bush shelter made a shelter
out of thorns or whatever.
So that night, I mean,
I listened to a kill go down about a
hundred yards from me and that was,
that's a freak most freaked out I've
ever been, you know, hear it going down.
You hear the screams and,
and in the end,
I think it was a Jaguar taken down
about boon cause they all hunt down and
baboons go nuts. And, and
that was like real close.
That was probably one of the
most nervous I've ever been.
Holy Shit.
A Jaguar and a bamboo and,
and there's no fence between you
in it and a wall. This is your,
you're in their environment.
Yeah. God Damn, that's crazy.
That is so terrifying,
man.
You know, it's not, it is,
but it isn't. I mean it is.
Well, it's like, you know, we, it was,
we were talking about fighting earlier.
I mean going,
and that can be terrifying going in
up against an opponent that you know,
is as tough a tough ass, but, but for
re and, and also if you're a fighter,
will, you're, you're geared for that,
right? Well, in my world, you know,
I spent a lot of years out
there. So for me, you know, I,
I remember I was out with my sister one
time and she looked into the forest and
she said, well, that, that's
really, really intimidating to me.
And I remember thinking all I want
to do is go right inside there.
And it was a real dark for
monitoring. So, um, I'm just really,
really comfortable out there. It's, it's
not that the other shit doesn't happen.
It happens. And it's not that
it's and real, it's real,
but I'm just really comfortable
whenever I'm in the Bush, I'm really,
really comfortable. And so the reality
of the danger settles with me, you know,
it settles on me and it's okay and I
can, I just, I just know what to do.
How much of a hindrance is it
while you're doing all this,
you're also setting up cameras and
turning them on and doing all your shit?
You're, you're filming it from several
different angles. Well, I was, you know,
that's the artist in me, right? I
mean, in the passion of a filmmaker,
I'd get out and I, and I
got it. And really I want to
tell a story, right? I mean,
if I'm there and I'm surviving,
that's one thing. Okay, that's cool.
Now I want to tell the story. In a very
beginning, I remember saying, Oh God,
she said, Oh, you know, have the camera
be shaky. Like it's like, uh, you know,
just a home video on it. And I, and I
said, why would I do that? I'm a good,
I'm a good filmmaker. I'm not going to
make my film look worse because you know,
you cause you, you know, I'm not,
you know, putting out movies,
I'm not Steven Spielberg, I'm going
to make it look as good as I can.
And so the passion of of filming
comes in really strong when I work at,
when I'm out there surviving because I,
let's see,
I got to walk down through a valley,
so I'll stop and look and go,
well I've got to walk through this valley.
So I got to tell the story of walking
through the valley and I've got four or
five cameras.
Well how am I going to do that?
Well there's a cliff up
there I could probably reach.
So I'll go put a camera up there and I
could way off in the distance and then
I'll have one on my buddy.
And all of that is about trying to
be a passionate filmmaker and, and,
and I just won an award recently and
it has to do with the film making.
I was really proud because it, it
speaks to the fact that it was, it was,
and I wasn't just a guy going out
sleeping on a shelter and doing a fire,
but I'm a filmmaker. I'm up making,
making a film, but like nobody else,
I'm actually really doing what
I'm making so I'm not, you know,
setting up nonsense. You were
creative and all the aspects of it,
the editing of it, the way you know,
you and you would be honest about like,
we got to walk over here to get this shot.
And I honestly,
I don't really want to go back.
I'm going to leave the camera
and the crew pick it up like I,
that was the other thing too, is just
being honest with all of it. Right.
If I'm going to do a show
like that, I, you know,
I can't tell you how often you'd
have discussion saying, well,
why don't you just say like, this
happened, right? It's like, no, you know,
I remember one time in an
argument, I said, look it,
I'm in the middle of the Amazon jungle
and I've got no food and just whatever
water's flowing and I'm alone for seven
days in the middle of the Amazon jungle.
If you'd,
and I'm saying this to like executives,
if you don't think that's dramatic
enough and get another boy,
because in my world that's pretty freaking
dramatic and it will be dramatic and
I don't need to embellish it.
So I always wanted to tell the truth with
what was going on up there. You know,
that's a real issue with reality shows.
It's like it's this dirty little
lies going on left and right.
They're creating
scenarios, you know, I'll,
I'll have no problem going on record
saying all the time that in my opinion,
reality shows suck. I don't
know why they're on air. I mean,
I do know why they're on there cause
they sell. But, but what gets me is,
is what I don't get is how many millions
of of North Americans and people in the
world watch him and think it's actually
hat or did you see it? It's like,
no, now they're even
scripted. Badly scripted.
I don't think I agree with
you in a don't agree with you.
I don't think they suck.
I think so.
I think it's a new art form thing
is creating and creating this,
this painting show out of losers or weird.
It's creativity.
It's different. You know what
I mean? There's just so many.
Like when Mark Burnett started it,
right, if it wasn't for Mark Burnett,
I wouldn't be on Eric as well because he
started with survivors series and then
I started getting these phone calls
because I was a filmmaker, survival guy.
And that's when I realized I could pitch
my idea and I said I'll do it for real.
So Burnett started it. And
you know what? My opinion,
the man's a genius and the stuff he does,
he's totally a genius.
But the shows are riddled with lies
and lies that you know are meant to the
public. Is meant to swallow so, so if,
if there's chill was really going down,
that's one thing.
But when you've got somebody like
I remember a single one time,
it gets really bad when you know you've
got to wait for the commercials to see
some good acting.
That's what's happening with Yachty shows.
There's definitely some of that too.
I think it's an emerging art
form are really thing. See,
I don't mind the competition shows.
I got a guilty pleasure for like
trading spouses and stuff like that.
The competition ones are cool. I like
that. But what I know though about I,
I've met a lot of people that do them and
like do behind the scene stuff and you
know, they're laughing at everything
along the way as they do it.
A lot of the times it's
this weird thing where we're
willing to watch a person with the,
there's no reason to watch them, but once
we locked, watch him for a little bit,
we get locked in. Yeah.
Just for whatever reason,
decide to keep following this
person around on TV. I Dunno man.
I've tried to watch,
you know,
I shouldn't say shouldn't name names
cause cause it was probably my own network
and stuff. But some shows like a,
you know, and they do like the,
the pawn stars and the, and
the shadow watch that. Um,
cause I, I don't watch TV, right?
So I'll watch and I'm in a hotel
room somewhere else. It's like, okay,
I'm in a hotel room, all my breath time
to put on and I'll put on the networks,
right? And I'll walk through
the reality and networks.
And I tried to watch some of
them. I can't do it. And I'm, I'm,
I'm alone in my hotel.
I told him actually saying out loud,
you fucking kidding me. No, no.
And I'm in my mind, I'm rolling.
I was like, people are watching this
and somebody who's watching this going,
they're gasping. And it's like really?
And, and so I struggle with it, you know,
plus I get called a reality show, just
surviving man got called a reality show.
It wasn't really a reality show. It
wasn't my God, I disagree completely.
I think it's a reality show in
the real essence of the word.
It's the new reality.
Shows are not reality shows.
They could should call
it like scripted drama.
Just call it hybrid or any bad actors.
We don't have to pay much,
but we'll say anything we say TV shows.
Yeah.
It's like loosely scripted scenarios. I
mean even though the whole, I mean look,
they didn't script it,
but they just edit what people say.
You can get a script out of it.
You can,
you can figure out how to edit it together
to make some stupid story or forced
them to go get pizza at five different
places and film and when they don't have
the right and they get to start getting
mad and like it's, it's really dumb,
but for whatever reason,
that infuriating feeling that you get
when you watch it, it's almost addictive.
That's a good way of putting
it and infuriating feeling.
Yeah. You might have a point. I knew,
I knew, I knew. I knew our forum.
I Dunno. A new art form that hit. The
thing is because I came from documentary,
right. I'm thinking that I'm a
documentary and a document, uh,
survival just so happens I really
go out and survive it. Right, right.
So then I get, but I get lumped in with
reality shows. One of the problems I had,
and I had it,
I had it with like in shark week and I
have it with different shows and stuff
I've been on. And is if you're gonna try
and do comedy than get a comedy writer.
That's what I think,
right?
Because there's a lot of documentary and
reality TV producers are like, you know,
26 years old and the all hopped up cause
they got a job and they're working on
the new show and they're trying to be
funny. And to me, I'm at home going,
this is like worse than
bad student art films.
I'd rather go see a student art film
then than a a producer who finally got a
job for company who gets to produce
this segment and it says, and then,
and there's, you know what, that
they're sitting around going, you know,
it'd be cool if, and it's like, it's
like high school comedy at that point.
And I and, and high school boys in the
locker room sort of thing. And I, uh,
that's why I can't do it.
So I sit there in a hotel room and
I'm trying to watch pawn stars.
I'm trying to watch the,
what are the t chopper dude's and then,
you know, but did you ever see
micro secret addiction? No.
So I dunno what w what
show was it is, well, no,
no porters who you've seen hoarders.
Okay.
So I'll be watching hoarders and I gotta
say I'm watching hoarders and I know a
couple of people like that too, but I was
watching hoarders and I thought, okay,
this is really kind of sick.
And then they're going to
clean it up and I'm coming up,
I'm kind of an anal
retentive organized guy,
like going to places I'm
really organized and shit.
So I'm watching hoarders go on.
I could clean that place up and
I'm watching it. And that was all
cool. And in one episode I watched,
and this is, this is what really pissed
me off and sweat through it for me was,
uh, the, well the mother was the hoarder.
And then they were injured interviewing
the sons and it was clear that most of
the people in the family
were intellectually disabled,
so that was the moment when I
went, fuck, whoa. Like why? Okay,
if I'd had the produce, I go, what
the fuck are you doing? You're you're,
I get when you do, when you're
taking people who are semi normal,
but they're kind of screwed up and
neurotic and you're doing okay,
I get all that, but you've got people
on there right now and they're,
they're intellectually disabled.
That's very clear.
You can tell they're not messed
up in neurotic or psychotic.
They're intellectually disabled and
you're running them through the hoarder TV
in that, that, that was the day I just
about threw the TV out the window.
I pulled a rock'n'roll.
Yeah,
I certainly see your point there.
The way I was looking at it as like the
keeping up with the Kardashians type of
thing that I feel like jewels,
it's no different than a soap opera
soap operas or silly, you know,
and this is silly too,
but it's silly with real people.
Don't you think that's something that a
lot of those people need though in their
life? They need that big of a
like slap in the face. Like,
because once you're on TV and everyone
in your neighborhood knows about it,
you're now obsessed with that.
You know what I mean?
Like you're being brought to light.
So I think that's maybe some
of these people who need to,
like the people who are on are
the people who are watching that,
people that are on it,
they,
they've gotten their life has gotten
to that point where they actually need
everyone in America to know that they
fucking suck and that they're a hoarder
maybe. Yeah. I don't know. I mean with
the reality shows, there's a lot of,
there's a lot of, you can, you can see
the hole. It's a culture celebrity, right?
I was getting messed up with
culture celebrity when we
get to La cause it's just
weird. It's was kind of weird, you
know? And so now you've got healthy,
it's one thing if you've got,
you know,
Brad Pitt and Johnny Depp and scarlet
Johanson and the culture celebrity,
they're kind of like groomed for it and
they're like superheroes and sort of
thing. And I do it. But
then you got, you know,
regular people are just messed up and
they're instantly thrust into the culture.
Celebrity just gets weird. Just gets
creepy, you know, cause they all,
you know how they always
do the outtakes when you,
the camera cuts to and now they're,
they're bitching about their sister or
somebody like that and you can see them
trying to project in that amateur
way. Well I just thought, you know,
ah, you know, one of us, you ain't
going to mess with my bedroom. You know,
and then he's like, I really
am I watching this. It's,
it's very apocalyptic. It's,
yeah. Well we're coming close.
I don't know.
Yeah, well that's, that didn't know who,
who's ever called a day right on it.
And has there ever been a time ever where
anybody's ever said that this is going
to be the day there's some shit
goes down then it really was? No,
no, never, ever, never. But
the Mayans, they were wrong.
Even predict their own demise.
They just ran out of it.
It's like they ran out of rock
and not, and not only that, the, uh,
most recent calendars that they've
found actually go past December, 2012.
It was just the end of this particular
cycle that they called the long count.
I don't know exactly what
it's supposed to mean to them,
but nowhere does it imply that it means
an apocalypse or doomsday scenario.
But there is, there is a, um, I think
predicted not predictions, but uh,
prophecies that,
that what it can represent or
possibly represent as a chess shifting
consciousness and that that
is the big sort of, you know,
apocalyptic. That's the
big, the big shift. You have
tier, you know? Yeah. That's a, that's a
weird word and a metaphysical kind of way.
Consciousness is a weird word when
people think about like a shift in
consciousness. Like, what
does that mean? Could be,
it could be a technology that allows
our consciousness to be elevated.
It could be, you know, that
we have access to, you know,
some new medical innovation that changes
the way the mind works. I mean that's,
that's a,
that's a distinct as well.
It's, it's, I mean, you can feel it now
though, we call the age of information,
right? Yeah. You know, or you know,
it's almost get almost mess with it
called the age of enlightenment because,
you know, we're just, we're getting in
tune with a lot of things. The whole,
the whole co, I mean, you know,
a big thing in my life in a big thing
and doing survivorman and beyond survival
beyond survival was really big for me
on this was the energy of connecting to
the earth and feeling like I was connected
again to the planet and the earth and
the natural world. And, you know,
thanks to the ceremonies and things
I did when I filmed beyond survival.
A kind of brought me back, you
know, cause with survivor, man,
I kind of lost that touch, you know?
And, and, and we are speaking little,
it's a little messy metaphysically
that's whole sort of thing.
But there's something to really,
the Po Energy,
power of energy, feeling it, you
feel it from one person to another.
You feel it from one inanimate object
to another, you feel it from the earth.
And so a big thing for me is,
you know,
with all I've done is
trying to get people to uh,
to connect with the planet again. You
know, kick his shoes off, walk bare feet,
get some dirt on your fingernails if
they see that it's actually healthy for
your body to sleep and grass.
And if he's sleeping grass,
it's actually like physically
beneficial and you,
your body has a positive feeling from it
and you wake up feeling great. It's got,
you know, if you get jet lag, one of
the cures is to kick your shoes off,
go walk up barefoot on your lawn wheel
and it just knocks jet lag out your
system. You know, pretty,
I've, I've actually,
I finally tried it one time and I dunno,
I felt great after.
So I have no idea if it's coincidence
or not, but, but that's what they say.
If you want to regroup after jet lag,
which I get a lot cause they're
always flying, just walk barefoot.
Grass is so hot right now.
Grass fed grass logging on as well.
Our relationship to plants,
a relationship to plants I think is,
we have to consider it the fact first of
all. And then if it wasn't for plants,
they wouldn't be processing the
oxygen. You know, they're, they're,
they like clean the air, the carbon
dioxide, they put out oxygen. Right.
Well just think of it this way. We breathe
out the plants, breathe in, breathe out.
We breathe in. Think of that. Yeah, I mean
that's, that's crazy. Pretty connected.
It doesn't get any more
connected than that.
And I feel like there's gotta
be something to touch in.
It has got to be something to
actually touching like grass and live,
live plants and organisms
like a rain forest,
like the feeling from a rain forest.
Like there's,
there's gotta be something to touching
all that stuff. What a whole though,
you know the whole thing. And
you hear about, you know, oh,
I go out to the wilderness and I,
and I get filled.
And that's what I feel every time
I get out there. There's really,
there's a reason why it's said that
way because you, I come here, you know,
I go out in the city and uh, it's like
everything's being sucked out of you.
And then when you go out
into the wilderness and you,
you just breathe it in,
you are taking,
you're taking really good shit and you're
taking really good energy. And I think,
I think we also,
we wonder like how much stuff
is coming at us all the time,
whether it's radio signals,
you know, cellular signals,
Wifi is, there's pollution,
there's all this stuff
around us,
noise,
pollution and all that stuff has just
forcing you to react to it. And it's for,
it's always coming at you when you're out
in a place with no cell phone service,
you see nothing but stars at night.
And it gives you this really
unique separation from noise.
This, this, yeah. You know what, there's,
there's two times I found in a year
in the wilderness where if you just,
you're just standing there and you're
in the middle of nowhere and the entire
forest, uh, goes still
at, nothing's moving.
I mean there's not a fly buzzing,
there's not a caterpillar crawling.
It happens twice in a year.
The,
an obvious time is like January
minus 35 degrees Celsius.
I don't know what that minus 40 Fahrenheit
even, you know, bitter, bitterly cold.
And you, and I've stood
there and I've listened and,
and I swear at that moment it's,
you can hear the sound of the
entire planet spinning on its axis.
You just hear this, this
moan, and it's really intense.
And the other time is in the middle
of middle heat of like June and said,
everyone knows this day in the wilderness,
if they ever get time out there,
middle of June, it's baking
Lee hot, super humid.
And all of a sudden you realize there's
not even a bumblebee. There's nothing.
It's just, and you can hear the planet.
I think you can, I've heard the phrase,
you can hear the planet.
He said try that.
God is deep.
That is fucking deep.
How many days all told have you
spent surviving outdoors like that?
How many, how many episodes did you do
on the show? Each was seven days. Um,
why you got to go about, uh,
I dunno what's 40 times seven?
It's about 40 times seven.
If you count other times as well.
Did the the all go seven days?
No,
cause I did the two new brand new ones I
did last year. Uh, I did, uh, two 10 day
dude. The new ones, the new ones, man,
I fucked up. I didn't know
that it had a different name.
I thought it was still surviving.
So I went to get them on the
DVR and I did get it in time,
whether it's a governmental 10 days.
And then beyond survival was the other
series I did so survive men 10 days.
The survivor man, 10 days. The one that
I didn't get on the DVR. I have my,
I have survivorman Dvrs, I've got all the
old ones. You missed the one in Norway.
Is that 10 days in Norway?
It's 10 days in Norway.
And it was toughest night of my,
of my lifeline.
Yeah. It was, um, you know, when I do the
journey sometimes if I'm trying to travel,
of course I, you know, I know
roughly where I've got to go.
I might've even scouted,
you know, I was like, oh,
I'm going to be over in that area.
And I come in the night, you know,
I get dropped in and I go do my thing
and I thought I had it set where I was
going to,
it's supposed to go to go down a mountain.
I'm going to go down the
mountain down this side.
That was sort of how I had it set up.
I'm going down there and I end
up getting lost. And it was, uh,
I was in the middle of the
mountain and the sun was dropping.
It was freezing rain and wet snow all day.
I was drenched to the bone,
both from sweat and from freezing rain.
And I was crawling down hill
on a steep mountain side.
The whole mountain side was just
like ice and steep. And I was,
and I came up to cliffs, Oh Jesus
Christ. And you can't go back. Uh, and,
and that was probably, you
know, probably the toughest.
How did you get out of there?
I just kept crawling.
I literally crawled down the hill.
It's,
you can sort of tell when you see the
show that it was way worse than I come
back and look at the film. I thought, man,
it was way worse than what that looks
like. But it was, I was crawling,
I crawled down a hill and I made a sea
cliff. I cliff's, yeah. Geez. How scary.
Yeah, I would this hypothermia. Right.
That's what I was worried about it.
So how did you get out of it?
Uh, when I got down there, um,
finally made it to the bottom
and I actually slept in
between two rocks and, uh,
got a little tiny,
um,
cooked up a little bit of food because I
had some fire starting stuff that I got
and then, you know, did pushups and sit
ups, sit ups and jumping on the spot.
A lot of times in a survival
situation when you, uh, when you, um,
are in the middle of the night and
you're sleeping on the ground and you get
that chill up your spine and just sucks.
I get out and I'll do jumping jacks
to pushups now just to get your,
just to flush it through
furnace up and you to,
you got to heat up and then it
buys you to 20 minutes. Right?
Yeah. It's amazing how it
could be freezing cold,
but if you go hiking up the side of
a mountain, you, you'd get sweaty.
Yeah. That's the worst case,
right. It, you know what I mean?
Everyone knows my saying is,
you sweat, you die. It was
a reason for that. You know,
it really is true.
It's the worst thing is to be like 4:30
PM and realize you're still soaking wet
and a winter day.
I went hunting in Montana recently and uh,
we spent four nights in the bad
lands camping on the Missouri River.
Nice. And uh, I'd never done that since.
I mean maybe when camping a
couple times when I was a kid,
but we went to Yellowstone and the
weather was good. You know, it wasn't,
there was no issues.
Like maybe it rained a little bit,
but this was cold as fuck and
wandering. But we had all, you know,
equipment and guns and all that
shit for deer mule deer. Yeah.
So it was, um, it was for a television
show that's a Stever Nela show, uh,
called a meat eater. You ever
seen that show? I have him.
Fascinating shot. Yeah. So,
but that was like literally,
um, one of my first,
or probably my first experience
ever doing anything like that.
Even sleeping outside like that many
nights in a row. And I'm 45 years old.
I've never experienced it before
until I got a couple of months ago.
Yeah. I think, I think everybody
should in a way, you know, I mean,
at the very least, you know,
we can be into what we're
into. We can be in the UFC,
we can be into hockey, we can be into
math, you know, doing math equations.
We're going into anything we
want. But I think that, um,
if you can take an hour a week and
get out and just stand by a tree,
you know, they're crazy. Yeah. It,
it's crazy. So you get out in a hunting
situation like that, you're, you're,
you're there with the guys
when you're doing thing, but
still you're, you're just,
you're just around it, right. You're not,
you're not underneath a bunch of hydro
wires getting, you know, zapped with,
you know, leukemia inducing
electricity. You're, you're,
you're in the Bush and you're
getting the positive stuff.
Yeah. I don't, those fucking
power wire towers freaked me out.
When you see like one of those things
and like houses right next to it,
you're like, yeah, that's not like a good,
it's the highest rate
of, uh, our heard anyway,
an escalated rate of leukemia
amongst hydro workers.
I used to do land surveying a lot of years
ago running the transit and doing the
land surveying.
And I remember every once in a while
we'd have to set up underneath like the
hydro wires are crossing or whatever.
And I,
I distinctly remember looking through
the transit and feeling electrical shocks
coming into my, my, my
forehead is, I wasn't trying
to mark the spot for the, the,
the, the party chief sort of thing. Yeah.
So I mean if that's happening and I'm
standing on the ground hunter, you know,
112,
200 yards from the wires and I've got
electricity coming up through my transit
and into my forehead. Come on.
It just can't be congested.
Good man.
This is not right.
It's like you're getting stoned all day.
Yeah.
Wow. Yeah. You can't live near that.
I don't think there's no science.
The science behind non conclusive
data, that feeling of uh, being
around nothing. No, no cell phones.
The weird, the weird thing about
it is it's kind of invigorating.
Like you don't need naps.
Like does,
one of the things that
me and my friend Brian,
one of the that we talked about like
we never got like tired and we got,
we went hiking and we got sweaty and
we were out of breath for a second,
you know, like that kind of tired. But
we never got that weird, I need a nap.
Tired that you get in the city.
There's this weird thing that happens
where you know the middle of the day,
like fucking go for a nap right now.
That'd be awesome.
You don't have that feeling when you're
out there doing something all the time.
I should try it in the Arctic.
If you go to the Arctic in June
and you've got the sun 24 hours,
you just, you're like, you're
just like, oh, you know, and
I'm alone. I do my thing.
So I'm thinking, oh, I'll,
I think I'll, you know,
go shoot the scene over here would be
starting a fire or something and I'll look
at my watch, he'll say
4:30 AM and I'm like, okay.
And I've been up, you know, you just,
you just stay up and you feel like staying
up because the sun never leaves and
you just, you know, you crash
eventually because you crash.
But you can stamp a long
time in the Arctic, in the,
in the, in the early spring.
It's pretty awesome. Max, how
many days have you stayed up?
I don't know because you lose.
When I was doing my thing survivorman
I would lose track of time anyway.
It's easy when there's nightfall,
but when I'm in the Arctic he just,
I can tell it's night because the
sun is over on that side of the sky.
But you know, cause it circles around
here like this. I'll, I'll just does this,
this oval loop around
the perimeter of the sky.
I would just think we gotta get Outta
here, man. This place is going to blow.
That's what I would think if this is, the
sun is only up all the time. We're like,
we got, you can't live here. We've got
to get the amendment in California.
This place is going to blow sooner
or later. How dare you bring that up,
scare the shit out
of me.
And December 21st is coming.
I don't really think that it
was an earthquake predictor
that predicted the big
one. I think it was just the
end of the calendar. Yeah.
But there's a lot of people want to like
get behind it and it becomes this focal
point, which could mean
that something could happen.
Just because so many people
are focused self fulfilling
prophecy. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I was asked to do a
bunch of TV shows on a,
on going out and like checking out people
who are preparing for the apocalypse
and preparing for the last days. And
uh, I just don't know. I couldn't get,
I couldn't really get my head around it,
but I want to find people that
prepare for y two K it didn't happen.
And then where are they now?
They went crazy for a little
while and then they said he know.
I think we were just a little premature.
It's 2012 it's really going down.
So what about the dude who put up
the 200 billboards? Oh yeah, yeah,
I remember that. And he actually
went on record and said, if, uh, if,
if it doesn't happen,
God is a liar and I'd love to,
I would have loved to call them the next
morning. So, uh, did, we're still here.
I think that guy had done that before
though. Yeah, he did. He isn't. Yeah,
I think so. I don't know if it's the same
guy or not, but there was another guy,
I did that shit. Oh, she's
one of those things, man. When
you're in a position like,
uh,
like especially guys who are preachers
and pastors and anybody's in a religious
position,
you're in this position of literally
being the word of God from God to the book
through your mouth.
If you're around a lot of dumb people,
you can, you can all of a sudden
believe your own bullshit.
You can start thinking that you
make sense. Next thing you know,
you're buying billboards.
He telling everybody the end's coming
and you give them a very specific date.
Like, do you have a like a plan
B? If this is incorrect or you,
you just rolling your diet's, you're
a crazy person. You're a crazy person.
Just rolling the dice.
I mean,
a lot of these lots of guys in that
position that they've carry a lot of
charisma, right? Yeah. You know,
Burt Lancaster movie, the rain maker,
and it's just so much charisma,
you know, you could sell, you know,
I've never fridges, two fridges
to an Eskimo, all kinds of things.
I've never seen that. Is that
a good one? That's a good one.
That's a good classic movie.
I think it's called the rainmaker.
It's Burt Lancaster. It's pretty, it's
pretty killer. And it's about that, right?
I mean,
he's so masterfully charming and
charismatic that you want to believe,
you know, and, and that's what
happens. And if you're in,
if you're living in the pit
or you live in, in, in, you
know, you've got misery. Um,
someone really charismatic comes along,
you know, whatever, whatever you say, man,
my favorite one is when the charismatic
guys call someone else. A false prophet.
That's my favorite. She put
all the charismatic, you know,
teachers in like the ring.
Yeah, I do a cage match.
It would have to be like
a Roman thing though.
27 towards everybody should
be dead there. You ever, ever,
ever seen the guy, um, he's got the hair
slicked back, I forget what his name is.
Famous guys. The one who always talks
in tongues. Jimmy Swaggart. No, no, no.
So one of the,
one of the last popular guys,
I forget his name, but he's
a, he was on TV, he said,
every time you write a check to me,
Satan gets a black eye.
He said that with a straight face.
Okay.
Maybe Satan says gay lover.
That's an unbelievable quote.
Like that's another like
the fact like you are,
your bar is so low like of people who
are going to buy that line who are going
to believe that it's good fodder for
south park shows anyway. Yeah, exactly.
But it was real.
It wasn't like it wasn't a Saturday
night live sketch that was a real guy who
was actually saying that you've given him
money and say it and gets a black eye.
They came up with it. That
strategy for extracting money, um,
where they were telling people
that if they were broke,
what they should do is give the church
money and then God would pay them back
like a hundred fold.
And like,
they kept like advertising that and
having all these people tell the success
stories about how they were,
they had no money for the
rent and no money for food,
but there was $200 they had stashed and
they sent it now and all the sudden they
want the lot and they will tell this
crazy story about all these great things
that happened to them when,
so they're literally going for people
who are beyond poor, they have net,
they have like there's still scraping
together their last pennies to send to the
council.
Extortion. It's like in a religious
extortion, you know, I know that, uh,
I remember years of, uh, just, you know,
just talking to this kind of stuff and
learning and searching and all that. And,
and the thing about like,
if you take something like a Jehovah's
Witness to thing to thing about it is
that
if you're not in,
then you are of Satan.
So therefore,
if you are of Satan than anything
you're going to say to me in the next 15
minutes is going to be from Satan.
So basically you just have to get finished
saying what you're saying and then I
will show you the,
the way,
and that's the tricky part is how do you
have a realistic debate with someone of
a dogma when they're
convinced that whatever,
that you're already connected to Satan,
so you don't even know what you're
saying anyway. You can't. It becomes,
it becomes an impossible.
Well
situation. Satan is the gateway
to to like you're crazy.
Like you can believe in God all day.
You can believe in angels,
you can all that.
It's cool,
but when you start thinking that Satan
is hiding in your basement or Satan's
around the corner or Satan's coming,
you can't bring up Satan
like no one can say,
we found site and in Afghanistan were
moving in right now hanging with Jimmy
Hoffa. Yeah. You can't say you found
Satan. You know, you can't say,
Satan is influencing me. People go,
oh, you're fucking crazy. You're,
but if you believe in God, a
biblical God, you really are.
You're supposed to believe in
Satan too, I believe. Yeah.
I believe it's part of the pack. I
better look that up. But you can't. Yeah,
you can't do that.
And you can't ever,
you're listening to Reverend Joe Rogan
here. Robert Tilton false prophet.
That's the guy. Uh, it's,
I'm looking at it a,
a website about a false profits and
that's what they're calling Robert Tilton.
He's the guy who every time
you write a check to me,
say it and gets a black
eyes, gets a back. He was,
he was a guy that he,
they took a video of him saying a bunch
of things and they put fart noises
behind it. Incredible farting. It's
preacher. Did you see that? No.
It's funny.
In a very juvenile and it's embarrassing.
You find it.
It's not good for more than five seconds.
You get annoyed with
it. Uh, Robert Tillman,
Tilton t, Tilton rather. T. I. L. T.
O. I. Yeah. This looks good already.
Does it? Yeah. Just from the, a thumbnail.
This is him for, I've seen all that. Laban
is, I've seen what Laban is done under.
Not Amazing,
but my word will not return void and
it will go to that which it was sent
and it,
but life and joy and
the the nature of God.
Oh,
laid Lu
for eating all salt provided multiply.
That's the opening of
the windows of heaven.
I'm a child. God bless you
too. I'm fucking childish.
I laugh at Childish Shit.
If it was just a cat on reality TV,
yes, I definitely problems like
I'm not, I'm not claiming that,
don't I? I'm, I'm silly person.
I find find humor in silly things.
It's your job to them. Yeah,
I guess part of it that's made it
a job. Yeah, that's more like it.
I sort of shoot.
Well still you see, I mean, so to die.
Who was doing what I was doing before I
was doing it. Nobody, nobody. I made it a,
I made it.
It's like,
oh well I'm going to go sleep under
some twigs and start a fire boat and you
will pay me some money to do this.
Did you start out like
just camping and say,
I wonder how long I could survive
on my own with a few simple,
no, I was actually a, I was working at
much music in Toronto, a much music city,
TV producing the video network there
and, and uh, and I was a singer,
songwriter, rock and roll
musician and playing in the bars,
doing all this stuff and we were getting
signed to RCA was doing well and I got
really disillusioned with
all of that industry and uh,
and I stood there and I was what, 25 and
I didn't know what to do and I was like,
what am I going to do now cause I'm, I'm
quitting. I'm getting out of this, um,
to actually,
you know what,
I left music in the 80s because the music
of the eighties sucked so bad that I
just said I can't, I can't get him
some more and Halan. Okay. Van Halen.
Well Ain't away to my window.
That's right.
And you got to go pre junk free jail.
Well there was other good,
wasn't that the same?
At least you didn't say
salmon hot for teacher was on
that album, was it? I think,
I don't know. I think so.
Yeah. It was a bad video too.
We'll jump was just a little
electric. They went poppy, they got,
they got poppy on that and it
was, but at least, you know,
at least it was pre Sammy.
You made a good point though.
There's not much from that era that come
on Depeche mode, the Thompson twins.
I just wanted to kill
myself. Thank you. Thank you.
Isn't there something until the hearing
a real guitar. It's everything man. And,
and you know what, I, I left the
music industry just dropped it.
I didn't play my guitar for 10
years. I didn't, I remember saying,
I don't even want to know
what's coming on in the rate.
I remember like audibly saying,
Oh yeah, you hear this new band.
But then they go to say it and I
don't want to know. I don't care.
I don't care about music anymore.
It's dead. Because you know,
rock and roll was dead. And I was
like Cindy Lauper. And so I, uh,
I what I did more on that later,
but what,
cause one thing I gotta say
I regret is I missed, uh,
pearl jam and Nirvana and sound good.
I missed all that cause I was in a canoe.
I don't regret being in a canoe,
but I missed that happening.
And I now I look back and going, man,
that was some pretty good stuff going on.
I wish I hadn't missed that era. I was
in a canoe. I spent, that's where I went.
So I looked and I thought
what I want to do.
And the first thing I thought was
I want to do wilderness adventure.
And I didn't even know what that meant.
I just said,
wilderness adventure is throw
it out there in the air.
And I remember I used to love Jacques
Cousteau and Tarzan movies and I saw this
little ad for wilderness survival course
and the college and I went and I took
the wilderness survival course and Humber
College in Toronto and I fell in love.
That was it. I've never looked back.
And His dog sledding, sea kayaking,
Whitewater canoeing, everything
I could do with being out there.
And I spent the next, you know, 10 12
years doing nothing but adventuring and,
and lots of survival to why that's,
that's how I,
that's how I learned and trained
was just all laymen stuff. You know,
I came down to the states and trained
with John and Jerry Macpherson and then I
went out and practiced a lot
when out and survived, you know,
first with classes and people and
then with buddies and then on my own.
And then I was, I'd been out on
my own and that's, you know, and,
and I got to say some of the best of your,
I was lean and mean and fit.
I mean,
I was carrying canoes all summer long
and guidance teenage kids and carrying
their canoes cause they wouldn't,
I was, it was great time.
I was about 28 29 by this time and I was
rock solid hard. And I love that man.
Someone's going to take that
and make a clip that they will.
I was so hard then every
day. And it was, yeah,
that's going to be a problem. That's
going to be a problem. I know.
That's all right. I hear what
you're saying. So you were, um,
you were just living like a savage.
Well, I was, I'm an outdoor guide.
I was an outdoor guide and I loved
it, man. It was awesome. And, um,
and it was a,
about 10 years of that into that where
I'm just to wrap the story up basically,
where I kind of got itchy for music again,
and I was in Yellowknife in the northwest
territories and w stepped into a blues
bar and they had a, um, Monday
blues jam. And I thought, well,
I used to blow some harmonica, you know,
uh, jumped up in a blue on, uh, uh,
some harp on a Mustang Sally. And the
minute I stepped on that stage, I went,
Oh man, I've missed this. And, uh, so I
started playing again as well, but then,
you know, uh, basically
that's right about, I mean,
I was keeping my kids in diapers
by playing the bars. At that point.
I started playing the bars
won't, you know, solo playing.
And, uh, and, and then,
you know,
then is when a survivor series hit,
did my interviews and made my phone
call and Survivorman Kinda took over.
Wow. That's incredible man. What
do you think happened in the 80s?
It made a music fall off?
Well,
there was a few things.
Number one was everybody was
hung up on saying rock is dead.
Everybody thought it was Zeplin
dinosaur rock and Floyd dinosaur.
They were calling a dinosaur rock. If you
listen to a Q and a seven Toronto, you,
oh well you're listening to
dinosaur rocky and, and I,
and so it was all synthesizer solos
weren't allowed to go on unendingly.
You had to have precise Nini, Nini, Nini,
Nini, Nini, Deany Neat Solos, you know,
all of this fed into
this synthesizer stuff.
And we had Thompson twins and
flock of seagulls and Aha on,
and it's not that there weren't
some bright spots, you know,
sting was doing some great stuff and
Peter Gabriel was the youtube, you know,
there was some bright spots,
but as a general rule,
the pop culture went to this and
the whole thing about rock and dead.
And then when I met what I missed,
when the whole grunge movement came out,
came out and I started listening
to Pearl Jam. Only recently,
I was like going through all this
old stuff. I'm like going, Oh,
this is just rock music.
That's all it is. You know? Uh,
Mike McCready, whatever his name
is from Pearl Jam, Ace kick,
he's doing a kick ass rock blues
solo for five minutes on alive.
That's all he's doing. He's doing the
almond brothers. He's doing cream.
He's doing Zeplin it. Absolutely. And
that, you know, so I'm, I'm actually now,
I think music's awesome. I
think, you know, Dave Matthews,
Ray Lamontagne, you know,
Adele, you know, off, I'll even say lady
Gaga, you know, pink, uh, you know, um,
the mom, Mumford and sons. I'm, I think
there's some great stuff out there today,
but in the eighties and the eighties,
I was so,
I couldn't bend more
disillusioned with music.
Wow. Um, have you ever heard
of roadkill ghost choir?
No. I just found out about us. I
just listened to this one song. Uh,
I think it's called,
I don't even remember the name of it,
but whatever it is that the, there
are a new band. It's like God,
this really sort of Bluesy Banjo.
He field to them.
Great vocals,
like really interesting songs.
There's guys like the black keys of
course here at the black case. Ben Harper.
I'm not, I've never really
listened to much. Ben Harper
men's cool. I'm going to, especially
at it too, we were talking,
you know if you're going to
go down the spiritual road,
you know Ben's and explorer,
right?
He's a spiritual explorer and so there's
a lot of words and a lot of lyrics here
that take you down that road. I don't
know anything about them. My player,
you know, he's one of those
famous dudes that I know.
It's not like I get a reviewer to see six.
Steve, what is it? C six Steve Seasick.
Google seasick Steve.
Okay,
everybody should Google see 60
if this guy is the real deal.
Jack White pulled him off.
I don't know where he found
them on a street or something.
He plays heavy slides,
Zz top light blues. On a broom handle
with a wire and the guy is the real deal.
Like he's just, and now he's playing at
the, what are they called? Isle Man Rock.
He's
playing of 30,000 people. Here
you go, man. That's seasick Steve.
How old is that dude? Old enough man.
And that's a real guitar. But he's got
like one that he plays with a broom.
He's got this bad ass Nigga,
this Nigga his guitar strap.
It's a strength.
You know who plays with them?
John Paul Jones has his bass player now
he played with Dave Grohl,
the foo fighters
called trust.
Y'all
see 60 man. So you know, I dunno.
I think now I liked the
music that's out there now.
Like what's coming down the pipe now?
I want to know what happened to them
in the 80s where did it go wrong?
How did they get from it's where day?
Yeah.
How did they get from Leonard scattered
to some of the shit that float and ate?
Some of it I blame on on on the
edge because as much as I really,
I like you too. You too much.
I love you too. But the edge,
you know, started doing,
you know, sort of nondescript
guitar Solos, no noodling, know,
riffing, you know, and, and um,
and so the whole whole group of followup
guitar players came into this and then
cleaned that up even more.
And,
and so you ended up with all these really
little precise little nugget that we
lost the rock and roller. We lost the
shredder. You know, I went to rose,
the sound that you two created and
fantastic where the streets have no name.
I mean that is a frilly and that's
one of the greatest songs ever.
That just that power of that fucking song.
Like oof.
I, I hear you though. There's
the other stuff is missing.
Even like Bruce was doing dancing in
the dark. I mean Bruce, you know us.
What were you doing? You know what
happened buddy? Courtney Cox was on video,
so that's an shit.
He's dancing so white to comparising
for a culture that was the ADC style.
Totally do that man.
You could totally do a version of that.
Know when it was like for the wild.
They were trying to cool the Dal something
coming on and they were trying to
make it cool to dance for like the
longest time they tried with center fever.
That worked for a little while.
And then you know why people quit quickly
got away from it when they found they
could go to bars and just not dance. Well,
there's only one Michael Jackson, man.
I mean, I thought Michael was a genius.
You see? What do you know what I love?
I love entertainers. Yeah. Pure
gene Kelly, Elvis, the Beatles.
Michael Jackson, David Lee Roth,
and quintessential from it.
So the other night I went out to see axl
rose in Vegas, guns and roses. Right.
And um,
do you know what Qi was?
Iconic. He did his move. He,
his voice was right on. He's put on
a bit of weight like bottled did,
but just like bottle. He was kicking
out his voice. He played all the hits.
It was awesome. What happens to
those guys too? They just go bananas.
Who He'd just get too famous
was axl rose type characters.
They just get to huge as rock stars.
And then they just go bananas for a few
years and then pull it together again.
I don't know. I Dunno. I Dunno. I at some
of them do not know. I mean, when I go,
not all of them listen to like welcome
to the jungle and sweet child of mine.
He opens with welcome to the [inaudible].
When you go back and listen to those,
you will like Jesus Christ.
You mean this guy could have been
putting out shit like this for 20 years.
If somehow or another he could keep it
together and still produce this kind of
shit. I kid, their early
stuff was fucking fantastic.
Mr. Brown stone. How could they, how
could they fuck that up? Alcohol, drugs,
women and Cat pee. Joe. Too
much money. Too much money,
but you don't like it. It
happens. You listen to right now,
Peter Frampton's going out and I don't
know, I don't know if my friend Danny,
Danny knows Peter at all, but
uh, Peters out doing his, his,
his co Frampton comes alive.
He's doing interviews and seven,
I was just too young. I had all the money
throw it. He was too young, you know, to,
to handle it.
It's different now because now you come
with like bookkeepers and people were
like, man, it's so much
different back then.
I just read Greg Allman's autobiography.
Really?
What a great read it's and you just,
I mean I literally read it as a rock and
roller with complete envy from page one
to the end. I'm like, Oh man, look at him.
Cause he'd be like every fifth page
and we just did it for the music man.
It was just about the music we played for
free and all of these parts cause it's
just about them like yeah, that's
why it's so good. It was incredible.
It's a great read. It's called my cross
to bear. He was a bad motherfucker. Yeah.
And if you hear this Greg,
I blew a mean harp.
I don't want to come play with you at
the beacon theater when you're playing in
there, adding jump up on stage and
blow some harp with you. Thank God.
He said Harp. Do you want, do you
want me to take a harmonica? Have you,
have you ever met him or
connected with him and then, no,
I just read the book recently and I just,
I just, you know, it was like, yeah,
I mean, I know I sound like an
old rocker, but you know. Okay.
So last night I was at Alice
Cooper's Cooper town in Phoenix,
Arizona cause I get to play
in the Chrysalis putting
some times and he's got the
solid rock foundation.
It's a great foundation that
Alice Cooper does for street kids.
Last night was a battle of the bands
and I was listening to the battle of the
bands and they're trying to
compete for one spot to play in.
As Chris was putting concert and a,
he's got all Smith's pudding,
that's what you call it, sales
Cooper, Christmas pudding concerts,
a big rock show for a in a theater.
And you know,
all the proceeds go to
the solid rock foundation.
So these bands are
battling it out last night.
So I'm watching twentysomethings young,
young,
20 somethings and even younger, uh,
playing it up. And you know what?
I sat and I thought,
these guys are playing rock and roll.
They were just playing rock and roll and
actually I was like thrilled. I thought,
look, check it out. It was a guy went up
there and he was ripping off Blues Solos.
They would and they were doing and he's,
these are kids, 20 year old kids
and they were playing rock and roll.
I was very happy last night.
Yeah.
There's something to be said certainly
for that particular type of music.
Like it doesn't need to [inaudible].
It doesn't need to be synthesized.
It doesn't need to like we,
you doesn't need to be overproduced.
There's emotion comes through that music,
through that raw guitar and
here in a real drum. You know,
like seeing a guy really hit
the base, having, you know,
having it like a band,
like the black keys,
like there's an emotion that comes
through watching their stuff that it's so
crisp. It's not like did, did,
did
you know that fake weird noise.
It's like you don't have to
reproduce the noise, you know,
just to keep doing it with,
with instruments like instruments,
you're expressing a person's
movement through, through guitar,
through the drums.
You're expressing this person's movement.
And as soon as I know that you're just
pressing some buttons and it's creating
them, that music that, that
sound becomes weird. Well,
my contention is that the thing, here's
the other thing that got lost in the 80s.
The thing that's missed is music is live
musical performance because you can do
whatever you want in the studio
with auto tune and you know,
a guitar garage, you'd Guitar what
I would, guitar garage bandwidth.
You can do anything you want
with pro tools and logic,
but you can't recreate that
live unless you've got a shit.
And I played a Gig in odd, uh,
Ottawa, Ontario a month or so,
a couple of weeks ago and it was a rock
bar and I've been playing my, my big,
my more sort of Nice stage
stuff with my, my, uh,
film footage from around the world. And
I do it survivorman question and answer,
but final say for some reason we got
booked into Mavericks and Ottawa is a rock
bar and I had a blast because,
you know,
not by the end of that night I was
almost in heart attack territory.
I was drenched with sweat. I blew my
harmonica like crazy all night long.
Had a blast with people. And it's
like, you know, you can't replace that.
You can't replace great live performance
with synthesize preprogrammed button
pushing crap. Yeah, you can't do
it. You got to be good on stage.
That's what separates the, you know, the
stars from the hackers. But then again,
I say there's some electronic music that
I think is very artistic should or is.
Yeah, it's not, it's not the same
thing. I'm an art rock lover.
I grew up, you know, Pink Floyd, I think
Radiohead's fen, fantastic muse, you know.
Uh, absolutely. You know, so it's
not, it's not to the exclusion, right?
It's just a,
something that went wrong in the eighties
cause it's some of the stuff that's
wrong then, you know, I dunno.
Cause bands were getting signed in the
80s that had never even been on stage.
You know, and I steely Dan, they got
grandfathered in for that. They're okay.
They're an exception. But in
the eighties you know, no,
I mean these people never performed.
It's Kinda interesting because that's
sort of one of the things that's happened
with the Internet.
It's forced live performances be much
more frequent if you want to make money
because they can't sell the
kind of records that they
used to be able to sell it.
This did the internet swallowed everything
up. I think it's a good thing. I mean,
only because I love the stage. Like I
was saying earlier, I like entertainment,
you know, I think it's a good thing too.
And it also prevents those like, um, uh,
Mike Meyers movie scenarios where they
construct a fake band. You know, I mean,
it seems like it would be a Mike
Meyers movie or something like that,
but that's like a lot of like milli
Vanilli a lot of these bands that they
create,
like they put together these artificial
things in a very like comical,
cartoonish sort of way and people just
ate it up. What do you think a of idol,
the idol, American idol, the voice, uh,
America's got talent and really
watched them. I've, I've only watched,
I watched American idol a once and it
was obvious that a lot of the people that
they were showing were crazy.
They were like their idea. Yeah.
The idea of like what was
good was there were nuts.
They were like saying their voice,
you'd be fucking terrible.
It was almost like they were doing
it on purpose. Yeah, they do.
That's the preliminary,
right.
That's a preliminary shows
and when it gets to the end,
I mean I have to meet you get to the end.
There's some talent on the stage. Sure.
There is.
And,
and that's why I said one of my
exceptions to the reality shows is the
competition shows, you know, I,
those I've never minded, you know,
for some reason that just seems they do
all the reality stuff around it for the,
for the, you know, 11 episodes
leading up to the last two. But,
but then when they get down to the
town and the performance, you know,
it ends up on some pretty talented
people. I think it's pretty cool. Yeah.
I think this is probably because of
the fact that there's more ways you can
deliver your music.
Like I found out about so many people
just because of a youtube video. I'm like,
someone would send me
something through Twitter.
You've got to check out this band.
So I go, okay, check on the band.
And then some of them you don't give
a fuck about. And the other one,
every now and then he'd go,
whoa.
And so then you started retweeting
it and next thing you know,
you're watching the, the numbers on the,
this, the hits just go up 10, 20,000,
30,000 feet.
People start telling each other about it.
Like it really becomes like a viral
thing if it's a really good song. Well,
let me let, let me totally,
this is totally shameless,
but I just found out this morning that
my song Arctic mistress is number 10 on
the, on the most download
indie indie download this week.
And I don't even know what that means.
It's called Arctic mistress.
That's a powerful word. Arctic
missed. It was, it was my, you know,
lyrical, uh, um, take on the
Arctic as, as a mistress,
as a seductive woman. And so I
wrote it that way. It's a beautiful,
it's kind of an AC song, so you're
not going to hear it on rock stations.
But anyway, my point is being
is ac mean adult contemporary.
You're going to hear it
in the dentist's office.
You're not going to hear it on the rocks
and when I'm not going to play it today
either, but, but uh, the point
being that, you know, I just
found that out. It's like,
what's that mean? It's, it's, it was
too ahead of Adele for indie downloads.
I'm like, okay, awesome. I
don't see any checks, haven't,
but I don't know what it
means. But anyway, anyway,
I just plugged it so I don't care.
Do you like doing music more than
you like doing your show? Yes.
Yeah. That's your, your
foot. Don't, don't,
don't misconstrue that to say that
I don't love survivor man, cause I,
I don't piss on the flag.
I mean, you know what?
Survivorman open a lot
of back doors for me.
I mean including going to play with
Alice Cooper, Stephen Stills, Tommy Shaw.
That wouldn't happen if not for survivor
man. You know? So I think you, uh,
you open a lot of people's
eyes on that show.
That's a tip for me.
That's like as far as pop culture goes,
that's one of the,
that was the one most revealing shows
ever because a lot of people have this
distorted perception of what they
would do if they got lost in the woods.
I just go fishing,
catch some fish.
Like a mother fucker was always
good at fishing and I'm like, dude,
get all the a dude, man. How
come you didn't like take
down a deer? And it's like,
well,
okay,
you take down a deer with a spoon and a
piece of string I can get all the time,
man, how come you didn't catch a whole
bunch of fish? Okay, here's a Bobby pin.
In some thread you go catch a whole bunch
of fish. So it's, it's people's. Yeah.
But on the other hand,
what I always pointed out was anybody,
like I went out there being just an
idiot because anybody could do what I do.
I got some survival knowledge.
There's no question and I've
got all that training for sure.
But I also am doing things that
anybody could do. You know the thing,
the way I survive, it's still
80% anyone. So you don't,
not physically impressive. You don't have
to be in incredible shape. You don't,
you just have to skillset,
skillset,
not not super impressive
in terms of skill set.
It's just here's what you
could do, you know? I mean,
I'm really good at the fireball.
So there's one of the ways that you
know the 20% where I kick it rubbing two
sticks together. Yeah. Yeah.
So that's not so normal for
everybody on the street,
but a lot of the other stuff
is just what anybody could do.
I tried to do that once and it was
not successful. It's just really hard.
It is not easy to start a fire with a
stick luck that I didn't have enough of
the little a kindling.
It's often like, you know,
watching your sidekicks on the gun and
youtube the other day, I can't do this.
I've been doing Muay Thai. I'm like
suck up my legs. I can't teach you that.
I know that you could. I know Micah
teacher, the fireball, it's just,
it's just that skill set, you know you'd
get, it's an exchange. Let's do it.
Alright, I'll teach you how to
throw a side kick. Teach me to live.
I live in the woods and cook
the food. What's the, the,
the first time you did it, did you
go out for a test run? Like I will,
I'll do two nights by myself in the
woods and then eventually kick it up to
seven. I mean, for survivor man
itself, no, I knew I could do it,
so I just went right at it. But before
that, had you done any trial runs?
Had you done any like, not for survivor
man, but in learning survival? Yeah, lots.
I done it with, as I said,
I went out with classes,
I went to a friends and I
went out on my own for sure.
And when you went on your own, did you
do the same thing you did on the show?
Like give yourself a scenario,
like a broken bike and you have to
dismantle the bike? Not so much.
That was for the show? No, I just,
I just went out. I go out hiking.
I go off in the Bush and do my thing.
Just just survive. It was all wilderness.
See, I wasn't trying to create
scenarios then. I love the scenarios,
but my stairs are fun.
Yeah.
My favorite for sure was
the hot air balloon because
that was just the freakiest
like you were going to shoot a rocket
at the line. That was cool. Hey, I know.
I still love that it's,
it's when we do a promo clip or something,
it's always in there because just that
I remember that moment just, you know,
crank and down on the fuel
and just shooting like a 12
foot flame in front of me.
Yeah, that's pretty rocket.
That was bad ass. It's like,
okay, lions bring it on man.
Bring it. You were fucking hanging
out. Wiki lions, man. You need that.
If you're hanging out with lions. Ooh,
that's so frightening. Barbecued zebra.
Now I heard you on opiate,
Anthony.
I think it was where you said that you
think you had a Sasquatch experience.
Ooh, I'll tell a story. If
I can get another dentist.
Am I allowed to say again?
We're not sponsored by any,
well damn it should be old.
Milwaukee is what I want to get.
Sponsors were too controversial for
alcohol companies, I should say.
Sorry my Miller,
I'm from drinking my Miller lite.
That's what I'm supposed to say, man.
I love you. This is delicious. Uh,
so tasty. What we ask him.
Oh yeah. Big Fake Foot, man.
I you said that you had more than one,
you know,
to Sasquatch experiences when, uh, when my
second wife and I were off
living in the Bush for you,
we lived for the Bush in the Bush
for a year and I'm just like,
it's like 500 years ago, no metal, no
matches, no plastic nylon. And we're like,
you know, just a couple
of original traditional
aboriginal is living out there.
And I did a film about it and all that.
And when we were, when we were out there,
there was this moment where, um, we're
in a, I don't know where we were,
but we were in like a little shelter.
We're out by the, by the river and it's,
it's one of those quiet nights where
I can hear, you can hear everything.
It's just nice and quiet
and I hear a large bipedal,
so you know,
two feet walking towards the tent.
Now I know what a bear
sounds like when I hear it.
I know what a moose sounds like it and
I know their feet might line up and all
that sort of stuff. I know those
sounds, and this was a very large,
I would say it was like a very large
man walking in the forest. Now that's,
you know, is that a big deal? Well,
yeah, we were in the middle of nowhere.
Like there was no roads for,
you know, a hundred miles.
So there should not be anybody walk and,
and it was walking and it came
closer and closer and closer.
It was about 50 feet from the tent.
I wished to this day I hadn't done this,
but I got nervous and I did the
same thing I might do with a bear.
I just kinda yelled at, hey,
we're over here, you know, uh,
not 10 minutes and send this
little shelter. And uh, and uh,
it stopped and I wished I peeked my
head out around the corner and then it
turned and it just walked away just
a little bit faster than it came.
And that was it. So that was, that
was episode number one, a big,
big man walking towards us
in the middle of the bush.
And at nighttime it was dark.
The second time was the one I told
an opiate Anthony. And that was,
I was in day five or day six of
filming survivor man in Alaska.
And um,
I'd filmed this scene.
It's funny because we just looked at
these clips recently and I had forgotten
something. I filmed this scene where
I was cutting grass up to make a bet.
So recently we were looking at the footage
and, and I'm going to look at that,
look at that. And my editor pointed
out and we'd look and every I'm,
I'm doing my thing and you
see me stopping and going
like that and I'm just looking now at
whatever and went back and I do the two or
three times I stopped and I look, I forgot
that I did that, but we saw it on our,
on our, our outtakes, so
to speak. And I'm starving.
I just keep looking on the bush.
Anyway,
I finished my scene and I turn the
cameras off and I'm just sort of standing
there and I hear the sound and the
heck, you know, and um, you know,
of course I'm thinking grizzly
bear of course. Absolutely.
That's what I'm thinking.
And about 50 feet away,
it's ruffles the sort of
roughing in the trees,
rustling in the trees.
And then I hear,
Ooh,
like that only way louder,
right up my spine.
And then he did it five more times
like that. Super, super loud.
Now I've heard Moose and bear of her
bears grunt. Well, I can make a wolf howl,
but I've never heard anything like that
before in my life other than a zoo with
a great ape exhibit. Right.
Oh, so to me, you know,
there's two ways to ask a question.
Joe. You can say to someone, hey man,
did you believe in big foot? That's a
hard question to ask because you know,
if you're sitting around at a party, it's
like, ah, no way, dude. You got it man.
Don't be losers. No Sir. That's
when we asked a question.
The other way to ask the question is,
do you think it's possible?
Did on our vast expanses of
forest throughout the planet,
that in tiny little pockets of maybe
six species sticks members that,
uh, uh, by peatal gigantic
epiphysis ape could exist.
It's very intuitive and sensitive human
beings and doesn't really want to be
discovered yet is responsible for
hundreds and hundreds of physical, uh,
audible anecdotes. That's a
different way to ask the question.
And so I actually presented
that to discovery channel
science channel recently.
I said, why don't I do
Survivorman bigfoot? Matt,
why don't I go out there and I'll
just go no camera co and they are,
they're down with it. We're trying
to make that happen right now.
Are you going to go back to the same spot?
I thought about that.
That was a tech Tekla arm or
something like that. I'll ask,
but there's some hot in BC and in,
uh, I think a Washington state.
So I'll go to a few so that,
I mean, so what am I saying?
Do I believe? I don't know what
the answer is. I don't know.
I just know what I heard.
When you watch finding big foot,
do you guys get out there bitch,
man, I'm looking for real.
You know what you're asking me?
You're asking me about a reality show
I'm watching and I'm just like, no.
Really? Here comes another episode of
what was that? I heard a squatch. Oh,
that's a squatch. And then you see
nothing cut to commercial catch. Conversa.
Every single, every show is the
same thing, right? Oh, let's,
let's do the night shot cameras. Cause
that's going to look scary. Yeah.
Holds finding big foot.
Not, we're looking,
we're looking for,
you don't even find shit every episode.
It's like what was that?
And they cut to commercial.
Well they know when they're putting
that together that it was nothing.
It's a TV show called the fuckers.
And so I gotta,
I gotta I with a friend
of mine at the network.
We got a bottle of Scotch on it and I
said if I come back with something that
makes the hair stand up on the back of
your neck, it's a bottle of Scotch to me.
And if I said, if I come back with
nothing, I'll you about us guys.
So we got a bet riding
on it and I don't Dunno,
I'm just going to go out there and I'll
be alone. Why isn't there some new stuff?
Brian there some new uh,
biologists have listened to some
big foot sounds and deciphered it.
It was really recent. See if, see if
he could find it because they, like,
they played the sounds that
these hunters made say a cause.
I'm not going to be like confirmation
bigfoot sound. No, they've, they've had,
that's one of the most
compelling pieces of evidence.
The only one that really makes any dent
in my imagination is the sounds that
they've recorded. They had,
of course scary. I'll tell ya,
the hair went up on the
back of my neck that day.
I heard a great ape is what I heard. I
heard the sound of an ape, you know. Ooh,
I mean, and I'm alone in the middle of
the Alaskan Alaska home of the apes.
Well, uh, for,
for people who have never flown over
the Pacific northwest or Alaska or in,
and then do you think they really get
how crazy it is? People don't know.
People don't know how vast
it is out there. I mean,
I'm the first one to kind of come up in
environmentally speak against, you know,
clear cutting and you know, all that
stuff. On the other hand, I've flown,
I mean four hours and not
seeing anything but trees.
And so if there was 12
Sasquatch living down there,
and let's say they were intelligent
enough that they buried their dead.
So that's a question, right? Well,
how come you never find a skeleton?
I've been in the woods for
many, many, many years.
I've never in my life come across a
black bear skeleton and there's 60,000 of
them in Ontario alone. Never once
seen a black bear skeleton nature.
So efficient moving.
I found one moose one time that
fell through the ice in the spring.
Other than that, or deer,
you know other than that.
So if you've got 12 by pedal apes that
co that live and they bury their dead,
I mean you're not going to
find a skeleton. You're going
to find, what do we find?
We tracks, we hear sound, somebody
gets rocks thrown at them.
Somebody sees something.
So we got, you know,
well how many times someone see a
mountain lion and we know there's so many
mountain lions. Yeah, that's the thing.
There's no like game camera trap photos.
You would think that someone would have
taken some sort of a game trap photo.
Well there is some stuff.
I mean if you can Google some of that
when it comes to big foot to photos,
I've never seen a photo. Nothing's
always blurry. And out of focus.
And if they're really smart and they're
good at hiding and they live in the
forest,
it probably would be tough to get a beat
on them that they might even know what
it is cause it's going to mind even just
recognize the technology and the tree
and say, I don't want to, I'm gonna
stay away from that. Who knows, right.
To most people like me, it's just
a sexy idea. It's just a very sexy,
I plan on going like Todd standing is a
real, it's a real cool gentleman. He's,
this is his whole life is, is, uh, is
um, researching bigfoot and Sasquatch,
uh, at, for the purpose of
protecting them. And you know,
when I go out, probably go,
you know, with him, the whole point is
we're not going out there to shoot them,
tag them or it was going out there to be,
go on their terms if they exist,
whatever they are and let it happen.
But the only way you can do that is my
way, which is to go out there alone,
spent long time and immersion. And
so, I hate to sound like a marketer,
but who else to do that? But survivors,
you're the fucking guy to you.
It's a very different thing though. The
news to me, I was saying it's sexy to me.
To you,
you had an experience like you've had
two separate experiences and one that was
like,
that sounds fucking terrifying.
A bear can't make a noise like that.
Nah.
Bear a bearing on the bark sort
of thing, but not, you know,
hoping, hoping, hoping,
hoping like that. Ooh.
Bears are and five times in
a row the exact same way.
I mean touch you wish you just got a
flashlight on it just to see what the fuck
was. You know, the thing
was, my camera was,
was 20 feet away and I wanted to
turn it on so bad, but I didn't move.
I didn't move a muscle the whole time.
And then when I finally moved is when it
took off and I heard this big crashing
and smashing and going
through the forest and
then I was gone shit
around right after it. Why?
When I went down to where it was really,
I went down,
I got to go see this shitting my,
and I was [inaudible],
I got scared
when we were sleeping, cause a deer came
in at the camp dear, made some noise,
like Holston stomped his feet and
I was like, oh, this is a fucking
dude asked.
Here's what if you find out that big foot
is just a bunch of murderers that are
hiding in woods, you know, like that's
where they live now. They've just,
they live in the middle of woods and
said, just whoop, whoop, whoop sound.
Because that's them trying
to think of the crap on it.
So you'd get the fuck out of that. Could
be something be, and they'd be like,
those dudes from swamp people, they can
make some noise and they can throw rocks.
They can make some noises to wear a suit.
Yeah.
Big Foot's a serial murderer and
there's just tons of serial murders.
Now that's a different theory.
I'm not even going out now.
Straight [inaudible] so you're talking
about serial murderers who live way off
in the middle of nowhere
working at people. Never go.
They can live. You know what,
being trolled. You know what that
means. No, that's a good idea.
Just trolling you with,
if you're a serial murderer that you
don't want to go to print to this
conversation. Shocked. Cover yourself
with here. He turns his face away.
Like
if I was a serial murderer and you
looked like a monkey, I get it.
And then you breed with other
ones and you make female. No,
you make people get scared of you.
Like you're some kind of animal or the
core big foot gets all the serial murders
and makes him his bitch. Ooh, Texas
chainsaw massacre. Where eight foot. Yeah.
There's a King Pin monkey
go steal me that backpack.
He just has sex with
all these serial murder.
There's a guy who's sending a
blimp over the Pacific northwest.
He's going to try to capture
one, uh, on campus. Saw
that. Yeah. Yeah. You got to go in.
I think you got to do a pull the survivor
man and go in and be there for like
two weeks on your own. In the
middle, sitting on a tree.
How long could you go out there for? Like
if you, uh, if you could bring like, oh,
you wouldn't want to bring an animal
because it would smell, right,
like the carry like alarm or something to
that carrier. You're, you're uh, items,
but like how long could
you live out in one spot?
Like if you went to the Pacific northwest?
Yeah.
Wherever you think that there's the
highest incident of bigfoot sightings and
you went wandering through the woods,
how long could you live out there with
what you could carry, what it could carry?
Well, if you're willing to hunt,
you could go, you know, you could,
you could really go and definitely
if you're willing to hunt.
So as long as you brought it full,
sorry, I don't mean it to be applied,
but, so I did a book will to live.
And in that book I wrote about it.
You just plug your book will to
live Harpercollins and I, and I,
and I did all these
stories of survival and,
and one of the stories that I dissected
was actually, um, um, Chris mcinnis the,
the into the wild guy that John Sean
Penn movie with Eddie Vedder soundtrack.
Cool soundtrack. And uh,
you know, he went in,
he didn't have to die.
I mean he had a gun and he just
went in with a lack of skill.
But there are men and women,
I mean there who go out there.
And as long as you've got the skill
set and you've got the ammunition,
you forget, you take, like he took down
a moose and then the moose spoiled.
That was ridiculous. It didn't have to
happen, but he didn't know what to do.
You take down one moose, you kind of
covered for the year at least six months.
Right. So of eating. So it's indefinitely
if, uh, if you, if I've got, you know,
a rifle and ammunition,
you know, wow. Otherwise,
if you're talking survival, it's
brutal. You know, if it's survival,
I have no idea it'd be is
you know, you, you can,
you can perish pretty quickly even
if you are a survivor man. Yeah. His,
the kid from that movie,
he went and he was like sleeping in like
a mobile home or something like that.
Right. He found a whole bus,
an old bus, all of us. And
he died there. Unfortunately,
very tragically. He did. I say
tragically because you know,
he was an intelligent man and create a
man. He didn't need to die, you know?
But it was also, I said in my book and
he was very, very charming. You know,
Alaska doesn't give a crap if you're
charming, you're not, you know?
That's a good point. Yeah. You can
believe in yourself all you want,
but if you're delusional,
if you don't freeze to death,
if you don't know how to cure me like
the most, if you don't know how to hunt,
you're going to freeze to death.
You need to learn those skills.
It's like it's a ridiculous proposition.
It just go out there and try to figure
it out as you go along. Like I said,
you know, I, I, in the
beginning of the conversation,
I tend to play it down a little
bit and I, you know, I say, look,
anybody could do what I do.
I still stand by that.
But that doesn't mean that it's
not, you know, brutal out there.
It doesn't mean that it's,
uh, that it's easy, you know,
because the worst thing is
three o'clock in the morning,
he tried to sleep through
the nights and three o'clock,
four o'clock in the morning, you don't,
I mean, when I'm there every time on,
on day three, I want to go home,
right? I'm like, what am I doing here?
This is stupid. Why am I doing this?
You know, I could be my, you know,
my by the crew that brought me in is
out somewhere at a hotel having a beer
right now, you know, and
I'm sleeping on the ground,
freezing my ass off and shivering
and its socks and I'm tired.
I'm hungry and I miss my kids and
all that, you know, blah, blah, blah.
All that stuff comes in and there's
nothing, there's nothing. This.
The thing about when the a
copycat shows all came up,
there's nothing fun about
survival. It's sucks, you know,
I mean what I do is survivorman is
can be brutal and can be very hard.
And I sh I do it with,
with a wink in my eye and with some wit
and I have some witticisms and I've got
skill set and I'm teaching
and I'm filming, but it
still sucks no matter what.
It's still very,
very hard.
And when the other shows came along in
the chat and make it look like it's all
so you know,
this or that are fun,
it's not be the reason is that they're
not there three in the morning,
sleeping on the ground. Like
I still am, you know, I still,
I'm still there at 3:00 AM sleeping
on the ground. I'm not often a hotel,
you know, working over the scripts
for the next day. I'm, and,
and sleeping on the ground
sucks. You, you, you, you don't,
you feel like you get the shivers up
your spine and it feels just like you did
when you were eight years old and
you had the flu. And you just,
you cry and you want to go home and you
just want your mum to bring you some
toast and peanut butter,
man. That's all you care.
And that's what it's like when you're out
there and you're shivering and Europe,
you know, 45 year old man,
it's still sucks. She's Christ.
That's in survival.
Wilderness travel is different.
Cause I can go out there
with food and a 10,
I ain't be out there forever as beautiful,
you know,
then you're connecting with the earth.
But surviving
is different.
So if you had like a campsite
in a tent and you know, uh,
various, uh, necessities,
fishing rod rifle,
you can just be out there near
a river where there's water.
You'd be out there forever.
Yeah, I've had a woman.
Yeah. Would you use,
would you enjoy that without a woman?
No. I mean, even with them,
with a woman, the first year
of a marriage, my second wife,
that's exactly what we did.
We spent a year living in the bush
a full year and you know what?
It was fantastic. I got to say,
wow, that was incredibly great.
Now did you forage for your own food?
We did the whole league. Really? Forest.
She didn't grow up there.
Now would I do it now?
I go out now and I did enjoy times
now, but you know, also love, you know,
Sushi in Vegas too, so. So I mean I
like, I like both worlds. You know,
I like jumping back and forth.
I love my music and rock and roll,
but I love hopping in a canoe.
So I'm always equally at home as I am
in a dugout canoe as I am going to New
York and watching a show.
Yeah. It seems like you,
uh, you found this, uh, uh,
that's a crazy balance.
It is crazy balance. Yeah. I like,
you know, when I was really young,
I watched a Tarzan movie one time and it
wasn't Weissmuller was Steve Reeves or
somebody like that.
And in it,
the beginning of the movie happens and
he'd guys in a suit and he's like New
York, he's like this high
end lawyer or something.
And he's got babe on his arm
and he's in a call, comes in,
it was trouble in the jungle and he and
he grabs the stuff and this woman goes,
aren't you going to need to pack?
And he picks up a Bowie knife in a loin
cloth and he goes, this is all all need.
And it was Tarzan and off he
goes off into the jungle. This.
And I thought that's the coolest
thing I ever saw in my life. Man.
This guy likes to drive an Aston Martin
and swing from a tree as like so cool.
And here I am now doing playing
survivor man and you know,
and rock and roll and I love jumping
between both worlds. It's cool.
I uh, there was a Charles Carroll whack
cause that what the guy's name was Jack
Heroin? No, no, no. Charles Kuralt.
Charles Corolla used to do those. Um,
I think it was a, for 60
minutes. It was. Anyway,
he was interviewing this guy who was a
trapper who lived alone in Alaska and he
lived there for like six months out of
the year and then it would come back down.
He would,
you know,
but he would stay up there for huge
periods of time with no contact with the
outside world. And he said that
once he started to do that,
he could read animals minds.
You do get a little loopy when you're
out there for awhile. You know,
a lot of times I'm the compare me to
Dick Prone Akia wilderness man in the
wilderness or something. And you know,
I think what Dick did was fantastic.
He was obviously an engineer mind and he
built this great place and he's out in
the wilderness like 30 35 years, 25 years,
something like that. But in my mind,
you know,
if you're leaving society behind for 25
years has got to be a little something.
You got to be missing something. I,
I, I think, and I've known trappers,
a lot of friends, trappers and
I, you know, I trapped. Um,
but you can get pretty loopy out there.
If he even in Survivorman for seven days,
my one of my guys I work with you say,
yeah, I always knew when you lost it.
Or a day on day five is like, oh,
this is the day less loses it.
Let's look at his eyes, you know,
and that's only five days, you know.
So you're out there for a few months or
few weeks. Um, do you get a little loopy?
If you're alone, you're not alone.
It all changes. But if you're alone,
I think you can. You can. Kettle little.
I liked that. Show me cabin fever mountain
men. Have you ever seen it? I heard it.
Saw the promo, but it would
be interesting. I don't
know how much of it is bs.
It seems legit. But uh, the one guy,
one guy lives in Alaska and he's a trapper
and all this guy does is just run his
trap lines all day with a snowmobile and
he's up there for months and months at
a time. It's fucking crazy.
Like you're watching it,
thinking about what the hell that's
like this guy's flying in a plane.
He flies for hours over this vast
wilderness for lands in the spot that he's
been walking around for years.
He goes to the same spot and he
has these different cabins set up,
these built log cabins and
he's constructed at these
various places and they're
just barely big enough to store like
hides and a bed and he has like a little
stove in them.
It's fucking cool.
It's escaping society, right?
It's just shunning society.
And the fascinating part about what he's
doing is you think about it that while
he's out there, he doesn't know
what's happening in the world. Yeah.
It comes out in the world changed, comes
out and you know, nine 11 happened,
comes out and something else happened.
Comes at a war, whatever he though,
so those guys don't know. They literally
don't know anything has gone on.
They might come out and,
and all sorts of stuff has happened
and then the dust has settled.
Not even ever hear of what happened
while they were gone because it maybe it
doesn't matter anymore by the time
they get out. That's wild though.
Have you ever seen then a vice piece
on that guy that lives in the Arctic?
Hi Mo or high mo. His name is a
thing. It's called high. Yeah.
Heimos Arctic refuge.
And it's about a guy who lives way,
I think it's northeast Alaska
and he has a this cabin.
It's like one of the last
ones that you'll ago.
One of the last people that is allowed to
live out their homesteading loss. Yeah.
And he's uh,
he's out there eating Caribou
and fishing and he gets,
he gets tr traps and he gets money
for the skins and that pays for like
vegetables or whatever the hell he
needs that he gets his vitamins from and
different supplies and
guns and stuff like that.
And he's just out there
with him and his wife.
A lot of these guys, they, they really,
if you taught when she
interviewed them and talking them,
they don't want much a society that's
not for me. Let's see that, you know,
that's not for me. And that's where
they end up is Alaska. Well he was tall.
Came about like this great satisfaction
that he gets from hunting and fishing
and, and being like a hunter
gatherer. He was like, this is like,
this is what peeps Manhattan.
It's the core of us. I mean, why does,
why did so many people like survivor? Man,
I think a lot of times it's because
it touched on the core of who we are.
We can have all this other stuff like
you got in here in this studio right now,
but if you're left alone, what
matters? Food, water, shelter,
done those three things. Food,
water, shelter over and over again.
And when I do what I do are these
guys go off and live like that.
You're bringing it down to that,
you know,
you're bringing it down to the
brass tacks, you sand, this is it.
There's nothing else that matters.
And so people watch it and go, yeah,
if I lost it all,
it would be like what Stroud's doing
and I'm going to Wa because that's like
losing it all man.
All you have to do is get warm
and get some water and some food.
Like that's pretty it.
And in many ways that's very freeing.
If you think about it, you don't worry
about rent payments or anything else,
you're just going to drink.
Yeah. But then you ought to know,
like every day is a search for food.
I think you'd get tired
of that shit real quick.
Do get it gets it gets old real fast.
Yeah. That's what I mean. You know,
if you're good and you catch a moose,
you know, that's it. That's a big,
that's of that spiritual moment when
something like that happens. But you know,
when, if you have me go in with stuff like
we were talking about, I'm a happy man,
you know, cause now I'm not worried about
trying to get the next meal. Do you,
where do you live now? He, without
giving out your home address,
basically live in a cottage country in
Ontario for people of Toronto other than
Muskokas. Um, and uh, I've got my
off the grid place as well. Um,
but I, you know, I wasn't raised by wolves
and I don't, you know, I don't live, I,
we did an MTV cribs came up and we did,
did,
did my place and so I did a sort of a
tongue and cheek show of my bedroom and it
was basically shelter and
the Bush, um, you know,
with a little fire going inside
some the master suite. Um,
but I asked live normal,
you know,
I live up there normal and
then you an off the grid place
too. Do, yeah, that's pretty
cool. Actually. Solar panels
and wind generator and,
and um, where's that 170 acres in
northern Ontario as well. You just, uh,
you built like, just a sustainable
home up there. Did you, I mean,
I'm not gonna say I built,
I had someone else you don't want me
building and give me an ax and a tree.
I will make you shelter. You throw in
an angle or a moving part. I'm screwed.
Not into precision. Not in a preseason.
No, absolutely not. Um, so yeah,
I did it for, I did it for a film called
off the grid. Okay. With Les Stroud.
I've seen clips of that online. I've
never seen the actual movie though. Yup.
You should watch it.
I will promise you when you set this up,
do you like go to visit it every now and
then and stay there all the time? Yeah.
Yeah. What do you do when you go
up there and just play guitar?
Live Lower Caveman and play guitar.
Play Guitar, get out in the ATV,
go jogging down the road. Um,
have people over sit by the fire.
Do you bring food with you or do you
hunt and fish where you're out there?
I actually, you know, I really, it now
I really only hunt for survivor man.
When I'm doing survivor man, I hunt.
Um, but I haven't had time to go out.
I actually,
my buddy,
one of my best friends hunts all the
time and I'll text him while he's in his
tree stand and he'll always say,
stop texting me and then I'll phone them,
stop phoning me any
deer coming. Uh, but I,
I don't have much time to
get out there anymore and,
and do much hunting or anything like
that. So Ted Nugent isn't, you know,
inviting me lay out when he does.
Have you ever done it with Ted Nugent?
No. No, not at all. To Nugeo
lives a crazy life. He uh,
he has like two places,
one in Michigan and one in Texas and the,
they're those uh,
like a high fence operation.
So he's got all these trees and
shit and he hangs out and I'm,
and the animals just run around and
he's like got his own like personal
playground to like shoot
deer. Yeah. He freak.
He comes up to Ontario every
year to, to uh, to hunt bear.
And he freaked out on Ontario because
they stopped the spring bear hunt and he
would, he'd went on a rampage and
said nobody go to Ontario anymore.
Which was like, people are getting really
ticked off about why did he say that?
Because we stopped there,
bring the spring bear hunt.
Now it's only a false all fall bear hunt.
But he still comes up I
think for the fall bear hug.
Well they do that though because
they count numbers. I mean, yes,
it's important to like, well there was a
lot of orphanages happening too. Right?
Cause you shooting the,
the,
the mother bear in the sprit with a new
spring Cobb who hasn't had a chance to
really get on its feet, you know, at least
in the fall that's had the summer to,
to Wean itself and to, you
know, do what it's got to do.
So I've been a lot of it was that
as well as numbers. Who knows?
There's science behind it somewhere.
Right. Most of the time. Right.
So why is he getting upset about that?
I thought that that would,
that was his whole thing is being a
conservationist. I Dunno. I Dunno.
Eyes cause he likes hunting
and black bear in Ontario.
He loves hunting period show.
It's fascinating to me.
He's always like thanking God and the
government and fucking thinking all the
army and the marines and Shit.
Shooting deer with arrows all day.
He's having a good time though.
I gotta tell you guys, Ted Nugent,
he's in his sixties he looks at me.
But besides all the right wing rhetoric,
it gets a little crazy.
Like Obama's purposely trying to ruin
this con. He gets a little muddy, but,
but the whole shooting deer with arrows
delex fun as fuck he's doing is doing,
you know Bruce the Bruce Lee thing. He's
expressing himself honestly, right? Yeah.
Yeah. Just, um, the, um, the deer hunting
aspect of it is kind of fascinating.
I mean, he, he really has like great joy.
Does he have his own show? Oh yeah. Yeah.
I haven't seen it yet.
Spirit of the wild.
I don't know if we get a
new jeep Canada on chip.
If you're into watching dudes
fuck up beers with arrows.
He's bad ass. He's a, I mean he's, he,
I don't know like what the limits are for
how many deer you're supposed to kill,
but he gets them all
he does.
He feels the quoting hills is
fucking tags. I'll tell you that,
that Ted Nugent knows how
to shoot some fucking deer.
Like there's a lot of like hunting
shows and like you'd say, well,
if Ted Nugent as a hunting show,
it's probably not as good as
like the real hunters we'd done.
And he's a real fucking hunter.
Like Alice Cooper's a real golfer.
Know what I mean? He's a
kickass Golfer. You know,
there's different guys like that. I mean,
that's the thing about being an artist,
being a performer. I
think you, you, you know,
you'd go at things with pretty much
full Gusto, you know, and your hobbies,
you know, uh, look at Ron Woods paintings,
you know, I mean things like that.
It's like we always ask surprise like,
well Ron would can paint too. Well, yeah.
You know, and it's like,
okay, perfect segue.
So me as survivor man and the whole
thing of me playing my music, it's like,
that's why blue harmonica on all those
shows is to say to people at a little
wake of my, yeah, I'm not
a one trick pony here, man.
I don't just do fire beaus that's why
you didn't know harmonica. That's cool.
Fucking dragged an amp out there with
a life raft. Do you pull a little
bomp bomp bomp you to like an hours
where the battery and he chose to play
Voodoo child on the beach just yet.
That would send a message,
wait for my traps.
And so confident I am in surviving.
I'm going to blow some blue and my ass
skills. Segue. Why don't we do it? Yes,
please. Um, what's the name of the
song you're going to do? Uh, let's see.
What am I going? Oh yeah,
we're going to do a, yeah, you
ready Daddy? You can set up.
Okay. So he's a showbiz man.
That's an awesome segue.
Danny Weiss is a, we say that's
how new of a friend Danny is.
Danny waste is a brand new friend of mine.
Just met him here in your studio.
A and good friends of good friends of
mine and a phenomenal guitar player of too
many names dimension. But we've got
iron butterfly, Alice Cooper name.
If you name a few, go ahead Dan.
That medlar ever doing so good.
And then he hit Bett Midler. Lou
Reed. Okay. Larry through it.
So Dan is a phenomenal guitar player
and, and, and I've just, uh, uh,
my friends have,
um,
I'm just kid connected me with it and
I actually like that Miller's show in
Vegas. Yeah, that's a rose is
a good fucking song. Sorry.
So we're going to do, uh,
I'll, I'll do it. What is the name of
the, I'll play. I'll just play at any,
I'm going to take the headphones off.
Okay. All right. All right. Nice Tattoo.
All right.
It's good that I had a beer drinking
pop renaissance man.
A man of many skills
can live out in the fucking woods by
himself and knows how to jam folks.
Woo.
Okay.
Whoa.
Got Fancy clothes.
I don't want a woman. God reigns. Zana no
new watches.
Lodo woman with a Nice Tattoo.
It could be
right across the chest.
She could have one on a lay
slip. Aware and a wet. Yeah.
Okay.
Don't go up that
long.
Is he into Wallman with a nice time?
Wow.
No, no. Give me my field.
Nice.
It could be
on the oh,
across crossfit shoes.
She could have one on her legs.
So step away.
Don't go up that girl.
Oh.
Oh,
whoa.
Awesome.
Scanning.
It's a mama with a nice,
it could be on the
chips.
You have one auto
slip away wet.
Don't care what that
is tied to last time.
Yeah. There we go, man. That's cool.
Thanks Danny. You're welcome. That
was awesome. That was fun too.
If I was a Checker,
I'll let you, fuck man.
If I was at a bar and you're playing
there like, oh let's go, fuck man, I
want to go hunting, man. I would do
things to is man. Yeah, because they say,
you know like those kinds of songs,
like they'll like putting ideas in the
girl's head and then you get off the
stage and she's like, I can't believe
how good your music sounds, Les Stroud
survivor man. Cause I don't want to
rock and roll is all about, isn't it?
It must be. It's a, it's a
very compelling, you know,
someone who could make awesome sounds.
It's a,
it's a incredibly compelling to people.
You, no, that was a, I told
you earlier that I was,
did I read the Greg Almond autobiography
and he was talking about, he said,
he said he had no luck
with women whatsoever.
And then he started to sing
the second he sung on stage.
You've got this cute little long blonde
hair dude. And he starts singing,
you know, stormy Monday, you know, and
all that. You know, and yeah, that was it.
Yeah. That's a great fucking
songs. Oops. Even so,
the later stuff, like I'm no angel. That's
a great fucking song, man. That's stuck.
I had some real soul to his voice.
Absolutely.
That was a voice of a man who's had
real life experiences. Real regrets.
Yeah.
Did. And the book hope
pulls no punches. You know,
it's a life of drugs and alcohol and
redemption and women and man has a lot
going on and yeah.
Mapi oh man, I don't know so
much good fucking music man.
The almonds.
Well, you know, that's one of the new
things to musically is coming out. I,
I didn't, you know, I
started listening to a,
uh, what's that? The, the
Sirius satellite thing.
Jam Jam,
something.
I can't remember the name
of the station gem on and
uh, uh, the plan, you know,
widespread panic and government mule and
a almond brothers with Derek trucks and,
and it plan all this stuff. And so
that's new stuff. And, and fish and,
and it's, it's great. These guys,
these guys went from hack noodlers
to pro top players now, you know,
they were hacked noodlers back in
the day when they were starting.
Now they're great,
you know,
and they're playing really super well in
the Warren hands and all these guys is
great stuff, you know, and I'm,
and I missed that, you know,
just some letting somebody go. I'm sure
Danny has had his share of just, you know,
shredding and cutting loose
and going and you know,
I do this thing when I play with my
band and my guitar player, you know Oj,
God bless him, he's a great
player, is really creative.
But he'll do the solo and I know
he'll do a solo based on, okay,
it's time to end the solo.
And if I'm having a great night and
I think he's got it, I'll go, no,
you're not done. And I'll turn my
back to him one on stage and going,
oh sorry man, you're not done. Keep
fucking playing man. Keep playing. And I,
and I just go, you got it. You went
to the top. Now go past it, you know?
Yeah. When you go off. We had a
Stevie Ray Vaughan, Andrew dice clay.
Believe it or not, his son Max is
a, an incredible drummer. And uh,
we,
uh,
we played a video of him at the Improv
and Hollywood and it's ridiculous how
good he is. I mean, what, what is he 21
yeah, he's very young, but he's been
playing drums his whole life, so I mean,
he's fucking incredible. He's like, like
a professional. I mean it's like, well,
kids, same kids these days, right? I mean,
man, they're starting young re quickly.
You've got 12 year old shredders.
Yeah.
You didn't have 12 year old kids shredding
in the 70s yeah. Way More listened to.
And due to Internet you
can learn how to do it.
Now when I want to learn new
track, I just go, okay, let's see.
How do I play that song?
I just youtube it and there's
some guy sitting there going,
and then you go to this chord and what
you don't know is he detuned it and put a
cape on and you're going, oh,
that's how he does that. It's crazy.
We live free for free. Yeah.
Yeah, we live in strange times.
It is strange. But again, Joe, I keep
coming back to the same thing. I mean,
you know, I obviously you and I both
like fights. The UFC were like, like,
like the martial arts, mixed martial arts,
all that stuff. Love it. That is a stage.
It's real and it's right then and
there and rock and roll or good music.
If not rocking, we'll just
good music, right? The country,
I don't care what you got pop right then
and there is when it's all, you know,
it comes down, he's got deck, this
drama guy you're talking about, man,
if they can do it right then and there,
it's an awesome thing.
It's nothing like it.
And that's why I love performing so
much because with survivorman and beyond
survival and shark week and all the film
stuff, I don't know for months and and,
and while though now it is a little
quicker with the websites and stuff,
it's like oh we loved your episode last
night but when you've got people in a
crowd and there's 8,000 people and
you've got 90 minutes with 8,000 people,
so a lot of energy and it,
it lives or dies right there,
you know that very second.
You know how to win them back and pull
them back if you thought you lost them
for a second. And that's intense. You
know, I love that stuff. I love the stage.
Yeah, well it certainly, what,
what people don't understand
about mixed martial arts,
a lot of people think it's
brutish behavior or they
think that it's a thugs or
you know,
violent assholes.
It's hard for them to wrap their heads
around it, but they really are artists.
It's,
you're expressing yourself
and you're expressing your,
when you watch someone execute
beautifully inside the octagon.
To me when I say beautiful, I'm not saying
cause I'm running out of adjectives.
I'm saying cause it is beautiful to me.
To me,
when I watched like a great
performance inside the octagon,
it's like a work of art and it's
dedication and focus over a years and
intelligence and learning and adapting
and changing and modifying and,
and constantly assessing until you build
your skills up to the point where you
have extreme competency.
You know,
like when I see a guy like Anderson
Silva inside the octagon, I seen him.
He is putting on a fucking show.
No, no, no one more clear than any.
Then the Anderson, there's never been a
more clear example. And his last fight,
he called the guy who's fighting,
Stephan Bonner called him to come to me
and he put his back against the cage,
like, come on, hit me.
And he just stood in front of them and
let's stop Steph and bought a throw
punches from inches away and just slipped
them and crack them and throw them in
the ground and need them. And then just,
it was a masterful ballet of violence.
It was a, uh, a beautiful performance,
an artistic expression of
who Anderson Silva is. Yeah,
he's a fucking artist when that guy does,
but people have a hard time accepting
the concept of an artist's attached to
something as violent,
as damaging a person.
But it's just because they're looking at
it wrong that it's not a violent act in
the sense of normal violent acts where
somebody find someone that picks on them
or starts a fight with him for no reason.
It's a contest of great
significance and repercussion.
That's what it is.
You looking at it as violence because it,
those techniques can be used in a violent
act and even though it's violent and
it's description,
it's not an act of violence and it's an
act of competition and the expression of
character.
That's why the best fights move.
Souls changed lives. Dude,
start jogging. I mean, it just,
you see that expression of character
when somebody really puts a training camp
together and really develops their skills
to the point where they're at a Manny
Pacquiao level or you know,
some someone that like sugar
ray Leonard was that chick.
That's that kind of shit.
That's art. That's art.
I agree with you.
I think it is or I think,
and I think seeing that kind
of passion in people in,
no matter what genre they're in,
you know, we could, you know, is,
is hugely motivating.
Hugely inspirational. You
know, every single day, ah,
sorry this, this circling it back. But
every single day alone in the wilderness,
I would sit on the edge of a lake about
just film day three of survivor man or
whatever.
And I would say to myself,
whatever it is I do let result in being
inspirational to somebody's life and,
and affect them in a positive way.
And then I would stop that and I would
think of, don't be an idiot last you just,
you make in a shelter who it's
what's inspirational about that.
And then I started getting
these emails from people.
You got me through eight months on my back
in a hospital bed watching your shows.
My son and I were a strange,
but because of your shows,
we got back together again. I left an
abusive relationship because he shows,
because of my shows. All I'm doing
is building a freaking shelter.
And so when you connect to it, I don't
just go, when you go like with the,
with the fights as well,
it's the same when you see people in
embroiled passionately in what they
passionately in what they do.
Like Silva, like so many others,
you can't help but be inspired by it.
I think an effected by it.
That's a fascinating,
I think those people that are saying
that you're changing their life,
it's probably the government trying to
get close to you and then just true.
That's normal now I'm, I'm, I'm
a Canadian. They don't care.
But I think they will try
to get closest in Canada.
You most certainly changed
people's idea of, of uh,
how thin like are a attachment
to surviving really is
like how little we really
know and how much we're dependent on
this whole system that we have set up the
cities and delivering food.
I used, I did a show once a, um, I'm
sorry, discovery channel. I love you,
but I'm so embarrassed by the show he did,
which was surviving urban disasters and
primarily because I didn't produce the
show. I, I, and, and I, and
I regret it to this day. Um,
and it was all about how to survive
an urban disaster, right? You know,
fill like a bathtub with water,
that sort of stuff. Um, you know,
just all sorts of little tricks and tips.
And now nowadays you can bet every time
there's a hurricane sandy or anything
like that,
I get phone calls from the new centers
if I'll go on and do an interview about,
we know what people need to know about
surviving to the stuff, you know,
and it still amazes me to this day though,
just how lacking in common sense I think
most people are, you know, it's like,
well, you know, it's hurricane
coming. Like, think of it,
think about the same thing.
Survivorman oh, is as shelter,
food and water. What else?
You got to think about whether
or not you're gonna be able to,
they call of duty that night, you
know, shelter, food and water, man.
Uh, you, unfortunately for a lot of
people that seems like an abstract idea.
It doesn't seem to be really
registering in their head.
The idea that you could have no food
and no water like their whole life.
It's true in supermarkets,
go to the store, get your
food, go to the restaurant,
get your food.
The idea of it is abstract.
Hey, I take every once in
a while I'll do, you know,
one of those corporate things and I'll
take some people up. They got one night,
one night overnight and if
freaking, you know, I mean,
people go four hours without food. I
mean my son will say, oh, I'm starving.
And I was like, dude, seriously,
you got to Ron's father to
say I'm starving to attack.
It gives you been four hours without a
hot dog. Like relaxing, you know? Yeah,
no shit. What's the longest you've
gone without eating? Uh, probably, um,
10 days I guess. Whoa. Few pine
nuts and things thrown in there.
Maybe a frog or two. So, I
don't know if that's, that was
one of the, one of the, no,
that was actually before survivorman
really now with the new, well
I guess with the new shows,
yeah,
I guess in Mexico I got a squid I found
and some clams and some stuff like that.
And then Norway, I get the deer
carcass. So there's a few things,
but founded deer carcass. Yeah. Well it
was one of those things where, I mean,
I knew there was hunters up
there. I mean, I knew them.
I knew there'd be hunting
going on up there.
I knew they would probably
be carcasses left around,
up in that area where I was going to
be. So, so I did, I wasn't set up,
but I knew that, that that potential
was there. Um, and sure enough, I, I,
I traveled around and found a hunter's
cabin, which was part of surviving, right.
D and e is doing a good be any as
part of survival sometimes. Right.
And it'd be stupid if you stayed outside.
So I know I,
it's ethically wrong to go through that
window. I will just freeze out here. Um,
and there was a deer carcass there. Oh,
someone had shot it and left it there.
Left the, the guys take some of it out.
So it was all, all the meat was gone.
It was just the cup,
the guts and stuff.
But there's a lot of food when you've
got it. I'm going to the liver.
You left the liver. It's like that
big Norwegian dear liver. Oh Wow.
Do your livers. Delicious.
Very proud of that show.
That was the first 10 days when the
Norway one does frogger to taste any
different? Well I don't, I
wouldn't, I don't eat toad
actually. Yeah. Really? Yeah.
I haven't had towed at all. So coming
frog. Hmm. He never had a toad. I Dunno,
I will next show a few. Is it, I mean,
take it in with me as far as how
they're related. Told to drive. It.
Will toad toads are dry
land and it's a dry land.
Amphibian and frogs are water amphibians.
But do people eat both?
Probably the biologist somewhere going,
oh dude, there's getting it so wrong.
Probably we ever, I don't
know. I've never heard of it.
And it told you been a toast?
No.
I grew up with a lot of toads in Ohio
Gi and I don't know, I didn't eat them,
but anybody had kissed him alive.
But I don't see him anymore.
Anyone become a prince? No, I
don't think. Is that that? No,
I think you just get like black dude.
If he kicks the toad
frog turns into [inaudible] frog legs.
That's very common.
But they do taste like chicken.
I don't think people eat toad,
but somebody is going to get right
in down into someone's eating them.
There's people eating a lot of
shit out there. When I was in,
I remember when I was in Costa Rica and
I was setting up to do the Costa Rican
survivor man show,
and this was before the show started and
we're standing is a little hut and it
was upstairs and I hear this
person walking up the steps.
It was a big foot. Costa
Rican, bigfoot? No, no.
He's not in the jungle at finally as
freaking me out. So I take my flashlight,
I go around. It was a frog
the size of us of a, of a,
like a saucer pan. And he was
going up the steps clump. Wow.
Clump. This isn't massive.
Costa Rican frock. Huge guys
are gigantic down here now.
That would be a good meal. I love
toads. Steak dinner. Um, would,
would you have eaten that?
Yeah.
If I'd find him a week later when I was
filming survivor, man, I want him to kill.
That's a big fucking, no, we probably
just, they don't sound like a Hollywood.
They don't have fangs or anything.
Is Anybody died from frogs? Uh,
well, and they also, they have the
poison tip frogs in Costa Rica. And what
is the deal with those? This is the
poison on their skin. You touch that,
touch it to your eye. You're dead. Whoa.
There's a lot of shit in the rain forest
that's designed to get rid of people.
I know. Did you, uh, you stayed in
the Amazon? I'm sure the Amazon.
I tell you the thing about the Amazon is
just so much there that's poison us and
it's not, you know what it's, it is.
It's not the snakes. It's not
the spiders, it's not Jaguar,
it's not other creepy crawlies.
It's the aunts every time it's the ants,
the ants or the worst part of
the jungle because they're just,
there's so many of them and
they all hurt like hell.
And the bullet ants are worse.
The bullet ants are like,
he gets stung by pulling out, first
of all, it's bomb is like a wasp.
And then he's got a big
teeth on the front end.
It's about two inches long.
And what it does is it sinks its teeth
into you and then it shoves its bumps
sting or into you.
And they say it's like taking a
scorching red hot pair of pliers,
jamming it into your skin,
squeezing as hard as you can,
twisting as hard as you can and
holding that for five hours. Oh,
and that's a bullet ant staying. Yeah.
And you can Google these, the, the, uh,
if it's the, the what?
Ani people and different,
they actually have a a coming of age
thing where the young men take a glove,
they build a glove out of twigs and
they trap on the glove like 30 of these
ants. And the other thing is you have
to shove your hand into the claw. Yeah,
we played it on the pog saw that, I
believe we played it. But yeah, we tents.
It's insane.
The amount of like disconnect that
you must have to have the tolerance.
Six of those things can bring
a full man full grown man down.
He can put them out. But think
the God, the show that I watched,
I think the host tried it.
I think the host good. Yeah.
I think it was some English guy.
Let himself get Jack by the bullet ants,
if I remember correctly.
The other was a bunch of young men has
doing it as a rite of passage. Yeah,
that's, there's a lot of that. I
mean what I did beyond the Syria,
did you see the series
beyond survival nicely? Okay.
So you got to check that out
because that was, you know,
that was a series I did where survived
around the world with remote indigenous
peoples. And I did ceremonies. I got
tattooed with a stick and a nail.
Where was that a in um,
by the mentor.
Why in Sumatra and the Tattoo on the
side too that it's like sticking a nail.
That was Britain. Then I did Voodoo
ceremonies, a seats, ceremonies,
trance dances, uh, all the stuff
I did around the world. And um,
and we did a plant
medicines in, uh, in, uh,
the Amazon jungle with the
Incan people in the [inaudible],
the Watani and that it was very,
very intense series.
I can't remember why I went to
that series, but in any event, uh,
it showed a lot of these crazy ass
ceremonies and combined with survival,
so are the split,
the distinction was made between
spiritual survival and physical survival.
And they said that I
went there to learn why,
what's their spiritual survival in the
jungles and deserts and places like this.
And so they all was these wicked
ass ceremonies where they are connecting
to the ancients and connecting to the
earth and, and, and learning
how to survive, but doing
all these things, you know,
as well. And so I got to partake in
a lot of the ceremonies and do them.
That was pretty intense.
So that series,
the reason why half soft said this
is the behind the scenes crop,
but the reason why beyond survival,
it did very well aerated very well.
The problem was they didn't
put my name in the title.
I know that sounds horribly pretentious,
but I said,
look at once you're flicking the dial
and you're looking at the screen and it's
got all the different shows listed
and you see beyond survival,
but you don't see less
Stroud's beyond survival.
He just going on and you're gonna Watch
CSI. It's true. You don't. But if they,
if they'd said less jobs beyond survive,
all the survivor man fans would have
gone. Ah, okay. That's funny that,
that's like an egotistic thing to
say. I know it is. It's right. Yeah.
So you're supposed to say it. It's
like one of those things where you at?
You're right though. It's
unquestioned. Like for me personally,
if I saw beyond survival,
probably wouldn't.
But if I saw less Stroud's beyond
survivor, like, oh survivor man, dude,
I'll check that shit out. You
could have like, you know,
a UFC podcast or something, something
podcasts. But Joe Rogan's names not in it.
It's like, oh well maybe I might listen
to my, check it out and then I see,
oh it's Joe Rogan's you have see
podcasts. Oh, I can check that out.
We should totally do that.
But I would probably get sued.
The problem is to shift that.
I can say on this podcast,
I don't want to like connect that with
the UFC has a different task and then so
then I'd have to like tone myself
down when I'm fucking ruin it.
Steevo was the one that, by the way,
they did the bullet and glove. Yes. Oh,
Steven did an on an on. Wild boys are
jackass. Crazy wild boys. And he also,
he also put him, I remember that,
but it put him in the hospital. Yeah.
Fucking weird. Have you ever encountered
a Brazilian wandering spider?
No. He never heard of it? No.
Oh my God. Really? No. I'm
going to Brazil in December.
Oh Jesus.
To the Brazilian wanderings party.
You've got to look this up cause it's a
spider that stings you and first of all,
it gives you the most unbelievably
painful erection cause it it shock jolts
your,
your production of nitric
oxide and injects it in some
sort of a venom form from
this spider and you,
you get like literally die with a hard on,
like your whole body stiffens
up and if you do survive,
it's the most toxic spider known to man.
And if you do survive, really? Yeah.
If you do survive your Dick's dead
forever, your sexuality is ruined.
It's called a Brazilian wondering spider.
It's unbelievable man to be a lot of like,
I don't know,
I think they're trying to uh,
figure out how to use its venom
to make the next hard on drug.
They're going to make something that
just cruise 70,000 Jaeger. Right?
And the Dick. Yeah, that's the baby.
I took some spider tonight and it wanders
on the floor. There it is right there.
Is that it? Yeah. Yeah. That motherfucker
will kill you with a boner. Mm.
I bet this guy. We'll explain that so
you don't think I'm crazy. That's a mean.
Let's see. Look at the spider.
It's still not entirely sure about
pack it up because it'll tell you about
what it does to men and scientists a
little bit before bitten by this beast.
You're going to end up
with a very painful,
long lasting erection and scientists
are still not entirely sure about the
effects on women.
The male brain actually mistakes the
chemicals in the spider venom for the
chemicals that the male brain normally
use this to trigger an erection and the
bizarre symptoms.
Now consider this.
This little spider has been doing that
kind of thing for millions of years.
Man has only just designed a drug
that does broadly the same thing. Now,
how lucky was that?
He's way too obsessed with boners.
I'm obsessed with that being a terrifying
fucking way to die. Die with a boner.
That's the thing. I mean, you know,
there's things down in the Amazon
jungles where Brazil, it's,
when I was down there, I was training off
the, what Ani and we'd learn to survive.
He was telling us a story through an
interpreter. He had actually, uh, was,
uh, a blowgun hit, uh,
a monkey up in the tree.
I had to climb up the tree to get the
monkey 60 feet in the air and he just said
the canopy, right? So
he just barely graze,
just brushed a caterpillar.
And the electric jolt was so powerful
that it jolted him right out of the tree
and down 60 feet. Oh my God. And he
didn't break a single bone in his body,
but he spent weeks, two weeks in the
hospital and his entire body was black,
just went black total black color,
just blow everything black. And uh,
they found one entomologists that was
in Brazil that had an anecdote antidote
for that caterpillar.
I mean,
so the stuff that's in the Amazon
jungles just bizarre. It gets,
it still freaks me out. I go down there
and like I said, but it's the ants.
I'm getting the crawl, the itchies
thinking about it. It's the,
it's the answer I always get to me when I,
yeah.
My friend Brian Callen wanted to be
a naturalist and he spent one summer
vacation,
uh,
or a will or a trip rather in school where
they went to the rain forest and they
had a sleep on these uh,
these elevated platforms that they would
cover the posts with like chemicals to
keep the ants off of it. And he said
when you were up there sleeping,
you could literally hear
the ants wall walking.
That's right. Yep. That's right.
They, there's so many of them.
That's what you need here.
That's like a fucking,
it's not fun.
There's nothing fun about trying to
sleep on the floor in the Amazon jungle
through that shit.
I'm not,
I'm not even sure how I did the
shows I did do down down there.
Cause sometimes I think about going
down again to do like a, you know,
a 10 day thing. And I think, man,
I don't know if I was just like lucky
the first couple of times cause I'm going
to get down there and one wrong
move and I've got, you know,
a fertile on snake or a spider or
a poison dart frog or a bullet at,
you know, and if, and I was sleeping
on the ground the whole time. Right.
So you didn't make any kind of structure
or anything? Yeah, I slept off the,
off the ground by about a foot
and a half on poles. I mean,
you know the answers of care,
the answer above your head.
And it was a walking from
chain tree. Yeah. And they're
big, big, big. Those bullet answers
so big. You only get 60 in a nest. Oh,
it's how big God, you know. And I saw
a man at one point, I saw six in a row.
I thought I gotta be near a
nest somewhere. Oh God. So
it's, yeah, that I got admit,
I mean the Amazon jungle
on the other hand,
I love the Amazon jungle and I don't
know if that's the Tarzan thing or what,
but I just loved the jungle. It's must
be so excited. Our full lie. Beautiful.
Dangerous. Yeah. Yeah. It's
really beautiful down there.
They see that Amazon, um,
that uh,
rather ants can actually
take out elephants and that
if a sufficient amount of
ants find a trail to the elephants ears,
they will literally crime up in
elephant's leg and eat him from the ears,
climb into his ears and just start
eating his brain. I don't know. Yeah,
that sounds,
that sounds like the craziest fucking
thing I've ever heard in my life.
But I know that ants,
if you're lying on the ground,
like there's certain army ants that
will fuck you up. People die from them.
You don't think I got bitten by a
couple of army ants. I was trying,
I saw them going across in a
stream and I wanted to film them,
a stream of ants and I, and I and I,
I put the camera down and you know,
about three or four inches from
the stream of that, no big deal.
They're just keep walking across in front
of my lens and I get this cool shot of
the ants going by. I literally put it
down just as I barely touch the ground.
I swear to you,
the ants from over there jumped over
like jumped onto the camera in my hand.
Like boo boo, boo boo like
that. I was like, wow.
And I instantly bit my hands like
they just started attacking. Yeah,
they just attacked. These are men,
they're big ass army ants too. So,
and then on the other hand, we had some
aunts come through the hot one night, uh,
beforehand. And, and the way that we,
they were going under my hammock and
what we did was we took a fire and we
scraped the ground in front of them with
a fire to break cause they all travel
on pheromones. It's all done
through pheromones, scent, right?
They follow each other on the pheromone
trail and you have to break that trail
with fire.
And we were guiding them and so they made
a new trail because we guided them to
go over this way and away from the hut.
That's, I was showing that by the Adani,
which is just using the fire thing.
Right? Cause saw pheromone instinct.
That's why if you've ever seen,
if anybody's ever seen those youtube
videos of the spiral of death,
they lose the scent of whoever
the fuck is in the lead.
And they just spiral around in a circle
until they starved to death. Really?
What VMC Brian?
It's crazy.
Spiral love video of ant death spiral.
This is going to freak you out.
They've never seen this before. This is
a, it's a rare occurrence apparently.
But the ants get confused
when they're, uh, they're,
they lose a cent and they don't
know who the fuck they're following.
And they get in these,
they look like hurricanes.
They're getting these spinning hurricanes
of ants and then they spin in a circle
until they all died. Yeah. It's called a
death spiral. It's fucking fascinating,
man. It's, it's rarely filmed. It's not
that common, but that's it right there.
Look at that there. That's essentially,
that looks to me like a galaxy.
It looks like a hurricane. It looks
like, you know it's craziness.
If you've never seen it,
you have to Google it because it
doesn't even seem like it's real.
It's this insane amount
of ants and at the top,
in the middle rather in the center.
There is so many of them that
they're piled up like many,
many times over like 10 20 ants high and
they're all just trampling each other.
And why do they think they think
it's because it's a pheromonal thing.
There's one error.
Yeah,
there's an error and they don't
know what they lost their scent.
They don't know what the fuck doing. Ah,
seriously man. Billy doesn't know the way.
Yeah. Yeah. I know the way guys who'd
I know where I'm going and trust me,
it's a fascinating thing to watch though,
cause an error that nature.
That's a thing. I've, I've been
really super fortunate with the,
all the film work that I've done is,
is,
has been to see the beauty that I've
seen. You know, the Andes mountains,
the Amazon jungle dude, your big
foot stores still freaking me out.
I gotta be honest, that 50 foot away.
How will they ape while you're asleep,
you're in this tent. Jesus Christ
man. When you're in Alaska,
G. U. E Z, that's the,
that to me is the ultimate.
If I had like one,
one question that I could ask where I
could find out like one truth about the
world, I would ask about big. Really. If
you could talk to God said, come on dude.
Is there anything out there?
Come on. I would be it, you know,
I would ask about this life.
I would ask about like an afterlife.
Maybe if I hadn't like looking
towards the dirt on the squatch man,
I wouldn't want to know.
Dude.
I need to know is big foot reel and Ufos
I would have to go with Ufo was before
big foot, but the right up there with
me both would make me equally happy.
You see that knew the meaning of
life. Have you ever seen, sorry,
have you seen that new footage in Denver,
Denver where they actually like the
television channel went down to actually
check it out? Yeah. Yeah. That's fucked
up. We don't even know what that is. Yeah.
But you know,
you can,
there's a lot of military shit going on
in Denver and guess what? They don't,
they don't tell those people
nothing. You know, when,
when you find out that there's the,
the,
the idea is that in the next decade
there's going to be 30,000 drones flying
above the s the city streets,
30,000 in this country. Um,
you don't think they
might just start that now?
Like what do they have
to wait until 10 years?
They already have like permission
to put drones anywhere they want.
So when I see, when I see something
that's floating over a city, bunch of,
a few people film it,
I'm like,
this is probably some government
shut they're working on.
I think a lot of that stuff
is pretty, you know, if you,
if you don't get caught up
in it, conspiracy theory
is fascinating. You know,
I listened to it lots of times.
I'll be doing a long drive from Toronto.
I'll throw on a George Norris
coast to coast and check that out.
I was actually on at one time where you
really, yeah, it was like a color in.
Did you ever talk to art bill?
No, I was talking. It was George.
He's the Oji doorbell shows were special
because art bell never questioned it.
No matter how fucking crazy you were.
And Call it art.
I'm aware of Wolf really
for how long he would put.
How did you get bitten? Where
were you? Tell us your story.
I think I would tell you some story about,
it was in Romania.
It was on a hunting trip.
It's good am radio in the middle, in
the middle, like two in the morning,
drive it home in a long,
dark night and you're just
listening to that stuff in my past.
And he introduced me to a Terence
Mckenna in a way because one of the first
Terence Mckenna recordings I've ever
heard was someone had taken a, um,
one of the, uh, art bell
shows and put it on mine.
It was like from the 90s and a,
it was a Terence Mckenna from Hawaii on a,
uh, like a wireless, a radio
spectrum Internet connection.
It was really fascinating.
So our bell had like some really
interesting people on a show as well as
Wackadoos who were like
playing conversations
backwards to find like hidden
meaning. And what someone
was trying to say is a spice,
but when they bring in like those, those
MIT guys and, and some of these, you know,
big thinkers and it's pretty fascinating
to listen to these people talk and it's
like, oh, this is so and so.
And he's just like, you know,
as sat is 10,000 or I don't know, I don't
know what you call it in America but,
but uh,
it's just super huge intelligent people
and it's pretty fascinating to hear them
go through and the covering all the
different basis of conspiracies, man,
let's just do, it doesn't
sound like a Wacko, you know,
then you get the phone callers.
That's a different story when you get
the phone calls in that slack. Yeah.
Well my grandfather is an alien.
I can prove it. Yeah. There's
dudes will call. He had a, a line,
if you could call that line,
if you were from the future,
it would give that line out.
If you're a time traveler,
there's a time traveler line.
If you've splitting out a time,
you're just asking for assholes. Okay,
come on man. How many time travelers are,
they really didn't,
they need their own line and then you
finally get through and the answer, man,
your line was busy the whole time.
It was busy a long time.
I've been calling for 47
years. It was busy. Yeah.
Why couldn't you go back in
time to when it wasn't busy?
Don't you have a good time machine
or is it just the one shot deal?
If time travel does happen, yeah you're
going to be able to do it all the time.
Or was it like a one you get one shot at
it and then there's no time machine if
you go back in time. So you know,
that's a way to think about it.
And then you have to choose where you go.
Which area. Going into other dinosaurs,
you going to be like the 60s.
What would you do if you could do,
say if there was a time machine that
could put you for one week in a era,
the Paleolithic Jurassic, like you could,
you could live at one point in time.
Could humans live during the dinosaur
era? Was it too hot? How hot was it?
I don't know. I think, you know, when you
see like the new version of King Kong,
every time I saw a dinosaur moving,
I always thought the same thing.
How come they never show really
big ass killer insects? And, uh,
finally when they did the new King Kong,
they got attacked by all this as like
if finally that's it right there.
That's what it would be like.
You'd be a human and you get
eaten by like a dragon fly.
Cause the dragon fly would
be, you know, this big. So I
don't know. I think I don't,
I have no idea.
I'm sure there's paleontologist right
now just like rolling their eyes going,
Ah man, he's idiots don't know
what they're talking about. Dude,
if you could go back in time with the
fucking camera and film you surviving
around dinosaurs, that would be the
dopest show in the history of the world.
If they invent a time machine
within the next five years,
promise me you will do survivor man,
Jurassic.
You would probably benefit from a
time where she, more than any buddy,
except people would like steel
gold and hide it someplace.
Then know where it is in the future.
Those people would benefit the most.
But if you could keep it
ethical, you would, you would
benefit more than anybody.
You could be able to go back to a fucking
dinosaur era and make of a show. Yeah.
What would you do? You'd have
to hide in the ground. You know,
I ain't go hang out with,
go ahead and hang out with the
brontosaurus cause they're like,
we know they're gentle.
Yeah. But they're sorting.
Things are just going to step on your
head while you're sleeping. Problem.
Steven Spielberg, they were nice.
They probably weren't though.
They probably were 10 at all.
Steven Spielberg, man, he
wants to make aliens nice.
Everybody's, everybody's nice
with that guy. Yeah. The, uh,
the t rex in Jurassic Park.
I will never forget that scene where the
kids were in that truck and the t rex
comes over the fence and the,
what's really amazing,
and that was like one of the first
movies that you really utilize Cgi to the
point where you got a realistic sense of
what an animal like that would be built
like, and what it would
be physically capable of.
It's so hard to think that
that was all over the planet.
Like they had a bunch of different kinds,
you know, enormous. Actually right now,
you know,
all the Donald Digs they've done,
they've only actually found 10% of what
they figure actually existed. And like,
so we've got 10,000 dinosaurs
that they know about,
but there's hundreds of thousands of
mammals on this planet that we know about
it. So they're just scratching the surface
of the file of what was here. I know,
but I think as, as humans, if
we walked in dinosaur time,
I mean the bottom line is we'd
be, we'd just be fodder. Yeah,
they'd get us too quick.
But I love the fact that there's people
possess to study that and it gave me
that information.
I am so appreciative of that because
if it was up to me to find out how long
dinosaurs, there's a scene, there's
a scene right there. Put the t rex.
God, Dan, that was terrifying.
It seems so realistic, man.
You just put music on this.
You son of a bitch style with Brian.
I know what you're doing.
Look at that fucking thing.
I'll still watch this movie
just for just for this.
I'll watch this movie
for fucking movie rules.
That thing is so
the idea that this,
this planet had a fuck load of those
running around at one point in time.
Boy, we are so lucky that
that asteroid hit the Yucatan.
We are so fucking lucky.
Could you imagine how about this?
You're on the fucking
highway in this thing.
Steps up and flips a cab over in front
of you and you're just hitting the gas.
It's like people who live around
mountain lions to go, well, you know,
we have to respect the fact that they
were always here. The fuck you do.
Let it kill that dinosaur son. Things
going to eat everybody. We're so lucky.
Those things aren't here anymore.
While we wouldn't be if they were,
that's for sure. I wonder if people
would try to bring them back though.
If they were here and we killed them off.
People are so dumb.
They would try to bring them back.
Pull the drastic thing. Yeah.
Well they're doing that thing
with the crocodiles in Florida.
They were almost done.
There were almost no scary monsters that
like eat dogs and jump up on fucking
boardwalks and snatched dogs from six
feet in the air and now they're bringing
back the crocodile population and they,
they're eating dogs now in Florida
and one of them pulled the dog off,
a six foot doc jumped out of the water
and snatch this dog right in front of
their friends. But we, I mean we
had saltwater crocs and floor,
we have saltwater approximately in yeah,
crocs in Florida cause they all hover
around the edge of the edge of the
everglades, but they were on the
brink of extinction. But you know,
you know when the python two right?
Yes.
That's huge problem down there that we've
shown the picture of the python eating
the alligator showing like 10 times
on this show. It's because it's so,
so wrap your head around that.
It's eating a fucking alligator.
Like that's how crazy these snakes are.
Like Pete,
that's like that Jennifer Lopez movie.
I remember that. That movie, Anaconda,
Anaconda, Yay. Literally like, I mean,
not quite that bank but pretty fucking
close. It's eating an alligator.
It's an alligator. And its Bot,
which basically by extrapolation,
if it can eat an alligator like that,
it can eat you. Fuck yeah, can eat you.
When I was doing a whole the shark
week shows and we were down and we'd be
diving with all the different sharks,
I tell you there's all the sharks in the
world and then there's the great white
shark and it's a different beast
altogether. It's just like a big truck,
a big bus with a mouth on the front end.
And the thing about the great whites, uh,
I had uh, I was in a
cage, I had it rammed.
It was an 18 foot great
white came up and Oh my God,
when you see the other sharks coming,
you get that classic sort of sharp
movement, you know, side to side movement.
When a great white,
it just sort of,
it's just this big feeding tube in the
water and it just moves slowly towards
you. And it, at the one point I
was in a, I was in a solo cage and,
and this 18 footer we were
calling it the megalodon.
It came and it came
slowly, slowly, slowly,
slowly and right towards me and just
all he did was like bump my cage,
like a little bump with his nose,
but of course that he's 18 feet.
It was like Bam crap, you
know, and throws me back and I,
and I was in the cage and
I had this much space.
I had like four inches in front
of my face that I could actually,
that's all the distance I had.
And so I had a great mouth,
great white mouth like right.
They're four inches in front of your
four inches in front of my face.
Shooting that shooting the great white
scenes for shark week was one of the most
exhilarating things.
Abigail. It's intense.
God and P and all the shark divers out
there and they know how beautiful is to
dive with the sharks.
I've,
I've hand-fed most of the
species ridden on the backs of
your hands. Got a great white,
I hand fed a great, what
the fuck is wrong with you man?
Have we not learned enough
from the crocodile hunter?
Yeah, well those are stingrays.
Well, it's all, I mean,
it could. It was a sting ray that
got them. But I mean that kind of,
he really handled everything
dangerous crocodile. I remembered the,
the picture was feeding a crocodile
is holding this baby. Yeah, that was,
he took a lot of heat for
that. Rightly so. That's crazy.
You got a God damn 20 foot dinosaur in
front of you and you're also holding a
baby. I don't like to be around dogs.
I'm holding a baby, you know? Yeah, yeah.
You know, you're like, I don't
know that dog get Outta here.
This guys got a crocodile
and it's his idea.
It's not that just wandering
through the woods. Oh Shit.
I was with my baby and I saw a croc about
what to do. Luckily I had a chicken.
I threw it the crocodiles way
and distracted. I know this guy.
Luckily I had this chicken.
Not for that. Crikey.
Sometimes those really big sharks can
break those cages, can't they? Well,
we had one great white that, uh, they
were bringing in so I could film.
I'm with a camera man and I got a camera
trying to film this great white and uh,
it's a big fella and they were bringing
it in close to the cage and they're
doing it with a rope and a fish head and
they're not supposed to let the great
white get ahold of the fish head because
then all hell will break loose because
he's got the big thick rope and it's
attached to the boat. Sure enough,
the great white gets a
full bite on the fish head.
And so we're now in the water in a cage
with a great white and shimmies around
and the great white gets in between the
boat and our cage. So we got a 16 foot,
17 foot great white shark that is
this wide as he's in front of me.
I mean that's a thing like, you know, the,
the girth of these beasts is incredible
and you see when you're under the water,
he could pretty much take me in one gulp,
like one gulp and they could do it.
That's the amazing thing of a
great white checked is so powerful.
And so he's in between
the cage and the boat.
And our cage was held on by
two ropes for goodness sake.
So we're in the water with a cage held
on by two ropes and the shark is Bam
crash, Bam crash. And if you
Google anything, you know
shark week, you could see it.
I forget which one it was a,
that was one.
That was one of the Times
I was really super, super
freaked out. I was like, look,
this is not good.
You know,
cause he's going to break the ropes and
we're going to cage is going to sink to
the bottom and we're going to like,
our ears are going to blow out as
we go down and the sharks out there.
So how we're going to have to hop out
of the cage where the great white is.
Oh it was insane.
It was insane.
Oh I long could you stay down there?
A cage went to the bottom of you?
It's combat. No, I think we were
attached by what they call hookah lines,
both align to the boat.
So we would've just,
it would've snapped who would have had
no where to blow out king way. Oh my God.
I tell you what happened to while we were
filming that this wasn't on the show.
I went down in the solo cage and
they slant, they slam the door,
like throw the door down at above me.
Right?
And I go down and they through the
door and it pinched my air hose.
So they're lowering me with my
air hose pitch and I'm under,
I'm Bam Bam.
And I'm punching as hard as I can at
the top of the cage because it's not
clicked right.
And I'm punching because they're me down.
I got nowhere and I've got a great white
going around dancing all around the
boat. I'm like, finally they
pulled me up. Oh Man. I, I they,
I ope that they opened the cage Huffman.
I jumped out, just tourist strip,
huge into the, into the guy who did
it. I just freaked out. Oh my God.
So it was just in common. Threw him
off the boat into the sharks accident.
Oh Jesus Christ. It was, but it
was like they have you on camera.
So they saw that you were freaking
out. No, no, we weren't filming it.
They were just lowering media
wasn't even,
I look at when we're
watching the checks ne Wow.
Oh that's me right there. That's when I
got bit. He's got my hand right there.
See right there. I still got the scar,
but that's just, that's just really a,
a little reef shark right there.
Not Bad.
So then mark the camera man, the
shark goes right up, is there,
I'm looking at right up into his,
got his hand in his mouth
as an underwater cinnamon.
Biggest danger we face is
the sharp that you don't see.
Oh my God. I could have ended
up serious transfigured,
but thanks to their chain mail suits,
they're able to preserve both my whole
life and thanks to I won him the narrate
everything.
I do go rogue and took a massive dome
before coming to the podcast studio,
thanks to Kale shakes and protein
made with hemp. It came out smoothly.
Frothy loads all over her face in a world,
in a room.
That guy was so cheesy, but
that video was awesome, man.
That was what happened to the guy.
How'd you get the shark off his arm?
He just pull out sort of thing.
So if you were in chain mail,
is that what that does?
That works with the reef sharks.
It doesn't work with lemon sharks.
Doesn't love tigers or any of
those cause they got picked it.
It works at the reef sharks
when they got small teeth. So,
oh fuck is that Brian's like wearing
a glove and having a of great wine.
Great Way. Fuck that. That
will take your leg off.
Apparently there's a lot of them
off the coast of San Francisco now.
They are beautiful beast man.
They're beautiful, beautiful animal.
You go down and you swim with a
great white, it's changes your life.
Look at the size of that thing. Are you
allowed to catch those? How's that work?
What's the, you know there
was a, you could shark fish.
I don't know about great whites.
I don't know what the rules are.
You've been hearing about all this
dolphins getting murdered and, uh,
is it Mexico or is somewhere somewhere?
No,
it wasn't by men or by people or
by the Gulf of Mexico. People man.
Murder, Rasor Cure. And like I'm a,
I'm a huge supporter of wrinkled
baron and it's filmed the cove,
which we showed all the Tai-chi Japan
where they were slaughtering. They still,
and they still,
they catch the dolphins and use them for
marine parks and they slaughtered the
ugly ones for food and they
just still corralled them.
There's that also work
with, uh, Rob Corddry,
Rob Stewart as a friend of mine.
He did the film Shark Water and
which exposed to shark finning.
I got up and spoke against
shark finning and stuff.
I actually live with some sharp fitters
when I was doing the beyond survival
serious,
I live with the sea Gypsies for a
while and they were in their off hours,
you know, they used to,
they were shark fenders.
The, the Shark Finning doesn't bother
me nearly as much as the dolphin thing.
I mean, it's fucked up that you're just
[inaudible] animals still bad in. Yeah,
it's fucked up.
But sharks are scary as shit.
I know we need a man. I mean
like you wouldn't wipe out
the wolves either. Right?
You need to write and uh,
I wouldn't wipe out to the wolves and
less I lived around them then I would go
check on them. Have you ever
had a wolf incident? Uh, no.
It just started,
started to scare me.
Over the last couple of years I've
been scared of basically all animals my
entire life and through the
streaks sock taking you.
I have taken you out when I do
survivor man. Big Foot. Yes. Dude.
I will fucking gladly go
with you and look for bellow.
Puts you on the other cliff. You can
sit over there on that. Rock would have,
do we get to bring tents at least? Yeah.
We'll take stuff you can eat. I don't,
yeah,
I don't mind the idea of going out
in the woods and look at for bigfoot,
if you're,
if you really believe that there's a spot
where there might be something and it
takes less than two weeks. Yeah. That's
what exactly what I'm doing. Okay.
You just had that moment of like,
shit,
what did I just thinking
about how long it would take,
how much time I could take off work
and stuff. You know, we could choose,
we get you to show. Yeah. Now where
would you go if you had your choice?
You would go to northern California.
The big thing is BC, Canada, BC, Canada,
where you brought already,
which is Alaska. That's
Alaska. But I think that'd be,
I don't know.
I should go back there actually.
But do you think there's areas where
there's more of them and what would you
base thing? So, uh, other
people who studied them,
they're all crazy. They're all,
there's this whack jobs out there for,
not all of them, but most all of them.
But most of them, not all of
them. Well, it's the end, by
the way. I'm an enthusiast,
you know, when I say that,
that they're all crazy. I'm
crazy too. Like I just don't,
I'm not base my whole life on it,
but like,
I want to watch that
finding big foot in there.
Like I've been hunting Sasquatch
for 25 years. Like, okay,
that's, that's fucked up.
You don't even have a video,
even a of him for 25. Yeah.
You need to get out of that. You
got your own TV show. Yeah. That's,
that's ridiculous. You definitely
need to take a different method,
that method of a going out for
one night without a camera crew.
I think survivorman method will
work when it comes to, yeah.
Not a lot of guys do. Willing to do what
you do, you know, and live like that.
We'll see. Of course if it, if
it had happened, it was real,
that'd be uh, that'd be
life changing. Yeah. If you
actually did find a Sasquatch,
you would be a change a lot.
Yeah. People would freak out.
You would go on a tour like the fucking
like buffalo bill and the wild west days.
Like the guy who shot to uh, Jesse
James. Yeah, something like that.
Now if you did the flex brother,
would you, if you, if you did find it,
like what would you want to get? What
you want to get a video? A photo,
but you wouldn't ever shoot one?
No, I, I, I suppose if it was me,
I'd like to get a very crisp
and clear and obvious video,
but when people believe that you'd
have to track, you know what,
when it came to the, the skunk ape,
they didn't believe about skunk, ape.
I think it's the Philippines
or Vietnam.
They didn't believe that in believe on
those massive ape now and Nana couple of
years ago, they got actual
video and it, all it is,
is video footage and now Rizek
there it is. There it is. You know,
it's kind of skunk ape. It's a,
it's a really big chimpanzee. Yeah.
You can Google it. I can't
remember where it, where it was,
but it's the same situation.
Nobody believed that it existed.
It was considered to be a myth, a
legend. This gigantic a champion. Then
there was a skunk ape.
I thought that's like a nickname
for bigfoot. Yeah, it is. Apparently
it might, it might be as well, but this
was to do with a particular chimpanzee,
Huh?
Yeah. The, I think the, um, there's
a nickname, unfortunately skunk, ape,
and then the skunk ape nickname is a,
it's a very popular,
and it's in reference to a
mythical animal from Florida.
And now this was a, I think
a, um, like Vietnam. Maybe,
maybe Phillip, he hitting on him.
Maybe I'll, okay, I'll try to find it.
Yeah. Cause that looks like big foot
stuff you've got going on there. Yeah.
That's what all this stuff is. This, uh,
when you look up a skunky cause I
remember when I was really into big foot,
I remember that was like one of the
nicknames that they called it the Florida
skunk ape.
Hmm.
Um, and this thing, they
didn't think it was [inaudible]
[inaudible] the silicon fish as well.
I mean they thought it was exist,
extinct for something like 500 million
years in the life out of school,
have them off the coast of Philippines
in New Jersey. You know, it's big,
huge fish, you know, or the,
the, uh, the giant squid. And
then a couple of years ago,
Japanese trawler brings up a squid that's
big enough to eat and kill a whale.
Did you ever see that video that
they got on one of the oil rigs?
It's an under really deep deep water
video of this squid that looks like
Brian. How dare you it the
squid looks like a crab.
It's the weirdest thing ever. It's a squid
with like crab like appendages. Yeah,
pull it, pull it up Brian.
Cause if anything is really,
it's all I ever sent real it's from,
it's just a weird type of squid
that we didn't know about.
Well are they still think,
I mean so much of the of the ocean has
not discovered terms of species. Um,
yeah. They said, what did they
call it? The squid crabs. Crab.
Like squid. How about
that? Crab like squid.
Okay. While you're doing that, why don't
we sit up and do another chimp to fuck.
Yeah. What does, what does this one,
it'd be like, this is my essence.
We're talking about conservation and I
think I'll sit right here. Danny. Yeah,
right there. Yeah. I
think I sit right here.
Yeah,
I can do it.
Okay. Here to Joe. You got to get
this set up like a recording studio.
Well we've never, we, you know it's very
rare that we have bad motherfuckers.
Like you actually have musical talent.
This is the thing.
You could see it right here. See
It on my laptop. Look at this.
Okay.
Less I'm watching. Oh you
can't see it. It's right here.
Look at it.
It looks like an alien.
I mean is that the freakiest thing you've
ever seen? That's a real thing. Yeah.
It's a real animal.
It's just an an undiscovered squid.
You know, that's the thing about
everybody having a camera these days.
We are going to start seeing
some pretty cool stuff. Yeah.
Courtesy of the Shell Oil Company.
Thank you. Shell will doing God's work.
Hopefully Bobo. We'll get some
camera. Yeah, I think Bobo.
He needs to be proven correct.
It would help them.
Hmm.
And what is this song,
sir?
All right.
Well,
so this is a,
sorry man,
I actually got to use some cheat sheets
here cause I haven't really played the
song live very much,
but it's a new song, uh,
on a new CD I recorded and um, I
played it recently, a in Ottawa.
We did sort of full band and we kind of
rocked it out and it really got a great
reaction. Um, but a lot of, I'd say like
a lot of the material that I'm doing,
you know, I mean it gets to starting to
be called Earth music. Uh, it's because,
you know,
I come by it honestly.
I mean I've survived in jungles and
deserts and forests and the big foot thing
going on and connecting to
the earth. So a lot of, um,
what I write about is that earth
music, you feel like, I mean,
I read that songs too,
right?
But,
but you were inspired by
your experiences in the wild.
That's it.
Powerful bass music. Let's
do this. And this is a,
this is a song called one giant farm.
Okay.
And normally we get,
let's see if we can work this out here.
We did the intro twice too.
[inaudible] hump
the dolphins.
Chill the way hills
bloodstains strip from your sales farmer,
florists,
pharmacies,
longline and strip mine with
these corporate farming.
Coporate fines will nothing left behind.
I know
this world is smaller now.
Don't ignore the bit of truth
is not one GI.
I'm fine,
Dale me when uh
oh wrong.
Tell me where now is my home.
My wilderness home.
Tell me.
Oh to hear the song.
Stop living blindly here.
What I say stem there.
Don't walk away.
Revolution is coming soon.
Children today won't be fooled.
I know
this world is smaller now.
Don't ignore the bit of truth
is not one.
Tell me when a Jan I wrong.
I wrong.
Tell me where now he is my home.
My wilderness.
Tell me.
Oh to hear the song.
The scene.
Okay.
Free the dolphins.
Save the whales and Breeza fill
up your sales love for forest.
I love mother
Earth Wall.
Shipley's
I know
I'm feeling stronger now.
Uh,
he,
the bit of truth
is not one giant
tail man.
When can I wrong?
Oh,
wrong.
Tell me when I,
his mom.
Aw.
My wilderness home to me.
Oh,
cool.
Tell me when I,
his mom.
Okay.
My wilderness home. Israel. Me.
Where now can I,
oh,
so I hear the song.
Thank you dude. You're fucking
serious musician. Thank you man.
This has got to be, is this,
Huh? Yeah. This has gotta be, um,
is it on now? It's on. Um, like such a,
a cool thing for you to be able to do
these gigs and you don't have to do it as
an unrecognized musician. If you could
do it as a guy that people already love,
they're already,
you know what love you from survivor man,
then they tune into it and you get to get
that wave of people that appreciate it
from that I, yeah, but you know
what? You're, that's, that's
the toughest part is, um,
you know what
people think,
you know,
here's the last survivor man's
coming into town to the local hall.
Oh is he going to tell stories as he gets
to see a keynote speaker and trying to
get people to understand,
no,
I'm going to knock your socks off off
with some kick ass music and I'm going to,
you're going to blow your minds was my
Monica and I'm going to tell some stories
from survivor man, intimate Q and a. Oh
you do? I do it too, man. I break it down.
I'll go in between a song, a land,
but again, questions and they're like,
you know what's the craziest place you
ever survive man and or you know that
show when and and I'll and I'll get right
down and then it's like you want me to
rock and roll a bit more like yeah,
start
up again.
Now I think we need a reality show about
you when you to follow you around doing
all that as well as a survivor. Shit, how
come we don't have that? Ah, well let's,
let's make that happen.
Yeah.
We're going to have to do surviving
reality with Les Stroud. Yeah.
You go
in and do shows as well. Yeah. That
mean why you can do something like that?
Why don't you have like one episode
where you do a kick ass show and then you
have to go live in the
woods for the weekend?
Like compliance one
eighties that's exactly it.
I mean I did a concert and
then we went down to Mexico,
Mexico to film survivor man. 10 days. It
was just like, wow, this is just weird.
Where did you go to Mexico?
What part of Mexico went to Tiburon
island also called Shark island actually.
Cause the hammer has a command
that was for the shark episode. No,
that was for a survivor man.
10 days. Last episode of shot.
Now when you go to Mexico,
like how dangerous is it for a bunch
of gringos with cameras traveled around
Mexico?
That's no problem at all. I mean if
you're hanging on the border towns,
it's a problem.
But you know,
we just went right down right to where
we had to get to and everybody was very
friendly, very nice. It
was no issues whatsoever.
So everybody gets worried about
like the violence in Mexico.
They should just chill her blown man.
And you know what happens when the media
gets ahold of stuff and they make it
sound like it's so crazy and
insane. It's like, well, you know,
people are getting killed other places
too, you know. Uh, it's just, it's,
it's where we went was just fine,
man, Ma rocked. It was great. I loved,
I love Mexican.
It's funny,
we'll talk about like third
world countries and places
that are devastated by
poverty and that the, uh, you know,
they talk about it like at some distant
faraway land and then you tell them that
in Detroit,
47% of the people can't read in Detroit.
That's not the middle of nowhere. That's
not a third world country in Detroit.
47% illiteracy rate. And
you go, Whoa, yeah, this is,
this is not well managed.
Yeah. There's a lot of nuttiness going on
in this system I think. I think, uh, if,
uh, my eyes really got open
from all my travel, you know,
I think people should travel,
you know,
and they should see what else
was going on out in that world.
Because while you go hang on in Sri
Lanka for a while and see what it's like,
it's a different world man.
Fuck that is on the other hand you could
also watch Brittany Spears in Sri Lanka
so it's, it's messed up. You know,
I remember being in in Thailand and
going down and this on this thing and
there's Brian Adams coming across the
speakers and I'm like, wow, really?
How could, I thought it was in
Thailand while I am in Thailand.
Thailand is a last refuge for the scumbag
in this country and this world rather.
It was like one right where it's like
okay to be a scumbag and all these
comebacks get together and they just
have found a place where it's and they
party every full moon. Fuck
yeah, they party every day.
I have a bunch of friends that have gone
to Thailand to train because there's a
lot of camps of multi-campus.
They'll take guys in and they
say it's an amazing experience.
I was in Thailand doing some stuff
there and just touristing and then I was
running everyday and everyday I ran.
I actually went up and ran,
but to the my training camp
and it's like, oh, this looks,
and there was a bunch of Canadians there.
It's like, it's five. I'm like, AH, no.
Really?
I hear it coming across the road.
It's like the blue dudes
where they're there, they all,
they all got the tattoos now
because it was, you know,
the thing down there that
and that style of thing. Yup.
They're survive man fans and that in
Thailand at him white tie training camp
is that style of tattoo that they do
similar. And because they're there,
they do a tap taps through town.
It's much spine,
sharp, sterile needles and
things like that. In the, in,
in where I did in Indonesia was a like a
rusty nail. Really? Yeah. It was nasty.
Did you get infected? Uh, no but,
but I, I don't know if I did really,
I guess I didn't for a while I did.
I went down and they rub it
off in the streams that hurts.
So rubbing brass and stuff all over
it and leaves and things in the,
in the water right after they've done it.
And what is the worst like infection or
disease or anything that you ever caught
while you were out? Yeah, a few lots,
but it's always the stomach, stomach
stuff from eating something fucked up.
I had one, one time, some parasite and um,
I remember it would,
it would leave these long
snake like leisure lesions
all the way around the roof
of my mouth and my tongue would be a
massive white and had to eat with a straw.
And I, and I went in, I checked off
all doctors and dentists and fun.
I go to this doctor,
he's a third world disease specialist
named Dr Keystone and Toronto.
Real cool guy, a great doctor. And I
go in, I opened my mouth and he looks,
he comes in,
he looks at my mouth and he's looking at,
and he's squinting his eyes.
He goes,
I have never seen anything like that
before. I'm like, ah, that's just,
that's a scene in a movie, man.
Oh Man. You know, of all people,
this guy's a number one third world is,
and it's like,
you don't know what this is. I'm screwed.
You know? So, ah, that was nasty.
That was like a year long. I had, it was
painful a year long. It lasted. Yeah.
Well until I got to him and sort of got
the pill and then he gave me some big
horse pills and that finally took care
of every once in a while though I feel I
feel stuff in my mouth and I ha,
I wonder if it's still in there somewhere.
Dormant stages because every once
in a while I feel things that are,
I are not there like that. You know, Jesus
said it was, I took, I should, I should,
I should just put this
on my Facebook sometimes.
I actually took a photograph of my
tongue and that when it was like, Oh,
put it up man,
come on Twitter.
Because I had to send it to the doctor's
a hair here as here it's it, it's,
it's bad today. Here click look. And
then I showed it to him, you know,
cause it would chat and you know what,
you know I talked about the snake,
like legions in the roof of my mouth.
That would happen over night.
So imagine that. It's like you
go to bed, you're Ruth was fine.
You wake up and it's like a snake or a
worm has been dancing around the roof of
your mouth all night.
It was at what was happening?
Was it like moving across your mouth?
I still don't know. It was just nasty.
So that that was, yeah. What
were the parasites? What
were the pill? I don't know.
They were just big ass
man. They were huge.
Oh God. And now, so
getting parasites in my,
my digestive tract and that's stuff
that we're, you know, worries me.
Even now to this day,
I always get traveler's belly too.
If I go somewhere and now because of
this, I like to just like, oh, here we go.
One time I was in a,
I think it was t Sri Lanka and I was
on the bathroom floor in the fetal
position. You know, coming out both
ends and the most pain I've ever felt.
I broken lots of bones,
but that's the most pain I've ever felt.
And it was just parasite, you
know, just digested parasite stuff.
That's the stuff nobody sees when I'm
out there being survivor man, you know,
that don't see that stuff.
What does that show the,
uh, the enemy within or something like
that. There's a show about parasites. Um,
it's all about people that don't
know what's wrong with them.
And then they find that a
parasail fucking massive.
Paris has have grown a nest in their
brain if they start doing wacky shit and
seeing things and hearing things,
and they finally go to a doctor and
that he remembered that time you went
swimming in that lake in Africa and yeah.
Shit. Crony here. Scary Stat.
This is a true Scott to stat.
There's more,
uh,
cells on us that are not
our own that are ours.
Yeah.
So if you add up all the parasites and
all the things walking on her skin and
all the little critters,
there's more cells making up all of those
critters that are inside and out of us.
Then we have that our actual own body.
That's insane.
I was joking. I was thinking one time
I was, my theory is that, you know,
every once in a while he'd be like,
Oh and you got to like scratch your head
or something. Like, oh scratch your arm.
Like for why? Boy, my theory is that,
well that's one of those little critters
like he like bit you or something,
you know, that's exactly what it is. Cause
you're crawling with stuff man. Yeah.
You really were just cry my, you know,
go Microsoft. We are crow were oozing.
We really are like an ecosystem.
Totally.
And that's one of the things that people
don't understand. Like one of the,
I always talk about the
benefits of probiotics on Mike.
You got to keep healthy
bacteria in your body.
Acidophilus for grapplers
it's really important.
Acidophilus is very important because
it fights off ringworm cause it's a very
aggressive bacteria. Acidophilus
says and uh, as is, uh, the Kombucha,
Kombucha is really good for
that as well. It keeps, uh,
keeps you from getting ringworm,
but the,
nobody really thinks about
the idea that you have.
Like there's this whole ecosystem going
on in your body that you have to support.
Like you can't just eat Twinkies yet.
It support
this ecosystem. I'm a huge, I'm a huge
believer in fasting and cleansing. Yeah,
huge. I think you know the, the,
the idea is this is, you know,
as long as you're eating that pizza or
that awesome falafel I had at your pita
pita place around the corner,
that was awesome.
And if that's some of the best
hummus falafel, so if you're,
as long as you're eating,
your stomach is like working its ass
off and when you cleanse it's just like
your stomach just goes, ah,
thanks man. Thanks dude.
I needed and they just,
it just gives you stomach a break.
And I'm a big believer in going in
the mornings. You know what I'm doing?
Well I'll go in the mornings,
I won't eat for awhile until I get
the stomach growls. Not a good thing.
You want the stomach to grow
because when you get to that stage,
it's now working on itself. It's like,
okay, you gave me a break this morning.
He didn't shall bacon and eggs down there.
So I'll tell you what,
how about I work on some stuff that's
been sitting over here in the corner for a
while and it just, it's
your system, you know,
so cleansing and fasting just
revitalizes your body. And when I,
when I would do, I do a, uh, there was
one point when, so many programs, right?
One of the ones I liked was called eating
alive, Dr Maths and out of Vancouver.
And I'll tell you by day six
of this eating to cleanse,
I felt like a prize fighter.
Now I was just walk around the house,
don't want him to hit on the bags
because it's like, and I feel good
and all because I stopped, you know,
shocking my stomach and pushing the hell
out of my stomach with pizza and crap.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well there's a lot of stuff that people
eat that your body's really just not
designed to process. And that's the
whole idea behind the Paleo Diet.
I said grains and especially like the
modern grains are just really not supposed
to be like eating giant pieces of
bread now. But it tastes so good.
That's fresh spaghetti.
So delicious. So yummy.
Fried cheese tastes ricotta. You know,
you know what I crave when I'm out there.
What? Fried Cheese Pizza. The
fried cheese pizza. Because I just,
my fat reserves start to
diminish and I think I want fat.
So I start thinking about pizza and I,
and I think about that,
just my mouth starts drooling on day four.
Thinking about that.
That's interesting. So when you're
fat starts getting diminished,
your body starts craving fatty things.
I think me and my case anyway,
that's my theory is that it makes sense
why I crave pizza on day four. Well,
when I work out I crave meat. Like
whenever I lift weights I just crave, oh,
I really like, oh, I can't
wait to have a stake. Yeah.
It's like your body knows like,
look,
we gotta we gotta I'll tell you
what the seven protein bill. Yeah.
We need to get that. Get that stuff.
You're breaking down your tissue.
We need something to build it up
quick. Yeah. What is, um, the,
like if you had to pick one place where
you would never go back and try to
survive again, where would it be?
You know, I think, um, I think, uh,
I,
I really love the desert,
but it's my least of places to be
because it's most inhospitable.
It's just dry man. It's
just dry and Kinda, I dunno.
I always remember feeling so uncomfortable
and sand in every crinkle of your
body, you know? And uh, whereas
the forest or the jungle,
even though it's raining all the time,
you know,
you're just walk around with
nothing on and it just felt great,
but it cold is harder. But, but, uh,
I just find a good being in the
deserts, uh, the beautiful though.
Like I don't want people, ah, how come
you don't like to, I love the desert.
It's a gorgeous,
they're beautiful.
It's just something about when you're
surviving and you're sleeping on the sand
and you're sleeping outside all the
time, you get sand in everything, man.
Or of the mixed martial arts
fighter. Evan Tanner? No,
really a fascinating guy.
Very, very interesting guy.
It was a really tough guy too as
well and get to leave. Yeah. He um,
decided to go on some vision quest and
you went out into the desert and uh,
apparently lost his water or something.
Got Disoriented, one of dying out there.
You don't realize like how easy it is.
Even for a tough guy like that. Get the,
if you don't know what
you're doing and you fuck up
your life, your life hangs on the balance
of water. Really. It's all about water.
I mean I'll go, I'll do the whole
10 day survivor man with just water.
If there's lots of water to drink, I'll
be fine. I'll get over it. Really it's,
the food is not an issue that, you
know, water is, is it, what about you?
What are your energy levels like? Totally
drop. Yeah. Oh, I'll shoot a scene,
I'll call it that way.
I shoot a scene,
I'll do the fireboat and then I'll have
to sit down and I think I'm sitting down
for like two minutes and it's like, no,
it's 20 or longer and I'm just sitting.
Cause you could become solar methodic.
So that's a problem without food
had the problem that food is,
you become lethargic, you
lose your energy, and it's
hard to get up and do stuff.
The problem with water is that you
may last 10 days without water,
but after three you're a basket
case and it you're, you're the,
just think of the migraines
that come through.
You get those intense migraines
from lack of water and stuff.
So the last seven days
of your life on a planet,
if you're going without water and
you're dying from dehydration are,
are horrible.
And that's why people in life rafts
end up drinking the ocean water,
making themselves crazy, you
know, and they'll literally say,
I'm going to go to the store and they'll
walk off the raft, you know, intense.
You know,
that's water's everything.
So when I do my survivor man shows and
everything to do with survival, to me,
the very first question is,
where's my fresh water coming from?
The mind fuck is to be dying of
thirst in the middle of an ocean.
It's crazy. It's, it is
crazy. It's, it's, you know,
Elaine Bombard proved
that you could ingest some
scientifically in very specific
ways, but, but you know, if you don't
have fresh water coming in, forget it.
The last show I did was in Mexico and I
was on the ocean's edge and I had to go
away and land to find water. How much
water can you drink out of the ocean?
Well, you can't really use the
proper answer as you, you can't, um,
you could take a shot of water
out of the ocean every day.
If you're drinking fresh water as well,
then you're actually getting some
salts and stuff and minerals. But,
but if you have no fresh water, you just,
you can't, you're going to make yourself,
you're going to, you're going to
poison yourself. How crazy is that?
Most of the fucking water has salt
in it. And that's most of it. Yeah.
These giant bodies, it's all salt. Yeah.
But also the amount of
fresh water that exists,
like under the surface of North
America and Russia. Intense. You know,
last question. Do you believe in those
defining rots where dudes find water?
Did they work?
I got to say it,
it did shit that I wasn't doing and they
were in my hands. We like, I'm like, Whoa,
Whoa, Whoa, whoa. It's like one of those
weird moments like, oh crap, oh crap.
And I was doing it and, and sure enough,
and then when we dig and we found water,
so I have to be a very light stick.
Uh, yeah, these are copper rods, Kai,
you don't want to, it goes back
to what we first started talking.
I think it's really about
energy, right? You know,
you connect in an engine in an
energetic sense, right? To everybody.
I think that's what if you want to
bring someone, you know, if someone,
if you brought someone in your life,
it's because for some reason your energy,
you know, and I think that's just a,
that's just a small manifestation of,
of energy skill set. You know, just,
you know, the energy through you and,
and these wires, like this member of
the store I said about, about, uh,
doing a land surveying and I'm
like hundreds of yards away from,
but all I've got a tripod on the ground.
I'm looking through a transit and I
feel electrical shocks coming off the
transit. That's practical energy we've
set up on manmade lines but the war,
the earth,
you know the world has all this energy
and I think the those dividing roles,
I think that's all you people
are tapping into. What was it
like?
Basically there's,
sorry there's some sort of a signal that
we just haven't been able to figure out
how to detect yet that certain aspects
of nature giving off like like underwater
water, our underground water. I
th I think, I think that that,
again I'm being ridiculously vague,
but I think that we simply
have flowing energy.
I think energy can be stored
like in rocks and so on,
but it's the earth is a whole
matter of flowing energy.
Water is like the physical
manifestation of that energy.
You can see it cause water moves and it
flows and it stuff and it's like more
vibrant energy all the time. So I think
when you get an a mez metaphysical stuff,
you have individuals, human beings
who who can connect into this or that.
I can't explain it. Who
can explain it. Right.
All we know is that weird shit
happens and stuff happens that you,
that is really difficult to explain
whether you're you're fully entrenched in
the Bible or the Koran or
atheism or whatever it is,
you're whatever dog more non dogma.
The reality is it's pretty damn hard
to explain some shit that goes on.
And my personal explanation is
just that there's, you know,
God's spirit energy itself, the
universe. It's just, you know,
it's all connecting that way.
I mean,
I live my life as survivor man by being
really super grateful for what I've got.
You know, I'm grateful for the abundance,
I'm grateful for my kids for health.
And the more I'm grateful,
the more I get it,
the more it comes back to me all the time.
When I, I always say thank you about,
you know,
I,
like I told you when I start off
survivor meant I would be thankful in the
morning or help me to do this.
You know,
and I call that a meditation called a
prick out, whatever you want. In my case,
it's a matter of being grateful for
what's going on. And I know that it works,
that when you are grateful for B and
Joe Rogan and having your show and doing
the things you do, guess what? You get
more of that. He get more Joe Rogan more.
You show more of the things that you do
because you show in the universe. Uh, I'm,
I'm grateful. I am who I am.
I'm grateful. I'm less jot.
I'm grateful that I was survivor man
and still am and uh, and I, I'm, I'm,
I'm just getting started man. Look, music
sounds get started. It sounds so hippy,
but I totally does.
Of course it sounds hippy,
but so at some point you
just got to go with a hippie.
Exactly. Listen man, thank you very much.
It's been an awesome podcast and if
people want to hear your music, what's,
what's the best way to it or buy it?
They can go to Les Stroud dossier,
right? You've got the Itunes,
the new LBA folks. Yeah,
that's the kiss. Some dude named
less drought in the states,
took less drought.com son of a bitch,
son of a bitch. So less dot dossier.
You can get all, all my
stuff there. Um, and um,
and you know what I thought about
coming on? I thought, you know, if, if,
if the parents that are out there,
I know there's a lot of scouts,
a lot of young people that love my stuff
and I know I got a little potty mouth
wells hanging out with Joe Rogan is
they're going to happen when you're here.
But the reality is I think that,
you know,
the fact that I've got fans from like six
to 60 has been blowing me away and uh,
and now I get a chance to do the music.
So did you need us to test?
You need a less job pause test. It's
thinking about it while you're in, in
the woods. That's what
a great idea. I mean,
think about all the time you have
while you're there and on today's show,
big foot dude,
you should totally do a podcast that would
be like you just musing about life by
yourself.
In a fucking tent and like do it that way.
You don't have to edit it for a television
show. You can do like an hour of it.
Background sound of just the,
the atmosphere that you're in would
sound so like a relaxing podcasts. Yeah.
Great. That's a great, I haven't, I
won't say I haven't thought of it.
Our friend bill bird does his
podcast totally by himself
and our guests tomorrow.
Greg Proops, I guess apparently he does
his podcast by himself to comedian. Yeah.
It's funny. Yeah. He's very fun. I was
addicted to whose line is addicted.
That was my stress relief when I was
editing survivorman so you could do that,
man. You could be out in the
tent making a fucking podcast.
I kind of do if you think
about it. Yeah. You kind of do.
You just don't release all
of it. No. Yeah. So just do
it straight up. Yeah. Just,
just decide like [inaudible]
make a little fucking opening.
This is the less trout podcast, you know,
and you just talk about where you are.
Would that be my opening
like that? Like, Nah,
I think you'd probably do better than
I could just play play harmonica song
every opening. Yeah, you could definitely
do that. Yeah, that could be it.
And today you want to lead us
out with that. All Right Joe,
ladies and gentlemen, Les Stroud.
You can get him on Twitter.
Real Les Stroud on Twitter.
Get them online. Les Stroud. Dot. Ca.
Anything going on?
We want to tell people about Brian.
Yeah.
Tomorrow I'll be in a San Diego.
What Doug Benson tickets are on sale
right now@americancomedycode.com and I'll
be with Joe and Austin December 1st
at the Moody Theater.
Shit's going to get crazy.
Joey Diaz is out for that Gig.
I'm very sorry.
I cannot in good conscience
tell you, uh, any day.
But Duncan trussell's in and
Brian red bands and as well,
Joey apparently is going to be doing
a television show and uh, they uh,
it conflicted with
this. So, uh, that's uh,
August 1st in Austin, Texas.
No, August 1st December 1st,
but the fucking went again that next year.
I'll be there August 1st again,
December.
I don't even know what month it is.
Less Stroud's musical harmonica has
hypnotize me to the point where I'm,
I'm no Rohn.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have become a Mo run tomorrow
night at the Ice House comedy club.
It is Joey Diaz, Greg
Fitzsimmons, Tom Segura,
me,
Adam Hunter,
and Sam Tripoli socket.
If you want to find out about,
uh,
any future shows that Brian might be
participated, again, go to death squad.tv.
And from there you can also buy a
beautiful psychedelic kitty cat t shirt.
This podcast is over.
We will see you dirty bitches tomorrow,
may Shiva bless you all.
Keep it real.
Stay black.
[inaudible].