Good.
Goodly Moodley Jamie.
We're all hopped up on adderall here at
the,
at the Rogan studio with Tj supplied
some adderall.
He came here from Columbus and they just
give it to you at the airport.
It's like,
you know,
they're handing out little samples.
Yeah,
I just got this little guy here,
Anna,
wrong.
Imagine if we did come up with a drug
that had adderall like effects but no
negative consequences.
In fact health benefits.
Well I don't know.
Some people are prescribed adderall so
for some people you know,
apparently they just think all right for
you this is good.
Yeah.
Oh No,
no,
no.
Does she just let people decide that for
themselves and they just,
you know,
let everyone try adderall and they keep
taking it.
If they don't,
they stopped taking.
Yeah,
I couldn't agree more.
I mean some people obviously benefits
them.
They should be able to get it whenever
they want.
They shouldn't.
I don't have the,
they should have to go to a doctor about
that.
How about that?
You want to try it?
Two Thousand Fifteen,
16.
We know what adderall is.
Yeah,
they at least have a place where you can
go get a free sample,
you know?
Well,
how come you can try whiskey?
All you have to do is be of age.
You don't have to have any knowledge
whatsoever about whiskey and you can be
on the 21st day or the 21st year of your
life.
The first day you could walk right into
a cvs,
buy a jug of whiskey.
Would no instruction manual?
No guidelines?
No.
No one to walk you through it going.
Have you ever done this before?
Do you have any idea what a shot is
like?
You just have to get to try to drink a
glass.
You might die,
you know,
thinking back to my first time drinking,
maybe it is a good thing that there's
like some barriers,
you know?
Yeah.
Because I don't know.
The first time I got drunk really drunk.
They just handed me like a Coffee Cup
full of vodka at a party and I never
even been to a party before because I
was so socially awkward and Shit.
I'm like 17 and my first party and I'm
like,
okay,
I don't know how strong this is,
but I'm just going to assume that one
cup is good.
Oh God.
So I just,
hey,
you know,
it was the,
the rest of the night did not play out
in my favor.
After that,
I had a very similar story.
My first time I was in high school,
First Party,
new high school,
just move.
There was all Dorky,
didn't hardly know anybody and I made
friends with this kid.
Jimmy Law is who's still my friend to
this day,
great guy and his fucking party and I
remember I couldn't even smell Jack
Daniels for like years later or I would
get sick to my stomach.
I had that problem for awhile.
I grew up in a cab that's always rough.
Throw up in a cab,
like halfway opening the door to
wherever.
Lucky enough to puke.
I always just piss myself.
Is that better?
I think that's better.
It's my pis that's not freaking me out.
Like,
I don't know.
I'd rather know if you puke and then
it's like,
oh God.
And then afterwards you're like,
oh,
okay,
I feel I feel kind of better now.
You don't feel good about waking up with
your pants covered in Piss,
especially because by that time you're
almost sober again.
You do have a point,
you know?
Then you've got to look down and like,
oh my God,
I'm a grown man.
That just piss my pants because I drank
too much.
Depends on how you look at it,
man.
I feel like a grown man.
It throws up.
Its more of a pitch to the guy who piss
themselves.
All right,
well then I guess I'm less of a bitch.
I think you're right dude.
Joe Rogan podcast.
All right dude.
Throw up is a contagious pisses and I
think that's part of the problem with
throw up.
Like if you smelled throw up,
you're like immediately you smell it and
you want to start throwing.
You never smell someone else's pissed
and be like,
I gotta take a piss now you imagine if
that's what it was like if somebody
farted and like Ah,
Kinda Shit.
How and when it was contagious.
Yeah.
Like oh my God.
I mean burst.
I heard him fart.
Now I got to shit.
What been,
why isn't?
And if you smell diarrhea,
shit,
all my friends had to.
Shit.
Yeah,
I guess.
I guess diarrhea is evolutionarily,
like if you,
if you throw up the rest of the people
around like,
Oh,
you know,
we're all eating the same shit.
He Sat,
we better fucking expelled this stuff to
100 percent.
That's exactly what it is.
It's really interesting because uh,
I,
I became immune to it for a long time
because I was around Puke so much on
fear factor.
It's,
it's back now.
A little freak out over puke now.
Like if I'm passing through a restaurant
and someone through.
I saw someone throw up recently in
Vegas.
I was,
I was close to him when I was like,
oh boy.
I felt it a little.
But all the years of fear factor man,
I saw people throw up like almost every
week.
Pretty much everybody threw up one time.
My fucking brother who's also my
business partner,
we've lived together our entire lives.
He got sick and he went to the bathroom
and be in the fucking idiot that he is.
He doesn't puke in the toilet.
He pukes in the sink and it fills the
sink to the brim,
to the brim with fucking puke.
Oh No.
Can you guess what?
He's so fucking sick.
He can't clean it,
so he has to clean face in the fucking
pool is the most horrible experience in
my life.
Oh,
how about those fucking crazy people
that administer colonics and they start
telling you what you're reading by
looking at your shit as it goes through
a tube in front of them.
What about those wacky folk?
I have no experience with that,
so I've never done it either,
but everyone that I know that's done it.
Like first of all,
I don't.
I don't think you're necessarily
supposed to do it that way.
I feel like if you eat fiber,
it cleans everything out from the
inside.
That's probably better than blowing
water up there.
I'll probably gonna get a bunch of
tweets from people that love Kalanick.
Oh yeah.
Well,
everyone's got their little health.
Craziest shit.
Some people think that they can poke
needles in themselves and hit certain
parts of their foot.
And you.
Have you ever seen that reflexology?
Like psychology.
That's bizarre stuff,
right?
Like pulling your toes to fix my
shoulder hurts.
Let me work on your foot.
Okay.
You,
I'm sure people believe it,
but I don't.
It seems unlikely.
Yeah.
It doesn't mean maybe,
I don't know anything more research
needed,
but I've talked shit about acupuncture,
but apparently people use it works.
Some people use all kinds of things and
say they work.
I mean,
you know,
right.
There's no,
but I think there's actual evidence
about acupuncture and made some sort of
a peer reviewed journal about hey,
if there is,
I'm open to it,
but I'm pretty sure it was pointed out
to me,
the mind a little hazy right now.
There's definitely been times when I've
said Shit on a show or in a video and
then I'll be like,
I am fucking certain about this,
and then I get a bunch of messages.
I'm like,
these fucking idiots trying to prove me
wrong and I look at their perspective.
I'm like,
Oh shit.
I guess I was wrong.
Well,
in six months I'll just act like I never
believed that.
Well,
do you change your mind though because
of people correcting me?
I'd definitely do.
You got to have to.
I don't want to be some close minded
idiot that just believes the same thing
no matter what.
Yeah,
and people love you to be beholden to
your earliest beliefs,
like if you had an idea a long time ago
and it was wrong.
Like if he said something I one of your
youtube videos and it turned and you
were like,
this is a fucking fact,
and then it turns out to not be a fact
and yeah,
you're not allowed to make a mistake.
It's just immortalized forever in
history like this time.
What about the time you said that it's
like maybe I think differently now
because years and years of time and
experience of pass.
Well you know what happened with dumb
people.
Unfortunately the term flip flopper got
out and what a flip flopper is,
is someone who changes their fucking
mind,
which means you're a normal person.
The idea that you're going to be a
president or a congressman or senator
and never changed your mind once you
establish this esteemed position,
once you're in there,
you get elected,
you got rock solid ideas about how the
world works and you're so enlightened.
You no longer need to learn or correct
your ideas.
That's ridiculous.
But to dummies,
now they have that term.
Oh,
he's a flip flopper fucking tj.
The flip video from seven years ago,
all those life experiences before that,
that fucking dude was saying this,
you're a flip flopper.
I wonder if they're just that consistent
in their lives.
You know,
they just want to find something to fuck
with you on.
They're just trying to poke,
poke out horse,
you know,
that's like the,
the nature of life,
uh,
you know,
on the internet or in any sort of public
lens,
even in the wild,
I mean,
it's natural you,
you find a guy like you,
you puts out,
you put up these very interesting
thought provoking videos.
You have strong opinions and you
broadcast them out there.
And then there's gonna be a bunch of
people that respond to them.
Some people really enjoy them,
some people get really mad at you,
but because your stuff is good and that
you have really interesting points,
you get a lot of attention.
And when you get a lot of attention,
people go,
fuck that guy,
man.
That shit.
I'll fucking kick his ass if I see him.
I heard that shit.
He said about all you have to do is put
it in context of lake.
You know,
even if you find like,
you know Christopher hitchens or
something like the most eloquent fucking
guy you can,
there's still gonna be people that fat.
Fuck.
What?
Did you see?
What happened when he doctored?
Yeah,
of course.
You know,
he's in hell now he's burning.
Yeah.
Because he's a misogynist.
Oh yeah.
Now that's the truth.
Yeah,
that's that,
that little bit of revisionism too.
I forgot about that.
The data was,
uh,
an interesting one that people chose to
attack because it was like,
it was so white nighty that it was,
it was like blinding.
Like you had to put sunglasses on to
read the tweets,
like,
oh,
Christopher hitchens was a massage.
I know what he was a debater.
He loved to debate people on anything
and he knew that a very thought
provoking subject was the idea that the
only way women are funny is if they act
like men.
And so he wrote that Vanity Fair article
and he's a fucking genius.
Trolls.
What he is,
he's,
he's batting around a mouse and so we
have to remember too,
is this,
the bar for massaging is so low.
I mean like better that I've made videos
like,
all right,
let's just,
I believe in equality between men and
women legally and all.
Always,
you know,
every opportunity man has a woman should
have.
Let's just get that out of the way right
off the bat.
But I think this wage gap thing is a
little wonky massage.
I just like,
yeah,
instantly.
I mean,
you know,
I sat there and I explained to you that
I'm just,
we have a fucking point of contention on
an,
on an issue of economics that doesn't
make me a fucking misogynist.
The wage gap thing is a really weird one
because people just don't want to talk
about it.
They,
when you say,
well,
this wage gap thing,
the way it's been explained to me is a
bunch of different jobs that people
pursue and the jobs that men pursue tend
to be higher paying jobs.
Also higher risk jobs.
More men die while they're employed.
They die on the seven percent.
Some crazy number is really high,
but when you taught,
when you,
if you,
if you even go into that,
you can't.
Those,
those are problematic pieces of
information because just the fact that
they exist at all,
you're attacking them like it becomes
this really weird thing where you're
not.
You're not supposed to talk about the
actual facts of what is happening in the
workplace.
So the actual numbers.
Forget about the fact that we know
there's white bosses who were racist.
We know there's men who are bosses who
were sexist.
We know there are women who are bosses
who hate the other women in the office
and you fucked them over.
We know people are getting fucked over
left and right.
We know and I think you could put it
into a good people,
bad people thing.
I mean that's really what you're dealing
with.
You can call it man or women,
you can call it whatever the fuck you
want to call it,
but it's good people and bad people and
that's you.
As soon as you pick a side,
it's only gender based and any
information whatsoever is unacceptable
and that's why.
That's why I don't like the,
the Mras and the snake towels and shit.
It's like all you're doing is inverting
the whole victim complex thing.
You're just saying,
you know,
you get after them for saying we're the
give us special
privileges,
but you're just trying to flip the
script and do the same thing from the
other end is the only place they have a
point is financially I may have some.
I think they have some points in a child
custody and stuff like that too.
But I mean as far as like saying that
they're victims.
Sure.
As far as like really establishing this
idea that for whatever reason it's okay
for a guy to get fucked over in a
relationship.
To the point where he loses everything
just because these two people don't want
to be together anymore.
That that's been firmly established.
That's not part of like a systematic
society wide impression of man,
not just an issue.
It's a legal issue.
It's it.
Yeah.
And it,
it can be taken seriously on its own.
You don't need an ideology to address
it.
Just like you don't need feminism to
address,
you know,
problems that women have,
which I'm sure there are plenty of
feminist grievances that are well
founded,
well thought out and shit,
but I mean they're drown out by,
you know,
the tits and video games are too big or
they're too small.
Like there's a famous example of this,
this,
uh,
Anita Sarkeesian,
you know,
she was complaining about the old Tomb
Raider Games because Lara Croft tits
were too big.
And then they made them smaller.
And then she said,
oh,
well look how they're defeminized Lara
Croft to make her look more like a man.
Just,
you know,
it just proves that she's an unpleasable
can.
No matter what you do,
I'm just going to find fault.
She's gonna find a fucking problem.
There's going to be people that whatever
hot button issue,
you know,
especially when it comes to gender,
gender is a real hot button issue.
It'd be crates like almost instant
argument.
I don't know why.
Why is it?
I don't know.
There's gotta be a reason there.
Yeah,
sure.
There has to be a reason,
but I don't.
I don't really get.
I mean I guess it's maybe just the
history of that inequalities have
existed,
but I mean,
I don't know.
I don't know why people still have such
a hair trigger reaction on the gender
thing or why it's so important because
like what's weighted?
It's weighted by the actions of the
past.
You can't look at it as a thing that
exists in the present.
I mean even the current,
if you're a person who is being
victimized,
like if you're a girl is being sexually
harassed by a boss or something like
that.
It exists in the present or whatever.
Fill in the blank with sexual
harassment,
but it's not you and it's not me and
we're not doing what I have in these
conversations about the wage gap when I
was working,
when I was a teenager,
I was working in my dad's office and
there was a woman there and she was
perfectly attractive,
but she would make very strong like,
come on,
it's to me,
you know,
she'd be like grabbing my ass and shit
and you know,
I just,
I wasn't interested,
but you know,
it's like when I wasn't interested,
it's like,
oh,
you know,
we think Tj is gay or something because
he didn't want that.
So I mean it's one thing,
at least for women,
there's that mechanism there of like
society kind of has something built in
to believe you if you're a victim of
sexual harassment.
But for me it was like there was nowhere
to turn.
Did you feel like a victim?
I mean,
I didn't feel like a victim because I
don't like to foster the victim
mentality,
but I certainly felt like there was an
issue going on in my life that I had no
ability to address.
Was she above you in the office?
Yeah.
Oh,
okay.
So that makes it weird too.
Yeah,
she was like,
uh,
the manager of all the people in the
call center because we'll call sand.
She was just a crazy lady you want and
how much fun in the office and she was.
She was pulling,
you know,
she was grabbing my ass.
I mean,
Hey,
if you want,
if,
if I was into it,
cool,
you know,
if I reciprocated.
And I was like,
yeah,
we've got a fun office now.
Right?
Because you imagine what would have
happened when it became obvious that I
didn't like it.
It's just like,
you know,
Oh,
why?
Why are you going to keep doing this?
Oh.
So she kept doing it like it was,
it was a persistent pattern,
just like,
you know,
day after day,
I don't know,
probably three or four months.
Holy Shit Dude.
So every day you would go to work and
you'd be thinking,
fuck,
this crazy lady's going to grab my ass,
and I just didn't like her.
Wow,
man.
That's not cool.
That's not cool for us.
I was so.
I was so passive than to.
I mean I really didn't know how to say
anything.
I got to assert yourself because you
know,
I wasn't very assertive at the time.
That's a hard spot.
That's a hard spot for a human being.
You know,
I,
I think there's a real problem when
people don't want to look at you as a
guy who's in a hard spot because you are
a male,
right?
Whereas if you were a woman and you were
in that same position at the same age
and the same awkwardness at the time,
I would feel really bad for you.
I'd be like,
fuck man,
what an asshole that guy is,
or what an asshole that woman is.
If the woman was grabbing her ass and
she was freaking out,
it'd be the same kind of reaction have
if you had a young girl who worked in
the office and was a little awkward and
there was this like super aggressive
woman who kept grabbing her ass all the
time and freaking out and it was a woman
who was above or in the office.
That would be a really creepy scene,
but you don't get much sympathy for your
store.
Why would I?
Yeah.
Because there's no.
There's no social mechanism that says
that's a problem.
Yeah.
It just looks like,
Oh,
you know,
that's just some funny,
isolated thing.
But you know,
when I've told that story,
I've had other people come forward and
say like,
yeah,
I had that problem too,
and I just didn't know what to do about
it because you know,
if you're a man,
you can't say I was sexually harassed,
but you know it just because you're not
interested in a particular woman who
seems to have way too much interest in
you.
That's not reciprocated on your part.
Yeah.
What the fuck,
man,
that's a weird.
A blind spot,
we have what I mean,
if you're a man,
you're supposed to deal with it,
but that's across the board.
I mean that's like.
It's not just men that say that women
say that to across the board,
but if you're a man you're just supposed
to,
but that's one of my larger point is
that when it comes to these like
feminist and gender issues,
it's like we're supposed to always
believe that there's a gender root cause
to what's happening.
It can't just be that one person is
horny for another person that doesn't
want that person back,
which can happen to anybody.
Yeah.
There's too many variables with people
to take a side based entirely on gender.
There's just too many variables.
Variables are a form of mysogeny there.
There are trigger warnings,
variables or trigger warnings and unto
themselves I think.
I think
you,
you know,
we kind of addressed human beings as
individuals,
as human beings being male,
female,
gay,
straight.
Who gives a shit.
Let's get on a team.
I try to do it too.
I think we all try to do it.
It's difficult when it's not being done
like universally all around us.
When I was a kid,
this is a true story.
When I moved from San Francisco to
Florida,
I was 11 years old.
Yes,
We moved to Florida and I didn't know
what the word nigger meant.
I didn't know.
I had no idea what it meant because I
lived in San Francisco.
San Francisco is super diverse in the
seventies.
This was like the Vietnam War ended when
I was in San Francisco,
so this was like hippies and fucking
people with bell bottoms and like my
stepdad would get whistled at her when
he was with me.
It was like crazy how weird people were.
It was like a real freaky place to be
like a young kid,
but no racism.
I mean,
none of that fucking never heard those
words at school.
So then I go to Florida and I heard it
like first day someone's calling
somebody a nigger.
I'm like,
what the fuck is that?
So I didn't want to say I didn't know
because then I would look like a loser.
So I had to go home and I asked my mom,
she got pissed and maybe she thought I
was playing a game.
She's like,
you're trying to get me to say it.
I'm like,
I'm not trying to get you to say.
I like,
what does it mean?
She was,
you don't know what it means.
I'm like,
you gotTa fucking tell me.
I'm like 11 years old.
What the fuck does it mean?
And so she had explained to me that it
was a derogatory term for black people.
I was like,
what?
Like at 11,
I was like,
what the fuck?
What,
what real.
Those are real.
Like I couldn't,
I couldn't imagine it at that time.
So it is possible to grow up in a place
like maybe it was just the area that I
was when I was young,
if we could somehow or another promote
that sort of universal look,
it doesn't make you immune to doing
something stupid because you're gay.
It doesn't make you immune to being an
asshole because you're a chick.
It doesn't make you immune to whatever.
I mean fill in the blank gender wise.
Just people as individuals.
That's why I like star Trek.
Am I running for office?
That's why you like star Trek Star Trek
because you're not enough diversity.
A lot of men run a white men running,
you know,
there's a lot of diversity,
especially compared to,
uh,
the shows on at the time.
And you know,
first interracial kiss on star Trek,
one of the first lesbian kisses on star
Trek.
Really?
Well,
not the original series,
but on deep space nine.
I don't count those as well.
I did.
Those aren't star track.
They just stole the name,
you know,
I don't even like the original series.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
I just don't.
It's too cheesy.
It's too corny.
Goodness.
It's a time capsule though,
right?
Well,
yeah.
It's definitely cheesy.
A cheesy time.
Best forgotten.
Well,
it's become a comedy.
It's a comedy.
It wasn't intended it as the time.
No,
it was not.
But if you watch it today,
it truly is a comedy,
especially if there's any aliens
involved.
Like when Kirk Kirk had to duke it out
with that one dude with the lizard head.
Oh my God,
it's so slow.
It was a fake,
it was so fake looking like sped up the
film or something.
At least they should have made it in the
dark.
First of all,
the plan should have been total
darkness.
So the monster was like very hard to see
because see,
when you look at all of it,
you're like,
what is this piece of shit you're trying
to tell me as an alien?
But my point about star trek was though
they never really talk about that kind
of stuff.
It's not like,
you know,
if there's a black character,
there's no issue dealing with their
blackness,
you know,
it's all been moved past.
Look at this.
Look,
is this real?
Oh my God.
Come on,
come on.
This is real.
Oh my God,
this is so hilarious.
Oh,
Kirk,
with a Shitty Moy Thai terrible
technique doesn't turn his hip over.
No weight to that.
So this is,
um,
is it playing with sound too?
Okay.
So what we're looking at for people
listening to this.
So I'm so sorry I haven't been
describing this.
Is Captain Kirk Duking it out with the
shittiest fucking fake looking green
man.
Alien on this planet,
it was like one of the cheesiest scenes
in all of Star Trek.
It's just so bad.
Kirk boxes is yours to get free.
It's just,
it's everything's bad about it.
The acting is bad.
The movement is bad.
Like they're moving in slow motion.
Like when he's trying to throw punches
at the guy.
Now Kirk is coming out with a rock.
Oh Shit.
He's got a rock and he's.
There's a closeup as he lifts it over
his head and throws it and he hits him
right in the chest and guess what?
It does nothing.
It just bounces off of a curse.
Like what?
Like do,
just start walking.
That fucking thing is never going to
catch you.
It is the slowest piece of shit of all
time.
Yeah.
Just stroll away leisurely and it walks
up to a big rock and that was going to
pick up the big rock look like that
fucking piece of shit.
Fake rock is good Lord.
So this lizard thing that literally it's
expression does not move.
It's a child's toy.
It throws this rock at Kirk and he
barely gets out of the way.
A little too casual.
They are correct.
If that was a real fucking rock,
you'd be shitting your pants,
man.
That rock was within six inches of
hitting him and tearing his arm off his
body.
Fucking goofy.
You're right.
It's too cheesy.
I hate when people are right,
you know,
at least.
I mean,
there's some cheesy moments.
I'm like the next generation or
something,
but there's nothing like that.
I never got into it.
I never got into it because there was
this guy named Kevin Knox who is a
hilarious comedian in Boston and he had
this ruthless bit about,
uh,
what the fuck did they do to the Old
Star Trek?
Wow.
Who's this fucking new captain?
Go,
who's this new bald guy is new captain.
He was,
he would do this long rant about like
how great captain Kirk was and how much
this guy sucks.
And out of respect,
I never watched the uh,
all right,
now at least I can.
At least I can understand the reasoning.
There was a little logic to it.
Very little,
but it's amazing how bad special effects
were just a few decades ago.
Yeah.
But you know,
that was a,
that could have been done better even in
the time,
like you said.
I mean like shooting in the dark,
speed it up a little,
you know.
Well that was done in what the sixties,
seventies and it was probably either 66
or 67 were like late sixties.
Right.
I mean you think about the great move,
I mean the hustler with Paul Newman and
Jackie gleason.
That was just a few years before that.
That is a great move.
So they were doing great.
We saw that last year,
you know?
Oh really?
Wow.
That's great movie man.
Jackie gleason was a fucking hell of an
actor.
It's really interesting to see his,
his career got so weird.
Like he did so many different things
going from like the honeymooners to like
doing a serious role,
like the hustler where he wasn't funny
at all to doing smokey and the bandit,
which is like so slapsticky and
hilarious.
Smokey and the bandit holds up.
It does.
It holds up.
Yeah.
My first girlfriend showed me that
movie.
I found it weird because,
you know,
I've never really thought of sally
fields is very sexual,
but in that movie,
you know,
I didn't like her ass.
It was very big.
I remember that good.
She's a sweetheart.
She was like America sweetheart.
Like a sweet woman.
Like you couldn't.
You could never see an engineer from my
generation.
The only role I really remember him
prominently if like from being a kid was
like the mom and forrest gump and I was
like,
fuck that.
Yeah.
Sally field when she was young,
definitely had something go on.
She had a little bit of that ginger know
Maryanne,
the little bit of that.
Maryanne from Gilligan's island thing.
Yeah,
but Maryanne was considerably hotter.
I agree.
She was like pretty like pretty much had
a girlfriend that was,
I don't know,
building is falling apart too.
We're being attacked.
I think there's people fixing something
or something.
Sorry about that.
Now UFO attack sally fields.
I'm ginger and Maryanne.
Maryanne had that thing too,
like if you think ginger is a little too
high maintenance,
if you've known someone like her,
look what we got.
We got this girl that probably knows how
to plant things.
I don't know if it's a good thing or a
bad thing.
It's probably a bad thing,
but I used to date a girl who wrote
Gilligan's island.
Erotic fan fiction does.
Definitely not a bad thing.
Yeah,
because that's fun.
That would be a bad thing.
You know,
I,
I don't know.
I like it because I'm like,
you know,
she can be turned on by Gilligan,
you know?
It seems like I'll,
I'll have an easy task of it.
Yeah.
Have you seen,
um,
there's a whole genre of bigfoot porn?
No,
I've not seen that.
Yeah.
There's,
there's a woman who's writing these big
foot sexual novels would like,
and they're there.
There they're like real books,
like,
I don't know if it's in like going out
to a book,
you know,
going out to bookstores kind of thing.
That's a good question.
I know they're definitely ebooks,
but I'm pretty sure they're real books
too,
but it's bigfoot.
I'm,
I might be wrong about that.
It's big foot porn like this is.
Here it is.
Come for bigfoot volume one.
We'll look at that bitch.
Three and a half fucking stars.
Volume one.
Customers books one through five.
How many of these fucking books are out?
All my God.
Scroll up so I could read this on a week
long outing in Mount Hood National
Forest.
What begins as a flirty fun field trip
soon turns into a nightmare when an ape
like creature kidnaps a group of teen
girls with the purpose of procreating
with them,
thus began the erotic adventure of a
lifetime and inconceivable love story
between a young woman in her horny,
sasquatch.
Wow,
right mix of horror and erotica says
scarlet Jones,
who is scarlet Jones?
I don't know.
She said scarlet's on the ball.
She said it's the right mix,
and so there's a bunch of these titles
come for bigfoot volume to a.
They should have had.
They could have some of this.
Another thing they didn't have to.
Oh,
this is.
It gets even better.
Hold on.
Go back to school.
Make that a little larger.
Oh my God.
Look at this kid,
horny,
ape like creature said,
Mount Hood,
national forest,
but her name is portia
for shifts.
Shelly and Leslie find themselves it'll
lusty situation as a tribe of bigfoot's
use.
They're willing,
willing new bio bodies to satisfy their
monster Cox.
How can porsche leave all this behind
and return to civilization when she's in
the arms of her sasquatch,
warm and snugly and is mad at for the
only thoughts going through her mind are
of utter bliss,
but challenges around
what the fuck,
but challenges abound for this star
crossed lovers including Leonard's head
injury.
The guy got a head injury,
there's a male,
so they kicked up a male to male human
and it devastating wildfire and as sexy
forest ranger named Mike.
Oh my God,
this is hilarious.
Do you think,
you know,
they say it's hard to go black and then
go back.
Could you go big foot and go back?
Probably not.
Definitely not.
You'd be all stretched out.
Fucked up.
It'd be like a like a
golf pencil after that.
Yeah.
What a strange genre of Erotica.
I mean,
I don't know if it's just this one woman
who's writing this or if there's others,
find out if there's a big foot.
Porn is an actual genre.
Young Jamie,
when you find out how legit this
actually is,
I mean,
why not,
right?
Why not?
I mean,
if there's bronies oh yeah,
that's true.
People jacking off to like weird
animated ponies and Shit,
you know,
I'll do hangouts and stuff for my
podcast and some of the people that come
into the private hangouts or bronies,
so I kind of get to like try to probe
their mindset and uh,
I,
you know,
I asked these guys like,
so do you jerk off to the all the porn
that they got out there?
They know,
you know,
for me it's more just about fascination
to go show with a good story.
Like show with a good story.
There's plenty of shows with good
stories that are made for adults that
don't have,
you know,
a little cute animated ponies in them.
Right.
Why would we care though?
Really?
Right.
I don't give a shit.
They can do what they want.
Yeah.
I don't give a shit either,
but I'm not going to trust your
judgment.
Right?
You,
you're going to like,
if someone tells you about something
that's awesome and you know he's also a
brony.
You're going to go,
oh,
okay.
Thanks dude.
Yeah,
you got to kind of weigh that out.
Yeah.
This guy says this place is cool,
but he is a brony.
So.
And
if you were a brony but you hadn't
discovered brony ism and you were
missing something in your life,
you just felt like there was just a
whole.
Would you recognize it instantly?
Maybe you would.
Maybe the moment you saw my little pony,
it was just your heart would just fill
with like,
like,
like sparkles.
Everything just feels alive and
wonderful and warm for the first time
and it's the perfect entertainment and
you watch my little pony and you just,
you get chills.
You just feel great about everything and
you go,
this is what I've always needed.
I needed this.
And so you start secretly wearing my
little pony tee shirts under your dress
shirts at work,
and you go home and you put on my little
pony way,
cooking yourself a lonely dinner.
But you're happy now because you
discovered what was always missing my
little pony.
You found the missing piece for somebody
that's got to be possible mad if people
want to be furries,
right?
If somebody wants to run around with a
chip monck mascot outfit on and like
furries.
You heard of the other kin?
Yes.
There are even crazier.
Yeah.
Once you describe those,
for the people that don't know what the
fuck we're talking about,
right?
Other 10,
prepared,
preparing mind blown folk.
If a Brownie is like someone who is
like,
I like to pretend to be a fox,
I wear this,
you know Fox mass.
Yeah.
I know I'm,
I'm,
I'm just starting with furries because
it's Kinda like you were saying brony.
Oh sorry.
The furry,
you know.
And I like to wear a Fox mask and I like
to gift with other furries.
That's their term for fucking.
I don't know why they can't just use the
word fucking.
Yeah,
they call it riffing.
Why iff?
Yep.
Don't know.
Anyway,
so that's,
that's a furry right.
And uh,
and other kin is different but similar,
but way worse because they actually
think like,
I am a Fox and I have the soul of a Fox
within me.
And they also claim to have astral
limbs.
Like they can feel the Fox tail.
It's not just Fox as it could be.
Dragons,
you know,
they say I'm a dragon,
I have the soul of a dragon.
I'm a reincarnated dragon.
Um,
you know,
all kinds of stuff.
Spirit,
animal,
they,
they even have like a fiction.
Can they go a step further?
They,
they,
they think they somehow are characters
from TV shows.
I even saw this post on tumbler where
someone's
like,
you know,
I was Joffrey from game of thrones and I
don't regret shit that I did.
You're allowed to be whatever you want.
Now.
You've got a lot of questions you
anymore.
No criticism is hate.
It is.
And,
and,
uh,
you know,
there's people that go around saying
they're like a laptop,
Ken and computer can we,
things that don't even have souls to
begin with.
Like I share a kinship with computers.
These people listed like,
Oh,
you know,
it sucks that I have this fleshy body
now because my true body is made of
metal because I'm an android kin.
Oh my God.
And they're serious.
I'm serious.
That's scary.
I mean it's like identity politics gone
fucking bat shit.
What are their preferred gender
pronouns?
Um,
I don't know if they have specific
pronouns for the each other kin,
but most of them do tend to like,
you know,
the CSI kind of shit.
I was on some websites that I was just
scrolling around looking for
information,
looking for new stories.
And I saw a story,
I think it was on dig about how William
Shakespeare used the pronoun they for an
individual and now it's coming back.
You're talking about gender neutral
pronouns.
Like William Shakespeare used it because
they talked goofy back then they had
just invented England.
There was a bunch of shitty ways of
describing things that we don't do
anymore.
Thou far out now.
Oh,
there's a bunch of stupid ways they
talked.
We realized,
Hey,
this is a lot of extra sounds we're
making with our face and it's not
getting the point across any better.
It's just dumb.
So let's cut the shit and let's clean
this fucking bitch out.
Modern English is the best English.
It's like they got the age gender people
that they want everyone to say they
until they.
Until they tell you their preferred
pronoun.
Exactly mean like you're fucking a
plural.
Yeah.
When there isn't a single is when you
say they.
This is where I draw the line.
You want to call yourself z.
Who goes why?
Mr Wiseman.
Mr. Okay,
but not what do I give a shit?
But they would you like teaching people
the difference is singular and plural.
Plural is they?
That's a bunch.
That's a few people.
They went to the store.
It's not a fucking guy.
Would you go,
well,
okay,
we'll meet them at the store.
No,
you meet them at the store.
What the fuck you talking about?
My meeting them like how many people
were there?
What,
what?
What the fuck did you just say?
Why don't you say even assuming though
that we started using all of these
gender pronouns,
like Howard,
how is anyone even going to keep that
straight?
Like assume it catches on like wildfire
and everyone gets to choose from a list
of like 297 genders with their own
unique sets of pronouns.
Like I can't even remember his pe.
Remember people's fucking names.
All right.
I'm not going to remember that many
different sets of pronouns for people.
Yeah.
It's.
I think people try really fucking hard
to define themselves because in some
way,
shape or form,
defining yourself helps you feel like
you have at least a little bit of
sovereignty.
This madness
that we're all trudging through.
I think that's the most interesting
thing about you is that you use some
weird pronouns then you're not very
fucking interests.
That's true.
But to those people,
it like one of the reasons why they
fight for it so viciously.
I think for a lot of like really
disenfranchised people,
they feel so outside of any little
victory they can get even in coming up
with a new gender pronoun that makes
them somehow another field.
But it's not a victory though,
but it is for them.
Maybe it's like a little tiny.
I mean,
it's not like,
oh,
like you're not winning the war.
Maybe you win a tiny little personal
battle,
I guess.
You know,
like,
yeah,
if you're in other can,
every,
every person that gets to tell you that
you're a dragon,
you know,
that's just another.
Yeah,
I'm a dragon.
But say I'm a dragon and agree I'm a
dragon.
The more true it becomes.
I think other kin is a very extreme
example,
that extreme example.
But I'm not into,
you know,
even like all the alternative gender
pronouns,
you know,
and I'm cool with transgender people.
I'm cool.
But uh,
you know,
there's not 200 genders there just isn't
going to go to that.
I want,
I want to read this.
This is Jamie just put up 2015 word of
the year is singular.
They says,
fucking who you can have a word of the
year,
asshole.
If there's a reason why there's millions
of words,
because words can only convey a portion
of an idea.
They string them together and form
sentences.
You don't get to have a fucking word of
the year.
That stupid shit that's really fucking
dumb.
Maybe the word of the year should be as
dumb as using the word gay as a singular
person because that's not what it is.
You fucks.
Okay.
God Damn it chose pissed.
God dammit.
Look if because it's unnecessary to.
Why would she have a singular?
They tell me Your fucking name.
Is it pat?
Okay,
Pat,
I don't know if you're a guy or girl.
I don't give a fuck.
I know I can call you pat.
They fuck you.
Fuck you.
Just fuck you.
You're asking for too much goddamn
attention.
Stop it.
They don't.
You think?
I think America.
I speak for you.
If Donald Trump speaks for most America,
I speak for everybody else.
I don't know.
He might agree on the whole day thing
though.
You guys could probably find common
ground where,
Oh,
we'd probably find speak you speak for
all of America there.
I think we need Donald Trump,
but we need Donald Trump on mushrooms.
That's what we need.
We need a Donald Trump that has a bunch
of psychedelic experiences and just
releases all this fucking aggressive
bullshit and realizes like he's in this
unique position to maybe link
legitimately changed the world.
Can't believe you found mushrooms when
he's 65,
but now that he did,
he knows he's got to do something about
this.
So give them shrooms and like a spear
and set him loose in the woods.
Well,
you know what happens is Donald Trump
has a science advisor.
This trying to keep him alive and this
an science advisor informs him of the
longevity properties of relaxation and
that is bound up 10 step thing.
One Way to cure this pattern or behavior
may be a breakthrough psychedelic
experience.
So they convinced Mr. Trump to go to
like Cedar Sinai or someplace it looks
legit and they bring them into a room
and they dose the fuck out of him with
like 10 grams of mushrooms from Mexico.
Just
the mothership,
hieroglyphs aliens communicating with
long,
stretchy fingers that go right to his
soul and rearrange his synapses and he
comes out of that two hours later,
a completely different cat.
Then we got a real fucking presidential
candidate.
Then we got somebody.
But right now we've got Bernie Sanders
and Hillary Clinton and Donald Trump.
And I think Donald Trump's gonna Fuckin.
When you think he's going to win,
I don't know.
This is what I.
I don't,
I don't know how healthy.
And this is a legit question,
how healthy Hillary Clinton is.
Like there's been some questions about.
Apparently she had had a concussion at
one point in time and she suffers
postconcussion syndrome.
Maybe.
I don't know if that's true.
So it's figuring out what's true and
what's not because everything is.
So.
It might be a rumor that you put a.
It was talking to your Jamie earlier
about a mine.
Well,
he's yours,
my friend Jamie,
Jamie,
Jamie.
I didn't want to presume,
but anyway.
No,
he was talking to him about.
I was talking about how there's just
like,
there's so much information now that
people can just kind of cherry pick
whatever they want the truth to be.
Yeah.
You know,
it's,
you know,
no matter what crazy shit you believe,
you can always find someone that's
selling that narrative.
So that's true.
Why not just go with them and say that's
the truth and everything else is a lie.
That is true.
I mean,
you can always find support.
So it's one of the more interesting
things about online communication.
When they ask you something,
what would you prefer between Hillary
and trump?
That's a good question.
I don't know.
I don't know them and it's all.
It's like saying like,
who would be the better mom?
Angela Lansbury or the mom from the
Brady bunch.
I don't fucking know those people.
I don't.
I don't know.
Who would you rather have as your mom?
I don't fucking know.
I don't know.
I think what you get when you watch
Hillary Clinton is a fucking polished
politician,
a polished lawyer who became a
politician who was married to a
president who's been secretary of state,
just group Frankenstein.
She's,
you know,
she's.
She's a deep political person.
She's deep.
She's deep in the system and in the
game,
and I think we all can agree whether
you're a republican or a Democrat,
that the game is fucking rigged.
It's rigged.
It's rigged in a bunch of real simple
ways and a map,
a couple of them out real quick that
everybody knows the have way too much
money that's being spent on these
parties by gigantic corporations.
Way Too much money,
way too much influence.
It was way too much cronyism.
There's way too many people to become
career politicians and they get
intertwined and I rubbed my back or rub
your back.
You Rub my back and they have these
weird fucking allegiances and then they
have parties to very clear distinct
party of Republican or a Democrat and it
would take a fucking meteor hitting
Virginia for them
to elect an independent candidate.
I mean,
it was some radical fucked up life
changing event would have to happen on
earth where people woke up out of the
fog and realize we have to try for an
independent party but don't yet.
But even what I was gonna say is the
idea,
even if there's only three parties is
fucking insane.
It's insane.
The idea that you have three choices and
two of them have proven to be inept at
managing the country over and over and
over and over and over and over again.
It's like having Walmart and like JC
Penney and they're both selling cancer
sticks and everyone's like,
you know,
art cancer sticks killed way less people
than their cancer sticks and then they
trade off back and forth.
One shitty fucking fast food joint
versus another Shitty fucking filling
the company Jackie fucking company
that's selling you terrible shit.
That's what the republic.
Don't you think it was at least kind of
interesting that we have,
as you know,
out of the three people who stand a
good.
I mean,
I guess you could put crews in there
too.
You really don't think you as an
outlier.
He's way too crazy as far as you know,
but the people who actually have a
stand,
a chance of being president,
I mean,
Hillary,
as we've said,
is total establishment,
whatever.
Donald trump,
he's really not taking money from
others.
He's mostly just using his personal
fortune at this point,
right?
Bernie Sanders is not taking money from
super pacs.
He's just getting funded by,
you know,
a private citizens and stuff.
So to have these people who are so
popular or people who have largely
issued this system of,
uh,
the moneyed interests,
pumping the,
these political campaigns full of money
and then expecting,
you know,
of course their,
their core values and return that,
that's,
you know.
So it's kind of interesting that at
least we have two candidates that are
not part of that.
It's a good point,
or don't at least seem to be on the
surface that are,
you know,
Bernie Sanders have the second most
popular Democrat.
He stands a pretty decent chance of
winning A.
Donald Trump is the most popular
republican.
He probably will get the nomination if
Bernie Sanders just made a little bit
more sense about finances.
I think I would be in his corner,
just don't you like there's a bunch of
things that I do like,
let me just say what I do like I like
what he says about having these people
that pay taxes or that I'm shelter their
money from taxes by putting them in
foreign banks.
They should,
they should have to pay tax on those and
that's bullshit.
There's tax shelters that are set up for
corporations where a corporation makes
billions of dollars and somehow or
another they don't pay any taxes.
That's insanity.
That all should be fixed.
That,
that.
And I agree with him 100 percent on
I agree with him on a living wage and
I've had people argue with me about this
and you know,
say that I need to talk to an economist
and maybe they're right,
but ideologically maybe they're right
financially,
but ideologically I think if somebody
works for you 40 hours a week,
they should be able to eat.
They should be able to have a,
an apartment to live in.
I mean,
you should pay someone a living wage.
Yeah,
a full time worker should definitely
have the ability to feed,
clothe and shelter themselves.
That's seems very reasonable.
It should be without debate,
right?
I mean it should be.
We're talking about a person dedicating
eight hours of every day of their life.
That's a giant chunk of money.
Whenever,
whenever these,
uh,
companies crunch the numbers like
Mcdonald's,
they cry.
How much would we have to raise our
prices to raise our wages to $15 an
hour?
It'd be something like,
you know,
five cents on every big Mac and shit
like that.
Real.
I mean,
it's so insignificant.
Oh,
see,
that's just crazy.
It's crazy.
They won't do that.
And you know,
furthermore,
we've seen,
well,
you know,
we're,
we're about to get a big experiment in
this in Seattle anyway because they're
raising the wages.
Well,
Seattle is also in the unique position
of being at a first year legal marijuana
sale and when that,
when the taxes came into Denver,
I mean it's twisting the whole economy
sideways there.
Real estate prices have gone through the
roof.
I think the real estate prices,
we're closing in on like 16 percent or
more up from the previous year when
marijuana wasn't legal there.
They're violent crimes kind of way down.
Drunk driving is that the lowest?
They've had it like 10 years.
It's fucking crazy and they've made more
money in taxes just in the first year
than they did an alcohol.
That's.
That's insane.
More money from marijuana and that state
from alcohol.
You think about all the places that
serve alcohol.
That's amazing.
Do you think they should take that
approach to some of the other drugs that
are currently illegal set?
One hundred percent,
especially the ones that don't kill you,
all the ones that you make,
any exceptions or would it just across
the board the real problem is going to
be children.
That's the problem.
It's a problem now.
It's the problem with prescription pills
that people leave around.
It's a problem with irresponsible folks
who leave around potentially dangerous
things like a prescription medication or
like a bag of mushrooms or coke or
something like that.
Like,
yeah,
that's going to be a problem,
man.
If you make coke legal,
if you make it so that you can go and
buy coke the same way you can go and buy
whiskey,
why not tell me why not?
I don't understand.
Why not.
If you want to tell me that alcohol
should be illegal as well,
then I go,
yeah,
okay.
I get it,
but I bet you if you looked at coke
versus alcohol,
if you look at like daily use of coke
I bet you'd see some real similar like
health problems.
I bet if it's real similar,
I mean it might be even an alcohol might
lose.
Like alcohol might be worse for you than
cocaine.
They're both are terrible.
No one's advocating them as like a
health remedy,
but alcohol might be worse than coke,
but we still that fucking shit
everywhere.
Yeah.
I pretty much agree with you on that.
I think we need adults and children,
but let's get back to children.
There was something that you didn't just
say get.
There was things about Bernie Sanders is
a economic platform you didn't like.
He just said a bunch of crazy shit about
marginal tax rate that he didn't think
the marginal tax rate is like was it
eisenhower had it at 90 percent while he
was in office and they asked him if a
marginal tax of 90 percent was too high
and he said,
no.
Now,
wow,
that's 90 percent.
Here's the thing about taxes and this is
the number one most important point.
We're talking here.
We're not talking about rich people.
Definitely having income equality,
having way too much money,
way too much influence in changing the
laws to make it even easier for them to
protect themselves and save money.
We're not talking about that.
We're talking about taxes and taxes are
sneaky because taxes go to the
government and the more money the
government gets,
the bigger it gets.
It becomes cancer.
It starts fucking growing and swelling
and you get bureaucracy and you get red
tape and you get a lot of bullshit.
If you could ensure that the money was
going to these really enlightened people
who are super wise and are going to
figure out some awesome solutions to
reengineer our society and they make
poor people happy and well fed,
well then yeah,
that's a great idea,
but until then what you're doing is you
just.
You're finding successful people and
you're taking more from them like you're
cutting away incentive incentive.
You're cutting away this ability to get
to the place where you could buy an
island.
You're saying you shouldn't be able to
do that.
Well,
I don't know if you can do cocaine every
day of your life or you can bust your
ass and develop a company like Google
and then buy a fucking island that's
also in the game.
It's in the game.
It doesn't necessarily mean you're evil
and this idea that because someone
figures out how to do it and I'm talking
about only ethically and within the
boundaries of the rules.
I think the issue that Bernie says that
I agree with is people that don't work
within the boundaries of the rules that
we all agreed on and they've figured out
all these sneaky fucking loopholes and
it essentially bribed politicians to
making it easier for them to move money
around and not pay taxes on things.
I'm with him 100 percent on that,
but the.
I don't think the answer is taxing the
fuck out of people,
I think,
and he's going to have to tax the middle
class higher too.
He's admitted that when he goes over his
life.
Sure.
It's crazy.
Plan you should take.
People don't need to be taxed more.
We need to do is figure out a
responsible method of managing the money
that we already fucking pay you guys.
That's way better than taking more.
That's way better than taking more so
when someone says they want to see more
taxes,
I go,
stop with this talk.
You're doing a shitty job of managing
all the money people are giving you
right now.
How about figure that out first?
Yeah,
I mean you're definitely right and I'm
running for office.
Jamie,
you're gonna run for office,
fire it up to Jay.
Got Me fired up.
I don't usually get this fired up about
something I think is a rigged game.
Well,
it turned progress.
Turned you into a believer in a ways.
A little bit.
But let me tell you this.
I mean,
I agree with you,
but I mean,
um,
you know,
government,
I mean the government program,
there's definitely some government
programs that produce results and have
efficacy and shit.
Yes.
But you know,
you're right,
there's,
there's too much bureaucracy,
there's too much.
There's too many things where everything
is just fucking in disarray.
Like the va and Shit,
you know,
there's,
there was so many files in one va
building that the building was actually
collapsing,
you know,
just under the weight of all these files
upon
files.
So you know,
it,
it is kind of hard to argue that more
money needs to be spent when the
situation is like that.
What's also going to the irs and the irs
is.
But I mean there's so many tactics
before.
There's so many problems though in this
country that really do need to be
resolved.
Like our infrastructure is shit and no
one wants to talk about infrastructure
because it isn't boring fucking topic.
No one wants to talk about the bridges
and roads crumbling and shit.
No,
it's good point.
That's a very good point.
You know,
the architects and engineers been
telling us for years,
our,
uh,
our grades and infrastructure are
fucking d's and f's.
We're not doing great.
You know,
I grew up in Boston or costs a lot of
money to fix it is.
I grew up in Boston and Boston had the
big dig.
Do you remember that?
That's also one thing I like about
trump.
By the way.
He,
that he has seems to be committed to
rebuilding America's infrastructure.
That's one thing I will give him.
That is true.
Well,
he's,
he's going to take a radical approach
that's different from the radical
approach of Bernie Sanders to,
in my opinion,
those are the two that are most
interesting to me.
Unless someone can prove to me that
Hillary Clinton is not totally healthy
and,
and cheese.
Um,
and that also she's not just some robot
monster.
That's what she is though.
She's color Schullery.
You don't think she's interested in her?
I think she's pure.
I mean like I've been.
Maybe I would be interested in her if I
could look beneath the mask,
if I could see who she actually is the
person and get a sense of a human being
that resides within this completely fake
exterior with just to be just a place to
advocate because I kept doing it.
Do it.
How hard is it to be fucking Hillary
Clinton?
It's probably brutal.
The scrutiny that she gets to the
constant attention,
the people like she probably has to put
up a wall just to get through life,
you know?
I mean,
her behavior as a politician probably
mimics her behavior as a person.
Look at the amount of Shit Donald trump
gets about to recommend mushrooms to
Hillary and Donald together.
Look at Donald Trump gets one thing that
Donald Trump.
He takes criticism way better than
Hillary because Donald Trump's response
to criticism is like,
I don't give a fuck.
Fuck you.
Right.
Hillary Clinton tries to project this
image of being this flawless being that
never makes a mistake,
and even if you think she did,
you're mistaken,
you're wrong to Donald Trump on
mushrooms with Mexicans in Mexico,
so he gets a deep love of Mexico.
I just fuck this border.
He just goes,
fuck this border.
Why do we have a border?
Fuck,
let's just have all the same money and
no border.
Boom,
the gates open,
legalized and legalize mushrooms and
weed,
and you would have liked the cartel
would have zero power.
They would go under or they would be
significantly.
We wonder what the result would be of
trying to merge the dollar and the peso
together in norland currency.
Well,
white dudes were to explode all over the
country.
You would have white,
white fat guys with like loose skin
screaming at the top of their lungs like
that movie scanners.
I love that.
Why?
If they open up the fucking borders,
oh my God,
it would be amazing.
It'd be.
It'd be great.
It would be.
It really would.
It would be great.
People need to stop just as long as you
don't let any Canadians in federal law.
They would make it way more polite.
I'll tell you what.
Are we in Canada?
One of the other.
Now there's less of them,
so I think that we would just make them
rude,
obnoxious assholes like us.
Um,
I don't know,
man.
They're pretty firmly established as
nice folks.
They are so much nicer than Americans.
I would say Canadians are 20 percent
nicer.
Yeah.
I've,
uh,
I've met some Canadians,
so I would agree.
It's weird.
They're strange country though.
When you first go waiting,
like going from Boston to Montreal.
I'm waiting for like the true people to
come out.
My can we,
you guys are in the cold to how come
you're not a bunch of evil cunt like me.
You can find mean people everywhere.
Sure.
But the difference between the way
people behaved in Montreal versus the
way people behaved in Boston,
I was like,
oh,
how weird.
Well,
Boston's like very aggressive.
Yeah,
it's like known for that.
Yeah.
It's boat people.
People that came over on boats drunk.
They crashed their 200 years ago.
They stayed and they fuck they had kids
ruined their lives.
They had kids ruin their lives and now
here they are right now,
a few,
four or five generations later,
maybe three.
I should point out that,
um,
the Boston accent is one of the most
horrible sounds to my ears.
It's disgusting.
It's really wretched.
I had one for awhile because I was uh,
you know,
when I moved to,
um,
hear it anymore,
but I hear it occasionally if I have a
couple of drinks,
a word will come out.
But I heard myself a talk once and I was
like,
what?
I heard like a recording and I was like,
what the fuck?
That's what I sound like.
I didn't realize I sounded like that.
So I made a concerted effort to stop
speaking like that where could really
hard and had oh,
stop things that they all talk like
that.
It's a monsters.
Don't do it,
but it's fun.
I'll tell you what though.
It's funny when it comes out of
comedian,
I'll tell you what though.
I'm my,
my southern accent will come out if I'm
angry or I'm really drunk.
Yeah.
Got To just do y'all,
did y'all ever come out of your mouth?
Oh yeah.
I'll say y'all.
Even even without speaking in a southern
southern affectation,
I'll still use y'all because I think.
Yeah,
I actually will make an argument for
y'all because you know,
it is actually easier than it's,
it's,
it's a,
it's a legitimate contraction.
You all,
y'all,
I mean know there's no a in in you,
but whatever.
You know what I like to know y'all,
it seems to buy pasta all.
It seems to be almost always friendly.
It is like,
you know,
y'all gonna get killed.
That's not even in that context.
It sounds friendly.
Fucked up.
I guess you could say it like that,
but it's like,
but it's more like what y'all doing,
you know,
like everybody's like casual.
It's a casual word.
Well,
it's the difference between the black
and the white.
Y'All,
you know,
what are you doing?
Getting racist here and a little bit,
just a Smidgen.
Listen,
if there are any differences between
black people and white people,
I'd like you to not address those
because those in faculty be
microaggressions.
Well,
do you not know about microaggression?
I do know about microaggressions.
I mean,
it's a white male.
You're a walking microaggressions.
True.
It's true.
How dare you.
But you know,
black dudes have bigger dicks so they
don't ever know.
They don't object to that one.
That is microaggression.
Black men,
they never backed black men that are
like,
they have that expectation.
What if white men or white women,
either one only go out with them because
they expect the big black Dick and
meanwhile these guys,
they,
they dread,
they live in fear of the moment.
They have to put out their normal cock.
Well,
all they gotta do is when they whip it
out and be like,
surprise bitch,
that'll work.
Once it will work,
it'll work more than once.
We'll work on different people,
but you're going to have to get to that
position over and over and over again.
That's the hardest position.
I guess you'll just have to get by on
personality or something.
Boy,
you're asking a lot.
I have to do it.
I'm not working with much.
How did you start making these youtube
videos?
Um,
well,
you know,
it's funny,
I was,
I was there,
I was there from almost the beginning.
I'm the one of the few people that still
from the old youtube because when did
you start?
Uh,
nine years ago.
Wow.
Two thousand seven.
Two Thousand and eight Christ.
That's how long youtube tube's been
around.
Yeah.
While,
and,
but I mean it's not that long at all.
Yeah.
Well to me it seems like a really long
time.
That's a,
you know,
I think it started in 2006 or something,
so I wasn't there from the very
beginning.
But everyone who was big at the time,
I don't think any of them are big now.
I think they're all gone.
So I mean it seems like the shelf life
of a youtube channel is pretty short,
so I'm glad I've been around this entire
time.
Yeah.
But I mean I guess I just started
because I went on there,
I was already being like a fucking
asshole atheist troll to people in like
Internet forums and stuff.
So a bunch of people,
they like the way I wrote,
they told me I should take my,
you know,
I should take it on youtube and I was
Kinda like,
Eh,
I don't know,
I don't really feel like I have much of
a camera presence or whatever,
but I,
I,
I went on youtube and I made a horrible,
horrible fucking video that is just
wretched in every way.
And you know,
I walk around my garage talking in this
monotone voice like this,
but for some reason some people liked it
and uh,
I kept doing it and I got a little bit
more natural in front of the camera as I
stopped treating it.
Like,
I dunno,
I started treating it more like a person
or a friend.
And uh,
over time it just,
I don't know,
I've never been like the biggest channel
on youtube or anything,
but it's just always been consistently
successful.
Consistently grows consistently,
seems to keep pace with,
you know,
whatever the standard of being on the
lower end of the
popularity scale of youtube is.
Well,
I feel like youtube in particular,
it's one of those things where if you do
a show like yours,
what's really important is consistency.
You've got to do it a lot so that people
get addicted to it and you also just
have to put a lot of effort into it.
And those are two things that you do,
you know,
you're really consistent,
you put a lot of videos and I try,
you obviously have like really well
thought out points of view in these
things and you argue them well and,
and in a funny way,
you know,
and that's kind of interesting that
before youtube and before the Internet I
got like,
you would have struggled to find a
forum,
like if you wanted to go to some
television production company and go,
Hey,
my name's Tj,
you know,
I live in Blah Blah Blah,
and I'm but thinking about doing this
thing where I just fucking turn a camera
on me and I just say what I feel about
shit.
Like yeah,
that sounds great tj.
Get the fuck Outta here.
Get outta here man.
And watch that piece of shit.
We know how many millions of views do
you have on your Youtube Channel?
High average.
Four to 5 million views a month.
Yeah.
Fucked up NBC.
You fucked up.
I could have got four or $5 million
views a month.
What are you doing instead?
What do you got instead?
Huh?
What kind of bullshit.
And you sell in America right now.
But you know,
the,
the weird thing about the whole youtube
thing is though,
I mean I have two successful channels
now.
I have the amazing atheist channel,
which is the older channel.
I have the drunken peasants,
a podcast channel.
I'm doing kind of what you were doing.
Um,
and that's doing well.
That's only a couple of years old,
but you know,
I was thinking if,
if,
if it weren't for Youtube,
I mean before when I was a kid,
I used to want to either be a writer and
really it was writing that Kinda got me
into doing youtube anyway because I was
just like a forum troll that would argue
with people on the Internet.
I had no fucking life.
Right?
Um,
well because it's exciting.
It's fun,
it's fun for me and I like pushing
buttons.
It pissing people off,
you know,
I'll say things just to piss people off.
Of course,
you know,
and um,
I do that.
I mean I guess that probably I would've
had to try to be a comedian or
something,
but when you were there in the day with
flame wars,
I wouldn't want to be a comedian though
because I don't want to have to always
be funny.
I don't want to feel pressure.
Like everything I say has to be a
fucking joke,
you know?
Well it only does on stage,
you know,
I know that.
But I mean I,
I don't want the,
I don't want people to think that the
performance has to be about laughter or
whatever you're producing,
whether it's a song of the cast stuff.
I try to be funny.
Another thing though is,
you know,
it's a lot harder to gauge whether
people are finding it funny or not
because you know,
I don't have a live reaction to what I'm
saying.
So sometimes some shit that I think is
really funny,
people would be like,
this video was cringe or something,
you know?
I'm like,
Oh fuck,
I guess I will.
That's always going to be.
The king wasn't as funny as I thought I
bombed.
While you're also dealing with a.
what's the sample group?
What percentage of people leave
comments?
Is it even one?
It might not even be one tiny.
It's a tiny in that sample.
It's a tiny percentage of people that
write the videos.
It's a percentage of people that
comment on the videos.
Most people they just watched.
They don't interact in any way
whatsoever,
so it's impossible to know what they
think,
but you know,
they keep coming back so they must see
something.
They're like,
well,
and the people that are fine,
like the one thing you said that piss
them off,
that makes them go on this rant about
it.
You should die in the fucking car
accident.
Those those people,
like you're missing the whole point of
what one of these things is like if you
have a different point of view,
you should establish your own channel
and you should go fucking make your own
videos about it man,
and if you can even link to them in a
reply video,
you could say,
you know,
fuck face made a reply to Tj and you
know,
this is what I think about you and your
fucking shitty atheists ideas and when
Jesus does come back,
make a video man,
make a video.
And that's the interesting thing about
today is that someone can do that.
Well,
the problem is they try and no one
cares.
Yeah,
well it's way easier to critique than it
is to do obviously.
Yeah,
it's very easy to sit there and say
you're an idiot and everything you do is
wrong.
To actually do what I do and be
successful at it,
it's a little harder.
The problem is like to really critique
someone.
If someone's critiquing someone,
I can read their words and I can try to
think if make it make sense to me and it
might make sense,
but I don't know them and that is,
that is a problem because if I don't
know them or I don't know their work,
like if they're an artist,
like I say Michael Stipe or someone like
that from rem writes something about
someone,
I go,
hmm,
well he seems to be a weird,
interesting Kinda guy.
I wonder if I would agree with his
opinions on things and wonder if his
perspective is skewed.
What?
What does it do?
His words represent honesty or is there
some sort of emotional imbalance that
he's a who?
What is,
what does that,
what is actually going on?
Unless you know someone,
it's hard.
Why?
Like why is he getting mad at the
amazing atheist?
What is what's going on?
Which I wish more people would think
like that.
I'm like,
why is he so angry at you?
Why?
Why is he threatening you?
Why you freak out?
People don't get mad about ideas that
they think are wrong.
They get afraid of ideas they think
might be right.
That's a big part of it.
You know,
and,
and when you,
when I'm someone who will come out there
and just brazenly say that someone's
most deeply cherished beliefs are just
wrong and stupid,
you know,
of course people are getting upset.
Of course people are going to have the
reaction of,
Oh my God,
this guy,
he's obnoxious.
He's an asshole.
He's an idiot.
Which all might be true,
but I still don't think there's a god.
Um,
do you think there's no god or do not
believe in God?
I don't think we even got.
Yeah,
I think there's a difference.
Right?
So you don't have a thing and let people
go with WHO's not you fucking more.
You're atheist.
Bullshit.
Let's just,
let's just follow me for a second here.
I think there's one thing if you believe
in God,
okay.
If you believe in God,
you are essentially,
you're,
you're believing in something that you
have no evidence of.
There's no proof of it.
There's no direction that points to it.
There's certainly some weird stuff going
on in the universe.
The Universe is fascinating,
matter itself is a wonderful.
It's amazing.
It's incredible,
incomprehensible,
incomprehensible and infinite,
right?
But believing in something that you have
no evidence is very different than not
believing in something because when you
say you don't believe in God,
it doesn't mean that there's no god,
but there's no evidence of it
whatsoever.
I've never seen anything like if you and
I die and we're in heaven and I'm like,
Tj,
can you fucking believe this shit?
Be like,
Holy Shit,
we were so stupid.
High Five,
you know?
I mean,
if there is a wonderful,
beautiful God that's all about love and
created the universe,
by the way,
he's going to know that you didn't know
and he's not going to be mad at you.
That's like a friend not knowing when
you're.
You don't know where they're from.
You don't know when their birthday is,
so they come over your house and beat
the fuck out of you because you didn't
say happy birthday.
He's like,
dude,
I didn't know you didn't tell me.
Well,
that's what.
What?
By God not being here to tell us all
this stuff.
Most people,
most people think that God is a is a
dick.
I mean,
most people who believe in God,
they called themselves God fearing,
you know,
they don't.
I'm sure there are.
There are people who preach about a god
of love and forgiveness and all this
shit,
but most of these people preach about a
God that expects you to blindly believe
in him or suffer eternal torment forever
in hell and be tortured.
It's nonsense,
but we don't know what happens when we
die.
It's really that simple.
It could be just like a DMT trip.
It could be like a completely new DMT is
released in the brain when people die.
Yeah.
During moments of heavy stress when your
body feels like it's going to die.
Um,
and we,
we even know now,
thanks to the work of this guy,
Dr Rick Strassman who wrote that book,
the spirit molecule spirit molecule.
It's amazing.
He wrote,
he,
they did these clinical trials out of
the University of New Mexico and he
documented it in this book or they're
administering DMT intravenously,
really fucking wild shit.
But he's got this thing called the
cottonwood research foundation where
they're trying to do more dmt studies
and one of the things they've found is
that they've isolated one of these
universities that mice produce dmt in
their pineal gland.
Like that is a fact now.
Whereas before it was just anecdotal
evidence that pointed to that.
So like the seed of the soul,
the third,
I like all that.
Like the,
this gland in the center of your brain
really is the DMT factory,
which is what you know,
ancient people have been saying forever.
I mean that's the third eye from eastern
mysticism.
That is,
that's what it represents.
So that is supposedly what we release
our brain releases when we die,
which is really amazing if you stop and
think about it or if you've had a dmt
trip,
but it might not even be that about
this.
That might be just the doorway that gets
you to diapers and all of a sudden you
wake up and you're a fucking baby again.
You got to do this shit all over again.
You got to live as Tj and you've got to
do the same fucking life.
Your parents make the same moves.
Your Dad,
mom gets a voice at the same time.
This,
this is like a Nietzschean ideal of
eternal recurrence.
Why not?
If existence kid
can be real.
If the hold on a second,
if these actual distance of us talking,
sitting here know airplanes landing,
all these things take place.
Why can't it take place in an infinite
number of times?
It could,
you know,
but that's kind of,
that's kind of a,
the one of the most compelling arguments
to live an interesting life if you're
going to have to actually go through it
over and over and over again in exactly
the same fashion with nothing different
or not.
Or maybe you do get to change,
I don't know.
But that concept of living the same life
over and over again is um,
that's been around a long time.
But actually a word for it,
full disclosure though,
my belief is generally that when I'm,
when I'm dead,
I'm just going to blink out of
existence.
But why do you believe that?
I just don't understand you believing
that you don't have any information,
but I couldn't understand you believe in
result.
The reason I believe that is because I
think that my consciousness has seated
within my brain and that my brain is
unique to this time and place,
and that even if it were to be recreated
identically,
you know,
right next to me,
that still wouldn't be me because
there's,
there's still a separation there.
You're not a clone of yourself.
I think that,
you know,
uh,
but I,
I kind of try to live in the eternal
presence,
you know,
just,
that's good.
That's smart.
I don't believe in a,
I don't believe.
I think that,
you know,
if you were to pull out a gun and shoot
me in the head that it would be the end
of my existence.
I would never form another thought.
I would never have another experience.
I can't prove that though.
It's totally just what I believe.
It's totally possible that you're right,
it's,
but it's also compelling the idea that
what the brain is is the universe
finding a way to imagine itself in a
physical three dimensional form.
That's what the brand represents and
that this dimension that we exist in
right now,
solid things is just one of an infinite
number of possibilities that exist all
throughout the cosmos and that what
we're experiencing right now is the
body,
the physical embodiment of life,
multicellular structures coming together
and forming these coalitions,
which is essentially what your body is,
right?
There's all this bacteria and all this
different shit that's going on and then
it has to take in life foods and enzymes
and creates this environment,
this in its most advanced form,
at least as far as its ability to
manipulate your house right now.
Have you ever heard Howard blooms the
frames or.
I'll forget it.
Okay,
good.
What did I say?
Fuck,
sorry.
But,
uh,
you're talking about a lot of stuff that
my friend Howard Bloom has written about
in a book he wrote called the global
brain that basically talks about exactly
that coalescence of,
you know,
a single bacteria to a biofilm,
a bacterial colonies,
to an organism,
to organisms getting together and
forming societies.
And you know,
it's,
it's all about how,
you know,
we,
we're,
we're climbing this ladder of
connectivity and you know,
like Los Angeles is a good example at
you.
You kind of likened it in a video I saw
of yours to the mold eating the
sandwich,
you know,
we're,
we're kind of that force because
humanity is like a super organism and
we've built this crazy large society
that no other ape species on the planet
has been able to come close to.
Well that was the concept was that it's
all moving towards this ultimate goal of
things being more and more complex.
Right?
Well,
while that's happening,
the brain,
which is what the human uses to go
through this experience could have been
created like over time and through all
these advancements for,
for the universal sort of experiencing
itself for the universe to imagine
itself and what we're doing as these
weird organisms that changed things as
we're,
we're designing something,
we're building towards something.
There's no question that if things
continue to get more and more complex,
which we are fucking starving for,
we're constantly thirsty for new
inventions.
Innovation.
That's what everybody wants and no one
wants like a static world.
No one says,
hey,
everything we have right now
technologically is perfect.
We need to stop spending money on
research and inventions.
Let's just have joy.
All the shit we have and just be nice to
each other.
That's not what we're interested in at
all.
But so if you look at us objectively,
if you like,
pull back and go,
what is this thing doing?
Like what is this thing doing?
This thing is constantly getting better
at getting closer together and it by
combining people and electronics,
combining people and technology.
I mean the dinosaurs could have had that
perspective though,
like yeah man,
we're built into like bigger and better
dinosaurs one day.
It's just going to be the biggest
ultimate dinosaur that rules the
universe or something.
You know?
Instead they went extinct.
Yeah,
but they got hit with a rock cheating.
If you fire like it's cheating.
If you find like a cannon ball,
I mean if it's going up and up and up,
you might make the mistake of saying
this is always going to go up and up and
up and then,
you know,
eventually gravity catches up with it.
I just don't think we could take it for
granted that we have some sort of great
destiny on the horizon.
I think,
you know,
it's up to us to make that happen,
but I don't think we can take it for
granted.
Oh,
definitely not.
No one's suggesting that definitely
can't.
I don't think it has to work out.
Look,
here's a fucking gigantic super volcano
under yellowstone.
Could easily blow up and killed.
Basically everybody on the continent as
close to it.
That fucker blows.
This is a global extinction event.
I mean this,
this.
Could they think that that one that blue
was at in Indonesia,
chop the human race down to just a few
thousand people 70,000 years ago.
They think it might have been as few as
2000 people left.
Well,
the real detriment is the clouds
blocking out the sun.
Exactly.
Lack of food.
Photosynthesis.
No vegetables,
fucking serious climate change,
very,
very drastic,
very cold,
real cold,
real quick,
no food and a lot of people are going to
die of sickness and illness.
Yeah,
it's a super volcano.
Could fuck up everything and then that's
the argument that a lot of people have
made as far as people that have looked
to try to revise those current model of
history based on cataclysmic events like
look back and say,
well,
you know,
there's a lot of these cultures that
created these incredible stone
structures.
Like maybe they died off because some
shit happened like he couldn't get.
It might not have just been disease.
There might be like a series of media
impacts.
Super volcanoes,
all sorts of different.
There's like shit that can happen to
this world all the time.
California is due for an earthquake at
any moment.
This we can be sitting here doing this
podcast and any moment a nine kid hit
and half a fucking Malibu could slide
right into the ocean and waves a hundred
feet high can just roll three,
four miles in.
At least.
It'd be an interesting episode.
It would be a dope podcasts,
but I think,
well,
we figured we need a battery.
Joe Rogan goes screaming into the abyss
of the earth.
We need a battery backup.
We're strategically far away from the,
uh,
from the ocean for that reason.
Oh,
you're saying,
okay,
you've thought of this.
You've planned.
I had been thinking about setting up
shop in downtown La.
Man.
I have this weird compelling notion to
try to get to downtown La and set
something up in there like put,
put together a studio in downtown.
It just seems like a spot to go to right
now.
Like I'm drawn to it like the ring,
you know what I'm saying?
Ring of power.
Yeah.
Well which are on,
was using it for
something about,
uh,
going there.
But that's a high enough to have a good
vantage point to see the waves come in
and know that you can't get it out of
the way.
And I don't know,
I just don't plan for stuff like that.
I figured if I'm gonna die,
I'm gonna die.
I'm not going to try to avert some
unlikely fate of the tsunami waves.
I mean,
you know,
I figured like if that's what's going to
kill me,
I'll just stand out there and I'll look
at them and I'll be like,
alright,
embrace me.
Death.
Right.
Like the final scene of deep impact.
Yeah.
You know,
just fucking like.
Except that shit.
Don't be trying to.
Fuck.
I'm going to watch from above is all the
fucking stupid people drown.
Told you it was going to happen.
You morons will.
That would be a lot like walking dead,
right?
Yeah.
Like the,
the people that are free are the people
that are dead.
The people that are trapped in this
shitty world surrounded by flesh eating
monsters.
Those are the people that are alive.
The of live fucked up.
That's why they did that whole like play
on words with that one episode where
he's like,
we are the walking dead,
you know?
Oh yeah.
I see a twisted it around.
Subverted expectation was fleshed out
that no,
I pretended it didn't happen.
It happened.
It was beautiful.
Do you watch the new walking dead?
No.
It's really fucking good.
Is it because I heard bad things?
How dare those people?
Those people suck and those people don't
know shit.
I'm addicted to that show and I know
that sometimes it's pretty hokey and
cheesy,
but I do like it.
I like it too.
I liked both of them,
but the new one is way more like a movie
or way more like maybe a netflix show.
Whereas the old ones seems like an NBC
show.
Yes.
I love about the walking dead is that
every episode is just like,
what?
Miserable Shit.
We're all characters go through next and
then it's just like misery,
executive object,
fucking horror,
terror.
Just no moment of goodness.
And even if there is,
it's just so it can be taken away,
you know,
and you know,
that kind of makes people feel better
about their,
their actual lives I think.
I think a lot of the sjw types around
the Internet need to get into that show.
So people who have a real life,
it's a social justice warrior.
It's what he's referring to when he says
asj w dot m r a.
that's not one said really.
Anyone on the Internet knows what I'm
talking about,
but there's a lot of people that are not
on the Internet.
They're just getting this podcast.
We have to help them.
Lucky them.
I don't want it.
If they don't know what a fucking sjws
don't do them the disservice of telling
them what you said Mra earlier,
which allowed people's rights,
activist or advocate.
Right.
I guess it can be advocate to.
I've always heard activists,
but it basically means like men are
oppressed in America.
It's both.
It's like,
oh my God,
shut up.
Yeah.
It's not a good position to be in,
but
we,
we discussed their valid thing.
It's easy.
It's easy to mock.
It's easy to mock it up.
Exactly.
But what that was,
you know,
uh,
my,
my whole point was like,
a men's rights activist would want to
support you when you were being sexually
harassed by that super horny.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe I'm biting the hand.
They should potentially feed.
Called a couple friends.
Had A fucking gang.
Bang.
That crazy bitch.
That's what you should've done.
She's like,
you all right.
You want to fuck,
here's some guys that are down to fuck
with wish she'd be like to kind of grow.
Whereas those weird fucking stockings
connected with rubber bands for some
reason.
Why is that hot when they have the
stocking and it's got like strap and
like you've got a harness and shit like
you're ready to go.
Fucking parasailing.
Like why?
Why is that hot?
Those.
What are those called?
Garter straps.
Are Gardeners started or something?
What the fuck is that?
Why is that hot?
Because that's what you're dirty boss
would have.
That's what she would have those,
you just see it in a lot of movies and
shit too.
You know why?
Because that way they can fuck without
taking their panties down because their
panties only go up to like mid high.
And then above that it's all just meat
almost.
I was uh,
you know,
there was probably a racist reasons why
I didn't want to get with her too.
She wasn't,
she's black and she's,
Oh,
well you're a racist.
Dare you.
That's the real.
That's the real problem here.
God Damn it.
You have a lot of problems.
I know I'm just,
I'm racist,
I'm sexist.
I'm just a horrible person.
Um,
if she was white,
you think you'd fuck her?
Maybe.
Wow.
Damn.
I know you're not allowed to have that
preference.
I'll just let you know.
That's racist.
Well,
I like Brazilian girls better than white
girls.
Too Racist to maybe she moved to Brazil.
Maybe should get the fuck out of my own
because I don't like crushing poverty
either.
So.
Oh well.
Maybe you can go over there and find a
nice gal.
Yeah.
And treat her for the wonderful life
that you live on.
Being a youtube star.
Yeah,
we can do that.
Do you ever like go back and forth with
any girls from there that are desperate
to leave now?
I'm not.
I'm not suave enough for that endeavor.
If this woman was like a really hot,
like stone cold Russian lady and she
kept grabbing.
Yeah.
I was thinking I should know just like
really sexy but strong.
A kind of scary but still really.
Okay.
I'm talking about you're talking about
like,
uh,
like that chick from rocky for.
Yeah.
Who still owned while up Marion diddy.
He married her.
Bridgette Nielsen?
Yeah.
She was a fucking giant Uber woman.
I like that.
Yeah,
I do.
that's exactly what I'm talking.
Things would have played out
differently.
Totally different.
It's just not in the blank checks,
but that's okay.
I am now.
Just not then.
Well,
you know what man?
Why is it a bad thing to not be sexually
into whatever.
I don't like meat.
Maybe it'd be like you don't like skinny
women.
You don't like tall women.
You don't like short.
It's not a preference issue.
Like are you allowed to say sexually you
you're not attracted to black women or a
black man.
Are you allowed to say that or is that
racist?
It's racist.
That's weird.
It's considered racist.
It's only about sex as a thing.
If you're a lover as a human being.
If you go to the SJ W,
which our audiences just learned what
that means,
circles,
then it's racist.
If you're in the MRA circles than it's
not so raised,
then I'm on their side now among them
that I will admit it's easier to take
their side,
but I still just think there's too much
of this.
I'm a victim.
Feel sorry for me.
Give me special rights.
Give me special privileges.
I just tired of that line.
I mean,
look,
we had people that were oppressed groups
in America for a long time.
No one denies it,
but I mean,
is that really still the case?
Like she'll give me.
I always asked feminists,
like,
tell me an objective objectively
provable,
right?
Give me a right that I have that you
don't have.
And it's just silence.
Like,
well,
uh,
you know,
oh,
what about the wage gap?
Wage gap.
There's no,
there's no right.
There's lots,
but don't just don't remember though.
Like there was a wage gap.
You know,
you already know this.
Somebody wrote this down and just don't
say it.
The wage gap is real.
Guys.
Just
stop that space.
You know what?
Can't argue with those facts.
I've done some research,
I've discovered that in certain
industries there are wage gaps,
there are individual wage gaps in
certain industries.
Like what industries are our primary.
I don't remember off the top of my head.
I think a real estate and stuff like
that,
but I mean that could in real estate's a
weird one though because it kind of
depends on how successful you are at it.
You know,
it's,
it's not like you're going in and doing
a nine to five and get into fucking
salary.
I know a dude who bought a house and the
girl who was selling the house was hot
and he was a single guy and he showed up
at the house and this bitch was in the
tub naked.
That's one way to sell a house.
There used to be able to do that in the
early two thousands.
My friend for fucking social media
ruined that party.
You know,
he'll blow her shit on facebook and ruin
her life.
She's just trying to get freaky and sell
a house.
Maybe get some Dick,
catch some of that loose dick.
This float around when you're a hot real
estate agent,
why not?
I want to share levels or no bubbles.
I envisioned bubbles.
Bubbles is bubbles is the move.
Yeah,
but it's pretty gangster to go fucking
straight,
naked.
Clear in native.
I think it's better if there's bubbles
because then she stands up and then the
bubbles kind of run down her body,
you know?
Well,
then also might be a decision of whether
or not she could become your woman.
Like she could be your girlfriend or
your wife if she has bubbles.
Like this pitch just loved me and she
took a chance.
She's crazy.
We went for it and now she's so fun and
spontaneous.
We get along great,
but if you show up and she's just cudi
ass naked,
he wouldn't be like,
this bitch is crazy.
I gotta get Outta here.
I can't buy a house from her.
She's going to know my number.
You know,
like you might immediately think she's
so nuts.
She took off her clothes and now she's
in fucking pussy soup over here.
Why there's got to be bubbled.
She's making a big cup of asshole tea
and she wants me to come over and look
into it like,
get,
get dressed.
I want to buy a house.
You want to go out for a drink?
We'll go out for a drink.
Um,
some other time,
but not if there's bugs.
Show me the fucking floor.
Pennants word.
Jesus Christ.
What's the inspection look like?
I would think she's trying to distract
me.
I can try to distract me.
What did the inspector said?
These,
this fucking house.
I've termites.
Crazy bitch house could be falling apart
all around you.
Just like,
Damn.
It could be right.
We don't know.
We don't know shit man.
She's distracting me.
It's sexual.
She's sexually harassing you,
right?
Because you didn't request this sexually
distracting you and she's using her
sexuality to distract you from the world
around you.
Let's keep you from making good
decisions.
Let's flip it.
What if you are a young,
attractive woman and you show up and
you're trying to buy a house and you
hear,
oh,
c'mon.
And Debbie,
I'm upstairs and you go up.
I'm Mike.
You looking for the real estate agent,
you're a little person,
you're holding onto your iphone,
checking the text message,
make sure you've got the right place and
you opened the door and this dude's got
a fucking rod and he's sitting there.
It's poking out like a periscope.
I was thinking the same thing.
Call the fucking police right away.
Even if he had bubbles.
Is he naked?
No,
I'm calm.
I'm wearing bubble bath.
You don't where bubbles are there?
It'd be like a court case.
Was he naked,
ma'am?
I was not naked.
You could not see me.
What?
Are you naked in the water,
sir?
No,
I was wearing bubbles.
That is not clothing.
Who are you to decide what clothing is
made up?
I was making.
So I was wearing something that does
that.
It,
it hit me in a modest way.
You could not see my genitals and uh,
I feel like I was okay.
Why would,
your honor,
why would it be okay if he had a towel
on?
But it's not okay if it's got bubbles,
doesn't tell them bubbles to the same
fucking thing.
I don't know if she would immediately
call the police.
I think she would probably just scream
and leave.
I call the police.
I'd say no,
I press nine slash 11.
While I was in the house.
I'd be like,
I'm looking right at this guy's Dick.
This is not cool.
It's not even.
His house is freaky fucker wants to take
baths and some houses that.
I mean,
what is she?
What is.
She was in it,
but what if she just showed up and she's
like,
Ooh,
Dick.
Because when.
What would you think at that point?
Well then you're good.
You know,
as long as that happens.
But that's pretty unlikely though.
Yeah.
That's like $100 off the ball ticket
ever fucking made off.
The chances are that crazy,
but they're close.
Think it's one and $292 million that
she'll jump on the deck.
If you didn't know the guy and you just
showed up and his dick was poking out of
the water,
you'd probably assume that was the last
few hours of your life
you would run and expect to immediately
run into a guy wearing a fucking hood.
You know,
like you,
you standing in the next room like this,
I'm going to die today.
I'm,
I'm a young girl.
I can't protect myself physically from
this guy with his heart on and who knows
how we set this up and who other.
Who else is in this building wants to
chop me up and burned me in the woods.
So I would assume,
I don't think they need to.
They don't want to chop her up.
You know,
sometimes they do though.
You just fucking has a big Dick.
He wants to maybe do something maybe.
Or maybe she walked into a fucking trap
and this guy's like,
Charles Manson,
you're always assuming the worst about
matt,
about meme man.
You know he guys,
some guy sitting there in a truck with a
big erection.
He wants to chop her up and fuck it.
Barrier in the woods.
Some woman's in the tub,
she just wants to suck this guy's Dick
and show him the time of his life and
maybe sell them a house.
Do you not watch TV?
What you're saying?
That's what I'm saying is not normal.
I think it is pretty normal.
I think that's probably how most people
would think about it.
Yeah,
I think so too,
man.
Why maybe the MRI's,
MRI's,
men's rights informant.
Hey,
I just want to tell you these fucking
men on this side plot and some shit.
They're going to troll your forums.
That's.
That would be a men's right informant or
a rat for the men's right organization
that tries to befriend feminists to get
close to them.
I try to try to be there.
Their lovers.
Would it be,
uh,
would it be um,
a men's with the men's rights informant
be someone who's a coil to the men's
rights movement and trying to gather
intel on feminists or reporting Intel on
the men's rights movement back to
feminine?
That's a very good point.
It could because I could see it going
either way.
They're bright.
You could totally see like a guy
pretending to be a social justice
warrior who becomes a male feminist and
he uses hashtag feminism on his twitter
page and he makes videos about feminism,
but really what he's doing is trying to
get deep,
deep,
deep into the roots of the organization.
His ultimate goal is to get a position
with someone like who's that woman you
were talking about earlier before what
Anita Sarkeesian got one,
like one of those like one of the queen
bees get very close to her and perhaps
maybe help write some of her stuff or
perhaps get closer and closer to the
organization to maybe perhaps he could
have some influence or find out their
strategies and then what he does in the
clan to Stein arrangement.
Whereas the fucking black peacoat and
fucking
a wool cap and he meets on the docks
with the.
A real man and the real man is like,
what are these cons planning?
And he's like,
oh,
I'll tell you right now.
And he and he becomes a men's right in
form it.
There you go.
Could be one of both things.
This could be a movie.
I would say it would most likely go the
other way though.
I would doubt.
I would doubt a guy would be able to
even keep the job if he was a real.
A real man.
That's right.
I said it a real man that goes deep into
the heart of the Social Justice Warrior
movement just to befriend feminists,
to try to be their allies.
A real man would get sick to his stomach
and a very short amount of time.
You think so?
Most likely,
unless they had really good points,
in which case they probably would just
be egalitarianism.
It wouldn't really be necessarily
feminine,
would probably be this thing.
They'd probably just be folks that
didn't want to get fucked with,
which is everybody,
which is all humans,
you know,
but men's rights act.
That's what I wonder though.
Why is it,
why is it a.
Why isn't it okay to just be like,
how about everyone just treats everyone
okay?
Should be like,
why can't.
What is it?
Why is that such a controversial idea?
Why when you present that to a feminist,
like let's just be gender,
egalitarianism,
egalitarian,
and all other ways and you know,
as long as someone's not hurting you or
you're not hurting them,
you could just do whatever the fuck you
want and you know,
you would think that that would be a
perfectly reasonable proposition for any
human being of any ideology.
But it seems like it's rejected so
roundly by so many people all the
fucking time,
like,
no,
we don't want to do that.
We want to have our stupid little
ideological clique's and be like,
yeah,
we're the feminist and where are the
Mras?
And we're gonna have some lame Internet
fight until the end of time and annoy
the shit out of everybody.
Well,
I think,
I honestly believe this all bullshit
aside.
I think people are way better at
communicating now than they've ever been
before and I think we're going through
some growing pains and I think that's
what a lot of this stuff is.
My,
my honest belief is that what we're
looking at winn block watch captain Kirk
Duke it out with that stupid fake lizard
is very similar in a cultural context
like that's art.
That's like a piece of art that was on
television.
That's unacceptable today.
Well,
there's also communication that was
normal back then.
That's unacceptable today and I think
along the way there's some battles and
some some lines get crossed and some
boundaries get established and I think
that's exactly what we're going through
right now.
When you blame men for everything and
then you won't talk about the real
issues like your issue because you're a
male,
you're getting sexually harassed as
inconsequential as compared to a woman
who was in the same situation or whether
it's divorce laws or whether it's
alimony or whether it's child support or
whether it's custody of the children.
As soon as you have a male versus female
perspective and you ignore the enormous
gigantic range of people that exist on
the female and the male side,
they're so different.
Everyone's so goddamn different to to
have an ATM or aB team.
I think it's becoming more and more
preposterous and I think that's sort of
been highlighted by why we can so freely
talk about this.
We're mining so much humor and goofing
on these people so easily because it's
so easy to goof on them that over time,
those differences,
the ridiculousness of it will be
highlighted by our culture to the point.
It will be common knowledge.
Everybody will know that it's ridiculous
to side with all women or decide with
all men.
Everyone will know that when two people
get drunk and have sex together,
if they're both consenting,
they both fucked up and no one raped
anybody.
You know?
There is a difference between rape and
two people getting drunk where the man
becomes a rapist and that's one of the
big problems right now that's going on
and this whole men's rights activist
versus feminists culture argument that
it's happened in at Occidental.
It's happened in numerous cases where
people have been blamed for things where
two adults get together.
They have consensual sex while they're
both intoxicated,
but the man becomes a rapist.
That's fucking bullshit and it's always
been bullshit.
It's so strange because there's no,
there's no other area where people are
exempted from their bad decisions while
they're drunk.
You know,
if I get drunk and I get in my car and I
crashed into a building or something,
no one says,
well you were drunk so you were
impaired.
So really the building attacked you or
how about this?
How about you assault someone,
you get drunk at assault,
someone you're responsible for your
actions.
100 for sure.
Yeah.
It's all stupid,
man.
It's stupid and it's,
it's based on if you hope,
if you're a woman and you open your legs
up while you're drunk and you,
they add,
bring it on,
you know you're not responsible for that
decision whatsoever.
Well,
I think that's the one decision where
society societal be like,
you know what?
You were taken advantage of.
You were raped.
I think that doesn't exist in most
aspects of society.
It only exists in universities and
amongst like super leftist,
progressive liberals.
That's the only way that they're trying
to turn the all of society into that.
Yes,
but it's being rejected is my point.
It's like the fact that there's so much
that's easy to criticize about it.
It's so easy to reject and uni just
sitting here when we just met today and
we both goofing on it like we like we
have a sketch,
like we planned out a sketch.
Was this the first time we've ever sat
down and talked together and we're like
bantering about this.
Like we've rehearsed it.
Like it's because it's so easy to mine.
There's so much preposterous,
stupid shit into it.
It's so.
I mean the,
the,
the stereotypes are so fucking obvious.
He's like really feeble men who like
defend these hideous women who have
purple hair.
Like what am I,
is this,
is this a fucking show on the WB from
the early nineties?
Like what is this?
Remember the web,
the Wayans brothers.
Everyone remembers that.
Come on.
I think as it becomes more and more
ridiculous,
the more people will crack on it.
Those,
those ridiculous aspect,
you know?
I don't know.
I don't have the same.
I guess I don't have the same faith in
people that you do because all what I
see right now is that here are some
ideas that I was subjected to these sjws
social justice warrior,
ultra feminist stuff.
I've been arguing with us on the
Internet for,
I don't know,
or six years
who said stop arguing with them.
They're not going to change.
I know,
but.
Well,
I do it because people like to watch it.
Like you said,
it's easy to mind,
but,
but uh,
I've seen them go from an obscure fringe
of Internet people who have no power
whatsoever to,
you know,
constantly having representatives on
mainstream media.
They've infiltrated the journalists on
so many publications now.
I know that right now America is kind of
going through a,
a disenfranchisement with the media in
general anyway.
But,
uh,
you know,
it does seem like these,
these people are permeating mainstream
culture more and more.
It doesn't seem to me like they're,
you know,
they're on the run or something.
Well,
you can put it this way,
and I'm not sure if this is a valid
comparison,
but when you choose to engage them
online,
it's very similar to them being
interviewed on CNN.
Whereas like it's fun,
it's fun,
or there's a point of view that's
controversial.
There's a hot a hot button that you can
hit if you have someone who does
something.
Some guy does something and some woman
goes on some television show and he
argues that that man should be tried for
rape because he had sex with intoxicated
woman,
let's say maybe a celebrity or a
rockstar or athlete or something like
that.
If that became an issue,
like you would immediately want to have
one of those people on because one of
those people is going to argue the very
strong position that that guy is a
rapist.
Whereas then you would have some other
men's rights guy on the other side or
some other,
you know,
social,
a libertarian type dude on the other
side and they would.
It would make for a great show and
that's what people do.
And so in doing that,
those movements grow and you find out
who that person is,
what their organization is,
what's the Hashtag,
find their twitter page,
boom,
like their facebook page,
you're in the circle.
And by doing that,
even you arguing with them online and
them doing this on these one of these
CNN type shows,
it's the same kind of thing and a lot of
ways because it's just,
it's creating a portal where people who
agree confine those,
those other folks that also doesn't
really seem like too many people will
find them through me,
agree with them.
Some of the things I see.
But that's comments and we've already
established the comments or maybe one
percent of the people watch if you
watch,
if you look at the metrics from the,
the,
the thumbs up and how many people
subscribe when they see those videos on
that stuff.
I'm sure there are people who find the
videos and to discover some feminists
through there,
but I've never made a thumbs up in my
life,
made a comment in my life.
Had Milo Yiannopoulos on the show a few
weeks back.
Uh,
I don't know if you're aware,
but he,
he,
his twitter has been unverified.
We talked about it yesterday.
It's insane.
It's very strange because I cannot
recall anyone's twitter ever becoming
unverified,
known plagiarists.
There's no plagiarists that are
verified,
that have been proven as plagiarists.
They're verified.
And One guy who likes to poke fun and
fuck with people and does it in a really
humorous wally funny.
I mean,
what is his fucking twitter handle?
Say the dangerous faggot.
I think that's what he calls himself.
Like it's in a giant label across the.
Yeah,
on the top is the dangerous faggot tour.
And uh,
his,
his username is like at Nero Nero.
But the thing,
the thing about it is,
it's like,
yeah,
there you go.
He's hilarious.
He's a fun guy.
We had him on our show,
the show not too long ago.
But,
um,
the thing is,
I mean,
it Kinda just goes to the point I'm
talking about have,
you know,
here's twitter,
obviously taking sides.
They don't do this to the people who
are,
um,
who are feminists.
They do this people who are critical of,
well,
here's the thing that's,
that's part of his bread and butter as
well with mining.
That's that,
uh,
you know,
my load doesn't have an egregious,
like,
isolated incident that they could point
out.
There's not one thing where you violated
the terms of service with.
They've alerted him on it.
They just unverified them because they
didn't cancel his account.
No,
they can't do anything.
It's not doing anything wrong.
So what they're doing by attacking him,
it's just making them stronger.
It's so crazy.
He got 20,000 new followers after they
unverified him.
Of course he did.
And also there's a shit ton of people
now impersonating him on twitter.
Of course he's not,
he's not verified so I can be Milo
Yiannopoulos and so can I.
and so can I,
it's been like hit the reaction from the
community,
but it's been a disastrous,
terrible decision for twitter.
But it Kinda shows where twitter's head
is at in this whole thing.
And there's so many sites that are
taking on these,
these guidelines.
Like if you actually read youtubes
guidelines,
like so many videos that I've made and
that other youtubers like me have made
like Sargon of cod.
I don't know if you're familiar with
him.
Yes.
A tenderfoot underfoot.
Yeah.
Like so many of our videos really,
if if youtube just changed,
not even the verbiage of the guidelines,
but just their interpretation like
those.
All of our channels could be gone
easily.
They can say all of this is wrong and
sexist and vulgar and whatever guy in
Canada going to jail for doing nothing
more than a criticizing feminist online.
I don't know if that's played out yet.
A gag order.
See,
Canada has different laws.
Surely this is how it's been explained
to me and that this guy had already had
an issue with these women and had a gag
order to put on him.
Then he violated the gag order by
responding to their criticisms of him
online.
His point was like,
you can't just talk about me on twitter
and not have me respond.
That's ridiculous.
You're bullying me now,
and so he went after them after they did
that and then he gets arrested.
Then he gets like legit legal trouble,
so the question is should someone be
able to have a gag order?
And he apparently was working with them
at one point in time,
knew them first,
then became a look.
If you have a gag order,
um,
you know that,
that doesn't give the people who put it
against you the right to endlessly
publicly humiliate you.
I think you have the right to recourse.
That was,
she felt she had free shots at
him,
so she started taking them and then he
was responding to those.
He's like,
I couldn't defend myself and somehow or
another in Canada that was worthy of an
arrest.
I don't know.
I get messages all the time about Sweden
too,
about how things are going crazy in
Sweden as a question though,
in terms of like I've been,
I've written several messages have been
written to me about how it's,
I don't know if it's,
again,
it's not against the law or anything,
but it's very frowned upon for men to
pee standing up anymore.
Yeah.
The should sit down like a bitch.
You got to sit down now.
Why is it so bad to sit down and pick?
Like if I ever showed it at the same
time,
I have a fucking problem with it,
but I like having the option of standing
up if I fucking want to.
Exactly.
You know,
I mean if it was like we suggest you sit
down and here's some reasons why I'd be
like,
okay,
these are worth considering.
Thank you.
But if it's like you should sit down
because it's unfair to women who don't
have a penis,
it's like,
well,
is that what they're signing?
Yeah.
I.
It's like,
I didn't write the biology.
What the fuck?
Wait a minute.
Someone's actually said that.
Yes.
That may be unfair to women who don't
have a penis.
That you can stand and pee.
Yeah.
It's like,
oh,
it's looked at as a male privilege.
What about birth till we get pregnant as
well.
Maybe we should put like Arnold 15 pound
rock in our stomach.
Junior.
I know if you remember that.
Yes.
But he got pregnant.
He actually got pregnant.
But.
So,
you know,
I would have liked that movie better if
they showed the scene of the baby
fucking coming out of his cock.
You know,
just like ripping it apart like a
bloomin' onion.
I think you got a c section.
Yeah,
probably.
I would assume.
But they should have had that scene
though.
Schwarzenegger's sneakers,
cock being destroyed by a fucking baby
swing out of it.
You don't have any faith that we're
going to work through this really
unfortunate moment in our culture.
Oh No,
I'm anything.
It's possibility.
Do you think if president trump gets an
office,
everything will be solved?
Uh,
you know,
I think.
I think he could solve some problems.
Sure.
What do he get solved?
I think he could do good.
Some good things on infrastructure.
I like his tufts stance on China.
I wish that he would be.
I wish instead of talking about a trade
tariffs against China,
he would actually talk about maybe
getting China to cut off supply lines
North Korea.
Since you know,
there's a country that actually poses a
fucking grave,
imminent threat that no one wants to do
anything about.
Yeah.
There's no resources over there to jack
because we can't poor people,
but you know,
it's like,
here's a guy that's,
you know,
putting his own citizens in
concentration camps whenever they
questioned is already killing people.
Here's a guy who was definitely working
on various weapons programs,
a hydrogen bomb.
Well,
I've heard some people be skeptical of
that.
I'm not sure.
Well,
you're online.
Yeah.
So there's always skeptics.
But um,
but yeah,
I mean like what,
what,
whatever the case may be.
It's a dangerous fucking place.
China is the only thing keeping them
solvent because they're the ones that
have the supply line.
So if trump wants to have this big,
tough stance on China,
I don't understand why he doesn't come
out and say we're going to fucking get
China to stop feeding this fucking
monster of North Korea.
But uh,
I do like that.
He's tough on China in terms of like
trade tariffs and shit.
And I think that,
uh,
you know,
in a lot of is a lot of his trade policy
and like a lot of his aggressive stuff.
I remember I was watching an interview
with trump where he was saying,
you know,
Vladimir Putin will respect me and all
this shit,
and I was like,
oh,
shut up.
Look,
I will cut you open,
you know?
Then I was watching a Vladimir Putin
talk and they asked him who he thought
the strongest candidate was.
He's like,
I like trump,
you're strong.
You know,
so maybe Donald Trump was right when he
was reading Vladimir Putin.
Maybe that is the guy that Putin will
respect.
It's interesting.
We're not sure that we should be looking
for Putin's respect,
but it's interesting when you go online
and see the trump supporters,
like,
boy,
it's more interesting to meet them in
person.
There's a lot of strange humans in that
group.
Yeah.
Like finally a candidate who sees things
the way I do.
Personally,
I was telling your they over there that,
um,
that I was at Disney world a few months
ago because my mom is obsessed with
Disney world.
She always wants to go.
She'd been 23 fucking times and I've
been dragged a few times.
But,
uh,
I met a trump supporter.
They're your mom 10.
No,
she's a 50.
But um,
I met this trumps for their big fat
woman stuck in a scooter cart.
Right.
And,
uh,
like,
um,
she's like,
I was like,
uh,
she's talking about trump and she's
like,
I hate Mexicans across the street from
me.
They are all illegal and loud now on day
nathen while now one do nothing about
it.
That's why we got to get trump in there.
I don't know what we going to do if we
don't get trumped.
Almost crying.
Wow.
Like emotional impassioned.
Like she wants fucking trump and she
wants him now.
Hmm.
And he's going to fix everything.
Yeah,
he's gonna fix everything.
It's going to be beautiful.
No one's ever fixed everything.
No one has ever gotten office and
fucking shit got way better.
But the reality of the presidency,
if you look at Obama's presidency,
um,
as far as accomplishments,
it's very confusing.
It's very confusing when you look at
the,
uh,
the data as far as,
um,
the economy because many people think
that he's done an incredible job of
building up the economy and,
and making the economy come back.
And like,
so I don't know because other people say
that the economy came back on a cycle
and that it was on a downward trend and
when the crash of 2008 happened,
there's automatically like a rebounding
and that's what happens.
Things go bad and then they get better
and there's been shifts.
The economy got a lot better for a Wall
Street.
It didn't really get too much better for
normal people.
But when you limit the statistics,
I went up a little bit.
Yeah,
that's what I'm saying though is a tick.
But there's still huge unemployment
problem.
Right?
Well isn't it also the see the
unemployment things confusing to me too
because I think what also happens with
unemployment is if you're not looking
for a job anymore,
it's not counted as unemployed.
Yeah.
So the people who gave up,
they don't count them,
but there's a lot of them.
They said there's a lot of people now
that are quote unquote retiring in their
twenties and stuff like they just given
up on work.
They're like,
Eh,
fuck the world.
How do you eat?
You just leach,
just Leech off other people.
Well,
there's gotta be a lot of that.
That's a,
that's a constant in society.
You're always gonna have people that are
lazy and unmotivated.
That's just always going to exist and
people will demonize those people and
try to say that all poor people or that.
And that's not necessarily true.
That's not true at all.
I know some really hard working people
who were very poor.
Yeah,
and it's also like,
excuse me,
circumstances which you were born where
you live,
the environment and where you find
yourself stuck as a small person with
parents that you didn't ask for in a
city that you didn't pick and you're
like,
well fuck,
you know,
and the idea that that person's the same
person as someone who's born in Beverly
Hills to fucking really wonderful
parents who bring them to a nice private
school.
It's,
it's crazy.
But this is,
you know what you're saying right now.
That's another one of these things
people like to rebel against.
They don't like,
they don't like the reality of like
maybe we all have different
circumstances and different hurdles to
overcome.
They don't want to hear anything like
that.
Yeah,
they just want to hear that America is
the fucking dream that,
you know,
anybody can be a success here.
Any,
any child born can be president one day
or something.
I mean it's,
you know,
it's just not realistic.
Well,
if the child wants to suck Satan's Dick
and make its way through the labyrinth
to the center of the heart of darkness,
yeah,
every child can be president,
but I don't have to go through the whole
song,
believe in Satan.
Whereas Satan's Dick is real.
Dude.
You seen it.
Bill Hicks had a joke about it.
I know it's real
effects.
He would do.
Yeah,
Satan's cock.
I saw him do that live couple times.
Oh Wow.
Awesome.
He had a really long Harlan once live.
I never saw a bill Hicks live.
I saw Hicks alive a few times,
maybe three or four,
I think four times.
That's awesome.
Yeah,
it's a lot of fun.
I saw him before anyone knew who he was.
Interesting.
I saw him when he had just done one of
those Hbo Young Comedian Specials and a
note like very few people knew who he
was,
like maybe a few people that knew that
he had been on hbo,
like if you,
if you were on the marquee.
Oh,
been on HBO.
all right.
But it's seven minutes on HBO.
It's just a bunch of funny gags and
bits.
But then when you see them live,
you got to see this full attack on
culture or life in general and the mall
mentality and Jimi Hendrix,
uh,
like it was some,
some betty did about Jimi Hendrix
meeting tiffany at the mall and
it was awesome.
It was awesome because I didn't expect
it.
The first time I saw him I was like,
wow,
this guy's crazy.
Like this is,
this is completely a different kind of
comedy.
Yeah.
I was,
uh,
he was already dead by the time I became
a fan of unfortunate man.
But,
uh,
I just know one of his ex girlfriends,
she was like,
I think she was his girlfriend,
like right before he passed too.
It was weird.
She was
a comic too and she was just bewildered
by it.
She just kind of went into a shell,
you know,
when she was like this link to me,
like I knew her,
like she was like the link to like one
of the late great ones.
Like,
Oh,
you knew him.
He actually fuck back.
I'm cool.
You know,
it was weird to uh,
to know someone who is intimate with
like one of the all time greats as the
power of his dick still reside within
you.
Do you know?
So it,
it was also weird too that he was so
young,
like he died of cancer.
I think he was 33 or 34 years old.
Yeah.
It was really young and so much work
done by that time and so much of an
impact on the people that saw it.
Like he,
there was a possibility that he could've
gone to shit if he'd still been around
because like what,
what is it,
you know,
it,
it's,
it's a thing with like it happens with
comedians that happens with musicians.
It happens with movie directors happens
with just artists in general of like all
their good shit is really early on and
then it just seems like it goes
downhill.
Is that just like a matter of public
perception or do you think there's
something that like changes in the
mentality or it's depends on the
individual and what they work at.
But a good example is David Bowie.
David Bowie kept producing to the very
end.
I mean he just really wants to grab
them.
It was great.
Yeah.
So I think it's,
what are your motivations like what's
motivating you to produce things so you,
you just trying to fill up a hole that
was left by having an asshole stepmother
who you know,
fucking screamed at you and kicked you
out of the house when you're 17.
Is that what it is?
Or a zero,
like a legit desire to create and have
you cultivated that legit desire to
create?
I think some artists continued to be
really good throughout their lives and
then some artists,
they hit this wall somewhere and that
it's a wall sort of seems to coincide.
Superstardom like I think there's
stardom and then their superstardom and
I think superstardom is almost
impossible to ask someone to navigate
whether it's Michael Jackson level of
fame or fucking axl rose or whatever.
I think there's a level where
everybody's just like your brain just
get fucking scrabbled.
Like,
dude,
I could take it.
Like if you ever,
um,
have you ever been in a fighter jet blue
angels type situation now they,
um,
they roller coasters.
I don't,
I don't fuck around with like g forces
shit.
Well,
and a lot of ways it's kind of similar
in some ways,
but way more extreme obviously in
someone else's piloting it.
But I'm just saying like,
I can't even handle the little kitty
pussy version of that.
So there's no way there's,
there's amount of g force that you can
take and it's.
Everybody has a number and it gets to
like six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
10.
And the guys who are like the heavy duty
hardcore blue angel dudes can get into
like the 11th and twelfth and they just
stay conscious through this insane
pressure.
So they're banking.
He take these hard turns.
The g forces is overwhelming because you
have a jet engine and a plane that
weighs nothing and it's just flying
through the canyons and you're black out
like you feel your consciousness closing
like an elevator door and some people
can take a lot of it and some people
can't and it's a matter of like how
strong you are,
how used to it.
You are how accustomed you get to the
experience,
how much you practice resisting it
because you have to hook,
you have to hook,
you have to do little stuff where you're
forcing blood into your brain,
but it's saint called hooking,
but I think that's a lot like that sort
of Michael Jackson superstar them level.
Yeah.
I think it just like the pressure
becomes so fucking overwhelming that
only a few people can hang in there.
Most people just elvis out just fucking
blackout and pills and chaos and
shredding to the wheat field and gas
fires.
At least.
Elvis had an entertaining end though.
Cold.
A little trap.
Yeah.
He,
um,
he went out,
you know,
they,
they remastered one of his concerts,
his last concert in Vegas.
They're showing it in movie theaters
now.
Really?
Yeah.
There was an ad for when I went to see
star wars.
It's fucking crazy,
man.
It's wild to see like it's like a time
capsule of Elvis on stage and he's kind
of overweight and he's sweaty and shit
and all these people going nutty for
him.
It's like,
wow,
this was a.
This was not that long.
You ever hear of extreme elvis?
Yes.
I know him.
You know him?
A little blog post about him in like
2002.
He doesn't do it anymore.
I know.
You've gotten too much trouble,
right?
It's a feminist.
No,
really.
That's crazy.
Told me he's a male feminist.
Wow.
I'm one of the argument with me about it
and debate then.
Good luck.
We're not interested in seeing how much
things weigh.
Doesn't do that anymore either.
I don't think.
Uh,
but I mean everything that,
that was good about them is gone.
We used to get hammered and he used to
be on stage and just get blast.
I'm like,
so wait.
It's like Elvis and Gigi Allen combined
into one.
That sounds pretty awesome.
It was pretty awesome.
Well,
here's the thing,
he's actually very talented as a
musician and so we're the band members
like the music was fucking good.
He sounded like fucking Elvis.
Yeah,
like spot on and there's a girl that
would sing with them who was hot and she
would take her top off and he would piss
in her mouth and it's like this micro
penis and he pulls out.
I mean it's a micro penis and he's
pissing in her mouth on stage because
like,
who wants to drink the kinds pissed.
She's like,
I do,
I do.
She's got her tits out.
The club's going crazy.
They can't like,
they're going to get fired,
right?
Or everyone's going to get a.
they're going to get evicted and closed
down.
So he's pissing in her mouth on stage
and the club owner comes up.
There was at one point in time,
he walked out into the audience and some
girl just started shoving a bottle up
his ass like a beer bottle.
So he starts backing up into the bottle
and then she panics and,
and just gets out of there.
I don't remember.
She would drop the ball a what?
But when he tried,
he's like,
that's the wrong holt's order.
We were hunting.
He like tried to help her stick this
beer bottle in his ass and that's what
she was like,
alright,
you when you,
when you took it too far,
they weren't willing to go to the same
extremes as extreme elvis,
but he was not getting paid for these
gigs because he was getting kicked out
and they would,
they would kick them out of there and he
would wonder why.
Strange.
Well me and Stan Hope,
um,
we're,
we're both there alive.
When it was,
it was like before we did the mantra was
like,
so it had to be like 2002 and he was
doing it back then.
It was really good,
man.
It was a good fucking show.
Like he was a really good singer and he
had great musicians and the girl could
sing her ass off,
like try replacing her.
A girl who can sing her ass off and she
lets you piss in her mouth onstage
because that's like the whole thing is
that like everything about the act is
like,
you know,
but the thing can't even conceive of it.
He's got his pants off.
Okay.
He's just pissed in her mouth.
The fucking crowd is in chaos and he
sang suspicious minds and they're
singing along.
Singing all caught in a trap.
Did it.
There's a little.
Dick is out.
He's fat.
She's a girl.
The girls next to them saying she's got
piss on her fucking tits.
He pissed her mouth where you can't go
on together.
It was fucking amazing.
It was one of the best.
It was on the best show in my life.
I wish I could have seen some of that
shit.
I need to be a club owner.
If I was a club owner.
I totally understand.
I'll be like,
I see what you're doing there,
man.
That was great.
You just went for it.
You could have just made him like the
House Act.
I connected him to Penn Jillette and he
performed a pendulum.
That's where I heard about him.
I heard about him for Pendula.
Oh,
okay.
Well I connected him with Penn.
Penn read my blog and penn contacted me.
He's like,
this guy real.
I'm like,
she's amazing.
Because Penn came on fear factor.
Penn and teller will bolt on fear factor
and I became friends with pen and uh,
and then he hired him,
but he made sure he was so he wanted him
to be sober because penn is.
Penn is no drugs,
no alcohol,
no nothing.
He just like,
he has parties on his house and he won't
let anybody do anything.
You have to go there and you have to be
totally straight,
which I don't know,
he's an entertaining guy.
I mean,
as long as you're around,
dude,
I'll stay sober if you promise.
Don't go anywhere if you to stay being a
stay being interesting.
But um,
I don't think he doesn't anymore.
I think he's,
uh,
he's out of the business now as far as
extreme elvis.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I know,
I know.
He was as aware.
He'd been gone for awhile,
but I didn't know the full story like
you.
I,
I can,
I can say that elvis picture behind you
keep just like drawing my eye,
you know,
I'll start focusing on that and then
you'll become blurry and I'd be like,
oh shit.
He was one of the few guys that was a
white guy that could rock sunglasses
indoors.
Look at that picture.
I mean,
this fucking dude.
Is tHat the white house?
Okay.
He's got a fake mug shot that's taken
out the white house and he's got his
sunglasses on.
He was a bad motherfucker.
I agree,
but again,
too much g-force.
He spiraled out,
hit the rocks,
died young.
They all do.
It's just too much.
I think it's too much.
I think there's a reason why miley cyrus
is sticking her tongue out and going
fucking bananas.
She's trying to stay above water.
That bitches just being overwhelmed.
And
I think that's what happens to all of
them.
It's just too much fame,
you know?
And I think that's why a lot of artists
go to shit.
That's what I think.
I think the fame overwhelms the
creativity and that becomes almost a
primary focus of your life is mitigating
the effects of fame versus just
experiencing life.
I think for artists especially whether
you're a comic
or whether you're a musician or a
writer,
I think you have to experience life.
You have to go out and do things by,
with this set idea in mind of enjoying
the moment and having life experiences
or being in the moment and not
constantly worrying about the business
or ticket sales or concert dates.
I've
always surrounded myself with people who
are more pragmatic than myself so they
can worry about that shit because,
you know,
it's good to.
I can't really conduct myself in that
way.
I can't be concerned about like how many
views in the last video get,
how much money am I making this month?
You know?
Uh,
so especially if you start considering
in your creative process,
right.
Because I can't do that,
you know,
I have to keep it separate.
So that's why I kinda like,
I kind of leach off of the
responsibility of other people because I
can't really be responsible myself.
I have to be very,
like sort of a flighty and chaotic and
always just off doing my own thing.
Like every once in a while my friend
ben,
we'll just look at me and be like,
jesus christ,
are you a fucking cartoon character?
Because I'll just do weird shit that I
guess doesn't seem reasonable to him in
some way.
Like I just conduct myself in a strange
how fashion.
Like I'll the other day where we like to
get to la,
right?
We were supposed to leave at 7:20
because we got a flight that's leaving
an 8:45.
I'm there,
uh,
you know,
bike,
my friends ben and scotty who came with
me.
Uh,
scotty's my brother ben is my friend and
cohost.
They're both actually cohost on my
drunken peasants podcast.
Doesn't matter because it on itunes by
the way.
Yeah.
And um,
they,
they come there.
They're both ready at seven slash 20.
Of course I'm not ready.
You know,
I'm still fiddle fucking around.
I'm barely fucking getting dressed at
seven,
20 7:40.
I come upstairs,
you know?
Uh,
it's like disaster after disaster.
The garage door fucks up,
it won't close.
We gotta fucking manually close it.
We get to the airport.
We were trying to drive the airport.
There's a traffic jam.
We got to change routes.
We get to the ticket machine.
The ticket machine says we can't check
in because we're too late,
but we already fucking checked in.
So we just needed to fucking print our
boarding passes.
All kinds of stupid shit happen.
So my friend ben,
he's like the kind of guy that gets
really stressed about shit,
like hyperventilating,
like when things go wrong and the more
shit goes wrong,
the more he's panicking.
Right.
And so he's really panicked.
He's in this fucking really agitated
state.
We're going through security,
he's running to the fucking plane
because he knows like this motherfucker
we're supposed to have taken off like 10
minutes ago.
It's going to be a miracle if he gets
there.
So he's running the onto the plane and
he gets on and uh,
you know,
then scottie gets on and finally,
like I guess at the last possible moment
before they're leaving the gate,
I show up and I get on the plane and I
sit down and I didn't realize it at the
time.
But ben,
scotty,
we're both
like staring daggers at me.
Like this is all your fucking fault.
You horriBle,
irresponsible piece of shit.
So you cartoon because you're late?
No,
no.
And then I fucking stick my leg,
you know,
staring daggers.
Me,
they're Pissed.
But I'm like totally oblivious to it.
I'm just like,
um,
oh,
let's see.
Has pretty good leg room for a plane and
they'll,
they're just like fuck it.
Burst out laughing at me and shit.
Cause it's just like I'm,
I don't make the connection between like
what other people think is supposed to
be serious.
What other people think is supposed to
be going on.
I'm just going to do my own thing all
the time.
So you're late.
Yeah.
It was like,
in other words,
I was late.
You were late.
I was late and I didn't give a fuck.
You're irresponsible.
a little bit.
I got it.
It sounds like a comedian.
I'm lazy.
I'm irresponsible.
I fuck with you saying it like it's
almost like a badge of courage.
Like you like it.
Yeah,
sure.
I like being the way I am,
but I'm just saying that I have them
around to be like these nagging bitches
to kind of be my handlers.
Cattle Prod me into fucking actually
doing an associate because you know,
left to my own devices.
Could I have gotten on a plane and come
to la and been on the joe rogan podcast?
Probably not.
I don't think so now.
That's sad.
I had to just been like,
feel like you could make it if your life
depended on it.
Maybe just not tell you if you're
standing on it,
but you know,
I'd probably just sit there and be like,
you know,
do I want to be on joe rogan?
Yeah.
Do I want to travel across the country
now?
I'd rather sit here and watch netflix.
Well,
we've always threatened to do shows on
skype,
but it's just,
it's no,
no,
you don't think you should,
you know,
you got this whole like face to face,
like in person thing going on,
you lose something with the skype thing.
I think so too.
But there's a few people that you can't
get,
like kim.com.
I'd like to get him because he's in.
You can't leave New Zealand or maybe
just make exceptions for people like,
yeah,
I want to do him because I want to do
him,
you know,
him doing show.
Um,
I feel like he's really getting a raw
deal in a real weird deal the way a lot
of people have asked me to describe your
height.
Five.
Eight,
five,
eight?
Yes.
Okay.
Describe it.
Well,
no,
because we found all this.
We found contradictory information.
We can unconsciously roommates or some
shit.
You said you were like five,
six some shit.
Said you were five,
nine,
five,
eight,
five eight.
Right in the middle.
Five eight.
I'm kim dotcom to giant guy.
he's huge.
He's like this cushion for the pushing.
Fascinating dude.
Man.
A key.
Um,
it all.
If you don't know his story,
it all came from,
but people that are listening to came
from mega upload.
he had one of those upload sites,
but they don't,
they don't really have those anymore,
do they?
Um,
I think there's still some version of
mega upload around,
but it's not at the same url or
anything,
but used to be that like you were,
I could upload something under an
account,
like you could upload a movie and I
could download it from your account so
you could take a pirated record,
sharp load online.
And so they made him responsible for all
this stuff that people uploaded.
He did.
He invented that,
you know?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He didn't invent shit.
I mean,
there was plenty,
there was plenty of services doing it.
Google had their own version of services
that we're doing it for some reason.
This guy was the problem.
Yeah.
Why was that?
Why did he get in trouble?
Because he flaunted it.
Is that what it was?
Yeah.
I mean he flaunted it and he changed his
name to [inaudible] dot com.
He made a spectacle of himself.
Yeah.
He used to be called like kimball or
something like that and he used to have.
We did this before,
remember jamie,
we played some of his old animations.
You remember that it was kimbo or it
might've been kimbo.
He was calling himself before kimbo
slice kimbo or kimber or kimba,
I forget what it was,
but he had this website way back in the
day when he was just like a really
resourceful hacker and he had like a
flash,
like a suPer complex flash animated
opening to his website like way back in
the day and he was way,
way,
way ahead of the curve and he made these
like really funny little animated things
of him being in his mega car going to
his mega boat.
You remember all that kimball?
That's what it was.
It does before he called himself
kim.com.
Yeah.
But I mean like,
you know,
it's kind of easy to see why he gets
singled out.
I mean if you got,
you know,
I don't know,
10 drug dealers and most of them are
really low key,
but one guy's out there like,
I'm the fucking drug king Pin bitch,
you know,
who the fuck you is going to attract the
attention.
Of course.
Yeah.
no,
I mean it makes sense I guess.
And also he didn't have the benefit of
being attached to a giant company like
google or one of the other file sharing
companies and he probably wouldn't
provide the information that they would
provide about the people that are
uploading things because I would imagine
someone like google or someone like if
you upload something illegal,
they probably made.
They probably make it pretty transparent
thing.
Gonna take your side over the
government's now.
Sorry dude,
we got.
We're here to make money.
You tripped us up.
So I wonder what's going to happen with
him because they took all his money,
right?
I mean know what his current situation
is.
I try to move them kind like a uh,
I don't know.
They're trying to fly him to America.
It's been like,
it's been two years since I heard
anything about that case.
I just don't know.
Yeah,
I'm vice went and interviewed him fairly
recently,
like I want to say within the last year.
And I didn't see that he's got a
remarkably upbeat attitude about all
this,
but you know,
it's essentially one guy and whatever
organization he has left versus United
States government,
the new New Zealand governments
complying,
they gave up all his money and the whole
thing's kinda kinda reminds me of larry
flynt and away.
Hmm.
Flint seem like more of a victim because
there was no one who is being stolen
from.
There was no lost revenue by him
showing,
you know,
but it was still someone who was,
agitating the,
you know,
not necessarily morality in the case of
kim dotcom but agitating,
you know,
the law abiding sector or whatever.
And you know,
he was kinda like,
they both got shit on and made a victim
of and just like almost was like a
one man show down against the entire
government and both of those situations
and.
But yeah,
movie star at a courtney love.
Yeah.
I think larry flynt was,
uh,
was probably a more of a victim though.
You're probably right about that.
Yeah.
It doesn't seem like there's any
arguments good in that she was playing a
heroin junkie.
So vain and it's probably not.
Did you see the church?
No,
I haven't seen it yet.
I saw the other night.
Whoa.
What is it?
Is it,
is it like a conspiracy thing?
Ah,
it's the conspiracy where they believed
that,
uh,
courtney love had kurt cobain killed or
was involved somehow or another in his
murder and that she had.
There's evidence.
They believe that she forged his,
uh,
his death letter,
her know I've heard the suicide note
forging thing when you listen to like
the recordings that he,
uh,
the private investigator has with her
and you get a glimpse into her mindset.
You're like,
ooh.
Like they fucked up either whether she
was innocent or not.
They absolutely fucked up the burden
investigation.
The murder investigation was,
or the,
excuse me,
the death investigation,
suicide investigation.
They fucked it up.
Like they ruled it a suicide before the
coroner did.
Like there was,
there was so much of it that varied from
the first responder,
like his version of the scene versus
the,
uh,
the police department's version of the
scene.
Like what,
when they compare,
compare the two stories.
The whole thing is it's definitely a
cluster.
Fucking sheriff wound up getting fired
for some other in competence or fuckery.
It's,
it's a very disturbing.
It's very disturbing documentary.
But who knows how many cases the same
department had botched before they just
had this high profile one to botch.
Sure.
I mean,
how many people are sitting in prisons
right now that don't deserve to be
there?
Probably tonight.
Oh,
a lot.
Yeah,
no doubt about it,
man.
Well,
that's what this making a murderer.
The other netflix thing is about.
Yeah,
they're,
they're trying to show you how fucking
chaotic and criminal some police
departments really are.
I mean,
how,
what kind of nutty shit really does go
down and some of these small town police
department.
I was reading about a,
uh,
a case.
This isn't something back from the
seventies,
but uh,
there was um,
these janitors.
There was like five janitors at this
high school.
I'm,
this white girl's body was found,
uh,
raped and murdered in the attic of the
school and the sheriff,
you know,
walked into the room with the five
janitors and four of them are white and
one of them is black.
She,
he's like,
you know,
someone's going to have to hang for this
and urine nigger.
So I'm afraid it's going to have to be
you.
So I mean,
that's like the attitude.
Um,
jesus christ.
Pretty brazen.
This was Texas,
I believe.
So what year was this?
Seventies.
God.
Well,
again,
what we're talking about,
if you know,
if you want to,
if I'm mistaking any details of it,
the whole thing can be found in this
video I did called like the top 10,
a false rape accusations or something
like that because was,
it was basically all these people who
have gone to jail for rape allegations
that later turned out to be false or
there's got to be hundreds and
thousands.
Tons,
tons,
tons.
It's terrifying.
The idea that people get locked up and
even executed for somethIng that they
had no part in.
It's terrifying.
It's amazing how,
I mean,
uh,
dna evidence.
I'm in my own state of Louisiana.
I don't know.
Everyone know what came of this,
you own Louisiana.
I did back then sarah.
It's my own state.
Just like you own him.
I only Louisiana.
Um,
no,
but uh,
in,
in when I was living in Louisiana at the
time I was watching some local news shit
and um,
they,
they wanted to do dna evidence to.
There was a guy who was a in there for
rape and murder and he said,
I want a dna test done to prove my
innocence and you know,
the da got on and said,
well we can't do that dna test because
if we do it and it turns out he is
innocent,
we look bad.
Like that's literally like the,
the,
that's not the subutex.
That's not like,
well,
you know,
we better come up with some bullshit
reason.
[inaudible] will look bad if this
happens.
No,
his overt reason for not doing the dna
test is maybe you know,
we might actually exonerate this guy and
make ourselves look like idiots who just
punished him for years.
Uselessly,
oh,
you're callousness now towards thIs
situation isn't exactly helping matters.
Is it?
It's terrifying.
I don't know how that turned out though,
but you know,
you see that shit all the time.
I,
the justice system is fucked.
It's fucked up.
Well,
people having too much is fucked.
People having the power to decide who's
guilty and who's innocent based on
withholding information or,
or releasing it.
Sensibility.
I don't know.
It's a really good question.
But in that situation,
it's not a good system.
It's a terrible system.
If they could withhold evidence and not
be god damn it.
What a dark thing that has to do to know
someone who's innocent and send him to
die in a fucking cement sell because you
don't want to get caught fucking up or
you didn't want to.
It's so terrifying.
They want to have the case.
They wanna be able to say,
case closed,
you know?
Well,
it's like a.
Who was it?
Uh,
was it ed gain?
No,
it wasn't at gain.
Uh,
there was some serial killer that maybe
you'll know who I'm talking about when
they found out that he was going around.
Really?
Lucas?
Yeah.
They found out he was going around
killing people and shit and they
decided,
you know,
we got all these unsolved murders on the
books and we could just pIn them on him.
They had him like a confessed to the
murders,
like as if he did like a murderer in,
like,
you know,
san francisco one day,
and then like New York city five hours
later and shit,
just any murder case around the country
that was closed,
that was passkey to them.
They just say,
oh yeah,
it was,
it was Henry Lee lucas.
He'd done it and he would go to the
scene and he'd,
they feed him information and then he'd
feed the same information back to them
and he got to be like celebrity serial
killer.
Created a mythology behind them that led
to a movie henry portrait of a serial
killer.
Yeah.
Which was the guy from the walking dead.
The brother that got his hand caught off
and the walking dead.
Oh really?
Yeah.
What the fuck is his name?
Really good dude.
He's using merle great actor.
I don't know they not the crossbow guy,
but his brother is one of the
interesting.
I don't remember the name of the.
I forget the guy's name,
but he's an michael rooker.
Yes.
Awesome actor.
He was Henry Lee lucas.
Henry lucas was this terrifying,
violent,
ruthless vicious man on the real
headline.
Really?
Lucas was this little shifty shufly
fucking hustler character who's just
really fucked up and lost and they made
him out to be.
This mom killed maybe like three or four
people maybe.
Who knows?
I mean,
well,
he killed his mother for sure.
I believe.
Maybe.
I Don't know.
I'm not positive.
I'm not one of these people that's
obsessed with serial killers and shit,
but that's just another example of like
law enforcement gone crazy.
There is in the movie fellow was a
really good movie though.
It's a.
It's an interesting movie.
It's,
I'm in a lot of ways it reminded me of
that fucked up movie where brad pitt
played was a California where brad pitt
played a.
I'm a serial killer.
So with California,
with a k?
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
That was a,
it was a dark movie.
It was fun because they didn't go with
the usual,
like super genius serial killer either.
They made him kind of like,
you know,
just a simple guy.
Yeah.
Which is probably more likely.
I mean,
I guess they say that serial killers
have above average iq was.
But the hannibal lecter archetype is not
really accurate.
Did you see that fucking thing where
they showed that more money has been
taken from americans from the police
then from burglars in 2015?
It doesn't surprise me.
There's plenty of laws.
There's plenty of laws that say you can,
you know,
uh,
I don't know what the amount is or how
many states allow this,
but basically they can just sees any
amount of money up to a certain amount
or more than $1,000 or something.
He just say,
well,
oh,
this is oBviously drug money received
for evidence and you know,
you could be on your way to buy a car.
You,
you know,
you've got a craigslist ad guy selling a
car.
Okay,
I'm on my way over.
You bring cash.
Okay.
I'll go to the back when I was a kid,
my dad was rIch and he would carry like
$15,000 around in his wallet ball and
big money,
you know,
did he have like crazy shoes and like a
lot of times he was like stupid looking
silk shirts and shit.
He looked like some kind of decadent
roman emperor and he always had big
orgies at his house to dad is cool.
He was cool.
What did he do for a living?
He was pretty much a con man.
Whoa.
Really?
Where uh,
he started as a diploma mill called
lasalle university.
Did you?
Shit,
I don't believe you,
but.
No,
no,
he just started.
He started a fake university degree
mill,
you know,
it kind of,
you could say in some ways maybe it was
fake or maybe it was just a precursor to
things like phoenix,
university of phoenix that just,
you know,
but his real problem
wasn't the school.
It was the government never went after
him and said,
you're running a scam school.
The government went after him for,
for committing mail fraud and for um,
a tax evasion was the big one because he
didn't feel like he had to pay any taxes
they felt otherwise.
So he ended up in jail for,
um,
you know,
three or four years over that will
actually was sentenced to five years,
but then he claims to be a drug addict
even though he wasn't,
never did drugs and they gave him some
time off his sentence for enrolling in a
drug treatment program.
God,
that's awesome.
He was always lookIng for the angles.
I wish I had that ability like my dad
did.
Is he still around?
Now?
He's dead.
Uh.
Is your mom still around?
Yes.
When you talked to your mom about him,
like,
like how long were they together?
Uh,
you know,
I think about maybe eight or nine years.
Wow.
What a,
what a blessed be like to be a woman and
to have a child with a crazy man who's
running around just scamming people and
hustling.
You know what I mean?
It wasn't like he was really scamming
people.
He was actually helping people to scam
employers.
If
they know the degree is fucking bogus.
Right.
That's a good point.
And actually it was crazy because when
it was exposed,
there was like congressman and you know,
they got their degree,
like ceos of major companies that all
had degrees from lasalle university.
Super successful even with fake degrees.
Yeah.
That's hilarious.
Well,
you know what,
degrees are bullshit anyway.
Well,
they certainly are not the only limiting
factor in someone's competency.
Yeah.
I mean,
especially not for like business or
something science.
Maybe that's a different story.
I'll for sure.
Medicine.
Yeah.
You want a real document?
We don't want,
you know,
a doctor with a lasalle medical degree
with an incomplete idea and I don't
think,
I don't think he,
uh,
he,
he issued medical degrees though.
Well,
either way,
that's not the most egregious example of
someone being a con person.
That's not.
No,
I mean,
uh,
there's probably way worse things,
but you know what I mean.
Yeah.
But he was an interesting guy though and
actually,
you know,
when he was dying,
when he was on his death,
he died of a super massive heart attack
at the age of 61,
you know,
basically I was sitting there at my
desk,
uh,
working for him on whatever he was doing
and my step mom comes and she taps me on
the shoulder and she's like,
something is seriously wrong with your
father.
And I follow her and he's sitting there
on the bed and he's just like a,
I'm like a dad,
are you okay?
I'm like,
oh shit.
We called nine slash 11,
uh,
took him to the hospital,
that stuff.
And that was reallY the moment when he's
lying there in the hospital bed and
everyone's saying,
you know,
he's fucked and you know,
this,
there's not,
you know,
his,
his wife is kind of align yourself and
saying like,
we'll be laughing about this tomorrow,
but not really believe in it.
And shit.
Well she knew she was in the will,
but there was no will.
Oh,
unfortunatelY.
But
anyway,
that was probably the only time in at
least my adult life that I ever prayed
or anything like that because I did,
you know,
even as a staunch atheIst and a strong
skeptic,
you know,
I was emotionally moved enough at that
time to prostrate myself before I or
power and say,
you know,
if there is something out there,
could you change this outcome?
Didn't happen.
Um,
maybe you didn't pray Hard enough or you
didn't really believe I didn't really
see people right now that are mad at
you.
I didn't pray hard.
And if you say that,
but we'll think about what you just
said.
How many people right now are going to
be mad at you for that?
You call yourself the amazing atheist
because god took your dad.
No,
I was calling myself tHe amazing atheist
before that I know,
but can imagine being the amazing
atheist and then in when,
when the test comes from a where I
failed the test.
Luckily,
luckily atheism doesn't have any built
in tests or anything like that.
It does.
Now I just.
What do you think about atheism plus is
that you are,
okay,
well,
if you're going to define sjw to people,
you've got to define atheism plus to
people because if they don't know sjw,
they certainly don't know atheism.
Plus atheism plus is a very weird little
offset group of atheists who want to
connect atheism with a bunch of moral
and ethical beliefs.
So in other words,
it's a cult.
Yeah.
And uh,
you know,
it's mostly a,
it's mostly just due to feminist
infiltration,
but If you look at what they've done to
the speaking circuit,
the atheist speaking straight like this
used to be like hot shit that attracted
thousands of people.
They wanted to see christopher hitchens.
They want to see richard dawkins,
they wanted to see sam harris.
They want to see daniel dennett.
They want to see all these like big
towering intellectuals deliver this
fucking iconic classic message and an
entertaining and compelling passionate
way.
And now you look at the conferences and
it's fucking,
I am a cis gendered white male and I
recognize that as such.
I have a lot of privilege here on this
panel.
It's gone from fucking christopher
hitchens to that.
And as a result,
attendance has dwindled.
It's shit.
These people still have something of an
online presence,
mostly spearheaded by a guy named um,
pz myers a hates my guts.
Hates everybody.
Really.
Um,
there's a lot of hate coming from that
dude.
yeah.
He's a very hateful fuck and you know,
I don't have no problem with them.
Look,
if you want to have atheism plus and you
want to be like,
we're atheism plus all this other shit,
fine by me,
have fun,
but you know,
you don't get to come to me and be like,
you're already to be atheism.
Plus thIs idea of shaming people into
changing or shaming people that somehow
or another you're writing.
Well,
that's how you become a warrIor,
right?
You have to go out and attack.
You have to shame people for their
differing viewpoints or sexist opinions
like big on sexism.
Very.
That's like one of the number one,
uh,
attacks they'll uh,
they'll use Is going after sexists like
and shaming them,
shaming them in some way,
hurting them,
lashing out,
making them feel that pain.
And it seems like a way of bullying in
response to the bullying that they've
experienced,
like dave experience,
negativity.
so they've decided to turn that
negativity on people they feel deserve
it.
You know,
I noticed uses that bullying,
that uh,
that shaming tactic to milo bEcause,
you know,
he,
he pulled this,
he pulled something on your show where
he did this thing,
this little bit where he's like,
you and him got in an argument maybe
about circumcision or something like
that.
And he's like,
I can't believe you of all people would
argue with me on,
you know,
and he tried that same shit on our show.
So he has this weird thing where like,
eh,
it's,
it's a really interesting rhetorical
trick because not only does it shame you
for not apparently being as extreme on
the issue as he is,
but it also bolsters itself is like,
look,
joe rogan doesn't even have the balls to
say what I milo yiannopoulos.
Say the drunken peasants podcast doesn't
have the balls to say what I milo
yiannopoulos saying because I think it's
just a clever debating tactic.
It's just he's,
he's trying to win and these guys,
when he's having fun,
it's effective,
but you know,
that's why I got to call that shit
because,
you know,
we can't let them get away with it
forever.
I see what you're saying.
If you only looked at him as being a
rational debate or I look at him as
being a theater.
He's what he is.
His problem is that,
you know,
on when he was on our show,
we had our,
one of our guys,
paul,
very popular,
I got a guy on our show,
uh,
you know,
attacking his arguments,
treat them like you would treat any
other guests,
but you know,
the milo fanboys or like how dare you
challenge the perfect walk,
kick of by.
Whoa.
It's like he doesn't have perfect lodge.
I think he's a smart guy.
He's an entertaining guy.
He's compelling,
but eh,
he's not completely 100 percent
objective dicks.
So didn't know anybody is circumcision
and he hates his own sexuality too.
Well,
I don't know how much that's real.
I think it's real sincere.
It,
it's hard to know when you delve into
religion with him too.
I don't know if you guys got into that
very much.
It's pretty ridiculous,
but I think that's.
I think that's connected though.
I think you know the hustle.
No,
I think he's sincere.
I think it's a hustle.
It's a hustle.
I want to be conservative.
You want to be respected and
conservative.
Circles need to be down with the baby
jesus.
You have to.
That's almost the only point of entry
that's undeniable.
You cannot be an atheist.
I got a staunch atheist advocate for
atheism,
plus being a republican.
They're not gonna let you in,
but you could be a gay guy.
He could be flamboyantly gay as long as
you have a sense of humor,
batteries,
fan,
and as long as you have plenty of self
loathing and wish you weren't and then
we'll let you in.
Well,
you know what we believe in jesus.
One thing that kinda does go to what
you're saying is that when he on our
show,
you know,
he specIfically told us like let's try
not to talk about religion too much and
when he did talk about religion and he
was very,
it was easily the most evasive subjects,
so maybe maybe you're onto something
there.
He didn't want to get into it too much
with me either.
I think he would go to this whole thing
that judeo christian values or what this
country is founded upon and judeo
christian centered countries are the
best countries.
Like he had these talking points that he
did not want to debate or explore other
than repeat those premises and I felt
like there's a certain amount of him
that I just,
I just give in to the fact that a lot of
his theater and I think he's
entertaining.
It's almost like his brand of gonzo
journalism.
She's bran of gonzo.
Journalism is sort of this gay
self-loathing jesus believer.
Like he'll put stuff on twitter like a,
like something about people believing in
god.
The only smart people.
Like that's it.
Like the whole sentence and people.
Yes,
yes,
the fucking apes to start fucking
banging against the cage and
appreciation and I imagined that he's
laughing while this is all going on.
I can't imagine that a guy who's as
rational as he is fact based and driven
as his arguments are about so many
different things when it comes to
arguing against social justice warriors
or whatever the fuck it is,
but it against religion.
He has this giant blind spot and there's
the religion in question that he
chooses.
Thinks that he's an abomination,
like it's preposterous.
I think intellectually you could make
the argument that it's not theater.
I believe he's theater.
I think he's the dangerous faggot tour.
He's havIng a fun time with this whole
thing.
It's the whole thing is awesome.
I think it's awesome that the twitter
unverified have to.
They just fucking created a bigger
monster.
They just threw gasoline on a fire.
They fucked up.
Why?
Why do you think they don't see shit
like that though?
Because they're assholes.
Just say they're too.
They're too blinded by what assholes.
They are to realize that all they're
going to do is add to his popularity and
legend.
They must the people that made that
decision must harbor social justice
warrior ideals.
There is no question about it.
The other.
There's no way other than that that you
could look at what he's doing and and
say that this is a guy that you should
unverified.
I mean,
yOu have to do something to get banned,
right?
If do something mean you have to harass
someone.
You Have to call someone problems.
well,
someone can block you,
so if you're bugging them,
they can block you and then
theoretically at least you're not
experiencing their,
their bullshit anymore unless they start
new accounts.
So they didn't,
they didn't ban him.
They just unverified him.
Well,
that doesn't make any fucking sense
because you know exactly who he is.
Verification it's supposed to be done.
Is this guy a breitbart journalist,
but you.
Okay.
Donald trump has said horrendous shit
about mexicans.
He's fucking verified me.
Say they're all.
Someone's doing them raping,
like he's saying crazy shit about
fucking race of people that's connected
to us on a landmass and he's still
verified.
well,
why don't you unverified trump too?
Like what you.
What are you gonna do anytime.
Anytime someone says something
provocative.
Yeah.
I wasn't aware that the verification was
supposed to be a badge of
approval or anything.
It's supposed to be like,
here's a notable personality.
He's notable.
Yeah.
He's been on a podcast that was seen by
him or listened to by over a million
people.
That guy's notable.
He's got a bright bart column that gets
hundreds of thousands of fucking views.
He's notable.
What are you doing?
Twitter,
what are you doing?
It doesn't make any sense and I've never
heard of him doing it before.
I never heard of doing it before either.
I don't think they have done it before
and they have definitely band people,
people that there's people that deserve
to be removed,
but there are assholes,
you know?
They were ruined in ruining what twitter
has established,
which is a really fucking cool
community.
Twitter is amazing.
I get everyday I get cool stories and
interesting articles and interesting
bits of information or corrections where
people will tell me about things we've
talked about on the podcast and most of
the time it's really polite and I find
my interactions on twitter to be really
cool.
I mean I enjoy it a lot.
I get a lot of like really cool website
referrals.
Like someone say,
you got to check this out or check out
this musician or check out this artist.
Lot of really cool stuff is being
exchanged through twitter,
but you can't take a guy like that who's
so obviously entertaining and having fun
and fucking with people and has some
points that he actually believes in.
Where's he crossing a line?
He's not crossing a line where you can
ban him like he's not advocating
violence or hate or going after someone
or doxing them or doing something that
we would all agree is fucked up.
So what Is going on here?
Like what?
What is going on here?
Why are you taking them down while
you're taking the little blue checklist
off
what I was asking you?
I don't understand it.
It doesn't make any sense.
I mean,
especially when you consider it.
Like I said,
it's not a badge of approval.
It's not we endorse.
This is just saying this is the real
milo yiannopoulos,
like are they taking away his identity?
Are they saying that's not who he is
anymore or that you know,
that being that is not notable.
I mean he's a breitbart journalist.
He has one of the largest and most fast
growing twitter followings of all time.
Yeah.
I mean like almost all of his twitter
subscribe.
Here's twitter followers which are like
massive dwarfing dwarfing.
Mine are in the last like 18,
19 months.
Yeah.
Like this guy has exploded onto the
scene.
Well he got 20,000 thIs week.
Yeah.
Just from this whole debacle.
Guy,
we need interesting people out there in
this World and when people have
disagreements or different opinions
about certain subjects tHat are
controversial and pertinent because
we're all discussing them,
whether it's men's rights or women's
rights or whatever the fuck it is,
you're going to have controversial
characters who stand out and their their
hot points of debate.
That's this guy is,
you know,
you might not agree with them,
you might think he's an asshole,
you might not want to read his tweets
anymore,
so you block them.
That's all fair play,
but it's as soon as they decide,
like I've said,
some pretty fucked up shit on twitter
before just to get a rise out of april
and like is that we're going to decide
that this am I going to be unverified
now it's going to be a bunch of fake
news out and one of them just happen to
have one point 7 million followers.
You got to find the guy with the most
followers to figure out who's the real
guy.
That's stupid.
You're ruining your community.
You will allowing someone,
the fact that you allow.
Like I could call myself the amazing
atheist in my heading.
I could have my same twitter handle and
just start crying.
Yeah,
I'm sitting here.
that's the.
That's another thing.
You know,
I'm sitting in a channel that has nearly
800,000 followers is getting four to 5
million views a month every month for
twitter.
You know,
and I'm not verified.
Where's my verification?
I'm the real fucking amazing atheist.
YOu are dude.
No verification,
but you kind of a rebel doll.
you're on the outside.
Maybe it's better like tHis know stay
underground.
You don't want to be that band that used
to be cool and now like people don't
like it because you're already know I've
already experienced that bullshit.
Have you sold yet?
No,
I haven't.
I mean I'm not sold out,
but.
Well maybe a little here and there.
Product placements.
Sure.
I guess I have sold out a little,
but the thing is though.
No,
I'm more talking about like the people
coming up from below that are the,
you know,
they're more edgy or whatever.
You youtube people.
You mean?
People coming onto the scene,
like the amazing atheist is a fucking
faggot bitch compared to me.
I fucking tell it like it really is.
That should be flattering to you that
someone's trying to steal some of your
thunder.
It is.
And it's also very flattering that they
never seem to succeed.
Well,
we got to meet a couple that have
succeeded.
No,
no,
not that I've seen.
No.
The people who go,
the people who would just ignore me and
is trying to establish their own unique
identity,
they can succeed.
The people who define themselves as the
antithesis of me never going to succeed.
Well also define themselves as your
enemy and it's almost like their
individuality,
their identity is based on being an
enemy with you.
Just making yourself contingent upon me.
You know,
you're,
you're done.
Especially if you get mad at them back
then,
you give them poWer.
You're their adversary.
there must be important if tHe amazing
atheist talked about me for seven
minutes and people are very nice.
Most people,
most people are very nice.
Like,
I mean,
um,
most of the messages I get
overwhelmingly positive.
Most of the tweets I received
Everyone is always cool.
Everyone's always nice,
you know,
there's a hater here and there,
but it's never really been that big of a
deal.
Sometimes I'll say something to piss
people off,
you know,
the things that really had been like the
most offensive though,
are never the things that I planned to
be the most difficult.
What do you think?
All the videos you've ever done,
what's like the most defensive point
I've taken?
Here's the.
Here's the three things that probably
piss people off the most
when I did a video.
Well,
I did a video against ron paul once,
but that was when I was a smaller
channel that really piss people off.
I did a video against buddhism.
People really pissed because they.
The strange thing about the boot boot,
you know,
you would never think that for doing an
anti buddhist video,
you would get death threats,
but I did.
People were like,
you fucking misrepresented the tenants
of buddhism,
bitch.
Now I'm coming for you.
It's like,
I think you understand them even less
than I do.
Apparently
insulted soccer.
Even calling it soccer will piss a lot
of football fans off.
Yeah.
That's the european style.
If you get an american that gets mad at
you call it soccer.
He's a cunt.
Yeah.
Agreed.
But I would,
I've never lost more subscribers than
when I made a video.
Again,
soccer when I said soccer is fucking
stupid.
I must have lost.
I don't know.
Uh,
my channel probably had,
I don't know,
a hundred thousand or 200,000 at the
time and I lost,
you know,
three or 4,000 people just for not
liking soccer.
I was really mean about it in all
fairness.
But I mean,
come on,
it's fucking soccer.
But why and others say the same thing
about baseball when I assaulted the
other kid.
Really?
Yeah.
They got this.
They got super pissed.
By the way,
refresh your memory.
Other kin is when we're talking about
people that think they're foxes or
computer elves or unicorn or a stapler
who fucking a golf shoe.
Fucking golf shoes and golf shoe kid.
Mom.
The you easily could understand.
Yup.
There's a lot astral cleats coming out
of my back.
There's a lot of people out there that
are connected to these small
organizations they're very passionate
about and they don't like you just
sitting in your hive throwing up on
youtube and hitting all over.
The thing I got with,
with the other kid was they said that I
was a kid.
I was putting minors at risk because
some of the other canner minors and if I
make fun of them then they're going to
kill themselves and it's my fault
because I made fun of.
So basically,
you know the guy who goes around saying,
I'm a dragon.
He's not the problem.
The guy that says,
no,
you're not.
That's,
that's the issue.
Strange logic.
I agree.
Well,
you know,
making fun of something like other kids,
like someone who believes they're a fox,
a in a,
in a rational world is a very safe
practice.
I agree.
And rational world that is like,
boy,
there's almost no victims there because
the person who really is a pretending
they're a fox,
they need to be slapped.
Someone needs to wake up and hey,
fuck face your,
your,
your name is mike.
You live in toledo.
You're not a fox.
You're a guy.
This is your mom.
Does your dad.
He goes to school,
you talk to people,
you drive a fucking car.
You know how to fox.
I don't know if you agree with me on
this,
but I mean if,
if mike wants to be a furry and pretend
these a fox,
he knows it's pretend I'm okay.
I'm okay with it.
And even if he wants to be a fox for
short periods of time,
like really
it doesn't even think he's mike,
mike at all.
Maybe that's like,
it's cathartic release.
Like he does get naked and he fucking
runs through the woods on all fours and
it really does feel like a fox freedom
to have fun.
Why not turn live dance?
It's 24 slash seven thinking you're a
fox,
like in the grocery store walking down
the aisle with your fucking cart or
whatever.
I'm a fox.
No,
that's rude.
That's just.
Well,
you know what it is,
is a dummy in.
There's plenty of dummies,
you know,
you find other things to do just.
But anyway,
I had away from that guy chairman to
leave them alone though because uh,
there are a little bit too extreme for
me.
They're upset because again,
being this other kin as we discussed
before,
is this tiny,
minor personal victory.
If they can say,
I'm a fox,
I am fox kin,
like now if you agree to it,
now all of a sudden they've gained some
traction.
They've got some motion going on.
It's otherwise dismal life.
That's real.
It's like it hurts to suck,
you know,
to be stuck in some horrible existence
where the thing that gives you the most
joy is pretending you're a chipmunk.
Like,
but,
but pretending you're chipmunk,
ken and that you'd meet up with other
chipmunk king online and like how often
do you guys eat acorns and you get
together and you fucking sit on your
knees and the park and you pretend to be
a chipmunk and you enjoy the shit out of
it.
Why?
Why is it okay to golf?
But that's not okay.
Golfing is way fucking dumber than
pretending to be a chipmunk.
While we agree on that,
if you,
if you're playing pretend to be a
chipmunk,
you like trying to commensurate based.
I can see why.
Pretending to be a chipmunk will be fun.
You get to like,
golf is fun.
Golf is just like,
you don't.
I really don't get fucking guys are
bringing their wives out golfing.
Like what?
What's going on here?
Like I have a friend of mine,
he told me that he'll go golfing with
his buddy and his buddy won't say that
he's going to bring his wife and then
just brings his wife and he's like,
what in the fuck I thought were going to
tell dirty jokes.
I'm gonna talk shit about this girl I
work with and we're going to have some
fun.
You fucking asshole.
And now we're putting the ball round
with your mom because she corrects you
every fucking time you say something and
she's mad at you when you don't
compliment her on her stupid fucking
golf game.
Oh man.
What the fuck?
Those guys are the worst dudes.
You bring their girlfriend everywhere.
I think the most brutal one of the most
brutal.
Right?
You know,
I don't know.
Some of the most part don't ever hang
out with other men,
so I don't really know at all.
No,
not really.
Whoa,
what's going on there?
I don't know.
I don't really.
I'm.
I mean I'm very solitary in general,
so.
So when you go out and you just hang out
with me,
I guess I just disagree because I don't
really have.
I mean,
let me see.
How many friends do I have?
I have always had with golfing.
Ben,
scotty,
chelsea.
That's pretty much my three friends.
Those are dudes.
Yeah.
Is it a handler?
Chelsea handler and hanging out with
her?
Chelsea is my girlfriend.
Oh yeah.
And yeah,
I mean uh,
you know,
I had a broader here if I could bring
her to la.
So I guess I am one of those dudes that
just would bring her everywhere,
but there's no but I can't see.
I can't see her ever being like I was
offended by the us or some shit.
Like yeah,
it's all dependent upon whether or not
your chickens cool.
Like,
like I have friends who bring their girl
everywhere and it's awesome because
she's fun to hang with.
It's when they bring their mom out,
I mean their girlfriends,
like their mom.
There are dudes that have that sort of
weird situation where a sorta tells them
what to do.
Fuck that.
That becomes an issue.
But I guess girls have the same thing to
imagine being a check.
You want to have some cool fucking thing
and this dummy brings her husband and I
know is your party.
I can't imagine myself being fun to
bring places because all I,
all I do is just bitched and complained
yet.
But it's entertaining.
That's what you do.
It's fun.
It's fun for me.
But I could see how someone else would
just be like,
oh my god,
you just second out of the fun out of
things.
It's like there's no fun to be had here
and that's what I'm pointing out.
Fuck them.
Yeah,
fine.
Other people that enjoy it and you have
a nice whole conversation.
Like if you and me we're at a party and
we met,
we started talking about shit.
We would have probably the same
conversation whether or not there was a
recording of us at all.
Right?
Yeah,
true.
That's what I'm saying,
man.
It's all good.
Fuck those other people.
Fuck them all.
Do.
You're the amazing atheist trying to get
away from that name that I know cause
you know,
it's not because a,
it's not because I mean like I'm not an
atheist anymore.
It's just like,
I don't fucking know what else to say.
Right.
But you're kind of tied into that name,
right?
Yeah.
So I'm kind of trying to phase it out.
How do you do that?
I don't know.
You're going to be like p diddy.
He used to be puff daddy.
No,
and then he'd hit a jarring.
You know,
people you should do that.
Like people don't like that,
you know,
when you just suddenly changed.
I just figure I'll use tj and amazing
atheist interchangeably long enough that
eventually,
you know,
they won't notice.
I'm not using the amazing agency.
Maybe you should have two different
outfits,
like one you should wear,
like maybe some sort of spandex yoga
type outfit,
like a superhero would with a they want
to see my physique,
but I do just for the sake of this
character,
like you have two a's,
like an a amazing atheist and it's like
a character that you play and then you
bring in tj and maybe you could have a
split screen where tj and the amazing
atheist can.
Can have different points of view.
Oh yeah.
It would be like two different fucking
versions.
You remember when garth brooks became
chris gaines do remember that?
Yeah,
that's what I'm talking about.
Yeah.
He's like the edgy garth brooks.
It wasn't even the edgy.
Garth brooks.
He was made a behind the music.
Remember that?
Edgy.
But it wasn't at garth brooks at all.
They made a fake pack.
Yeah.
Well they made a hole behind them that
and like wearing mascara.
Yeah.
Well you had a crazy wig and background
and drug problems you've got away from.
And I was a tortured artist and he's
like,
you're a garth brooks.
You fuck,
we know who you are.
Like what do you two have pretended to
be this new guy?
Why are you wearing a wig?
Garth?
What do you do it?
I thought you got friends in low places
with all this bullshit.
What's this?
Moody fucking smashing pumpkins.
Shit.
You know,
if,
if I was a.
I don't know if you show me a picture of
garth brooks in a wig and said,
who is this?
I don't think I would be like garth
brooks.
You not?
No.
You didn't know about chris gaines.
I'm looking up more.
Apparently he was australian.
Oh,
chris gaines is Australia.
He had a whole different country.
You came from god damn.
Anti american son of a bitch.
I thought he was all about country
music.
I got friends in low places on man.
I just had to listen.
That shit on the bus
was like fucking trent reznor.
Trent reznor fuck prints.
That's what you see in right there.
That is so hilarious.
What was he?
What kind of drugs was he on?
I'll tell you what.
He was on fame.
G-force.
THat's what happened to garth brooks.
The same shit that happened to elvis and
fucking everybody else,
man,
donny and marie,
all of them
all.
I don't know what to say.
You don't have to man.
You don't have to know.
We just,
we're here.
We're,
we're experiencing.
We're existing.
We're basically out of time though.
So,
um,
I want to thank you for doing this and
give you an open invitation.
Man.
I enjoyed talking to you.
So thank you.
You want to come back?
Get your fucking lazy ass out of bed on
time.
Make it to the airport.
Don't shake your head.
You can do is I surround myself with
responsible people.
There's like a manager type character
who takes you in the road.
You can pretty much.
That's pretty much scotty though.
You could do these like you could do
live shows.
You could do this on the road.
We've been thinking about doing that
with a drunken peasants,
you know,
while we're here in la,
we're doing a meet up with our fans.
Beautiful.
Uh,
well I don't want to announce it and you
hear a bit because you can fucking have
either.
We already have so many people rsvp a,
I guess.
I guess I can say we're going To get the
v lounge in santa monica on a friday
from five to nine,
but we already have a shit ton of rsvps
so I don't know how many people flake.
You're in California.
Maybe flakes.
So fog.
We're really interested in it.
They can go but yeah,
we're going to do like a big q and a and
shit.
But yeah,
we do want to do lIke live a podcast at
some point,
like actually in front of an audience
and she totally should.
Guy.
We're going to,
we're going to try to figure that out
maybe logistically one of these days,
but you know,
maybe not quite yet.
Anyway.
Thank you.
Tj is,
it's really cool to like see somebody on
youtube and laugh at their videos and
then you know,
agree with some of your points and then
meet you and have a nice conversation.
It's fun rock on youtube.
Motherfucker.
Rock on.
I like your tattoos.
Thank you sir.
Alright.
Uh,
amazing atheist on twitter.
Amazing atheist on youtube.
You have a website?
No,
I don't,
but like drunken peasants also on
youtube,
drunken peasants on youtube and on
itunes and that's it.
You fox will be back tomorrow with tony
hinchcliffe.
Tony hinchcliffe new netflix special
comes out this friday and it's called
one shot.
He fIlmed it all at my favorite club in
the world,
the ice house or one of my favorite
clubs.
Um,
it's really funny and tony is a really
funny guy.
He's a really good up and coming.
Standup comic.
He'll be here tomorrow too.
And tom segura specialists outright now
and it's fucking awesome.
It's called mostly stories.
It's also available on netflix.
So go and halacha boy.
All right.
Thank you brother.
Appreciate it man.
Thank you everybody.
We'll see you tomorrow.
Bye bye.
Much love here at carver.