The joe rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by the flashlight.
If you go to Joe rogan.net and click
on the link for the flashlight and then
enter in the code name Rogan,
you will get 15% off the
number one sex toy for men.
It is an excellent alternative
to masturbation. Without it,
I recommend it. Brian do recommend it.
I like it a lot. It's awesome right now.
It comes in different shapes.
You can get buttholes mouths,
you can get whatever are,
whatever you're down for it.
Even like vampire mountains.
Let's go get some alien mouths
are alien Vaginas, right?
I need an Easter bunny flashlight.
You know it needs to look like a bunny's
vagina. Cross the line and fellow.
Imagine with like art, like real
rabid hair on it. Ooh, oh yeah.
And the or the fake rabbit. We hear
like when you see this rabbit foots,
that truck stops that are so creepy.
It looks like there's like a hard
bubble gum in the middle of it.
But it was a cop in San
Francisco and he found a, uh,
he,
this guy had a sheet,
a Chinese guy had the sheet over
his lap and my buddy goes to,
something's going on
with that fucking sheet.
And that guy's parked in a
weird place and that's weird.
And he found that the guy was
fucking ate chicken. Oh my God.
Chicken. Oh fuck chickens.
Let's start with your mom. Oh,
what went wrong in your childhood
here to fucking in the egg.
Did you fuck it's Po?
Yeah, he's fucking poultry.
I guess you that's where you
fuck a chicken. Right? And
his egg whole. I guess so.
I never thought of that in the egg hall.
She gross.
I never even thought of that.
I didn't even know where,
where he would fuck a chicken.
There's like strong side of it.
That's exactly right.
When it is like websites
dedicated to do to fuck chicken,
she can hold out to be enough people.
That's about chickens sort of movement.
Have you seen Nica Nica Schwartzman's
that had bid on that? He goes man,
before the Internet,
if you've got a fetish it must've sucked.
Cause you had to feel people out.
He'd be like dinner and you'd go, Hey,
I'm going to go to the bathroom,
but a or I could just piss on your face.
I'm just kidding. I'm just kidding.
I'm just kidding. That's so true.
It's so funny. Mad. I'm like,
you know the story about the documentary
zoo there was based on those guys go
want to have sex with animals. There was
two files. He didn't know this weight.
How to, how to buy a zoo or
I don't know. No, no, no.
It was just called zoo and it was about
zoophilia if that's the correct way of
pronouncing it.
It's people who are attracted to animals
and they would go and they will be in
Washington state. It was legal,
real hot shit up until this movie,
until this documentary came out, this guy
died. He got fucked to death by a horse.
Oh my. Then they pretty bright. Yeah.
I've, I've told you about this. I know.
I got a guy, the guy had got brought
him to the hospital. He had bled out.
And then the, the, the people that brought
him in all got arrested and they said,
what the fuck's going on?
And somebody cracked and then
he took them back to the barn.
You can't crack in that situation. You've
got to, he'd go, Oh man, he'd been,
he was who he was trying to jump over
this fence post out man for act lines.
You can't tell the truth. You can't say
that you go to jail for fucking a horse.
That's a,
that's weird.
You bring a dude to the hospital and
his asshole's bleeding and there's some
kind of sperm all over the place.
They didn't clean his ass.
I'm sure you know,
once that thing blasted and chicken whole,
the whole thing is just so crazy that
there was hundreds of hours of footage of
this stuff and they found
each other on the Internet.
You know what they find with a,
um, a lot of people like that,
they have an inability to feel as
deeply as a lot of other people.
So they do these day that they have
to go extreme. That's what happened.
It's a term for it, like a, like a,
like a banality. Like they have a, um,
sort of,
there's a pathology where you,
you essentially are numb
to most of what goes on.
So they found the serial
killer in England.
He was a doctor and he had,
when they found out he was doing all
kinds of terrible things. In fact,
I think he was the guy, they did a, they
based silence of the lambs on the guy,
eight people.
And they found it.
He had fucking like 25 pins
in his testicles and a punch.
I had pins in his anus,
he was sticking them all the way
upstairs and they were like, you know,
when the psychiatrist,
um,
found that it was because he couldn't
feel anything and he had to do that just
to feel something.
Like he always walked around numb.
And so the only way to get kind
of a rush was to stick. Hey, hey,
he's a doctor, ladies and gentlemen.
Hey Doc, I got a pain in my, uh,
in my balls. He was a doctor
in England. She's Christ.
You don't need a doctor to get alpha
brain, which we'll do commercials.
This is the beauty of the
organic commercial. Anyway,
go to [inaudible] dot net click on the
link for the flashlight and when the code
name Rogan 15% off bitch.
Cause I'm also,
we're brought to you by [inaudible]
dot com that's o n n it makers of Alpha
brain, the, did I ever give you reaction?
Yes. And did you enjoy that shit?
I don't really, didn't really feel
a big difference. But then again,
I don't know why, you know, I only
took two pills. Does just once.
You didn't try it for a while. Yeah, just
once he didn't feel anything. I mean,
you know, it's hard to tell. Hard
to tell. I had a lucid dream Joe,
that somebody broke into my car and
I want to know if I take shrink tech,
what helped my dreams because I,
my car got broken into and somebody
took off with my car and I ran outside.
I'm like, AH, fuck this. I'm not going
to chase you. Think caused that dream.
But then I was lazy. My dream. I didn't
want to chase like a dream car around.
I like, I was like, no, I'm not
motivated enough to chase a dream.
I want to come see you when it comes to
the 50, if you examine the statement,
the efficiency of your brain so your
brain would work more efficiently and then
otherwise I would,
I would imagine that if I were to put
you in a life and death situation or if I
were to put you in a situation
where that really counted,
your brain would work
better or at least on,
on more efficiently or at least more
alertly then then would your brain,
if we were just sitting around and shit,
right.
So you should play chess in Iraq.
That's exactly right. Well, when
you're playing, you know how they,
those guys playing cards and when, and
they let a bull loose. You ever seen that?
And the guy who, the guy she gets up from
the table, but last rice is the winter,
winter. Jesus Christ. That makes my
dick hurt. Just thinking of that,
that is the craziest shit in the
world. Um, but you know, the,
the reality of consciousness is that we
have ebbs and Lowe's and we have moments
where we can't remember
things and we have,
where the fuck did I put my key moments.
You have your days where you're,
you know, your, whatever your connection,
whatever the full symbiotic connection
of things that's going on to make your
month. That has to do
with hormones too, right?
When you have an insulin overload,
apparently that sugar,
because sugar can cause too much sugar,
can cause that sort of what
they'd call clouding of the brain.
I never used to believe that sugar is
bad for you until him. As I got older,
I started looking like more,
I love sugar.
I love like delicious chocolate
cake and ship it once in a while.
But if you live in fucking good
for you at all, it's like drinking.
It's like getting hammered.
There's a guy named Robert Lustig
and another guy named Scott caught both
doctors and another science writer named
uh, Gary Taub, who a couple
of great books. One is a
good calories, bad calories.
And another book that was
follow up to that book,
which is shorter book called I think
what makes us fat or why we get fat.
And through 20 years of
research, you know, and more.
And by the way, Barry Sears,
who was us, uh, I think, uh,
doctor over an m a scientist over at
MIT who was one of the pioneers and time
release drugs. And he
also wrote the zone. Well,
well if you look at all their research
and these guys are on a clinical level
and they're looking at,
they're looking at what happens to your
body that try to measure things like
inflammation in the body,
which is a very difficult to do,
but they're doing all these things.
What they,
what they found is that insulin,
which is this mother hormone is directly
related to a lot of health issues.
And,
and so when you look at athletes that
you look at people trying to be healthy,
they, the idea is to eat foods that
keep your insulin somewhat neutral,
um,
because that,
that otherwise when you eat
foods that oxidize as sugar,
glucose in your system, uh, right
away you run into a host of,
you can measure that there
are a host of health problems.
And so a guy like Robert
Lustig just came out with this,
this long hour and a half
speech that he gave somewhere.
And Gary Taubes kind of conferred in
the New York Times saying, he said,
I think sugar is a toxin. I don't
think it's bad for you. I think it's,
it's a toxin, which is kind of a radical
thing where you go, well, come on man.
You know, so he said, yeah,
so there's so do you give to your
child is doing your child harm.
It's not just, doesn't just rot the
kid's teeth, it's doing the child harm.
And here are the,
here are the host of reasons for it.
And if you actually look at the
literature and then more importantly,
if you look at what athletes are doing
and especially Olympic athletes or,
or they are, they stay away from sugar
for the most part, it's a smart move.
Should stay away from sugar,
does make your body feel different.
There are natural that your body can use
and sometimes you buy needs to
glycogen, you know? But um, anyway,
on a.com and it kind of
where I got my degree.
Hey everybody else talking about sugar.
By the way, listen to Brian Calendar.
I know it's not good for you. Um,
um, we, we have a Alpha brain,
which is the cognitive enhancing
supplement. And then there's also, um,
shroom tech and shroom tech comes in two
forms. It comes in shroom tech sport,
which I don't recommend unless you
like a real serious workout fiend.
Would that have helped me in my dream
though that car and been able to catch
that burglar be,
you would have had some extra endurance
in your training if you were on shoom
tract.
Imagine if there was some shit they
take that could specifically charge your
dreams in a certain direction.
Brain. You know what,
one of the things in Alpha brain did,
they believe a is making people have
such vivid dreams is B six apparently
vitamin B six gives you some pretty
fucking vivid dreams and that's an Alpha
brain as well. It should call Alpha
Tech. Make that few having vivid dreams.
Doesn't that mean you're getting rem
sleep, which is the sleep you need?
Not necessarily. I mean, yeah,
you'd need rem sleep, but there's,
I believe there's a deeper
cycle than rem sleep.
I don't believe Ram is like
the deepest cycles of sleep,
but when your dream isn't that,
isn't that when you're having,
but that's an rem sleep as
far as they can, you know?
I mean,
who knows?
You might dream in the deepest states as
well and they just can't figure it out.
Who knows how to,
I don't really understand how they can
figure out exactly what the fuck is going
on in your head. I guess it's
electrical signals or something. Yeah,
they're getting better and better at
that, but I don't know. It's crazy shit.
When you really stop and think about it,
you shut off for eight hours at
night and you just sort of accept it.
The juice you just disappeared. And
some people, some people, not many,
but some people can recharge in
four hours versus eight hours,
which is really weird. And, and,
and they think maybe that has,
that's correlated to testosterone to
people with higher testosterone sometimes
need less sleep.
The sleep above an hour a night.
That I was always saying that Arnold
was always saying that really will lose
sleep a few hours a night.
Why would you go just that's
the best thing all the time.
Just tell us about that
time to give someone Dick.
Anyway, as we say with all of our
products at [inaudible] dot com what else?
Or I'd leave out, oh no mood,
which is the five HTP supplement,
five HTP and l Tryptofan
is a bunch of other stuff,
things in as well and it
gives you a nice little,
a nice little serotonin boost
and the shroom tech immune is,
this is the new one as far as I understand
that the way it works is that this a,
it's a different mushroom
and this mushroom gives your
body the impression that
it's under attack by like a bug,
you know,
like put or cold or something like that.
So [inaudible] system fires up
for an attack that never comes.
That's is boosts your immune out.
Yeah, it's called shroom tech immune.
Anyway,
and as I say with all of these things,
the ingredients are available on
[inaudible] dot com go to o, n n I t.
And if you think it's because
it costs too much money,
if you have any sort of
a argument about pricing,
go buy it in the cheapest form steel,
the ingredient list and make it yourself.
You can do it and you probably will
save money and good luck to you.
I would be the,
the most important thing is I don't want
anybody buying anything that doesn't
want to buy anything. If you don't
want to, that's totally cool.
If you buy it and you don't like it,
you get 100% money back.
So it's,
it couldn't be any possibly fair.
Like you don't even have to return
the product if you don't like it.
If you try any of this stuff and it
doesn't work, just say it doesn't work.
I want my money back.
Boom. It's that simple.
I could a bottle and I
can't make it any easier.
It's trying to make it as,
as neutral and as honest as possible.
I enjoy all the supplements I use
them, they're awesome. And uh,
go to Joe rogan.net.
Click on the link for Alpha brain
entering the code name Rogan,
and you will get 10% off or not if don't
even buy it. And your own podcasts pod.
Ken, here's my podcast. Ready
to start right now. Hit it
Logan to experience Joe Rogan podcast.
[inaudible]
what does that weird
effect that you always do?
At the end of that we make it all
wonky and I know, why do you do that?
I'm taking drum lessons and I was
trying to play that riff dues.
They would play drums at like at a
diner and be like serious about it.
How about the guy that would
bring his drumsticks, places
for greatness, you know,
stick them in his back pocket
with a Bandana. Events.
Just play with this drunk
driving and my, my, my blood,
well Brody would do it but on stage
Brody's a really good drummer. Yes.
Part of his act Brody would get up on
stage and have chairs to put chairs up
there and do like a fucking drum show.
And the band,
I mean you know that I'm an honorary
member of dawn Buress is uh, air band.
Well I didn't know that there was a whole
dawn barrows air band called the Paris
Kennedy overdrive. First of
all. Second of all, I play,
I play 32 different air instruments,
one of which is the baby.
I take a baby out and I blow on its
stomach and then I throw it into the
audience. That's one of the things I
do. I play the harp, I play the cello,
I play the violin and I play the,
um,
I played the 13 year old Filipino boy and
that's when I saw him and he was quiet.
Now he's 17. 13 is a, that's not right.
It's 17 which is legal in some states.
And uh, and I, I mocks automize a 17
year old Filipino boy as he screams,
that's part of the music. So we, they
all play drums. Like the fuck is this.
Oh Dude, you don't look at two o'clock in
comedy store. I'm one what? Dawn Burris.
She is, he's the last guy to
perform every single time.
And he has the bears overdrive and they
play music and he has an air band up
there.
He lip syncs,
Brody plays the drums and then
he's got various guitarist.
And then I,
when I'm there I get up and I'm a guest
performer and I start with the guitar
and I'm also a guest singer.
And then we play like five,
six songs and it's all air instruments,
but I have my own air instruments.
I choose, I play humans and
I play fucking, you know,
things that most people don't. You have a
job. Yes I do. Yes I do. How am I growth?
Really happy. When I come home at
three in the morning, she's like,
what the fuck you doing? I'm
like, the Ben was playing late.
Like you're in your forties fucking loser.
Get away from me.
I always watching that, just watching
it. I'll go there and be like,
why am I here at 2:00 AM watching
an airbag always like seven,
seven alcoholics and my fork comics
and we play like we're playing it
entertaining for me. For me, it's
really fun to watch. It's one.
Don Berries is so hilarious. I'm going
to get them to do it at the death squads.
John Behr is one of the
funniest people in the world.
Nobody knows that dude killed.
He's a great personality. Great.
I always enjoyed hanging out with Tom.
We do it.
We do a sketch every single time we
see each other every single time. Yeah.
He's one of those guys.
Every time I start something up,
he'll be talking as all these people
and I go by and I go, Hey, I had done,
I don't want to embarrass you in front
of everybody, but I need my money.
I need my money. I didn't go,
why? I go, Oh man, I'm sorry,
but it's been a month now I need, I really
need to see my money. Let me 10 grand.
He goes, you're embarrassing me in
front. All my friends like this, look,
I don't want any trouble.
They get the fuck over here.
And he slaps him and I and he's,
and then he mocked mouth rapes me and
then I begged him as to what I'm doing.
Oh my mouth.
Shut the fuck up.
No. Are you, are you, how close
are you getting Mouthy Dick?
Right up against his dick.
Oh my God,
your mouth is on his day.
Thompson,
my,
he mocked dumps in my mom and he pushes
me away and I lie there in the fetal
position and everybody around us doesn't
know what the fuck just happened.
And he just kind of quick pretends
to zip his pants up and he goes,
sorry about that. Goes back to his car
a little hard. Uh, not that I know of,
but then it's all a blur for me. So what
did I just commit to the skin manage?
Have you did how many times you've done
it? Sketch? No more than 50. 60 Times.
I like to limit myself every single time.
Every time you see him.
So every time we see him you've run
up to him and shoved your mouth on it.
Every time I see him I go,
I just asked for my fucking money
that he owes me and my 10 grand.
There's different results. Oh, I see.
Then then first he'll either beat me up
and then fuck my mouth and then I begged
him not to drop a nut it and you know,
he's so committed and it
looks so real and people,
he actually thinks something like that
is going on is I'm begging home times.
Has Your mouth touched his dick?
Dude? No more than, I mean,
this is a stupid question. I look, I'm a
straight man. Maybe 30 times, 40 times.
I don't know what the fuck. Why am
being grilled? Why do I have to be,
you've got to get video on it cause people
think we're serious because I grew up,
I, I go, I act like I'm a
little afraid of Meridian. Don,
I don't want to bother you, but you know,
I need my $10,000. It's been a month.
He goes here. Okay. What'd you say? I go,
I ain't more money cause you're gonna
embarrass me if I front all my friends
like this, I go, no, I'm not trying
to embarrass you. I just need,
I really need the money.
I'm having trouble paying my rent.
I go ahead and he goes, yeah. Did
he say, you get the fuck Outta here.
And he pushes me away and then I
come back and ask them a second time.
Sometimes we'll do it that way.
And then he's just fucking had it.
And he just slaps me to my
knees and mouth rate today. Hi.
I'm a grown man, ladies and
gentlemen. That's right.
What the fuck man call you comedy.
How did I not know this about you though?
Dude, he's so much fun to do bits with.
How long it was this all comedy
store stuff. Oh, comedy store shit.
When did you start doing this? How
many years ago? Like four. Yeah.
That's when I stopped going there.
This is all,
this is post post me at the comedy store.
That's all.
That's all we ever did there. Have you
ever had a man's finger in your asshole?
Uh, that's, no, I haven't.
I have had a man's thumb in my asshole
and I think I told that story last time I
was on the on. Yeah. You
don't remember? Yeah,
I thought that I was just remembering
stories he told that story. Yeah. I mean,
not with a tranny. And see reading this
off Twitter? No, no I'm not. I'm looking.
Look, when I'm looking at, I'm
just spaced out. I was like, wait,
was he the one that,
yes,
there was a bunch of
other stories as well.
So every time you come here you met
Geisha.
By the way, forget all the gay stuff.
Um, are you fully aware of where,
what's that were simply guys,
listen guys,
nobody cares about that
person. I don't want to say 30,
40, whatever. You guys
are a bunch of pure,
I'm offering up this information.
So I'm trying to hide this dog 40
carts and now you're whatever, uh,
you, you are aware, I hope we're aware of,
I don't know if you watched the nat geo
thing called a great white invasion,
I believe it's called.
You know that the Santa Monica Pier,
the Santa Monica pier has a,
a large concentration,
a great whites swimming between
the pylons. You wear that? Oh No.
That good way to get us
off the gay subject. Yeah,
give us the two favorite topics.
Actually got missiles
pointed right at him, Bro.
Dude is getting tricked into blowing guys.
And cray most they can kill you.
That's me all day.
So how many are we talking? Think
about how many sharks? Well,
at one point they were tagging them and
what they found was they would follow
them after they would tag them and they
were all coming into four and five foot
deep water at the Santa Monica Pier.
Crazy and all around.
There were some of the largest of
great wise at any given time. Can Be.
How about that now? Now
largest concentration of
great whites. Trust watching,
not tambien the great white invasion.
Okay.
They don't know why they're coming
so close to the shore, but they,
Bashar Shark ecologists
think that's a good sign.
But bottom line is they thought
or houses or homeless Pete, Dude,
they stock seals here. Well here's
what's fucking incredible. Okay.
And there are great ones and if you take
a helicopter ride over Malabo there's,
you can youtube it right now.
Just go great white Malibu
and you'll see a helicopter.
It was shooting out website thing and
there was like an 18 foot or just swimming
around just about, you know, I don't know,
a quarter mile less than it was probably
an eighth of a mile off shore, you know,
let's call it 300 yards off shore.
That shit happens all day and by the way,
they are eating seals all the time.
Surfers are always in the water.
They know you're in the water and they
don't fucking buy you because it's gotta
be the perfect storm. Oh Jesus.
What the fuck ever. Whatever.
It's to be the perfect.
Exactly. It's called.
It's called like an 18 foot
fish that will bite you.
It takes a hundred pound bites. Freak me
out. I go into the water up to my ankle.
That's what I do.
My feet stay white.
My buddy's bronze in Hawaii last summer
and I freaked out a little bit while I
was in there. I was snorkeling and I
was like, what am I doing? I'm going to,
I'm going to be one of my own jokes when
we get eaten by something. I was down,
I was down in West Palm Beach and I was
staying at this place called the Onfi,
this great, great, really great resort.
And I asked, I asked one of the guys,
he was parasailing and I go and I go,
any sharks out there? And he goes,
Oh yeah dude. Oh yeah.
Oh No, they're times,
certain times of the year they
put flags up, purple flags.
You can't swim because the bull sharks,
they're all migrating this way.
And then you've got the
spinners and they'll bite your
hand and feet. I was like,
why are you talking about said,
Oh yeah, did they you do there?
They're all over the place.
They're there. Co He goes,
I don't know why people swim
in this water. They're crazy.
Cause I'm always kite surfing
and I stay on my kite.
Surf Dude may well go check out how many
shark attacks that have been in palm
beach. The fact that there,
but there was one summer,
they were like eight shark attacks.
Yeah,
like a fight in your leg off bull sharks
will, the bull sharks are so crazy.
They'll go way, way in shore. They'll go
into fresh water. That's exactly right.
200 miles,
200 miles up the Mississippi near
Illinois in freshwater sharks,
man.
Well,
you know the story that inspired
jaws that was based on a river,
a test in New Jersey that was based
on one summer where these bull sharks,
where Jack and people in a river,
it wasn't a great wife,
great wife for Hollywood. You know, when
Peter Benchley it turns it into a yeah,
post sharp. Pretty sure that's
what he was a spicy. It was,
I remember it was like this aberration
where they were being, you know, they,
they will, they'll go, they've
found them way far up river man.
There was one of those, um, monster
quest shows. They had freshwater sharks.
One of them was the reality of it.
That was a fun fucking show.
Even though they never found any
monsters. [inaudible] never had.
They actually even Paranas piranhas
don't eat you. I always thought,
what if you jumped in? Water is honesty.
You, you got to Eaton. If you're living,
they swim away from you.
They don't eat you.
The only time a Pronto we'll actually
use when they're starving in little mud
pools and you put your hand in
there and they haven't eaten.
They beat and everything else there and
they're starving. They'll bite your hand.
Otherwise Sick Ville each other.
Actually they,
they even put a duck in there with
a live talk with a bunch of uh,
Paranas Protestant swam away. No, I
used to have Pronto's. Yeah. Yeah.
Don't listen to that nonsense.
I remember that it was
called that you had the,
you had the gold fish on the other side.
They called it death row.
It's death row at two tanks.
I had a tank filler Paranas and
then a tank filled with goldfish.
Goldfish would just swim looking
at their, their, you know,
what they were going to be. Yeah. Their
future. They would fuck those goldfish up.
It was wild to see man fish,
I guess really wild to say.
They don't just eat fish bro. Delete
anything. There's videos of them.
I never fed them anything
other than goldfish.
And that's just what their natural,
it was natural for them to eat fish.
But I got tired of it. It's
too creepy. I mean it's like,
it is a part of the food
chain and everything and it's
life and it's natural and
it's just the way it works
out in the wild. I mean,
animals eat animals and
that's just the way it goes.
But there's something about just washing
this slaughter every couple of days in
my house,
fucking morose man,
a Burmese python and I used to have a
feed at rats and really you have to stand
the rats. You take them by the tail and
you throw them against the wall. Oh Dude.
It's felt bad after awhile. I was like,
I've got to kill this greatness. You know,
rats are kind of cool cause
you can't just let it in there.
There was a rattle fight back. Right.
And it's nice to snake its bit.
But here's the other thing. Here's the
other thing. Snakes are fucking boring.
Okay. I like that. It just
sit there and they, I guess
they slither, they're creepy.
I'd rather have a rat and
pythons are fucking mean.
My mind got to be eight feet
long and the thing was like,
he would try to fight you every time you
stick your hand in there. I was like,
keep this fucking thing. Those are
creeps. Those are monsters, man.
They're monsters.
They get used to you touching them.
They don't give a fuck about a reptile.
Yeah. They never give a fuck about you.
I don't give a fuck about. Yeah. People
are weird man with their connections.
Reptiles, you know that. How about that?
That guy who had swims where he's got a
Costa Rican crocodile 17 feet long and
and raised from a baby and swims with it.
Seeing that crazy,
crazy shit in the world I've ever
seen. It's nuts. It's close to,
we can crocodile 17 feet and
he's a salt water crocodiles it.
Those are the big ones.
Those are the brackish water.
They will be with each of us
fucking crying. No, I don't
believe you can do that.
Costa Rican crocodiles and I've,
I've done the research. They are,
they are way more timid than most
crocodiles and Nile crocodile.
You couldn't do it with,
there's no fucking way because they will.
You are as tasty to a Nile
crocodile as any food source.
They have Costa Rica. So beautiful.
Even the CROC crocs are chill.
That's hilarious. Exactly what it
is. That's not actually a little shy.
They're shy crocodiles.
Whereas good luck with a fucking Nile.
Krakatau good luck raising that thing.
It's amazing that there's animals
like that that essentially served.
I mean they must have survived that
big asteroid impact that killed the
dinosaurs. Yeah, the Yucatan one.
Yeah. It must've. Then they had to,
if they are dinosaurs, they're old. Isn't
that right? I don't think like here,
like virtually unchanged for like more
than a hundred years when they found that
they found this one skeleton of this
huge crocodile where the skull itself was
six feet long and yeah, I heard
about that one. It was basically,
if you look at the anatomy of
the, of the animal, it was a,
it was no different than a real crocodile.
It was just a giant one. Back then.
Animals were huge. Yeah.
An ambush. Predator w well,
look at this. You all just,
I just did a radio show and then
sue just was on the show in a,
in a fucking Fort Lauderdale.
Right.
And the guy's been to Africa 35 times
documentary filmmaker. And he said,
uh, he goes, dude,
I was in Rwanda and I watched a
giraffe drinking and a croc come out,
grab batch raft by the head,
pull it into the fucking water,
drown it and twist its head off.
And then it's friends came in and
ate the rest of that fucking giraffe.
So nobody's safe. And by the
way, you know what I'm saying?
Safe baby elephants.
When they stick their toe in the water,
they grabbed that date, grab
that. I mean their, their Trump,
they'll grab that trunk and drown
it. Okay. They'll eat elephants.
Whatever's in the fucking
water. So Jesus, oh by the way,
that I mentioned that the ones in
Tanzania weigh in at over 2000 pounds.
I got a, there's a video that, it's a
one of those iconic ones where w one,
a crocodile jumps out of this waterhole
and grabs. It was a big animal.
I think it was a water buffalo were up,
but will the beast probably a be
350 pound a little bit. He's like,
when I'm around the fucking midsection
and whip this thing around like it was a
children's toy. You Go, you
get, you get caught, you,
you're brought them to the water.
That's it. It and it happens in a flash.
Here's a piece of the world is going on
in the same time as us that's going on
right now. I mean, we're
just not there. That's right.
There's a spot where if you step
in the water in the wrong spot,
I'll monster that lived to a hundred
million years ago. There's going to eat.
As I get older, they're all, like I said,
is it's different realities of how some
people live your fucking worst nightmare
and somehow I'm lucky I
never lose perspective and
that shit. Look at history,
look at history. You know the fact
that we live in that side of it,
I don't have to worry about,
I'm Mongol hoard coming over that hill.
Everybody I know.
Yeah. Blown this. Obama was in office.
I'll tell you what, you got to suck.
Failed, so pussified way ain't
got nobody to have guns no more.
They're got to make it hard to have
guns. Then they're going to take over. Or
by the way, did you hear about
this and I'm sorry, go ahead.
I was going to ask you if you know
how big a blue whales tongue is.
It's fucking huge. It's the size of
an elephant. God Damn. What about Tom?
His heart's the size of a car.
His Dick is gigantic.
I wonder how big his tickets
pictures are enormous.
It's pictures of the voice and the will
live there 95 feet long and they weigh
200 tons, I believe too can
wait for the documentary.
The guy that fucks Wilcock. Wait, well
we guys from it. What were you saying?
What were you going to ask me? I
don't remember now. I said, well,
you're going to tell
me. Oh, the Obama thing,
the NDA that just passed,
they just signed it on New Year's Eve.
He sand signed it.
That was the bill that makes a,
essentially it makes America a
battleground officially classifies it as a
battleground so the military can
come in and stop civil unrest and uh,
they can detain people and definitely
they don't have to have warrants anymore.
That kind of thing won't
get through the Senate.
You've got through Obama just signed.
We got there.
It's done. Touchdown. Terrifying.
It's terrifying. First of all, the,
the use of military is, you know,
it's supposed to be strictly
for Hipaa did this and we don't,
we don't want to ever consider that our,
our, our people are the enemy. That's deal
don't difference between the FBI and
the CIA. FBI deals with domestic issues.
The CIA supposed to deal with
foreign issues and by the way,
you're never allowed to spy on
your own citizens. There is a very,
very specific reason for that.
Very strong separation between
a foreign power service,
a foreign service and a domestic sir.
Yeah.
When you get to the point where you're
just all automatically opening up to the
idea that you can't trust anybody,
that everybody must be able to be
scanned and stopped and searched and,
well,
we were talking before the podcast.
I have a book that I'm reading now
and I've read some of his other books.
Leon Uris is considered one of
the great writers, Leon Uris.
What's the guy's suppose you r
I s and Leon Uris wrote, right?
Writes historical novels. And if you
ever want to learn history, you know,
whenever you say to somebody,
we should learn the history of Ireland.
The problem with that is that how do
you, you know, I, a lot of young people,
I get like text after I do these
things or tweets and they say, Hey,
can you give me a
reading list or whatever.
And the problem with educating yourself
today is it's very hard to know what to
read. It's also very hard if I say, well,
you should educate yourself on history.
What does that mean? Do I pick up
a book on history? I mean, Jesus,
who wants to sit slog through that?
No. If you want to learn about history,
you want to learn about the
history of the Middle East.
You want to learn the history of Ireland.
Do you want to learn history of the
founding of the state of Israel,
which I'm reading now, a
book called exodus a. If you
want to learn about Ireland,
read a book called Trinity.
If you want to learn about the Arab world,
the Middle East, read the Hodge.
Uh, Leon Uris is a, is a guy who,
who was a foreign correspondent,
who,
who spent a great deal of time all over
the world and happens to be a fucking
brilliant writer.
He wrote most of his books in the 70s
and the 80s I think even the 60s but he's
considered a great writer. And, and
the point I'm making is that when you,
when you talk about how a society and
its laws and its government can sneak up
on you,
if you read exodus about the,
about what happened to the Jews
in Poland and in, and in Germany,
you're talking about a group of people
who lived there for 700 years and many of
them were very well established in all
fields, whether it was science, academia,
um, uh, the arts and things like that.
So when all this antisemitic behavior
started occurring under Hitler's regime,
and it started really in my 33
where stores are being broken in,
articles are being read about blaming
the Jews for everything. Uh, uh,
people were being dragged out in
the street and beaten up. If you,
if the majority of the Jewish people
who were established in those societies
were like, look, my, my, I go
back generations. I'm a German,
I'm as much a Jew as I am a
German I, and by the way, I am,
I've written several books and I, I,
I'm, I, my roots are in this society.
If you ever told any of them that well,
your government's going to come
round up. All of you, all of you.
I'm going to give you some numbers
in a second and they're going to kill
everybody, you know, and worse,
they're going to gas torture and starve
them all in a systematic way in the
concentration camps.
That was a troop apocalypse.
And if you don't know anything
about the Holocaust or, or,
or, uh, the World War II,
then you're remiss because it's, it's,
it's the worst event in recorded history.
But it's also very important to us to
study because you don't understand and you
can't fathom the, the depth of
human evil until you see that.
Because here's what it was. It wasn't
mad men. It was very rational, cold,
cool minded men with shaved cheeks who
sat in a room dressed in metals and in
suits who came up with something
called the final solution,
which was to kill every single Jew
in the world. And they almost did it.
And in Poland alone,
out of 3.1 million Jews who had been
there for 700 years, mostly in ghettos,
but who had deep roots
and huge contributions to
society so that society and
Germany at the end of World War II,
and this is just five, six years,
there were 50,000 left, all of whom were
wretches, all of whom were starving,
all of whom were coming out of the
concentration camps like Birkenau,
Auschwitz, a Triblinka and all
these things. So when you, if you,
if you really think that you're safe or
if you really think that anybody giving
anybody power over you is a good
idea, is a good idea, you're,
you're,
you're fucking wrong.
And you should pick up a history book
and what makes this country very,
very special and what makes this country
and what you have to fight for his
government, by the people, for the
people. And that's very easy to forget.
And even George Washington said,
you gotta be careful because people
will invent laws to take their own power
away from that. That's what George
Washington said and it is very human.
And if you, if you look at like
if you look at anybody in power,
I don't care if it's Republican
or Democrat, uh, you, you did.
This is why I'm a Ron Paul supporter.
Because if you look at anybody in
power that when you're in power, you,
you have an impulse to
try to solve a problem.
You want to solve a and the only
way to do that government does what?
It passes laws and it grows and it,
and attacks.
Those are too taxing and passing
laws are too coercive measures.
That's what they do. It's just,
and you do need some laws.
You do need some taxation,
let's be honest.
But when you have a central
authority like that,
the big question for anyone is who is
going to govern the governor, governor,
who is watching the governor? That's the
central question of political science.
Who is going to govern it
to and have someone who'd be
on? And the answer is who?
The people,
that's the answer.
And it just choking
dead out a daily basis.
Choking that out slowly.
This is the biggest enemy.
And you have to be on guard at
that all the time. And by the way,
it always is under good auspices.
It's always any society, oh my God.
Even the Nazis,
for God's sake,
even the Nazis that monstrous machine
defined what they were doing along what
they would consider moral grounds. Hitler
was trying to quote unquote solve up,
solve the Jewish problem, et cetera. And,
and it's a propaganda that
got that, that had lift, uh,
Ukrainians and pull,
cheering on those firing squads
as they were killing Jews. Uh,
that's what happens.
You can poison an entire mindset.
So it's amazing that it's within
our grasp. Historically. Look,
we can see things,
we can have photos and video because
things like this have happened.
This is, this is their worst than
you can imagine. They're there.
As you read exodus and I, I studied Nazi
Germany was my area of focus in, in,
in college.
But,
but if you read that book and he brings
it down in such a personal level,
it is the unthinkable and it's
the unspeakable. And it's like,
it's almost like it was the first event
of that magnitude or horrific event of
that magnitude where, you know, a,
her travel had just become like a sort
of a big player in the way the world
functions because people could fly
over you and drop shit on these things
changed very quickly.
They accelerated very quickly.
And it's just amazing that it's all
within our capability of recording it and
watching it, if that's right. But here's
the big difference too. Back then,
nobody was watching it. Nobody was
seeing what was going on in the,
the Russian countryside,
you know, stop. Hitler said,
I want to get rid of is to hit Stalin.
Hitler said,
I want to make part of the Russian
countryside habitable for Germans.
And so what he said is we have
to just get rid of all the,
all the Bolsheviks that's just kill
everybody who's their kid. Just,
just empty the villages of people.
So what they would do is they would have
these soldiers come in and they would
dig these huge mass pits and shoot
everybody into the pit. Oh Man.
That's how bad it was.
And so at the end of World War Two,
there were 50 million people dead.
The wow.
How do you get that many people to do
that? How much? How does that happen?
What is the, that's a very good question.
Let me put it this way. And in, in,
and I believe these are the numbers,
but by the 1943 in Birkenau, Birkenau,
which was about a mile away
from Auschwitz, so it's,
I'm saying Auschwitz in Auschwitz,
let's call it Auschwitz.
They were probably killing
close to 40,000 people a day.
And the way they would do it as this,
what they found was that when they
brought people in and it was at a peak,
is this a constant
steady stream? Yes. Yes.
That's why they were able to
kill 6 million Jews. And Look,
and let me explain something to you.
And it's important if that on
those numbers for a second,
because there's just the overwhelming,
the number of the
overwhelmingly for killing.
And these are children are children and
these are women and these are infants.
And they all had names and they all had,
they all had families
and they all connection.
They were all as human as you and I,
and it's very,
it's very natural for us to kind of say,
well,
that was a long time ago and they may
have looked at life differently. No,
they had all the same dreams.
They had all the same hopes,
they had all the same love.
They all had all the same bonds and it's,
it's overwhelming and too much for your
heart to bear if you really think about
what human beings have done to other
human beings, especially the Holocaust.
It's why the Holocaust that that
word, that word, the Holocaust,
which I believe means the great
fire or a derivation of that.
That's why that word is used only for
that specific event in history because
they did get burned. They did get
put in ovens and they did get that.
They're all trace of them was washed
away because as the Russians and the
Americans closed in on those camps,
they had to get rid of all the evidence.
So they blew up all those gas
chambers. They, they burn the bodies,
they crush the skulls,
and they would use other Jews to do it.
They would make you do it.
So you'd be 14 unloading bodies out of
a fucking think about this. I mean it's,
it's as crazy as it gets, right?
It says worse than it did,
prayed as it as it possibly gets.
But the way you get people to go about it,
it's two things. One is
deception, one is, and,
and human beings have always done it.
And I'm going to,
I'll explain why we're in a living in
a world where it's harder to do, but,
but what you do is just misinformation.
Propaganda. You say, hey,
guess who's causing all
your financial problems? Uh,
a group called the Jews or our group
called the Chinese or a group called the
blacks and there,
and by the way,
they also kill their own
kids and their subhuman.
And you take young men who
have no education or have
been educated specifically
and they're full of fire and what they
go to war for us to protect what they
considered their way of life. See, I
don't think people go to war for hatred.
I think people go to war because they,
they're in love with their way of life
and they're trying to protect their
families. They're trying to
protect their way of life.
And that's how you create a real
soldier and a dedicated patriot.
You create a sense of misinformation
and young men who are 18 and 19 are not
asking questions.
They're trying to be a hero.
And if it means having to kill all those
bad guys over there and even their kids
and their, their women, while the kids
are, when women are kind of sub human,
you always, you always quit a sub human
context for the other, for the enemy.
And that's, that's
what, but the good news,
the good news in 2011 is
that it's becoming harder
and harder to do because of
the Internet. And we're all
getting closer and closer together.
And it's easier to kind of empathize
somebody when you see them suffering when
we'll videotape doesn't lie.
And when you can,
when you can hear their voices and you
can hear and they create political bodies
and groups. And they
say, you know, look, we,
we believe and we cry just
like you do. Right. And, and,
and that's,
that's what I think has a lot to do
with breaking down these natural tribal
tendencies of human beings have because
human beings are tribal. We are tribal.
Even if you belong to one martial arts
school, it's so natural for you to go,
yeah, we're better though. Those guys
over there kind of. Yeah, they're fucking,
they do that thug jet too. We do
the original pure, you know, you,
you'll find that an [inaudible],
right. We're tribal and look at teams.
But the nationalism involved in my team
versus your team, I mean, you know,
these big rivalries. So the, but the
good news is that I believe that,
and I may be naive,
but I don't think so that pulling off
something as horrific as what happened in
the Holocaust would be very difficult.
Very difficult today and almost probably
impossible because too many of us would
go, this is outrageous. I don't think
it would get as as bad as the Holocaust,
but I think it's happening right now.
Well, it happened in Rwanda and the 90s.
Right. And uh, and that was, that wasn't
the, that was the, yeah. Yeah. And,
and those places again are pretty remote
and still haven't, but most of Africa,
I can't remember the number,
but there are an inordinate amount of um,
cell phones in Africa.
And during the violence in Kenya recently,
people started videotaping soldiers
raping women and they started tweeting and
texting where the concentration
of violence was happening.
So people were able to avoid that. So
what's happening is just like in Mexico,
at the drug cartels, people are
being empowered by social media.
And when they see a house
where drug activities going on,
they can just tweet it
anonymously in the cops,
go and find it so they don't have
to worry about retribution. So the,
a lot of these things,
a lot of the social media is a really
good thing because it's creating,
it's truly democratizing power.
It's really spacing power out.
And,
and in some ways it makes for, um,
it makes for a better place to live.
Know, could you imagine if you had
a move to Africa? Cause you'll have,
imagine if something happened,
like America doesn't like
Brian Calendar anymore.
You've got to get out of the country.
I've been to Africa twice, you know,
I know what if you have to live there,
I'm sure there's nice place.
There are very nice places of
Africa but for the most part,
and you'd probably want to be in the
United States to live in the Congo.
Could you imagine that?
That would suck that Japan has had
another fucking earthquake by the way.
7.0 like three days ago.
And I think right off site
Tokyo like in the water,
like a 7.0 all the shit makes me
wonder when I got to get ready,
do I need guns?
So I need to start scoring water.
What are we going to do
as an earthquake in Ohio?
And they found out where there's some
controversy dead that it might be because
they're drilling for wells and that they
actually had to shut it down because
there was recent,
uh,
activity from this drilling.
Like they've noticed that the activity
has been higher than normal and so they
shut it down. And then like, uh,
just a little bit of time later,
there was a 4.3 earthquake and Youngstown,
Ohio.
That's possible. They said that you can
do that. They say they can start some,
some sort of minor movements with like
some hardcore drilling kind of makes
sense if you drill a gonna fault,
you know it seems like, yeah,
but that is that you want
to fuck it up for good.
Now we're going to be
earthquakes all the time in Ohio.
Would you imagine if they did,
if they just the greedy fucks if they
just drilled the hole the wrong spot and
now it's like the worst fault line ever
and you can't really blame them because
no one,
there's no real science behind me.
It's really difficult for you to do prove
whether we know what caused maybe all
these earthquakes we're going to
happen anyway. And they wrote,
we actually have a thousand wells that
we've done in Ohio and in Pennsylvania
and we've never had a problem before.
The drill.
1,000 gigantic holds a thousand that's
so weird to like ten one hundred
you know you really got that fault line.
Good guys.
Just think about that a hundred
oh fire under those states because we
have a water source shorters and parts of
this country and but apparently
there's a massive aquafyer that that,
that they say is going to push a
lot of industry in that direction.
Like properties. What do you mean by
Aquafyer? I mean under a stream of water.
There's a massive natural
reservoir of water. Really?
Shit weird.
Is it agriculture?
It has all these creepy fucking
layers underneath us. You know,
we're just living on this crust.
We don't like to think that man
just right under you. You know,
whatever it is on my own.
What are from
what the Colorado River, I mean this
is where the La doesn't have water.
There's no water different.
We had to divert water from the Colorado
River and the Owens valley is just to
ride the fuck out.
Like,
that's what Chinatowns about where the
[inaudible] valley had all these farmers
and this way of life and they were
like the powers that be came in and go,
we need to, we need to grow a fucking
orange groves. And by the way,
let's start the movie industry here
because the weather is predictable. Oh,
we need water. Ah, fuck the Owens valley
rather redirect the river over this way.
And they, all these farmers were
like, my fucking sheep are dying.
I don't have any water. And
then, then they went fucking
nuts. But they were like,
sorry, we have the money. Wow. That's
what happened. What a creep move.
They stole their fucking river.
They'd dried out a whole fucking valley.
They stole their water. Isn't it amazing
you can do that? You could decide power.
He could decide, well, I like
the people that affects. That's,
that's when guys had power, like
smoking a cigar going, let's just, uh,
let's just divert the river. So what
do you mean sir? The Colorado River,
one of the biggest rivers in the country.
Yeah,
let's do that until they created
that salt and sea. Right.
I guess and then what it is.
I don't know. Some did alum,
I might be talking out of my ass.
I think it's
natural lakes in this, we're all,
and that result of just, you know,
figuring out a way to get water to
land so you could grow food. Yeah.
Is really a ridiculous place to live.
It's a fucking desert. So stupid. It is.
But as long as the water could get taken
away at any time and we're just like,
fuck it, it's 73 degrees and breezy
you all the time was 93 when,
so it's always really nice. Today was 85
degrees. He was 93 minutes driving. Jesus.
That's insane. I like it.
It's beautiful. I love is in
January. I love the heat, man.
It's a lot better than fucking freezing
your ass hawk. And I'll tell you what,
it's a lot better than black
ice and dealing with Boston.
I looked at high Sierra dude the
winter times driving it scared.
I remember going to high school up in
New England and I would met the nostrils
that deep my nostrils,
the mucus in my nostrils would freeze.
Walking from one firm to
breakfast next Thursday. Joe,
I've been on the highway before and uh,
watched it rain and washed the rain.
Just sort of start sticking to
your windshield. You're like,
what the fuck is going on here?
The rain was like just beginning to
s to to turn into, I like Christmas.
It was just beginning to become icy
rain and then the entire road became a
skating rink to anyone's
just slide into a ditch.
I'm going to do it. Everybody would
just wait. Have you been caught?
You ever been caught in a hailstorm?
Oh yeah.
It's a New Mexico in the summertime
and I got caught in a hailstorm,
like huge hailstone.
So New Mexico's got home,
they got legit hail got hail that they
put on Youtube. Yeah, it's crazy. Yeah.
I golf balls and the whole city had it
and everybody's cards with or fucked up
and everybody does the same
thing I did, which is like, Oh,
they gave me $1,200 to fix it.
I'm just keeping the money and buying
some x box games and stuff so everybody's
cards had we're fucked up.
Like for years.
Their dog's got jacked, peoples
got, dogs got fucked up.
There's one video that I watched
this kid put a a video up of.
It's starting and he didn't know how bad
it was going to get because it was so
crazy. It was like, oh my God, this
fucking, this, this tail is so bad.
We had to film it. So He's, look,
you're filming in his backyard and it's
coming down, man. You're watching it,
but then as he's filming it,
it just turns into the preposterous.
It turns into the end of time.
It turns into a fucking shotgun of ice.
It's coming out of the sky every second
to mean his fucking pool is exploding.
Exploding with splashes. Yes. Yeah.
There's a lot of them. Oh my God,
you can't believe it.
It's the most horrific.
The thought that you could be on your way
home from somewhere or walk home. Yeah,
but you've got headphones on.
I don't even know what's happening.
You get hit with the first ice
pellets. I ain't, that's what,
that's what I was talking
about. Okay. That's the,
that's the random shit that drives me.
I don't want to die randomly.
Like for example,
how about this?
I told you the story where the couple
is driving down the fucking highway and
they hit a bear 60 miles
an hour there it goes,
flying into the other lane and kills
the people coming in this way. Oh my
God. Flying fucking bear.
Wow, that's annoying.
Can't bear proof your windshield. Okay. It
happened in West Hollywood. I saw, dude,
what a thing on his car for a deer though.
When I lived in Colorado,
he had this bad ass fucking
battering Ram Fraley grill.
He had a pickup truck and he was a hunter.
I here kill more people than any
other show. A lot of people, man,
you gotta be really careful.
They're crazy. They just, you know,
they have nutty instincts that just leap
out in front of cars and I don't think
they quite understand something can move
as fast as a car because in nature they,
I think they get a lot more of a warning
then that judge cause the cars on one
level.
So when it's coming at you on a highway,
you can't tell it fast because it
operates on the same plane. Oh.
So cause it's not jumping up and
down runs or a Predator runs,
they stay on one level.
They're not jumping up and down.
Whereas it cause hell is jumping up
and down. Right. You can, you can,
you can measure how fast they're
going. But when uh, physics wise,
when something is operating
along the same plane,
it's much harder to judge their speed.
That's why when you're on a
highway and cars coming at you,
you can't tell what's going 90
or 60 staying at the same level.
Now is it an efficiency thing
for a cat or something like that?
More more apparently more
just the evolution wise. It's,
it's so the animal can't tell
how fast it's coming to racing.
It doesn't run according. It
just runs right. But, but,
but the cat looks like it's farther
away from you then if it was John.
And it's also hard to see.
It's also staying,
it's also staying low on the foliage.
There's a cool video of a guest
South America's Jaguars, right?
It's a Jaguar eating a giant rat
like thing Kappy Berra. Yeah,
that's exactly what it is on video.
But they're number one.
This dude's filmed it
[inaudible] 90 pounds.
It's enormous. It's like the
size of a big fucking dog man.
And this Jaguar is sitting
there just completely frozen,
like not moving at all.
And the video takes like,
it takes four minutes of the Jaguar doing
nothing until he launches himself on
this thing with Jaguars, which are very
big. Cats will eat a human right quick.
You, you the one, the one hand,
the one cat you don't want to be around
is the Jaguar more than anything else,
including a tiger. You don't want to
fuck around with it. But you know,
when people take Iowasca,
that's that DMT beverage that
they take in South America.
One of the big visions that
people have is Jaguars.
They have lot of Jaguar visions. Did
you, you know, my buddy works for, um,
like the secret service,
you know, and you know,
they get calls all the time because like
sometimes they'll get there for foreign
service guys who go in and nail,
they'll fucking take like gr.
They try to mix in with the locals and
I'll take drugs and then they'll just end
up in the middle of the fucking
Amazon or the Congo and they have to,
they have to get a search team to go find
them cause they took some fucking drug.
And there are several stories like
that. Or how about this, how about this?
If the guy during the Haiti,
not during this earthquake,
but there was another disaster back
in the nineties people were trying to
emigrate
to the states. Right. And I'm
the guy, they had one dude,
some young dude who is like basically at
the embassy who there's a long line of
people trying to immigrate to the u s
and none of them were getting it, right.
So you basically just go with denied.
Denied, denied. This is one they had.
This one young guy was like a shit
assignment there, right? And it's hot.
There's a fan on them. And he started,
he just like, people kept lining up.
He just kept going. He kept
going, denied, fucking denied.
Finally started going stir crazy. Right?
And, and uh, he had this little, um,
what's that? Star Wars? Well, who's a star
wars character? Both of fit well of that.
And bubba fat. Okay. So we have
a little Boba Fett all there.
And so he started going,
he just started going crazy and the guy
would come up and he'd go, hold on, sorry.
I boba Fett says denied. Sorry. And
he start doing that. The beaver,
that's like Mel Gibson's
movie. Okay. Well, so he starts
going, Boba Fett says no,
right?
Cause not all of a sudden the people
started giving him Boba Fett offerings.
Okay. So like, like a week later,
Boba Fett has a fucking pile of
everything from food to cigarettes,
like a whole mountain like right here.
Okay.
Then then a block markets are
developing over a Boba Fett dolls,
Boba Fett costumes.
And people started coming up with Boba
Fett costumes and dolls and stuff trying
to get in because they thought that
was kind of who you had to talk to.
And I figured the sky was,
they figured this guy's obviously talking
about the fat and this guy and he's up
Boba Fett fanatics.
So we should show allegiance to Boba Fett.
So people were coming and trusts like
Boba Fett and the u s embassy had to be
like, all right, we got
to fucking stop this,
take that fucking doll out outta
here right fucking now as this will.
Cause the guy was like, Hey, yes,
I'm more money. Yes, thank you.
Thank you very much. And Boba
Fett says, no, I'm sorry.
And the guy who dressed like Boba Fett,
like what the fuck?
It's amazing that that guy got so
far that just shows you that was,
that was a story.
That was a story that this guy was as
foreign foreign service guy told me about.
Oh, by the way, my other buddy buddy
came to visit me. I can't say his name,
but he's a CIA guy or something like that.
I don't know what he does,
but I know he's been under a rock
for 10 years and Afghanistan.
He was telling me about that fucking what
the waste that goes on. How about this?
How about this? In in Iraq,
they, they, it's a desert, right?
They spent $100,000 importing
sand for volleyball courts,
so they had to,
they brought $100,000 worth of sand in
for the volleyball courts as opposed to
just getting the sand in Iraq.
I'm sure you could find fucking
sand somewhere in Iraq. Nah,
let's import it from the states because
everybody's got their fucking mouths at
the government trough and
when you got a war going on,
there's so much money to be made and
everybody does it and it's just a
confluence of fucking events in everybody.
Everybody who goes there,
you'd have a project, you have money and
you want to build a big dam or a power,
a power, a big power plant, right?
It doesn't matter if the
fucking Iraqis needed or not.
What matters that you burn your money.
You get judged by your burn rate, okay.
And it has you, you, you,
you have a certain allotted a budget
and you have to get a fucking huge power
plant. Whether it's needed, there are not.
The point is to get it done because
then you get a promotion or your aunt or
your project is a success and that shit
was going on and continues to go on in
Iraq for the past 10 fucking years.
The waste is so outrageous.
It's ridiculous.
By the way. You know the,
the Iraqis you're not,
do you know how much oil we've gotten
from the Rockies? How much oil revenue?
None.
It's all gone into her rocky coffers.
This whole thing costs us a fucking
fortune. And let me go on. Let me go on.
Maliki is creating his own secret service.
Police forces that direct report directly
to him. Does that sound familiar?
So we fucking take the country
apart and now we're creating.
We're leaving behind Saddam light. See
you later. Thanks a lot guys. We uh,
you know he's consolidating power, keeping
the Sunni's out. So as soon as like,
fuck you, we're going to lose all our,
we're going to lose all the resources.
You guys are sitting,
all the resources in the south.
We're going to bomb the fucking shit out
of you guys until you come back to the
bargaining table. Hey, civil war in Iraq.
It's fucking a tragic past that.
But,
but you know who was calling
all that shit? A lot of people,
including this fucking idiot. And
I'm an actor and I, and I, I said,
how are you going to stop the Sudanese
and this she has from getting into a war
after all the shit breaks down.
And how do you stop the Shia who are a
majority from aligning themselves with
Iran are number one
enemy. Huh? That's weird.
Wasn't Iraq kind of a who playing a sort
of a countervailing force to a Iran.
I'm an actor and I was asking that
question. I'm an actor and you know what?
I read one newspaper a day,
that's all.
I don't know anything and these
fucking guys couldn't figure that out.
So why is it so why do you think that
our foreign policies so self destruct?
I asked him,
I asked him that question and,
and obviously there's a lot
of people are making a profit,
but it almost seems like burning
the farm down had a great answer.
He had a great answer cause I said, how
much of this is like a, a group of men,
a cabal of evil men or how much of
the centrally planned or people have
different interests? And he said, dude,
he goes, it's not like that. He said,
what it is is there's
just a whole bunch of the,
and I'll give you another
example of what's happening
there. I said, what is this?
There's a whole bunch of interests
working a whole bunch of money to me and
everybody has different opinions and some
opinions when the day and others don't.
Right. And so the State
Department has their own agenda.
The executive have that has their agenda
and everybody has their own agenda.
But ultimately enough shit starts to
be kind of like talked about where you
start creating an enemy.
You start saying this might be a good
idea for the following reasons and pretty
soon there's so much,
there's so many sort of, um,
there's so many groups of people that
have a vested interest in going in.
And usually it's an intellectual
interests. Usually it's like,
I think we can bring democracy
to the Middle East. Uh,
and that's a very grandiose idea and
grandiose plan. Oh, and by the way,
because it's going to make the
world safer. At the end of the day,
they're a lot of idealistic
people involved in this.
Well, not just money people.
And all of a sudden all the shit
starts to come together. And,
and before you know it, you're fucking
on your way to a war, you know?
And the way he described it
made a lot of sense. It's just,
it's like a tidal wave. It's like starts
as a snowball. And before, you know,
you got a fucking massive tsunami
on your hands up. Just momentum.
And there's just so many interests in is
so much movement in one direction that
what are you gonna do then call it off?
No, you got weapons of mass destruction.
He's used to before. Let's go, let's go,
let's go take out the fourth largest
army in the world because it's not safe.
And, uh, you know, let's, let's,
let's make the world a better place.
And you get a bunch of
people like that who do it.
And then of course you get a lot of
people, if you haven't seen, it's gone.
We can make a lot of fucking money.
Boeing, Lockheed, Raytheon saying, dude,
they're going to need a lot of weapons
systems. They're not going to need them,
but we can sell them to them.
It's an amazing thing to the,
once that money starts coming in and
coming in and just billion dollar look
contract after billion dollar contract,
I mean the amount of money is
defense contractors, Halliburton,
the clean up people, all the different
people in the amount of monies. Insane.
Try asking them to cut it off. How about
this? Well, not only that, $11 billion,
we have an $11 billion arms
deal with Iraq right now, okay?
And it's about to go through it.
But here's the thing,
can't give around the arms because Maliki
is not not agreeing to the terms heat
we set for him,
which was you have to share power with
the Sunni's because we don't want a civil
war there. And we have a lot of American
interests already in Iraq and Iraq, okay?
There's a lot of American companies
making money. Now here's the thing, you,
you tell a politician to veto that 11
million on dollar arms deal. You now,
how many people that employees, you
know, how many people that, that, that,
that you know, how many
constituents are fucking, um, uh,
our voting based on the fact that they
get a job because of leaven. Bill,
you're going to take $11 billion out
of the American economy. Good luck.
Good fucking luck. And that's
what happens. Isn't that
amazing? It's amazing money,
but the money to make shit that
kills people unnecessarily. Yeah. Oh,
we need $11 billion.
We're going to give you 11 million now.
It's owned by the way, we're going to get
that to you and Maliki. So you can see,
you can create your own army of
Shia to keep the Sunni's down.
And that's called the civil war.
Without the military industrial complex,
how much less war would there be? I
don't know the answer. I don't know.
I don't, I don't think it's war that you
would stop. But I do think if you take,
I think I do think with, with, with,
well I think the private sector makes a
lot of money off of the decisions made
in government. And so there is
a profit to be made from war.
And if that's the case,
it does raise an important question.
How if war becomes big business?
Uh, let me give you another example.
A Iran. Iran has nuclear program. At
least we're trying to stop, right? Uh,
we did sell bunker buster bombs to
Israel about three years ago now.
Now what?
Our bunker buster bombs,
bunker buster bombs and these particular
ones we sold to Israel are bombs that
can penetrate deep into the
earth and take out on arsenal.
So if you have an, uh,
uh, nuclear, um, uh,
facility that is churning out weapons,
these bunker bombs supposed to go into
the earth and blow that fucking facility
to smithereens. Okay. Now we don't
want to do it, but maybe Israel will,
we'll drop those bombs on aunt cause
they know where Iran is making these
weapons.
I uh,
do you think that the Americans are
sitting back and using the Israelis as a
proxy to see if those fucking
bunker buster bombs work? Uh,
there seems to be a lot of noise
headed Iran way. It seems to me.
There seems to be
something brewing in Iran.
They have taken a very aggressive
stance with the, uh, with the, the golf,
with, with blocking
off, um, oil routes now.
And the U s navy is saying
this is unacceptable.
There's a whole bunch of noise going on
and it seems to me things are moving in,
in a,
in a direction that is not an Iran is
favor and let's see what happens next.
But a lot of money, a lot
of money is real. You know,
we probably gave those those weapons
Israel without, with, for, for no pay,
but we want to see if they
work. You know, Wesley Clark,
the guy ran for president
predicted all this shit. Yeah.
Predicted every single stone. He
lives it every day. It's amazing.
He sees the fucking waste.
Yeah.
He sees how much money and
what kind of a lobbying,
uh, power, Raytheon and
Boeing and Lockheed are.
You don't think they have
massive lobbying efforts. Uh,
there's just too much money at stake
and they can find a way to justify it is
legal. Yeah. You know,
has been done employment.
I'll employ 10,000 people in your
state cause I'll take my thing,
but we got to build this. We've got to
build these very important, um, you know,
fucking [inaudible]. These are
all, this is all shocking shit.
It's all big bummer. End of the
world. Shit, how do you fix it?
Is there a way, is there a way
to fix? I will. I will tell you,
I'll tell you what Ron Paul would say.
I'll just,
Ron Paul would say,
the only way to fix it is to make the
government the government that everybody
feeds off of.
And it has a lot of power to make these
decisions that you make the government
smaller. You take away some of
government's power and that's his NFU.
And there's a,
there's,
I just watched a speech by Ronald Reagan
that he made it and I think 1969 and
it's called a time to choose.
And if he made that speech today,
Ron Paul, Ron Paul could make that
speech today. And, and it would,
it wouldn't be any different at all.
He talks about how 37 cents of your dollar
is gone to the government before you
even wake up in the morning. 37% of
your day is working for the government.
And the government keeps getting
bigger and getting better.
He talks about the war on poverty and
if he say he did a little arithmetic,
it goes,
if we take the money that we spend on
poverty and he takes a list of how many
poor people that are, he said everybody
should be getting $4,600 a, um,
a year.
But it turns out we're getting $600.
How that happened is some
money being lost along the way.
It was all the stuff that wrong. Let's
just go, let's explore that, right? Okay,
here's the deal. What if you do make
the government smaller? What do you,
how do you,
how much do you keep?
And then what happens to all those people
that used to be government employees
that have a career in
being government employees?
Is that this the biggest problem?
And by the way,
I mean some of those folks are
hard working folks and you know,
they do a great service to the country
and some of those folks are useless and
there's a lot of people that are a
little leeches unto a sister. Me, yes.
And for me it doesn't have to do with
being Republican, Democrat, conservative,
liberal. It has nothing to do that
for me. What, what I look at it as,
as anything big at whether it's a
big corporation or the government,
which has no accountability
and is that big.
I don't understand how you can make that,
that power run efficiently.
I do see how it can grow and it
keeps growing and that's the threat.
And like you just said, you just brought
up the biggest question. What happens?
How do you make government smaller?
It has so many vested
interests and not only that,
it's not just government computerize.
Privates private industry is
involved in this. You're right,
technology computers is the right answer.
Instead of having some asshole fucking
suit that represents your state, you know,
go up in front of everybody and
no misstate everyone's position.
Instead of having that you could have
the people actually let me say it,
they'll actually let me say one
other thing. You're not alone.
You're not alone in your thinking and
what the conversation we're having is
being had all over the country,
both Democrat and Republican circles and
that this whole Wall Street occupy Wall
Street movement is, is,
is in some ways, uh,
voicing some of those frustrations.
W what w I'll give you a piece
of good news in my opinion. Okay.
And a piece of good news that
we've never experienced before. Um,
you hear a lot of people talking about
inequality. Income, okay. And there is,
however there is, we
are, we are experiencing,
and I'm stealing this from a
Wall Street Journal article,
so I'm paraphrasing this,
but there is an equality of consumption
that we've never experienced before.
And let me give,
let me tell you what I mean by that.
Take somebody who's very wealthy,
very wealthy.
You have a lot more money than I do. I
do pretty well, but you got a moment.
Your life, your life and my
life are very, are very similar.
The only difference might be might
be that you drive a faster car,
but we sit in the same traffic. You
drive a Porsche. I drive a Prius,
but we basically sit in the same traffic.
But the interior of my car,
not that much different. I got gps, I got
a great stereo, I got everything I need.
The the,
you wear the same clothing I do.
I guess you could wear Armani and Versace.
You never would. And the rest of that,
it's fluff. We eat the same amount of
food. And if you look at most people,
and I'm talking about the
middle class in this country,
including people who are struggling
for money and stuff, most people,
the average amount of for a wedding
spent in this country is somewhere around
$26,000 a year.
I'm $26,000 that's a lot of money.
So what we are doing,
what we have now as an economy where
very rich people invent something.
Say it's an application or a computer or
something that we all we all use. Okay.
But they don't make any money unless they
can generate mass consumption of that
product so that most of us own a computer.
Most of us own a cell phone, and that
cell phone has all kinds of applications.
Most of us have a TV that brings to that,
that allows us to watch
pretty much anything we want.
High def TVs cost $700 of the
technology that you have in your phone.
Let's take the old Wall Street, the
first Wall Street with Michael Douglas.
He pulls out,
he pulls out a Motorola phone that weighs
two pounds and cost $3,995 back then.
Okay.
And it was,
it was a brick and weighed two pounds
and that was for the illegal is a little
more than that actually,
but that was for the elite back then.
That was what Michael Douglas pulls
out a cell phone and we go, Holy Shit.
He carries his own phone now a days.
The difference between,
I'll tell you Steven jobs and I use
the same fucking phone, Warren Buffet,
and I use the same foam, right? The only
difference in Warren Buffett and me,
the only difference is he flies privately.
But I can fly anywhere I want for under
a thousand dollars anywhere in the world.
If I, if I, if I get on
the Internet fast enough.
So we have an equality of
consumption in this country,
unlike any time in the history of the
world. And that's good fucking news.
Most people I'm talking about,
most people at least have enough to eat.
They have an ability
to contact each other.
They have an ability to entertain
themselves almost the way they want.
How many people own Xboxes?
I believe it was last year,
60 million were sold or something crazy
as Xboxes. So think about that. Yeah.
So, so, so we have access and we have
access to information and inspiration.
How many people listen to your podcasts?
You don't have a lot of money,
but they get inspired that you turn them
on to things that they can afford. Uh,
you, you, you know, this is what's, this
is what the good news is about. Yes,
we may have inequality of income,
but we have equality of consumption
like we'd never seen before and that's
fucking, that's a big deal.
And nobody talks about that.
This definitely isn't the worst
time in human history. The great,
the thing I think what would really
is killing people is the unrealized
potential of the human race. That's what
drives people nuts. People that really,
truly are patriotic people that really,
truly do have respect and
admiration for the human spirit.
They believed that there's a much higher
level that our society and our culture
can achieve. And I do too. It's
not that I'm an unpatriotic,
it's just that I think, God damn, we
could do a lot fucking better than this.
We don't have to be the crux of the
world. It's not necessary. We can,
we were going to die some day.
We are temporary beings the way
we're doing this is ridiculous.
The fact that we've allowed these people
to continue to operate like this is
ridiculous.
They're not looking out for our needs.
We shouldn't be playing
police all over the world.
We should have a hundred fucking military
basis over the world. It's ridiculous.
Our military industrial complex as
somehow or another co-opted the entire
government and they're forcing people
into some shifted. The people don't want,
even the patriotic people don't.
Very few people think it's a good idea
that we stick around and Afghanistan,
I mean Afghanistan doesn't even need is
we overthrew the government. I wreck.
We took off and left them
in chaos obviously. Right?
Everything's fucking falling
apart over there and guess what?
Afghanistan doesn't have a government,
right? They're not even a real country.
It's ridiculous.
The idea that we can't leave it on.
We don't want that to happen
over here. My, my buddy,
the other guy was a CIA guy said to me,
he said,
he said when he spent a lot of time in
Afghanistan and he said they were talking
to a dude on the border of Pakistan
and a of Afghanistan was Xerostomia.
That lawless area. The guy didn't know
what Pakistan was. He never, he was on,
he lived on the mountain. He was like,
what are you talking about? I don't,
that's not my reality. I, and you want,
you want a guy in counter hard to have
loyalty to add somebody to the government
in Kabul. There's never been
a tradition of that. Never.
So what are you talking about?
The just war lords, by the way,
I drunk a corrupt government like you
think Karzai and his group are, are,
are looking out for all the [inaudible]
and the touchy acts up in the north.
The fuck you [inaudible]
brother who was a CIA drug.
A drug runner. Yeah. Drug runners
slash getting checks from the CS. What?
They're having a tough time
getting people to not grow poppies.
Oopsie for heroin. We'd rather, you know,
grow cotton and soybean because it's a
lot more profitable. It's, it's, it's,
these are, these are a lot of
those soldiers. I was out there,
I was out there and
those fucking soldiers,
those soldiers that were
building hospitals and schools
and those guys are brave.
And I fucking him proud where
every time I see those guys okay.
And a lot of them died and a lot of
them got fucking grievously a grievously
wounded. Is that a word? It doesn't
matter. So, so, so the, the,
the bottom line is I'm not,
I'm not, uh, that's what,
that's what kills me is that effort
and that fucking dozers, real heroes.
You'll fucking men and women
up there with it. Yeah.
And then we go out there and anybody,
you can tell anybody you talked to anybody
who really knows about the country,
including those soldiers who've
been there a long time ago.
What the fuck are we doing, man? You
can't build us is going to build a nation,
Afghanistan. And you're going to build
a nation where there never was one.
What are you talking about?
All you're doing is taking money and
moving it to people with bigger guns.
What is the deal with al Qaeda in
Afghanistan isn't there's like almost none
left. No, there's no awkward. No Al Qaeda.
And by the way, you think the Afghanis,
but there is a Taliban. It tell,
you know what Taliban button means.
Tell means student. Really? Yes.
So you're a student. So tally bond.
She has say is you're telling about I
tally bond means yes, I'm a stew. Yeah,
you're here. You're a student students.
Yes. Italian. You know, you're, you're,
and you're a student. So you know,
then that why? Because the, the,
the notion came out of those schools and
put shower and in Saudi Arabia, most of,
oh,
most of those schools,
all of those schools in the shower
and came out at were financed by Saudi
Arabia. Our number one ally in the Middle
East. Okay. They were financed by that.
Why? The Saudis are what? Hobbies.
That is a puritanical sect of Sunni Islam.
Okay.
Obsessed with purity. Okay,
so let's start there. Uh,
that's what happened and you have to go
all the way back to when that Soviets
actually invaded Afghanistan and we were
financing the Mujahideen and everything
else with the help of the Isi, which
is the music truths. You would be,
the growth got
to ask about this because I watched it
in a documentary where they were saying
that the,
the whole term for jihad was originally
a war on your own vices and that it was
subverted by the CIA. The root word,
if you had an Arabic is struggle,
struggle and struggle. You had meant
she had meant two things. I look,
I said that was very sad. She had very
authentic. It's so authentic. I love you.
And the idea behind it of
course, was the, was the,
with the battle that always wages between
the flesh and the spirit in your own
heart.
And then when the CIA was training the
Mujahideen and supplying them with arms,
they somehow or another subvert it
to get them to meet the who did it,
who got them to change it to holy war.
What happened was when,
when you had people who were fighting,
first of all, what the Soviets did too.
I've gotten some, it's pretty horrific,
right? Cut Out, cut down all the trees,
bombed all kinds of villages. And
you had these, you created fanatics.
You created men who,
who basically had lost their village,
gotten and they're young men and
basically looking for natural gas.
Is that what they're looking for?
We're just looking for a buffer.
They were looking for a um, uh, they were,
I believe they were looking essentially
for a buffer zone between Pakistan and
and themselves. Oh,
okay. That makes sense.
It was all just all due to
the Cold War and, and um,
and they were afraid they were going
to lose control of Afghanistan.
Never really had nobody ever
wanted to be in Afghanistan.
You didn't want to be living in the
Khyber Pass. It's too forbidding.
There wasn't oil there. They say
there's minerals there. Good luck.
Nobody fucking wants the
minerals that we don't have.
We get what we get plenty of minerals
from Africa and places that are much
easier and nobody wants
to go into Afghanistan.
It's always been a group of unruly.
You still not totally
true because of the one,
there's a lot of people that he had
the resources to top those. Yeah,
but nobody wanted to get involved.
It's just back then in [inaudible] 79,
when they [inaudible] Steve
is just fucking too difficult.
They didn't understand that nobody ever
anticipated the worth of the minerals
though the crew for cell phones, you
know, like lithium ion for batteries.
This is one of the the best,
uh,
mining areas in the world for all
these different, I don't know,
it's all over all these different
scientific journals. I mean,
they found over $1 trillion worth
of minerals and Afghanistan.
We'll see if anybody is willing
to put the money into that.
It's such a fucking pain in the ass to it.
I can't understand why you
would say that there's,
there's $1 trillion laying in the ground.
You,
you're telling me that it's not going
to be big businesses going to pull that
out of there $1 trillion oil.
Do the trillion dollars can
change the fucking world.
$1 trillion couldn't put a company into,
I'm a senior out of a position of power.
You should research it before we talk
any further. I don't know. I don't know.
It's indisputable.
They found a gigantic or of minerals
they had always suspected, but it's much,
much larger than they thought. I don't
believe that we went into Afghanistan.
I think we went into counseling
because they were harboring al Qaeda.
I think that's what it was very
hard to get it politically.
You can't get the American public
that you say the American public,
hey we got minerals, we've got everybody
wants it to be either or, you know,
all we went into there because were
corrupt and we're trying to take all their
poppies cause it's not billions
dollars with a heroin. No, it's easy.
It's not an either or. It's a god
damn soup of Shit. And by the way,
it doesn't hurt that they could make
money off the poppy. So it doesn't hurt.
There's $1 trillion worth of minerals.
It doesn't,
we should try to predict the next six
out there. There's opportunity. Right.
But isn't it funny how everybody
wants to have a black or white issue?
It's either a crazy conspiracy
theory that's, or you know,
this is just the unfortunate
nature of reality. That's movies.
That's what we want. We want, they're
so fucking stupid. It's so amazing.
It's way sloppier. Real life is
waste sloppier. You know when you,
when you talk to, I think it was Tony Snow
before he died, said they were saying,
well what are you guys gonna do
about this situation? He said, guys,
when we're in the Oval Office and you've
got a bunch of people there with all
the top brass in the military
and the CIA and then you've got,
you know the State Department,
we do exactly what you think we do.
Try sitting in a room with 10 we strike,
try sitting in a room of 30
people and come up with one,
one idea to try to come up with one
thing everybody agrees on you don't
everybody's banding ideas back and forth.
People are disagreeing with each other.
People are pissed off cause they you over,
you talked over me so nobody can get the
presidents here and that's what happens.
And then the president has to go into a
room with three of his advisors and have
to fucking go. We got seven options
that we'd been presented. No.
Why do you think that in that case, why
do you think that Obama is like such a,
a wishy washy dude?
Why do you think he's the guy that
is willing to pass the NDA bill?
He's the guy that is, I think
my, my feeling and I don't know,
but my feeling is in the mistake
Obama made and I think the,
the opportunity he wasted was not,
not, I think he's an academic,
first of all. And I think he's
by nature a very, very, um,
uh, he's, uh, he's, uh,
he's an intellectual and he looks at
both sides and I think he's by nature
fairly indecisive maybe because he's an
intellectual and I think, I think so.
I'm just, I'm just speaking,
he's compromised. I think
it's clearly compromised.
He doesn't have the, uh, I don't
think, I don't know. There's nothing I,
I don't necessarily agree that
he's that smart. And also,
I don't think that he has a,
the backbone. I don't think,
I don't think it's an effective
leader. I think that, uh,
he should be more convicted.
He should have stronger convictions.
He does have strong convictions
towards the people. Got them in power.
And that's what you've got to look at it.
If you guys look,
people spent a lot of money to get that
guy into the position that he's in and
he's working for them now. It's as
clear as day. Yeah, well they'll listen.
Let's let look at that.
I mean a president spends two years doing
as policy and then he spends the next
few years trying to get reelected.
It's just basically trying to keep
everybody reasonable. You know? It's like,
come on folks, let's just be reasonable
with how hard we fuck these people.
I mean that's really where
the president's job is.
They get it and the best they can do
is say, I really don't agree with this,
but I have to sign it.
He voted against what he did with the NDA.
He voted against a rock and I,
and I always appreciate that you said,
I don't believe in going into Iraq.
Yeah.
But meanwhile here we are who we are.
A lot
of it's tough for a presence. Yeah.
It's tough. I don't know if it's read.
Do you think the problems,
how much say do you think he really has?
How much say do you, I mean,
is it possible for him to
go against those people?
Is it even possible? Can't do a thing
without congress. Right. So he has,
he has executive power,
but they used to be that way,
but you don't have to declare war anymore.
You just start going over places and next
thing you know, shit happens. I mean,
was war ever declared and it was there
a couple of conflicts that we were
involved in were congress did not step
in and declare war. Vietnam. Yeah,
there you go. I mean that's, it's not,
we don't necessarily know there's,
there's an emergency executive powers,
you know,
and then that's another creepy thing.
It's like when you find out how many
fucking bills and laws are passed just
under your nose. Congress passed flying
bombs passed 40,000 miles last year.
$40,000 Ladies and gentlemen, why
is that? Do you really meet them?
I believe that is the,
uh, that is the number.
What I say is that you need Clint
Eastwood laws and this sort sorta clinics
would laws. If you couldn't imagine
cleany Twitter arresting somebody for it,
then it should be common sense law.
It's fucking Clint Eastwood.
It's only assholes. Douchebags
meth heads guy who needs a punch.
Someone you have to shut but you gas laws.
But you get into really complicated
issues with, for example, antipiracy laws.
How far do you go with that stuff?
Right? So, so you know, you and I love,
we raging debate on my website about this
because we will, because the website,
because the web is the last frontier of
free speech of free everything and it's
not regulated.
Now my take on it though,
electrical property from being stolen
by countries like China. What do you do?
Do you pass a bunch of laws? Would that
help the problem? I don't think it would.
Well we would have,
we would have to step up and say
somehow or another we're going to,
we're going to boycott the, I
mean, they wouldn't eat you kill,
you couldn't boycott the whole country.
That'd be ridiculous.
You couldn't knew that.
You couldn't make a few people that won't,
won't play nice internationally
responsible for the whole country.
And what the fuck would you
do it, man? Well, you know,
we've got to do is somehow or another
get it into people's minds when they're
really, really young, really young,
that the world is so much better if you're
cool to people and then once they get
there, the mean it's spreading that Ma,
no, we haven't. Not only in other words,
in other words,
we haven't never will but what,
but here's the thing that's
not necessarily true because
we've never had access
to human beings.
The way we have access now
and the Internet and I think
that human beings to two
things happen. One, you develop
in a terrible environment and you,
you develop all these defense mechanisms
at genes that are only activated under
extreme stress and you need to develop
like a whole culture of people that are
in a bad situation on a regular
basis and are wired for that shit.
That's terrible. Okay. You,
you also develop a bunch of people
who don't get love on a regular basis.
They don't know how to give up.
They don't have a real true sense
of community if real problems,
if you don't educate people
and how to be a perception,
but once you do and once you can,
you can slowly change things.
You can change the way
children are raised,
you can change the way relationships
between your neighbors or form and you can
slowly spread this out to the point
where it can have a real effect.
You can essentially be a new
operating system for people.
Well, for the most part, I
got two thoughts on that.
One is if you read Tim Ferriss's book,
the four hour Workweek, not for our body,
but the four hour work week.
Listen man,
I ain't got no time.
I'm trying to get some four hour
bike season a hair and he's a really,
he's really a great author,
isn't he? I really love that.
Lot of that fascinating
poker and I love that.
I love the other one and he said,
and he said something and it goes to the
internet and stealing and things. Look,
he said you,
when you give people,
when you like what you doing here
with the brain thing, you say,
if you don't like it, I'm sending back
get, we'll give you your money back.
When you do something like from a business
plan and he talks about it, he says,
just tell people you'll give
them either you can give people,
you can tell people, you'll give them
double their money back and people go,
well that people will abuse it.
I'll, I'll go broke. Guess what?
About 2% of the people out there always
abuse it always and the rest of them
don't. And the bottom line is
it's like stealing music. Okay.
Once you started getting out there
to piracy is stealing. Most people,
and I don't steal fucking music.
Okay. Some people do, but I was like,
I'm an artist. I bout to come up
with my one hour special. I'm like,
I don't want people stealing it.
And it'd be nice if they paid for it.
I guess you, if I feel guilty, I feel
guilty because I listened to some,
somebody a great song and all
the effort that went into it.
I don't want to see like, and
actually most people, most
people don't steal music.
Most people go to Itunes,
they down to the 12 Shawnee five
cause they have no money. Sure.
But even that man,
even then if you look at the statistics,
even then if you look at this disease,
I my Shitty,
I'm a shitty business person because
I don't think about business.
I try to think about it.
I want to think about business as little
as possible and if anybody's ever said
to me like, Hey, if I could get your
your DVD on torrent or should buy,
should I buy it? I'm
like, you know what man?
You should do whatever feels right to
you. That's what you should do. Okay.
If you don't want to pay for it,
don't pay for it.
If you feel like it's okay to take it,
just go ahead. I mean it's not, look,
I'm going to,
I'm going to put stuff out there and
I'm going to put it out there with the
honest intention of trying
to entertain people.
I'm going to say this is what the
fee is and if you pay it, you pay it.
And it would, Louis CK did is the perfect
thing where he released it himself.
Total direct connection between the
artist put it out for five bucks,
which is awesome. You know, it's
a perfect price and you know what?
I think that that's the future.
I think all these other relationships,
amazing books. I'm talking about exodus.
I downloaded for $7 and even Louis,
they pirated his thing even
though he said, you know,
he asked people not to steal it.
Don't put it up on Torrence,
but you're always to have
some people did that.
But there are always going to him.
But you know what man?
Some people don't have five bucks.
Okay. And I know it sounds stupid,
but you can't
unless you're starving because of all
this, you can't fixate on it. Those,
the correct thing to fixate on is get
out your point of view. And you know,
I look, I've been in a position
before where I was broke
and uh, unfortunately for
me there was no internet at
the time. Right. You know,
I didn't have the opportunity
to just download music, but
of course I would. Yeah.
When I had no money, I mean
what I'd be like, you know,
I would love to listen
to this led Zepplin over,
but it wouldn't be a good person.
You know,
when I would say I'm going to buy this
fucking thing someday when I have some
money, but right now I'm going to
download the shit out of this. Beautiful.
The way artists make money, they're still
making money. Yeah. They're not starving.
And by the way, it's beautiful
that all that shit gets out there.
I want everybody to download every fucking
led Zeppelin album that's ever made.
And if it's,
you know,
a dollar that you can't afford to
get fucking whole lot of love goes,
you'll find it somewhere man. But
he will. So listen to it on youtube.
This like things you can take where
you can take a song off youtube,
they'll convert it into an MP,
three 40 now credit card companies have,
I think it's setting a ceiling,
but credit card companies always have
what they factor in a certain fraud
quotient in their business plan.
And I think it's almost all,
it's really interesting because
actually like 2.2 or something,
it's almost always the same percentage.
2.2% of the population is going to defraud
you and you're going to lose money.
And they just factor that in.
There's always,
it's the same percentage that you were
talking about earlier with double your
money back guarantee, you know with
the, the Alpha brain supplements. Yeah.
If he did do that,
I bet you're right.
I bet it'd be the same 2% of this group
of people that are out of a hundred
suck. Maybe that's the number.
Maybe that is the number.
Cause I've always said it's like 50% like
it's, I don't, it's like sociopath's.
Right. One in a hundred people is a
sociopath or something crazy like that.
He like that. Yeah, that's,
that's a disturbing figure man.
One to a hundred people doesn't care
if you're fucked up and not one in a
hundred people just have no feelings
for other people sticking rods in her
asshole and well, those are very rare
like serial killers and that sex,
sex slash by the way,
now that I just remember it,
I mean you were talking about that
guy who got fucked death by the horse.
He might have been one of those.
He had piercings all over his balls.
There you go. There you go. You fucking
nailed it. I totally forgot about that.
Yeah. The guy had like a member.
He had a gang of piercings.
If you're doing extreme things like that,
you've lost the ability to feel
and you've got to think about it.
You've got a jacket. For me, the
fleshlight is fantastic ladies. Gentlemen,
get it on.
Joe Rogan.
Isn't it crazy with that recent
arsonists here in Los Angeles or die?
It doesn't happen more often that that,
that one out of a hundred just
doesn't start fucking, I mean,
I guess it does in some ways,
but not to that extent.
And reality is what Brian was talking
about earlier is that Brian Kallan was
talking about earlier, is that this is
a pretty good time to live. You know,
we can fix it on the negative shit.
This is a pretty good time to live.
And it's 2012,
you know,
this big change that everyone's going
to look back on. You know, like the,
the idea that the Mayans were correct
and the TimeWave zero novelty theory,
you aware of what that is?
No.
Timewave zero novelty theory was a
mathematic algorithm created by Terence
Mckenna, the great silence Psychedelic
Bard and author and botanist. And He, uh,
went on a mushroom trip in the jungle
and came up with this idea based on the
chain,
cause he had studied the teaching and he
came up with this idea that the eating
was
a map of time and then he was going to
construct a mathematic algorithm based on
the each thing that would literally track
progress and human innovation that you
could track it like a wave. That it
was a mathematical program. Wow. Yeah.
That's how high he got. How about that?
Sit around and think about the fucking,
they have original thoughts that are,
so it came and it came to a point
of what he called ultimate novelty,
which means something,
novelty, meaning innovation,
novelty being some new thing that had
not existed before or some new branch of
some new thing.
And that a period of a point of ultimate
Davonte will be achieved December 21st,
2012 now here's what's
fucked up about that.
That is the exact same day to the
day as the end of the Mayan calendar.
So he came up independently on his own
with this crazy mathematical algorithm
that I don't even know if it's real.
It sounds ridiculous,
but if you believe the guy,
he says that he did not know the end of
the Mayan calendar until much later that
he had been working on this
mathematical program for like 30 years,
bringing in mathematicians to work on it.
And apparently there's some debate over
whether or not he had fudged numbers or
I don't. I'm way too dumb when it
comes to math to understand any of it.
But the idea has always fascinated
me of even if it's on a date,
20 December 24 2012 even if it's
not a date, but the idea of it,
the idea that it's inevitable that like
really must have, it's going to happen.
And if you look at how fast
shit has happened to get to
the point we're at today,
and just a few hundred
300400500 years ago,
the way we were living is
just an unrecognizable, the
hard surfaces on the road,
things flying in the sky and the lights.
And now you know his name because he
made up this whole bullshit. You know,
like he knew the Mayan calendar from
the whole time. You know what I mean?
They got it.
You're saying that that either he knew
about it or he didn't know about it? Well,
no, they hadn't even know he
had axe. Lord. He knew about it.
I'm pretty sure he actually
had come up with it.
I'm pretty sure it's been proven that he
had either come up with it before they
had deciphered the Mayan calendar or it
was that he definitely hadn't studied it
and it wasn't mainstream news enough.
There was, it was enough though.
I would give him the benefit of the
doubt and plus the dude was like super
honest. It's like if you listen
to Terence Mckenna lectures,
really fascinating individual, had an
interesting, fascinating things to say,
but brilliant, brilliant guy.
He goes mad, really amazing.
Matthew has killed me,
but he's on a math theorists.
See that's the crazy
thing is that he wasn't,
he just had this crazy idea that came
to him on mushrooms and this is the most
ridiculous aspect of it was he
asked the mushrooms, why me?
Why are you giving this to me? And they
said, because out of the, you know,
thousands of years that
we've been in this field,
no one's ever come up to us who had
the teaching and their head before.
So what it was was to him was he happened
to be in a place where he had studied
some incredibly ancient
Chinese divination system.
It's a real mystery with the, each
thing is because it's a method of like
fortune telling and it seems to
be like incredibly effective,
like statistically numerically effective.
It's really weird.
Like people try to figure out
what it is about the ching,
but it works more than it doesn't work.
And what does that even mean?
I don't know. I don't understand
it, but it's based on hexagrams.
It's based on these patterns and
Mckenna coming into this field,
eating these mushrooms,
tripping, it's fucking balls out,
had this ridiculous idea that what the
each and really was with the Chinese at
some point in history way,
way a long fucking time ago
had figured out a map of time.
Well you know like, like the
guy when it feels metal, right?
When he figured the answer out there
was an equation. The Russian dude. Yeah.
And so, and they don't even know.
So the quote it just the equation,
just the question was already
theoretical right there. All right.
The question is what if
it may not be a question?
Let's just say it as a question where
Matt and mathematicians had been
contemplating the answer
for the past 200 years.
They got comes up the answer
and the answer I think was,
I think it was like 357 pages long.
But the funny thing about that is
that at the end of the 350 pages,
all the great mathematicians went,
fucking guy. He got it. He fucking,
ah,
I miss that Dan.
And he like think about your mindset that
you were able to read the answer that
but 357 pages long ago. Ah
Fuck. And then as a group,
the group of great mathematicians that
award the metal go mother fucker for one
person. That is an incredible
achievement. Right. But the answer is it,
but also the fact that you can prove
mathematically that the answer has right.
That's pretty cool. That's
pretty cool. Right? I mean,
whether you want to be real clear that
I'm not supporting this Mckenna Theory
[inaudible] I am absolutely not,
but much money did door am I 12 he's dead
bro. Like how much do you think? Oh no,
eight off of that. Well, one of the
things, you can look at it that way,
but I think he made a lot more money
off of lectures on psychedelics than he
ever did on this time wave zero thing.
When you look at the fact that the
guy worked on it for over 30 years,
it seems to be some weird labor
of love and obsession that he had.
I don't know if it's correct.
I don't know if it makes any sense at all.
I don't know if it's total horseshit.
I just think it's fascinating that a
person would spend so much time making a
correlation between the
each thing and a 13 cycle,
28 day lunar calendar,
that it is a,
apparently it's like more accurate than
the calendar that we employ today and
that you could use the,
each ching as a calendar and the,
each thing was somehow or another,
some map of waves and that the,
that novelty and, and positive
things, it comes in it. The never,
it's never a steady rise to the top
you're
bringing up is that the fact of the
matter is with, with technology,
and we talked about this before,
we're probably going to live.
If you live long enough
for the next 30 years,
we're probably going to live through
things that are going to take our entire
paradigm of reality and what we see as
reality and certainly the world we live
in and, and, and destroy the entire,
the boundaries dissolve the boundaries.
I mean we'll have to reinvent what,
um,
I think that questions of being
a human being will always remain.
I think there are questions that
we ask ourselves as human beings.
What is fulfillment? Or who am I, what am
I doing here? It doesn't questions that,
those are questions that you can't,
that's a responsibility
you can't run away from.
It's why I love like Seneca and reading
those guys cause you read those fuckers
and that these dudes were
sat around thinking 25,
3,500 years ago and they came
up with questions that we,
you still have to answer it. And most of
us, most of it, when you read that Shit,
you, you go, you go, you use
what happens to you as you go,
oh I'm living in a fucking,
I'm living in a glass house or a box of
cards. Like most of my belief system,
most of how I live my life, a lot of
times, you know, when you read it you go,
there's not a lot of scaffolding for
that. There's not a lot of, you know,
there's not a lot of like I can't really
justify it along true moral or truthful
terms. And that's what
Socrates in Seneca would do.
He would just ask you questions like
that. It's really interesting. You know,
you Kinda, you Kinda, that's why reading
the dialogues is such a mind fuck.
Cause all it is is just a
series of questions and you go,
fuck well I believe this and they have
some standing and now you're asking me a
question I don't really
have the answer to.
I was listening to this talk about the
library of Alexandria and how it was
burned down.
Not once but twice,
once by a followers of the
Qur'an. And they, they, you know,
they apparently they looked at it.
Yeah.
The Muslim said that apparently
they looked at it and
said to anything here that
disputes the Qur'an is heredic anything
that supports the Qur'an is unnecessary.
Burn the whole fucking thing down.
It's like a million volumes.
And it was essentially the same people
that built the God damn fucking pyramids,
you know? I mean what kind of
information was lost? I mean, how,
like when you talk about the each thing,
if Macquarie forget about whether or
not it's really a map of time and I make
but what it, what is it? It
is really obviously something
incredibly complicated,
you know, and that there's this
series of hexagrams and the,
there's obviously something to it.
It's not a random thing.
There's something studied about it.
How the Irish saved civilization. Have
you heard of it? No. By Kaplan is, um,
the camera thing. His name is
Kevin. He's great, great historian.
I've read a couple of his books and uh,
the when, during the dark ages, after,
when when Alexandra was burned down and,
and a lot of during the crusades,
the Christian Crusades and also
during, during the, um, the,
when the Ottoman Empire came
in and took over and things,
a lot of this knowledge was lost.
But the people that actually were the
only people that could write back then in
Europe were primarily the Irish scribe,
the Irish clergy,
the priests, and they would
write down, they would date,
they copied these books.
They wrote painstakingly capitalized
books and carry them around with them.
And carry them in their
oral traditions as well.
And so a lot of that information like uh,
like the Greeks and all the things that
we base our political system on was
carried through.
At least the thesis of this book was,
was carried through by these,
by these Irish scribes by this hour,
by the Irish clergy who during the dark
ages kept the tradition of alive in
books
and kept their own libraries hidden.
This is an amazing,
when you look back at like really,
really ancient academics like you know
when when people would go to Egypt,
a lot of the Greeks would
travel to Egypt to study.
You know that there was at one point in
time there was obviously some gigantic
pool of information. There was a, I'm a,
I'm a much more advanced aside and
then we give credit to I theirs,
that's for sure. That's amazing isn't
it? Some asshole burned it all down.
They lost everything. But then,
but then you don't lose everything.
But then as you get older but it's like
it's probably more advanced today. Right.
And you assume a yes in many ways
because we are privy to more information
because we are becoming,
you know, it's like, um, I,
I would liken it to how how martial
arts has changed exponentially because
everybody is sharing of
information with you.
You can agree with you 100%
until we started talking
about the pyramids and then
I just go, we'll explain that.
How the hell did they do that?
That's amazing to at least 2,500 BC,
maybe even early. Insane. That,
that's a good point too. I mean,
it's the most amazing
physical accomplishment that
human beings have ever done.
Forget about.
Not In the industrial age.
I also think like if you look at Saint
Peter's Cathedral, you've ever been there?
Have you ever seen that? No. And
photos, but it is incredible.
It's beyond what you can imagine.
And even as young boys to go there,
because my uncle lived in Rome and I would
go and I'd look and I'd spent all the
time there because that
would never be that.
Would nobody would ever do that today. And
the reason nobody, that's not true, man.
Did you hear about that guy
that got arrested in Italy
because they thought that
he was building some sort of a
military thing and they were gonna,
they were gonna storm his house
with guns until he let them in.
He had a modest home in the countryside
and then inside his house was a giant
fucking construction that went
into the hills and the mountains.
It was a beautiful cathedral,
incredible artwork.
I mean this place was massive
and stunning and stunning.
And it was him and just a few friends
and they somehow or another been working
on this for 20, 30 years. Everybody was
like, what is this crazy ass hole doing?
Digging a hole,
dude,
you have to look at it because
it is art for the sake of art.
He didn't want anyone to know about
it. He did. And it's beautiful.
He has rooms that are like Egyptian
rooms where like hieroglyphs sarcophagus.
It's online just to look
up, um, uh, Italian, uh,
Home Mountain,
uh,
look up or what would you call it? Art
Work. What would would you call it?
A Cathedral temple. Temple.
Italian home temple. Well,
what I mean is that the craft of
stone making and, and when, when one,
when when they take a tap street and two
generations of artists would work on it.
So you one generation to
work on it for his lifetime,
then die in the next generation.
The next day his apprentice would come
and finish it and all those things.
When you look at Saint Peter's Cathedral,
that was so,
that was a group of people
that are so divinely inspired.
The notion that they were just making
what you said art for Art's sake as an
Omar, come over here and
look at this real quick.
Come over and look at this real quick. Put
this down. Look up folks. Look up eggs.
Eighth
wonder of the world on the
Wii u k or the mail online.
Stunning tempo. See really carved out
below ground by paranormal. Eccentric.
Look at these fucking photos, man. I mean,
you can't even wrap your head
around this shit. This is uh, this,
this guy made this in,
in a countryside.
It's insane. I mean, this guy built
all this shit in the countryside, man.
Look at this. Look at a ceiling. Wow. No,
it's incredible. It's you would say that,
but he did it today. This is recent.
Look at this. I mean this is incredible
shit. Look at the floor on this place.
Look at the artwork on the pillar.
I mean it is some of the most stunning
shit and I don't like that stuff.
Like I was over these people's house.
They were there. Very nice folks,
but they have this ridiculous mural like
a painted mural on the wall and it's
like bad art and it looks
so like a boat and shit.
Fucking asshole fishermen and you're
like, what are you doing? Is there a wall?
There's the restaurant by my house and
just hired their daughter. I'm sorry.
One more. Take a look
at this. I want to show,
this is the hallway that leads into it.
Who did that?
They carved that into the mountain.
The carved out in the mountain. Yeah.
It's an amazing folks that you've got
to folks that are just listening to the
artwork on the wall is spectacular.
The floor,
the marble and the floor is
just immaculate. It's amazing.
And look at this is the outside of
the house. Yup. Just a regular house.
Just a weird regular house.
That's cool. Yep. And they were,
they were moving so much dirt out
of there that everybody was like,
and they did it for a
long ass fucking time.
That's what makes the world a better
place. They occupy 300,000 cubic feet.
That's an act of faith. You know that,
that's an active thing of this big Ben.
The clock is 15,000 cubic
feet under this guy's house.
He had 300,000 cubic feet.
Think of how big this fucking thing
is that this guy built inside the
countryside underneath his house.
That's incredible. It's amazing.
57 year old former insurance broker
from northern Italy who inspired by a
childhood vision began
digging into the rock.
It all began the 60s when
he was 10. God Damn. Yeah.
There's some mother fuckers out,
dude. I mean, why isn't this a movie?
[inaudible] went blind from painting
the Sistine Chapel. Oh yeah. By the way,
I credit, uh, I credited Leonardo
Davinci without the other day.
We were super high. Me and
Everlast we're talking. So folks,
folks corrected me on Twitter. Thank
you very much. I appreciate it.
For some reason when I get high,
I forget that Leonardo Davinci and uh,
bank that they were their contemporaries
though. Yes, they were. But I forgot that,
you know, I forgot that the Michelangelo
was a different guy. Yes. You know,
leader out at Vinci and Michelangelo,
my stupid head or like one personnel.
In fact, if you read the agony and
the access saved by Irving stone,
but just short kind of skinny with a
pug nose and that Da Vinci was a stud,
he's a stud beginning and Davinci did.
Davinci was the one who was the real a
inventor to Michelangelo was a Badass
artists. But Davinci was a convent
and fucking space planes and shit.
That's right. Yeah. What a,
what a freak show. That guy
fucking chaplain went blind.
He couldn't stop when the greatest thing,
the greatest fucking, the greatest line
for a Michelangelo when he, when he,
and to define what you are as a person
and art was when he looked at the fucking,
uh,
at this huge piece of marble and he's
about to carve the statue of David and his
girlfriend at the time is one
love said to him, what, uh,
how are you going to do this? And
he said, it's already in there.
I just have to get all
the stuff out of the way.
And it was a great metaphor
for art or a human being.
Like you start a piece of shit and as
you can delete enough stuff you, you can,
you know, just through hard
work and carving and stuff,
you can become a better person.
It's so important that people do things
and that you do things and other people
enjoy. Correct. Action
is huge. Whatever it is,
whether you're a fucking a
Datsun repairmen and you're like,
oh Frankie and failure is,
is more important than success
to become a better person. It's,
you asked to look at fighters but,
but what I'm saying is that like
doing something that people enjoy,
it really is like the fucking key to
happiness in life is like doing something
that makes other people happy in some way.
It really is the key to happiness in life.
And it's one that so few
people ever figured out.
And that's one of the reasons why people
were so fucked up is because so many
people have this selfish,
it's all about me attitude.
And you don't understand that you
will never be happy. Not only that,
you will be prosperous,
either you won't be because you are a
part of a gigantic system and you are in a
symbiotic relationship with every human
being that you come in contact with.
So when you fuck them over,
you fuck up your whole system.
You spread out negative energy,
you put out bad ripples and it comes back.
It's impossible not to see it with fight.
Or sometimes you see fighters start come
in with like a lot of guys who are real
angry and there and they come from broken
homes and they're just fucking sour
guys.
But they learn and they learn and to get
better they have to confront that anger
and they have to learn to control it.
And a lot of times by
the time they're done,
they come out of it really well adjusted
just men in some ways. The best guys,
the best of the best are martial
artists. You know, Anderson Silva,
he's a martial artist.
He's a martial artist.
Would you say is in the George
Saint Pierre is and martial artists,
no doubt about it.
He is 100% martial artists.
And the way he behaves around people,
the way he conducts himself,
he conducts himself as an exemplary
member of society who can fuck you up.
That's what he does is you never get the
feeling hanging out with chores that he
can kick your ass. You never get the
feeling. Of course he can, you know,
he can the cycle, you know,
psychologically, realistically,
you know you can kick your ass but you
never feel that around him because he's
always so humble and so
friendly and so nice.
Where we were talking about that though,
you know,
some people have a lot of trouble
managing success and a huge,
it's a character issue. It's whether or
not you accept bullshit lies or you know,
whether or not you look
at yourself realistically,
it doesn't get better and stay on top.
You've got to confront that
in your store thing all day,
every day and you have to
have a completely open mind.
That's why a lot of fighters choke or
they freeze up and stuff and it's just
human. You know, you've got to be able
to assess your objective, your, your,
your objective strengths and weaknesses
at a moment's notice and you've gotta be
able to do it completely accurately.
You can be burdened down by some ego
that has you convinced that you're right
and you're doing it
together and avoid all the,
you also have to be doing it to
some extent to to check in in.
It's, it's a fine line because you don't
want to do things for other people.
You're doing it to surprise yourself,
but your motivation has to be pure
because if your motivation is not,
you will pay a price for it. You Do,
you do it for art, man. You know,
when I don't, this is how I
approach everything. I write.
Okay. I, you know, I say,
well, you know, I really got
to get together and fucking
do some writing today.
I'm don't be lazy bitch.
And then I sit down and I started
writing and I never say, okay,
here I'm going to write things for
people. I'm going to, I, I got to,
whatever it is, I got to conjure it
up. I got to let that bitch trying to,
I'm trying to be funny. I just try to
write what I think is interesting. Well,
that's one of the reasons why I enjoyed,
uh,
writing blogs before I started
writing my book. I started,
I was writing a lot of blogs and there's
still all up@joerogan.net somewhere you
could find them. We need to make
that shit easy to find. Um, it's uh,
yeah cause the blogs and the videos
were all together in the same pile
because you have blogs,
you have it as a blog or most people
don't even know what a tag is. Dude,
most people just want something
real clean, clean can click on,
here's the shit you wrote. Click.
Well, I'll get that done eventually.
But my point is that I would never write
anything on purpose. Trying to be funny.
I would just sit down and just
look, man, the world is funny.
This is just stupid shit that's
going on all day, every day.
If you can't see some funny in the world.
But it's also the, that's some funny,
especially when you're writing blogs,
it's all always balanced out
with the shit that's not funny.
That makes the funny stuff
even funnier. It's like, it's,
it's got to be whatever the
fuck is coming out of there.
And then I just extract the jokes from
that. The stuff that's actually funny,
I extract it from that.
The ironic point we've always looked at
your comedy is to me has always been, um,
you know, I've always been, I've
always been more absurd, but you,
you look at the truth of situation
and then you just fucking, you just,
you carve it out and shine a light on it.
I try to put a lot of observed and there
as well because I found out along the
way that first of all not being
observed can be a trap. You know,
people take it seriously. I don't want
you to take me seriously, man. I don't,
I just, I don't have time for that. Okay.
So please don't, you know, but that,
that becomes a trap and I've
seen some comics fall into it,
especially when they develop a following.
You know, they have a, this, a,
this group of people that want to follow
in the way of what we're talking about.
Don't fucking listen to your following
to passion because you start getting,
you start believing the hype. You get
older and people like I go on, but yes,
but appreciate it. But as a
responsibility, it's a resource.
It's a responsibility that your
friends out there, you know,
you just got to respect it.
Just don't let it,
don't let it find you because then you
will start trying to be a certain way.
They just think it's all about when
it happens to you that you develop a
following anyway mean develop,
develop a following.
When you're 17 years old and you're on
a Disney sitcoms and you don't really
understand yourself or do you
develop yourself when you're,
when you're 30 and then you,
because back to
Mark's example, back in the day when your
teacher would taught you martial arts,
you've got a karate teacher.
He was the master.
He would never fight
sparring bands or wherever.
He's two deadly to spar with those.
The Brazilians are like the blue man.
Like they, they're your teacher. They
fucking rolled with every fucking day.
That's the difference between real
fighters and guys who are, well no,
the real issue is striking versus
a Jujitsu. It was, you know,
because he can't do that every day with
striking. It's just too difficult. I mean,
if you, if you have a great group of
people where you guarantee, you know,
like any man, let's
just go light, you know,
and you really do not try to
kill each other. That's awesome.
But that's not normal.
Normal is like the gentleman that
we were talking about earlier today,
the very successful gentleman, and
we won't, won't mention his name,
who does know how to spar. He just
tries to kill guys in the gym. You know,
they tell him, listen to man, you're not
gonna get any fucking sparring partners.
You're too crazy. You know? And that's,
that's a god that's he's missing the
whole point. That's exactly right.
And you know, you missed the
whole camaraderie of being
a teammate with someone,
part of it as he, you, you know, you build
each other up, you know, you, you, you,
you could hit your teammate,
but you don't,
that's one of the things that is
like an extension of those guys.
They'd all those teams, those teams,
they're, they're just, they become close,
super close because they're bleeding
and fucking dying together, you know?
Exactly. And they can trust each
other when they're sparring.
It's really important, man. You
know, even though you spar hard,
it's nothing mean dudes are
getting hit no doubt about, look,
you don't get as good at boxing as Nate
Diaz does unless you got a guy like
Gilbert Melendez and your camp.
You know what I'm saying?
Like these guys are going at each other
all the time and they're doing it the
right way and they're both get good as
fuck. And same thing with Nick, you know,
you know, he's so God damn good.
And you know what Nick is doing?
He's constantly boxing with Andre Ward.
He boxes what Andre Ward is a Olympic gold
medalist. Hell of a box. It brilliant,
brilliant boxer.
I mean that guy never gets hurt.
So he boxes and Nick Diaz is
professional boxing level.
He could, yes. First of
all, he's a super athlete.
He can put a pace on those dudes
and they can't handle. He's for me,
he's my favorite fighter. He's a super
endurance athlete. And you look at him,
he's obviously in great shape.
I mean it's not, it's not that.
But what you don't understand is his
cardio is like double with a normal humans
is like literally double. Yeah. And
because he has that man that's a weapon,
he can use that weapon cause most times
aren't willing to work that hard to
trial. He does triathlons
all the time, man.
He'd fucking swam back
from Alcatraz twice price
and the fucking in the
shark infested water.
I mean the reason why they put Alcatraz,
there they go, we'll put a prison.
Who the fuck's gonna swim that they
thought it couldn't be done and this crazy
assholes. A cage fighter because
done it twice just for the fuck of n.
That's not even when he does.
He's not like an ultra endurance swimmer
in the ocean. No, he's a cage fighter.
But his mind is so strong because of that,
because he has so much fucking endurance.
He can just take his name if he goes,
let me tell you something.
If every round was like a 20 minute round,
you could never beat Nick Diaz.
You can never beat him because after 15
minutes you'd be huffing and puffing.
You'd be waiting for that stool
and he'd be like, what? Bitch?
And we still pop pop pop in with
those 50% punches in the face.
Does he talk to Funky? Does
you know why? Cause he's smart.
Cause that's a psychological
war that's going on right there.
And if you can get a guy flustered and
call him a bitch and get up in his face
and get him thinking about your emotions,
that's the intelligent thing to do.
If you want to teligent fighter,
you would add that.
I know it's beautiful to be a George
Saint Pierre and to, you know,
to bow at a martial artist and didn't,
it's never be talking shit
in the middle of a fight.
Do a completely respectfully and he gets
it done masterfully. But in my opinion,
I like watching the garlic. Nick Diaz get
in there and go live bitch, bitch, bitch,
bitch.
Moving his head.
He's half forest moon is Henna moving
his move his head back and forth talking
mad shit to truly hate the guys he fight
doesn't until he fights him and then
he's cool with them. You know, he yells
after he knocked out frank shamrock,
he'd get it. He goes, come on and get
up. You're a legend. And he helped him,
helped him. I picked him up by
his here in Lafayette. Same thing.
Neda's brother Nate. After he beat up
Serone this weekend, he said, you know,
listen man, it's all good. You
know, it's just hype and bullshit.
And they hugged and it was cool, you know,
and Serone gave it up to him, period.
He was a better fighter.
That's it.
No excuses was he kicked my ass and they
just let it go. It's beautiful. You know,
I liked that.
I like when dudes can let it go,
but it's a smart thing
to get guys upset at you.
Smart thing it seems Nate
and nick don't give a fuck.
I don't give her dare to kick your
ass and it's, it's really sad.
I don't want to talk to
you to kick your ass,
but they're punching I then it sees,
it's brilliant. They're punching.
It looks like he's moving in slow motion.
I was watching it the first time
I watched and punch. I was like,
there's a little bit,
he's, it's so emotional.
Looks like he's not trying to hurt you.
He's like, dad did that. It did. Oh,
you know why?
Because don't throw your punches at a
hundred percent throw your punches at 50%
land.
82% of them,
they still hurt and he wasn't even
throwing them at 80% I mean, I would say,
I would say baby,
like he went through a lot of punches
that were around 50% of his full power.
What he could really, if he really wanted
to haul off and blast you in the face,
he can knock people the fuck out.
But him and his brother had figured
out this really effective style of like
volume,
technical topic.
That's a real good question. And I
would be out of school if I said that,
but I don't think so. They
have a boxing coach. It was a,
a Mexican gentleman that's in
the ring with him all the time.
I should credit him because I need to
find me. It makes me want to go, uh,
become uh, like a, I'll never, it's over
for me. But you just see those guys.
They make it look so easy there.
Their submission game,
they're fucking punching
kids. They're so fun, man.
Nick Diaz is just, I love it. Sorry.
Sorry. Richard Perez. Richard Perez.
I should've known.
He's one of those guys that I,
his name was at the tip of my tongue,
but they'd been with him for a long time.
He said every one of their fights and
he's there boxing coach and he always,
you know, they always credit Richard
Perez afterwards and you know what?
He's gotten them so slick.
Their head movement, their
counters. There are angles,
man. Dude, two fights. I
mean, how much, how many,
how many they practice boxing every day.
I mean, oh yeah, they're boxing a lot.
I mean, they're very boxing centered in
why not be, because look, first of all,
everyone knows that Jujitsu's nasty.
So you don't really to take them down
necessarily and wind up in their guard.
Nate Diaz fucks guys up from his guard
and so does NEC. They both catch guys.
So we're going to do,
you know,
you have to stand up with them and
if you want to stand up with them,
they're both along. And they both were
all these volume punches and I was tap,
tap, tap, tap, tap. But that pap pap,
and they're so fucking accurate, man.
So what had broke the Compu strike record.
Nate Diaz. Dad Serone fight happens.
I think it was 82%. I believe
it was nuts, man. That's nuts.
[inaudible] I've never seen anything
like it. He boxed him up, man. He was,
his boxing was brilliant.
And then in the last two fights and
attacking Nori Gomi fight in this fight,
he just turned this crazy corner.
And I think it came out of the
loss to what Roy Mcdonald's,
that Roy McDonald kid is a
fucking beast. You know that, uh,
the young man from Canadian Canada, you
know who he is, Roy McDonald, he's uh,
he's only had a, a few UFC fights. He,
he had a real close fight with Carlos
condit and he got stopped in the third
round, but he was winning
the first two rounds and uh,
it really quick demolition of Mike Pile.
I was like really blown away by that.
I expected Mike Pile.
It's going to be very difficult for him.
I mean he caught them early and you know,
you catch anybody really is, no, he's a,
he's a full on MMA fighter but,
and he's a young kid.
He's been training him and may only for
his whole life from the beginning to end.
Well, Nate had a fight with them
and then Nate lost a decision.
It didn't get hurt. He never got beat
up. He got thrown around a little bit.
The guy took him down a few times, like
soup plucks them and stuff. But you know,
one of the things about the Diaz brothers
is there amazing defense. You know,
they're,
they're always,
they're so used to fighting against brutal
guys and training that they're really
good at surviving,
you know,
and so he realized that he
probably should be at 155 pounds.
It was like a better way because he was
fighting one 70 and he build up to get
there. He didn't go up to like one 85 one
90 and then cut his weight down. He was,
you know, he was essentially,
you know, weighing in like much,
much closer to the 55 pound women, but
the last two fights, yet at lightweight,
it was tacking or go me and this last
one against the, and both of them,
it was just tense. Wrong is no joke,
man. No, he's a beast. You know,
I think what happened was I think,
you know,
naked pissed off at himself after that,
uh,
that fight with Rory Mcdonald and
he said, you know what? Fuck it.
I'm kicking it up a notch and decided,
you know,
one 55 was where I was supposed to be.
And they're just really get to,
it gave him the finger like that, that
now it's beautiful. It's beautiful, man.
It's, this is war man. It's
psychological war. You know,
like Larry Bird used to show up at
every three point contest and go,
who's coming in second?
That's it. You know,
you gotta think about Larry Bird when
you're fucking shooting that shot now
because you can't be in the zone because
no one, no one's fucked with you.
And you could have your
own positive thoughts. No,
you got Larry Bird's freckly little
white ass cracker phase going,
who's coming inside?
You know?
And you know what I said to me when I
saw him give him the finger, I went,
that guy's not tired. He's not
tired, he doesn't get tired.
He's just like his brother.
They go on, you know,
they do some fucking
extreme endurance work, man.
And they keep their conditioning and a
really high level. And if you do that,
you can put a face on it, dude, they
can't fuck with. And then on top of that,
if you have really good striking,
you know, then it's like, man,
you're getting striking. Like that
is so difficult. That takes balls.
You have to have balls,
you have to go in there with
guys who can take your fucking
face. Yeah. And you get here hit
and hurt. You gotta learn defense.
You got to learn how to roll with punches.
You gotta you gotta learn who not to spar
with or some dudes that it's not worth
it. Some days you could spar him every
now and then like especially if you're
feeling fresh or something like that.
Do you think they keep a guy out box
with just strict boxes like Andre Ward?
Do you start to try to fight
him just to Zach's or MMA guys?
A lot of different though.
A lot of guys,
especially in the early days of him and
may like I've had long conversations
with dude about this dude's about
this who started out in like the early
nineties they didn't know any better
and they would just go full blast in the
gym all the time.
And then somewhere along the line
people start telling them like, hey man,
you shouldn't do this.
Like you guys should be sparring with
technique and this is how you do that and
this is how you save yourself for the,
yeah,
because nobody is ever using the
jab back then or anything like that.
Everybody was like, Hey, maker
central and then you get in there.
That's one of the reasons why a
guy like Anderson shines. You know,
you get in there with a guy like Anderson,
like Chris Liebing just charged at him.
Just went to try to maul him, which was,
you know, if you're going
to give him a good strategy,
which is a good strategy
to stay on the outside of,
let them pick you apart or chase
that motherfucker down. I would,
I would have told Chris
to do the same thing.
He just wasn't ready for that level yet
in that technical level that Anderson's
achieved, you know, he has
all the techniques. He doesn't
have just haymakers he's,
he came from a technical Moyie
Thai background, you know,
so his technique is beautiful.
I was watching a tagline office down
in American top team trained with them,
right? Yeah. Train with that.
It was best friend I guess.
And coach Muay Thai coach
who's a stud himself,
just like this real good looking dude.
He's like, and I got, I was, I was so,
it was so exciting cause Tiago was,
is a big death valley fan.
So he came up to me, it's like this is a
show that you're on for people. That is,
I do the, I'm a huge fan.
You May, you crack me up.
It's so funny and terrible accident.
Not at all.
But he's so funny and we had such a
laugh when he took me around and we had a
blast but he gave me a private
Moy Tai class and then,
and then he rolled with me and Jujitsu
and if you ever want to feel like a hen,
a wolf, that's, that's, it was
ridiculous. He's so strong.
He kicked the bag at one point
just lightly. I was holding it.
He was showing me around
house like a low kick it,
the power is retarded with that guy.
You know,
the beautiful thing about him is
when he throws things, he does it.
Everything is like tight and Tucker,
he's a,
he's got some of the best defense
as far as like MMA strikers.
He's got some of the best deal I can
tell and I spent enough time with him.
He's fucking smart guys doing everything.
Very technical.
He's very smart.
He's matured a lot.
He's 28 now and he was
just very open about what,
what a what a crazy fucker
he was when he was younger,
spending money going crazy and you see
his last fight against puppy a baby. No,
I tore the guy who was beautiful
because this guy's a monster man.
This patio Betty looks like the
last guy you'd ever want to fight.
You look at him,
he's just ridiculously shredded.
He's a judo black belt who can strike.
He's like a of very similar
to a shirker. No, no, no.
The Beltour Hector Lombard, very
similar to that. Bella toward champion.
Hector Lombard. Really similar.
Just build and ridiculous power
punches really fast and Tiago
just stayed in the pocket.
Managers caught him with a little shot
at the little shot leg kicks and the dude
was swinging it. Tiago man,
the dude was a scary guy,
but it was a beautiful display
of technique and patients
and being a veteran and
overcoming, I have be everybody
fights in the UFC, man,
that's a lot of fights and
that pappy a betting guy,
I feel like he could beat anybody.
I feel like if he just,
if you fuck up and let that
guy punched you in the face,
like if somehow or another you zig when
he should have zagged and you get caught,
which happens to guys. Well you saw
the John Fitch fight this weekend.
He got knocked out, knocked
out with one punch. Well,
you know there's a followup punch,
but essentially the one punch was
the one that really did it. Yeah.
Johnny Hendricks caught him and
he tried to come back from it.
You know we tried to, well with
those, with those little gloves,
your margin for error really
slims down and that's where,
that's where learning technique and if
you look at boxers when they teach you
you're, you're spending more time
avoiding them, throwing punches.
Anybody can throw hands but,
but moving out of the way and then,
and then hitting or just being able to
slip punches that tells us there's a lack
of like real high level technical boxing.
A lot of a lot of areas takes forever.
It takes forever and it's really
hard to learn everything. You know,
it's one of the reasons why a lot of
people think you should be awesome at one
thing before you ever got into MMA.
Cause you know,
it's like the Rory Mcdonald's of the
world are very rare and this is this young
kid who's starting out and he's
got great wrestling, is wrestling,
is outstanding kickboxing as
nasty as Jujitsu, solid as fuck.
He's really got no weaknesses.
But you know, he's,
he's one of those 22 year old
kids that can actually do that.
This came up with it from the, from the
get go, you know, for the most part,
most guys they came up with
one discipline or another.
And the best thing that could hope for
was to be really good at something.
But they're really good at wrestling.
So they'd take God down are
really good at striking.
You just learn how to sprawl.
Like Mirko Cro, cop, you know,
he never really became
anything other than a striker.
He has a couple of submission victories,
but they're mostly after he except the
random and fight mostly after he was
fucking a guy up the, uh, the question is,
can anybody beat John Bones Jones
and does he go to heavyweight? Sure.
Anybody can.
You know what?
Nobody ever expected the Jon Bones
Jones was ever going to exist. You know,
before he existed,
nobody would have suspected that some
brilliant young kid could come in here who
was a, an excellent amateur
wrestler with, you know,
a few years of karate and taekwondo
or something under his belt.
And maybe not even a few
years, I should say, like, you
know, months of it. But just,
you know,
practice some kicks and knew how to do
them and then you get him with some ace
trainers like Mike Winkeljohn and Greg
Jackson and they mold this kid into some
fucking prodigy.
I would,
I would've never said that could have
happened before that some kid could have
been in the game only like three years
and just dominate guys like shogun
dominate cause like Machida Yoel he
put machine at asleep with a standing
guillotine.
When's the last time anybody put on high
level champion to sleep with a standing
gate and then dropped him
like it was mortal Kombat.
Like he just beheaded him and shit. It was
like, Hey g, it's ridiculous. So he's a,
he's, you know what he is man. He is the
king of the new school. That's what he is.
Jon Jones is the king of the new school.
There's no one who can fuck with him.
You guys, there's a level,
there's a high level,
there's a higher level than has ever
existed before in Jon Jones is at the peak
of that junior dos Santos.
But there's another way of coming and
another way of coming as those Roy
McDonald dudes,
you know,
Jon Jones started out as a wrestler and
learned all that striking and slowly
become better at striking.
Rory Macdonald is great at everything.
He's great at everything. It's his fucking
head movement is nasty. It's striking,
it's clean, it's technique is
perfect. He got knockout power.
It's fucking 22 years old and he's
smart and he's a little savage.
Those guys are coming up and there's,
there's a 14 year old right now
that will probably fuck him up.
And that the guy that was hitting pads
in Vegas right now ever see those two
little kids, the little Mohawk kids
do. Those cool kids can do everything.
They're like little treats.
I don't know how they all now,
but they're super dedicated.
They love the sport, you know,
and they get a lot of attention. So they
do it a lot in their parents. Love it.
And come on man. That those kind
of guys, that's the next wave.
So as crazy as hoists,
Gracie was in 1993 John Jones is in 2012
and as crazy as Alistair Overeem is in
2012 you're going to have some new dude
that's going to be 10 years from now or
whatever and he's going to have some mad
distance between them because there'll
be a,
there'll be a sport as itself,
cause right now it's a sport
that's piecemealed from a
bunch of other different
sports, right. With no
clear formula. That's right.
Eventually they're going to
get a pretty clear for them.
Yet eventually there's going to be,
there's going to be, it seems MMA as a,
as its own fighting system is going to,
it's going to solidify most likely,
most likely boxing like,
yeah.
But part of the fun is the
ebb and flow in the battle.
Walt's happening all of a sudden,
karate is what everybody needs to know.
Nobody could touch Machinga oh shit.
Who would've ever thought it was karate
after all these years if you just have
the sprawling than it's karate.
And then you know a guy like
Jon Jones comes around and
I was like, oh no, no, no.
It's length. It's distance and
intelligence in a wrestling background.
That's what's important.
And the willingness to believe in
yourself and just throw wild shit.
And the fact that nobody can hit you
because you're a mile away from them,
you connect on them.
What about,
what about him and junior desantis
will they fight? Maybe eventually.
I think Jon Jones was somewhat someday
be a heavyweight cause he's so young.
I think he's only 2,400 see what
weight does he walk around that?
That's a good question.
You know, I should ask him.
I think he's above two 15 to 20 I think
he gets pretty heavy and then he drops
the weight, you know, and eats healthy.
And I think he's got a big family and
I think it's, he's got big, you know,
I was young kid, he's going to fill
out, I think one professionally.
I think you'd be amazing as a
heavyweight too. He's big enough.
He's just got to skinny legs. Yeah. And
those could get bigger. And by the way,
he'd be even more ridiculous than could
you imagine if all of sudden you had
super legs underneath them.
We did all fucking squats and dead lifts
and just triangle the fuck out of my
gym. Imagine that evolves in
these triangling people. I mean,
he can do anything that's,
he's a guy you shouldn't,
I believe he's six, four, I believe.
Six, four really tall. He's really tall.
But his reach is what's ridiculous.
Yeah. But we'll pull that up, Brian.
Find out how tall John Jones, and by the
way, what is Anderson Silva Tall? Is He,
I think he's six too. That'd be great to
see that fight. Yeah. But you know, the,
the issue is a wrestling issue,
you know, I mean, he's, um,
Anderson Anderson is like, he's
an amazing, amazing fighter.
But when you're taking on a guy who was
physically much bigger than you, right.
He's Anderson is, well,
we ask him how tall he is.
Six foot four. Yeah.
He's got a six foot four,
but he has a reach that's bigger
than some seven foot tall people.
He's got a crazy reach. Yeah. I mean,
I just said that and that's real.
His reach is the longest
of anyone in the UFC,
including semi shelt who
used to fight for the UFC.
So his ability to touch you with his
hands is like right up there with Stephan
struve. Stephan skyscrapers. Struve has a,
I believe he has a shorter
wingspan than Jon Jones does.
So he's just got, he's got everything
going for him. He's got intelligence,
he's got confidence,
he's, he's got the, uh,
the courage to get in there and fucking
throw down against the best fighters in
the world even though he's only been
doing it for three years and he's got the
athleticism to pull it off and he listens
to everything. And then you're like,
you listen to like interviews with them
to do it is on youtube all the time.
Like watching wrestling
matches and learning moves
and putting them in his head.
He's a fucking, he's loving that. He's
the baddest mother. Tell me that, that,
that Anderson's,
I said what's interesting like,
and he said he's a martial arts nerd.
He loves martial arts.
He like watch his stuff.
Old Guys.
But you don't get as good as Anderson
unless you're completely obsessed with it.
You know, there's the story of
Anderson's fight with Tony Fryklund.
Did you know that story?
Yeah.
Anderson fought Tony fricken and he had
this crazy upward elbow that he wanted
to try like some shitty song and on Bach
moving and uh, his coaches were like,
we get the fuck out of
here with his elbow.
Like he kept practicing this really nutty
elbow that like would never come up.
It was like a Kung Fu move,
you know, it was like, I,
it was like some stuff that you saw in
a movie that you would never see in an
MMA fight where, you know, it's
much more dangerous. But, um,
he made his wife hold the Pellot forum
and he would practice this upward elbow.
They made his wife like hold pads and he
would practice this shit over and over
again.
He had to do it away from his coaches.
And so then he was like in in the the
actual cage and he like told his fucking
coach,
I'm going to do that upward elbow,
the league who shut the fuck up and get
out of here with this crazy upward elbow.
And Bob Blam, he catches Frickin with
this upward elbow and puts them to sleep.
Not just put them asleep but stiff
armed them who went down like stiff leg,
stiff on nothing,
was working and he blessed them with an
elbow and then Anderson just walks away
like he's a Ninja.
It was the most ridiculous shit ever.
But that's what it is.
He like,
he learned a technique that
was outside of his discipline.
He's just such a bad motherfucker.
What he's got is just like John Jones,
he's very intelligent and
his timing is amazing.
And his confidence and intelligence,
timing, confidence and character.
And with Anderson to Anderson is
a guy who's been proven. I mean,
Jon Jones has never been in a fight where
he got dominated for four rounds and
then pull it off in the fifth you know,
there's,
there's something invaluable about
what Anderson has accomplished.
And the Wood Anderson showed them that
shell son and fight was that he's not
just the hammer, that, you know, he can,
he can take it, dude, you can't break him.
And if you slip, yeah, he's looking for,
he's looking for a way to win, man.
And if you slip, he's going to find it.
Guess what? Yeah. It's only unmet need
to go, but look at this. What's, this?
Could not believe that bitch.
Yeah.
I mean he just did what he had to do and
one came in, they're injured, you know?
Oh, is that what it was? Oh yeah, he
edited it. He had a rib issue out of it.
Well that's why he let him take him
down. You know? He's like, you know,
I could stand up but this guy,
or I could just fucking barley fight
off the take downs. Interesting.
Yeah.
If you can't take them now,
but Chelsea and has the best
double in the sport. His running,
charging double dude,
he just takes motherfuckers down.
Even if Anderson was like fully healthy,
I don't know if he could stop
that guy from taking them down.
A lot of people don't know she does.
The thing about shell son and dude is
Chelsea and the one who's right and right
now he's right. He's one of
the best on the planet. Dude,
that wrestling is insane.
His top position is
boxing is fucking good.
When he caught Anderson with that
straight left and wobbled him, look,
I don't give a fuck what you say.
That's got to put some
thoughts into a guy's head.
You've got to guard charges at you.
Throws fucking clean, crisp punches,
different can take a shot and
his wrestling's ridiculous.
And now after the Brian Stann fight,
oh, he's strangling people too.
And now we started submitting people.
Jesus Christ. And you got to tell you,
you want to talk about a guy
talking shit fucking with your head.
[inaudible] he's the best ever.
The grain white said he's the best
since Muhammad Ali. I, you know,
Muhammad Ali was in a
different world because he was,
he had a different flavor to them.
It was like a ridiculousness to which
chill sort of has a little bit of a
ridiculous to him. But God
damn, that dude's funny.
He's hilarious and he's so prolific.
He's amazing.
He's always coming up with
new ridiculous shit to say.
I wish they didn't hate him so much in
Brazil because he said a lot of crazy
shit. I know, I know, I know, I know. And
you know what he probably mean. Whatever.
I shouldn't say you probably shouldn't
have done that, but now he can, you know,
if he went there, I mean it would
probably suck for him everywhere he goes.
People be screaming and yelling at him.
If he has balls ballsy enough to
actually fight you gonna fight.
Is he going to finance itself as I can
be on the boat? Who knows? He says, no,
he said that he's got a, an
announcement and he said, uh,
my next move after Mark Munoz,
what he said was, I don't know,
but if I was a George
Saint Pierre or John Jones,
I'd take a real deep gulp right about now,
chill son and said that.
So He's,
he's insinuating that he will want to
fight Jon Jones or George Saint Pierre and
since her real gold right now he's,
he's a hilarious showmen and since
George just had knee surgery and he had
patella tendon graft,
knee surgery,
which is particularly difficult
to come back from, not difficult,
but time consuming because you have,
well you have, yeah. You know, it's,
it's a little more,
I mean differ.
Every doctor has their own philosophy
and doctors have their own specialty,
but some doctors don't like to do it
that way because they believe that it
compromises
the strength of the patella tendon and
it makes a knee a little bit wigglier.
I have both. I had this one done. My
left knee was done. Patella tendon graft.
My right knee was done with a cadaver
and the right knee came out way better.
Maybe it was a better doctor.
That's very possible.
But the God that I did in New York was
a top notch guy that did like New York
Knicks and did basketball teams and shit.
He was supposed to be really good,
but it took a long time before
that knee felt right. Again,
this is my right knee would
felt great in like a few months,
like four or five months. My
right knee was fine. My left knee,
well Noah did surgery is very different.
They take a chunk out of your
bone and they slice your tendon.
They'd take a strip of that tendon
and a chunk out of your Shin Bone.
So they pull it off intact and one thing
and then they open you up and screw
that in place and that becomes
your new ACL and he tore his ACL.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. He tore
it. He tore a training.
He heard it and then he had to pull out
the Nick Diaz fight or the Carlos condit
fight, whichever fight it
was at that point in time.
I believe it was Carlos Condit.
Yeah, it was Carlos Condit.
He pulled out of that fight and then I
would have loved to have seen that Nick
Diaz. Uh, yeah. Well he
kept trying to train.
I guess that's really what fucks you up.
You know,
I have a little back injury
and this little Mussel Pole,
it's where my floating rib head is.
It's like we're connects to
like where your scapulas. Yeah,
it's been a fucking pain in my
ass for like a couple of months.
And the reason being because it
was hurting me and I said, oh,
I'll just go and roll light.
And that's when you do like when
you have an injury you have to,
it's like driving your car with a
flat tire. Like yeah, just go slow.
Like you gotta be Super Smart in
combat sports when you have an injury.
And George hurt his knee.
He had to pull out the fight and then
he tried training again too soon.
And then he blew it and then it exploded
on him. You know, you, you know,
it just lost the ACL and
that's what happens a lot of
times. You have like small,
you do damage to the knee,
the knee will be compromised and
week and then you heard it again.
That's exactly what happened to me.
In fact,
on my first knee surgery and the four hour
body, that's why it says that Soviets,
the Soviets,
coaches as well as guys don't they?
The way they get you conditioned
for an Olympic condition,
they make you walk really fast for 15
minutes and every day you have to cover
more ground. So walking is your
aerobic exercise and if you walk speed,
walk for 15 minutes as fast as you can,
you'll get in the best shape of your life,
especially if you do it uphill.
That's hilarious.
That's a great idea.
Fucking if you get on a treadmill and put
it at four miles an hour at 15 degrees
incline at 50 at 58 the highest inclined.
Just try that shit sometime.
Try Walking for four miles an
hour and at for 15 minutes.
[inaudible] had a great article
on his website about, uh,
in intelligence and efficiency over
overtraining and how important it is to
build up real
undertrained.
What they found is that Dan Gable and
those American masters overtrained,
what happens is you get
injuries later on that stuff.
They have unstoppable mental
strength because of it. Of course,
their ability to dominate competition,
the ability to there, you know,
no one has more mental strength in combat,
then they're,
they're on another level. Man Readiness.
I went to, Dan gave us camp for two weeks.
I remember and not realizing if this
is what it takes to train in college.
I don't want to fucking be a
college wrestler. This is this.
I don't want to get up and sprint for an
hour in the morning. I was like, this,
this, I was 17. I was
like, fuck this. I did it.
Then I came back my senior year and did
pretty fucking well just cause I had
been in Iowa.
But yeah,
it was one of the reasons I quit wrestling
over a taekwondo when I was in high
school.
I was doing wrestling and taekwondo
and wrestling made me so fucking tired.
I remember have the first
day after practice we ran
stadium stairs or something
like that.
The first after practice I couldn't walk.
I was like walking in the hallways.
I would have to like stop for a second
and like massage my upper thighs and then
walk again.
Matches,
matches sometimes masters to go over
time and an extra three minutes.
You thought you were going to fucking die.
I'll never forget that.
That that is a young man.
When you,
when you wrestle like you know I wrestled
pretty, you know, it was my sport.
You never that,
that fear of going walking on that and
mat against somebody you don't know when
you're 14 1516 1718 yeah.
It does change you.
It really does force you even any
sport and he's just playing basketball.
Anything we have to step up when
you're alone for cultural sports,
when you were alone, it's a lonely
place on that mat. It is definitely,
I think more troubling or more more a
taxing and more testing of your character
and to go to Iowa. To this
intensive wrestling cabin. It,
Dan's gable and you're around,
all these all have a Midwestern
animals and you're like, holy,
you're ready to dedicate every
wrestling. Why is that? 17,
I'll have a fucking mustache.
You know,
one of the first times I
ever saw Matt Hughes fights,
I remember thinking like
this back when he used to,
they used to let them wear wrestling
shoes. Okay, good luck. Good luck.
Good luck stopping that shot
with his red wrestling shoes.
I got so fucking God told me he was
the strongest guy he'd ever, Russell.
He said Matt Hughes was the
strongest person I'd ever,
oh, I believe it. You know,
Matt Hughes tapped out
fucking Brock Lesnar when they
were training together. No,
dude, he's a black belt level
Brazilian Jiu Jitsu artists. He just,
you know what I mean?
He learned everything from like Jeremy
Horn and from MMA classes and you know,
catch wrestling. He does a lot
of wrestling submissions too.
Like the one he put Ricardo Almeida with,
he put them out. Remember that Ricardo?
Uh, he got him in that, um, uh, the, um,
it was the Schultz headlock and he just
fucking cranked it down to the beautiful
and put them out, you know,
and made it even know.
He didn't even know he's in danger. He
didn't even freak outs, you know. Yeah.
It's ridiculous.
So I remember watching when he first
started fighting in the UFC and I'm just
like, man, these guys are common
man. I always knew they were around.
I always knew from my time in wrestling,
there was always guys that would,
we would go to the states and,
you know,
watch like the best guys in the states
go out of the division champions so fast
and so and just so flexible. Yeah. The kid
in our, um, we had a kid in our, um, our,
our, when I was a sophomore, when
I was a sophomore in high school,
we had one kid that was in like national
level. It's a who smoked cigarettes too,
by the way. Mark Collins. And
he was a great fucking car,
like a really passionate dude.
And I remember one time, uh, uh,
believe the coach's name was Hurwitz. I
believe that was, it was her wits end. Uh,
the other guy was, fuck the Irish,
fuck, I can't remember his name,
but hold on,
Hook this mark calling guy would have
this fucking crazy practice and everybody
would be dying.
Hands on their knees and calling would
run across the fucking room and slide
down on his knees and go, come on, let's
go. Who's next? And just wanted to,
wanted to keep wrestling learned,
keep going, want to keep drilling.
And the coach pointed at him and he goes,
there's guys like that in every
weight class. He goes, get,
you better get that in your head. There's
guys like that in every weight class.
And I remember realizing myself, you know,
being 14 years old or whatever I was,
you know,
it was either 14 or 15,
and I was looking at him and I was killing
my God like this. Yeah, you gotta know,
you gotta know that there's dudes out
there that are willing to take it like
that. They're willing to
go that far. Coach Murphy,
that was the Irish guy and Murphy was
always trying to get me to play football.
I'm like, bitch, are you
crazy? I am a small person.
There's a dude on our wrestling
team that was also playing football.
His name was Bob Baker.
He was 300 fucking pounds in high school.
I wrestled one 34 I don't want
to lose this fucking giant dude.
Someone on another squash on top of me.
Fuck that man.
Oh my God to for one season.
I was so afraid.
I just seeing these huge guys run
at me. I was like, I'm so dangerous.
Man has made a paper. It's such
as such a dangerous sport. I mean,
people love it and everything now,
but charging into guys.
My 14 year old who I've
worked here on nephew is,
is 185 pounds and he's six foot
one and he squats to 85 for reps.
Okay. He's 14 and he's a giant Jesus and
he plays football and I watched that.
I watched him play Jv.
He's only 14 and I watched,
I watched those kids hit
each other and I was like,
nobody's heads built for this.
I told his dad, I go, look,
he's a monster and amount of there,
get him out of there and get a good
amount of it in a minute fighting and he
plays guitar.
Let him play guitar.
They don't even know how bad the
damage is until these guys die. Yeah.
You remember that guy that fell off of
his back of his girls? His truck had it.
He had an old man's brain and an old man's
like rotten brain and it showed like,
you know all this degeneration 23 or
something. I think he was 25 but yeah,
close enough. I mean it's insane. These
guys have been doing this device school.
Exactly. It's not even a
layman alignment or or running.
I have a friend who was an alignment and
he said back in the day when he was to
play in college,
he,
they didn't allow you to use your
hands so you couldn't push guys.
You would slam head to head with guys.
Is that true? Does that make any sense?
Use Your hands.
You always use your hands always.
Is there anything different than what
you couldn't cause he was telling me that
the pig gets spiked guys in the chest
with the big difference is that now in
football you can't have a helmet to helmet
contact. You can't do it deliberately.
So if you hit somebody,
you tackle somebody and a lot of guys
just to run at you and they'd hit you with
their helmet and you always allowed to
use your hands and push guys where you
will have to do, you have to unblock
them on the line. You can use your hands.
But yeah, you typically held your
hands this way. But what are the rules?
Can you grab a guy and fucking on Juno
is asking me about office all offense.
You cannot do that on defense. Kenyon,
you know, holding on offense and defense.
Offense, you can grab and move.
You can pull people out of the way.
So on defensive of dudes coming at
you can judo his ass. Yes. Really?
You can grab his clothes and
fucking hip toss on. Yeah.
But it's really hard to do. Cause those
guys know what the fuck they're doing.
Yeah, no shit. Right? Yeah.
That's one of the craziest thing is
when you see some nutty running back,
one of those fucking freaks,
one of those incredible specimens.
And I remember this one where Peterson
dudes were trying to get ahold of them
and he's spinning. He keeps
spinning. Adrian Peterson
tried to grab a hold of me.
He just spins out of their
hands. Oh Adrian Peterson
sprinting with a shirt off.
There's like a,
there's I've commercial.
And just take a look at the
physicality is a guy who was so fast,
he runs I think 27 miles an
hour or something like 20
what is the human athlete
going to look like a hundred years from
now? A lot of things going on like,
like Venus and Serena Williams.
Okay,
they're going to have sex and
they're gonna make a baby.
And I can only hope they have sex with
some Olympic athlete motherfucker.
And we see what's possible.
And everybody just keeps doing that
until the point where that just becomes,
you know, the, the,
the number one seed on the planet earth
and just see what is possible with this
human form. I got to come to that
because we're going to have two things.
You're going to have training methods
of course, and nutrition and all that.
Nano bots and shit.
Genetic engineering. Yeah.
Science is going to step in and
take care of everything that nature,
manipulation, myostatin
inhibitors, all those things.
If we think that you know that the stock
market crash is a wake up call, wait,
so the genetic crash comes, have 400
pound linemen, 500 pound linemen.
We're going to have to fucking
women that are 10 feet tall,
squashing men on the head.
Dad Way.
Could you imagine if some woman became
a like a mad crazy man hater and they
genetically engineered a way for her
to be like a check of the giants?
How big giant. It's huge.
What are you gonna do?
Are you going to fuck around with you,
Tanya?
She's going to use you like a Dildo and
just grab you by your little ass hole
and stuff. You inside her pussy. I
do imagine if there was like some,
if you could just decide I want to be a
10 foot tall woman because men have been
fucking with me.
I'm just going to walk around and kicking
guys and the ball and shove them with
other animals.
Your genetic structure with other animals.
That's what's interesting.
The idea is can you stop that technology
from getting to that point and can you
keep it out of the hands of a person
who would use it for a terrible thing?
Probably not. Probably not. Right. You
think everything will look at this.
I mean there's laptops that were,
we use just your phone.
Your phone has like so much more power
than anything that existed in the 1960s
but everybody's going
to have access to it.
So everything is going to come
up together just like computers.
But will there come a time where we have
to stop people from becoming 10 foot
tall attack of the giant women's
stomping on dudes and shit? I mean,
what could you imagine if there the
manipulation of actual physical life,
if it actually gets to a point where you
can design what you want to look like
and like you can say, mom, Dad,
I've decided to be one of the blue people
from Avatar and you just decided the
Pentagon is definitely the thing.
Trying to figure out ways
to create super soldiers,
whether it's a cloning or
tissue regeneration and yeah,
but I mean what if I forgot
about super soldiers?
How about things that don't even exist?
You can make things that you
could become a dragon. You know,
like I want to be a dragon. That's what,
that's what Craig Venter, Craig Venter,
the guy who created that synthetic
biology quick vendors team that the
implications are 21 years. Is
this the guy who created um, um,
it's made out of metal or
is he the guy who so poor?
Basically I'm a synthetic form of
bacteria. That was, that was basically,
it's a host genetic blueprint was created
on a computer. It's synthetic biology.
And, and the idea is that anything you
can conceive of a human being can make.
Do you know that scientists have been able
to grow sperm and the laboratory dish?
Yes, I do. Your time was up, son. I
know our time on this planet as men,
we will no longer be useful.
Just that biology is going to be an
antiquated and antiquated machine
controlled by technology.
It's going to be some mad rush to see
who can dominate whatever aspect of this
new reality comes up.
Because if there's no morality and there's
no humans that are in control of it,
clearly it's going to get to a point
where it's gonna. It's gonna be wild,
wild west for genetic manipulation.
But also the idea is that if
you're going to live that long,
what does that say about
your earning power?
You've got to make a lot of fucking
money for a long time. You know,
you know that a Apple's got, you
know, we're not going to be able to,
we're not going to need to charge our
phones anymore. They have flow cells.
They have the patch.
It's going to blow up on your patent from
fuel cells and every two weeks you'll
take an action. Cautious ago.
Check. That'd be set for two weeks.
What I'm going to pay, I'll be really,
it's going to be that. That crazy. Yup.
Why don't you just hold your pee
and we'll wrap this bitch up. No,
a la based comic. Angelo Bowers. No,
he had died today. What does he know?
Immediately hung out at the comedy
store a lot and stuff like that.
I don't know the exact details,
but I think he might've been in a car
with another friend of ours who we talked
about earlier in the podcast, Josh, Adam
Meyers and maybe a drunk driver hit him,
but I don't know if that's real. Do
you have a picture? Yeah, I don't know.
I that's,
that's songs.
Recipes to Fred James Too. I don't,
I don't know that dude, but fat.
Well maybe I might have met him
before. I'm not sure, but Fed James.
I knew very well. You Remember Fred
James Comedy store? I should do.
He was one of the first person
I met. No, he looks like a,
like Andrew dice clay, but squished
in fat jolly guy. Nice guy.
Yeah, he passed away
unfortunately. He was a great dude.
So rest in peace. Fet, James. Um, uh,
thank you to Brian Callin
for coming by brother.
Always like whenever I think you know,
you're just like Joey Diaz,
a Bert Kreischer when a or Duncan
Trussell whatever thing you're out of.
Interesting Shit to talk about. You come
with a wave of new things and I swear,
man,
when you were talking about the Holocaust,
I've always been aware of
the holocaust of course,
but there's something about the way
you were describing it that it was put,
it was shining like some extra light on
how fucking crazy and barbaric it was
really like you were, you were
saying, it's so eloquently,
it really made me like really tuned in
to how chaotic and Insane and disgusting
and horrific it really was.
It's really was and,
and important to keep in mind.
Also the lesson to the Holocaust is
that it can happen again in some form or
another human beings when you give
people power over you over you.
Yeah. Uh, you, you, they'll, they'll take
advantage and it sounds melodramatic,
but something like the Nda
actually does that. It's,
it's not what the constitution is the
first step. It's not how it was founded.
The country,
they knew that the people who founded this
country knew that shit could go wrong.
And so they had a bunch
of things in place.
And one of the things that Benjamin
Franklin said, and she never forget this,
that he who would sacrifice liberty
for security deserves neither. Oh,
that's a good way to end this
podcast. I love that. Say that again.
He who would sacrifice liberty
for security deserves neither.
They knew back then. Man. Someone's
going to play a shell game on you, man.
They're going to tell you this,
some bad people out there.
We need to look at your email to
protect you from them. That's right.
Those Fox get your own porn. Thank
you to liberty, liberty, liberty,
and justice for all. One of the most
important things that people forget,
and that's the issue of a liberty
God damn constitution. All right.
It's the bill of rights. It's in the, the
idea that this country was founded on,
they got away from a system
that's sucked and they said,
let's make one for the fucking
people, by the people, for the people,
by the people.
And now it's become for the corporations
and lobbying groups and lobbying groups
and cunts. It's for the cuts.
He just stopped the Kuntz.
We could be okay.
Fleshlight stop the cont start fucking
training on it. Nick Diaz, camp camping,
just started balling. They'll
kill you. They'll kill, you know,
there'll be nice to make sure I'll be,
I'll make 'em laugh.
Thank you to the fleshlight for
sponsoring our podcast. As always,
everything we sponsor everything always.
We will never sponsor anything that we
don't believe in and both Brian and I and
even Brian Cowen have fucked
these things and I'm telling you,
it's way better than beaten off and
you know you're going to beat off.
Stop playing games. Just go ahead
and auto one. And when you know,
when you're not in your little fake
vagina thing and you're like, oh,
you'd be like, Joe Rogan was
right. If you make this this, ah,
I usually go
fucking crazy silver back when I
thought, you know what, I sound like,
I sound like I stubbed my toe.
Oh my God,
I like to let six notes quickly.
Jimmy Burke, I heard him,
I heard him having sex
one time and he goes, oh,
oh God bless America. That's the
thing. When he blows Jimmy Burke,
I was like, Jesus, Jim,
thank you to [inaudible] dot
com makers of Alpha, brain,
shroom, tech, sport, shroom,
tech, immune and new mood,
all different types of supplements
for different things. Alpha brain,
is it cognitive enhancing supplement?
No. Mood is a serotonin boosting,
serotonin boost, boosting supplement,
and then of course a shroom tech.
Shroom tech sport is the one that's
for people who are like seriously in to
working out. If you're not,
skip that. And then shroom,
tick immune is a fascinating one where
it fires up your immune system because it
recognizes the mushroom that you're eating
as some sort of a a possible threat.
And then it gears up for a
fight that never takes place,
leaving you with a charge of
immune system. Pretty wicked
from what I understand.
But I don't understand any of this shit.
I'm just talking
out of my ass. I just work here.
If you go to Joe rogan.net,
click on the link entering the codename
Brogan, you will get 10% off. Uh,
all that shit and always, uh, everything
on it is 100% money back guarantee.
If you don't like it, just fucking
tell us and you get your money back.
You don't even have to send in the
product. And uh, on top of that, if you,
if you like the idea of it,
you think it costs too much money,
please buy it in bulk.
We've defined the ingredient list online.
It's in the exact dose and make
it yourself. I am much more,
much more concerned with
people not feeling ripped off.
I don't really care if you buy
it or not buy it, don't buy it.
But if you want to buy it, get it
on at.com. O n n I t Holla. Okay.
January 27th, uh, the Chicago
theater is still not quite sold out.
The whole bottom has gone. Now.
They opened up a new top layer,
so there's still some tickets
left. It's going to be me, Duncan,
Trussell and Joey Diaz dream the
day before the UFC in Chicago,
it's, we're actually, the Chicago
theater is actually where the winds are,
so we're going to go
there for the way ends.
I'm going to Mc the way and then we got
to show that night should be a pitch in
time.
A T one two combo to Duncan Trussell and
show he does is if I was going to show
Friday also at the ice house. Powerful.
Am I in that? Yeah. Oh, that's right.
Yeah. Friday the icehouse pitches
and the icehouse chronicles,
which is only available on a death squad,
the desk squad label on Itunes,
it's free. As always, all of our
podcasts are free. We're committed.
You will never see my podcast costs you
money. It's just always going to be this.
It's a,
there's some ads in there and some of
them are a little hokey and some of the
little verbose, but whatever, bitch, you
don't have to buy anything. Just what?
Why am I, why am I justifying anything?
I just want to tell everybody.
Thank you everybody who came out for a
new year's cause it was a fucking awesome
vibe in the room, man. And uh, I had, uh,
a great fucking time and I appreciate
the shit out of all of the people. Uh,
this is, um, there's never been a
time ever in my life where, uh, I had,
uh, people that would come to see
my shows that get me more, you know,
I mean having this sort of a,
don't you feel like that too?
Now Brian, Callum was just telling
me about this because of the podcast.
People know who the fuck he is.
They understand them now. And uh,
it's just the coolest resource ever and
we appreciate the fuck out of you guys.
I just want to let you know,
we've, we've tuned into a,
a really awesome group of human beings
out there and every one of my shows,
people say that all the weight staffs
are always saying how generous everybody
is and how nice everybody is
and how smart everybody is.
And there's no Douche bags. And that means
the world. To me that means everything.
That means we're putting
out the right vibe.
You guys are giving out the right vibe.
It's spreading you dirty hookers and uh,
that's it.
Fall Brian Callan on Twitter,
B r y a n Callan and uh,
Brian Reichle is of course red band,
red ban hollow.
That's it.
We'll see you dirty freaks most likely
Thursday with some fantastic new guests.
Not sure who we're going to
try to fit a girl at one girl.
We need to get a girl in.
We haven't had a girl in a wild chicks
are complaining vague of course.
And of course Kelly Carlin to
who's the George Carlin's daughter,
I want to get her in as well. Um, yeah, it
comes highly recommended by Kevin Smith.
He said he was, she was awesome. And
um, other than that, uh, that's it.
Friday night, uh, at the Ice House
will sell out is a very small place.
It's only 85 seats and a,
we do it all the time and it's
going to be the best of the best.
Whoever's in town. You in town Friday
night. I am not in touch pitch.
Where you at on the road? Yeah.
All right. Well, whoever's there,
it was always like Jody has Doug Benson.
It's always,
there's a lot of great comps
at the next one. All right.
It's fucking shows over. Thank you
very much for everything. Oh, oh,
you guys were were on this thing
together, right? It so I got by,
yeah.