Real good experience.
Can we are
flying Ocean Pacific flying above
the Pacific. I'm with Dana White.
What's up? Tony has gone hello
everybody. And uh, we're uh,
basically we were in shock right now.
No one,
no one here should be allowed to vote.
They shouldn't be allowed to drive.
We should all be forced to settle in.
Don't make any rash decisions.
Like right now we're dealing with a,
this is a crazy time. We just got,
we just got done watching.
It might not be the biggest
upset in combat sports history.
I know I said it after the fight.
I think Buster Douglas might've been a
bigger upset because buster Douglas was
kind of a fuck up.
He was kind of a guy who didn't,
didn't really train hard,
didn't take care of himself,
and he was a 42 to one underdog
when he knocked out Mike Tyson.
Holly Holm was only a 12 to one underdog
when she knocked out Rhonda and Holly
was, you know, very respected
in the combat sports world,
multiple time boxing,
world kickboxing champion,
but still on Twitter when I was hyping
this fight off and I was telling people
about this fight, so many people saying,
you're trying to sell us bullshit.
You know Holly doesn't have a chance.
Freddie Roach said Ronda Rousey is
going to destroyer and it was all these
articles and you just going.
So it was an upset,
but it wasn't just that it was an
opposite. It was the way she did it,
the way she did though.
She fought the perfect fight and when
she had kicked Ronda, just the icing,
the cherry on the cake,
goodnight everybody and hammer fist
at her when she was out. I mean,
we're all shocked.
I'm in shock
placement shot.
I mean there's a reason right now why
literally my phone at four o'clock in the
morning was going crazy. Every
media outlet on earth, I mean,
you name it, my Dave Sholler,
our Pr Guy said, pick a,
pick an outlet. Say it. Just say
something to pull it, pull the name out,
they call it, and they want either hollow
Holly, Rhonda, they want to talk to him.
I,
and I was saying earlier to you guys,
it's like patriots looking
good this season. They just,
they just went nine to know did
they could win another Superbowl.
The world will not go fucking crazy
the way the world went when to,
you know, went to bad ass human being
square off and, and uh, and uh, and uh,
you know, combat fight in the
world goes fucking crazy man.
We're not used to women doing that.
And if we are using, there's a,
there was like a brief moment in the past
or Christy Martin got big of the coal
miner's daughter and she used to box
on TV and she would have these kinds of
fights.
But one of the things about watching
women fight was they didn't really knock
each other out. They sort of beat
each other. They had each other. But
when when Holly head kicked her
on the last night, he was like,
it wasn't just that she beat her,
it was just that one.
It was such a superstar. When such
a superstar gets beaten like that,
the whole Russ to go, what? It's like when
buster Douglas knocked out Mike Tyson.
It wasn't that a guy got knocked out.
Everybody knows guys can knock guys out.
We've seen Mike Tyson
knock out a hundred guys.
It's not that it was at Mike
Tyson got knocked out. What? What?
What's like it didn't fit in our
paradigm of how the world works.
The world works. Ronda Rousey runs out,
grabs girls, throws them on their head,
armbars bars or she needs the most
dominant punches him in the face.
Takes him out to see that
happen the way it happened.
To See Holly Holm fight the perfect
fight and be so classy to all through the
media, everything. She did cool as
a cucumber during the weigh ins.
Rhonda screaming at her in her face,
everything Holly was stone faced
never changed her expression.
I mean the whole day,
it's almost the same feeling,
not the same feeling,
but almost the same feeling that I got
on nine 11 watching this Cheyenne trade
centers come down. No, I'm serious.
I mean we knew when the trade centers got
hit by planes, we were like, holy fuck.
But when you watched him actually
come down and you're like,
there's no way something that's solid
and that stabilized and strong and
powerful is coming down right now.
And that's how I felt when
the leg kick happened.
Like I felt like if there was a
delayed reaction from everybody,
like people are like, oh yeah, she
just got head kicked and she went down,
but it's up over.
It's not really over.
And until the graph and tell
her dean wave that hand,
I still think it took 10 2030 seconds
before people really realize what was
happening.
I was outlining it before the fight and
what was funny was all these people on
Twitter were like, you know, you
try to show us just bullshit.
We're already watching. Stop trying
to sell. It's bullshit. You know,
Ron is going to kill her.
But as I'm outlining it,
I'm outlining kicks.
I'm talking about old bleak kicks.
I'm talking about movement and distance
and Holly Holmes striking credentials
and like this is, this is a complicated
fight for Ronda in this space.
It really sunk in with me when
I saw her at the weigh ins.
You could tell that
she realized like this,
even though Holly wasn't
doing anything disrespectful,
she wanted to get this emotional,
she wanted to turn this into
something like very, very
personal and she, you know,
I don't know what was going on,
but Rhonda was,
you know when you do that
at the day of the weigh ins,
you're trying to get in their head,
do trying to rattle or shake her up and
Holly was not rattled or shaken one bit
at all exchange.
What was the other thing that we were
talking about during the broadcast?
We're saying like this is a girl who's,
she's faced intense pressure before world
championship pressure and boxing and
kickboxing. She's been there, man, she's,
we're shooting all over this fight.
I kept saying,
I did
a radio tour the week we
left for Australia. I said,
these girls had 45 fights and
had multiple world titles there.
There's a, there's a
sense of, of uh, you know,
experience and,
and,
and this just calm feeling even though
she's going in against Ronda Rousey and
Rhonda is,
you know,
I guess now you could say she was really
the female Tyson for or for the sport
because of the way everybody's
reacting to her a loss. But you know,
this girl has a lot of
experience, man. It's,
it's a big deal and she has the distance
to range. She has great head kicks,
you know, and good hands. This
was, this was a great fight.
This was the fight to make.
Well, you know, what it was is
that she didn't come into our own,
in the UFC until this fight.
Like even though she looked great and
other organizations and should not be out
when she fought in the UFC,
the few fights she had in the UFC,
she was still trying to find her footing.
Like in the Raquel Pennington fight.
She looked good but she didn't
look like a world beater.
It's like we talk about this all the time,
but being in the UFC is such
an overwhelming experience
for fighters that it
takes them several fights like Kyle
Noke, like Kyle. No cause had what,
10 fights in the UFC.
I don't remember.
I don't even know how many fights
that in the EOC, but last night, Tom,
into his own last night when
Kyle Noke fought Sabata,
he came into his own, he landed that,
he looked fantastic, land that front,
kick the body and said to himself
a lot when I was interviewing him,
he's finally believe it in themselves.
It takes a while to get
comfortable in there.
The other thing to this sport
and this sport, it's so different
to coach. This is, we're on a plane
right now. What's your name, ma'am?
To sell and just though is, uh, the flight
attendant. Thank you very much, ma'am.
Would you change that to eight
together? I'll blackjack JB on. Yeah.
We'll pause this for a moment. We'll
come back in a little bit. Yeah. Oh,
you're going to set up the tray right now.
Is that what you're doing? Okay. Okay.
Thanks. All right. Thank you.
Just so well. The other thing is
that in this sport,
and we say this all the time,
there's so many different
ways to win and lose and um,
it's so hard to be perfect all the time
of the sport to go undefeated and go on
these long runs for 10
years like Josie Aldo,
or as long as the Anderson Silva did,
or as long as Ronda Rousey did,
it is hard to be perfect
every time you go in there.
Because I don't care how
good of an athlete you are.
How long have you been competing?
Not everybody jumps out of bed every
day and feels perfect and feels good.
The timing is on your body feels
right. You know, it, it just,
it's not possible for that to
happen all the time. It's for,
that's why when people go on these
undefeated runs in this sport, they are,
they're fucking great.
They're truly great. Uh,
and then you take all the things about
physically not being perfect then had the
pressure and the workload that gets put
on you when you become a UFC champion.
Ronda Rousey did it better
than anybody's ever done it.
The amount of work and the time she put
in how hard she trained the things that
she would do.
She didn't become a huge superstar the
way that she did for no reason. She,
she worked at it. And you see Conor work
at it and these guys that, that, that, uh,
that can go on these long runs
or are very unique individuals,
pressure that she's under and the
pressure and the distractions, you know,
when you see her and all those media
events move all seen her on all these
different talk shows and all these
magazine articles. Is that yours?
Oh my God. It is like,
listen to this song.
He's got his beats headphones blaring,
but the,
when you see all these things,
I tune into them and I,
I see them,
but I don't think of how many she's doing
that. I'm aware of them. You know, if,
if someone's aware of, if you're
aware of someone on the tonight show,
if you're aware of someone
in a rolling stone article,
think about how many things they're
doing that you're not aware how much shit
Rhonda is doing all day long constantly.
Or phones blowing up.
Media requests constantly.
People asking her to do things
and you know,
you know,
most people don't realize they look
at somebody and go home, big deal.
You got to do interviews,
you got to do this. It sucks.
A lot of energy I imagine doing
that stuff is very time consuming.
You always have to be on, there's
tons of preparation that goes into it.
The travel that's needed to
do it. It's, it's a, it's a,
it's a heavy workload when you're,
when you become the champion.
Let's a heavy workload
guy like you who doesn't have to fight.
It's a heavy workload.
Constantly doing interviews for
someone who has to fight and you have
preparation, you have to train, you have
to eat right, you have to sleep right.
You have to make sure that you get
all of your physical preparation in.
I mean the, the, it's, it's, it's
a massive, massive distraction.
Carlos Barsa we'll call those
bars. Uh, um, you know, one top,
she was the champion. She,
we started putting her on,
she had to do media than we
needed her to defend her title.
And she started to freak out early.
Like, I, this is, this is, um,
to this too much. I'm, I'm breaking down.
I just got off the ultimate fighter.
I trained for this fight.
I won the show and now I've
got to defend the time.
I got to go back and just people start,
you know,
Rhonda said this quote this
last week, she said, um,
these people who think they want to be
the world champion have no idea what it
really takes to be the world
champion. And it's so true. You know,
I remember when Bj Penn beat Matt Hughes
when I was interviewing Matt in the
Octagon and Matt was very
candid and very honest,
and I really admire the way he
approached it because no one's ever,
I never interviewed anybody before and
they talked about it like that. He said,
honestly,
losing as a relief.
He said it was a just a tremendous amount
of pressure being the champ and having
all these people coming after me. And,
uh, honestly it was a relief from my wow,
what a ballsy guy he is
to admit that bite. That
what an honest guy.
It's so true. Th th the,
the amount of pressure that these guys
are under and the workload and then you
take Rhonda and you had
movies on top of it.
She's doing movies on top of it and books
and going on book tours and all this
stuff. It's, it's, it's a,
it's a lot of work for anybody.
And uh, like I said, she,
she did it better than anybody's
ever done it. She really did.
Now when you look at
the fight stylistically,
that's one of the crazy things
about fights. Um, you know,
you can get a guy like Floyd Mayweather
figures out how to box people and get to
a 49 to no record,
but to figure out how to beat every
different style of martial artists.
When you're talking about takedowns
leg kicks, all these different things.
We had talked about the one thing that
we hadn't seen Rhonda deal with with
someone who knows how to kick and we
really had cats in Ghana was the only
possibility. And Kat just made
a, a crazy mistake and rushed.
Rhonda got caught in a
scramble and got arm barred.
But what Holly Holm was able to do,
it was the first time we ever saw
anybody knows how to kick keep her on the
outside. A lot of
movement, a lot of kicking.
And that's kind of missing in Vonda's
game. The, the, the kicking aspect,
we really, I don't, I don't recall
ever seeing or throw a kick.
I mean if she has maybe one or two ever.
I mean if you,
do you remember seeing her
kick? Yeah. I don't know.
The thing is is that Ronda was a fucking
tornado and ripping through everybody,
like in seconds. Um, you know,
so he probably don't get to see her full
name or what she's got in last night.
You know,
last night was just craziness south.
So it's tough to to sit back and look
at game play because the other thing is
what are you going to do with holidays
now you can look back and said, well,
she probably should have tried to grapple
with or she should maybe try to double
leg or getting the clinch, take her down,
do this, that and everything else. But,
but that's not Rhonda. Rhonda
is, I'm going to go out on
a fucking bang with you.
I'm going to try to try to throw you off.
I get the opportunity to throw
you off throw you. She just,
she never got any opportunities.
She got into a couple of exchanges.
She rocked Holly a couple of
times but she never really,
you think she blocked her? She did.
From what I remember seeing the fight,
I remembered seeing Holly look like she
got hurt a couple times in the fight by
Rhonda.
I didn't see that.
I remember seeing her charging after
Holly and maybe connecting a couple of
times at punches, but Holly was
always moving back and you know,
like when someone's moving
away and you hit them,
it doesn't have nearly as much him.
No doubt.
She was on the outside and she was
picking her apart and hitting her with big
shots, planting up, planting and
then throwing that straight left.
No vin planting hit her with a shoulder
one time hitting her with hooks.
She hit her with a couple of those oblique
kick to the legs to jar your knees,
you know,
reminded me of watching an actual both
fight when the bull charges and the,
the matador hits that sword a couple
times. Like that's what it reminded of.
So you were saying
about the time where Rhonda
Yeah. Oh my God. When Rhonda missed that
one time and she turns around and looks,
it looked like a scene from a movie when
she misses stumbled. Yeah. She like,
she fell down and, and Holly just
ducked under him, was out of the way,
turned around and she had
a look on her face. Like,
who am I going against right now?
It's exactly what her face said
and she was wearing it and,
and I think that was a huge turning
point. I also think when, you know,
I went crazy when Holly Holm took her
down cause they were clenched up and it
looked like Rando was trying to get that
toss and all of a sudden Holly lifted
and sort of just did like a standing
double leg sort of then got her down.
It was, I think psychologically
a huge turning point. There was
clinch there at one point and they ended
up going down to the ground and Rhonda
was trying to get an arm bar owner and
then Holly pulled out of it. Um, yeah,
I got to see the fight again. It
was, it was so fast and crazy.
We replayed the entire second round,
but the second rail,
she was already beaten up. We had time
and I was said to Bruce and the truck,
I was like, let's do the whole fight
again. Let's do the whole fight,
comment on it. And you know, with,
with the knowledge of what had happened
and because we're only dealing with,
you know, seven minutes, let's,
let's do this whole thing again.
But we wound up playing the second
round again and Rhonda came out for that
second round already flustered already.
She was so tired.
Going back to that first round lake,
her legs were wobbly.
She was breathing heavy.
And I like Edmond.
I talked to Edmund all the time. I enjoyed
talking to him. I was a hug that guy.
When I see him, I do not, I do not
like what he did in the corner.
He wasn't honest with her. He told
her she did great. He was like, great,
round champ. Everything's great. I mean,
maybe it was trying to
psychologically pump her up,
but that's not what you need to, I mean,
she needed technical advice. She needed,
she needed someone to tell her what
she's doing wrong and how to correct it.
Then I think, you know, I mean,
he's more of like a boxing coach
than he is an overall MMA coach.
Yeah. I mean, well, the thing
is, is that, uh, you, uh,
if it isn't broke, don't fix it. Right.
You know, that's a very good point.
The thing is now is as you know,
what do they do?
He listened to at the end of the day,
Edmunds,
a guy who really cares about
Rhonda and her career and you know,
all of that stuff. So I
think as it, as a team,
they'll sit down and try to figure out
what went wrong and what needs to be
fixed.
You know, and Tony, you had a great
point. We were at breakfast today.
You were like all these people on Twitter,
like they knew what was going to
happen. Oh, you knew he was, oh, well,
I assume you bet everything you had there.
Yeah. Everybody wants to stay that they
knew what happened. Well then where's the,
where's your bedding?
Well, you want to know something?
Vegas went down last night.
A lot of people did bet on
Holly home last night. And um,
apparently there were some big college
football games last night with,
with huge spreads and they parlayed
Holly Holm and college game.
And this is what I heard,
I don't know if this is fact,
but this is what I heard
today here in Australia,
is that the Bellagio had to shut down
for over an hour because they didn't have
enough money in the cage to pay
everybody from the Holly Holm bets
that we, you know, and
there's some guy, uh,
his name's Vegas Dan or something
like that. He bet $25,000 on her.
Um, 2021 to 40. Yeah.
12 to one allegedly is going to
have to shut off their fountain.
Save that water bill for a little
bit. Huh. They, uh, the other,
the other big bet that everybody was
taken was the over the over was around and
a half.
Yeah.
You know, it's, um, it's an
interesting situation because, uh,
I'd love Rhonda as a person.
I consider her a good friend.
I really like her and I
know you do too. And, uh,
as a person,
I'm sad for her loss that
this happened to her. Um,
but how home is a great person to,
you know,
and there are two great competitors
and I think ultimately what happened
yesterday last night is great
for martial arts. You know,
and it's great for MMA because even though
it was terrible for Rhonda and I feel
terrible for her, I still,
I feel great for Holly Holm.
It's very con very conflicted. It's
like I'm trying to figure out when I'm,
when I'm interviewing Holly
in the inside the Octagon,
I'm going in there as a
person who cares about Rhonda.
It's tricky because this is the
biggest moment of Holly Holmes Life.
And I want to honor that and I want to
go in there and I am genuinely happy for
her while at the same time
genuinely sad for Rhonda and it,
but I can't,
I can't acknowledge that I
have to be happy for Holly.
And not only that, not only do
I have to, I, I wanna I want,
when I'm interviewing
someone inside the octagon,
I am trying my best to get them to
express themselves. I want Holly to set,
I mean this is the new
bantamweight champion of the world,
Holly Hall,
and she's got tears in her eyes and her
dad's dad and her husband's there and
winkled John's there and everybody's down.
It says intense and tense moment and I
just want, I want to get that out of her.
While that was all happening
and I was thinking to myself,
what a good person she is because she's a,
even though you know,
like love Rhonda and I care about Rhonda,
like what a good person Holly Holm is,
you know, she's, she's just
like, you can't help feel
happy for her. That's true.
It's the, it's the crazy thing
about this business that we're in.
It's not just Holly and Ronda to every,
every,
every person that goes in there and
competes in the octagon both have these
fucking dreams of,
of winning and glory and,
and world titles and money and all
the things that go along with it.
And then every fucking
weekend when we do a show,
one guy or girl moves forward and one
guy or girl moves backward. It's, it's,
it's a crazy thing in the
Holly Holm and her, her,
her father,
her husband and all the crew that was
around her could not have been better.
People could not have handled the
whole situation, but could it just,
I couldn't agree with you more.
Such a very, very good people. Um,
I went to the hospital last night and
I had Joanna young Jane check there.
I had Valerie Laterno there and that
Ronda Rousey there and I'm walking from
room to room going, Jesus Christ, this is
a crazy business more man. You know, it's,
it's just so crazy. These girls, you know,
even even Joanna as, uh, you know,
as dominant as she was last night, she
was hurt. She broke her hand, you know,
she broke her hand. Valerie,
what turnover is? Oh my God. Her,
I was massive. It, I'm serious.
It was the craziest thing that
I've ever seen her eyes last night
and I was so swollen by
the end of the fight,
I can only imagine all
looks like in a hostel.
Joe, it was so bad. So then I'm like,
how's your leg?
She looks at me and she pulls the
covers over and shows me her leg.
I've never seen anything like that.
It was,
I'm telling you that for a little
girl is banged up right now.
Took some hard, hard shots in her
leg and really kept kicking with it.
Kept coming forward. She is so
fucking tough left on top. So time,
the women are tougher than the madman.
Women.
Women have fucking
babies for Christ sakes.
They're way tougher than us where he
talked with them. Well, I'll tell you,
I'm so impressed.
First of all was a Latino's ability
to rise to the occasion too,
because that was the best
fight ever fought in her life,
or at least what I've seen in the octagon
and against Yolana who's a fucking
killer.
She's so good.
See, we always believed in Valerie
thought valor was good, big, strong,
115 pounder for that division.
Now she's at least going to sit
in the rankings where she belongs.
You know what I mean? She wasn't
ranked number eight. She's, she's,
she's better than that. Then she
approved it last night. Um, Joann,
it's just bucking the monster.
Yeah.
She's so tough. She's so tough. And
Tony is in love with her, by the way.
Yeah. I'm in love with the
Ohana. If you're listening
right now, Johan, I love it.
Yeah. They don't call it
Johana then call Yohanna.
Yohanna. Yeah, it's no
age. There's no age.
Everybody pronounces it differently,
including her. I've heard,
I've seen her in different interviews and
say her name, toto six different ways.
Some of them, when you know, people would
start calling a yawn. A champion. Yeah.
They call it our champion now.
They don't even want to
fuck with young Jedd check.
It's like you try spelling it.
There's three people on the planet.
They could spell her last name.
How bout she broke her hand and was
throwing punches right up until the bell,
like she didn't have a broken hand.
She's awesome, man. She's a beast.
She's a beast and she's arguably one of
the most technical strikers in him and
made today. I know. She's
so good. Without a doubt.
And then going back to the HollyRod thing,
I mean, Holly and Ronda are the two,
the two best in the world
on a 35 pound division.
Holly Holm fought the perfect
fight last night, man.
As you sit and just think about
it and run it through your head,
fought the perfect fight and there
was so much going on to Rhonda.
Didn't want to touch gloves.
Were there all the animosity and the land?
We Lady Gaga came out today and said,
that's what happens when
you don't touch clubs.
Lady Gaga should know cause
she's been fighting for years.
She's been crazy. Fucking Donald
Trump. No, that's crazy. That's,
that's how big this fight was.
When you really try to wrap your
head around how big this fight was,
Donald Trump, who is running for
president tweeted a nasty tweet at Ronda.
Tell us, hey, the between,
uh, he said, uh, he said,
I'm glad Ronda Rousey lost last night.
She's not a good person.
And to help Donald Trump's
plane apparently was pissed
because he came out and
said that Rhonda was
endorsing him for president.
And then Rhonda came out
and said she was not well,
she said she was endorsing
Bernie Sanders and she,
which is ridiculous cause
she's rich. Rhonda, Rhonda,
I love you. But Bernie Sanders is that
there's a lunatic socialists then yeah,
he's going to take your
money. Right. You've got too
much money. Go with Hillary.
Had them hunter post to that.
I'm pretty Sanders.
We'll take 90% of her wins as
soon as he's elected president.
He's got some ridiculous
ideas about wealth,
but I just can't imagine lady Gaga and
Donald Trump tweeting about an MMA fight.
Like how big this fight was this,
this fight broke every record we've ever
had from the venue to merchandise to
commercial paper view. Um, everything,
I mean, everything, the, the,
the numbers that are rolling in
are astronomical. Holly Holm has,
when we just took off, we took off
at 1230 in the afternoon. On Sunday.
No, on Monday, right?
It's Monday and yeah,
we just took off at 1230 in the afternoon
on Monday in Australia and Holly Holm
was still trending worldwide, number
one. And the NFL is going on right now.
And there were crazy games like
green bay lost, uh, again, the, the,
the Patriots barely beat, uh,
barely beat the giants with us.
Last second field goal with six seconds
left and Brady drove down the field with
a minute.
Let Holly Holm is still number one
trending worldwide will because it's so
stunning because he,
you've seen football a million times
when the ball goes across the line. Yeah.
But he gets crazy.
But to see someone like Rhonda Rousey,
a movie star, you know, the transcending
the world of mixed martial
arts get fucking head kicked
like that flat lined and
blood and the hammer fists like Whoa.
Just so stunning.
And when I think about Lady
Gaga and Donald Trump won,
the first thing that I was thinking when,
when we're talking about this was you and
I had been friends for a long time and
one of the first UFC that I came to
when we became friends was right after
September 11th in 2001 when Tito Ortiz
fought Vladimir Matt Yushchenko and you
guys went over the paper
view. So the, the what,
what happened was there was a cutoff of
three hour cutoff and when the cutoff
hit, the fight was still going
on. It had timed it wrong.
So then you guys had to
give a fuck load of money.
I wasn't even working for you back then.
Right.
I was just your friend
and we were hanging out.
We were drinking and that you
and Lorenzo and frank like Whoa,
he lost millions, millions who just like,
everybody was like, I was a bad one to,
everybody was like,
oh fuck at palms over the base who window.
So the paper view shut off with
two rounds left to the flight.
And uh,
so people,
people want their money back
and it was not that many paper.
If you buys back then, man, it was,
it was so fringe and I had to,
I felt a responsibility as
a fan to try to support it.
But there was no social media back then.
It was nothing you could do to support
it. I mean, there was nothing I could do.
I did. I talk about it in
the interviews, you know,
I go and do the Howard stern show
a talk about it. But that was,
they would put them on these fear factor
tours where he'd do these radio tours
and talk about UFC instead
of your backpack. I mean,
nobody even knew what it was and it
was like, it was so fringe back then.
But to go from that to,
here we are in 2015 and a fucking
guy who's running for president,
Donald Trump is tweeting about the
results of the fight in a catty way.
And I'm like, I'm glad she's
not a good person. He is.
He running is basically a front runner.
Right?
Well I think Ben Carson is for the
Republican Party bike guy doesn't have a
chance. He's a sleeper. I can't even
keep his eyes open when he's talking.
It's unbelievable. Well, I
don't know who has a chair.
I think they're both Jeb Bush is
probably the more likely candidate.
It's like wait for the dust to settle.
But just the fact that a guy running for
president is addressing mixed martial
arts, which, you know, we, we've, we,
you and I both talked about that
when we first got involved in it,
it was like talking about
being involved in porn.
True. Yes. It's, it's
crazy. And, and, uh, again,
just last night was
massive man last night.
It was massive when you
talk about it and all those,
all the people that were tweeting
about the fight before the fight,
Rhonda brings in this crowd of people
that don't normally watch you, I'm saying.
Yeah, sure. Definitely.
Well, John Wayne Parr,
who is a 10 time world Moitai champion,
he's a good buddy of mine.
He was at the fight yesterday.
He brought his daughter,
his daughter's a huge Ronda Rousey fan
and his daughter was so conflicted after
that fight was over because she's a
kickboxer herself. She loved kickboxing.
So on one hand, while
percent, yeah, she's 12,
she's 12 she's, she fights, she fights,
she fights, she's good. And last night,
great kid
felt bad because I was actually sitting
right next to her and she got bon on.
Come on, Rhonda. Let's go Rhonda.
And you know me, I want her to,
I'm not going to lie. I wanted to see
history get made. I like Ronda Rousey.
I like villains. I liked
the bad guys. I like an ego.
I want her to see history get made.
I was that close.
And I also know that it's good for Rhonda
and it's good for the UFC if Rhonda
finally has some competition.
And so I was cheering every
time Holly Atlanta to punch.
And when Holly landed that takedown,
I launched out of my seat.
I couldn't help myself and I felt sort
of bad cause she got con Rhonda Come on
Rhonda.
But me,
I selfishly just wanted to watch history
get made and I couldn't believe it when
it happened,
but I think it was great for her.
This 12 year old girl who loves
fighting to get the seed that you can do
anything, you can accomplish
anything with hard work.
And we got to hang out with the
guy that trained Holly before this.
And he said that Greg Jackson.
Yes.
Greg said that she trained so
hard every day that you know,
she was almost in tears every day,
training hard.
And that makes me so happy
because it just proves,
it sounds like hacky and redundant,
but hard work really pays off
in the sweat and the tears.
That's what it takes to
get good at anything.
So zero and then such a good point.
And one of the things Holly said that
was cool at the press conference last
night, she said, they
said, one of the guys that,
did you ever doubt that you could do
this? She goes, yeah, I doubted. She goes,
there were days at the
gym when I had a bad day,
and I just walk out and go in
my car and cry for 1520 minutes,
take an I can't do this. You know what I
mean? I, I look terrible in there today.
If this is the way I'm going to
fight, I'm not going to win. She goes,
then I'd go home,
I'd eat and relax and I go back at six
and work on everything that I wasn't good
at two hours earlier until I got it right.
You know,
and that goes with exactly what you're
saying is you can tell physically when
she went to the art dot,
she was shredded.
She had a six pack and I've
never seen her hand before.
I mean she looked in incredible
shape and she was also so poised,
even though obviously she was under a
tremendous amount of pressure and the
enormity of the moment wasn't,
it didn't escape her,
but she was bouncing around
and she would pace and bouts,
pace and bouncing pace and bounce.
I was watching her during Ron doesn't
entire insurance, which is, you know,
sitting that close to something that
you don't really get to see on TV.
That I had my camera,
my eyes focus directly on holiday,
on holiday the entire time Rhonda
was coming out and she was,
she was doing five steps,
bounce, go the other way, five
steps bounced when she was getting,
uh,
her mouthpiece put in when Rhonda
was stepping in. The octagon.
Holly was nothing but focus,
100% no distractions.
It was amazing to see
was a different kind of a focus because
it was a girl who's experienced that
kind of intense pressers
pressure situation before
that world title pressure.
Like when Batchko Hay was in
Brazil and she was facing Rhonda,
she had this look on her
face before that fight,
like she was about to go fight a
werewolf with a butter knife. You know?
She was just like, oh, I'll
put on a brave face. She,
she almost knew she was
going to get fucked up.
It was almost like the enormity
of the moment was just like, Ooh,
like you can't breathe. Like you
ever take a shower, a cold shower,
and you can't get, you can't breathe.
You just, that's how it looked like.
She was just overwhelmed.
That wasn't the case with holiday.
It wasn't the case at all. She was, she
was. She knew it was intense pressure.
She knew it was a big moment,
but she was prepared
for it.
She's back again.
How great should we do it now?
Oh yeah. All right. We'll do
this and we'll come back to
this. What are we at here?
We're at 33 minutes. All right.
Listen, Ladies and gentlemen,
I know you're like, oh,
it's only three, three minutes. How
could that be the whole podcast?
We're gonna eat.
We're going to have a little Vino.
Got a little Sharise and we'll be back.
Maybe I'll even grab Greg Jackson from
the cheap seats. Bring him up here.
See it a bit,
and we're back around to ladies and
gentlemen. I was just sitting there.
I was watching Birdman.
God Damn,
it's a good movie.
I got to stop listening to Howard Stern.
He was saying it was boring. The
fucking movie's Great. It's really good.
It's really good.
Howard was just jealous that somebody
successful at the bigger news than,
Oh, I get it. The bird. Is that what
you're saying? Okay, here we go. Ah,
we were just talking about whether
or not people get pissed at the,
the length of the podcast. Um, they don't,
I mean, they do, but they don't, you know,
it's like some people do, but
that's the UFC, right? I mean,
some people get pissed at everything.
It's like that about it. We have wheat,
wheat. I think we're unique in this
era and if you're putting out content,
if you putting out a,
anything you do in that,
there's too many people that have
opinions. Everybody can talk to you.
So it's hard to sample and get like an
accurate assessment of what's going on.
It's hard for me to live in a world now
where everybody gets to have an opinion.
How many times have you guys
had to deal with people? Say,
oh he's fucking cords or water down.
I'm tired of this fucking bullshit.
How's this guy's still floating?
What is, you have to, you know,
especially in this,
in this new world we're living,
you have to be able to tune that shit out,
man.
If I listen to the shit that you know,
the media or on or some of the
Weirdos on social media said,
this will be all fucked up.
Do you still fuck with
people on social media?
Cause you used to go back and
forth and get angry at people?
I don't get angry when
I'm on social media.
If I'm on there and I'm talking to people,
trust me. It's like I'm having fun.
I'm not angry.
I have time to kill me.
And me and a guy called fat boy,
you got into it today.
It's fat to wait for the morning
cause Nate, you call that boy. I said,
stick to what it looks like
you're good at eating. Um,
let me let me analyst.
But as one with him, uh,
he was saying that now that
women are fighting in the UFC,
I must be really desperate.
Like we're going out of business
and I must be really desperate.
What's funny is these people and
on social media, he says, uh,
he says to me, you know, he
obviously ripping on the UFC.
So I hit him back and I say,
where have you been living under a rock?
You know,
you don't know who Ronda Rousey is a,
you didn't know there was a Rhonda
Rousey, Holly Holm Fight. And uh, he says,
yeah, apparently a lot of people
live under a rock. Nobody,
nobody watches the UFC anymore.
Nobody would, you know,
something like that. I said,
listen,
why don't you stick to what it looks
like you're good at eating and then leave
the fighting of the day. He comes back
and says, I live in the same town.
You seem real tough over Twitter. Why
don't you come see that? Yes, exactly.
Flutter on the size on,
I'm easy to find fat boy.
Come find me. You know, just
like, but I have fun with it.
I'm not serious and I'm
not, you know, listen,
if you say stupid shit and I got some
time, I'll play. I'll go with you. I'll,
I'll do it.
It's fun for me.
I'm actually actually called Joel
recently and asked Joe what he thought of
rose.
Do you like rose and Joe
also very opinionated. Head does
not like rose at all and doesn't,
uh, like the type of comedy, I guess.
You know the type of people that would
row somebody that the front, yeah,
I like to watch it, but I don't like to
do artistic, this is mine. My personality.
Yeah. I'm, I have, I'm very extreme.
Either I go to war with you
or I'll go to war for you.
Either I love you or hate you.
I'm not, I'm not ambivalent.
So like if I loved you,
I don't want to mock you.
Ride this motherfucker.
This is the number one writer
for roasts in the country.
He didn't even know he
writes. He, he's one of the,
like the main writers for
all the comedy Central Roast.
If you hear like a good singer,
I'm not a comedy central roast.
It's absolutely brutal.
Most likely Tony Hinchcliffe wrote it,
but he's got that sense of humor.
My sense of humor is not Mike that I,
I feel bad if I make fun of somebody I
care about and if I don't care about you,
I don't want to be on a show with you.
You know,
if there was something like roasting Tony,
if I had a rose Tony on some think,
what does this ma'am, no thank
you. Your birthday. Don't mind.
90 gif coaches has their time.
Oh yeah, I don't eat that.
That's how I keep my girl is figure.
I'm trying to honey,
what does that lollies lollies. What is a
lolly? That's not a lolly. What is that?
It's a raspberry lonely a lot, but
it's, these are like gum drops. Yeah.
I'll let you put in Australia.
Oh, you call them lollies? Oh,
we call lollipops like it as a stick.
Yeah.
You said it was Molly tried to
get sex cause Exposito birthday.
Quantis look, you've got
16 hours. Don't be a pussy.
No. What can I have a cup of
coffee though, please? Just black.
Um, where were we? Roast a ballbuster.
Yeah, and Baltimore and guys,
not bustle bells is good but,
but if I wanted to go like he goes,
like Tony goes deep.
He writes so stealing shit like he does,
he writes the best jokes for rose.
He's just got this,
he's got everybody's personalities. Like
we were talking about this last night.
Like he's like a guy,
like he doesn't do this on stage,
but we're joking around and he,
he'll say puns like
ridiculous play on word puns.
My brain doesn't work like that.
And you know, there's different
comedic muscles. There's like cons,
there's roasting, there's staying
in the pocket, doing long bits.
Like when you do, you know, you'll talk
about the same topic for 10 minutes.
There's like different muscles, you know,
like I don't move around a lot on stage,
which it is something that
I sort of wish I could do.
I can't do impressions like
you can either, you know,
there's just different muscles and
stuff. It's sorta like, you know,
to use an analogy,
it's sort of like UFC fighters.
Like some people are good at some things
and sometimes the audience once those
certain things and uh, you got to know
which muscle to use against your opponent.
If your opponents, that
audience, that venue,
whether it's in Australia or Sweden or la,
you know?
Yeah. Just when it comes to like the
roasting thing, I enjoy watching it.
Like I go to cause a thing called roast
battle, but they do at the comedy store,
it's fucking hilarious.
They have to comics and
they'll go back and forth.
Like one person will tell a joke and the
other person will tell a joke and it's
fucking brutal. A rap battle for
comedy. Exactly. That's great. Cool.
These motherfuckers,
they steal years from each of those lives.
Like we've seen some who were like,
oh my God,
we have to sit back and hold your head
and you just feel the pain to the other
person.
I can't do that where I can't do that.
We're thinking about doing a
roast on fight pass, you know,
roasting different people.
Yeah. Oh that's your guy.
That's your guy.
I mean I've been literally not with his
second of hesitation if you said, yeah,
I need one guy to roast people.
I'd say Tony Hinchcliffe
wait before you'd say rose,
he ba 20 inch left before you even get
the word people out. I would say so
Tony is a huge crossover in there
because obviously you know, people,
you know the UFC in the
roasting is very close,
closely related in the way that if you
like watching people get slammed in real
life, you know, you'll love
to see them get verbally slam.
It all started cause I'm from Youngstown,
Ohio,
a tough neighborhood and I sorta defending
the little guy so I defended myself
with my words. So it's all sort of
in the same ballpark, you know? Yeah.
I'd love to help you out with
the UFC rose. That's easy. You,
he's your guy and Adam Hunter's good
attention. Yeah, I knew Adam with,
he's great with MMA to him because
he knows so much about MMA. You know,
he's very, very knowledgeable.
Yup. No, I talked to Adam off.
So you've got to do
something on fight pass.
We're talking about it with fighters.
Tony's a perfect guy to, cause they won't,
it will feel like they need
to beat his ass. I Dunno.
I Dunno how many fighters could
actually be roasted. I think that a lot.
Can I not do it? I can't tell
you how many guys get mad at me.
I point out like situations that
they're not necessarily the best dad or,
or skills that they may need to like
look into. Like they get mad at me.
So it was just an idea. It might not
even work, but I don't know how many,
how many fighters would
actually want to be roasted.
I think a lot of them have a great
sense of humor, I think. Yeah.
I think you'd be pretty surprised. I
think if they're from a different country,
like resilience, probably wouldn't
want to get made fun of that much.
Just thrown it out there like did.
I think it all depends on the culture,
but a lot of, uh, a lot of
Americans are into it. You know,
like I know that Brendan Shop, he's
like, it'd be great with things.
So many of those guys that I met.
What you need to do before you, uh, have
Cyborg, have our first fight in the UFC,
have Tony Roaster,
let's each still haunts me.
Still wants to be a part of the big show.
Yeah, that'd be amazing. I
don't even know where I'd begin.
Where would I start properly?
She's the only person that cuts the
weight by chopping off her deck.
Yeah, there'd be a, there'd be a lot of
different angles and you'd approach that.
I think it would be tough
for a fighter to do a,
Roche was sold back to the
Ronda Rousey Holly Holm thing.
Obviously you can't talk to Rhonda
right now because it's too, too soon.
It's too intense emotions.
She's probably just in agony right now,
but,
um,
how long do you wait before you
think about scheduling a rematch?
Yeah.
Well normally when fighters come off,
we'll fight like the Rhonda fight,
the Lawlor I'm Mcdonald's
fight. Uh, you know, you don't,
you don't even talk to them
about fighting for, uh,
the last core me a fight
with, uh, with uh, yeah,
it just, you just wait and, uh,
probably a month, about a month he
call and say, Hey, what's going on?
Really thinking how you feel
and you know, yup. You have
lunch with her and you
going to like talk car on
the phone or do you want to
do an in person? Rhonda? Yeah.
Yeah. You know, after this thing,
when Holly is going to be in a
fucking whirlwind, when she gets back,
she's going to be, you know, normally
she'd probably just get home.
We'd take some time off hanging
out with a, she's going to be on
radio tours, television. She's
going to have a lot of work to do.
Rhonda will be able to go home and
just chill out, relax for a while,
got her head together. He'll level
a little bit. Um, and then, um,
you know, I'll see her next
week in person and then, uh,
what I'm talking about fighting,
he won't talk about fighting next week.
You don't think she'll want to talk about
it immediately? No, no. If she does,
that's cool. She wants
to talk. We can talk,
but I won't talk to her about it and give
her a month. What will you talk about?
We say Divia how about the weather?
Just hang out,
have lunch with her and hang out with
her and see how she's feeling. So yeah,
she's doing, you know, um, yeah,
job is very weird, man,
because your job is,
you're not just a promoter
and a lot of ways,
like you have to be almost like a
counselor or like a psychologist in a way.
Deal with so many different egos
and personalities and quirky,
you know, that without a
doubt. Personal problems,
business problems, you
know, a lot of stuff.
We deal with a lot of stuff with the fire.
Well,
you do probably wouldn't go back to that.
When we were talking about
earlier that 2001 Vladimir, Matt,
you Shango Tito Ortiz fight like that
was when you guys were first started.
Did you ever imagine that you
would have this kind of role now?
Like what did you see the
role of a promoter being?
Because you're not just a promoter,
you're,
you're a promoter and a very
weird way cause you're a promoter,
but you're also like the main
personality behind the UFC.
Like you mean like when I checked into
the hotel yesterday called me Mr. White.
I'm like we're both bald but I'm not Mr.
White. Like you know what I'm saying?
Like if they say, oh this fight looking
guys coming in here, it must be Mr. White.
I see shit on social media where it says
you and I are turning into each other,
which is fucking photo.
That's true.
Yeah. You know what? When you
think of the term promoter,
most promoters are fucking now
secretary to fax machine. Right?
Seriously there, there's no
infrastructure there. There's no,
we're so different because not only
do we have 500 fighters under contract
at 300 and something employees
to employees, um, you know,
in a weird way, we're more like a media
company yet we promote fights. It's,
it's, it's, it's really morphed
into this weird thing. But you know,
a lot of this stuff, a lot of
the things is in the, in these,
in the growing pains of
building this business,
the relationships that you have have
with, with, with a lot of these guys.
You know,
there's some guys on the undercard said,
I've never even met before.
And then there's people that I'm really,
really close to. And, uh, and you
were saying it earlier, you know, you,
you learn to care about these people.
Um,
no people that are involved in
their lives and you become clubs.
Yeah. And you see them lose. Yeah.
And you know, and then there's,
there's so many times that,
you know,
two people go in and care about both
of them and somebody is going to win or
lose that night. You know, there are some
fights that I don't even want to watch.
You know, it's like shit, I don't
even want to watch this fight.
It's going to be one of these good
people are going to have to lose.
Yeah. And there's no way around
it. There's no way around.
And then there's times when I'm like
it out. It's the complete opposite to,
I mean, let's be honest, where I don't
have a great relationship with a guy,
you know, you know, there's a
parallel between you and me too.
And that there really wasn't a you before
you and there really wasn't that many
people doing commentary before me.
Like you don't,
you don't like a a normal promoter
in a sense that they think is by,
I mean you have, dawn came, it was like
only in America, but it's all, you know,
it's mostly showmanship and bullshit and,
and you just somehow another figured
out how to just be Dana White.
You know,
you've,
how do you do a member like some sort of
a conscious decision to not put on some
sort of fake professional attitude?
Or is that just not in you at all?
You know, you're, you're
you, you're the Ui new.
Like before you were famous.
See at the same dude,
thanks man. What we, what
we, I don't know man.
I don't know really how to explain it,
but
I just go in there and we put on
fights and we, you know, we've,
we've tried to put it on the best fights
that are available with, with the best
talent that we have for, for instance,
I believed that the Ronda Rousey,
Holly Holm fight was the fight.
But you get all these fucking
conspiracy Weirdos that, that,
that start talking about. All
anybody wants to say is, oh,
I want to see Dana White's
face after Holly Holm beat her.
And I want to see what he,
two women are going in there.
Rhonda and Holly are going in there.
Somebody's going to win and
somebody's going to lose. I mean,
anybody that's stupid enough to
fucking think that. I think, you know,
somebody could win forever or somebody
else couldn't win is ridiculous.
Or that Rhonda hasn't fought the best
competition available on his phone.
All the best girls in the world.
That 135 pounds.
We brought Holly Hollman.
Yeah,
it's just that made the wait time.
The wait Cyborg has had opportunity for
this fight.
All she has had to do was make the weight.
She hasn't tried it would that much
money on the line and all the things that
are going on.
Look at last night's event,
Holly Holm stepped up and
took the opportunity and won.
She won the fucking fight.
The opportunity was there for the
opportunity has been there for Cyborg this
whole time. Guaranteed. Oh,
get out there and said all that crazy
shit that they said and she die if she
made weight and all that
stuff that was going on.
What was Ronda supposed to go to?
One 45 or fight her to catch weight for
what Ron does. The 135 pound champion.
Like it or not, that's, that's her weight
division and that's where she fights.
There's plenty of women there. And I
felt like going into this next fight,
I saw the Misha Tate fight twice, saw that
fight, none of that finance, you know,
and, and yes, we did. We did set
that fight up as a contender fight,
you know what I mean? But I felt
like that wasn't the best fight.
That wasn't the best fight.
I felt we brought Holly Holm
and to fight Ronda Rousey.
And I felt like that was
the best fight to put on.
We're literally in a fucking meeting room.
We sit in this board room
all day and I'm like,
we got to make this Holly Holm fight,
man.
This is the fight you're going to
ask Lorenzo's. Exactly. Actually,
the way it went down.
This is the fucking girl.
This is the next big challenge for Ronda.
This girl is fucking tall.
She's got the heightened read advantage.
She fucking kicks. Uh, you know,
she stays on the outside.
Ron has never faced anybody like that.
This is the fight that make it,
not to mention the fact that she's
undefeated and she's got legit boxing
credentials. This is the
fight. And we did it.
Yeah. I mean, we're right now, it's
kind of funny because we're in a plane,
we're flying over the ocean,
and when we land,
it's the buzz just as kind of started,
I made it exploded,
but it's almost like a tidal wave.
And that tidal wave is just going to
reach all across social media and all
across television shows and radio shows.
And you know,
by the time we land,
it's going to be Monday morning,
all the morning radio shows are
going to be talking about this.
All the television shows are
That's when the party really begins.
And that's when the Holly Holm coming out
party really begins. True. And you know,
we're, we're right now, we're kind of
like sitting here while the fuse is lit.
I've been doing this for 15 years,
man. And let me tell you what,
anybody can beat anybody on any given day.
You know,
even even reporters and fans and even
you win this fight was first announced
Kevin Alley. He's like, I'm not flying
over there for a 15 second fight.
I think we'll be over in 15 seconds.
And you never, Freddie Roach
said in a lot of people said,
well I didn't think that Holly
was going to get destroyed,
but I thought that Amanda Nunez was
a more dangerous fight based on her
performance against Sarah McMahon cause
she smashed her man, knocked her down,
beat her up and I know she had beaten
up cats in Ghana and the first round,
although she got stopped later in the
route, I think cats, Donald stills
dangerous as fuck. She just made a
big rookie mistake. She's charged,
got caught in a scramble and you know
Rhonda is so nasty at catching those arm
bars and even in this fight she had been
tagged with all those fucking straight
lefts.
She had been rocked and she's still,
when they went to the ground she was a
immediately threatening with an arm bar.
She still has the best arm bar technique.
And Emma.
There was one part for a second where
she caught her on standby and grabbed it
like a crocodile and just, I don't
know what she was going to do with it,
but she fucking added trying
to take her down, had it.
She got Holly just kept fighting.
She got defensive and she just
kind of rolling out of it.
I think this is a,
this is a pivotal time for Rhonda
because she's a huge superstar.
She's a huge movie star.
She's a huge celebrity.
But what got her to that position as being
a great fighter and there's a balance
there somewhere and you've got
to find out where's the balance,
is the balance spending all this time
working on movies and all this other shit
and, or is the balance going
back to fucking rocky for
going to that cabin in the
woods and going, running up the
hills, the snow and you know,
and focusing on just fighting.
And that might be what she needs
to do now. I mean if she or,
or that's it, you know,
or figure out what it is.
I mean she's got enough money now and
assume she probably, if she's frugal,
it doesn't have to work again for the
rest of her life. She does. She doesn't.
Right?
So she has to decide what she wants to do.
Does she want to figure
out what rent wrong,
figure out what she could have done
better. Get back to the drawing board,
maybe work with some new coaches that
are going to work with her on kicks and
distancing and flip work or maybe figure
out some other ways to try to get Holly
down. Other than the collar
tie and and clenching. I mean,
she's the mentally strongest fucking
athlete I've ever met in my life when she
gets over this, this loss she's going
to, she's going to be a savage man.
I mean she was,
she was a maniac in a hard worker
when she was the best in the world.
What's she going to be
like now that she lost?
And the thing that makes this
fight great again is Holly Holm.
Now everybody knows how talented Holly
Holm is and that Holly Holm is legit.
And Holly Holm is a workhorse to both
of these two are going to take the next
few months,
go back in and start working on shit,
and they're going to clash again and
there's second fight will be fucking
awesome. Does Rhonda have a broken jaw
because social media was reporting on?
That's what, that's bullshit. There's
nothing wrong with Rhonda, Rhonda. Well,
there's definitely something wrong
with it. Well, I mean, she's concussed.
She's heard.
He had a huge fucking cotton in her lip.
Her lip was split open and uh, I
was, I was there and I was like,
you know what? We don't want a
doctor. Someone that fucking lip.
What's lip going gonna look like at the,
so we brought in like the best plastic
surgeon and from Australia last night.
He came in late last night. Soder lip
over and her lip looks awesome today.
They do. When they do that,
did they do interior stitches?
So they do it from the inside out and
plastic surgeons are just so much better
than dockers. I'll give you an example.
In here. Something fucking crazy.
So at the last fight, um, when
we were at the core MBA fight,
Courtenay Gustafsson sitting there and
my phone starts fucking ringing during
the fight and, uh, it's my sister in law,
so I pick up the phone during the fight
and my wife was on the phone going
fucking crazy. So we have, uh, uh, uh,
English massive two year old English
massive who jumped on my daughter and
ripped her ear off her head
in my house. How did he do it?
Fucking just jumped at his paw in it.
No teeth.
Watts ripped her ear in half
this way and then off the head.
So it was hanging by the thing here,
like by the bottom of the ear.
So how old's your daughter? My
daughter is nine. Oh my God. Yeah.
Nine years old.
Fucking dog rips her ear off during
the core me Gustafsson fight.
My wife is hysterical. Can't even
understand a word she's saying. So
I have to calm her down. What the fuck
is going on? Tell me what's happening.
And she tells me, I said,
okay, I grab doc d. Uh,
one of the doctors for the UFC,
he gets on the phone and calls Las Vegas.
The first thing he did is trying
to set up a doctor and I said,
I don't want a doctor. I want a plastic
surgeon. Get me a plastic surgeon.
He calls them his plastic surgeon.
They go to the hospital. Um,
they had to wait like an hour and a half.
So you can imagine the freaking out.
They got to wait an hour and a half
because they're waiting for the plastic.
But the plastic surgeon came and put her
ear back on and then fix the ear this
way,
sewed it back together.
My daughters ear looks
unbelievable because you can't
have a doctor do that kind
of shit because if you
have a doctor do it,
all he cares about is getting the fucking
ear back on. Not How it looks, you know,
but you cosmetically, it's like the doctor
will come in and Stitch Rhonda Slip,
but did Rhonda, his lip is going to look
weird. So when we do fights in Vegas,
there's a, there's a doctor named Dr
Shoe. I Dunno if you've ever met Dr Shoe.
He's a tall Asian guy with glasses.
He is the man when it comes to he's so
he sews up these cuts because as you
know, in fighting cuts are a big problem.
They have to be sewn up the right way,
not only cosmetically,
but if you're going to continue to fight,
you have to sell them up so that they
don't rip open all the time and getting a
lot of scar tissue under there and
things like that. So we're very,
very careful and stuff like that.
But if anything traumatic ever
happens to your kids or your wife,
you're looking for a plastic surgeon,
not a doctor.
What the fuck did you do to that? Doug?
Did you kill that dog is gone, Doug Bit.
Your daughter's here. Dog's gone. Yeah.
Ah, to kill that dog myself. I know.
It's crazy.
Fuck Great.
Massive too.
But he's the sweetest dog in the world.
Doug would never do any of that on.
My daughter had a buck,
an ice cream cone and the dog when I was
trying to get the ice cream cone and my
daughter said no, and the dog just
freaked out, man. At the end of the day,
even though it's a dog, it's a fucking
wild animal and went and they're just,
they're fucking nuts with food
and now when you have food there,
you could feed your dog,
feed your dog till he's full and then
you're sitting there eating food and the
dog is like looking, you know, he
wants some more fun. Wow. Look at this.
Hello fellas.
We're doing a podcast right now.
You guys circled Gerkin as
hanging out with just one way.
Good luck with that. This plane,
his playing is so bad ass.
Then it has two different levels.
There's 500 people on this plane,
1100 bags and there's actually a lounge
upstairs where people can hang out in
the lounge. He had, it's
like a little bar area.
He's Quantas flights are fucking
ridiculous. We're not great.
This is the first podcasts, by the way.
That's never been done in an actual pod.
Yeah,
we're in a pod and the pod that's
it might be right. Yeah. Everybody
else just does it in a room.
I says, well, how did it
become, it's from iPods, right?
I guess that's the
name, right? Yeah. Yeah.
I had to get done branding in everywhere.
Chocolate Dell had that crazy cut in his
lip after the rich Franklin fight and
now you can't even,
you can't even know that.
Yup. What's even crazier
is Robbie Lawler. Oh yeah.
We had Robbie Lawler's done
with a plastic surgeon too,
and actually the Jessica Penne a fight
when she fought. You want to on Jay check.
See her nose.
We flew her straight to la and she went
and saw the best plastic surgeon in La
and we got her nose fixed, so everybody,
next time you see Jessica Penne at,
you'll notice that her
nose looks phenomenal.
You look at that Gash and what that
looked like. If we sent her to a doctor,
she looked horrible.
Right now a doctor would have stitched
or stapled that thing together and she
would look terrible.
They sent her to the best plastic
surgeon in La and she looks phenomenal.
That's amazing. By the way, I
remember her nose after that fight.
I've seen snow men with better noses.
You son of a bitch. You had
one ready? He had one ready.
Can you know Kevin Ross is a Muay
Thai fighter from America. Great.
Great fighter fights for a lion
fight. He was uh, talking about how,
why he got 'em.
He got hit with some elbows and one
of his fights in Vegas and the, uh,
the doctor,
you staples and the doctor was so shitty.
He actually stapled like one of the
things was in the crease of the actual cut
instead of like pinching the cut
together to staple, went in the hole.
It was like this fucking guy was
blind or drunk. Now we know. What
people don't realize is
when you go to a doctor,
a doctor is not worried about how you're
going to look after. It's about healing.
Whatever is ready. I gotta
close this whole, I have to,
I have to fix this thing. It's like an
artist. He's not an artist. Exactly.
So when you go to see these
doctors and they give you stitches,
you are going to have a nasty scar. In
fact, I don't care who your doctor is.
That's a fact. That's the way it goes. And
they do that though. Can they fix that?
And they score a Redo it
with like a really good job
of playbook for like a girl
like Jessica panic.
It would cost her a ton of money to go do
it later and all this stuff. Fuck that.
Let's just get it.
They might not even work because like
there's going to be all that scar tissue
and healing from Yammer sutures and you
have to cut that out. Maybe. I don't know.
What am I? I'm just making shit up
that, listen, there's the eds, you know,
there's a completely different,
um,
angle to this thing now when dealing
with women, we have women who fight me.
You can't have Jessica Penne a
scar on her nose and stuff.
Like I said, we get a lot of shit. We take
care of a lot of people now with what,
it really comes down to it. You know,
we don't say, Hey, send Jessica Penne,
I over to some doctor in stitcher.
We sent her to the baddest plastic
surgeon in La and he fixed her nose,
sent Robbie Lawler to a guy who fixed
his lip chocolate doubt and his LePen
Rhonda and her lip,
which is broken.
We literally got the best plastic
surgeon in Australia, not,
not Melbourne. We've got the best
guy in Australia. Um, you know,
so we're, we're, we're pretty big on
the medical side with the fighters.
Yeah. I mean it's, it's,
it's gotta be like an incredibly difficult
job to do, to like stitch up, uh,
a cut like that and it makes sure
that it heals. And a nice theme,
clean line like that. You
know, my friend John Wayne par,
he was at the fights last night.
He's 10 time World Moy,
Thai champions and Australian guy.
He's had more than 300
stitches in his face,
in his face. That's crazy. With that.
Um, no thank you. Yeah.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
I saw this stuff.
We want you to hear what it's like
in first class people just to,
just to give you a little taste.
Knollies no chill clip. No,
I got some child. Anything
at all. I can get coffee.
Yeah.
Is there a blowjob?
I'm saying they didn't offer you that.
Oh yeah, it was, it was the guy though.
The guy, his name's Joe and it
was amazing by the way, but to
bed too.
It's really incredible though.
Like, like what you do.
It's amazing.
I grew up in and chose about to kill me.
I grew up a huge pro wrestling fan
and there's something about what Vince
Mcmahon has been able to accomplish with
the crazy circus that he's running and
turn it into a huge company with
tons of bands and watch every week,
even though it's all fake and you've
been able to fake or real life cause like
always say, great. I've always
admitted that on your show. What is it?
You're the only one that keeps
making it look, what does it to make?
Still fake always has been
bullshit. Right? Right. Just
like your game of Thrones.
Exactly.
What's wrong.
But it's amazing to me that you have
been able to accomplish what that with
reality,
like everything he did,
he wrote it out himself
and wrote scripts and has,
they have 2030 writers that
he pays six figures a year,
big time, more than six regular,
like lower middle six figures a year.
They all get paid to write that stuff
every week and you have been able to grow
this thing.
And I guess that's really like,
it's mind blowing because you
get those writers all day.
You're never going to do
what Conor McGregor can do.
Just on instinct. I have to,
I have this thing that reality is better
than any script you could ever. Right.
And, and, and that's the reason that you
see, so it's so real and it's so like,
like last night,
man,
you put on the fight with
the best fighters in the
world and reality is going to
happen, man. And when you see it,
it goes fucking global and electric
like it did last night, man.
Even triple h what? Aaa chip
me up last night and said, wow.
He goes, what? A show and want a shocker.
That's what triple h me with
last night. It's like, you know,
w w when you do have that reality and
it goes off like it went off last night,
it's, it's bigger than anything
you could ever write in.
What it does is it makes it so that
you never know what's going to happen.
Now people have to watch every fight
because people can hate and people can say
that they knew that home was going to win.
That's the biggest bigger.
It's bigger than this plane.
The amount of bullshit that
nobody knew that was going to go.
Even the people who bet on Holly
and had all this shit last night.
There's one reason, one reason only, that
they bet on holiday because of the odds.
Odds were so big. Why not take
a shot or they were her family
or a family or friend?
Hello.
Would that be more comfortable?
We're good. We're good.
No, he's, he's a Ninja. He's
an acrobat. You can flip.
These are all my people here.
No, no, we're good, but
thank you though. Thank you.
So nice hair. That was
a polite, strong arm.
She was trying to strong arm us up to the,
uh,
to the lounge and Joe shutters down.
That was dated. Get Low. Yeah, she
was definitely, that was her polite
way of saying you guys should go up.
Don't match. People want to sleep now.
Is that what, is sleep at like 10 in
the morning or something? Fucking time.
You have a, we're landing at six in the
morning and write, but what time is it?
What time is it in la? Well, it's
only 3:00 PM in Australia. Okay.
People want to go to sleep.
That's their fucking problem also.
That means it's the, but it's not. That
will be the middle of the night in Vegas.
In La is eight 28 20 La
and 3:20 PM in Australia.
I haven't been able to sleep
since I got here. I'm so confused.
I sleep like three hours a week.
I've got five in the morning.
I'll fall asleep and pill for
you, pal, if you want to take it.
Don't take sleeping pills,
man. I don't take them.
It's not only one you don't
do as a sleeping pills.
I want to be able to wake up at all.
Like I was in a hotel fire in San
Francisco in the middle of the night.
It was a, it was actually,
it wasn't a fire.
So people that set off the
fire extinguishers and it
filled the room up with
that smoke, you know, that, that fog
of those fire extinguishers green.
And it was four 30 in the morning. These
alarms went off. Plam Pam, Pam, Pam,
I got up,
didn't know what the fuck was going on.
I'm trying to shut my alarm
clock. Rob. We, no, no, I didn't.
But all the people that were
in the fucking hotel and
sleeping pills and it was
in San Francisco and he had this narrow
staircase and it's really hard to get
down the stairs. It's like
really narrow. And uh,
these people were walking like real slow
down the stairs and half of them were
fucking sleeping.
They're like waking up as it were walking.
They were all whacked
out on sleeping pills.
Cause a lot of people when they
stay in hotels or when they travel,
they'll take a sleeping
pill and it was dangerous.
It was dangerous to the point where I
was ready to start a fucking stampede.
I was like, like, like why
are you fuckers not running?
Like there's a alarm going off and
announcement saying the building's on fire
and you people are strolling down the
stair and half of them look like zombies.
And um,
um,
I've had some friends that have done
some shit when they on sleeping pills.
Like Kevin James,
Kevin James takes sleeping pills to like
cook himself dinner and doesn't realize
he cooked dinner and wake up in the
morning like, what the fuck is this?
And then someone has to tell him that he
cooked it. Like I'm not down with that.
I've seen some crazy. She had to
asleep and us. Man, what's funny,
I took one number. I told you on the
way here, I took one when I saw it,
a sleeping pill, I woke up,
my throat was so fucking so,
I dunno if I was snoring like a biester.
I don't know. I don't have
that. You usually don't have
a problem with sleeping.
And I figure if I'm not awake or if
not, I'm not sleeping. I'm awake,
I'll do something and then they'll
do something, tell him tired,
then I'll sleep and when I get back to la,
LP blacked out.
But I just work out and I'll deal
with it, you know? I don't know.
I'm not into
the drugs that I like that they're
like, uh, you know, they don't,
they don't incapacitate you like that.
I'm not into like,
I'm not in the sedatives. Right. Got It.
I'm just sleeping pills either. But if
I need to fall asleep on this flight,
I might go a couple rows back
and have Holly Holm kicked me in.
The neck is hard to judge.
She's not even on the flight.
She's probably still back in
Australia. Right? I think,
well she was trying to leave today.
She was supposed to stay a couple more
days and then she changed her mind and
want to leave today.
So I don't know if she got out or not.
Do you schedule fighters to leave a
couple of days after? So they can recover.
Yeah. You give the, the fighters on the
car to a couple of days that you still,
you'll see fighters
getting on all banged up.
And I was just always think after
you've had a fight, you should,
you should recite a couple
of days without a doubt,
without some people want to get right
home. Can't tell them what to do. Right.
Just imagine that like
after a brutal fight,
a year ahead would be so fucking swollen.
Everything you wouldn't want to get
on a plane like it is. It sucks.
And being on a plane when you're,
he knows his stuff.
It's true.
People don't really understand or
appreciate how fucking tough these human
beings really are, that compete. The FCA
man, these guys are so tough and girls,
it's, it's, it's, it's pretty fucking
spectacular how tough these people are.
When you were talking about the Robbie
Lawler and Rory Macdonald fight,
and after that fight,
Robbie Rory rather, uh,
tweeted a photo of his face like the
next day and his eyes were close shot and
his nose was fucked up.
And what's crazy about,
and he said that it was the greatest
night of his life. You know,
like that's how you know,
you're supposed to be a fighter.
That's it. Are there, they're
special people. They're
different than all of us, man.
We, uh, that's why I, when
I think about fighting,
these people are so special that
very few people can actually do it.
You know,
how many people can actually become a top
three fighter in the fucking world and
how many people can become a champion
and then hold the belt for any amount of
time? Very few people.
It's, they're very special.
And I think that's why as human beings,
we're sewing on a professional fighters.
You know, I always say that, that it
out findings in our fucking DNA and we,
and we just, we, we look at
fighters and we're like, Holy Shit,
that fucking guy is the
toughest dude in the world.
Or that girl is the toughest girl in the
world and why we put them on such a big
pedestal that they deserve to be.
But at the same time,
the craziest loneliest fucking,
you know,
Ronda Rousey loses one fight
and everybody turns on her.
So she had the Anderson Silva loses one
flight. He was never that fucking good.
Anyway, the 85 pound division isn't weak.
It's just, it's the craziest fucking,
yeah.
You know what that is is,
is people,
the people that are mean and nasty and
insulting after fights are the weakest
aspects of humanity.
They're the people that are scared and
terrified and they know they could never
do that. So when someone does
do that and falters they just,
because that's their own demons,
their own insecurity there
all the knowledge that they
could never do that in a
million years.
So when someone does it and fails,
all of their insecurities just come flying
out of their stupid fucking mouth or
their fingers.
That's what it is.
When when I went on Instagram last night
and Twitter and I was reading all that
means shit that people were typing about
Rhonda, I knew what the fuck that is.
That's the weakest aspects of humanity.
If we could pluck those
people out of our culture,
the world will be a way better place.
And if the people listening to this,
if you're one of those people you
need to fucking go for a walk,
recognize who you are because
that's why you did that.
That woman put at both of those women,
put everything that they are on the line
and for you to insult them after they
came up short. The reason why you're
doing that because you're a con,
you're a con of epic
proportions and there's no way
around that. There's no, no.
It might go up. You might actually know
something. No, you don't know shit. No,
you're a con because if you do no shit,
you would just look at it and you
would recognize the sacrifice and the,
the, the drama of it all and the danger
of it all and you would have respect for
them.
That's true.
So,
so well said and these special individuals
who want this fucking earth and go
out and fight in front of millions
of people and lay it all on the line.
You know,
and I've seen guys walk in
with the fucking belt and
an entourage go home and a
fucking ambulance and by
themselves since raise them. Yeah.
That's when they find out
who's really their friend.
But it all goes down. I mean,
how many fighters have developed
these gigantic entourage? It's like,
remember Mike Tyson in his
prime was buying everybody.
Look at Floyd Mayweather.
Floyd Mayweather is hanging around with a,
he's got a God damn army with them.
It's mainly parky out knocked him dad.
You know,
it's one of those guys knocked him dead.
All those dudes would disappear.
Everybody would disappear if he
went broke. Everybody would this.
As soon as he retires,
he has retired for what?
I don't believe it.
I think he'll be back.
I'll be back for at least one more fight.
Especially Manny Pacquiao started
talking about coming back.
Why wouldn't he come back and make
another hundred million dollars? Right?
But I think that this,
the cling ons and the hangers
on and the yes people,
there's some of the most dangerous
people for a fighter's ego because what a
fighter wants,
they want affirmation.
They don't want to like a reinforcement
of the love that they're missing,
which kind of leads them to
fighting in the first place.
And they surround themselves with all
these people that are boosting their ego
up. Those people are fucking dangerous
for you though. So I like, have you seen,
have you seen what Teddy Atlas is doing?
Teddy houses training Timothy
Bradley now. So amazing. He's,
he Bradley's last fight. You know,
we talked about, I can see it,
but you said it was awesome.
Phenomenal. Bradley looked fantastic,
but one of the best parts about it,
as Teddy Atlas said, no entourage,
no cell phones, no nothing. He doesn't
want music plan. No one's in there.
It's just him and him. They look at
each other, they go over technique,
they focus on the game plan. They focus
on what the work there has to be done.
And that's it.
You know,
Floyd Mayweather has got a goddamn circus
and he's counted and he could pull it
off with that surface.
Right? But the moment he can,
and those guys have to
go out and get real jobs.
It's a moment he finds out that
they weren't really his friends.
They were paid friends,
they were employed friends,
friends that were there to try to
boost his ego up. And there are only,
they're only occupation. It's like
they're, they're professional friends.
They're there to be Floyd
Mayweather, his friends. Yup.
Floyd is Floyd's good at the surface
though, you know, and all it,
the best Floyd had the circus, you
know, people weren't as interested. He,
he really took it to another level when,
when, when he was pretty boy Floyd,
nobody can, nobody can became
money. Mayweather. Everybody
cared. He's a wizard.
I mean, look, that's the same
thing with Rhonda. You know,
Lady Gaga doesn't fucking get it.
Like all these people don't get it.
Like half of what Rhonda does is
psychological, but half of it's marketing.
All that stuff is marketing. You
know, you talk all that crazy shit.
That's where you get all the money.
The money comes from what Conor
Mcgregor's doing, you know, Bill with, oh,
I don't like what Conor Mcgregor's doing.
Mixed martial arts is
supposed to be about respect,
but you got maybe 10
years if you're lucky.
But realistically the great fighters,
you'll get the great fighters,
they have like an eight year period
that they can operate at this incredibly
high rpm and then your body starts giving
out. You can't take any shots anymore.
Your fucking knees or bad,
your back goes bad,
you're next all fucked up at a
certain point in time, it fails you.
You have two things you're trying
to accomplish during that time.
You're trying to win. We're trying
to make as much money as they can.
And the best way to make as much
money is get people to pay attention.
And the best way to get people to pay
attention as to talk out gang. I Shit,
I'm going to tell you right now.
So I was laying in bed last night
after the fight, you know, and, and,
and Melbourne,
the fight was over around five something.
We were all back at our hotels by
nine. Um, the notorious was on,
have you seen
that is a fucking ratio man.
They literally ran five
episodes of it last night.
I laid in bed and watch five fucking
episodes back to back. I'm like,
Jesus Christ, this is really fucking
good. It's a good show. I mean it's,
it's unbelievable. They just follow
this kid around and it is compelling.
Great television.
He's a wizard and it's amazing because
it does this thing where either you fall
in love with them,
right?
And this goes for Mcgregor Mayweather
and Rousey at the fall in love with them
and you want to watch them retain their
chief in ship or you start to hate them
and you want to watch them lose. Either
way you're watching and it's beautiful.
And again,
you know,
pro wrestling
smeared as it is, the fact that it's
not real and this and that, you know,
that's definitely something that, you
know, they built their entire Moi.
Yeah. Pro Wrestling fans are going to
go crazy. That hear you say that. I,
I you hear what I call the fake that
time I had every crazy lunatic pro
wrestling fan on my
fucking Twitter for like
three weeks, man. Well, Tony, I did
a podcast and a, there's like, well,
there's only a few times
while I've gotten, like,
there's two times when I got like more
hate than anything I've ever done.
One of them was a,
when I said that Fallon Fox,
that man that became a woman
shouldn't be fighting women.
I got all the fucking progressive's and
social justice warriors coming after me
being a trans folk.
And the other time was when I said that
pro wrestling was retarded because Tony
and I did a podcast and I just
mocked him for about an hour.
I got all fucking tsunami of
misspelled tweets my way. Just,
Ooh. I was like, I was drowning in
misspelled tweets and I was like,
I just wanted to correct their
drug. The grammar, that's not your,
it's y o U Apostrophe,
r, e Fox. And I was like,
I got the same thing people were called.
Then there's these guys that
used to wrestle and guys
that have podcasts and all
these things that were on there.
And then, and then the stone cold,
Steve Austin came to my rescue.
So listen,
I don't think that he was saying
he said fake, but you know,
they don't know the work and that that's
that. And he didn't mean any disrespect.
You know, stone called had to come and
save me from all the fucking [inaudible].
That's what happens.
Fully did that for me.
Yeah. Mick Foley for the man,
everybody knows that it's fake.
Where they get super defensive and crazy
is if you say that they're not like
real athletes because they do like
every night. You know what I mean?
They do a different marina every night
and on Mondays it's filmed and then they
do pay per views on Sundays.
That's it.
The only thing that really
Ruckus is up the fans.
If you say that like those
guys aren't real app.
Well they,
it is a tough job.
Those guys put in some fucking
serious numbers. I mean,
how many days a year they go on the road?
Like that was one of the reasons why
Brock Lesnar decided that fighting in the
fucking UFC at the highest
level of the game, which one,
one previous MMA fight was
easier than doing pro wrestling.
That goes to show you how hard that,
that entertainment business has.
It's true,
man,
that they're on the road like 330 days
a year and a 230 days in here and wait,
no, three 30, I think it's three
30. It's a big number. It's a lot.
Most of the entire year.
And they're always in pain.
It's why a lot of them have pain,
pill problems.
Every one of the people over
at the WWE or fans of UFC.
And anytime I've ever had any type of
interaction with the WWE, you know,
uh, star, they're always really good
people. Really good people. Really Nice,
totally respectful,
just like the best people to deal with.
So I have nothing against
wrestling at all. Do you think cm
punk is ever going to actually
fight? I do. Yeah. So what
happened was he got hurt.
He hurt his shoulder and
he was fucking devastated.
He thought he was going to have to have
surgery and he did. And he actually,
he lucked out and got out with therapy.
And uh,
so he's went through his therapy and he's,
he's coming back now.
Tell them to go to doctor d to take them
to that guy in Vegas and get the stem
cells.
Oh my God.
Maybe I will tell him that you should get
stem cells in every part of your body.
Just do it. Trust me. The
greatest thing I've ever done,
I'm going back in December.
I'm just want to start shooting shit up.
Shoot my elbows up,
tuck it.
Duane Ludwig told me did that Dwayne
has hips done and shoulders done.
Didn't even need anything wrong.
Just just decided to just get stem
cells shot in there to heal things.
It's incredible.
This is total next level shit.
You were saying that that guy in Germany,
what's his name? Peter a Dr. Beard.
Rolling. Tell me, what was he saying about
the college and thing? Yeah, so they're,
they're working on this
thing over there were,
you know how testosterone replacement
therapy works. You know, as we get older,
our testosterone levels drop
and then they can, you know,
give you an injection and put this,
this testosterone back into your body,
make it feel younger, sex, life,
all these other things. Well.
Now what these guys are working
on is these collagen shots.
So they give you these injections of
Collagen and it replaces the college in
your body. Collagen is what keeps your
skin young and as we all get older,
it goes away and they did this thing,
I guess that they've been testing on this
10 year old rat and the rat looks like
a fucking rat.
Looks like a baby rat now.
So they're, they're literally right
now, I guess this shit's ready to go.
They're just building up
the infrastructure over
there because when they,
when this thing comes out and when
they announced this is going to be $1
trillion business, it's going
to be ridiculous. That was it.
They're injecting collagen
or the injecting something
that makes you regenerate
college. Again, don't take the fucking,
you know, I can't give you the, you know,
the scientific explanation of it,
but they basically came up with this thing
where you get these injections and it
makes you younger.
Again,
it's almost like replacing the Collagen
in your body and your wrinkles go away.
They go away and your face looks like
your face. Look when you were younger.
So ladies out there that
are banging your face,
it's all up with all this
crazy shit that they're doing.
A plastic surgeon and all this stuff.
I'd lay off and wait for this
stuff to come out. We're,
we're fucking year away from this APP and
hang in there gals. Just hang in there.
You know, it's interesting, we were
talking about testosterone replacement.
That's been one of the
biggest controversies in MMA
over the last few years was
that for a while the Nevada state athletic
commission was allowing testosterone
use exemption.
So if you guys got it and you know,
Vituro may be unfairly takes the brunt
of the criticism for that because his
results on testosterone,
we're so fucking spectacular when
you get an old guy like [inaudible]
who has all that experience and all that
knowledge and you give him testosterone
and his body performs like a young guys,
Bonnie.
But with all that knowledge
and all that experience,
you get what happened
in the Henderson fight,
the Bisping fight and the Rockhold fight.
We just looked fucking sensational.
But now, you know, now they pulled out,
they pulled the testosterone
use exemptions back and
these guys are trying to
force to try to compete and
like Mark Hunt, perfect example,
the first fight with bigfoot Silva,
uh,
and Mark Hunt was this crazy fucking
five round war and after the fight,
big foot test, positive or not positive
because we knew he was on TestTalks.
Steve was allowed to take it. He
actually, out of all the fucking people,
he's a guy that actually medically has
to take it and not because of his age,
because he has some type of
pituitary pituitary gland.
It causes gigantism look,
stops his body's production of a lot
of hormones and interrupts a lot of
hormones.
So he's the guy who actually really has
to take it or bad things can happen to
him.
And uh,
the problem was he took the shot the
week of the fight or two days before,
you're not supposed to do that.
You are not supposed to do that.
And the sad part is,
you know,
some of these doctors say it wouldn't
even help them at the time that he took it
to have that much in them. It wouldn't
even, we say that they say that,
but I don't think they know
because he, oh, that's the problem.
The problem became that if
you talk to fucking six guys,
they give you a six different answers.
And that's what started
to happen with this shit.
Nobody was really an expert on it.
Nobody really knew what it
would do or wouldn't do.
Then if you had two different,
if the commission had a doctor yet,
he was talking to his own doctor,
they would disagree on what the,
you know what I mean?
So,
and not to mention the fact
that if you have something good,
when testosterone first came out and said,
well this is going to be good.
You know, guys can replace
it and guys careers and this,
that and everything else.
But, but the other problem is is if
you have these guys who are like, well,
if this much is good for me, how
much is this going to do? Right?
So they're cheating on it.
So they're,
they're basically doing their hope camp
using so much that they might as well
beyond steroids.
Yeah.
Well they are on steroids. They're,
they're taking hyper human levels.
And that was what, what had
happened with Mark Hunt. But look,
the proof is in the pudding because
if you watch that Mark Hunt fight,
Mark Hunt hit big foot with everything,
but the fucking kitchen sink and big
fudges ate it. He ate it. This all,
and Mark Hunt's one of the
biggest knockout artists
in this sport and those two
went to war for five
rounds in the rematch.
Big Foot's awesome off the
testosterone replacement.
Mark Hunt hits him with one
clean right hand and drop it.
And Alex is big food is having
trouble taking his shirt off.
I know it sounds crazy, but like
it was like stumbling, taking,
it did look like he might have been
having problems with his shoulder or
something. Right. And Navy, Yeah.
Also just seemed a little bit of a slow
to come up the stairs and it's like
those aren't cutting weight, right?
No. Well maybe a little bit. Yeah.
Baltimore to 65 I think they both weighed
in at 65 and how they did cut weight,
but Hans said he didn't have to cut
weight for this cause he dropped a lot of
weight training.
He looked a lot leaner.
You look really good and you trade
with Mike Sweat over nick k by the way.
I couldn't be happier for him. Yeah, I
mean to dude. Good to see him succeed.
Good stuff.
Yeah.
The big filling on the scalp person,
he was slow,
slow in a few different ways and then
Mark Hunt was introduced and he came out
with this stuff already off.
Like I said this before
on one of your podcasts,
but I feel like you can learn a
lot about them during the way.
Yeah. So to tell them, look
into where everything relevant.
Yeah, it's everything.
You really do see
everything at the way end.
See, please. Psychological,
and I mentioned this,
I don't think I mentioned this in this
podcast, but maybe yesterday. I said,
if you look at the way in
between Rosie and home,
exactly what Rhonda did at the way in is
what she did in the fight or the second
she got off that scale.
She ran over to home.
He was standing her ground
in her place and rushed her.
I mean she really bum rushed or I think
harder than Rhonda has ever win for
anybody. Even her last fight when the lady
said about her dad's suicide, you know,
don't kill yourself or whatever.
She seemed more mad and
Holly Holm for what?
For drinking or drink and moving her hand
towards her a little bit like she bum
rushed her during the way and she did
exactly that way and exactly what she did
in the octagon.
Didn't you say that the way in
change the betting line? Yeah,
I did got changed.
The mind moved after the after the
way and moved and Holly's favorite.
Oh see yeah.
There's a lot of times the wins
tell you everything that's,
that's my second favorite day.
It's the day that you get to see
who's on wait, how do they stare down?
Does it either Guy Flinch?
Does either one of them budge?
Does somebody have trying to get the
mental edge? It just, it's, it's,
it's the fucking greatest day
of the week except for Saturday
to break it down even more.
I've watched the last four weigh ins of
Johana NJ check and this was the first
time that Valerie Laterno was the first
person that also put her head down and
matched up with the Ohio Mason. No,
Valerie did that at the on sale too. Yeah.
And it's basically saying,
let's fuck fucking,
I'm telling you dude,
your dad on fucking right
on it when we were in, uh,
whatever. I fucking luck when they
squared off a lot of, lot of the time,
my job is to make sure they don't touch
each other because when they touch each
other then people start
feeling disrespected and
whatever value return on laid
her fucking head right on top
of Joanna's at the item on sale.
When we came out of here for the onsite
and they switched their fucking nose to
nose and
I have to kind of gauge what's
going on there. So that shit doesn't
happen. And I felt that, that,
that they were both and I was
like, God damn, this is bad ass.
I just let it happen because
they both just did it, you know,
but you gotta be careful cause you'd let
guys do that and you'd get the core me
Joan situation. You know what
I mean? It's real tricky,
but you're dead on with what you're
saying. And even that was the day I said,
well the turnover is here to fucking
white man. And not only that,
but definitely a little bit more icing
on that cake when Johana and Laterno
we're heading the forehead. Johana was
talking and you asked her what she said,
but if you watched that again,
the allergies talking to and they're
just talking over each other,
both saying stuff.
She wasn't listening to you.
I know in your mind I
wasn't listening to her.
Craziest.
Well you don't want to said,
I told her yesterday is your lucky day
today and tomorrow on my lucky days have
some fucking creepy
fairytale hobbit type shit.
Can we just the same way asked for
them and they're too slow for me.
She's a dean.
I gave her cooking
theme and she's awesome.
And I think that like having these two
champions in the women's divisions and
both of them now or just he's
skilled killers, you know
both of them. I mean look,
Ronda was a skilled Keller
Holly Holmes or skilled Keller.
John is a skilled killer. These
are, there's a, there's so skillful.
It's like though the highest level
of MMA in the women's division is,
is like comparable to the highest
level of men's mmn. We absolutely,
I put you on a striking up with anybody
on the fucking planet that fights in MMA
six times. World Muay Thai
champion, clean, striking.
I mean she's obviously 115 pounds so
she's not dropping people dead like rumble
Johnson is,
but she is fucking nasty.
The first time I saw her I said she's my
favorite fighter and I make jokes about
one in the area and this and that.
Truth is,
I have a girlfriend who hates all this
Johana Mumbo jumbo when she reads it on
my Twitter. And a searching
what people are saying about me,
who's this Johana Nj check? Would you
really hook up at their this and that.
The truth is,
you know,
I make the jokes about Johana cause I
say I need a woman that will keep me in
line. She's really just my
favorite fighter. I love UFC.
I've been watching it since Gracie
was in the, there's something about,
he'll honas straight clear name
back that she draws Joanna. Yolanda,
Yolanda. I want to not Hannah.
Okay. Yolanda. Yolanda.
I mean just calling Joanna,
she's my favorite fight or the way that
she strikes and it's just fun to watch
it. There was a guy that through
four or five punches at a time,
all for the center of your nose. That
guy would be my favorite fighter. Yeah.
And then you look at Holly Holm obviously,
which would Holly did last
night was perfect. I mean,
she fought the perfect fight.
She didn't,
I mean there was nothing
amateurish about it.
Nothing clumsier slopping that was as
skillful as you could ever hope for in a
professional mixed martial arts fight.
And the way she took advantage
of Rhonda at end of that, the
exchange in the second round when you,
when when Rhonda was tired and she
slipped and she caught her with that punch
and then head kicked her. I mean that's,
it's perfect. It's perfect technique.
Everything was perfect.
So we have now in women's MMA,
we have the two representatives now in
the UFC there as skillful as anybody in
MMA.
It's true.
And then when you think about shaking
out the rest of that hundred 35 pound
division, you know, you, you,
you, you pair up any way you want.
Amanda, Misha, Julianna Pena,
just opinion. It's nice to have her back
to those four, those four women, you know,
in any mix and match that any
way you want. Well, you know,
the perception was that Rhonda was at the
top of the heap and everybody else was
just under skilled. But man, that,
that perception's been blown
wide open by Holly Holm now.
Now the whole game changes.
It just opens it, right?
It's like the same thing that happened
with buster Douglas knocked out Tyson and
then a Vander Holyfield came along and
knocked out buster Douglas. I mean,
the whole thing just more,
it just throws the paradigm into a
fucking turmoil. It's true. And you know,
the thing about having someone like a
Rhonda Rousey or like a Yawner is that
greatness beckons greatness when you
have one person at the top that is just
fantastic and spectacular and
has these incredible results.
All these people that are coming up,
they have this insanely
high level to aspire to.
And that's what makes mixed martial arts
so great in 2015 it's not a coincidence
that if you go back to 1993 and you look
at the level of the fighters and then
you look at it in 2015 there's just
a head and shoulders above everybody.
It's insight.
It's barely the same sport.
And the reason being is that slowly but
surely everybody aspired to the people
who are at the top.
And the people coming up got better
and better and better and better.
And that's how we have the
level that we have today.
And you're seeing that neared
now in the women's divisions,
and that's one of the most
exciting things about this room.
And it's that way, not only for the UFC,
but from life. You know what I mean?
Like sometimes I forget that until,
you know, I'll go once in a while,
a month or two without working
with you or you know, but like the,
there's only a few people left that I
watch. I do stand up comedy every night.
I work really hard for
the last nine years,
basically training every night to get as
good as I can yet. But when I see you,
Joey Diaz,
Bill Burr,
which are the only three people
left that I'll even watch it,
it's a straight shot of
adrenaline inspiration.
All of a sudden I'm riding harder
the next day I'm sleeping. Right.
Doing more things. The people, you know,
it's important to use inspiration to
your advantage for everything you know?
Well, human beings, all, we all
need other people to inspire us.
We all do.
It's one of the most in one of the most
important aspects of MMA is competition
and the competition in between.
So I,
these are not people that evolve in a
vacuum. They evolve looking at each other,
mirroring each other,
and also now one of the things that we've
said many times is that martial arts
is evolved more since 1993 when the UFC
was founded than they have in the past
10,000 years.
That's 100% true,
but really one of the reasons why
it's true is because you can see the
techniques.
You can actually watch them.
I remember when I was a kid in 1986 I
went to watch the World Cup in Colorado
Springs in taekwondo and I flew out there
and it was a giant turning point in my
taekwondo career because I
was, I was, I was really good.
I was winning like like good level
tournaments and I was doing well,
but in [inaudible] 86 when I went to
watch the best guys on the planet,
I came back 2030 40% better.
I was just way better.
I saw the top of the mountain.
And I think when,
when you get people that are
sitting in the crowd, you know,
you get these young contenders are
sitting there and they watch someone like
Holly Holm Dismantle Ronda Rousey did
watch someone like Chris Weidman knock out
Anderson Silva,
they watch Josie Aldo or Tj Dillashaw,
they Washington's fighters and they go
back to that gym and they're a different
fucking person.
Jay Go back to that gym when they
have the memory of that spectacular
performance in their head and
it just makes them rise up.
And I think also to people that don't
have anything to do with fighting,
don't watch that Holly Holm fight and
they'll wake up in the morning and they'll
go to their fucking yoga class
inspired, you know the, the,
we'll take spin classes, they'll go run
up hills there. They'll show up at work,
fucking fired up, ready to kick
some ass and get some shit done.
Yeah. And it's so true. Champions
should take something from this cause.
What's one thing in my opinion that
Anderson Silva has lost a Weidman,
the first one and this loss. Ronda
Rousey, Holly Holm have in common,
and I see you go Silva was
showboating when he caught that punch,
maybe he would have lost anyway,
but he was showboating he caught
it and it was over and I'm sorry,
but Rhonda was fighting with
pure ego yesterday. Her head,
her chin was out or hands were low.
She was just bum rushing.
It seemed like she just thought
she was gonna out cushion.
I think it was more desperation in ego,
but it's,
I think you're right in some ways,
but I think really instead of ego,
I think pressure is a better
thing to concentrate on the good.
I think both with Rhonda
and with Anderson,
many Anderson had the
pressure of everybody saying
he was the pound for pound,
greatest fighter of all time and he had
all these murderers coming up through
the ranks. Like why men, Yoel
Romero, all these Jocko Ray,
all these guys waiting in
line to get a shot at him.
And the pressure of that is just
overwhelming. But unlike Anderson,
or unlike Rhonda Rather Anderson
didn't have all these movie offers.
He's not constantly doing
television shows and,
and I mean he had some media obligations,
especially particularly in Brazil
where you idolize. But Ron,
Ron is on a totally different
level. Enough credit for is the
guy was fucking 37, 38 years old.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
People forgot and he was so good and so
talented to still be doing what he was
doing at the level he was doing it
at 37 years old is unbelievable.
Are you guys going to do vetoer
versus Anderson? I don't know.
That's the fight we're, I don't,
I don't, I don't disagree.
I love the fight. God
Vittoria into that. Uh,
I think Victoria is. Yes. When
does Anderson suspension go up?
Um, might be the first of the year. Oh,
that's our fight.
That's the fight.
Do you think they'll ever
be a time when marijuana is
allowed in, in the UFC? Well, marijuana,
these guys can do
whatever they want to do.
You can't do it the week of the fight.
Please not even legit.
Novitsky said,
it's like literally the day before the
fight now it's like you just can't fight,
whatever, whatever, whatever,
whatever it is that it's going to be out
of your system needs to be out of your
system by the fight. You can
do whatever you want. There's,
there's so many misconceptions
about how this thing goes down.
Oh Jon Jones can do cocaine,
but he,
John Jones tested positive or
lead paint out of competition.
Right out of competition.
Nick Diaz tested positive for
three times in competition wells.
The difference,
the problem with the last time though
was those two water tests that had him
below the threshold,
which are much more comprehensive test or
blood test and the one quest labs test,
which was a urine test,
had them above it.
So it's controversial what
happened in the last fight. Very,
that's why he's going
to do well in that deal.
Well that just that they're so out of
control that they would fucking banned him
for five years when they do that.
I mean,
it's one thing to find a guy or to
figure out some sort of a compromise,
community, service, whatever
the fuck you got to do.
But you're taking away the guy's career
five years when you're 20 is a long
time. Five years when you're
32 is a death sentence.
No, I agree. I agree. Well,
they lost their lawsuit against Vandelay
so Vandelay his suspension has been
lifted, right? I mean, or
if it hasn't been lifted,
their lifetime ban of him has been,
it's been thrown out by a judge.
Yes. I don't know. I'm, I'm, uh, I do
know that. I know he definitely, I mean,
I dunno whether or not the Nevada state
athletic commission is going to appeal
it, but I know that they did throw out
his lifetime ban. They haven't seen,
they haven't licensed him. I mean, it's
not like he can go back to work right now,
but if they just banned him
or gave him a suspension,
that was the same amount of time that
you would have gotten if you tested
positive for steroids. Especially
Vandelay had never tested positive before.
You know, and look vandelays
nope. You know, he's no saint.
Who knows what the fuck he had done?
Lee's in pride,
but the point is when
they were testing him,
he followed the guidelines,
at least in his term as far as when
they tested them and they banned him for
life one time he runs away from a
drug test. They ban it for life.
That's fucking crazy.
That's crazy, right? I mean,
I think someone needs to pull
those guys aside and go, look,
it's what you do is very important.
It's very important to have you there.
It's very important to have a voice
of authority. It's a very important,
important to have penalties for people
who violate the rules and cheat,
but it's also very important to have
some common decency and some compassion.
You can't take a legend
like Vandelay Silva,
a fucking mixed martial arts legend
and banned him for life. I that's,
I find that disgusting and,
and it's,
it's bad for them because
it makes them look bad.
I don't disagree with you.
It's not good for PR.
It's not good for how everybody,
I know they were mad at me because a,
I tweeted the phone number for the Nevada
state athletic commission after they
been Nick Diaz for five years and am like,
let everybody know like let them
know what you think about it,
but you have to understand what I did to
you was nothing in compared to what you
did to Nick Diaz. Nothing.
Not David. Yeah, I tweeted it.
I was going to eat it every day for
like a year, but I changed my mind.
I was like, I'm not helping anybody.
No, just change her number or whatever.
But the point being is that they didn't
take any consideration that to WIDA
tests,
which is fucked up and they abandoned
for five years and find them $160,000.
That's just crazy. Yeah.
It's too much money.
Chavez jr they find them 1 million bucks,
man.
What's it 1,000,900 and
something thousand for pot?
Yeah.
Oh my goodness. Let's see. Maybe,
maybe there should just be some matches
where the fighter and their opponent and
have to smoke pot and all of a sudden
they're doing crafts and stuff.
I know.
Crazy weed smoking dudes,
man, love your weed,
but don't smoke it two days before
the fight. Don't smoke it one day.
Keep it simple. Let's, well,
let's, let's play it safe.
Let's go two days before the fight.
Hold the word on Nick Diaz.
Was that the goal me fight that he tested
so high that he had to be high when he
was fighting me? Yeah. Yeah.
It's crazy. It's amazing.
It's one of those things where
like if you're in college,
you study for a test high that you
should take the test time and you know,
really? Yeah. I've never heard that.
Oh yeah. It's one of those like things,
I mean I cannot confirm before you guys
start tweeting at me that I don't know
my science,
you know,
I'm just saying I've heard this before
and that it's sort of makes sense to me.
So I mean, I don't know.
Maybe if nick trains,
I mean I know sometimes
I go on stage. Hi. Yeah.
And while I know what I do do is I work
out a lot of my material when I'm doing
a, like a late night spot at the comedy
store, I purposefully get high, you know,
it's like working out with ankle weights
on and then you do that stuff. So Bert,
you'll fucking slay a theater.
Oh my God,
your timing and beats are just impeccable
because I don't know, maybe like,
I don't know, maybe he trains high
so he feels like he has to fight.
There's been arguments like that when
it comes to testosterone replacement and
even though some performance enhancers
that if the two fighters had made an
agreement that they would both
allow the other person to do,
you know,
whatever amount of whatever that that
should be ethical on the lounge and then
instead of saying, you know all you're
cheating, it was just like saying,
you allow someone to me,
we all allow people to take multivitamins,
we allow them to take creatine,
we allow them to use cryotherapy,
chambers and all these things that
have shown to have a pretty significant
impact on recovery. Why
not allow them, you know,
to make an agreement like a steel cage
match, right. If all sign up for it.
Yeah, I know. I'd rather
fight a stone guy than, so
I say that you say that
you wouldn't want it.
I'd rather do Jujitsu with a guy who is
sober. Then a guy was high. When you,
when you get, I think I do Jujitsu
better when I'm high. I really do.
A lot of people do
lie to Jujitsu.
People do Jujitsu high, they train
high, they compete high. Super,
super common. The difference
is it's not striking. You know,
I know I'm better at eating and
watching movies when I'm high.
I wonder what's going to happen, Dana,
you know what you're talking about.
Things like this, a
doctor welling, you know,
coming out with this college and stuff
like when they start coming out with gene
therapy and all these different ways to
make your body young again and he'd get
a guy like v tour who is an old guy
with all this experience and all this
knowledge.
But you know that's,
that's the trade off in life
is that as you get older,
your body doesn't work as well.
So you might be a crafty old veteran,
but you got to conserve your energy more
because your body is just not capable
of the same kind of output.
But if you get a guy like Vito and then
you bring them to that doctor and he
does some wacky shit to his body
and all of a sudden he's got both,
he's got the knowledge and he's got the
youthful body. The whole sport gets very,
very different and very, very strange.
Yes. And that'll change all of sports,
not just fighting,
but the difference in basketball and MMA
is that in basketball you don't have a
finish like you had last night with
Holly Holm head kick and Ronda Rousey.
You have someone's slam dunking on you.
That's like the, you know, that's the pit,
the equivalent, you know, someone
shooting a three pointer in your face.
But like you said,
you have a guy who's really talented,
has the knowledge and how much laundry
for Jordan played, if you know, if,
if this what about now around
when he was here. Yeah.
It's going to be interesting. It's
definitely gonna change the scores. It is.
And you got to wonder, you know, this
stuff they're doing with stem cells,
they're regrowing cartilage.
People that have bone on
bone arthritis,
they inject them with stem cells and it
regrows Cartlidge it regrows meniscus
tissue.
It's insane.
So all these people that have these
chronic ailments and injuries,
they're going to be able to get those
things fixed and all the detrimental
effects of constant competition.
There is slowly but surely going to
be able to chip away at that stuff.
That's true. They're getting
rid of arthritis. Arthritis too.
It's the stuff that they're doing
out there now and those injections,
arthritis goes away. You
know, all these, I was Regena,
key nation in your body that's going on.
It's uh,
it's going to be fascinating to see how
this changes everything in the next 20
years. Yeah. And it's going
to be fascinating to see,
like what kind of regulations,
if any,
are they going to be able to establish
to keep up with that stuff because it's
way, even though, I mean, how would
you even know if a guy was doing that?
We'll Novitsky was telling me when he
did my podcast that there's an issue that
they're having now with,
they have testosterone that they've
developed through animals instead of like
the way they make artificial
testosterone award. Uh,
synthetic testosterone as they use wild
yams. I don't understand the processing,
but they use yams.
So when they use a carbon isotope test,
they can tell that the testosterone
that's in your body is not indogenous.
It's not created by your own body, but
with this animal shit, they can't tell.
So the testosterone they're
getting from like, I don't know,
wild boars are what the fuck
they using for the testosterone.
It's the same as the testosterone.
It's being cooked up,
write down little Tony's nuts,
nuts.
And what's crazy is
he was telling me that there's
this thing right now that you know,
those strips that you put on your tongue,
like a mountain, Washington, you know,
there's actually,
they have these trips that they're
putting on their tongue and uh,
it gives you all the
effects of, uh, you know,
like a growth hormone or,
or test Thomas Testosterone
injections or whatever it is,
and it's out of your system in 12 hours.
If you take that before you go in to work
out and you do your whole work out and
everything,
we'd get all the benefits of it and then
it's out of your system in 12 hours.
That's incredible. I mean,
that's incredible. They
call not microdosing. Right?
But it's,
these guys are there,
they're really playing Russian roulette
with the testing because they just
hoping they don't get nabbed
inside that 12 hour period.
That's why when the drug test show up,
they're showing up at your house at six
in the morning and you know, yeah, yeah.
It's, um, it's, it's really
interesting times because it's pretty,
it's been pretty clearly established that
at least the early days of the UFC and
the early days of pro,
well pride period,
there was a lot of performance enhancing
drug use. There was a lot of it,
you know,
off the record,
I've talked to guys who did it or in
pride or told me that everybody was doing
it and I'm on the record,
uh, NC in any way,
told me when he was on my podcast that
they had in the fucking contract gave him,
it said, we will not test for
steroids in the contract. And we,
but we know it when we watched watch
Vandelay at 218 pounds and you see all
these fucking guys who
were competing over there,
we kind of knew they were juiced up.
It's going to be interesting to see
the culture of the sport transition to,
you know, as clean as you can get it.
And you know, you guys have to take,
you guys have to be given credit for
that because you stepped up and you did
something that was very dangerous, very
dangerous for the product and it's very,
very,
very dangerous for the reputation of the
sport because as more of these people
keep getting popped,
like in your spending fucking billions
of dollars to do this and these guys are
getting popped work,
you could just do what the NFL does.
The NBA does kind of turn
a blind eye and you know,
no one's begging you to do this or
forcing you to do this. You know,
and I'm not sure if it's in the NFL or
major league baseball and one of them,
they get warned that they're
going to get tested. Yes.
They know that the test is coming. Um,
well that happens in college sports too.
I mean I've talked to guys who played
college ball and they say, hey,
Friday is going to be a test and
everybody's fucking drinking vinegar.
And you know, gallons of water and
trying to clear this year, right.
When you say this,
you know when you look at what we're
doing right now to clean the sport up,
you know we have contracts in place and
how many flights we have to deliver,
not just the television,
the paper view and you know all these
things that we have, we have contracts,
we have obligations.
Yeah,
we're going to spend $5 million
a year and testing and testing.
It could completely crippled the entire
business, but it's the right thing to do.
It's the right thing to
do. Yeah. I don't know Def,
I definitely don't think it's
going to cripple the business,
but I think it's definitely
going to figure it out.
If a guy gets tested and you know,
you get a big star and he's on something,
he's gone.
Isn't that a big problem too with camps
is that it's not like the NFL where they
have this like giant infrastructure
set up for, they know like,
I mean there's,
there's some variables when it comes to
strength and conditioning training when
in,
in in many professional sports,
but they have protocols that
are pretty clearly established.
Whereas in MMA there's a bunch
of different ways to do it.
And this guy's a competed a very high
level that have really wacky camp
environments. We like, you know,
this is not really the most
professional they're hanging out with.
Like that fucking guy that Anderson hangs
around with the guy from black houses,
60 year old guy who looks like Arnold
Schwarzenegger. You know what I mean?
I mean like, what do you
think that guy does? Oh,
nothing is fucking fruits and vegetables.
Steak and chicken. I mean, come on man,
I'm fucked. You guys choose to the
tits and, and no wonder, you know,
Anderson tested positive other than
the way he's hanging out with that guy.
Why would that guy tell him
the, the positive benefits
of steroids? You know, it's,
it's weird. It's weird and you
know, this sport is so big,
but has that aspect of it still
that there's, there's, you know,
it's not, it's not universe,
not across the board.
Like look at Kansas City royals
and the Los Angeles Dodgers.
How much fucking difference
is their training?
How much difference is there preparation?
I would say probably not nearly as much
as comparing someone who trains at Nova
Uniao or so on trains at AMC pankration
you know, I mean the variables and MMA,
they're pretty,
pretty stark.
Yeah, that's true. Um, and working now,
the training has to evolve. You
know, we're building this new campus,
basically building new offices and uh,
building a state of the art rehabilitation
center fighters and it's like the New
England patriots, right? If something
happens to Brady, they don't tell Brady,
see you later and come back,
go,
go do your surgery and all your stuff
and come back and let us know when you're
ready to play again. He's, they're there,
they're there making sure he's
doing therapy. He's got the best.
That's what we're going to start
doing it with the fighters and Vegas.
And how do you set something like that up?
Like who do you have running?
So we're actually taking a looking
at companies right now to come in,
you know,
we're going to find the best of the best.
This will literally be a state of the art.
Um,
the best in the World Rehab facility.
It's going to be insane.
And now we're going to have everything
of everything in there to Rehab.
We're going to have the, the, the, um,
therapist and trainers in there
to show people how to, you know,
how to get a lot of these guys.
A lot of these guys will go get an ACL
done and then not do the therapy when
they come back. And, and you might
as well not have to fucking surgery.
You have to go through the
physical therapy to get it
back and then you have to
keep working on that way, you know? Um,
and Conor Mcgregor,
that's what's so another fascinating,
his whole thing about movement,
human movement and flexibility and stuff.
He's very into that. He, you know, he
fought the Chad Mendez fight with them,
with really blown out knee,
um, to, what did he do for,
we did he get a stem cell shots?
So he went out to Germany and
got those shots and uh, Germany,
he went to Germany and in Ireland,
so he just went over to Germany
and got those shots. And uh,
he did some in California too. He did do
some in La too when he was out in Vegas.
Um, and that's all you
needed. You did that.
And he did his own physical therapy and
he brought the knee right back. Well,
that's what's incredible
credible about the stem cells
shed man to the regenerative,
regenerative potential for
stem cells is just incredible.
And they're just now
starting to tap into that.
And when it comes to sports
and rehabilitation, when
you're establishing this,
this place has this whole center, um, are,
are you going to establish like
strength and conditioning protocols to,
are you going to bring people in
for that kind of stuff as well?
Like and like movement specific,
like different guys who have Organon
certain things, different guys
who are grapplers were gone.
Certain things I don't dig where to
get into the striking and grappling.
That's not our area.
That's not our thing.
They can pick their own coaches
and who they'll work with them.
But I mean as far as like improved like
strength and conditioning aspects of
that body balanced, you know, proper
strength conditioning, stretch,
you know,
all the things that that um,
they're definitely not learning
at their jumps so much to learn.
You know what I mean?
You know,
there's a lot of coaches like
Edmond is a good example.
He's obviously good at holding
mitts and good at teaching. Rhonda,
the mechanics of throwing punches.
How much does he know
about defending gay teens?
How much does he know about the
transitions between boxing and grappling?
And we don't, you know,
we really don't know.
And I think the same can be said as far
as what are the requirements of your
sport when it comes to
strength and conditioning.
It's still kind of being
learned and everybody does
things differently for every
guy. Like GSP and thinks
you have to use gymnastics.
There's certain guys like fate or gave
up on all weights in any strength and
conditioning later in his career and
just did fight training. You know,
you look at John Jones right now who's
totally getting into all this power
lifting stuff. Um, have you seen some
of that stuff? Oh my God, he looks huge.
It's unbelievable. Shrek a freak of
nature. That guy is, he really is.
I'm hoping he straightened his head
out and comes back because when you,
when you want to talk about
just a spectacular talent,
I mean Jon Jones is probably
the most talented guy we've
ever seen in this sport.
I mean it is,
is,
he's just an incredible athlete and
what he's been able to do to top level
fighters like really early on in his
career is nothing short of amazing.
If he has a wake up call from all this
and just cuts the bullshit and focuses on
just, just taking advantage of
the prime cause he's in his prime,
he's in his prime, he's in his
prime. He's so big, so talented.
Such a gifted athlete. I mean,
you look at, like you said,
what he's done in the Fed and the sport.
Then you look at what he's doing now,
he just gets into power lifting and he's
benching 500 pounds and squat and dead
lift and 600 pounds. I mean, it's
crazy. And he could fight it.
Fucking heavyweight too, by the
way. Easy. He keeps powerlifting.
He's probably gonna have
to, I know, right? Yeah, but
it's just, it's, it's cool.
It looks like, it looks like he
is, he's doing the right thing now.
He's doing what he's supposed to
be doing for his community service.
It looks like he's working
hard in the gym, you know? Um,
it looks like his heads into it
and he likes it. And you know,
we were talking about
inspiration. Look, he's,
he's in camp now with the fucking
woman's bantamweight champ of the world.
Holly Holm is definitely going to give
Johnson inspiration because I know
they're close friends. Yeah. That's
cool. It's fucking awesome. I said,
I think we gave these people enough
and this bitch podcast on a plane. Oh,
we look at this. We did another hour
and 27 minutes. Shizam Holy Shit.
That two hours. Yeah. See Time
flies when we talked Dana White.
Good Lord. It's going to be the
first podcast you have to be on TV.
The one, one of those two, like I
said, changing the game. All right,
well this is the end of this. Thanks
brother. Appreciate it. Tony Hinchcliffe.
Say Goodbye to the people. Good by
people. Tony. Tony in each color.
One hour special. One shot coming soon.
My first special that might be on Netflix.
I mean that's what I heard. Uh, might
be, um, any more message to the fan.
Any word? Nothing. Anything
you want to say? Thanks. It
was, it was a historic night,
you know, uh, Rhonda Rousey versus Holly
Holm broke every record UFC ever had.
And thank you everybody.
We appreciate it.
Attendance pay per view buys everything.
Attendance.
The Eddie had a gross
record. Gate record. Um,
the, uh, the merge, the,
the commercial paper view.
Um, the paper views trending
well over a million buys. Um,
what else? I'm trying to think. I just,
there were so many records that were
broken that night. It was crazy.
Now here's the last question.
If you do do a rematch,
when do you think you would do, which
tried to do it for UFC 200 in July? Um,
I don't know. I, again, we got to see,
we've got to see where Ron does
that figured out. Yeah, I mean,
obviously that's like UFC 200 would be
awesome. That would be the move. Right?
Great. All right folks, that's it.
That's the end. Thank you. And Goodbye.
Oh, you still here? Well, if you are,
please enjoy the lovely sounds of Dana
White's snoring on the flight home from
Australia.