I start the video.
Um,
tell me what's up for folks who
would just hit me on Ustream.
You can just start
talking about Sam Harris.
A big,
big fight.
Islamophobia.
Okay,
well good experience.
Try my day.
Joe Rogan podcast by night all day.
What are those guys?
What does that neighborhood
like now discuss?
Is this you right here on the right.
That's me all the way over there.
But scan my legs disgusting.
And what were
his legs?
Which one of his legs?
That right there.
The Italians moved down to Charlotte.
Had money.
Guys are the union.
I'm Yulia Jorma teams
and make $24 an hour.
What?
I make up about 80 grand,
they go to Atlantic city.
I don't want that much.
I'm saying they all moved down the shore
and the rest is fucking like not even
killed but I'm Puerto Rican.
It's like El Salvadorian Hindus.
That's how it always goes.
It comes in waves.
Fucking crazy.
And then my grandparents,
it was all time and then it changed to
black and then it went from black and
Puerto Rican and they
went in from Puerto Rican,
Dominican,
Nicaragua and shit like that.
Delicious.
I'm on site twice the size.
It's giant.
Huge.
Almost too huge.
I thought it was almost to the month,
but then,
uh,
when I first got it,
I took it to England and
that was on the phone a lot,
like doing text messages
and emails and stuff.
And I was like,
this is a much better
experience for that much better.
I don't know how to shut it off.
So if everything,
so you were just a here just with
a hearing and Henner in Manchester,
right?
Yeah.
That was this guy's,
yeah.
Well I train with here on,
I know and Oh,
you training with him now
you would train Chris Harder,
is that who you're talking to?
And I was training with him and I'm a
black belt under here and in Henner and
then I kind of migrated to hearing
you the bad ass of the intellectuals.
Now when you go look
the skeptic conferences,
they have seminars.
Uh,
I,
I don't,
I don't think I've been to a
skeptic's conference since I started,
well,
I shouldn't say Steph skeptic conference,
I should say debate.
You know,
you've,
you've been in quite a few very
entertaining debates online,
um,
more atheist than skeptic,
right.
With the,
I,
there was one that you did
with this really smart dude.
It was really fascinating.
Um,
I believe he was a Jewish guy
and he was so passionate about,
about religion.
He was so passionate about
the intellectual pursuit
of religion and it was
really fascinating to
watch him like we've,
his dance,
like he tried to make it
seem like it made sense.
It clearly didn't,
but it was fascinating to watch him.
We've this dance and it was all pros
and delivery and drama and you put it
together in such an entertaining for,
you almost want to go with them.
Like God,
maybe.
Maybe there is a god.
Maybe the Bible's true.
I think you're talking
about a rabbi Wolpe yes,
that's exactly what I'm talking about.
Debate at twice,
once alone,
and once with Hitchins and it was Hitchins
and I against role hoping in another
rabbi.
You get accused of something
that I think is very fascinating.
You get accused of Islamophobia and
it's by liberals and progressives.
There's this new thing that's really
interesting to me that you can goof on
Christianity to the
fucking cows come home,
you can shit on Mormonism and polygamy
and any other cult Scientology.
You can goof on anything
and no one says a peep.
But if you say anything about Islam,
progressive people will
dean you Islamophobic and
they'll say there's something
wrong with you.
I think that's a really
interesting thing that we do.
And I show there's a lot of psychological
reasons because you know we're,
we're bombing them because here there's
less bendy right here and going back to
this and you've gotta I handle,
don't put your hand around.
Put It on this.
Okay.
And if you're going to
put your hand around,
go like this and squeeze
the fingers together.
You like that?
Oh,
not the small finger right here.
Yeah,
now it's squeezed them.
Okay,
now you're cutting the blood
spy off the thumb a little bit.
A little bit.
Okay.
This is a curl.
This is a rip curl and rip curl and rip.
And you get used to that.
And when you're cranking
guy's neck or choking him,
it doesn't slip.
If you squeeze the
thumb and also you know,
you,
you're going like this
and it might slip off.
Right.
But it's my slip.
Yeah,
but no,
not that finger.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now Curl and Rep.
So you feel like this is
more stable than I do of all.
Uh,
but uh,
I always see this this way.
Now you're going like this,
you're using your back to c and
you're pulling them in clothes.
It doesn't feel like
you smash your fingers.
Like this is the time.
But just,
just the thumb.
Squeeze the thumb.
Are you squeezing the thumb,
your theater,
getting red.
Now as you squeeze the
thumb and go like this,
that's a curl.
And this is a rep across his face.
I like that.
Huh?
Now do it the other side.
Yeah.
And go this way.
Now you're still working out
at the Machados or any of that.
Yeah.
And then he brought was to everybody.
I've been injured for a little bit about
how big of a neck injury and it just
got of time go car said to come by
our place of not to prove yourself,
you know,
just to go there and see the
place I used to have those days.
They are,
these are uh,
peer counseling.
Um,
I like to use these for
the hook because even for,
for kids,
I had also it teaches the,
um,
it just,
it,
it simulates a lot better cause I feel
the pad when you're hitting something,
I'm holding the myths,
but they can actually see
the power in this one.
So when I teach it,
I teach you like the karate kid hook.
Even all my students do this.
So you didn't,
you know the credit kid when
he has a on the bow and the,
he was in the island and the guy was,
he had the drum thing,
right.
And everybody was doing it right.
So it's kind of like that because you're
spinning your hip and your whole hook
comes from your hip and your arm is
just a rope in your hand as a rock.
So I tell people,
visualize your hand being a rock.
I mean,
and you're harming a rope,
no power in your arm.
Your arm is relaxed,
your hand is tight,
and it all starts from your hip.
So just so just turns that way and
you spin it and you don't stop.
You go in this direction has almost
the same with the right hook,
but it's mainly the left took,
I teach that way.
So it's like a whip,
it's like a whip,
but you're hitting them with a rock
and most efficient use of movements.
And then,
and then the commitment is not there.
Like with a right hand,
if I throw it hard,
I'm giving the person my hip so
the wrestler could get my hip.
When I'm throwing my hook,
I'm trying my hip over
there on the way past,
I'm trying to hit their chin
from my hip's going here.
So even if it's a wrestler,
I just step out this way.
It's easier to defend a take down
cause I'll commit all the way.
Even taking my eyes off him cause
it's really hard to counter this hook.
He might grab her single
and I can step through,
but I want all my coat hook.
So when I'm did hooks I did it this way.
And then,
and when I,
when I teach them not coming back first,
the way I teach them to not pull back
first is have this guy tried to drop it
because you'll see a guy like
this and then they pulled back to,
so the hook every time.
But if you're out here more like I
used to have chuck find out here.
So then from here it says he steps in,
you can just turn it right over.
So if he's right here,
you don't pull it back first.
He can drill that.
Alright.
And so it's ascending,
it's going to get a network
connection with other second.
Okay,
great.
So this is easy.
Um,
yeah android APP is much
nicer than the iPhone is it?
Yeah.
Cause at first it was really annoying.
So that's gone.
So now if you go into your piggy bank,
okay,
wait a bit.
That's all right.
Don't phone.
So I go send.
That's all.
I liked the Samsung.
Thank you.
This is cool.
Now I can say,
so I say scan the Qr code this
most you heard that the um,
the mega is not as good as the galaxy.
You know that resolution is not as good.
It's actually the guts of the gs three,
a galaxy
guts.
It's not that good.
It's just big.
But I gotta copy George Dress.
You see how it says one,
three HC.
It's just to send me this in an easy way.
You could also copy
paste that in an email.
There's nothing secret about this.
It's like an email address.
Just your identifier.
And at one point I say 0.005
and said,
and asked me for a second password
because I'm trying to send money
and then you just wait a few seconds.
It's still sending on this side.
Oh,
thank you.
Okay.
Now this was not from
my phone to your phone.
This was from me to the bitcoin network.
From the Big Horn network to your phone.
So if you weren't,
Kuala Lumpur would have taken
the same amount of time.
Right?
Let's just mediated by the network.
Now tell me when you could
send $5 electronically to
some random person without
jumping through hoops
and taking seven days.
And I know this is a lot
more than paypal obviously,
but even as,
as to how it does such a better job.
And if I wanted to,
I want them to freeze this by the way.
No one,
oh no,
this is sitting on keys
or a wallet on this phone.
Also on the website to best as a backup.
Now,
if somebody wanted to buy more bitcoin,
how would they go about doing that?
Um,
two ways for Americans.
Probably the easiest one is you go to
coinbase.com I can write it down for you.
So Coinbase is a San Francisco company.
They work with the banks,
they're registered as
a money transmission.
They've done some of the regulation.
So connect via ACH,
direct debit to your bank account.
They'll do two small deposits to verify
that it's yours and you give them,
you know,
like paperworks.
And then once they've got that link up,
you say,
buy bitcoin $5,000 boom.
It's going to say,
this is the price we're going to get you.
It's going to debit your account in four
days and four days later your account
debits the dollar accounts,
and it's a bit coin appears in your
bitcoin account and the long time it takes
just because the dollar side is slow.
Then once you have it in Bitcoin,
you can send it to anywhere for 40 cents.
It's the standard say by,
it's great meeting you.
Thank you so much.
Can't wait to talk to you again.
The Joe Rogan experience.
Try my day.
Joe Rogan podcast by night all day.