You speak frequently
in your lectures about,
I guess the war between good and evil
or the struggle of life really is a
struggle between good and evil being at
the core of a conscious lived existence.
And I guess on that note,
if you were 100% certain
that there was no afterlife,
would you still be able to preach that
there's a positive meeting in life?
If you're 100% certain,
some atheists seem to be 100% certain
and yet they still preach that there's
some positive meaning to life,
would you be one of those
or would you turn into cane?
You know,
so cynical.
I think that,
well for as far as I'm concerned,
one of the things I learned from studying
20th century history is that like even
if the idea that even if you
take the most cynical of ideas,
let's say that life is irredeemable
suffering and perhaps isn't even justified
because of that,
it still seems to me that
you have an ethical duty,
let's say to live in a manner that
reduces that to the degree that that's
possible.
And so,
and I think that that can be
experienced as meaningful in some sense
independently of the transcendent context.
Now I don't exactly know how to strip
off the transcendent context because one
of the things I would say that's happened
to me is because I've spent so much
time looking at the horrible things
that people have done is that it's like
young said that he wanted,
this is one of his famous quotes.
He said,
no tree can reach up to heaven unless
its roots reached down to hell.
And so as I've dug deeper into
the depravity of human beings,
my sense of the possibility of
human beings has also grown.
What would you say in proportion and
until I've become convinced actually that
good is a more powerful force than evil,
even though evil is an
unbelievably powerful force.
And so I can't really
strip the transcended away.
Now whether what bearing that has
on eternity say on an afterlife?
I mean,
I,
I can't say anything about that.
The only thing I guess I can say is that
there are many things about being that
we don't understand in the least.
And we don't understand the nature of
consciousness or the nature of time.
So I,
I'm not,
I wouldn't despair about that,
but yes,
I think that life can still
be meaningful without,
without there being a
necessity of an afterlife.
So.