Four,
three,
two live.
Mr Brown,
how are you sir?
Great.
It's great to be here.
I have been enjoying your latest book,
but I do have to tell you,
I think you broke my brain with gage
symmetry.
I had to go over that about 30 or 40
times to try to figure out what that
means and how that works and.
Well,
it's amazing you did.
It breaks our brains.
I,
I put it in there in spite of the fact
that it's hard.
That part is hard,
but it is so central to the way we think
about the world nowadays.
So I thought I got to try and explain it
and I was.
I spent,
I broke my own brain trying to think of
ways to explain it and I figured people
wouldn't devote as much time as you did
to doing it is so.
It's so subtle that it's that many.
They'd even.
Physicists have a hard time in some ways
grasping the implications of it,
but it is so central.
The way we think about the universe.
I thought if I don't include it for the
inquiring mind like you then,
then I feel bad.
Just so baffling.
It is.
But you know,
it's one of the things that when I write
books,
I write,
I do most things for myself in a way
and,
and in every book I write,
I usually learn something [inaudible]
always when you're explaining stuff,
you'd suddenly.
Most teachers say the first time they
understand that anything is when they
teach it and gauge them,
you I'd never thought of really how to
explain it.
And I tried to explain to my editor,
which was great because she didn't know
any science and she kept not
understanding yet.
And,
and then I came up with this
explanation,
involve these chess boards,
which is still subtle,
but I realized afterwards it was kind of
neat because when I developed this
explanation for gates and mature,
I not only understood it in a new way,
but I realized,
Gee,
I now understood physically.
If I'd been.
If I'd had this explanation before I
could have predicted this higgs
mechanism and all the things I only seen
mathematically all come out of the
picture I gave,
so I loved that I was.
It's a new way for me to think about the
world that I didn't
before.
Well,
most of what you guys do is almost like
another language to someone like myself
and what would this seems to be.
This gauge symmetry seems to be a very
complicated word in an alien language.
Yeah,
everything it is,
but it nevertheless it.
It's so central and it's.
If you can picture the fact that it's
fundamental to nature and they're free.
If we really want to understand nature
at some level,
you got to grapple with it.
You know,
it's,
we're stuck with the world the way it
is.
It'd be great if it wasn't,
if it was a lot easier,
but what?
Because I think that's one of the more
fascinating things about it is that it's
so bizarre.
Well,
yeah.
In fact,
that's why it's the greatest story ever
told so far because it's bizarre and the
fact that it's bizarre and we've come
this far is amazing.
It's just amazing.
We could have come this far and a few
hundred years and it's kind of sad that
people don't realize because they cannot
stuck it.
All this myth and superstition and the
real world is so much more interesting.
It is unbelievably fascinating when you
delve into the world of quantum
mechanics and quantum physics and all
these bizarre things that are happening
far smaller than the eye can see.
You really realize it is kind of magic.
Well,
it seems like magic,
but the fact that that we get it at some
level is remarkable because with the
other thing I find that makes it magic
is when you realize that the world we
experience,
it's such an illusion that the real
world is so different.
And,
and I love telling the story of how we
got there because you see scientists are
biased and prejudiced and have,
you know,
they,
they know where they're going,
when it's even when it's wrong and,
but science can overcome those biases
and prejudices and drag us kicking and
screaming in the right direction and,
and that's why the story is neat,
but it's also lately I've been thinking
in terms of politics,
whites also need because we need that to
cut through the crap that we're hearing
about in Washington that same,
the same scientific methods that have
skeptical inquiry of reliance on
empirical evidence of testing,
of looking at many sources.
All those things are so essential for
the working right democracy,
but they're the same tools that have led
us to from just beginning to understand
how balls fall when you let them go,
to understanding the inner workings of
atoms,
Nuclei and how the universe came to be
and why we're here.
I just find it's the story so wonderful
that it's a shame.
More people don't appreciate it and the
best part is the so far part to me
because everyday the story gets better.
I'm like that other greatest story which
was written by illiterate peasants 2000
years ago and never changes because it
was just as boring as it is now.
And this one keeps changing and we're
surprised every day.
Well,
I think one of the things that's
important that you said is that
scientists sometimes have ego problems
and they have an idea where it's going
even if the evidence disproves them,
but that science corrects it.
So I think that using that explanation
or using that definition,
it sort of defines what's important
about it because human beings,
even the most brilliant ones are flawed
because we do have egos and we are just
people.
Yeah,
exactly.
And this story that I tell,
which is for me actually,
it was,
for me it was interesting cause I really
had to learn.
I thought I knew the history,
but of course when you write something
down you,
you suddenly realize you don't.
And I and I had to learn it more,
and you want wanna,
you want to take some of these people
and shake them and say,
look,
the solutions right here,
you got it.
Why are you waiting 20 minutes,
20 years,
you're looking in the wrong direction.
The example I was just thinking about
the other day and I was giving a talk.
I don't know if you ever saw this video
where you're supposed to look at these
people bouncing basketballs and and
you're and you're supposed to,
I'm going to ruin it for you and all
your listeners if they haven't a show
where you're,
where you're supposed to count the
basketballs and see many people are and
there's a guy walking between them and
an ape suit and a gorilla suit and you
never see them,
right?
You don't even see them because you're
so focused on the wrong thing.
And that's the way physics often
happens.
We're focused on.
We think the direction is one direction.
We're so focused on it.
We don't even realize the solution is
there before our very eyes.
And I think it's important because you
know,
people think that science,
you know,
is that scientists and science are the
same thing and they're not scientists or
ones.
The good thing about scientists that's
the good scientist is they're at least
willing to recognize in the end that
they're wrong.
So they have these preconceptions.
And the great thing about sciences that
trains us,
yeah,
there's these things,
we are central to our being,
but ultimately we realized we're wrong
and were willing to change our minds.
That's the difference between science
and religion really.
Is that.
Yeah,
we have biases.
Yeah.
We have prejudice.
We want to believe we really want to
believe just like the x files,
but eventually when nature tells us
otherwise,
we throw out those beliefs like
yesterday's newspaper.
That's why science is so neat now.
People that are listening to this and
probably going,
what is gauged cemetery?
Dude,
you just passed over that and you said
it was crazy.
Okay.
Is there a way that you could possibly
just.
Well,
I'll give a try.
We'll see how we do.
Okay.
So.
So it turns out that that there's a
fundamental principle in nature,
which,
which really was discovered by this
wonderful woman mathematician,
I mean your author who was,
who wasn't even allowed to get a job if
she would,
because she was a woman and the at the
turn of the century,
but she discovered so there's things we
say and we tell kids,
unfortunately schools,
energy is conserved and momentum is
because driven.
It sounds like the 10 commandments like
we come up with them because we liked
them and now we understand them
differently.
We understand that everything that is
conservative doesn't change in the
world,
is due to a fundamental symmetry of
nature.
So energy is conserved because we now
understand the laws of physics don't
change over time.
So as long as you it contest that the
laws of physics are two same tomorrow as
they are today,
than we know energy is concerned.
It's not something we take on faith.
It's a mathematical consequence of that
momentum.
Conservation is a consequence of the
fact that the laws of physics don't
change from place to place that they're
saying in this studio here as they would
be if we're having this conversation in
New York that seems reasonable,
and she showed mathematically it's the
case,
so there's a.
there's a famous,
everyone's experienced this who knows,
learned any physics,
conservation of charge,
you know the electric charge and any
system doesn't change magically
overtime.
That's a fundamental property of
electricity and magnetism.
You got certain amount of charge at the
beginning.
It's got to be the same at the end.
That's a consequence of the fact that
it's arbitrary.
There's a symmetry of nature that says,
you know Benjamin Franklin called
electrons negative,
negatively charged,
but it doesn't mean anything because I
could have called them positively
charged.
It's just an arbitrary definition.
If I changed every negative charge and
the world to positive charge and every
positive charge and negative charge,
everything would work the same way.
A symmetry of nature represents
something.
It doesn't change about nature.
When you make a change in the
definition,
so making every calling,
electrons positively charged,
protons negatively charged would not
make the world difference.
It's an arbitrary name.
Martians could call electrons,
positively charged and protons.
The negatively charged is nothing
fundamentally important about the word
positive charge.
It doesn't mean any different than a
negative charge.
So I could change every right now I
could make all neck,
I could change the charge on every
electron,
the universe and flip it is signed.
So every electron is negative.
Lead charged now,
but now suddenly I'm God and I make
every electron positively charged and
every make,
every proton negatively charged.
Nothing about the laws of physics will
change.
I don't understand that.
Why would,
why wouldn't it change?
I mean,
does.
Is there a function of them being
positive and negatively charged?
No,
it's just a name.
That's why it's so that I can call down
and down up and it wouldn't make any
noise you make with your mouth.
Yeah,
exactly.
So the name I give it is irrelevant.
Okay.
So it's not like you would change the
actual function of the electronic.
No,
no,
exactly.
I call it's,
it's electrically charged.
That's important.
Okay.
And it repels other,
other electrons because they have the
same electric charge that's important.
Right?
To electrically negative.
Charged particles repel.
Right.
But look,
if I made the both to positive charged
particles,
they'd also repel so,
so the.
So the physical consequences would not
change at all depending upon how I named
them.
I see.
Okay.
Now,
so the example I used in the book to try
and they sort of described that is a
chess board.
You Got White squares and black squares
and you and you know,
you played with the white chessman of
the Webinar.
If I changed all the white squares into
black squares and I rotated the board by
90 degrees it would look identical.
And if I changed the black players,
white players and white players,
the black players,
the game of chess would be identical.
Nothing would change about it.
So what's white and what's black is kind
of arbitrary,
right?
It doesn't matter.
Which is good because it kind of wasn't
than chess wouldn't be a fun game
because if you always had black you
might win.
If you always had white,
you might win,
but it's,
it's the same,
right?
Right.
So,
so I could change all white squares to
black squares and black squares,
two white squares and the game of chess
would not change.
So that's a symmetry of the chessboard
and that's like,
that's like electric charge,
white being negative or positive and
black being,
you know,
let's say I say white is negative and
black is positive.
If I switched all black to white or
negative positive,
nothing would change about the game of
chess.
If I switch negative to positive in the
universe,
nothing changes in the universe.
The game of life,
the game of physics would not change.
The rules wouldn't change.
The dynamics.
Everything would remain the same about
the universe.
So that you could sort of see even that
is not so easy.
I can tell from looking at your face,
it's already not so easy.
Okay,
but,
but you couldn't sort of accept that.
Yes.
Okay.
That's the easy part.
Okay,
so here's what gates symmetry says,
man,
this is really weird.
I can actually do better than that.
I can arbitrarily change each white
squares on a chess board to a black
square.
I can choose randomly which white scares
to change the black squares and I can
still make the game of chess the same if
I just have a rule book and the robot
tells me,
Oh,
if you're on that square,
you can do what you could have done if
it was a white square.
So if I have the rule book,
then it doesn't matter what color is the
squares are.
If I know I was in the square that used
to be white,
but I call it black and I look at and
say,
okay,
my my night can do this and that square,
but it couldn't do that.
So if I have a rule book,
then what?
Then I've arbitrarily free to change the
color of each square on a chess board.
As long as a rule book tells me what
I've done,
right.
That's,
that's electromagnetism because it turns
out electromagnetism as a symmetry that
says,
you know what,
I could change the definition of the
charge on electron here,
but in the next room differently.
So I could call this electron positive
and one negative and it wouldn't change
anything as long as they had a rule book
that told me that I made that change.
And how and how the electromagnetic
interaction would be the same as long as
I,
I'm free to change the definition of
what I call positive and negative charge
locally,
not globally.
That means I can do it differently here
and there as long as I have a rule book
that says,
you know what,
that electron used to be negative.
So it'll still repel this electron here,
even though I call it positive and I
call that negative.
I've changed locally the definition,
but I also changed the rules.
I understand that.
Okay,
now the need for the rule book.
Now it turns out that the rule book
really tells you it's a rule at each
point in space,
right?
It's a rule tells you what you can and
can't do at each point in space.
So we call that a function because the
function is a number or a rule at each
point in space.
A function at space is,
uh,
is,
is exactly that.
Well,
it turns out the function that does that
is the electromagnetic field.
If you ask what would be the
mathematical characteristics of a
quantity that would make sure the rules
remain the same no matter what I called
an electronic place to place and you
asked how I could write it down
mathematically,
it would have exactly the mathematical
form of the electromagnetic field,
the thing that that we call the electric
field or magnetic field.
The mathematics of it is precisely fixed
by being able to allow us to change the
definition of charge from place to place
in a way that doesn't change the
ultimate dynamics doesn't change the way
the world works.
It's prescribed by the mathematics of
the rule book is prescribed and the
mathematics of that rule book turns out
magically almost to be exactly the
mathematics of Maxwell's equations,
which are the equations of
electromagnetism.
Here's where it gets squirrely from it.
Why would you do that?
Why would you change the definitions?
Why would you need that rule book?
Well,
because I mean what it says is that
nature somehow as the symmetry,
it doesn't depend what will you don't
want to,
but it says nature.
Nature has designed itself such that the
definition of electric charge from place
to place is arbitrary.
It really came.
If you want to step back,
Einstein told us,
you know that length and time are kind
of relative to be.
They depend upon the observer and his
theory of general relativity actually
said,
I can define locally what my coordinate
system is,
what my length is,
what my time is.
I can define that arbitrarily locally
and it may differ from place to place.
My rulers could differ from place to
place but the war,
but the universe doesn't care because
there's this thing called the
gravitational field that takes into
account of that and nature has that
cemetery.
So it doesn't matter if I change the
rule book,
if I change the what I define as space
and time locally,
the universe behaves exactly the same.
So when you say by symmetry,
do you mean essentially there's a
balance that there's always going to be
an equal numbers of negatives and
positives and that's changed.
That's the functions of each one.
Well,
it balances itself out as well.
That's sort of a consequence.
It says
universe can't be charged and
ultimately.
But no,
it really says that that's.
That's a quality of nature,
that nature doesn't care about law.
Namely you.
That's a.
that's a label,
but nature has a symmetry in physics.
Symmetries are things when you make
changes,
they don't.
Then the object doesn't change.
Take a sphere.
Okay,
that's fair.
You can rotate it,
but it looks like a sphere.
No matter what rotation you make,
right?
That's a symmetry of the sphere.
That's why it's so beautiful in
mathematically is the same way.
I can take another quantity,
I'll call it electric charge at this
point and I can change it if you want to
say,
make a rotation and some internal space
and I can imagine an internal space of
positive and negative charges were part
of some continuum.
I make a rotation and nature doesn't
care about it.
It's a symmetry of the equations that
govern nature,
but it turns out the reason this is
important.
Let me step back again because your face
tells it all.
I wish people could see it.
They can.
Yeah.
And,
and,
and um,
so what we've discovered is that the
playing field determines the rules.
The characteristics of the playing
field's determine the roles.
If baseball,
if you played baseball and there were
five bases instead of for the rules will
be different.
If the distance between home plate and
first base was a mile,
the rules would be different.
If you had 25 out of feelers out in
Outfield,
it would be different.
Okay.
So the playing field determines the
rules,
right?
You can't.
Baseball will be very different game if
we played on a field that's different.
What we've discovered in nature as we
used to think the forces were kind of
fundamental,
you know,
Newton told us that goes man and all
that.
What we discovered is the thing that
really constrains what can happen in the
world is the playing field and the
characteristics of the playing field.
And for physicists,
what determines the characteristics of
the playing field are the symmetries of
that playing field.
In fact,
baseball,
the fact that it looks like a diamond is
a is a symmetry,
right?
I can.
The thing feel looks the same.
I could call first base,
home plate and home played first base if
I rotated the whole field,
right?
It determines in some sense that's the.
That's a characteristic of baseball that
sort of determines the rules of the
game.
Okay.
And what we've learned is what's really
fundamental in nature is the of that
playing field and what determines the
characteristics that playing fields are
the symmetries of nature,
the things that that demonstrate to us
that what we think is fundamental is
really just an arbitrary label like
electric charge isn't we've discovered
is an arbitrary label locally as well as
globally,
and that determines the whole nature of
the forces that can happen.
Once you say the electric charge is an
arbitrary thing in nature,
doesn't care what you call positive and
negative from here or Mars.
That determines the nature of the force
of what we call the electromagnetic
force.
It's completely prescribed and it turns
out that's true for all the forces of
nature.
The nature of gravity is determined as
Einstein showed by the fact that you can
change what I define as one meter here
and on Mars called one meter or
something else and nature doesn't care
what I label as a meter.
It turns out gravity takes that into
account and says what we define as
length is irrelevant.
The fundamental gravitational field is
due to a curvature of space that that is
independent of what we define as length
or time locally.
It's a weird thing,
but it's a property of space and time
that Einstein discovered for general
relativity.
We've discovered it for
electromagnetism.
It turns out all the forces of nature
respect that same kind of same kind of
mathematical symmetry,
that there's some quantity that you can
change in your equations.
I can change its definition and the
equations,
but the physics remains the same and the
nature of the equations this is
prescribed.
The mathematical form of the prescribe
equations is prescribed precisely by the
requirement that I can change.
In the case of electric charge.
That electric charge is arbitrary,
I can call an electron positive or
negative anywhere I want in space,
and the equations don't care.
That prescribes the fourth formula
equations.
They have to have a very particular
form,
a unique form,
and that unique for them happens to be
the form that it has now,
so you can say,
look,
it's an accident that really there's
something fundamental that the equations
have this form in low and we've
discovered this mathematical symmetry is
an accident or you can say that the
mathematical symmetry is fundamental.
It's a property of nature and it
prescribes the form of the kind of
forces that nature that the world.
Laos.
When you say that the,
the,
that it's fundamental that the
dissymmetry is fundamental.
Do you see this image?
Do you study like ecosystems?
Do you study?
Like I know about them but I'm an but do
you ever contemplate them?
When you thinking about theoretical
physics and when you,
do you ever look at like how these
animals sort of stay in balance in these
ecosystems when they're untouched?
Well,
I mean the mathematics of.
I mean that's the great thing about
physics.
About Science in general,
it's kind of like Hollywood,
if it works,
you copy it
and and so we often find the same
mathematical formalism plight,
a vastly different systems,
so there's a famous set of equations of
Predator and prey for ecosystems and
and,
and you can look at those equations and
they're the same kind of equations that
apply in many different systems and in,
in,
in oatmeal boiling and also it's amazing
how the same mathematics appears and
very different systems and we can
therefore use what we've learned in one
case to apply to another.
That's why we copy it because it works
so broadly.
It's amazing that very few equations
turn out to so broadly described so many
vastly different systems and Predator
prey relationships,
which is I think what you're talking
about in ecosystems,
how you know there's a in an evening
with plants as well.
I mean,
I mean like the full system.
Yeah.
Once you.
And it becomes more complicated when you
include more variables,
but physics of course is generally much
easier than many ecosystems.
That's why I do physics.
It's so much easier.
It's because it's really the low hanging
fruit nature and it's fun for you.
Well,
I know,
but,
but for most people listening to this is
probably 100 people that have driven
into trees by now.
Like what the fuck is this guy talking
about?
I'm glad there's people like you out
there that are.
They can feel good that the laws of
physics are independent of whether
they've run into the tree.
So feel good.
I'm sure that gives them great comfort.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's just the study of this is so it's
so taxing.
It is,
but you know,
that's okay.
I mean,
sure.
What,
what,
what sort of bothers me is that people
when they think it might be,
might be taxing.
They don't want to think about it,
but the interesting thing is that
doesn't apply in other areas of actually
so people can be.
They don't think they have to be or
Clapton to enjoy guitar music or pub or
Picasso to enjoy where paintings or,
or Shakespeare to enjoy place,
but somehow and all of that,
that's taxing in its own way.
Okay.
And the more you want.
Let's,
let's take Bach.
The more you understand music,
I'm sure the more you appreciate box,
Bach Cantatas,
all the different voices,
but I can enjoy just listening to it,
right?
And,
and,
but people say in every other activity
it's fine,
but when it comes to science they say,
Nah,
it's not easy for me.
I can't even touch it at all and what I
try and do in my books and a place to
say,
look,
there's things you don't have to master
it,
but,
and,
and so you may not know.
Master gave some of the most subtle and
complicated thing in all of modern
physics,
but you can still,
even if you skip that section of the
book,
there are still things in there.
You can appreciate it.
But how we understand the world that we
couldn't appreciate before and have that
orgasmic Aha experience that hey,
the world is different than I thought
and that's,
that's what's wonderful.
So you can appreciate science without
mastering.
It's sure it gates,
symmetry and things like that are
basically mathematical concepts.
So to talk about them in language
without math is always sort of verbose.
Well,
I think what's important about your
book,
I'm in chapter 10 or 11,
I think.
I think what's,
what's really important about it is not,
you're not speaking in layman's,
but you're also
not speaking in theoretical physicist
terms.
You're making a bridge.
Well,
yeah.
And,
and someone,
I think Richard,
a few people said nicely said about the
book that as they say,
they claimed as long would said,
I'm trying to make it simple but not
simpler than it can be.
Yes.
And I think the right way saying,
well,
but I think it's important to do that,
right?
I mean as it respects the reader,
because it doesn't,
you know,
it,
it says,
look,
you want to understand it,
okay,
here's,
here's what you need to know it,
understand it and here's how I can try
and explain it without math.
And you can puzzle through it and think
about it and eventually maybe get to
that Aha stage.
But,
or I could just say,
you know,
poof,
it all happened,
you know,
and then that's religion in a way.
But except the differences.
This as content religion doesn't
for people like me that have never
studied it.
When I read what you're doing in a read
what's been done and I read all of the
people out there that are trying to
decipher all this magical stuff out
there in the universe.
It's,
it's,
it's important to just to be aware that
this is going on because I think for the
vast majority of the 7 billion people on
the planet,
this is just unknown exactly,
but it said it's being.
It's being discovered,
it's being contemplated,
it's being studied
and it's not just that it's being done,
but it's amazing.
It has changed our picture of our place
in the universe and therefore I think
science is like art and music and
literature.
It's they all serve the same purpose.
Science also produces technology and
somehow people think that's all.
Science is good for sure.
It produces the technology that's
making,
allowing you and I'd have this
conversation and people to listen as
long as you and I live longer,
all of the rest,
but the really neat thing about science
is it is just like those other things.
It changes our perspective of ourselves
and,
and that's what's so wonderful that I
once said that science is sort of one of
the purposes is to make people
uncomfortable.
And I thought I felt regretted that for
a while,
but it really isn't.
If you're never outside your comfort
zone,
then you're never,
you're never growing.
I completely agree.
And I love that quote in the book.
Um,
I think that for,
for a lot of people that discomfort is
just people are tired,
you know,
they work the jobs,
they've got families,
they've got a lot of stuff to do and
something like this comes along that
just like throws a monkey wrench into
the gears of the mind.
Yeah,
it does.
But sometimes you want your mind blown
and sometimes you know,
you can skim over or I try with him
books and say,
okay,
so that part you can get,
but,
but you know,
it's not like suddenly you won't
understand the rest of the book.
And the stuff is so neat.
The idea that there's this invisible
field everywhere in the universe that
changes the way you haven't got there,
the book yet.
But,
but that changes our picture of the
universe is amazing and people should
have the opportunity to know that our
picture is shown that we are a cosmic
accident that were just like an icicle
on a window,
that whose direction if you lived on
that icicle might seem very special to
you,
but as an accident and it turns out the
forces nature are what they are by the
same kind of accident because some field
froze in the early universe in some
direction.
If it had frozen in another direction,
you and I wouldn't be having this
conversation.
That's what we would we be a different
thing.
In fact,
in most cases you wouldn't even have you
and me because there wouldn't be
particles that have mass and you
wouldn't have stars and galaxies and
planets.
Now what?
There would be,
I can't say,
but I can definitely say that everything
we see in the universe would be gone.
But you're confident that it was an
accident at some point in time and what
I've created.
What I mean by accident.
No more of an accident or less of an
accident than an icicle.
On a window now,
if you look at icicles on a window with
they're beautiful patterns,
they're in all different directions now.
There's a physical reason ultimately why
one icicle forms in a,
in a given direction,
but there's no significance to that.
It may have been a dust particle that
caused that part that we're not saying
it's magic.
There was ultimately some micro physical
reason why that happened and why oatmeal
we'll boils a bubble up occurs in one
place and not another,
but,
but there's nothing significant about
that bubble popping up here or that
icicle pointing in a given direction.
It's not fate and not fate.
It's not designed right it anything is
possible in that icicle.
Okay,
and so what,
what I'm saying is our universe is the
way it is because of field frozen a
certain direction.
Now it's true.
There are laws of physics.
Say the field Kent can freeze in that
direction,
but it's also laws of physics.
Say the field could have frozen maybe in
another direction,
and if it did,
everything would be different.
Now what my field would,
how are you defining where the field is?
A Oh,
you had you gotta take him.
Yeah.
No,
no,
no.
I was worried about the field is.
Well,
it's like the electric field.
Okay.
Some quantity that's defined in each
point in space.
And,
and the neat thing in particle physics
is every field,
like an electric field,
every field is associated with an
elementary particle.
So the electric field is produced by a
coherent state of photons,
the ultimate Quanta of electromagnetism,
the,
the individual particles that are,
that are being,
that are going into your eye right now
and are being absorbed by your eyes.
So you can see me.
The reason you can see light is it's a
lot of little particles entering your
eye that had been that,
that are reflecting off my eyes so you
can see them.
Okay?
And it turns out in quantum mechanics,
every field,
which is a point which is a function of
points in space.
The electric field in this room,
there are,
there's a magnetic field in this room
because we're in the here in the.
In the earth has a magnetic field,
right?
If they put a compass here,
will feel the magnetic field that's
actually.
There's this coherent state of photons
that are basically very regular in
space.
That's really what a field is,
and quantum physics,
a very regular configuration of
elementary particles that are sort of
hidden in space and it turns out there's
this background fields we call the higgs
field,
which is everywhere in space and happens
to have a very particular configuration
and then when the particles that make
your body and my body up,
when we moved through it,
they experienced a resistance that
causes them to behave as if they have
mass.
If the field wasn't there,
the particles will be massless.
It's like swimming in molasses.
It's,
you know,
if you're swimming in water,
you feel pretty light,
but if I've filled the pool up with
molasses and you tried to do 100 meters,
you'd be pretty damn tired.
At the end of it,
you'd feel like you're weigh thousands
of pounds.
We're swimming through molasses.
We just don't see it.
It's amazing.
It's there.
I mean,
it sounds like,
as I was just saying to a group earlier
today,
it sounds like religion,
right?
I think there's an invisible field
everywhere that's responsible for our
existence.
That sounds like religion,
except for the fact in physics we can
say that's not good enough.
If it's there,
we got to find it and if it's there,
what do we do?
If that field is associated with
particles?
If I,
as I as I like to say,
it's cosmic sadomasochism.
If I spank the vacuum,
if I dumped enough energy and empty
space at a single point,
I should kick out real particles.
If that field is there,
if the higgs field is there,
if I dump enough energy and empty space,
I'll kick out real particles.
I'll call them Hicks particles,
and you know what?
Let me build a big machine in Geneva,
the biggest and most complicated machine
humans have ever built,
call it the large Hadron collider that
dumps enough energy into a point in
space that can maybe kick out higgs
particles of the really there and you
know what?
They're there.
On July Fourth,
2012,
we announced the discovery of 50
particles that looked and sounded and
walked and quack like Higgs is,
and we now have tested them much more
produced many more and they're they're
higgs particle.
They gives us evidence that that field
exists.
It was an outrageous and audacious claim
that the properties of the universe we
see are an accident due to this
background field that's there,
and if that background field wasn't
there,
the world would look very different.
It's an amazing claim,
but is it a consequence of this field or
an accident?
Well,
the properties of the universe we
experienced are consequences that field,
but that field being there is as much an
accident as an icicle freezing on a
window in a certain direction.
The field could have frozen with a
different value.
It could have frozen with a different
magnitude or if that's where I'm gone.
Well not just that.
It's very difficult for me to understand
why you can determine in one way or
another,
the field here.
Here.
Let me give you an example that I try
and use.
In fact,
it just got a version of it just got.
When I went online,
I used a beer bottle as an example.
You may have drunk beer once or twice in
your life.
I have.
Okay,
good.
I don't know if you've ever had a party.
I have.
And you forgot to put the beer in the
fridge.
So have done.
Put it in the freezer.
Okay.
So.
And then what happens?
You forget that it's in the freezer and
then.
And then the next morning you discovered
in the freezer explodes.
Explodes.
Got It.
Why?
Because really the,
the,
the beer would rather be frozen,
but when it's under pressure in the
bottle it's liquid.
Okay.
But for example,
if you open the top,
so the pressure is released and it's
suddenly freezes.
Okay.
The beer has changed from one state to
another.
It's gone from liquid to solid.
When it's gone to solid,
it's suddenly releases a lot of energy.
Okay.
If you wish,
you could think of the,
uh,
of the properties of that beer as a
field.
It can either be liquid or solid.
Okay.
And it changes depending upon the
temperature and the pressure and all the
rest,
it turns out the state of the universe
changes as the universe cools.
And you can think of that.
Higgs is like the,
as like a sort of a cosmic fluid that's
everywhere.
And as a universe cooled down,
suddenly it found would rather be in a
certain configuration.
It would rather be frozen in liquid.
Okay.
And at some numbers that tell you
whether it's acting like it's frozen or
liquid,
just like I could describe the beer and
I could define some numbers that would
tell me whether the beer was frozen or
liquid.
And so as the universe cooled,
that cosmic fluid,
which is everywhere,
all these elementary particles,
if you wish,
that are permeating space suddenly found
themselves preferring as the universe
cool down to be in a certain
configuration rather than another
configuration.
Okay.
Then it really is no different than the
arbitrary state of an icicle know
exactly.
It's just essentially as arbitrary.
It's not magic and it's not as if you
know,
if we in some sense the accidents of
what the dust that's on your window and
the wind that's blowing and everything
else is going to determine what that,
what that pattern looks like,
but every day if you had a new cold day,
the icicle pattern would look different.
Okay.
It's not as if every day you'd have the
same icicle pattern on your window.
It would be different and that's what I
mean by an accident.
It's not as if the laws of physics at
some level of couldn't have told you
that if you knew all the configurations
on that day why would look one way or
another,
but it's not significant.
I guess what I mean,
there's no special significance to that
pattern that meant God meant it to be
and there's no special significance to
the universe in which we live.
That meant God meant it to be.
It could have been quite different.
We should celebrate that.
It's not quite different because you and
I can have this conversation,
so it's a wonderful thing that it is the
way it is and let's celebrate that.
We're that we've evolved and I can still
say that word in this country.
We've evolved a consciousness so that we
can appreciate all of the wonders of the
universe.
Let's celebrate that so it doesn't mean
we're meaningless just because the
universe has no purpose.
We make our own purpose in our own life.
It means to me in some sense that life
is more purposeful.
There isn't someone pulling the strings
were pulling the strings,
and so it's okay to live in a
purposeless universe.
It doesn't make life worse.
It makes it much better.
We just always ascribed significance to
things that happened to us.
The physicist Richard Feynman used to,
used to go up to people and he used to
say,
you won't believe what happened to me
today.
You won't believe,
and people say,
why do you say absolutely nothing?
Okay?
Because when things happen to you,
suddenly they're significant.
You know what?
You have a million crazy dreams and then
one night you dream that your friend is
going to break their arm.
The next day they break their leg.
You Go,
Oh my God,
I'm clairvoyant.
You know?
Or he'll say that.
He'll say,
you know,
I just saw a license plate.
I,
you wouldn't believe I just saw a
license plate.
It wasj two,
four,
seven,
nine,
six.
Can you believe it?
Because you know,
that's a significant,
a single license plate that says one
one,
one or,
or a license plate that says,
I am God.
Okay?
They're all just as significant.
But the things that appear to mean
something to us suddenly take on some
significance because we're hardwired to
want to believe.
Just like the x file said,
we want to believe.
We all want to believe we are.
We're hard.
But well,
here's the reason we want to ascribe,
ascribe meaning to everything.
And I think there's an evolutionary
reason for that.
For example,
if you're a,
uh,
an early modern human on the Savanna in
Africa,
the leaves can be rustling in the trees
next to you.
You can say,
ah,
no reason,
or he can say maybe there's a lion there
and what happened was,
so maybe there's a line causing maybe
there's a cause for that happening now
that those of our potential ancestors
that said isn't a reason they got eaten,
the ones that didn't are the ones that
we produced.
Right?
Right.
And so in some sense we're kind of hard
wired by evolution to want to find
purpose and meaning and everything,
but isn't that just recognizing danger
or potential danger?
Of course it is in that case,
but,
but have side effect of anticipating
danger is to ascribe significance to
things that may not.
You're much luckier if you're much
luckier,
but you're much more likely to survive
if you ascribed significance to
everything.
Perhaps in the early days then if he was
grabbing significance to nothing.
But when you say,
when you're talking about significance,
essentially you're talking about divine
significance about it can be divine
significance,
but it can just be.
You can think there's more more to it
than meets the eye.
Right?
But when you're talking about
clairvoyance or when you talk about some
sort of a divine intervention by a
deity,
you're talking about something powerful.
This is the one that is meant to be the
leader of this tribe,
but that's the consequence,
right?
Yeah,
but it works at all levels.
It works at all levels,
from the fact that the leaves are
rustling and it means that line.
But once we have that hard wired thing,
then we want to be then our,
our,
our desire to believe continues and,
and,
and social beings may be found that if
they imposed some meaning on the
universe,
on a universe which otherwise is hostile
and dangerous,
that maybe it might help bind them in
tribes that maybe would help Mike make
them happier about being alive early on
because they might be so scared of a
universe that wants to kill them all the
time that it would bolden them.
So there's obviously an evolutionary
purpose to,
to what is religion,
because if there wasn't,
religions wouldn't be everywhere.
Right?
I mean pretty well.
All human cultures have religions.
Each one is inconsistent with every
other one.
But which was the reason we know that
they're probably all wrong,
but,
but it works the that it's universal,
must mean there's some evolutionary
utility to the believing,
but then certain things eventually,
even though they worked and were useful
early on,
as our human condition changes,
they may not be so useful.
Well,
that seems to be the place where we're
at now as a civilization.
Exactly.
I,
I would argue that religion is turning
out to be counterproductive.
Now it may have been useful early on in
human history,
but now what it's doing is it's getting
in the way,
not only of progress,
but have a few in cooperation and so
evolution is now is now
counterproductive.
But the great thing is we have,
we have a consciousness.
We have an intellect,
so we can actually overcome that
evolutionary predilection by realizing
we have that predilection and as as
firemen said,
that the easiest person to fool is
yourself.
So if you're a scientist,
what you have to do is ask yourself,
am I believing that?
Because I want to believer because
there's evidence.
So if we constantly are,
are skeptical of ourselves,
we can know to overcome that ingrained
impulse,
we have to want to believe that's one of
the utilities of science.
So I may listen to you and like you and
I may listen to another radio person and
not like them and I may be therefore
naturally willing to assume that they're
wrong and you're right.
But I should also say to myself,
is it really the case or is it just
because I like Joe Rogan and I don't
like,
you know,
you pick your favorite right wing nut,
right?
And,
and,
and so we should be asking ourselves,
okay,
maybe I should go beyond my
predilections,
me on my biases to ask why I am
sympathetic to what I'm hearing.
And if we did that in everyday life,
I think we cut through the crap more
carefully.
So science says,
look,
we are hardwired to want to have these
weird beliefs and it's fine.
Maybe some of them are right,
but the only way to know is to test
them.
If we're not willing to contest our
beliefs and subject them to that,
the test of nature,
then then we're going to be diluted and
that's the problem with that with a lot
of what's happening in our government.
People saying,
you know what,
I really want to believe in this absurd
story and therefore I refuse to accept
evolution.
If you're the.
If you're Mike Pence,
the vice president,
the country,
you say,
I don't believe evolution because I
don't.
It doesn't agree with my ridiculous
fundamentalist ideas.
And he said that in Congress,
right?
He said,
we shouldn't be teaching evolution in
schools.
We should be teaching intelligent design
and and why?
Because he,
he,
it,
it offends his personal faith.
Perhaps it might also be a political
ploy.
It might be a thing because he knows
that a large percentage of the country
finds comfort in a leader that
subscribes to the same sort of
superstitions that they do.
Yeah,
I,
that could be a.
He did this before.
He was in a national office.
He was a congressman.
I suspect he did it.
It sounds like he believed it,
but you're right.
Who knows,
right,
but at,
but the point is that we,
we,
we should realize that the only that,
that we shouldn't listen to that kind of
nonsense because we may not want,
because there are a lot of people in
this country who do think that evolution
directly confronts their belief in God
or the Big Bang directly confronts their
belief in God and therefore they don't
want their children to learn about that.
But what an awful thing to do to your
children to withhold evidence about how
the world really works because you know
you don't have to believe in the big
bang,
but it really happened.
You don't have to believe in evolution,
but it happened.
It's like Philip K,
Dick said,
the science fiction writer reality is
that which continues to exist.
Whether or not you believe in it,
okay,
and so you may not want to believe in
it,
but it happened.
And,
and for you to withhold that kind of
knowledge from your kids because you're
worried it's gonna Affect.
Their faith is,
in my opinion,
child abuse because you're hindering
their capabilities as an adult in a
society which is highly technological to
function effectively.
They're doing it because they believe in
as well and they need.
It's right.
I'm not believing they think they're
helping their kids,
but most of it,
I don't know if you're a parent.
I am.
We've all screwed up our kids,
right?
We all do things for our kids because we
think it's good for them and sometimes
it is and sometimes it isn't.
I'm not saying these people are doing it
because they.
They want to hurt their children.
They think somehow that not believing in
God makes you a bad person.
Right?
But there's no evidence of that.
In fact,
in fact,
Steve Weinberg,
who was a Nobel prize winning physicist
has said,
and I love it,
he,
he said,
so they're good people in the world.
They're bad people.
Good people do good things,
bad people do bad things.
When good people do bad things,
it's religion.
Do you think that religion in its
earliest stages was in a sense primitive
man with no science trying to figure out
the world and trying to have some sort
of rules like almost like a scaffolding
in order to to move to the next?
If you see that it exists in so many
different cultures,
it might have been something along the
course that way.
Was there effort.
It was their effort to understand the
world around them based on what they
knew it was noble.
You know,
they tried to understand the world and
so there's nothing wrong with it,
but claiming that we today should be
guided by the worldview of of illiterate
peasants in the Iron Age.
Peasants who who didn't know the earth
orbiting the sun and wrote down
scriptures based on their beliefs at the
time they argue that that should guide
our life.
Today when we discovered 100 billion
galaxies in the universe and discovered
all this stuff is ludicrous.
So you're absolutely the birth of
science and religion are the same and in
fact,
modern science grew out of religion.
People point that out and they send to
me,
how dare you talk about religion,
you know,
as,
as being outdated.
Science grew out of religion and I say
to them,
well that's fine,
but children outgrow their parents,
right?
So great.
No doubt.
Religious ideas and all our early
scientists were religious because it was
the only game in town you couldn't be
educated except the church controlled
all the universities and so it was like
the National Science Foundation of the
16th century.
It's not surprising they were all
religious because that's that the only
game in town so that,
that ca helped create the birth of
modern science.
But science outgrew it and that's okay.
Kids outgrow their parents.
Thank goodness.
Well,
I think maybe that might help kids
outgrow their parents.
Why the getting religion forced down
your throat is one of the best ways for
kids to,
for suggested as they get older.
Son,
for some kids,
kids like you and me.
But I get lots of letters.
You know,
we made this movie called the
unbelievers and and which followed
Richard Dawkins and I around the world
as we talked about this stuff.
And it was nice and maybe I,
and I hope and it's a,
it's a well made film.
I liked the filmmakers have made it,
but I found people come up to me,
I had no idea of this.
It's one of the negative aspects of
religion that I never appreciated.
I have people come up and he almost
everyday I write me and saying,
you know what?
I saw that movie and I realized I'm not
a bad person for asking questions and
I'm not alone.
You know,
these people from small towns in
Georgia,
they have no one to talk to.
They think that the only ones who's
asked the question is God real?
Is it okay to not believe in God?
And they're told by everyone else you'll
not only you'll go to hell,
but you're a bad person.
And suddenly they discover that's not
true.
And so I think there are a lot of people
who have that forced down their throats.
It's really hard when you're a kid,
you know and have these.
And that's why I do think any kind of
religion for kids,
it's kind of child abuse,
not a no matter what,
because these concepts have a daily and
the possible existence of a purpose of
the universe are very deep and subtle
concepts and expect a three year old kid
to,
to the ram that down a curial kid's
throat is unfair because the kid
candidate,
resident,
it ends up being internalized in ways.
And a lot of people,
you know,
I hear a lot of people who've had deep
religious educations who say,
you know,
it's hard to outgrow that because when
you get,
when that's thrust into you as a child,
it's really hard to over ever overcome
it.
The guilt feelings that many religions
introduce the fundamental notion that,
that you know,
you're ultimately sinful and no matter
what you do is sinful,
is something a lot of people have,
hard times within that claim of sin is
just so you know,
I've debated people who,
you know,
who argue that homosexuality is sinful,
and then,
and it's unnatural.
God intended it to be otherwise.
And then I pointed out,
well,
you know what,
you take all mammals,
10 percent in every species,
almost 10 percent have homosexual
relationships.
Sheep have long,
10 percent of sheep have longterm
homosexual relationships,
or they sinful.
Okay?
It's not a natural at all.
It's a natural consequence of whatever.
But now why it's a case,
it's an interesting evolution in
question,
but it's certainly not a natural and it
seems uniform than if it's 10 percent.
So.
Well being a plus or minus a little bit,
it certainly seems to be biology.
There's some purpose,
there's some,
there's some biological purpose to it.
And so to argue that it's both unnatural
and wrong is to misunderstand biology.
But people grow up being told it's evil
because the Bible said it right?
And then they don't want to give people
who are homosexual the same rights as
other people because they tell them,
they say God didn't want them to have
the officer.
So the problem is people are told these
things that are ultimately wrong because
you know,
maybe you know,
because for whatever reason,
the tribe that wrote down that that
scripture wanted to make sure that there
weren't homosexual relationships in the
group,
which just really
baffling when you talk to people about
the Bible in the Old Testament versus
the new testament and they don't even
understand where the new testament was
created by Constantine and a bunch of
bishops they throw up.
And by the way,
they think it's kinder,
gentler.
Sure.
The Old Testament is one of the most,
you know,
look at the current people say the
Qur'an is violent and vicious.
Read the Old Testament.
You know,
you're supposed to stone your kids if
they disobey you.
Yeah.
And,
and the reason killed people that were
two different kinds of clauses.
Exactly.
And the reason that nowadays,
sort of the Abrahamic religions of
Judaism and Christianity may seem a
little less violent than Islam for some
people is because,
you know,
people take the Quran literally,
and that's part of sort of
fundamentalist Islam.
Very few,
very few people take the Bible as
literally as namely,
Hey,
we're going to stone kids in the twelfth
century they may have,
but now we've outgrown it and the is 600
years younger and so it's just the old
testament is just as violent as the
Korean,
but no one takes it seriously.
But people,
most people who call themselves
religious,
they pick and choose the things they
like from the Bible or the New Testament
or the old testament.
They pick and choose the nice kindler,
gentler things.
You know,
Richard Dawkins Foundation in England
did an interesting survey.
Uh,
so they,
the British government does a census,
you know,
and,
and they,
they asked people's religions as part of
it.
And in the last census,
remarkably only 55 percent of the people
said they were Christian church,
Church of England,
which was one of the lowest ever but
fun.
They went to those 55 percent people.
They did a survey of those and they
said,
okay,
why do you call yourself Christian?
Do you believe in the Virgin birth?
Do you believe in transubstantiation?
Do believe in,
you know,
and went down the list and people say,
no,
no.
And then they'd ask,
why do you call yourself Christian?
And the answer was,
we'd like to think of ourselves as good
people,
so religion is usurped,
morality,
and somehow people throw out all of the
evil and it's not just the old
testament.
No one talks about hell more than Jesus
Christ.
Okay?
Jesus guy is supposed to love.
Everyone talked about hell.
This eternal damnation for people who
disobey,
as,
as Christopher hitchins used to say,
God is like a cosmic Saddam Hussein,
but worse because Saddam Hussein was
just torture his enemies while they're
alive,
God has worse.
He takes the people that I was liking,
torches them from all eternity.
Who wants such a God?
What an awful disgusting idea.
My wife bought the sauna thing.
You don't want to thing.
It's like a sauna suit.
You Zip it up and you hit these buttons
and it heats it up and heats your body
temperature up neat.
And it comes from China and it has this
hilarious instruction manual because
it's translated from Chinese to English
by people that are not.
I love.
Every time I read one of those manuals,
I love him.
It's unbelievable.
It's like make waste of body,
go away,
excels to fat,
disappear like very,
very strange stuff.
And she was laughing and she was
reading.
She handed it to me and I go,
well,
this is the problem with the Bible.
One of the big problems in the Bible is
translating from ancient Hebrew and
Aramaic.
And some cases we have not even hit the
Dead Sea Scrolls,
but ancient Hebrew,
the letters doubled his numbers.
So there was no number.
So when the letter a is the number one
and words also had numerical
value.
And when you think about,
I mean,
and this is,
if you've ever actually ever looked at
this,
and it's amazing.
So people say the Bible,
you know,
it's just the word of God.
But then realize that this came by.
In fact,
the King James version was decided by a
bunch of people who decided what to
throw out.
There were parts of the of their earlier
Bible they didn't like.
They threw out.
They determined what is now the Old
Testament in the King James version,
which was a bunch of people who got
together
and decided to throw things out and how
to translate things and what to do.
It was people just the word of God.
It's a bunch of a bunch of people.
Have you ever heard of John Marco
Allegro?
Mm.
Well,
I know a lot of people that want to
grow,
but grow is one of the scholars that was
a.
He was one of the people that was
deciphering the Dead Sea Scrolls and he
wrote a book in the 19 seventies called
the sacred mushroom and the cross.
Oh,
I've heard of the book is his
determination after 14 years of
deciphering the Dead Sea Scrolls at the
entire Christian religion was a massive
misunderstanding that it was really all
about consumption of psychedelic
mushrooms.
Fertility cults.
Yeah.
I've heard that.
I'm skeptical of that,
I should say,
but I'm skeptical of everything.
It's fascinating.
There are a lot of people who have
written really interesting books.
On the early history of,
of,
of the Christian religion and Judaism
and I,
you know,
I know a number of those scholars that
it's really fascinating.
In fact,
there's really great evidence that Jesus
wasn't even divide in the early
Christian,
right?
Mean his divinity came about 300 layers
later.
It's some really interesting work and,
and so,
uh,
religion is evolved and we now take it
as if it was sort of was obvious.
Apparently according to the books I've
been reading lately,
there's really good evidence that,
you know,
not only did Jesus never called himself
God,
his followers never did either.
And,
and the,
and this resurrection thing was put in
later when people want it to make him
divine.
Wow.
And so that's fascinating.
Again,
you could be skeptical about it.
We should be skeptical of everything.
But what's really amazing,
and this is what bothers me,
I wrote a piece for the New Yorker once.
It said all scientists should be
militant atheist.
Yeah.
You were really criticized for that.
Well,
I by some,
by some people and the first praised by
others.
Yeah.
But the real point is that people
criticized me,
never read the piece,
which often happens for my work because
there was the title and the editor chose
the title,
which is fine,
but I wasn't.
But what I said was when I simply asked
the question,
could it be that Jesus was.
You know what I just said,
could it be that Jesus wasn't always
considered divine in the Christian
religion?
You know,
a scholarly question.
When asked the question,
in many cases,
I'm called a militant atheist.
How dare you question our doctrine?
And I said,
if nothing should be,
should be above questioning,
nothing should in our society,
nothing should be sacred.
Everything should be open to question.
So if simply questioning makes me a
militant atheist than all scientists
should be melted atheist because we
should adore questioning.
And so I wasn't arguing,
you know,
we should be handing out pamphlets and I
said we should be asking questions.
And so the discussion you and I just had
would be viewed by some people and will
be viewed by some people as sinful
sacrilege.
A sacrilege should not be on the air,
should not be allowed to have that
discussion because how dare we
questioned the divinity of Jesus Christ
because after all he was God and to
question his divinity is to,
is to do the work of the devil,
and that's so sad because you know you
should be questioning
and it is fascinating where people draw
that line to whether they draw the line
at the new testament or whether they go
back to the old testament or whether
they even bought.
I mean,
how many people are believers in the
Dead Sea Scrolls?
I mean,
how many people have gone over the work
from Iran with a fine tooth comb?
Exactly,
but by the way,
I don't like the word believer.
I should say that I use it as well.
I think if you're a scientist,
you'd never use the word belief.
Something's likely or unlikely,
but that belief is not a part of the of.
If you really want to think of rational
inquiry,
of course you can have.
We all are colloquium.
We all have beliefs,
which means we have preconceptions,
but,
but really what we're saying is this is
highly likely based on what I think or
what I know before and,
and
learn something.
Does it make it more or less likely or I
respect that,
but if you're a Ta,
I use the word belief all the time,
but I try not to.
Okay.
It's one of those things like the word,
like I try not to use like in sentences
because people like use it like way too
much.
I just got to be a way.
If you go to high school now,
fucking kids.
Yeah.
Um,
but it's,
it is strange to me that people do draw
those arbitrary lines and when they
decide that doctrine is real,
like they'll tell you,
if you start talking to him about the
Old Testament and they're trying to be a
Christian apologist,
they'll say,
well,
we'll listen.
You're talking about the old testament
and we don't go by that.
We go by that thing.
That emperor of Rome created with a
bunch of bishops and he wasn't even
Christian himself until he was on his
deathbed.
Well,
you know exactly and people,
but people like to define themselves
and,
and I don't want to,
you know,
it sounds patronizing as if,
oh,
I'm,
you know,
we're better.
We all believe crazy things.
You and I also did.
We all were crazy leads.
You believe 10 in.
Well,
here's the,
here's what we all believe in impossible
things before we get up for breakfast as
Lewis Carroll would you say you believe
that you'd like to do is carol are a big
proponent of acid?
Probably when he wrote it may be maybe
there's lots of things,
but it doesn't matter.
The idea is interesting.
We all,
humans are not rational beings.
In order to make it through the day we
convince ourself of 10 impossible things
might be that you love your wife.
It might be that you like your job,
it might be what if you do love,
you live what you do,
love your wife,
Lynn.
You do love your jobs.
It,
that's not impossible,
but there are other things that you may
find.
You may find you.
You could pick it.
You know what I mean?
You know,
you might find that you,
that,
that I don't,
but do you believe anything weird?
I'm sure I do.
But you.
Do you ever explore it?
Of course I try some of the things I
probably,
I'm a human being so,
so I make it through the day.
Um,
I may convince myself I'm interesting.
Interesting.
Well that's nice but,
but,
but you know,
I thought you were interesting before I
met you and now you've confirmed it.
Oh good.
I was going to say,
now I know,
but,
but you know,
I,
let me put it this way,
make convincing myself I'm handsome and
sexy and whatever it is that we all
convince ourselves with one of you,
if you were in a room full of 100 year
old dudes,
you'd be handsome and sexy but it.
But exactly.
But if I'm in a room full of maybe not
100 year old dudes,
I may not have issues,
but no,
but bunch of male models.
So we don't have issues.
We say,
oh yeah,
those male models.
But they looked like,
but that's great.
That's great.
If you have your eyes wide open.
If you're,
if you're comfortable enough in the
world's going to end,
hopefully part of growing up,
part of becoming an adult is learning
that a lot of the ridiculous notions we
had are just that and getting
comfortable with that.
That's part of maturing I think so when
we were now more comfortable in our own
skin,
we're able to accept those,
but I bet when you were a teenager you
would have had a harder time saying,
you know,
all those other guys are better looking
and more interesting than me.
For sure.
Okay.
And so,
so that's part of growing up and that's
what science helps civilization do is
grow up.
That's a good point.
Yeah.
Boy,
do you think that any of those bizarre
beliefs are important at all to people
today?
Or do you think,
how do you think society would function
if we all abandoned religion and what
about the people that have included it
as part of the sort of,
again,
the scaffolding,
how they operate and this level who do
good things,
who there are people who are more
generous and give to charity because of
religion and help their neighbors and,
and go to,
you know,
at Christmas time go to soup kitchens
and all that.
There's no doubt that that happened.
And they generally do genuinely do
experience positive results from
solutely.
Absolutely.
So it's not as if religion breeds
badness in everyone,
but what people should realize,
it's not as if the lack of religion
breeds badness is everyone.
The question is,
is it necessary?
Right?
Altruism and kindness can exist on their
own.
Exactly.
So when,
so you can do all of that.
And I know people who go to soup
kitchens at Christmas,
I'm who are atheists.
The point is it's not necessary.
So for some people it helps.
I would argue that on average,
and this is where you can have a debate,
but on average I would say the net
effect of religion is negative and I
know colleagues of mine who some of whom
would disagree with me in that,
but I think if you look at the net
effect of religion on society and the
current world and maybe even over human
history,
the net effect is is is negative and I
would argue you could probably get many
of the same features if we dispense with
religion right now,
it'd be a problem because right now for
many people,
religion gives them a sense of
community,
of sense of belonging and maybe for a
sense of of of comfort it and death and
all sorts of things,
so we couldn't just sort of it.
It provides useful things.
As I said before,
it fulfills evolutionary purposes.
If it wasn't,
it wouldn't be so ubiquitous,
but I can imagine at least a world where
we could fulfill those things in other
ways.
For example,
instead of picking,
bringing people together for church
every Sunday,
we could bring them together for a rock
concert every Sunday.
Okay,
and they'd get the same sense committee
or maybe for quantum mechanics class
every Sunday,
but maybe they might find it fun if it
was we made a quantum leap,
but they'd find a central or maybe
they'd find a sense of community and
everyone rolling their eyes just like
you did now because I suspect that
happens in church a lot too.
For sure.
Will sunset sense of community is very
important to bond people and bring them
together and religion does it?
Yes,
but,
but the point is what bothers me is when
people say,
well,
therefore we need religion and the and
the answers may be now,
but could we imagine building a sense of
community because we care about our each
other and we have a commonality in other
ways.
That's another thing that makes science
so wonderful,
right?
I've called the large Hadron Collider,
the Gothic Cathedral,
a 21st century because the gothic
cathedrals were built in the 11th or
twelfth century by thousands of artisans
over centuries working together.
They had different languages,
different cultures,
different religions may be not so many
different religions back then,
but they work together.
This large Hadron collider is built by
10,000
scientists from over 100 different
countries with different languages,
different religions.
They're working together.
They have a commonality science really
much more effectively than religion.
I would argue binds people globally
because religions are still an US versus
them thing.
I'm Christian,
you're a Jew.
I'm Christian or Islam or you know,
whatever it is.
I'm Buddhist.
It's always us.
Versus them was science in principle.
It's anyone can do it and,
and we're all working towards a common
goal,
which is to understand how the universe
works.
It we're not,
we're not interested in,
in,
in pushing our own picture or joining
together to believe anything.
That's the other thing people think of
is,
Oh,
you know,
scientists push evolution because we all
get together and at night and with
special rings and talk to each other,
say we don't want wanna,
we don't want to believe anything else.
They don't realize if you're a
scientist,
the biggest way to become famous and
what we all do when we go into work
every day is try and prove our
colleagues wrong because that's how you
really make progress.
Hey,
something we thought was right is really
not what we thought it was.
Those are the great discoveries that
push people forward.
So it's not as if we all buy into the
same thing.
We're all trying to push knowledge
forward,
which means we're trying to discover
perhaps old biases and,
and overcome them.
And so scientists are bound together not
to push their own.
I mean,
of course we all have theories,
but we're all willing to throw them out
if the,
if,
if the theories are proven wrong and
we're all willing to celebrate being
wrong.
And,
and that's a wonderful thing.
And I,
I,
as I always,
if you're a theoretical physicist to two
favorite states to be enter either wrong
or confused because that's great because
then you're going to learn something
and,
and if we are more comfortable with not
knowing,
which is the other aspect,
I think that science for many people is,
is terrifying because if you're,
if you're deeply believe you know the
answers,
if you believe really believe there's a
god you can,
you can put aside that uncertainty.
And for many people,
uncertainty is terrifying,
but be comfortable with not knowing is
wonderful and moreover I would argue is
better for teachers and for parents.
You know,
your kids ask you questions and you
really want to always give them the
answer whether you know it or not,
but it'd be much better to say,
you know what?
I don't know.
Let's figure out if anyone knows this.
Because then they participate in the joy
of discovery.
They're not told something by some
authority.
And same with teachers.
I do think we should be teaching
questions rather than answers.
We should be teaching kids how to
question and then how to search for the
answers,
how to distinguish the wheat from the
chaff out,
how to distinguish the nonsense from the
sense,
especially in our society right now.
We used to,
we used to teach school is if it's just
a composite story of information,
now we know why I have in my phone.
I have more information than in school,
but also have more misinformation.
How do I tell the difference if the
process and that's it.
That's what we need to teach in school.
The process of skeptical inquiry,
relying on evidence,
checking many sources,
testing your ideas constantly.
Then we teach.
Those are the tools kids need to to deal
effectively in the modern world with a,
with an internet that's full of and and
with new sources which are equally full
of misinformation as well as information
and one of the biggest issues I think
that people are having with religion in
the 21st century is these areas where
you're not allowed to question and
explore that things hit.
These walls were this is God's will and
this is the way it is.
And in my mind,
what we say that is just code word for,
I don't want to think about it.
It's too confusing.
It's too complicated,
too terrifying to terrifying and,
and that and,
or people say,
and this amazes me,
people,
I get people,
religious people saying,
you will never understand the origin
years.
You'll never understand what love is.
Science will never ever explained love.
Science will never ever explained x or
will.
And then I say,
well that's incredibly pompous statement
because if you say that science will
never explain this,
you must understand it because how do
you know that will never explain it?
We never know what we won't be able to
explain until we try.
And maybe there are things about our
universe that will never understand,
but we don't know until we try.
You can never say upfront that science
will never explain this or that because
you haven't tried.
And in my experience as a scientist,
I've been,
you know,
I,
there could have been brick walls but
I've watched progressively those brick
walls crumble as we move around them or
we break them.
And it is so exhilarating.
And that's why it's the greatest story
ever told.
It's so exhilarating to see them knocked
down and things you thought we'd never
understand.
Or I remember one of the forces of
nature,
a very prominent physicists,
the 19 sixties or early 19 actually in
[inaudible],
69 said it will be a hundred years
before we discover,
understand this interaction.
Next year the theory came out and it's
so wonderful to see how the story
surmounts the biases and the
anticipation of individual scientists.
That's the greatest story ever told so
far.
Well,
what's ridiculous about saying no one
will ever figure anything out is that
what we figured out over the last 200
years is monumental.
And then human language has only been
around for 40,000.
Absolutely.
We live another 50,000
years.
100,000
As long as we don't.
As long as we keep open inquiry.
You could imagine moving.
I mean,
look,
we went through a few hundred years of
the Middle Ages where the incredible
inquiry based civil culture of the
Greeks was just forgotten.
I'm,
you know,
the Greeks had determined the
circumference of the earth.
Not only that it was round,
but what its circumference was by simple
measurements that were van not accepted
because of dogma.
So we have to,
if we want to progress,
we have to be aware of dogma.
How did they figure out the
circumference of the earth?
So it's really neat.
I think it was an aerostar guess I
forgot.
What year was the Greek.
Now it's amazing what he said was,
look,
so at a certain time of day,
in a certain time of the year,
the sun is directly overhead at 12 noon.
Okay.
And in my.
So.
And I can tell that by looking down a
deep well,
and I see the reflection of the sun
exactly in that deep well,
okay.
So the race and the sun which are coming
down in the same direction towards the
earth.
Everywhere it comes down to the deep
well,
but a hundred miles away the well
because the surface is curved,
the well is pointing a little bit
different direction.
So the sun's rays come at a slightly
different angle.
So this on this day I will measure that.
The Sun is directly overhead for me,
but I'll get my friend 100 miles away to
measure the angle of the sun relative to
the well,
and if you that tells you that the earth
is curved and if you do the geometry,
you can work out.
If the 100 miles of the earth's surface
causes the sun's rays to suddenly be at
that angle,
how curved the earth is and what the
circumference of the earth is.
It's plain geometry that in principle
any high school student could do,
but when you say 100 miles away,
first of all,
how are they communicating with this guy
hundred miles away.
They're not immediately,
but the guy writes it down and then they
takes a horse and they come and compare
notes later and they use a Sundial to
determine the time,
the Sun Sundial to determine the time
and and the 100 miles a minute away.
Would there be a deviation at all in a
time,
a minute or two?
Well that,
yep.
But so to something accuracy you,
you,
you get it wrong to some accuracy,
but they did pretty damn well.
They came up with the circumference was
darn close to the circumference of the
earth,
and so,
uh,
it's amazing that they use these
techniques so they were just so confused
and so curious about it all.
They just tried to figure out what it
has got to be a way to figure this out.
Well,
and they didn't.
They weren't,
they weren't forced with the dogma that
the earth is flat.
As you,
I've,
I've told today you were dealing with
people who are still
forced with that dogma is very strange.
How do you feel about that in 2017?
It's amazing,
but you know,
nothing's surprised.
Not only that gravity is not real and
dinosaurs aren't real.
And you,
the people who say gravity are real.
I have a great solution,
but it's a building.
Walk out the window of the 13th floor
and test your ideas.
And the great thing is do it before you
reproduce,
but it's a magnetism thing.
They believe it's electro magnetism or
something like that that suddenly people
down to the.
Yeah,
that's what I'm thinking.
Think so perinatal magnet and look at it
as what happens as you're falling into
the earth?
Well,
it's even more hilarious is that they.
we talked about this before the podcast
started,
the Japanese weather satellite.
That takes an image,
a full image of the earth.
What is the name of that satellite
again,
Jamie?
It takes a full image of the earth from
22,000
miles ago away.
People keep saying in this flat earth
theory thing that there's no images of
the earth in full at.
They're all composites.
That's not true.
It's not true.
There are images of the earth that are
taken every 10 minutes by this one
satellite and they're high resolution.
You can.
You can access them online anytime you
want,
but people see those and they want to
think they're fake,
but yet they believe there's an ice wall
around Antarctica that you crossover and
you fall to the abyss.
Where's this photo of the ice wall it or
have they never?
Well,
how does someone fly from Japan?
They don't believe that people can fly
around the world.
I've done it,
I've done and that they're all lying.
Here's no one,
have they ever thought at time zones,
why are there times zones of the earth
says flat where there time zones,
the only reason they're telling me they
should go from New York to La and see
you know what?
The time is different.
Do they will know,
but they probably think it's a human
invention,
but you know the sun is still shining in
la when it's gone down in New York and
they can call their friends and check
and if the earth was flat,
that wouldn't be the case.
It's only the case because the earth is
curved.
I mean,
so those simple things should should
convince people,
but people are willing to throw out
evidence if they have a belief.
That's really from,
and what I said before is we have to
realize the easiest person to fool is
yourself.
So if you're not willing to question
your beliefs,
especially those that you hold
particularly cherished beliefs in,
if you're not willing to question those,
you're not gonna.
You're not gonna ever grow.
Yeah,
well that's a good way to put a
particularly cherish because I think a
lot of people do cherish these ideas.
Things like the earth being flat because
it gives them some sort of information
leg up on everybody I know.
Something that people don't know what
makes them feel better about themselves.
They may hate gays because it makes them
feel better about not being gay or maybe
they are gay,
but you know what I mean?
You always worry about that.
And so I,
I think we all,
that's what I mean about being believing
10 impossible things for breakfast.
We,
I don't want to make fun of people
because we all do think of things to
make us feel better about ourselves.
It's part of being human,
the psychological pitfalls and so we
should be aware of those and I have them
in.
You have them and I don't pretend I
don't.
What I do try and do is question them,
but we can all do that
and I don't,
I don't.
I understand why people are beliefs.
Certain things.
It's not.
And you can be.
Again,
Richard Dawkins tells me about an
astrophysicist he knows who during the
day,
you know,
studies objects in the sky and,
and,
and looks at at galaxies or stars and
measures that they're,
that they're 12 billion years old or
whatever,
and then,
but yet he goes home at night and then
it's an and is convinced that the earth
is 6,000
years old.
So somehow we can really do both.
Yeah.
He knows a guy like,
oh yeah,
and people can and we're all capable of
believing in to mutually contradictory
things at the same time.
It's just the way we're built.
And so how does this guy really measure
the cause of these planets?
Somehow it doesn't affect his
fundamental beliefs and it's amazing.
It's true because we can all believe
things that are wrong and so it doesn't
mean they're stupid.
It doesn't mean because this guy is
apparently a fairly accomplished
astrophysicist.
It's the psychological pitfalls,
but we all have trap.
So,
so many people,
you know,
when I talk about this,
I don't want to seem pompous in the
sense of saying,
Oh,
I'm better or scientists are better.
Science is better because science helps
us overcome those pitfalls.
Why do those pitfalls exists though?
Because because obviously evolution,
I would argue that they have lived in
evolutionary purpose that somehow they
allow.
If they didn't have an evolutionary
purpose,
then they wouldn't have been selected
for.
Right?
Right.
There does seem to be some weird
inclination or some desire to expose
secrets to find secrets and did know
them.
Yeah.
It's nice.
Well,
but on the other end,
that's great.
Let's exploit that.
Discovering secrets is about is
discovering mysteries.
Discovering mysteries is what motivates
to do is to do sign,
so let's put it in a positive light.
We all want to solve puzzles.
We all want to understand something and
maybe the first one to understand it.
We all want to access information may be
and make us feel special for doing it.
Really,
that's the reason I do science,
right?
It's not save the world.
It's because I really wanted to know,
understand.
I mean,
and it's nice to be the first person to
maybe understand stuff.
It's gratifying for your ego.
It's a and we are driven by ego and,
and let's not pretend otherwise.
Right,
but you,
I think you're talking about measurable
things and elements and things that you
could sort of expose and explain,
but what these people seem to be really
obsessed with is people lying about
stuff and covering up secrets about the
earth being flat or chem trails.
Yeah.
They'd like to believe there's a
conspiracy.
Conspiracy's are very,
very attractive.
Yeah.
Because it.
Because,
and I,
you know,
I don't,
I'm not a psychologist,
so what I say here is just speculation,
but the world doesn't care what you
believe and it doesn't treat you fairly.
Right?
Right.
And that's just a fact.
The world,
he doesn't treat me fairly,
doesn't treat you fairly.
It doesn't give a damn if it's my
wellbeing or,
okay,
so,
Hey,
I'm being treated unfairly.
Isn't it better for me to think that
someone is actively being unfair to me
than just assume it's just the way it
is?
Because then I can blame it.
And so I tend to think conspiracy
theorists tend to say,
you know,
the things I don't like,
there's a real reason for it.
It's not an accident.
It's not just haphazard,
it's not anything.
And in and it,
you know,
it's,
I've lost my job because there's gotta
be a reason.
There's got to be a villain.
There's got to be someone making it
happen.
Just like the reason we burned witches.
Right?
Because there were storms or there
wasn't.
It wasn't crops that year.
And a lot of people say it's an
interesting historical theory,
which I think is seems quite plausible
to me that when Newton discovered the
laws of gravity,
the universal law of gravity,
it contributed to the ending of the
burning of witches.
Well,
I thought that that was a,
meant the burning of witches.
I thought they drowned them mostly.
Well
had they hung a lot of them too.
They drown them.
Where do.
I don't care whether it's burning.
They killed her.
I understand.
Okay.
They blamed crops.
They blamed the bad things.
And then when Newton discovered that
even the planets are affected by the
same laws that Annapolis,
there's a universal laws.
It meant that physical effects had
physical causes and when bad things
happen,
there's a physical reason there's not
someone you can blame and and witches or
whatever.
And so there's a lot of arguments that
suggests that that kind of development
and physics led to the end of blaming
people for those for bad crops or,
or for bad things happening.
But I think that's the kind of thing
when we.
We want to find someone to blame rather
than just saying the universe doesn't
give a shit
about me and anybody interested in this
is a really fascinating subject.
But the whole Salem witch trial thing.
Then there's a lot of really convincing
evidence that seems to point towards
ergot poisoning.
That there was some,
a late freeze and that this particular
type of fungus grew on some of their
wheat that makes Origami,
which is a very.
Has very lsd like properties.
And they think these people thought they
were being bewitched because they're
being contaminated.
It's,
it's a great idea if the evidence for
it,
but it's interesting.
I know it is fascinating,
but let's,
can we all I think behind that is,
is uh,
you know,
we've all had.
I mean,
I think what we're seeing are extremes
of characteristics that we all have.
I think many of us assign blame when we
shouldn't.
When I lose my keys,
sometimes I see them out.
Where do you put the,
my wife,
where did you put the keys?
Right?
And then I learned very quickly that I
shouldn't have said that.
And so I think it's just an,
it's a characteristic of being human and
accepting it as a characteristic of
being human.
It doesn't diminish us,
but what's really great is we can
understand that and try and work and,
and try and figure out ways to avoid
those pitfalls.
So a lot of these ways of thinking,
these patterns of thinking,
these are sort of hold offs from the
ancient days.
That's the things that helped us to
survive those pathways now are
counterproductive.
And,
and I ran a meeting at my origins
project is about the origins of
xenophobia and w and w no US versus
them,
and it turns out there's really useful
Zena evolutionary purposes for us versus
them tribal purposes and not just that
actually it goes back to biochemistry.
Immune systems is us versus them just
being able to recognize foreign bodies
and cells.
So it goes back to single cell
organisms,
but then the question is,
is it now got to uh,
uh,
is,
is it now run its course and become on,
of course,
to be counterproductive.
Exactly.
And then we have to look at those things
and ask what their is and if we explore
those things,
then then there's a better chance that
we can deal with them and asked what's
useful and what isn't.
But if we refuse to acknowledge that
those things exist and that they may be
the purpose of our religion or our
beliefs or whatever,
then we're,
then we can't possibly overcome them.
Or You.
I'm going to change gears a little bit.
Are you concerned at all about ai?
Yeah,
we will.
Yes.
We just had a workshop again at my
origins project in which you can watch
it online,
the public event anyway.
Where can.
Someone said,
Oh wow,
dot origins dot Asu Dot Edu.
We run these amazing events and what's
neat to me by the way,
is we get 3000 people attending the pain
to attend.
People really want to hear science if
it's done right and interestingly.
That's awesome.
Yeah,
I'm,
I'm.
I'm so pleased and privileged that we,
that people find things that interesting
and come over and over again,
but so we ran this,
this event called the future of ai who's
in control because associated with.
We had a scientific workshop on what are
the possible disruptive influences of
Ai.
Now Ai is gonna change the world.
It's going to.
The future is not going to be like the
past.
What it means to be human is not going
to be like it was the past.
Get over it.
Now the question is some of those things
which we think are horrible,
may not be so bad.
For example,
the ancient Greeks thought the
introduction of writing would be
horrible because oral storytelling would
be destroyed,
but writing wasn't such a bad thing.
It actually made the world kind of maybe
a more interesting place.
It maybe,
maybe ai will take over certain
functions that humans have teaching or
doctoring or whatever,
and maybe it won't be so bad.
Okay.
Maybe it maybe it seems terrifying for
us,
but maybe won't be so bad.
On the other hand though,
you can imagine awful consequences,
ones that are already bad.
So we.
We looked at these disruptive possible
consequences and the point is it can
have both.
What's really important is,
unless you think about it,
pasture said fortune favors the prepared
mind ultimately.
So yes,
Ai is both terrifying and exciting.
The future is terrifying and exciting.
For example,
I'm really excited by the possibility
that ai might become better physicists
in us,
and I'd like to know.
I'd like to know how intelligent
computers,
especially intelligent quantum computers
understand quantum mechanics.
They may understand it better than we do
and I might learn from them.
So maybe there'll be the dominant
physicists in the future of the dominant
academics and we can learn from them.
We can learn from intelligent artificial
systems that wouldn't be so bad.
Maybe it seems like it'd be bad,
but what's wrong with that?
It's really rose colored glasses though
what that,
that may be.
But on the other hand,
it could be that,
that,
that intelligent is ai decides that
there's no need.
For example,
here's something that,
that one of the people who was at our
workshop and Yon Tallen who,
who founded skype was one of the
coordinators of our workshop and he
says,
well,
you know,
oxygen is really bad for,
for,
uh,
oxidation of,
of,
uh,
of uh,
electronic systems.
Okay?
So if ai could control,
you know,
a technology,
they might want to systematically reduce
the oxygen content of the atmosphere,
right?
That wouldn't be so good for humanity.
Okay.
So you can imagine the other extreme
where basically intelligent ai systems
control most of the technology in the
world and maneuver things.
So humans become extinct.
So you can,
you can imagine one realm or the other,
but unless you think about the ways that
you can try and and ensure that the
future is as good as can be,
you've got to at least confront those
possibilities.
You don't put your head in the sand and
you don't go,
oh my God,
the world is ending.
You say,
look,
this is going to.
There are changes are going to happen.
For example,
Ai will displace millions of people from
their work.
You know,
the,
there's no doubt if not billions,
if billions.
Let's say billions.
Now,
what's that going to do?
Well,
there are two.
There are two possibilities and one of
them was imagined by John Maynard Keynes
when he thought about what
industrialization would do.
He said,
you know,
the effects of it is that machines are
going to do a lot of the work that
people are going to do.
But the great thing is that'll free
people from the work.
There'll be able to go have coffee and
coffee shops,
go see read books,
do you know see plays.
The quality of their life will improve.
But of course that didn't happen because
you know,
the,
the increased resources that were
decreased,
increased money and,
and,
and all of that that was generated by
industrialization wasn't,
wasn't uniformly distributed at some
point when we are billions of people out
of work,
we're going to have to decide to say,
you know,
what,
those machines that produced a higher
net quality potential quality of life
for everyone.
Maybe we have to spread the wealth,
maybe some sort of universal basic
income.
And I think frankly,
we have a choice either we as machines
begin to do just that.
We have a choice to move in that
direction.
It seems to me.
Or we have a choice to move in a
direction of incredible socio economic,
uh,
problems and Tom Moulton and,
and,
and that's going to create huge,
huge societal problems.
And I'm worried that in our society,
for example,
that doesn't even want to provide
healthcare to everyone where some people
say,
why should I pay for you when you're
sick?
Even though we live in a society that's
wealthy enough to do just that,
that will never get to a point where we
say,
you know what,
these machines have generated incredible
wealth.
Let's allow all the people who've been
displaced to to,
to benefit from that wealth.
I suspect that won't happen,
and I,
I,
I'm,
I'm pessimistic about the future.
Otherwise my friend Cormac McCarthy
says,
because he's a really chipper fellow,
but he writes very dark books and when I
first met him I said,
how can you be so cheerful?
And he said,
you know,
I'm a pessimist,
but that's no reason to be gloomy and
that's become my mantra ever since then.
That's a great statement.
Yeah,
I love it.
Now,
what I'm worried about with ai is that
we're looking at it as if it's an
invention.
It's a human invention,
which most certainly is,
but it's also a life form.
What I'm worried about is that it
decides,
well,
eventually,
if you extrapolate,
yeah,
but okay,
so big deal.
Well that it decides to make a better
version of itself.
Then it continues to do that and we're
going to be completely obsolete within a
shorter amount of time.
Great.
Really?
Well,
I mean no law,
so that's could be good or bad.
So it's to this note,
but this is your illusion that you're
significant with.
No,
I'm not,
it's not.
It just stay alive long enough to die of
old age,
but maybe eaten by robots.
So there's lots of things that,
that don't have any real purpose.
But what would the robots,
you know,
if you want to go with robots,
would it be and why would they feel it's
necessary to destroy us?
Because we're polluting the environment
we made.
We made your world.
Well,
not when we're,
when we're not governing things.
We might not be,
you know,
we might want to say they might want to
save us like we do the turtles and,
or you know,
in various places they don't want the
lights to happen because the turtles
don't.
Don't,
you know,
mate,
if the lights are on the beach and we
don't do such a good job of,
we don't,
but there'll be better than us.
Right?
Right.
But what we might be an evil hyena like
species,
if we are,
then why should we be around?
That's a good question.
But I mean I'm worried about that.
Well no,
but maybe give us a chance to get
better,
but maybe you could view them as your
offspring and then you then,
then you say,
look at my offspring.
And in fact actually I do think
ultimately if,
if,
if machines can,
can program themselves and ultimately
come better than it will be difficult
for biology to keep up.
And our future is humans will be,
could easily be what you would call the
Borg in Star Trek.
Could easily say the only sensible ways
to merge.
Right?
And,
and,
and you know,
what's really interesting.
So then the dominant life form,
it'll be really interesting.
So we tend to think of why,
why are carbon based individuals that
dominant life form in the universe.
But it could be if we're looking at the
out in the universe of looking at the
dominant life form their silicon based,
they're not carbon based and,
and,
and it'd really be interesting because
in this case it would be intelligent
design.
You can imagine a bunch of intelligent
computers having a podcast in the far
future.
So,
you know,
I think we were designed by these,
by these monkeys and they would be
right.
Yeah.
That's what's really fascinating is the
idea that we are some sort of a,
not just a creator,
but that we're the predecessors
of some greater species
and who,
who knows who knows what the is going to
be.
But,
but to be afraid of the future,
it's inevitable.
Ultimately what can happen will happen,
will happen.
We just have to accept that and we have
to try and,
and,
and prepare for it as best as possible
to try to make sure it works out as well
as possible.
I begin this book,
the greatest story ever told so far with
the,
of a quote from,
from Virgil,
from the idea saying the.
I think these are the tiers of things in
there.
I should,
you know,
I don't know if you have a copy of the
book around.
I was going to bring my name,
but I'm sure you'd have with you anyway,
and the stuff of our mortality costs us
to the heart.
That's a Latin phrase that people
remember that famous,
but the next phrase in the night and
eight,
which I talked about,
the very last page or two of the book is
this phase release your fear and I think
that's the important thing,
that stuff overall mortality does cause
us to the heart,
but release your fear,
use it to make our brief moment in the
sun more precious,
but it's fascinating to me that we're so
connected to this particular form that
we find ourselves in now and that we
were.
We're so attached to it and that even
though we know that we are a finite life
form as individuals.
Some people don't.
Yeah,
go on what I'm saying irrationally,
but we know that we're a finite life
form.
We would like to think that we stay in
this state for as long as
history and we would like to wait,
but you know,
but of course we're just temporary.
We've run as humans,
even that's almonds.
Homo sapiens have only been around for a
Spec of time,
a couple hundred thousand years.
Right?
And who would expect our future to be
the same,
but yeah,
of course it can be.
And,
and what if,
what if,
what if?
The things that are wonderful about our
culture are preserved by our
descendants,
but our descendants aren't carbon based.
Okay.
So what's wrong with that?
Why do you,
why do you care if your great,
great,
great grandchildren look like you,
right?
I mean,
of course we all do because we want
somebody mortality.
Right?
Okay.
So the robots are made to look like you.
I mean,
I don't care,
you know,
they all have Joe Rogan faces on them in
front of them or did you see x Makena?
Yeah.
And Yeah,
and I've talked to Alex Garland who was
a hesitation there.
There was a little nod and you know,
as,
when I,
of course whenever I see science
fiction,
I,
I try to suspend disbelief.
Okay.
I think the idea,
in fact,
I showed a clip from smacna in our event
because,
uh,
because I think there are many possible
negative consequences of,
of,
of artificial intelligence.
One of them is malevolence,
but the other is unintended negative
consequences.
And I thought Max Malkin it was,
it was a wonderful example of unintended
negative consequences of artificial
intelligence.
I don't think that lovely young woman
was designed to be evil,
but it was an unintended consequence
when she saw an opportunity for herself
and the other one I showed,
of course it's from 2001 a space.
The great how warehouses.
Sorry Dave,
I can't do that.
And,
and,
and I think,
uh,
I think it's wonderful and thoughtful
and it was thought provoking.
And I,
and as I say it,
I've come to know Alex Garland who wrote
it and directed as innocent and,
and he's a very thoughtful,
interesting guy and one of my favorite
all time movies.
I love that.
Yeah,
it's a really interesting movie.
I agree.
Uh,
I always,
I always try and analyze it afterwards
and sometimes as a scientist I,
I,
I try not to get in the way of liking
science fiction because of course they
all involve suspending disbelief and
certain things in.
And the difference between good science
fiction and bad science fiction is not
how scientifically accurate it is.
It's how good a story it is because if
it's a good story,
you can suspend disbelief easily.
Uh,
someone was asking me the other day on
a,
on a science fiction podcast where it
said,
you know,
what's the worst example of this?
And,
and,
and the example that comes to mind is,
I remember in New York Times reporter
after the physics of Star Trek came out
said,
can I go with you to a science fiction
movie and watch you and then talk to you
about it?
And so we went to see a starship
troopers and this is the stupidest movie
of all time because.
Well,
because they're,
you know,
because,
because you know,
these,
these ants poop out things at supersonic
speeds about cross the galaxy.
I mean,
you know,
that's amazing,
but it's stupid.
What's a very campy movie,
right?
Yeah,
I know,
but when the problem is,
because he was asking me to look at the
reality of.
I couldn't even suspend disbelief if I
want it to,
but that.
But it's things like that.
For example,
when something happens,
it's suddenly takes you out of the
story.
You suddenly go,
Oh shit,
here's another one,
another movie I hate called ghost,
maybe liked it with,
you know,
the family more Demi Moore and what's
his face?
Right.
And here's the idea.
So this guy's a ghost,
right?
And he,
he,
he wants to show his long lost love
leads around.
It's beautiful.
It's wonderful.
So he tries to lift a penny,
but of course it goes through his hands,
right?
He tries to hug her,
but it's hands go right to her.
But you noticed each time he stands on
the floor,
sits on the couch.
He stands on the floor and sits on the
couch.
So his butt or his feet have some
incredible ability to be stopped by
matter,
but nothing else does.
I mean,
I saw that the rest of the movie went.
That's a good point.
I didn't even think about it now.
I didn't want to ruin it for you,
but I just.
Well,
I saw it when I was like 10 older.
It's an older movie.
How old?
When is that movie?
I probably wasn't 10.
I was probably 20 or something.
Yeah,
well I'm older.
It's a stupid movie.
It is.
But,
but,
but for that,
what I'm saying is the minute I saw that
it was hard for me to enjoy the rest of
the movie.
Plus they have an unhealed bit,
which also sounds stupid.
So sometimes,
sometimes,
sometimes something like that when
you're in.
It doesn't have to be science,
it can be watching a drama and you say,
why the hell did they do that?
It's just how to share Sheriff Dermot.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And then.
And then it's hard for you to enjoy the
rest of the movie.
Yeah,
I find that all the time.
I have a real issue with that.
Um,
when you think about artificial
intelligence,
do you consider like one of the things
that freaks me out is that what we
consider life will,
when we think about instincts and needs
and desires,
those won't necessarily be programmed at
all into any artificial life.
Well,
one of the questions that arises,
and this is a huge point of discussion
among ai researchers because I've been
to a bunch of meetings in preparation
for our meeting is whether,
and I find the statement almost vacuous,
but I'm amazed that they use it all the
time to program machines with human
values,
right?
Why would we be programming?
And my problem is what our human values.
And they said,
well,
one of the,
it was a very smart guy and I won't,
I won't say who said this meeting.
Well,
they just have to watch us.
And I said,
what do you mean they watched Donald
Trump?
And they know what human values are.
I mean,
come on,
I'm not sure there are universal human
values and so.
So how do we program them in.
But neverless the question is do we want
to align their programming?
In what way?
In terms of what we think will be
beneficial to us,
right?
Because after all we're programming
them,
so we do do we in part St [inaudible]
values?
Who knows?
I mean,
I find that a very interesting question
and a very difficult one to resolve.
I my own feeling is if it were up to me
and I am not,
it's not an area of active research for
me.
You produce the smartest machines you
can.
Just like you have kids.
I have kids.
Do we want them to believe everything we
believe?
No.
We want to give them.
We want them to become the most capable
human beings they can be so that they
can go out and do the best stuff.
Right?
So why is it different for computer?
I'd want to make the most capable,
intelligent,
resourceful machine I ever could because
then I,
at least all the evidence suggests to me
that that machine will make the best
decisions.
All right?
But if the machine doesn't have an
ability to breed sexually and if it
doesn't have ego and if it doesn't
necessarily have creativity because it
doesn't need to be praised for its ego,
I don't think we,
I don't think creativity comes from
needing to be praised for you.
I think creative,
I mean as another great intrinsic
aspects of human beings that makes being
a human being worth being human being.
Well I think I agree with you,
but I think if you're going to connect
that sort of mindset to a computer or to
artificial intelligence,
don't you think it would have some need
to create like what?
What is our need to create as like we
like to express ourselves to other
people.
If you were alone on an island,
do you think it would create?
Yeah,
sure.
Here's of yourself forever.
You think you would paint on?
I'd like to think I would because I.
because I kind of.
Because that's what I find gratifying.
But I think one of the things people
find gratifying is it that other people
are enjoying it.
So no,
I don't do science because other people
enjoy it.
And do science because I enjoyed.
And,
and um,
and so you think you would do science if
you were the last person on earth?
You would be alone with what I do.
The work I do is,
I mean I don't want to make any
pretense.
I do it because it's fun for me and I
think most people do it.
They may claim actually I shouldn't say
there are people probably better than me
who do what they do because they're
constantly trying to save humanity in
one way or another.
I like to think what I do has a net
positive effect and I try to take time
out of my science to try and counter
things that I think are wrong with the
world because I have a cause because of
my background and also because I have a
soapbox.
I'm lucky enough to have people listen
to me for one reason or another.
So I try to take that responsibility
seriously.
But on the whole I do what I do because
I enjoy doing it.
I think most of us do and we only do it.
We're only good at it if we're good at
it because we enjoy it and look at,
here's an example,
so the best one of the best machine
learning machines and existence just
beat the best go player in the world.
Right?
Right.
How to do it.
It learned,
constantly.
Learn,
taught itself to you better go,
okay,
that's creativity if you want.
It's trying to be better at playing the
game,
but didn't I just calculate every single
note?
No,
no,
no.
It can't.
It can't do that.
What it can do is try to teach itself
strategies that work and just creativity
and look at it and it does teach itself
strategies at work,
new strategies by looking at old
strategies that didn't work.
That's creativity.
I mean who knows how to define
creativity in all senses,
but you can imagine that a sufficiently
intelligent computer would be creative
because in order to do physics and
science,
you need to be creative.
You know?
In fact,
I was just.
I just did an event with Alan all day in
New York City and I all the from Mash.
Yeah.
Who's a great guy at intelligent man and
very interesting science and science
communication.
We've done a few events together.
One with my origins project we can see
online,
so he was interviewing me or we had a
dialogue,
but he was interviewing me about the new
book and and,
and,
and in the context of that and science
communication.
And he said something wonderful both
there in earlier he said,
because it's so counter intuitive to
modern culture's reception.
He said,
art requires rigor.
Science requires creativity.
And I thought,
wow,
because that's the opposite of what most
people think,
but in fact,
science,
art requires rigor.
You gotta just get just the right colors
and,
and work really hard to get the right
patterns.
Whether that art is music or you know,
buy art.
I'm looking very broadly.
Whereas to do science makes progress
because we're creative.
It's also rigorous,
but people somehow have this artsy
fartsy notion that oh,
artists are creative and scientists are
nerds.
You know,
they're just,
they're just rigorous.
Science is just rigorous garbage.
It's not,
it's creative.
Just like art and art is rigorous.
And the scientists who say,
oh,
these artists,
these musicians,
they're not,
they're not as good as we are,
they're equally bad because the art and
doing anything well requires rigor,
discipline,
effort,
and rigor.
And I think that that beautiful
dichotomy,
that juxtaposition of art and rigor and
science and creativity is something
wonderful that Alan said and,
and we should realize that it's a
characteristic science is,
does involve creativity and rigor,
but so does all the areas of human
activity that make the,
the story of humans so wonderful.
That's why it's the greatest story ever
told so far.
Well,
many,
many aspects of human life require
creativity.
Many endeavors right here and right.
Whether you're a better kickboxer,
I mean,
there's a lot of creativity and
fighting,
eager to learn rules.
Sure.
Discipline your muscles over and over
again.
Any sportsperson and maybe there's even,
maybe there's even creativity and
football,
but,
uh,
you know,
there's Gregor and creativity and
anything that humans push to the limits.
Yeah,
no,
I absolutely agree.
The question would be,
what would the motivation of artificial
intelligence be if it's not,
if it doesn't have any.
We were essentially riding on the
motivations of our ancient genetics.
We want to have sex for gas.
Exactly,
and it'd be interesting to see those.
What would it be interesting to find
out,
right?
Well,
what would their motivation to be
creative because because we've.
We've developed in them problem solving
capabilities and because they're self
aware and the amount of asked questions
because they're self aware.
They may want to improve their
understanding of the world.
Partly for technology.
They may want to make the world better
for themselves.
All sorts of reasons,
but we'll,
we'll see.
Have to some extent will import it,
it programming,
but to some extent we'll see and to some
people that's terrifying that we won't
know the motivations.
Of course not as terrified about it.
I guess I'm concerned that we got to
make sure we understand what we're doing
at each step so we don't produce massive
negative results that could have been
avoided,
but I'm not as concerned that the future
will be different than the past.
I hope it is.
When you see some of the emerging
technologies like Crispr,
some of these genetic engineering
technologies where they're starting to
use non-viable human fetuses and run
some tests on them,
are you concerned at all about that?
Are you concerned about,
or I shouldn't need to use this term,
the term concern because obviously
you're obviously mindset.
No,
no,
no.
I'm concerned has happened.
No,
no.
It's not.
Just let things happen.
Let Watch what's going to happen.
Trying to anticipate the results,
understand them in detail,
anticipate what the results are and
avoid negative ones to the extent you
can,
but it's life is all about the things
are going to change,
but to accept the fact that things are
gonna change and if and,
and that's not,
that's,
that's why aren't we happy that the
world is different than it was during
medieval times.
I mean,
except for you know,
Mike Pence and other people with the
rest of us are happy or you know,
that can pick a lot of radio
commentators,
but most of us are happy that we,
that the world has gotten more open,
more interesting.
And so that's part of the human drama is
that it's going to go places and we
don't know where it's going to go and
that's okay,
but we should all work as much as we can
to try and make sure to the extent that
we can,
that the direction of heads is a good
one is,
is beneficial,
more interesting,
more exciting,
more possibilities,
more fun for everybody and,
and maybe even more sustainable because
it seems reasonable that it should be
sustainable if we think we care about
not just our children but our
grandchildren and their grandchildren.
And so that it's self interest in some
sense,
you know,
to be interested in,
in conservation and sustainability
instead of immediate profit.
If you really have,
of course,
you know,
might say if I amass enough wealth and
my children will be fine forever and who
gives a damn about the rest of the
people's children.
But you know,
we can decide that maybe it's in the
best interests of everyone.
If humans societies sustainable because
there'll be less likelihood for extreme,
more extreme violence,
blah,
blah.
You can.
I would argue that we behave well in
large part because of reason and and and
my point is,
and I've had this,
we had a session in my origins project,
a whole meeting on the origins of
morality and and I've had this debate
with a number of colleagues who point
out,
I think it was hume who said you can't
get ought from is okay,
you can't get off from it is just by
rationality.
You can't decide how to behave.
Maybe,
maybe,
but here's the point without,
is you can never get to ot without
knowing the consequences of your
actions,
which is what science is all about.
You can't decide what's good and bad and
so science and reason is an essential
part of any progress because we can't
possibly decide what economic policies
to enact or what or what social policies
are,
what technological policies if we don't
know the consequences of actions.
That's why,
for example,
here's an example.
It was so stupid for the Republicans to
design this healthcare policy and
promoted before anyone in analyzed say
the economic impact of it.
I mean,
they could have still decided to do it.
It's not as if but,
but at least that data would have been
useful for making a final decision.
It's that simple.
What?
I guess getting back to that crispr
thing,
if that becomes available and if it
advances to the point where it's
available to people that are alive
today,
would would you,
would you give it a shot?
Would you change anything about
yourself?
Would you become thor?
I mean if it really gets to that point
where we can worry about a lot of
things,
but I'm not anywhere near as worried
about that as am hacking.
Right?
Right.
Because if we can hack computers and if
you can hack the DNA as a lot of kids
want to do.
In fact,
I was told years ago,
I'm chairman of the board of something
called the bulletin of atomic scientists
that have the board of sponsors that
sets the doomsday clock every year and
so we have to think about existential
threats to mankind.
I remember about seven or eight years
ago,
we had a,
a fresher from mit who said his computer
science students were most interested in
hacking DNA.
Much more interested than hacking
because it's just an attitude,
it's just a code and and so if you could
manipulate arbitrarily in a very precise
way,
DNA,
then of course there are many good
things that can come and maybe you can
make yourself stronger,
bigger,
whatever you want.
Maybe we're not you,
maybe your children,
whatever,
and maybe you can overcome genetic
diseases,
which of course would be great,
but you can also with,
you know,
with great power comes great
responsibility.
And with that you can also imagine
hacking,
right?
And creating new viruses or whatever you
want.
And so yeah,
it's,
it's any new technology is terrifying.
Does mean we shouldn't create new
technologies.
I mean,
cars are terrifying.
Cars kill.
Look how many people cars get killed now
maybe we'll have self driving cars.
Maybe fewer people die.
Some people are afraid of self driving
cars because they do present moral
problems and it's as if a car is
designed to minimize the number of
people it kills and it can do that by
killing you.
If you're faced with running into five
school children or the car turning and
hitting a wall,
what do you want your car program to do?
And it's,
these are fascinating questions we will
have to address,
but technology can,
so technology can be used in many ways
and it's terrifying.
But uh,
it's trite to use this old expression,
but I do think of it at times,
which is that the little thing I gave
him a stepdaughter once,
it said ships are safe in the harbor,
but that's not what ships are meant to
do.
I mean,
if you can,
you can bury your head in the sand.
You can never go outside the house for
fear of being run over by a car or being
embarrassed or whatever.
Or you can choose to live a life.
It's your choice.
But to me,
living the life as it is more
interesting.
That's why it in,
in,
in the,
in the book I point out you can choose
how to look at the world.
You can choose to say you're the center
of the universe and if that makes you
feel better finding the universe was
created for you,
or you can choose to let your beliefs
conform to the evidence of reality and
go and assume the universe exists in
evolved independent of your existence,
and in that case you're bound to be
surprised.
Isn't it better to be able to have a
life full of surprises and a life that
doesn't have any?
No.
It's a wonderful philosophy.
What I'm thinking is I'm wondering about
these technological advancements when it
comes to the ability to manipulate the
human body and when they get to the
point where we,
we don't have the same issues that we
have today with diseases and when
injuries or even with a biological
inferiorities with everyone.
Looks like Lebron James.
Yeah.
Okay.
You could imagine that's the case.
I,
I suspect people will want different
things,
but okay.
That'll be a very different world,
but look at this way.
Um,
you're a pretty buff guy.
Okay.
You manipulated your body,
right?
Yes.
Okay.
What's wrong with that?
No,
nothing,
but I'm still five foot eight.
Okay.
Lebron James is seven feet tall and
manipulated his body.
It's a very different deal.
Someone gives me a seven foot tall pill.
I might take it.
Yeah,
but you manipulate your body given the
technology of the time.
Right,
but you did what?
You do changes and everyone can seven
feet tall and it was at worse because
you can manipulate because you know
enough physiology now or whatever.
Exercise physiology that you can
manipulate your body more efficiently
now than you could before and people can
run faster miles or jump higher because
we've been sports for forever and so
that's okay.
You know,
that's fine.
I'm just wondered what your thoughts are
on the future.
Well,
I physiological imbalance.
I try to anticipate the abilities
and to the extent I can discuss what
they are so that we as a society could
address them more cogently.
I do not.
However,
generally predictions about anything
less than 2 trillion years in the
future.
That's a great quote.
What's going to happen 2 trillion years
when the universe expanding to the point
of cooling off and everything dies.
There's two reasons for that statement.
One is it's pretty simple.
When you start thinking about the
longterm is the universe is probably
going to expand forever,
all the galaxies,
and if it doesn't,
the sun's burning out.
Anyway,
point is if it doesn't do that,
no one's gonna know I was wrong.
That's a good point.
That's a very good point.
Yeah,
so yeah,
so that's why.
Yeah,
that's my general.
I've read a quote once about
supermassive black holes that has
matched with my brain ever since I read
it.
Okay,
and the quote was that inside every
galaxy is a supermassive black hole
that's one half of one percent of the
mass of the galaxy and that it's very
possible that inside that supermassive
black hole is a whole nother universe.
Well,
the up to up to that,
what does that mean?
Up to that point?
Everything's fine.
Everything sounded fine.
Okay.
It is true that it's amazing that most
galaxies that we can measure have large
black holes on center,
which leads to an inch.
The question we don't have the answer
to,
right?
One of the reasons we're building the
James Webb space telescope.
The James,
what James Webb Space Telescope.
The one that's going to replace the
Hubble space colors that.
Is that going to be in space?
Yeah.
It's going to be much further orbit.
It's going to be launched next year and
it's the.
It's the successor to James Webb is
going to be 100 times the the collection
area.
It's going to look at different
wavelengths of light.
It's going to push what Hubble has been
able to do to look back to the earliest
galaxies that ever formed first light as
we call them and starts first turned on
the first stars that formed in the
universe.
It's going to be fascinating,
but there's a chicken and egg question.
If most galaxies have supermassive black
holes in them,
which came first and did the black holes
form and that was necessary for the
galaxies to coalesce around them or did
the galaxies existed,
and then the black holes built up
hierarchically by swallowing things and
getting bigger and bigger and bigger.
It's a question we don't know the answer
to.
When we build that thing,
we might have the answer to it.
It'll be an interesting question that we
resolve.
It is amazing that as far as we can
tell,
these supermassive black holes exist
even though we don't know they're black
holes.
By the way.
We know they kind of looked like black
holes and quack like black holes and
walk like black hole black holes,
but we.
What I mean is there we can tell their
mass contra concentrations that are
immense.
A billion solar masses in a region so
small that our theories tell us they
should be a black hole,
but we don't know if,
if,
if the consequences of generality tell
us that they are black holes,
but we.
The simplest assumption is that they
are,
that nothing escapes from them,
that they,
that they formed classically like black
holes and they're fascinating and we'll
learn about.
We're learning about black holes by the
way or putative black holes in ways we
never thought we could because we now
have a new window in the universe.
Gravitational waves.
These,
this ligo detector just detected graves
gravitational waves from colliding black
holes to coalesce and just discovered
that the predictions of general
relativity or validated,
it's a whole.
We're like Galileo,
when he first turned his telescope to
the heavens and saw the moons of
Jupiter,
we've just opened a new window on the
universe and it will be the new
astronomy,
the 21st and 22nd centuries and we will
learn things we had no knowledge about
because that new window will reveal to
us the dynamics of black holes in ways
we never thought possible.
So it's an amazing time to be alive.
And I attended.
Think that's also a time invariant
statement.
But,
but anyway,
so everything.
So the black.
But what happens inside black holes is a
question that's much different and the
answer is we don't know.
We don't know.
We know classically,
if general relativity tells us what's
happening,
we know that this things will collapse
to an infinitely dance singularity,
but you know,
most of us physicists think infinite is
a pretty bad word that in than in
physical reality,
things don't get into dense that the
laws of quantum mechanics,
you're going to change things and when
things get sufficiently dense so that
quantum mechanics has to be applied to
gravity and the only time that really
happens operationally or either the
beginning of our universe when our
entire observable universe was in,
in potentially and infinitely dense
singularity or at the center of black
holes.
That's the only places where that
matters.
When quantum mechanics must be applied
to gravity.
Our current physical theories breakdown,
so we don't know what happens in the
ultimate state of black holes.
We don't know.
One possibility is indeed they do our
portal to another universe.
Because what's really interesting is
when what you see from the inside of a
black hole and the outside are very
different.
If you're inside of a black hole in
space could look like it's expanding.
Whereas outside the black hole,
it can look like the black hole is
contracting.
Why is that?
Because general activity tells you that
your,
that your perceptions of what space is
doing around you in some sense depends
upon your the gravitational
configuration in which you live.
You live in general,
you can be moving and standing still at
the same time.
We're doing it right now.
I'm not moving much with respect to you.
I had a little bit of coffee so I'm
shaking a little bit but but,
but relative to a radio conversations
that are happening in the studio at the
other end of the visible universe,
we're moving away at the speed of light
and those individuals having that
conversation are also at rest and their
local surroundings,
but they're moving away from us at the
speed of light.
How is that possible?
Because locally spaces at rest,
but globally space is expanding.
So generativity says that what you
consider to be happening to space around
you depends on your local environment
and what you defined so you can locally
be at rest,
but globally be part of an expanding
universe.
Similarly,
inside of a black hole,
the direction of time reverses,
it turns out because space and time are
tied together.
So if you see so,
so what you perceive inside of a black
hole to be happening,
um,
to,
to the time evolution of the system
you're in would be very different than
what's seen from outside to be happening
at the surface of the black hole.
I mean,
whack holes are fascinating and there
are laboratories of the boat that allow
us to focus on the physics.
We can't yet fully understand how long
have we known about them?
Well,
the idea of a black hole was first
thought about,
uh,
people wondered whether what was the
ultimate state of gravitational collapse
and people that argued that maybe the
ultimate state of gravitation collapse
was these things called that we now call
black holes.
There was a big debate about it.
Oppenheimer and Snyder in the 19 forties
and fifties,
the person who first named black holes
was John Wheeler.
It amuses me.
He came up with the term black hole in
1965 or something like that to describe
the ultimate state of collapsing met
people felt it was impossible.
There'd be that physically forces would
stop things from collapsing to the kind
of densities that black holes would
format,
but based on the work of Sake Saker and
others,
it was discovered that if you have a
more massive object that's massive
enough nuclear forces and all other
forces cannot fight against
gravitational collapse and eventually
things will collapse inside of what we
call the event horizon.
It's the ultimate say clap that it was
hugely debated in the thirties,
forties,
fifties.
By the 19 sixties it was accepted and
interestingly enough,
wheeler was one who first thought it
couldn't happen later on,
came up with the name black holes and I
think that's one of the reasons that
people are so fascinated by black holes.
Turns out in Russian,
the term for black hole was frozen star
and you don't see movies made in Russia,
but about frozen stars.
You see a lot of movies about black
holes is a great name.
Yeah.
And you know why the weights,
why it's a frozen start.
Let me blow your mind a little bit.
Okay.
When objects are falling into,
so one of the things you need to know is
the rate at which our talk,
our clocks tick depends on the
gravitational field we're in.
So if I'm way above the earth's surface,
my clock is ticking at a different rate
than your clock.
This sounds so crazy,
but we needed every day because you
know,
what did you use gps at all today?
Wouldn't have worked if it wasn't for
that.
Because the clocks and the set gps
satellites are ticking at a different
rate than the clocks on earth because of
general relativity because they're in a
different.
They're higher up with respect to the
earth.
So they had to calculate.
We have to know,
use that effect to Qa to correct.
If it wasn't for that case,
your GPS would go out of alignment and
less than one minute.
We use it every single day.
So explain that please.
So the GPS,
the GPS,
global positioning satellites that are
in orbit,
they take into account the fact that
there are higher above the earth,
that their clocks are ticking more
slowly than ours.
How do we know that?
Because how do they know where we are by
by a triangulation,
they.
They basically look at the time it
takes.
They have atomic clocks,
clocks the time it takes for a signal
from your watch or your phone to get up
to the satellite and back and that other
satellite and back allows you to
determine your position [inaudible].
But if the clock is ticking at a rate
than you get a wrong answer for the time
it takes for it to go on the the,
the number you get from that satellite.
When it reports to your watch,
is it slower,
faster?
Well,
due to there are two effects due to its
motion due to its motion.
It's,
well,
how can I say this?
It's basically slower,
but due to its motion,
it's taking it a slower rate.
Okay.
Due to its height in the gravitational
field,
it turns out that it's faster.
So the two effects counter each other.
General relativity in class and
specialty J in this case,
general relativity winds,
I think it's something like,
uh,
they're,
they're ticking more slowly at.
I calculated once I wrote a New York
Times piece on this and I forget the
number,
but it's something like,
of the order of 38 microseconds per day,
they're clicking,
they're taking at a slower rate,
million,
38 millions of a second every,
every day different.
And that may not sound important to you,
but if you calculate how far light
travels in 38 millions of a second,
it's pretty far.
And so therefore,
if you,
if you keep getting wrong by that
number,
your,
your determination of your position is
going to keep getting wrong by that,
by that number.
And,
and I worked out I,
and then this should allow me to work
backwards.
If I had a pad and paper,
um,
I see a pad,
but I know I'm not going to do it right
now because I'm okay,
but I remembered you'd be out by
something like a kilometer in two
minutes.
Wow.
Isn't that amazing?
That is amazing.
So we use these abstract esoteric
principles and they govern our lives.
So general activity really isn't matters
for our technology,
but it tells us.
But what's really interesting,
so as objects fall into a black hole,
because they're getting stronger and
stronger gravitational fields from the
outside,
we see them moving more and more slowly
and eventually we seed them freeze at
the surface we will never see from the
outside.
It will look like it will take an
infinite amount of time for an object to
fall through the event horizon of a
black hole.
Even though in its own frame it falls
through no problem for us.
It will watch it slowly,
slowly,
slowly because it's clock is literally
ticking at a different rate and it will
take an infinite amount of time for us,
for any object to fall through the event
horizon black hole.
If we're watching from the outside,
that's why the Russians call them frozen
stars.
Isn't that weird?
It's crazy.
It is,
but it's true.
Now,
where did the concept come from that
inside every black hole is perhaps
hundreds of billions of galaxies each
with a black hole in front of it.
Oh,
well I don't.
I never heard that concept.
What I have heard is that is that at the
singularity,
the singularity,
maybe a portal to another universe,
right?
And moreover that,
that that inside the black hole you
could,
you could imagine that,
that you're observing a space that
appears to be expanding instead of
contracting.
And is it possible that those inside
that black hole,
that universe would not have the same
laws of physics that we.
Well,
once it goes through the singularity,
who knows because the laws of physics
breakdown,
but one thing I can tell you for sure is
there aren't millions of billions of
galaxies inside that black hole.
And you know why?
Because gravity allows us to measure
what the total mass of the black hole is
for in that sense of black holes it.
Well,
if it's a portal that's a different
universe,
right,
that's what I'm saying.
But after that's when then it's no
longer inside the black hole,
but it's wonderful that the black holes
are just like any other stars,
you know,
you can rub it around them,
you know?
Not everything falls into a black hole
because if you're far enough away you
can just do an orbit like a planet
around the sun.
The Sun is attracting us,
but the earth doesn't fall into it and
not in a normal amount of time.
Do you anticipate that that's something
that we might try to do in the future?
Send a satellite into the black hole
first we'd have to find a black hole or
the one in the center of our galaxy
perhaps.
Well,
that you know how long it takes to get
to this end of the golf is 40.
The center of our galaxy is 40,000
light years away,
so it's a long experiment.
Yeah,
it's unfortunate.
It's not clear to me the national
science foundation under trump or anyone
else is going gonna Fund that fund that.
Yeah.
Now what about having a week?
I'd be interested if we could send a lot
of congress to explore what the what
it's like at the center of the black
hole.
That would be a solution.
Maybe suit them all up.
Yeah.
Sued 'em all up.
Go boldly go where no man or woman has
gone before.
What about black holes that are not
attached to galaxies?
While we don't see them,
we don't.
I mean right now we have.
I don't believe anyone's because here's
how you.
How do you see a black hole?
You have to see the star circling
around.
Exactly right.
It's the only way you can see that.
So those just theoretical.
The stars that aren't the black holes
rather that aren't attached to.
Well,
I mean and not only are the theoretical,
I think very few people argue there are
many such things because we tend to
think that stars conglomerated around
around regions where there's dominant
mass,
right?
They collapsed and so while it's true
that the galaxies are just the tip of a
dominant of a cosmic iceberg,
most of the massive galaxies isn't stars
or black holes.
It's this stuff called dark matter.
What is that stuff you can see and try
to explain it to me and told him,
get in there either.
Well,
it's look,
it's really quite simple when we way
galaxies,
which we can do by seeing how fast the
stars move around them,
we find out that they weigh a lot more
than could be accounted by counting all
the stars so the dominant mass doesn't
shine.
We call that dark matter,
not too surprising and what,
but what we have discovered,
and this is the surprising part,
is we can estimate how much normal
matter there is and by normal matter I
mean the stuff made of protons and
neutrons the same as you and me and when
we add up how much dark matter we see in
the universe.
There's a heck of a lot more of that
than can be accounted for by the total
number of protons and neutrons in the
universe.
And that means that we think the dark
matter is made of some new type of
elementary particle.
Something that was created in the early
history of the universe that's different
than normal matter.
That's not too surprising either because
in the early universe there was lots of
energy around and if they're new
elementary particles that are stable,
it's not too surprising that there are
lots of them around and if they don't
interact with light,
we wouldn't see them.
In fact,
not only is that reasonable,
but we cannot understand how galaxies
would form.
If it weren't for dark matter.
We can do the calculations and show that
if it,
if the,
if there is a dark matter weren't made
of stuff that's different than protons
and neutrons,
there would not have been enough time in
the history of the universe for galaxies
to form.
Therefore,
that's really strong evidence that that
stuff must be there and it must not be
made of protons and neutrons because
we're proof.
You and I that galaxies formed.
It's so fascinating that there's this
element that's a huge part of the
universe itself.
The word,
not really exactly sure what it is.
Yeah.
Isn't that great?
It's amazing.
There are mysteries.
What unfortunately people get told is
that it makes it seem like,
you know,
science was done and it's all done.
It was done by dead white men 200 years
ago.
That's not the mysteries continue.
That's why it's the greatest story ever
told so far.
That's why young kids should be
interested in science because life is
full of mysteries and we've learned so
much about the universe,
but it gets more mysterious and more
exciting and every time we open a new
window on the universe were surprised.
That's why we got to keep looking out
and not looking in.
Tell me about hyper Novas.
Hyper Novas.
I watched a science documentary freaked
me out about how when they first started
measuring gamma ray bursts out into the
unit.
They thought there was wars going on
between alien races.
Well,
the point is that you know how you know
there are these things called gamma ray
bursts and what they are.
Gamma rays are extremely energetic forms
of light if you want to think about it,
and they're among other things that are
admitted in nuclear weapons explosions.
Okay.
And,
and you know how they were discovered.
It's really neat.
It's one of the few examples of defense
money,
well spent in my opinion,
but maybe not the few,
but I now that you'll get lots of eight
mil.
So we'll like that.
Anyway.
Um,
so there were these satellites that were
designed to go up that were earth
monitoring to look for gamma rays.
Why?
Cause we were looking for nuclear
weapons explosions to see if the Soviets
or some other country where we're having
nuclear weapons closer.
There's one way to monitor what year was
this one?
Oh,
this was.
These satellites were put up in the
sixties and seventies.
So this is around the time they did that
operation starfish prime,
where they detonated in new,
into the,
uh,
atmosphere.
The magnetosphere probably,
I don't know,
but I honestly don't know the answer to
that question,
but,
but the point is they were used by the
as monitoring systems to look for
nuclear weapons explosions.
And then these things are sure,
looking downward discover these,
get these short bursts of gamma rays,
which would be a potential signature of
nuclear weapons explosions.
But they discovered they weren't coming
from earth and then they discovered they
were coming from everywhere in the
cosmos,
and that's how they were discovered.
These devices,
we're monitoring the earth,
looking for nuclear weapons explosions,
and then saw them out in space.
How many of them were well?
They're everywhere.
There's millions of them and they happen
there.
One second,
two second,
one minute long bursts that are
incredibly energetic.
It meaning more energy than Sun may meet
in this lifetime,
in its lifetime,
and they're happening all the time.
They're happening all the time.
You know why?
Because the great thing about the
universities,
it's big and it's old and therefore a
rare events happen all the time.
Let me give you an example.
Stars explode and it's good for us.
It starts exploding about in this book
because it it's it.
Because every atom in your body and
every atom in my body was made inside
stars that eventually explode.
Well,
how do we know that?
Because in the big bang,
the only elements that were created were
hydrogen,
helium,
and a little bit of lithium.
Okay?
But the importance for some people,
that seems important,
but the rest of us,
rest of us,
carbon,
nitrogen,
oxygen,
iron,
all the stuff that makes us human was
only created in the fiery furnaces,
in the cores of stars.
And how could it get into your and my
body?
Because there were stars that were kind
enough to explode.
So as I once said,
and some people put on t shirts now,
so forget Jesus.
The stars died.
So we could be born.
Okay,
but,
but here's the deal.
Stars explode about once every hundred
years per galaxy.
So in our galaxy,
once every hundred years to stars
explodes,
there have been about 200 million stars
explode in the 14 billion years or 12
billion years since our galaxy has been
around.
And that's produced the raw materials at
four and a half billion years ago,
coalesce to form our sun and the
planets.
And you and I.
So all the atoms in your body Balms,
restores and been through the most
intense explosion that we know of in
nature.
A supernova and every atom in your body
is experiencing maybe more than once.
Because to get to the amount of carbon,
nitrogen,
oxygen,
and that's in our bodies,
it had to be recycled many times.
So the Adams in your left hand may have
been inside a different star than your
right hand.
You're really star dust.
We're all stardust where we're really
connected the cosmos in really
interesting and important ways.
We literally were created by stars.
That's great thing,
but,
but that's not the point I wanted to
make.
The point I wanted to make was stars
explode once for a hundred years per
galaxy.
We use supernovae as a way to probe the
universe.
How can we do that if one,
if we're looking at galaxies and one
star explodes every hundred years and
the galaxy,
how can we use them as probes?
Well,
as I say,
there's one way is to sign a graduate
student teach galaxy.
You know,
the phd period can be about a hundred
years and if they die,
students are cheap.
So you get a new one or we use a nomad.
This fact that the universe is big and
old.
If you take your hands up tonight and
and we're in Los Angeles where you could
see the stars and it held a dime sized,
made a dime sized hole,
and looked up at a dime size dark region
of the universe.
You know what?
You didn't see any stars.
If you had a telescope that as big as
the telescope in Chile,
you'd see 100,000
galaxies,
100,000
galaxies and that small region.
Then if one star explodes every hundred
years per galaxy,
if you work out,
how many stars will I see?
Explode tonight?
You'll find out.
You'll see two or three stars explode
just in that dime.
Size.
Yeah,
because the universe is big and old and
rare events happen all the time and
that's what makes the universe so
exciting because now we can use
supernova to study the universe because
astronomers write proposals and say,
tonight,
I mean use the Hubble space telescope to
look at this region and I'm going to see
three stars explode.
Wow.
Isn't that amazing?
That is amazing.
Yeah.
It's just the.
And isn't it a shame that more people
don't realize that?
Because that's as amazing as you know,
as anything.
I mean,
that's the kind of thing that makes
like,
oh wow,
that's,
that's neat.
And it's,
as I say,
it's neat to see a great movie too,
but that they're all together.
Science is fun and Neat and interesting
and you don't have to be a scientist to
find it.
Amazing.
Yeah.
That is about as amazing as it gets.
I think we don't.
We have a real issue.
I think with cities were light pollution
prevents people from seeing your amazing
stars.
In fact,
there's a lot of astronomers who are,
who are doing,
in fact I'm active work to try and
reduce light pollution in cities near
telescopes.
And there's other.
I mean,
the accuracy,
but radio telescope is an amazing.
If you've never been down to Puerto
Rico,
it's beautiful.
It was actually,
you would have seen it in to James Bond
movies because they made it into like
the layer of,
uh,
you know,
the pictures of it in the layer of,
of,
of some crazy evil scientists.
And I've been there a few times and it's
amazing because it's this thousand meter
wide net of,
of,
of wires in a,
in a natural sort of volcanic volcanic
cap account.
It's really beautiful.
And there's jungle growing underneath
it.
I'd walked underneath it.
And the receivables Pedro scope is
amazing because it,
it,
it because it's so big,
it allows us to measure lots of neat
things in the universe.
In fact,
you could measure a light bulb on Pluto
if there was a light bulb.
You know,
we're looking at the picture of it now.
It's amazing.
And you can't even get the sense of the
size of it necessarily from that.
It's all wired.
So it's all wires.
It's not solid.
It's wires because it's only measuring
radio waves if the wavelength is large
compared to the spacing between the
wires,
you don't need something solid.
Right?
Okay.
So,
uh,
they were worried.
And this is a real example they're
looking for,
among other things,
a frequency of radiation which is
ubiquitous in the universe that is
emitted by hydrogen.
It was the first sort of thing that
people used to do,
radio,
radio astronomy,
hydrogen Mitsa a has a characteristic
frequency of emission of radio waves due
to due to what's called the high
performance building and hydrogen and
it,
it.
And so people have said,
you know what,
that would be a wonderful frequency for,
for aliens to commute if they really
wanted to show it,
if they're smart enough to know that how
the universe works.
That's a universal frequency.
That's everywhere because hydrogen is
the dominant kind of matter and it all,
it always emits radiation at that
frequency.
Okay.
A thousand 40 megahertz I think is the
frequency.
Okay.
A yellow,
again,
it could be wrong,
but something like that.
And uh,
but they're worried because there was
nearby are stable.
There was an evangelist who had a huge
radio station and wanted to broadcast to
the continental United States is
evangelical message and he was going to
basically at a frequency that would mean
that she couldn't work anymore.
Speaking of light pollution,
we talked about light pollution.
That was radio pollution.
And in this case,
it was pollution in many ways because
everything you said was polluting,
but,
uh,
and,
and finally they managed to be able to
fix that,
but there would have been one of the
most amazing windows on the universe
that would have been blocked out by
radio light,
just like from an evangelists.
Yeah.
That's it,
isn't it,
isn't it?
It's very ironic.
It's,
I think it's very symbolic of many
things.
Wow.
That is fascinating moment of silence
because it's so amazing.
Yeah.
Well,
it's confusing.
yeah.
But that's okay.
Being confused is that I told you being
longer.
Confused is the best part.
No,
that I and I can get it.
I get it now.
Um,
when,
when you talk about the vastness of
space and you talk about space being 14
billion or whatever it is,
point 8 billion years old plus or minus
a little bit.
What's the going theory about what was
going on before that?
When I wrote a book about it,
first of all,
but,
uh,
called the universe from nothing.
The point is we don't.
The simple answer is we don't know
because the at the incident of the Big
Bang,
the whole universe was contained in a
region.
We'd have to understand gravity is a
quantum mechanical forest to really
understand what was happening and we
don't have a quantum theory of gravity,
so it's okay to say we don't know,
but we can say what plausibly was the
case and one possibility and the
possibility that looks most plausible
that I talked about is our universe
spontaneously came into being from
nothing by quantum fluctuations,
a space and time that did not exist.
So our space and our time didn't exist
and there was no matter in the universe
and it's suddenly popped into existence
and one of the neat things is if you add
up the total energy of all the stuff on
our universe,
it adds up to zero as far as we can tell
what?
Zero.
What does that,
how's that?
Because it.
Because gravity allows things to have
positive energy as well as negative
energy.
You add it all up and our universe looks
like in its total energy zero,
but I know you're shaking your head,
but that's the neat thing is I'm trying
to.
If you were going to create a universe
from nothing,
what would you make?
The total energy,
the total energy thing.
Why would you?
Once you realize the total energy
universe can be zero,
then the possibility that it comes from
nothing becomes plausible because if it
doesn't,
you may need to dd to create everything,
but it turns out you can create a 100
billion galaxies each containing 100
billion stars without violating energy
conservation,
and that isn't it.
It's the ultimate free lunches Alan guth
would say,
and it's amazing that that's possible.
Now,
can we prove that that happened?
No,
but everything we can point to makes it
plausible.
In fact,
you can ask the following question.
What would the universe look like today
that was created that that that arose
spontaneously from nothing,
13 point 8 billion years ago just by
known laws of physics or at least
plausible laws of physics.
What would it look like today,
if that,
if that was the requirement and the
answer is it will look just like the
universe in which we live in that.
Does that prove that that's what
happened?
No,
but it makes it plausible and it makes
it plausible without supernatural
shenanigans and anytime you can get rid
of God,
it's a good thing,
but isn't something out of nothing.
Supernatural Shenanigans because it
happens all the time.
Right?
You know,
I,
this is an example I've been talking
about to a few times today to people.
The lights in the studio,
the lights above us,
our head.
So what happened?
So electrons change energy levels and
Adams and they emit photons were,
were the photons before they were
admitted,
they weren't in the Adam.
Where were they?
They didn't.
They didn't exist.
They were spontaneously graded.
They were turned on by the lights
switch.
No,
God,
no.
They're spontaneously created because
there's no cause for any of them to.
Each.
Adam spontaneously decays into a
different level because quantum
mechanics says that these things can
happen spontaneously.
And when it does,
a photon is created from nothing.
So here's what I was getting at.
Yeah.
What is the difference between this
infinitely dent,
small point that the universe came out
of and the center of a black hole.
The event horizon of a black hole?
Well,
another event horizon isn't the center.
It's the outside of the black hole.
The will.
The,
the answer is there is no different.
No different.
No,
they're singularities where the laws of
physics as we know them,
break down.
Is it possible that inside of each one
of those black holes is the birth of the
universe maybe?
Is that how we were?
No,
no,
I think it's,
I think it's more likely to.
Quantum mechanics just burped us out per
cosmic burp.
Much like,
you know,
I mean I think it's great.
I don't know if you saw in my,
in my jacket,
which I don't know where I put it,
but it was probably outside.
Uh,
I had the flying spaghetti monster
because I love this because he boiled so
that we could be alive today.
But it's,
it's,
you know,
it's just pissing people off me.
But.
So this infinitely dense point of 13
point 8 billion years ago,
this was whatever it was,
is this something out of nothing point.
What are your thoughts about before
that?
Well,
here's the thing that you're going to
hate one possibility,
which is quite possible and plausible.
If our space suddenly popped out or
nothing.
Einstein tells us that space and time
are together.
We live in a four dimension universe.
So space began at that instance sort of
time.
So there was no before the question
isn't a good question.
Tom didn't exist to the universe came
into existence.
So to ask the question,
what was before is not a good question.
So time didn't exist before 13 point 8
billion years.
It could be that if our university is
all there is and that we happen to think
by the way is not likely.
But if it is then it doesn't make sense
to ask the question what was before
because Tom didn't exist.
It sounds like a cop out and it Kinda
is,
but it may also be true.
So.
And if there's no before then all of our
notions of causality go out the window
because we all depend on but before and
after to decide causes and effects.
But if there was no before,
then we have to change our notions of a
cause and,
and that's awful.
But Hey,
that's what we call learning.
What about the idea is that the universe
is in a constant state of contraction?
No,
it isn't.
And well,
I mean some people think that no,
it's not been abandoned.
Some physicists will argue that there's
a cycle because it looks nice and they
aren't.
I think most of most people,
I mean there's some people who are
arguing for that pitch something neat.
Well,
I think they're trying to type their
ignorance in something that isn't any
more plausible than the picture that
expands forever.
And as far as we can tell,
the most likely possibilities that our
university will expand forever fought to
make you a little bit happier.
It's quite possible.
The best pictures that we have of our,
of,
of the early years is that we actually
are universities.
Unique isn't alone,
that there are many universes,
we call it a multiverse and that at any
instant in time and kind of a cosmic
super time,
there's always university being born so
that that multi-verse might be,
might be infinite and eternal.
Where are they outside of our universe?
Oh,
how's that?
Even possible.
How?
Of course it's possible.
I understand.
Okay.
No,
no.
Well,
first of all,
the simplest possibility is that there
outside the region we can see right for,
for,
for example,
the edges of our visible universe space
is expanding faster away from us than
light because you know,
we taught you in school.
Nothing can travel faster than light and
you may remember that we lied.
Oh,
okay.
Well No,
you have to parse it more carefully.
Like a lawyer.
Nothing can travel through space faster
than light,
but space can do whatever the hell it
wants.
So locally,
as I told you though,
radio host is,
is at rest,
they're not moving and the other end of
the galaxy at the other end of the
visible universe and we're at rest,
but the space between us is expanding.
So that galaxy,
like a surfer is being carried away from
us faster than light relative to the
water.
The surfer isn't moving right,
but relative to the shore,
the surfer is right,
right.
Okay.
So this,
this galaxy is not moving relative to
its local surroundings,
but it's moving away from us faster than
light.
And like a surfer in an undertow,
they can swim really fast in the water,
but if the water's moving away from the
shore,
they'll let me take it back to the
shore.
Right.
And so that galaxy,
the light from that galaxy is traveling
through space at the speed of light,
but it's the space in between us and the
galaxies moving faster than light.
Then the poor like can never make it to
us.
We call that a horizon.
Wow.
So the space is traveling too far for
the light to reach us so fast.
The two spaces too fast.
So the light can't catch up with the
expansion of space and it never gets to
us and that that galaxy disappears from
our causal horizon.
We call it will never be able to see.
It will never be able to interact with,
it will never be okay and it could be
that that there are different regions so
far away from us.
We're space is expanding faster than
light,
which which have a very different
history than our own,
so there could be space,
could be infinite,
just our simple unit space that we know
of and love could be infinite in extent
and different regions of that space had
different histories and some of those
regions.
Everything we can see we know emerged
from a single point.
Okay,
we can tell that.
We can tell that by measuring the big
bang expansion of everything we see and
working backwards and the university
that our visible universe was once
smaller and smaller and smaller.
If you go back in time,
we can actually follow the laws of
physics back to the earliest moments of
the big bang until those laws break down
and we can make predictions about the
university would look like.
All those predictions agree exactly what
the observations we make,
which tell us that that picture works,
but another region,
if you wish,
could have come from a different big
bang,
but is that another universe or is it a
part of the university?
We see,
here's how we've changed and this is
semantics,
but nontrivial semantics,
namely when I was a kid,
universe meant everything.
Everything right,
but we say that's it's pretty stupid
definition.
A better definition is an operational
one.
Universe means that region of space with
which at one time we could have
communicated or one time in the future
even if the future is infinite,
we might communicate with because that
describes the region of space we're
causing effect works some measurable
distance.
Yes,
and so that art we think of the universe
is that region which could throughout
which everything could affect everything
else ultimately in an infinitely long
time and in that picture,
universes can be restricted in size and
then other regions which could never
have affected us and which will never
affect us in the future.
We call other universes a and when and
now there are many different versions of
a multiverse,
but that's the simplest version.
And this picture we call inflation,
which,
uh,
you know,
I talk,
I just did two little clips associated
with the new book,
one for us for a publisher and one was
for big think one is a,
the universe and under two minutes so
you can look up online,
looked for Lawrence Krauss,
explains the universe in under two
minutes where I talk about this cosmic
expansion and how it might mean there's
a multiverse,
but the other is,
um,
explain the universe in terms of this
beer bottle that I talked about you
earlier.
So you can,
that's a video.
You can watch that.
But at this theory of inflation,
which actually says our universal,
the qual,
the qualities that we see of our
universe can best be explained if some
early time in the history of the
universe when it was a billionth of a
billionth of a billionth,
of a billionth of a second old.
It had a huge expansion suddenly and
increased in size by 30 orders of
magnitude in size.
In a billionth of a billionth of a
billionth,
of a billionth of a second,
which is by the way particle physics
suggests is highly plausible even
though,
okay,
and then and then,
and then it would produce a universe
that looks more or less like we look
like you look like and,
and uh,
and it's right now the only explanation
of how that would cause the university
to look like,
what it looks like.
But the neat thing about inflation is
it's eternal.
So inflation that puffing up ended in
our universe.
And then boom,
a hot,
big bang followed it.
Okay.
So the region,
the universe universe puffed up by huge
amount than all of that energy which was
stored and empty space got released like
the beer bottle and we got a hot,
big bang and the rest is history,
but that's locally,
but somewhere else between us and their
space is still expanding exponentially
and faster and faster and faster.
And only maybe somewhere else today.
Boom.
Like an ice crystal forming boom.
That that region of space is suddenly
left inflation and maybe a guilt a
gazillion years in the future,
there'll be another region of space
that's expanding away from it,
so much faster than light.
So we'll never know about it where
suddenly that region leads inflation and
boom,
another hot big bang happens and it
turns out in each of those hot big
bangs,
after the inflation ends,
depending upon how it ends,
the laws of physics could be different
in that universe.
And that's what we tend to think.
It's quite likely that there are many,
many separate regions of space and in
fact it's eternal.
So such regions are forming eternally
for all time and,
and,
and there are hot,
big bangs happening in many regions and
the properties of each of those regions,
whether they're conducive to forming
galaxies and stars and planets and
people may be different.
So we could say logically in that
picture that the reason the universe
looks like the way it does is because
we're here to measure it.
Oh my God,
we should leave it at that.
Okay.
We should close with that.
That is the mindblower wind blowers.
Wow,
I'm glad I wore you out.
Not the other way around.
Was amazing.
Thank you so much.
Fun fact mandated.
Again,
that's two and a half hours,
man.
Just by good.
Thanks.
Wow.
Thank you for you and me and my have
flown by.
I don't know how the little strip.
Listen man,
that that was a mindblower.
Okay.
Thank greatest story ever told so far.
It's available now.
You can get it an audio books.
It's on a.
You can get it on itunes and an audio
book form as well.
Thank you very much.
Really,
really appreciate it.
It's been great to finally get to talk
to you.
I really appreciate this.
Thank you.