Four three,
two,
one.
And we'll live teddy atlas.
Thanks for being here man.
I really appreciate it.
My Dad keeps saying that.
Stop make you guys listen to
anyone out there mad at you.
No one's mad at anything.
There's no real set time.
You know,
I can't,
I gotta tell you since I announced
you're going to be on the podcast,
I had about a hundred people
tell me to get you mad.
They want you to rent,
get scraped every since that we're
firemen speech you gave to Tim Bradley,
everybody wants you to
start screaming to get mad.
You get,
you get people hyped up.
Oh,
believe there's only an occasion flood.
And I don't think there'll be an occasion.
I,
I'm looking at this stuff here.
You got a nice place here,
by the way.
Thank you.
And it's making me think about
the Denzel Washington movie.
Uh,
the equalizer,
the first one where it was
in with those Russian guys.
So were like messed up guys.
And he was trying to
protect that girl and he,
he started pointing,
there were skulls and
stuff at the guy's desk,
you know,
and,
uh,
he was pointing the stuff he was
trying to explain to the guy,
listen,
let this girl go,
you know,
I'll give you $9,000.
Whatever was let her go.
She was like 15 years old.
And,
um,
he,
he didn't want to listen to them.
And so he started the head
stuff like this with the skull.
I don't know if the people could see it,
but,
um,
and he started pointing
it towards him and I,
the guy didn't like take the hint,
you know,
the guy.
Then a couple of minutes later
he killed everybody in the room,
but it's just,
it looks exactly like the
thing from that movie.
The Denzel Washington where he,
uh,
he also had guns and stairs right there.
There's,
this is Jamie pulled the scenery.
Oh,
really?
He was fair.
I never saw that movie.
Yeah.
So you see like the scene
where he starts pointing,
they might have taken this from here.
I mean,
they could've gotten it from,
it's from Mexico.
Who props.
Um,
so they,
they pointed,
he pointed at all towards the guy to kind
of warn the guy what was coming next.
But
that's probably the only good movie that
ever came out of a terrible TV series.
You remember the TV series?
The equalizer?
I remember the name,
but I don't know that I ever really
watched it.
I was a fat,
sloppy white guy driving a Jaguar that's
supposedly kicked everybody's ass and
you'd watch it and you know,
get the fuck out of here with this movie.
I didn't watch it.
I heard a TV show.
It was a just a dumb TV show
that didn't make any sense.
And when they turned it into a movie
and had Denzel Washington in it and I'm
like,
what?
How is this possible?
I'm going to cause you freaking out.
Not really,
but like I was just thinking about that.
So listen man,
you were,
you just came back from
the Canelo triple g fight,
which was a phenomenal fight.
That was a phenomenal fight.
I really enjoyed that fight a lot.
We'll
exaggerate how good fights nowadays.
Like if they're around,
everything's great.
Everything is,
if a pitcher has one
good year in baseball,
he's great and he's,
he's like the next Sandy Colfax.
Like people don't wait to see and,
and truly graded,
uh,
against things that were
out of their IRA because,
you know,
we're human.
Like,
Hey,
I was there.
I reported on it.
It's the greatest fight ever.
And No,
no,
but that's what people will do.
What they do.
I think it was a really good fight,
but everything's relative,
you know,
and it depends on
everything is influenced.
The judgment of people is influenced.
At least I see it in my field for whatever
that's worth by what's around and how
hungry they are.
Like everybody bought to Pacquiao,
Mayweather first fight
because the fans were hungry.
Their imagination was like,
there's no good fights.
There's going to be a good fight.
So they're anticipating it.
So you've got them at the right time.
If it was the 80s,
and you had Leonard Duran,
Porno would've gone.
Hagler Hagler uh,
you know,
you had,
um,
Hearns,
I mean,
you had all these great fights.
Aaron Pryor,
he had all these guys fighting each other.
You probably couldn't have pulled off the,
the Mayweather
Pacquiao thing that you pulled
off and it turns out to be a,
you know,
a bit of a,
I don't want to say scam,
but,
uh,
it,
it definitely was what it lived up to be
because back Ya'll came into the fight
injured.
I don't believe it.
I never saw any listener.
I must tell you need to have an injury,
but you,
you're in a tough position as you,
you wouldn't taekwondo and all
that kind of fighting stuff,
Lma and whatever part of it.
I'm probably not giving it the proper,
um,
understanding of what it was and,
and exactly what part of the fighting,
not just that my,
maybe I'm being too broad,
but I know you did taekwondo,
you did kickboxing.
I know that you're,
you were national champion
when you were young.
Somebody show me some more about it.
So,
um,
you,
you do things when you're injured.
I mean like when are you not injured?
If you're,
if you're a football player,
if you're a fighter,
if you're in the contact.
But tell me when you're not in,
like when there's not something wrong.
So I had never saw proof during that
bout I was there covering it for ESPN.
I never saw proof where he went store or
he didn't fold that hand or he threw it
in a,
in a poor way or in a,
in a less than high level way.
I never saw that.
So listen,
I'm not in his body.
Uh,
you know,
and,
and um,
I'm not a mind reader,
but I didn't see it.
But what I did see,
I saw him in his trainer in the runway,
was more telling to me taking selfies
because they had got paid a few extra
dollars to promote some kind of product
where the selfies were attached to it.
So I saw that,
to me that was more debilitating to see
a guy before the biggest fight of his
life where people were going crazy
and going to break the paper view,
recommend paying $100
for the freaking thing,
to see him taking a selfie with the
mentalities should be in a different place
and normally is in a different place
before you're about to walk that hundred
yards to the ring where you
might not come out of there.
It's always possible.
You have to have that mentality.
I thought that was more debilitating
than anything I saw physically with what
was supposed to be an arm injury.
So to me,
look,
to me,
maybe it's,
I don't know if it's fair
to say it was a money grab,
but obviously it was a
bit of a money grab our,
they were beyond themselves.
Uh,
you know,
one guy was retired,
he came back forward.
They were beyond the peak of
their abilities in their career.
And I just,
I just didn't see,
uh,
I,
I didn't see that fight.
Uh,
the purpose to it.
Well,
it happened about five,
six years late.
Yeah.
I,
I just,
I mean,
I,
I you ever,
anyone who gets in the ring,
they deserve to make as
much money as they can.
I never,
I never say that a fighter got overpaid.
Never.
I don't care.
I never say that because I understand
what it took to get to that point and,
but you know,
you can,
you can play with things and you know,
you can kind of lead people to things.
And again,
where we started with this conversation,
you know,
it's the time you are around the,
the environment,
what's not around,
not just what's around
but what's not around,
you know,
not that many great fights
to be made right now.
So what you're saying,
so in triple g Canelo fight is important
because there's not a lot of guys
waiting in the wings.
It's not like the old days of the 1980s
are the glory days of the welterweight
in the middleweight division.
No,
it's not.
And the people,
you know,
they,
they have a thirst,
if you will,
to see something that the
PR department can bring.
It can use the right
material because they,
they,
there has to be fighters that obviously
a marquee fighters with a name that they
can build it and get the
imagination of to people to say,
this is going to be a great one.
So when they see it and
they pay $100 on $85 or $95,
whatever the heck they're playing,
um,
for the fight and then it's a good fight,
well becomes a great fight
because of all those elements.
Because,
uh,
you know,
it's during your time you saw it,
you committed to it,
you sacrifice to pay that money,
you sacrifice a fly there and yeah,
it's a really good fight because,
uh,
iconic and fight.
Right.
And,
and I don't think we
separate that in our minds.
I don't think,
hey,
who says we have to,
because right.
It's about enjoyment.
So if that,
if that makes people happy,
hey,
that's part of,
that's part of what goes into
the mix of entertainment.
But I didn't see it when I tried to
separate that being in the business.
I didn't see it as,
you know,
the thriller in Manila I used,
I saw it as a really good solid
fight and they once again,
unfortunately it took away from it.
We'd controversial with the decision.
Did you think that just,
I thought the first decision was terrible.
I thought triple g clearly won the fight.
I thought the second
decision was arguable.
I started like this,
this looks like a draw to me.
And it was an amazing fight.
I mean,
I gotta be honest because I mean,
that's what you're supposed to be.
And who do you think one?
I added one 17 one 12 and a lot
of people going to say four.
You had the to fall.
I tried to pick off,
can rattle all week long.
I pick Canelo to win on ESPN,
on sports.
And I was working,
so I was on team one 12 is
big and it's five rounds.
So I,
yeah,
so,
um,
you know,
you,
you start to,
you're human.
You start to hear people like you,
you know,
that knows something about fighting
that has had it closest to.
Maybe you don't want to yell at,
you had one 17 one 12 but yeah,
you still got to yell at
because that's what you believe.
That's what you saw.
And I still say it,
I still yell at that.
It was,
they didn't give him credit for gems.
Like jabs don't count normal.
Like
I'm not going to pick out anybody because
that's not really fair to do when you
have a podium and they
don't have a podium.
But
sometimes it is because they deserve it,
but not generally.
And the judges nowadays,
I think that
they just give it,
I see too often that they
almost go down the easy route.
Like you know,
they just give it to who's
aggressive for guys walking forward.
Guys,
Tom Punches,
it's like their favor now.
Chi.
And it's more to it than that.
And I understand that the
sport doesn't help itself.
They don't make a clear criteria for,
but it's supposed to be clean,
harder affective punches because the
separation of professional boxing and
amateur boxing is you have to sell it,
you have to make money and you've
got to put fannies in the seats.
So you want to see guys get hurt,
you want to see guys and pack guys.
So it's the cleaner
who hurts the guy more.
It's the cleaner,
more impactful punches,
but it's not just thrown.
It's not just aggression because the
aggression has to lead to something
affective,
affective aggression.
So I I saw for me to get it to that
one 17 one 12 I saw Goliath skin on the
outside controlling rains,
controlling distance.
You want to use that silly word ring
generalship cause I have the time.
I don't know what they're talking about.
They say ring general.
Like what?
What are you talking about?
I just saw the way you judged it.
Where,
where did,
where did you fit in ring generalship
into that into your thinking because I'd
like to know but if it is ring
generalship he was controlling range.
He was controlling outside.
He was keeping the shorter
man on the outside,
catching him with a jab,
making him earn his way in,
making them pay a price to get in.
Now was the other guy.
Can Lob and the other guy landing the
hard clean body shots that sometimes you
don't get credit for?
Yeah,
he was all,
like I say on ESPN,
he was putting water in the basement.
Yeah,
he definitely was.
But the Jeb didn't count suddenly was
suddenly in a universe where the jab of a
guy doesn't mean anything.
When we don't want it to mean anything.
When we want to give it to
the aggressive guy to the,
to the guy trying to,
you know,
trying to get in there.
The question is what,
what's more important is a jab more
important or a hook to the body.
What is more important
in your rock to the body?
Clean is more important,
more important.
But if the jab out numbers to hook
to the body through many rounds and,
and the numbers are significant
that it's greater than,
then you have to account for that.
Right?
So you think that people are watching,
they're watching a couple of jabs and
then one hook to the body and they count
that one hook to the body better
than they count the two jab.
And I don't have a problem
with that because our counted
that way till if it's a
good shot.
Because again,
a power shot.
Yeah,
because that is what's going
to drive people to the event.
Right to the sport is a harder punches.
So I have no problem with that.
But if the jabs or 20 jabs
and it's two body punches,
well then I'm starting to save.
We can't forget the jabs because the
body punches got your attention and,
and it,
you know,
it,
it moved Gadi his seat a little bit.
Maybe because for whatever reason.
So I'm just saying that the criteria
is not clean enough for the judges
sometimes.
Well it's a bit even bigger mass and
MMA and it's a lot of the same judges.
I mean I think the problem with
judging is it the same in both sports.
You should have someone who
has experienced in the sport.
I mean they have to have a
deep understanding of what
they're actually watching.
And that's not the case.
I know it's not the case in boxing because
I know a lot of the same judges from
boxing also judge MMA.
They don't know what they're talking
about in MMA and I don't think they know
what they're talking
about unboxing either.
And that's a real travesty.
It's a huge disservice to these
professional athletes who literally are,
as you said,
risking everything as they step in there,
there's a real good chance
that they might not come out.
I mean,
it happens every so many fights.
A guy dies.
This is just a fact and boxing and the
fact football to sure and MMA as well.
We'll MMA has plenty of problems,
you know what I mean?
There's,
there's less deaths in MMA,
but we're getting desk from Wayans.
You know,
we have a lot of extreme weight
cutting issues and some of the small
organizations in particular,
all of that stuff is legitimate.
It's a problem.
Something that should be,
it's just a shame that the judging is
so poor and it's been this way for so
long.
Well to the boxing,
I mean you have a,
then,
I'm not saying this in a derogatory way.
In some ways it's a good way,
but you have a dictator running,
you know,
UFC and no but,
but it's okay to have a dictator sometimes
because at least you have rules that
are adhered to.
At least you have structure and uh,
you know,
as long as they're not,
taking people out and killing them.
I know what you're saying.
And so boxing has boxing.
He has no real
accountability,
no structure.
Of course the board no real,
you know,
a lot of role structure and conformity
and not done unilateral because you have
different states that have
different commissions and you know,
they're supposed to be tied together but
they all act differently and there's no
natural commission.
There's no body,
there's no dictated,
there's no czar,
there's no it,
there's no NBA commissioner,
there's no NFL commissioner,
there's no MLB commissioner that
overlooks and polices the whole sport.
And
there's those separation of
church and state,
so to speak,
where the people making the
money in the sport are separated,
truly separated from the people
supposedly administrating this.
But there's no separation.
They,
I mean,
promoters actually that are making the
money and have obviously a horse that
running in the game,
so to speak that night,
uh,
that they want that fight it
to when they pay the judges.
And there's no,
there's no,
again,
there's no buffer.
There's no separation where you can
have promoters and managers that can
actually go to the commission and say,
we don't want these judges to judge.
They can't say,
put this judge and,
but they can knock judge
his out and in commissions.
We'll listen to them.
Uh,
the alphabet organizations,
they're corrupt.
Um,
they are,
I mean,
it's not teddy atlas saying it.
It's everybody saying that there's very
few people are gonna say they're not
corrupt,
corrupt.
I mean,
if you're going to be honest
about it and you're not,
and you don't have an agenda where you're
afraid to say it because you have an
agenda,
which is a lot of people
do in my business,
they have agenda.
So then not going to say,
dude,
because they're part of it,
if then are part of it.
Uh,
they're,
they're friendly with
people that are part of it.
And,
uh,
they want to have access,
they want to have relationships.
They say away from it.
And,
and Eh,
they understand how the culture works,
so they understand,
uh,
you know,
is it,
is it a smoky room with
cigars like the old days?
Well,
Frankie Carbo was one of the things,
and you put an envelope,
no,
it's not that,
but you might be paying
$30,000 for an ad and,
and,
and uh,
at a convention for the WBA or
the WBC or the w IBM for Wbl,
whatever the heck they are.
And you might be paying 30,000 for an ad.
What,
what you,
you know,
why you paid the 30,000 for that?
I don't think that you just like to see,
um,
your name and add in a,
in a brochure.
There's,
there was a purpose
behind paying that head.
And um,
so there's no,
again,
yeah,
you have the administrators have to sport
the commissions and then you have to
alphabet organizations that get paid
a sanction and fee fund the champion.
So they want that champion to win.
And so they get to sanction fee.
And especially if he's a popular champion,
so they,
so now you have
no body saying,
well the manager can't talk to the
sanction organization for modern can't.
Of course they can talk to them and say,
I want my guys rated high.
Of course they have access so they
have access to talking to somebody,
influencing somebody to move
their guy up in the ratings,
these honest ratings and they have
access to telling an organization.
While I,
you know,
I'd like to push a mandatory,
I like to push my guide
to get the mandatory,
which means of course that he's going
to fight them within a certain period of
time.
He's got to fight the champion,
which I was missing you never MMA.
Yeah,
that's absolutely missing.
So you have all that
stuff going on and where,
where,
where is the,
where's the,
where's the oversight?
Yeah.
Where's the oversight?
Where's the police in?
Where's the,
where's the line where,
because again,
people making money,
people running the sport,
people administrating this sport.
It's not supposed to blur.
It is supposed to be a separation.
Now,
if you know where to go in Europe,
America,
United States too,
but all to Europe where
there's a lot of big fights.
It was just a big fight with Joshua,
uh,
in London,
they drew 90,000 people,
which is good for the sport and it's,
it's,
it's incredible.
Um,
but if you know where restaurant
to go to tonight before big fight,
you were walking around.
So,
and I've been there,
you were walking in the restaurant,
I'm not going to say something
and if I can't stand behind it,
and you will see at the restaurant,
it's a big table,
kind of like,
you know,
not the last supper,
but it's a big table and you will see
all the officials at that table that are
going to work to fight the next night.
And you will see the organizational heads,
the heads of that sanctioning body.
And,
and the guys are in charge.
The presidents,
vice presidents,
um,
supervisors are judges,
referees and guess who
the host of the dinners,
the promoter,
some more with that.
I mean there's something
greatly wrong with that.
So the host of the dead end,
it's a big bill obviously.
I mean there's a lot of people.
It's a good restaurant.
The eating all the best of drinking,
the best wines and everything else.
So it's a big bill and it's being picked
up by the promoter who wants a specific
fight to win that night and he's got all,
he's got access to all the judges or the
officials or the organizational heads
now.
So I would say to the people that
are listening out there that,
just to make the analogy dead really I
think would hit home the New York Yankees
there obviously your universally
known our name and brand,
the organization maybe
the biggest of all time.
So how about in New York you go to the
best restaurant and a night before a
world series game you walked into the
restaurant and you saw all the umpiring
crow,
all the visuals that are in charge of
the umpiring for the world series game,
sitting at a dinner hosted
by the Steinbrenner's
problem.
Problem,
problem,
problem.
Giant problem.
Yeah.
And it can't happen because there's a
commission would never let that happen
because the integrity,
the credibility of Dysport would be
down the tubes in one moment before you
could finish his shrimp cocktail and,
but so it can't happen.
It happens on checked inbox
puns all the time in boxing and just
the look of impropriety is wrong.
It should be wrong.
A baseball is,
should be wrong and
football should be wrong,
an MBA,
but it should be even more wrong in
a sport where you risked so much.
Yeah,
no,
I agree.
Yeah,
it's a very,
very good point.
And I don't know how
you would ever fix that.
I mean,
how would you have some
universal oversight of the
entire sport and how would
you get everybody from the Wbo w you know,
WBC,
they wouldn't,
no,
they don't care enough
because the president of the
United States started Karen
when there was a problem with baseball.
He got,
he got involved.
That was about steroids though,
right?
Yeah.
But it was a problem.
It wasn't that a horseshit problem.
I mean,
it was a real problem,
but it was more of a problem of they
wanted to clean up the image because it's
America's sport and they had these people,
the door,
the fence,
we're going to leave
the game a little bit.
So it was a problem.
This was a problem that
was impacting them.
It was loosen
w it was impacting the
perception of the game,
which impacted the,
the gates,
right,
what they're gonna make.
And ultimately the fan base,
which of course impacts them financially.
It impacts the country because of
less people care about this sport.
Um,
you're going to see it less.
And if you care about it,
you're going to be one of
the people that are left out.
So it was a problem and they can't,
I don't,
I'm going to be careful saying this,
but not that careful,
but because you have to say it,
I don't think that they care as
much about the people in boxing.
I don't think they do there.
I just,
it's,
it's more of a dangerous,
dirty sports in their eyes.
Yeah.
And,
and,
and the people that come
into it and everything else,
how am I going to get into all the other
stuff that you could get into that,
you know,
was so popular to get into
in some ways nowadays?
You mean like racism?
Yeah.
I'm not going to get into that because
I don't want to and I don't have,
you know,
definitive things to show for that.
I just know how I feel precise.
I just don't,
the supports,
it's not,
it's not cherished the
way baseball's cherish.
When is a big fight like Canelo and
triple g people get excited and a lot of
people will buy it,
but it's not necessarily thought of
as something that represents America.
And in particularly in Canelo triple g,
you're talking about two people
that aren't American to begin with.
Yes.
Yeah.
And there's a history to boxing.
No,
that unfortunately,
you know,
because I care about the
sports has been my whole life.
Um,
that it's it,
yeah.
It's got a reputation as being correct.
And,
and unfortunately,
fortunately or unfortunately,
like there's a pod,
the good part where the
history goes back long ago,
father than any other sport,
any other sport.
I mean,
it was the first sport in the Olympics.
It goes back further.
And it was the biggest
sport in this country,
bigger than baseball.
At one time it was that big.
I mean,
you know,
so and now it's,
it's not,
and it,
it's too bad because,
and it's too bad that the kids,
that the younger people,
they don't have the ability
to learn about those fighters,
those special fighters that were special.
They really want,
and it was special for different reasons.
Like,
like Jackie Robinson was special.
We know,
we don't have to go
into why he was special,
but nobody knows that Joe Lewis,
who's quiet and everything,
but when he was in the army and it was,
you know,
segregation and all that crap going on,
he,
he quietly use his position as heavyweight
champ of the world to make sure that
when he went to movies and they,
him in the front row and he saw that
blacks weren't allowed to come in.
He said,
I'm not going in there.
And Liz blacks can come in there.
When he went to other sort of events
where the same kind of junk was going on,
he very quietly but powerfully
integrated things and,
and said,
no,
I'm going to make a change here.
You,
you're not going to have me.
And I'd have people that look like me,
you know,
kept out.
So he,
and there were people I've read about
it because I like reading about those
things,
but history,
um,
to see how we could be better.
And then,
um,
where we've come from.
And there were history of black families,
you know,
poor black family,
he said would,
would get hope from just saying,
hey,
Louis did it.
They would tell their kids,
hey Joe,
listen,
I don't want to hear this.
I don't want to hear that.
You can't do this.
Joe Louis did it.
And then so he was that important.
That's all.
That's the only point I'm making here.
He was that freaking important that
that history and the history of other
fighters like him.
It doesn't have to be black fighters,
but that what they fought for,
what they did,
what they overcame,
where they came from,
her bedding leaded,
um,
one of the greatest Jewish
fighters of all time.
It was a time when,
uh,
and,
and it's still around.
Unfortunately there's
a lot of antisemitism,
but there was a time where it,
you know,
it was tough being a Jew and,
and you're,
you're growing up and he get caught or
cake and have I'm pronouncing right.
I think it was right.
And you get caught.
All those kinds of,
I don't even know what the hell it means.
I just know it's a bad
name to call Joe and,
and you had all that
stuff going on and Jews,
woman thought of being there were thought
of moving towards banking and they're
moving towards things will make them
money and that later on they started doing
that but they wouldn't the ghettos and
they were trying to pull themselves out.
And so at that era,
during that time to twenties to thirties
the truth was some of the best fighters
because that was their way of getting out.
But there was other,
there was another significance to be in
a Jewish fighter that a lot of the kids,
their own thought of is bringing Tufts.
So they got picked on and,
and thought of that they're going to go
more towards academic and other stuff.
So there was a weakness
perceived not true.
None of this stuff is useful.
Yeah.
So now all of a sudden Benny
Leonard comes along when the sports,
the biggest sport in the country and
he's the best fighter in the game.
And he calmed his hair before he got in
the ring and he would come out without
it being mast.
And this was,
this guy was,
I mean he was,
he was Michael Jordan.
I mean before that stuff performed,
Michael joined before Air Jordan.
Bill pointed,
I mean this guy was down only coffee,
cause I'm only a champion,
puts obviously connected
to be in tough by itself.
But it was,
he was smart.
He was,
he was cool.
He had Pazazz,
he was a man and there
were Jewish families.
You don't hear about these stories,
but there were Jewish families I've read
and I've heard from people where say,
Hey,
don't let nobody pick on you.
Benny Leonard is the best
fighter in the world.
Choose a tough where we're
not just smart but tough.
Benny Leonard shows that.
So that kind of history,
that kind of pulling of people
up in many different ways,
not just economically I out of poverty,
but,
but emotionally,
mentally,
because you can be in poverty mentally,
you can be in a low place mentally.
It doesn't have to be,
you know,
financially all the time.
You know,
where you have holes in your shoes and
you and you're wearing shirts that don't
fit.
No,
it can be the way you feel about
yourself that is without is.
It's without prince parity,
with with without value.
You'll have no value for
yourself as a person.
That's the worst poverty
in the freaking world.
There's not the lower than that
and Joe Lewis and Benny Leonard,
they were fighters.
They won't baseball players.
They pulled people out of those places.
They let people know they had value,
that their rates had value,
their people add value,
they had value and that should be known
and you can go anywhere and I'm glad you
can because I love all sports.
You can go anywhere and you can read
about the greatness of the baseball plays
in the greatness of,
of course NFL hasn't
been around that long,
but the greatness of those players
and the greatness of the NBA players,
but where did the kids have a get to
read and to hear and to see about the
greatness of these people,
these fighters?
V Nowhere,
very little.
Very little.
It's not there.
Why?
Because again,
I'm not going to get into craziness,
but the powers that be the listen,
it's not marketed properly.
I get it.
It doesn't have a commission so
it doesn't take care of itself.
The way the UFC,
the greatness about to why the UFC grew
so much as they marketed themselves in a
tremendous way.
So there's nobody,
boxing is just dead.
It takes care of itself.
It exist because it's man against man,
so it's always going to be there,
but nobody's building it.
Nobody's marketing and no one's
feeding the monster to make it bigger.
And it's a plant that's in the corner of,
of,
of your office that doesn't get sun,
doesn't get warranted,
but it's still there.
It's still,
and what I'm saying is that
[inaudible] I didn't want to yell
because now probably happy but,
but
it should be fed a little bit.
It should be watered a little bit
because of what I just described.
Guys,
guys like you guys who have a deep
appreciation for the history of the sport
guy,
guys who have a deep appreciation
of what it meant when Joe Louis,
Max Schmeling guys,
guys who understand what it meant when
sugar ray Robinson was the best fighter
in the world and everybody knew and he
pulled up in a fucking pink Cadillac with
a beautiful suit on
and any,
any made the elevated,
elevated people in Harlem everywhere.
But Harlem,
he had,
he owned have a Harlem,
he owned restaurants and
stores and barber shops and,
and everything.
And,
and you want it to be there because
that's where sugar ray Robinson came from.
Yup.
It was great.
Yeah.
I mean,
it's a rich part of history
that really does get ignored.
Let me tell you something.
I was smelling,
you brought up,
you know,
a lot of his stuff and that's
what it's nice to talk about.
Which
smelling was a hell of a fighter.
Joe Lewis was the brown
bomber who was coming up.
He was undefeated and um,
Schmoley had to Greg
quote before the fight.
You know,
it's kind of like the grapefruit thing
that did it really happen where he
pointed out and then he hit,
you know,
those,
those are great stories,
but,
but what's the real truth behind them?
You know,
we don't know.
We don't care.
We don't care to a certain point.
You know why?
Because they let us feel good.
They let us dream about possibilities
and we should all have possibilities to
dream about.
And they make somebody feel good because,
you know,
the Babe Ruth one was
connected to a sick kid.
So it's a nice thing.
It's where sports can be better
than just sports than just somebody
participating in it.
It can go beyond that.
He agreed stronger than that and
that's some of the good stuff about it.
And so smelling the great story,
he didn't point to,
you know,
the,
to the fence,
but he said before the fight,
I see something,
uh,
with,
that's my,
my,
uh,
my trying to be an accent for the German,
you know,
but I,
I sound more like Sholtz
from Hogan's heroes.
I don't know why.
Every time you tried to do
something like with certain,
you know,
ethnic,
pronunciations,
um,
you,
you sound like you go
to one of those sitcoms,
you go to one of those places,
you know,
and when I say somebody,
I think my kid,
I think my son said,
Eh,
you know,
he had watched one of them and I think
he said he sounded like Sergeant Schultz,
like from Hogan's heroes,
but,
and he said I something and what he saw
was that Louis would jab and he would
leave.
You should never leave your head on a,
on the right side because
if you leave your head,
you know,
you move your head to the right side,
you're in a path to the right hand.
You should actually finish on the left
side because then you're outside the
right hand,
you follow,
there's the right hand over here.
It can hit you over.
Yeah.
Outside.
So he had a habit of,
and he had a great trainer.
He had a habit though at that point
of leaving his head off and a right.
So smelling saw something as
he said that he could hit.
And we were right in,
he could time it over the gym.
Now smelling was of the ilk
of the level of the caliber.
Wasn't just about talent.
He could punch it was a good fighter,
but it was a pro.
What do I mean by that?
A lot of guys would hesitate a little bit.
Same opening.
They might see it,
but it was the brown bomber
who was knocking everyone out.
So they hesitate.
They will.
They were afraid normal.
But people are afraid of that word.
I mean it's there.
I mean without it,
we're not alive.
So he,
they,
they might see the same thing,
but they weren't going at a pro level.
Pro Level is a guy that can do what he
has to do and no emotions interfere with
doing it.
I mean that's my simplest way
of Webster's might not say that,
but that's what I would say.
So they might've seen the opening but
they would hesitate just enough and it'd
be gone the door close.
Cause it's so it's like life.
It's moments captured moment,
lose a moment.
And,
but this guy was a pro.
He,
he didn't let that come in there
and make them hesitate that,
that fear,
he controlled it.
And if a Doberman was there,
Bang,
he was going to throw the punch.
So he did and he dropped lose
a few times and you know,
he,
he won that fight and
was around and stop them.
I can't even remember,
maybe,
maybe the ninth,
but it was late in a fight,
but he had heard them and you know,
Louis was taking a beating.
So Louis went on,
he won a world title and um,
he'd be Bradick for the title,
Cinderella Man.
Great movie.
It maybe,
you know,
he came from welfare to
be in a world champion.
That's the product story without
getting into it too much.
So he lose pizza product and
had to give a percentage.
You know,
Don King and Ara might
not been around then,
but,
but the people that taught him what
to do around taught them how to take
advantage of fighters,
told them of how,
of what options were for four
options where ever known,
you know,
Eh,
the Vladik I think,
I forget his name,
but products manager.
Basically made Lewis and his people agree
to give them a percentage of his purse
for the rest of his
career to get the fight.
Yeah.
So I mean you could obviously
research it and look into how much,
what percent.
So I don't know.
I listen,
I could say 10% but I don't want to say
definitively because I'm not positive,
but,
but there was an
understanding that you know,
you,
you're not getting a fight otherwise you
won't get the fight now and listen to,
like I said,
you know,
not great guys,
but king and uh,
they,
they had other guys before them that
taught them some of these moves,
you know,
that warm and so nice.
But there's always a
history of good and bad.
Sure.
Always.
Who's good?
Well this is,
if there's a,
like a shining star promoter out there,
I try to think about it,
but so we,
so they go and they are,
he wouldn't sign the title and of
course the biggest sport in the country.
So all the prices there and there,
Joe Champion was not yet.
Not yet.
What do you mean not yet?
Just one the title.
Not yet.
Not Too.
I beat that man.
He didn't even have to say his name.
Not Too,
I beat that man.
That's how much pride he had.
And listen,
he's the real deal because in his mind,
how can I be champion
if a guy knocked me out?
Right?
So when that fight took place,
I mean you talk about setting a stage,
you know,
the nowadays people say,
oh I'm on the stage is a lot of pressure,
you know,
hey,
I'm not saying it's not,
I'm not saying it,
but a lot of pressure,
you know,
Amazon,
a lot of people look in,
a lot of people,
you know,
dependent on I,
I lot of stuff going on,
you know,
and I,
maybe I got a headache,
but Cho Lewis had world
war two on the horizon.
The president of the United States
call them up and you had Nazi Germany,
he had a guy named Hitler that
that is saying that he's got,
you know,
the master race it's going
to take over the world.
Just starting that stuff was not
too far away from World War Two.
And you've got all that stuff permeating
in the air and you got Louis fighting a
guy who of course,
you know,
propaganda was started by the Germans,
if you want almost to me almost invented
that word because you had to propaganda
minister and you had all these terrible
people with Hitler that we're putting
out to dare the master race to
this day that you had to judge.
You all win situation Olympics.
Yeah.
And now you had the biggest sport in
the biggest country and the champion of
that sport to heavyweight Joe Lewis.
And he's fighting the German fighter
Schmeling the second time now for the
title.
And of course you had
Hitler and all his psycho fence
or these people that were,
their job was to promote it,
so to speak.
And they come and they're saying,
we will show the world that we're superior
and there's no better way to show it
then in a ring.
And so Lewis has to,
he's got,
and he's got to carry all this stuff.
I mean,
take about it.
And he's a black Guy Kaci that,
that he still can't go
into certain places,
teat.
And he's got to carry the whole,
he's got to carry the whole country
and not let them down in the president
because I didn't get,
we don't know if there's
a legendary story,
we don't know if it's completely true,
but supposedly the president
called him and said,
Joe,
you got to witness one for
the good guys that that's,
that's one of the legends.
I don't know if it's true,
but I know of that.
I'm sure he corner,
I'm sure we called them
and Louis has to go into,
is kind of going to Yankee Stadium
outdoors and in Times Square in New York,
they used to have it set up where they
would the radio because all the fight,
why radio back then and
some of them on fights,
on TV,
on Gillette,
Calvert,
Keto sports and all that stuff.
Friday night fights,
but was,
was coming along,
you know,
to start coming along.
But radio was the thing.
And so in Times Square you had
to radio speakers outdoors,
you know,
playing a fight,
podcasts in the fight.
So people are out on the streets,
they hear the radio and he uh,
you know,
Joe Lewis is walking into
the ring and you know,
and,
and you got Yankee Stadium,
you've got to place four and you've got
the whole world of everything I just
described.
The good,
the bad,
the evil,
the ugly,
every thing.
It's not a movie.
It's real life.
And you got Joe Lewis and he gets in that
ring and he annihilates with all this
pressure with that,
that he's got to save the,
basically the United
States in a world from,
from looking like this ugly
scorge and,
and disease of the Nazi party is,
is going to take over.
The world is greater than us and he and
he single handedly has to prove that.
And he,
he goes into any annihilates the Chi in
one round with all that stuff hanging
over them.
I think that's the greatest single
event in the history of world.
Pull that fight out,
pull out,
fight up and put it in the background.
And I think that diet,
when you talk about all the things,
the way here to talk about,
about character,
about talent,
about perseverance,
about resiliency,
about,
about caring,
about more than yourself,
about selflessness,
about strength,
when you talk about all those things
that we try to say that we care about and
that we sometimes look to,
to be,
um,
very rarely can we be that
he was all that he was all of that.
And there it is right there.
I mean,
how great is that?
And he stalked the guy,
he stalked to guy and his punches
were short and powerful and he was the
greatest finish in the history
of heavyweight bouncing.
Because when he hurts you,
you didn't survive.
He got rid of you.
He put punches together and it was
short and he was always in position.
Look at his legs.
He's always a position.
You move forward.
It takes a little stub fall back to get
yourself all those punches is absolutely
beautiful.
If you wanted to teach a young
fighter how to punch correctly,
Joe Louis,
there's no better guy
to watch and Cholon oh,
did you see Joe?
What he did a little minute ago.
No a minute ago,
smelling.
Tried to catch him with
that same right hand.
He had knocked him out two years earlier.
Go back.
They just missed it,
but he changed.
He stepped out.
He changed his distance this
time because jaggy Blackburn,
who's a great fighter,
a black fighter,
he was a training.
It was a great train and nobody hears
about Jaggy Blackburn what a great fighter
he was and what a great trainee was and
how he wasn't allowed to fight white
fighters.
And he beat everybody.
Look at that.
Cattle love talk.
Instead of laying his head on the
right like he did the first fight,
he changed his range and he
made that right hand mess.
I look how calm he is.
Look how calm he is.
Look how focused he is.
It's beautiful.
Watch shortness of those punches.
Phenomenal watches legs,
Joe.
Watch.
Watch how he's always in position.
Look at Atlanta.
Well,
what did we miss?
What didn't you see?
Go back.
The sides don't.
No.
The Blinding Jab that we
don't see what the jam was.
Just a dick boy.
Just so we can hit it with
the right so you don't see it.
Right.
What a beautiful sidestep to right
after he lands the right hand.
Beautiful.
Right.
Well that's why he's the
greatest finish of all time.
Watch,
watch,
way finishes this guy.
What it's going to go to the body
and the head right hand to the body.
Right ahead to the head.
Oh,
that is so short.
And even when he's got the guy hurt,
look at the guy.
Look at that.
Phenomenal,
phenomenal.
And he did all of that with everything
we just talked about for the last 20
minutes.
Hanging over him.
Yeah.
Oh,
it's a giant piece of history
that people don't talk about it.
Doesn't that make you think a little bit,
doesn't it make you
feel something about us?
Really?
Yeah.
Well it's one of the reasons why
I'm a giants fan of the sport.
Yeah.
Thank you.
I mean,
and that that alone is in terms
of like historical impact.
I agree with you.
It's one of the biggest moments
in all of sports ever in life.
In life.
You know what I like about boxing?
I like a lot things at all.
Like I don't like the administrators.
I hate them.
I know there's a powerful word,
but you know,
not every single one of them,
but I'm just saying I,
I,
I hate their weakness.
I hate that cowardice.
I do.
Because they sit outside the ring.
A lot of them,
you brought up a point,
they should have had an experience one
way or the other and they've never ever
had anyone.
He punched him.
And I'm not saying you to be a man,
you got to get punched.
I'm not saying any of that stuff.
It's being a man is a lot more than that.
A lot more now.
Plenty of people get
punched and then I met.
But what I'm saying is that you should
understand what it feels to a person to
put themselves on the line and to
risk so much and to risk everything
to try to get their
family in a better place.
I think there's also,
they should be a fan and I don't
think some of them are even fans.
No,
they're not.
And in some of my,
not even like it,
they wouldn't tell you that.
Right.
But they just do it for a job.
Yeah.
And,
and what I'm saying is that
when you,
when I see these people
that haven't put them,
been in that place and not
everyone can be in that place.
So again,
I gotta be careful with that
if I'm going to be fair,
but for them so easily to take
something away from somebody,
see what's different for me,
why I get passionate.
And if you want to use that word,
people say Teddy,
you can get a little crazy
if it happens in baseball and
the guy beats out to troll.
Now you have cameras.
So you didn't use half that.
But if a guy you didn't
have replay back in the day,
the guy,
it happened a lot of times,
guy was safe and,
and call him out.
You know what?
Too Bad.
It's a,
it's a shame,
but you know what?
The next day he's going to play the game
again and he's going to be able to make
amends for that.
He and his family and he's
got guaranteed contracts.
And you know what it's going to be okay.
I mean,
was it right?
Wrong is never right.
No,
but you know what,
in the mix of things
we could overcome that.
But now you take a fighter,
same thing and the judge judges
make a mistake maybe on purpose,
whatever,
but they make a bad mistake to fight.
It can't go back the next day and
rectify that to fight it doesn't have a
guaranteed contract.
He only has what he can make
if he gets to that fight.
That's it for that night.
Cause where that fight a goals,
he go back to the
dug out and then come out the next day
and play again with a new uniform on.
Now he goes to the back of the line
and boxing and has to take hundreds,
maybe thousands of punches
to get back to that place.
He was to earn the right to get closer
to the exit in a business because
everyone's trying to get to the exit.
They're trying to gain what they can
gain but their legacy with for their
families,
for themselves in many ways financially,
you know,
and,
but also what's inside them that they,
that they have to prove something,
that they have to make it
for all different personal
reasons and they're close
to doing that and now they're
forced because of some crock.
Maybe it's incompetence,
it either corruption and incompetence.
Okay.
But sometimes it's corruption and they
have to go all the way to the back of the
line.
Now then I'm playing a
football game the next Sunday,
then I play in an NBA game two days later
and they got to take all those punches
and hope,
hope
they get back to that place.
And you know what?
I seen it.
I did 22 years of ESPN boxing.
I've been with ESPN about 22 years,
but I did like 18 years,
whatever it was,
a Friday night fights.
We did a lot of title fights.
Not to big names,
not to Canelo's,
not,
not to go off gins,
not the Mayweathers.
What guys that had mentors as much
to even more because they didn't have
millions of dollars and they got this
shot and I watched them get robbed
and I saw that they never got back there.
That night was the right night for them.
That particular night,
everything worked.
Everything was perfect,
all that training,
everything came together
and they were beautiful.
They were magnificent and
they were freaking robbed
and it's wrong.
It's really wrong.
And that's what they do when they do that.
But the glorious thing
of if that's not too
made up of a word,
it sounds like glory.
But the beautiful thing about boxing is
that with everything wrong in the world,
and I hate to use this cliche,
this terminology,
but you know with life being unfair,
because I don't like to use that because,
because sometimes people nowadays,
for me,
there's too many excuses out there.
There really are.
There's too many damn excuses.
You're in this country,
you got a chance to do something
where you don't have in other places.
But having said that,
he can feel like life's
not fair sometimes,
especially when you think about some of
the things we just talked about in a day
that's gone now.
It's not there no more.
But,
well,
Dave Lewis
and all those kind of people,
life was unfair.
That really they really had a
right to use that say nowadays,
I don't think people have of white,
black,
purple,
they don't have a right to say that
to the extent that they did back then.
Not to the extent,
no,
they don't.
They really lose all the things
wrong or they're messed up.
People still out there.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But sometimes it's too easy to use that.
Yes.
It's just too easy.
So,
but there was a time when
life too often was unfair.
Ruthlessly unfair.
Really unfair.
Ruthlessly.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Okay.
And when life was unfair,
boxing was around to make it fair.
And I'll tell you how
on one given night,
if you worked hard enough,
if you dream big enough,
if you were tough enough and
you made yourself tough enough,
you sacrificed enough,
you became polished and savvy enough.
And and technically
equipped to do things that you had and
you learn those things and you just work
yourself to the ball.
No matter where you came from,
no matter what part of the world,
no matter what,
who your parents were,
no matter what your poverty
level may have been,
may not have been,
no matter what you had,
would,
you didn't have,
no matter what people had told you,
I didn't tell you
all of that.
If you made yourself and took advantage
of that opportunity and get yourself
ready
and you were ready to
behave like a champion,
you could get in that ring on one given
night and make the world fair and have
your hand lifted,
heavy call champion of the
world that makes boxes special.
And that's what these judges don't get,
that kids are waiting to hear
that and they give everything,
you know,
you hear too much to crap.
Where I would dive for that was
people that would die for that.
So have people in our times in his world,
in his country,
and you use the right world word,
you know,
tragically,
whatever powerful word you
had just shows ruthlessly.
Yeah,
yeah.
There were people because of that word,
because of the reality of the
actions attached to that world word.
If you told them,
listen you,
you got to you,
you're going to have to die,
you know after this,
but you'll get to have this,
your hand will be lifted.
You will be called champion of the
world or your people will see it and the
people you want see it and yourself,
but your die afterwards
I would give you that.
People would sign on.
That's how important that was.
That's what that stood for and then you
get judges that have no conception of
that.
I don't mean to laugh,
but no,
I learned saying they have to
have a complete conception of it,
but no feeling of what
we're talking about.
I think they're like DMV workers.
That's what I think.
I think there's a bunch of
them that are real good,
but a lot of them are just like people
that had just taken a government job.
That's what I think.
And I think it's a travesty
that they're not removed.
That's what I think when
whenever I go to a UFC and it,
like I said,
a lot of it,
the same judges,
and I see some of these,
these scores,
I want to take my fucking headset off
and throw it into the cage and scream and
flip over the table.
And you just kind of take a deep breath
and calm yourself down because there's
nothing you can do.
And these athletic commissions have kept,
kept these people on for whatever reason.
And you're watching a bad decision.
You watched someone who trained for eight,
10 weeks for this one particular fight
in years and years to get to that
position.
And they're getting fucked and the getting
fucked because someone just sucks at
their job and they don't care.
And this person,
they,
they're going to be there two
months from now at another fight.
And there's nothing you can do about it.
And I don't understand it.
I don't understand how the
commissions let this slide.
I don't know how difficult it is to
fire these people would approve they're
incompetent.
But I do know that especially with with,
oh,
I guess it's probably true
with both boxing and MMA,
there are countless fans out there.
They would do a far better job,
countless,
countless people that have,
have experienced in fighting countless
people that have a deep appreciation and
understanding of what's actually
going on inside the fight.
And these people don't get those jobs.
And instead the same fools continue
to give piss poor decisions or corrupt
decisions.
I mean,
whoever that woman was,
you know,
there's mention people's names,
but there's been some decisions,
there's been some horrific
headed for with the Mayweather.
Uh,
you told him about the
Mayweather Canelo yes.
The woman had had in a drawer.
Yes.
What?
I'm not going to,
I know a name,
but I'm not going to
her name either because
she was also involved in,
uh,
another one was it?
Yeah,
she got Tony Brown,
I think.
Manny Pacquiao.
Yeah.
She was involved in a couple.
Yeah,
a couple.
At least two.
I think we're being,
we're being responsible.
Um,
why was she still there?
Right.
Seriously.
Why was she still that?
Why?
Yeah,
why?
Why was she still there?
I mean,
we're not talking about
neurosurgeon said really,
right.
We're talking about a job.
There's a lot of people that could do it.
I'm not saying it's an easy job,
but I'm saying there's a
lot of people that are,
have a real understanding of boxing.
They would have done a way better job.
I mean,
somebody robs a bank.
They're not your bank
teller the next week.
Exactly.
Well,
yeah,
that'll all the promoters
today is golden boy.
The best.
I mean,
at least Oscar de la Jolla,
Bernard Hopkins,
they're legit world champion fighters.
They have a deal,
but they're attached to,
they got one.
They got to strengthen and got a weakness.
That weakness is,
they attached really
attached at the hip to one,
you know,
the solar system,
so to speak,
has one son and I sign is called Canelo,
but Canelo disappears
tomorrow and they're fucked.
Yeah.
They're not happy.
They've got some problems.
But listen now,
Hayman's out there,
you know,
he,
he's PBC.
You know,
he came along,
um,
he just signed a deal from what I read.
Um,
I think I'm saying the numbers right
where Fox gave him $50 million for a four
year deal to put fights out there,
and he's probably got the
best stable of fighters.
I mean,
he's a,
he's got what the guy
hasn't been fine but took,
I was,
I think was one of the best guys.
Thurman.
Um,
but you know,
he's got who I really loved.
His guy's a beast.
My son loves him.
A Spence arose fans.
He's a beast.
I mean,
the guy,
I like him inside and out.
What do I mean by that?
I mean,
he truly believes that he
should fight all the best.
He truly believes he's the best.
He truly believes he's
going to get to you.
You know what I mean?
And any fights that way.
And he's a great guy.
He's a good guy.
So it's,
it's clear.
Articulate.
Yeah.
It makes it better.
He's fun.
Got a big smile.
Yeah.
It's better.
You know,
Terrence Crawford is another one.
I'll try it.
And so,
I mean haven's got a lotta,
he's also got wilder
and heavyweight champ,
but one of the champs,
whatever that is.
But what a,
technically he's got a lot of problems,
but he's kind of one thing that's
not a problem and confidence.
But one other thing,
oh my goodness.
He's thought
instead of a hammer,
it's the right hand.
Oh my goodness.
He,
oh listen,
I mother fucker knocks everybody,
man.
He,
if he hits you,
uh,
and the Ortiz fight was very interesting.
He was hurt,
he was in bad shape and still referee
might have helped him a little,
but he was in bad shape.
And uh,
but boy,
oh boy hill,
you know,
I say it a lot of times
he had that eraser,
you know,
I remember,
I remember I was not a great memory,
but as a kid,
somehow I wound up in a
Catholic school for a minute.
And those nuns,
they,
they should have been fighters.
They were mean.
I think they were a little twisted.
Some of them but I'm not going to go to,
but they were little they would mean,
but they had no problem hitting you
in the head with that black racer.
Like you won't Pay Bang.
It just like,
and it was hard.
It was like,
I don't,
that's what I'm fine.
You know.
And he has that eraser.
He has done a razor where
bank put his technique,
his feet come up on the tone,
take the bear lands technique,
bed power,
good Sherlock log,
boom.
Really?
And he lands,
people go flying.
I mean,
and he of a giant heavyweight
either in terms of his,
but you know what he is though.
He's long and he's tall and
he looked at those arms.
He was long.
I mean he could,
if he was in here he could
hit your cost as well.
So Tyson fury and that's one of the
things that makes this fight very,
very interesting.
That's one of the times where
that's saying styles make fights.
That's gonna.
That's going to be this fight.
That's going to be the whole thing.
Tyson fury as a motherfucker.
Well,
he could move not only six,
seven or whatever the hell he is,
six,
eight,
nine long.
But he could move his,
each had legs.
Phenomenal.
Somebody forgot to tell me he's a
heavyweight because he moves around like a
lightweight and that could be
a problem until he gets hit.
Also,
it talks tremendous shit until he gets it.
Well then things change.
But I always used to say when
I was doing the broadcast,
I would always say,
and I,
of course,
I wouldn't say it if I didn't
have a belief in us and,
and the proof of it,
in my mind at least that
punches are born then I made,
yeah,
you're born or you're,
you're not born to be
a punch of that level.
You just talk.
And I'll tell you something funny that,
because you brought it up about him being,
you know,
he's not a big,
he's not that prototypical big Husky,
you know,
uh,
wedge style.
Yeah.
He's not that.
But I'll tell you when
I was training fighters,
when I was young and I was taking
them to smokers in the Bronx to get
experience,
uh,
every week,
tough places in the South Bronx,
and we were taking them to these
unsanctioned fights just to get them
experience.
And if I didn't know the fight,
I say I have,
I'm responsible for these kids back then.
I'm like their parent.
And that trusted me.
Some of them didn't have parents,
but the ones that did,
they would trust in me
to take care of this kid.
They didn't know what was
going to the South Bronx where,
where,
I remember one time I
borrowed a car from somebody,
they didn't have to cut enough car.
It was the publisher of the newspaper,
the Catskill Daily Mail.
And,
and I've gone through is
the name and the publisher.
And I bought his station wagon.
I didn't have a car pick
enough to take the kids.
And um,
as I'm leaving,
he says,
you're not taking a real bad place
where they'd like rob hubcaps.
So something.
And I was like,
no,
because I didn't think I was lying
because to me they brought the whole car.
So,
so I said no,
because he left it at hubcaps.
Right.
So I said no.
So I get there in the first
thing I did those Ipos,
the,
you know,
underneath the l you know,
for people don't know is to train subway
in the train and I underneath and,
and uh,
that was,
you talk about life grown up quick.
You in one night,
it was like live reading chapters of a
book to you went through different things
and you learn different things about
yourself and about what's there,
what you don't see.
Uh,
you haven't been around,
but it's there and it's good to know
it's there a different life to different
way.
And I'm down in the South Bronx and,
and our first thing I did,
I went to Mrs. Santos,
who was the father,
one of my kids.
I went to his ball,
cross the street,
submissive,
central,
my cars over there.
Gotcha.
And why come out?
And all the batteries of the
cars were client accept mine
quite often.
And,
uh,
but my car was good.
That's the Santos and his crew made
sure that nobody took my battery.
And so we were good.
So I was looking out for the kids
because I did what I had to do,
but it was a scary place.
It was a tough place.
And um,
the kids grew up fast.
If it was three flights and it was often
thought that it was meant to be three
flights because she had time
to think during those flights.
The first flight,
quite frankly,
are you saw syringes,
sometimes kids didn't know
non buddies' kids will care.
It's going to New York,
they really syringes
then.
Then the next flight,
you know,
you smelled urine because
people were there.
They went up there and they were,
you know,
going to bathroom,
doing whatever and shooting
up or whatever and you smell.
But then by the time
you get to dirt flight,
you've started to hear noise,
started to hear salsa music
and you,
uh,
you could smell some.
There were,
they were cooking all
the Spanish specialties,
the A to five bananas,
the uh,
the meeting with the,
with the potato in the middle
plantaris and all that.
I remember,
you know,
I don't remember all the names,
but all the different inn of course,
a lot of room,
a lot of,
there was a bar,
but that's how they kept,
that's how they paid the rent for the
gym because they would do these smokers
twice a month.
You know,
there was a smoke every week in New York.
Every week.
People had to know where they were,
but they were every week.
And Leah,
they won't sanction and
there was no doctrine.
Listen,
I'm going out there and saying,
yeah,
that don't sound too good.
I got you.
But we made it good.
Yeah,
we made it good.
We made sure we took care of two.
We've,
we've made it,
I know it was still dangerous.
It was still older,
but you want to know something?
A kid drinking a bottle of vodka a
day was pretty freaking dangerous.
Okay.
I had some idiot one time.
I was trying to get money
from my foundation and I
was explaining to him and he
was a political guy and I was explaining
to them many calls have you got brain
damage of bugs and it is very day like I,
I was trying to like you when you want
to throw your headset when you see these
trucks.
I was like trying to control,
I'm trying to talk to him.
I supposed to talk to
right guy where this guy,
but I'm going to get money for my
foundation that helps these people.
Right.
So I'm trying to talk
to them and I'm saying,
um,
do you get brain damage from being out
in the street and getting hit with a pipe
to get by deed because there's
the people I'm helping.
Do you get brain damage
arm from doing crack?
Do you get brain damage?
I did have a kid who drank a bottle of
vodka now when he gave two to my program
and the foundation that we run,
uh,
for two years,
he's been announced three years,
he's been clean or his back was family.
He was living on the streets.
He was with gangs and when he got
into boxing in one of our programs,
uh,
he,
he stopped all that,
but he was drinking a
bottle of vodka years.
True.
15 year.
Yeah.
A lot of people say,
Teddy,
how do you drink?
Uh,
yeah,
but it was how do you do it because you
have a lot of pain maybe or whatever,
whatever.
But yeah,
he was,
and so I was,
I said to the guy who was trying,
not to get into an argument,
but I was like,
boxing causes brain damage,
but I'm taking guys away,
kids that the alternative
is to bottle of vodka,
the crack the needle,
the pipe on her head or maybe the pipe
on someone else's head where they caused
the brain damage to someone else.
May.
Maybe.
Unfortunately you'll one day
walking out of your house.
What about that brain damage?
That's your way of telling me know
that your way of not giving me what I'm
asking for to say that.
Why don't you think it
out a little bit more?
Why don't you think it out a little
more and give me a better excuse?
Why don't you at least
understand what we're doing.
Yeah.
There's a reason why we're doing this.
So these kids,
we would go,
we would go to the south
Bronx and these kids would,
they'd walk up,
you know,
like I said,
they've woke up two steps
by time that door opened up.
And again,
this is how they paid the
rent by selling liquor,
by charging $3 to get in
and selling that food.
And a place would be packed,
packed.
And when the l one by you talk about,
you told him,
we talked a little bit
about pressure and about,
you know,
what pressure does to you.
It can form,
you could destroy you booker form,
you can make you realize
what you're capable of.
You know,
the greatest thing about what [inaudible]
does for somebody who makes them know
teddy,
what is box and do for you?
Oh those are your jab.
You do know your condition,
you take care of your temple,
your body,
all that stuff.
Yeah it sounds good.
Teddy,
give us one thing that
box and does for it.
Lets you know you could
depend on yourself.
Lets a kid know that he can like himself.
We don't know.
He can like himself and depend on himself.
These kids.
So
was it rough?
Was rough.
So we're in the place and
has is no doctor here.
We had no sanction in organization.
We made own fights,
but there was a danger.
But it just told you the other dangers.
This was taking them and
replacing those other dangers too.
Just taking them away from the,
you know what?
It was the only positive thing in
the neighborhood for these kids.
It really was,
was a rough,
yeah,
it's boxing,
but I just talked about life is rough,
especially for these people refer.
So it was an alternative to violence.
People say Teddy Way,
you're talking about bugs and no,
because if you're angry,
which these kids are,
if they don't learn to lose that anger,
they never become anything in boxing
because they walk in and get head.
They learned that they
can control that anger.
They could put it somewhere.
They learned that they
can control themselves.
They can depend on themselves
to be something positive.
So I would take these kids and we would
go there and we were the only white kids
in the place
and they loved us.
There were funny,
like I said,
the guy who ran it,
Nelson,
he,
he's a great guy,
but he,
you know,
I would look,
he carried a gun in his holster and
it's in his belt felt because he knew it
could be rough.
I mean,
I did,
I leave that part out to the parents
when I was taking him that the proprietor
of the place,
you know,
has a gone and every once in a while he
opens his jacket and make sure that the
people remember that he has.
Yeah.
Alright.
But they looked out for you.
They,
the kids.
I know,
I know it sounds contrary.
I get it contradictory.
But it was these kids,
they learned so much about
themselves and we protect,
I looked at,
we'd looked out for him and when it
came time to make the matches to point,
I was making about Walden.
You talked about being long and about you.
I'm sorry I jump all over the place.
But uh,
above I,
oh I learned,
cause taught me this.
But you have to learn it yourself.
You have to see it.
You have to be in it
because told me about it.
But that's only part of it.
He always told me,
teddy,
be careful with skinny wirey guys.
They had the greatest punches.
Think I was thinking,
you know this,
they're the greatest punches.
He never told me why he
let me figure it out.
I saw it.
I saw when he get him out.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
Hearns here,
but I know why now leverage.
Yeah,
talk,
whatever you call that.
And so anyway,
so here we are.
And if you saw the guy you
knew who to match with,
but if you didn't see the guy,
you had to depend on other things.
Who's the coach?
Certain cultures had no good fighters.
Certain coaches,
they're good fighters.
Another coach.
Does he have a good
realize he honest sea lion.
Does he have,
does he have an opinion that is
good or does he just say things?
So I'd have to go to all that
if I didn't know the guy,
I wouldn't put my kid in with the
guy unless I was sure what he was.
Sure.
And it was hard because
everyone was lying though.
There was like a cold.
It was all connected
to lion unfortunately.
But,
but everyone looking out for their kid,
like if you'd said it,
I'll give you an example because we,
I guess who the matchmaker was.
I became the matchmaker with,
you know,
in a place where all Spanish black anyway,
but Nelson made me the matchmaker.
You be the matchmaker and a lot of
the people didn't speak English.
So you know,
we've,
we figured out we get there,
so I'd be there.
So you make a column,
the name of the fighter,
the weight.
Yeah.
He saw you your way in.
You know,
that's one thing.
You see it.
Okay.
That's the only truth.
The rest of it got dicey.
Okay.
How many fights most important thing,
most important thing.
How many fights?
Zero.
Everyone in this place got zero fights
and Alice said nobody
got fights in its place.
Even doing this for years.
And it's all okay.
Here's the code.
Zero fights means two or three.
One,
two or three fights meant six to 10.
God forbid anyone ever said they had five,
six fights,
anywhere from 25 to a hundred.
Real,
real.
This is the world that
I lived in for five,
six years.
Took them every Friday,
every drove down to the Bronx
and got them a smoker every week.
And so you figured out
to code after a while,
but you're responsible for these kids
who you wanted every tangible thing you
could have.
So again,
if I wasn't sure how much the guy was
lying that he was lying a little extra,
I would,
uh,
I'd go to Nelson.
You know this guy?
No,
but talk to Pablo.
Talk down.
Hell,
all right.
You know the guy?
No.
Yeah,
he's stay away from no fight.
You know,
because I'm not taking the church.
But then when you get to the
point where you don't really know,
then I would just,
your instincts come alive.
You're protecting your kid.
It's your kid,
it's your kid.
As much as it's paternally your kid,
I remember one time I went up to the guy,
I couldn't get enough info.
I went up to the guy
bought Nelson as an interpreter
because he didn't speak English.
And I said
I know what we do here.
Well I'm telling you is
I'm not putting my kid in,
but to get beat up if it's fair,
it's fair by not putting them in
with a kid that's got 30 40 fights.
My kid legitimate
legitimately has two fights.
I'm telling you,
I know we don't do that here.
I'm telling you that's what he's got.
If your kid's got 40 foot,
tell me,
just tell me and say no fight and,
and I'll shake your hand and that's it.
We're good.
Yeah.
So he kept,
he stood to story.
Okay,
so we get close and I'm thinking,
I'm thinking,
I'm thinking and I'm watching a
guy warmup cause always told me,
watch the Guy Walmart,
watch them warm up.
I'll watch in a more more pop pop pop by
bap,
bap.
I said this guy didn't have to fight.
I mean,
I'm a pretty good trainer
and even with our fights,
I think I teach them technically what
they need to know before they get to
explore.
But this guy was beyond that.
I mean,
you know this was sugar ray Robinson,
so I go back to Nelson.
I said,
bring him over here again
10 minutes before the fight.
So bring them over here again,
comes off
a little bit of an attitude,
so,
right.
Everyone's got attitudes in his business.
Is it?
Hey
listen,
one more time.
I'm just want to tell you not threatening.
Yeah,
but I have to tell you this.
Okay.
It told me he's got no fights,
whatever,
to five with them when the bell rings.
If you got over on me,
I was wrong.
You were right.
Soon as the bell rings,
I'm going to see.
I'm going to know it.
Yeah,
there's not,
you can say afterwards
to say to explain it,
handle it,
and I'll stop the fight if I have
to because I'll protect my kid.
I might have to.
I do that.
I'll be coming over to you.
That's all I'm going to say.
So please,
please for you,
for me,
please.
If it's,
if it's,
if it's what I'm saying,
please just,
just tell him,
Nelson,
you don't have to tell me.
Just tell Nelson when I leave here
that we're not going to fight.
Nelson came back to me four minutes,
three minutes,
two minutes later and said,
he said no.
Fine.
Thank you.
Tell him thank you.
That's the world we lived in there,
but we got it done.
We got it done though,
Joe.
We did.
We really did.
And thank God that someone like you was
able to understand that there is a big
difference and that you can,
you know,
these guys that sandbag like that,
that's very,
very common and,
and yeah,
and see they think that they're gaining
something because you know what I mean?
They just want to fuck somebody.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And so,
but let me tell you something.
My kids,
I mean like when,
when we first started fighting there,
they had bungled Trumpsters hi.
I,
I mean my kids had never seen bong.
I didn't see Bongo drums.
That,
what am I saying?
But they were this high,
they were bilingual and they win a ring.
They only came out,
you know,
when,
when we,
when we got ready to fight and they're
playing the bongos and great music.
I mean,
really it was,
you know,
but you know what,
when you're hearing that bungle music
and you're in the ring and you're talking
to the kid in the corner and they're
outside now with the bangles and they're
playing the bongos and you're talking,
that's an atmosphere.
Yeah.
That's different.
That's real experience.
That's experience.
That's life experience.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
That's not taught in the classroom.
And,
and my kids have to six years of that
because that's about how long we did it.
No,
I was up to seven years
train of photos for cost.
So,
um,
I'm telling you,
my kids grew up,
they go,
did they all go on to be pros and did
they go on to be Olympic chair now?
But they took that and they used it
to be better at what they did into,
to have the confidence to do things they
might not have had the confidence to do
without that experience.
I got a couple of them
that have state troopers.
I got a couple of them that
are teachers in high school.
I got a co,
you know,
all different things.
Who,
couple that went to college that,
that the nobody in their,
in their history of their family
ever went beyond high school.
But they went to college and
they were kind of told them,
you're never going to go to college.
They went to college and I would like
to believe it had something to do with
that,
you know,
and um,
I,
a lot of people ask me who was your
greatly because I had Tyson to there,
you know,
he was,
he became one of them.
And um,
I remember it was funny because
when I would put it down,
like I said,
everyone lied about the experience,
but you know,
they lied about everything.
But I would put down,
uh,
you know,
the,
the age and everything else,
all the stuff for what it was worth,
you had to have something
to try to believe in.
If I didn't,
I'd figure it out from there.
So Tyson,
when I first had him,
he was 190 pounds,
not a bum.
Also 12 years old.
Okay.
That's what it was.
But that's what he was,
I mean,
that's what God made it.
So,
so I go down and I put the first fight.
Nobody's seen Tyson,
nobody's ever seen data,
but 12 years old,
zero phase flow.
Okay.
Hello
Daddy.
Now you go too far.
You like more than I
know.
You learn a lot from us.
Okay?
I said,
thanks.
That's a compliment.
I mean,
I'd take it,
I as it is,
right,
right.
I'm not like 12 years old.
190 pounds.
Please,
please,
please.
And also,
I'm going learning.
Okay.
He's 12 years old.
It's got to be 13 soon,
but he's technically,
he's 12 years older.
Gay.
Oh,
come on.
I said,
all right,
I'll make you feel bad.
I put down 70.
[inaudible] now you tell the truth.
Okay.
But I knew what I like side.
I knew what I had.
So I fought a 17 year old.
I wasn't going to find no 12 year old.
That wasn't going to happen.
Right.
And plus I get arrested for murder.
So,
oh,
what was he like at 12 years old?
Physically or mentally weak.
But physically,
what do I mean mentally weak,
not weak for the average guy,
but before fighter,
um,
he's still have remanence
he still had residual
stuff from his upbringing.
Listen,
you wanna know the truth about the guy.
He orders,
but he used to hide in between abandoned
building walls in Brownsville was a
rough place.
No doubt about it.
Didn't have a father of whatever,
the mother of whatever.
And uh,
he,
he used to hide between
walls to not get picked on.
And I believe when you do that,
you never get outside of that
wall to a certain extent.
You're always hiding in our
wall for the rest of your life.
That's just my belief that teddy,
what are you talking about?
It became everyone chip.
Some people think he's the greatest.
I begged her.
I don't have his record in front of me
and this is going to blow some people
crazy,
but what are you going to do?
I don't have his record.
Let's just say we're going to make an
arbitrary number because your man is going
to pull it up,
but let's just say it's 50 and six I
would say five 15 five but whatever.
I think his record
is truly,
if you're going to be this,
and we're not truly in life with anything,
but if we're truly,
truly in an Absolut world,
which we don't live in,
but I would say he's all in five.
I know everybody says everyone who is
listening to you think it's just like,
let me get with Teddy's drinking,
like I don't see them drinking nothing,
but he probably had
some before he came in.
To me,
a fight is not a fight into
this resistance to there
is something to overcome,
something to overcome.
Otherwise it's just an athletic venture.
It's an exhibition.
I think life is that.
I think the,
you don't know of a
lawyer is a lawyer into,
into the some,
the overcoming the courtroom.
Something goes for,
okay.
I know he's a lawyer.
I know.
He went to see,
I get it.
Nobody has to tell me that,
but he ain't a lawyer.
He ate that until everything goes wrong.
The judge throws all this crap out and,
and he's,
he is EFT,
so to speak and,
and he figures and he's still handles it.
Then he's a lawyer.
A doctor is not a doctor too.
He opens up this kid,
a kid.
It's just like he's got it.
Home and arteries are bleeding
all over the place and,
and it,
it's not in a textbook.
It's not in a big and
textbook and he got to do it.
He got to figure it out and he got,
then he's a doctor that he's
a surgeon at that level.
You,
you're not,
yeah.
You are not in a fight.
I,
I look,
I admitted.
I equate life to a fight.
I do.
You're not in a fight.
And so there's pressure
resistance overcoming something.
Otherwise it's just an exhibition.
Tyson's talent was so great.
His physical ability,
his talent was so overwhelming.
Just like somebody
intellect to some parties,
charisma,
whatever beauty until it
came to something else.
But his talent was so superior that
the other stuff never got tested.
He was blown guys out and
he had never got tested.
If there was anything in the warehouse,
so to speak of is anything
inside you never knew.
And then five times,
whatever the real record is,
five times there was resistance.
Five times it became a real fight.
Five Times.
It was something to overcome.
And He fell it all five times.
He was only in five fights
in his life and his own five,
I'm sorry sal graves,
because we know my history with them.
I am.
Am I capable of died?
Newman.
Yeah,
but I can honestly tell you
that I,
I took,
um,
I try to be better than that,
that,
that I've called many
fights where the people,
the corner,
I couldn't stand him.
I had no respect for them.
But if they,
if they did a good job in a
corner to fight it did a job.
I talked to about,
I'm like,
they were radio cell like they were
Angelo Dundee because that's what it was
supposed to be.
That's all.
And it's selfish because I don't want,
I wanna have,
I wanna know and I want my kids to
know that I can be better than that.
That,
that it's,
it's about right.
Okay.
It's about the code of,
of the profession.
It's a,
it's about you.
It's about,
you believe in that.
Would you say is
she'll be honest.
It should be what you believe.
It shouldn't be tainted or,
or,
or influenced by lesser things that,
that it does represent you.
It does represent your family.
It does represent where you came from.
It does stay.
Do you know your blurted out for those
five minutes or maybe two hours on ESPN,
but it stays somewhat,
could go back to it.
You could go back to it.
How do you feel about it?
It does mean,
so it really does.
And so I'm only saying it because I
would say it about somebody else in a way
that I calibrate things.
The way that I evaluate things that I
don't think that you know crap about
somebody until they're tested.
You don't know the friend.
You don't know if they're good wife.
You don't know if the good girlfriend,
you don't know crap you think you do,
but until they're really tested,
you don't really know.
And Tyson,
when he got tested,
when he had to overcome some,
when,
when he didn't run him over,
like,
like one of those big monster trucks
running over a Volkswagen because he was a
monster truck pull Volkswagen's.
Yeah,
he was.
And was he wanted the greatest punches or,
yeah.
Yes.
Could he pumped from
either side of the plate,
like Mickey Mann or the
greatest switch hitter?
Was He that in by,
yes.
Could.
He could punch evenly.
Great with either hand.
For me,
the side,
was he all those things?
Yes.
Was he as great intimidators Sonny Liston?
Was he a great finisher like Joe Louis?
To a certain extent,
yes.
Okay.
But he wasn't a great fighter.
Yeah.
Because great fighters won.
The fight came to them.
They found the way to
do what they had to do.
He found a way to disappear.
They found a way to show up.
Yeah.
Show up.
He found the way to go and not show up
and look.
You could go talk to psychiatrists and
you could go to all the reasons why.
Hiding between a wall when he was a kid.
Yeah.
That,
that's part of it.
I'll tell you another part of it.
To be that,
not to be the power puncher,
not to be the aggressor,
not to be.
Just those things.
To be,
to tighten,
to be the Viking,
to be the Samurai,
to be the warrior,
to be those things has to be inside you.
You have to believe it.
It all.
A lot of times people lie in life.
This is Fullerton plays.
You can't lie.
You know?
Sometimes we'd say that the
ring is a chamber of truth.
You know,
it sounds good and all that,
but it is.
It is because just just like
in other places in life too,
when moment comes
for those kinds of serious things.
Okay.
You have to feel like that.
You say that you're the conqueror,
you Alexander the Great,
you all those things.
Right.
Okay.
Words sounds great.
Makes good soundbites.
Probably bring more people to the TV,
but when the moment comes and you didn't
intimidate a guy that didn't work.
Okay.
We all try it to a certain extent.
Right?
Probably.
Yeah.
I'm sure you've looked at guys certain
ways when you were younger and and you'd
purposely looked at them in
a way to invoke a certain
kind of action,
a certain kind of result,
fund them.
Just,
just look at them in a real serious
way that you hope that we can them.
Yeah.
And but because I know your background,
you were prepared to do
what came after that,
but some people aren't,
some people aren't.
And Tyson wasn't as great as he was.
I just said it.
He's great guys that hate me for today.
Your hero or whatever,
your favorite guy,
he's great,
she's not great.
And in his area.
And when that moment comes,
you have to,
that's where the truth matters.
You have to believe that you really,
that guy.
And if you're a guy that he
lives and he was convicted.
So I think it's fair.
They've raped somebody.
Okay,
now listen,
I was in an Nav Rome and I don't know,
a lot of people don't take okay,
but he was convicted or,
but I know enough people in the business
that there was a lot of other bad
things that he did that it just not things
that that you would probably want to
hang around with somebody if you know,
if you're a halfway decent human
being that he did devil week things.
Okay.
Week thing.
So when you do read things
and you know you did though,
and I don't know what,
but I'm just saying you do week things
and you know they will week things and
now you got to do a strong thing.
How do you become strong when you know
that you did those weak things and you
know that's really you and you've
got a guy a cause from your name,
Nevada Holyfield that doesn't give
a shit about how hard you punch it.
Does it give a crap about
what a finisher yard does?
It give a crap about how fair is
you put your punches together.
He wants to find,
you're going to have to make him a
believer by doing it and doing it in a
difficult place because he's got to make
it difficult because he ain't got to
cooperate.
When that happens,
you got to feel like that person and
when you don't feel like that person,
you got a problem
and that's what happened.
Wasn't a matter when he bit his ear,
it was a matter that he was hungry and
he was a savage and he was from the
should stop the crap.
It was a way to get out
because he knew he wasn't
that guy and when you're not,
that guy goes,
what do you have a great talent off?
Recognize when somebody is
there as your greatest talent.
He can recognize when somebody is,
and he recognized that Evander Holyfield
was and I was his way to get out
and he did.
So that's why again,
it's not sour grapes.
It's really not because
I'm more selfish than that.
I really do care about what well my
reputation is and whether or not,
uh,
I've been honest about things I say.
It doesn't mean I'm right per means.
I believe it.
I do care about that.
I do.
And so it's not that it
doesn't mean I'm right,
but it means I have a reason to
believe on right from the way of live,
from what I've seen,
what I've experienced in the business,
the human condition,
how strong it can be and how we could,
can be.
And,
um,
he was a strong guy is
you ever going to see?
But he was his week a person
as you ever going to find
that's intense.
But I see what you're saying in terms
of you are judging it by the highest
standards possible.
You're judging it in
comparison to other champions.
You're judging it.
You,
you what else you got to
jump through with Joe.
Yeah,
of course.
Well,
you look at guys who are known for
incredible heart and their ability to come
back like Diego corrals,
Daigle,
corrals,
and some of those wars when
you would say could steal.
Yes.
That was one of the
greatest fights of all time.
The forest of credible,
greatest fight of all Micky ward.
Arturo.
Gary,
the first one,
right?
Not the second door.
The first,
the first.
Unbelievable.
I mean,
no,
if you want to go back,
if you want to go back farther,
most a lot of people will know this,
but you should call him was involved
in a lot and unfortunately he paid the
price.
Okay.
Yes,
but Bobby should call it in the 70s
eighties he was involved in those fights
every other day.
You know,
I'm just kidding.
But he was invited to
many of those fights.
Yeah.
And unfortunately you don't know about
Bobby should call and you talk to
somebody again,
I'm not like the baseball thing.
You talk about the average guy,
Bobby Chicago,
and who the hell is that?
Who the hell is that of course is the
guy that would know his name anymore.
But uh,
he was a pretty special
guy and everything.
He was pretty damn tough.
Tougher than most people.
There's guys that unfortunately
relied on that toughness.
Right?
Yeah.
Like when you,
when it comes to guys
known for incredible Chins,
that can be a detriment.
Yes.
And it can be if that's all you have.
Do you think that's what you have?
Cause she used to put it this way cause
she used to that because he wanted me to
a great trainer.
So cause she used to always be with me.
All the tools,
you know,
scientists and cause would say date.
Got Two tough guys.
Okay,
Gotcha.
Now what's tough,
it's a prerequisite to being a fighter.
You better be tough.
But what Lovell,
so all levels,
degrees and I got you.
But how special is being tough?
Because if you're a fighter
you should be tough.
I got Ya.
I'm listening.
So you got two tough guys,
but one of them is smart.
Taught,
developed.
That's him.
He's tough one now.
That's how he explained it.
Tougher because he's smart.
Yeah.
Tough and smart.
He,
he goes from here,
he's here because he's not just
dependent only on toughness.
So He's tougher than this guy,
cause he don't have to
depend on just that.
Right.
You might not even have to get to it.
It's there as a reserve.
It's always there to call on like an army.
You call on,
you need it.
Right.
But he's not dependent just on that.
Isn't that the balance though,
is knowing that you have it.
Yeah.
Knowing that you have it and there it is.
See what you just said.
You have to know that you it.
Yeah.
Tyson didn't know he was it.
Were you ever admit that?
No.
He probably knocked me and say dessert,
whatever.
I don't,
it's okay.
And so I get I,
Well there's certain people that you
can't question and the random Holyfield's
one of those people,
that's why that fight was so
fascinating because it was,
feel was he is a 100% warrior.
Well,
he had to write nickname.
Most of them don't.
Most of them don't have to write
fight nickname and whatever they do.
Right,
but the real,
the real deal,
he was the real deal.
Yeah.
And you know why small heavyweights,
you want to know why?
I mean trace it back,
cause always told me this but I
learned it in natively on my own too.
But trace it back to the parents,
trace it back to the background to
trace it back to all that stuff.
Trace it back.
He did.
He didn't live up to something.
He didn't face something.
He didn't do.
Whatever it was.
There was about,
he had a mother that he talked
about a few times and I,
I'm sorry,
event of,
I'm not saying exact but,
but it's,
it's there
that and a great model obviously,
but she,
they had a,
the crop up in Georgia,
I think it was Atlanta of
whatever suburb of Georgia
and she,
you have definite age and know
different time down south and all that.
Had a little,
I guess a little shack in the back
with a thing called twitches switch.
It switches,
I'm sorry,
I'm twitching
switches.
And
she basically
had different size switches,
you know,
short ones,
long ones,
medium ones depending on the occasion.
And when he didn't live up to
what he had to tell the truth,
whatever,
be accountable gay
face where he had to face whatever,
um,
she had a switch for him and you know what
it um,
informed him cause he faced things.
Tyson,
Tyson on the other hand to listen
did he asked for it and now my,
he didn't ask for that upbringing.
I get it.
But I know people have that upbringing
and they get to a point they can,
they can make a left
turn instead of a writer.
Is your ability to make a choice.
There's also the,
the overwhelming hype and celebrity
involved in Mike Tyson in his prime,
it was probably so difficult for
them to even understand himself.
Yeah.
But,
but what he did understand,
and I'm glad you said that
right backwards,
what he did and what he did understand
was there was a way out of Anda learned.
There was no way out,
you know,
put those away.
And you know what I mean?
Right.
Yeah.
Somebody would come and pay and he did a
lot of things before he became champion
and somebody was always there with a check
or cash or whatever and would absolve
them from,
it would,
would not have to face what he did.
Right.
And,
and,
but there was a switch that Amanda had
to face and that's what made him what had
made him.
And that's what allowed Tyson
part of would move loud.
Tyson,
you look,
you make your own choices
at a certain point in life.
So there's not make too many excuses,
but it is part of it that,
that he was formed by what he was
allowed to do when he shouldn't have been
allowed to do those things.
So that was one of the issues
that you had with costs,
right?
Yeah.
That you felt like cus was ignoring his
own principles and teaching because this
guy was so special.
Yeah.
And cause he was getting older and cass
recognize you didn't have much time left
in this guy had a legitimate shot at
being a world champion and for cause
everything in his June or everything
in the world of boxing success.
And everything.
He was great.
He was special because his whole life,
he didn't get married for a reason
because he was married to box.
And as he said that it wouldn't been fair.
I mean this was a different guy
that it was boxing his whole life.
Everything.
Life was boxing and lessons
were connected to boxing,
everything.
And um,
principals boxing.
And uh,
so there's,
uh,
there's a guy that his whole,
you know,
you used that word legacy,
but really his whole existence was boxing.
And for him it was heavyweight champs.
He had Floyd Patterson,
youngest heavyweight champ ever.
That was cost.
That was because it
was about lightweights.
Lizard.
He had lightweights.
He had welterweights,
Jose Torres,
Jose toys,
light heavyweight champion.
Exactly right.
He had other guys too.
But it was the heavyweight champion of
the world because it was around where we
talked about before when
box was the biggest sport,
bigger than baseball.
And it was the heavyweight champ of the
world was Babe Ruth was rocky Marciano
and that,
and you're going to say that before you
leave this earth that you have a chance
to have another heavyweight
champ that might be the best,
could be one of the best ever and
could break Patterson's record,
which was part of the plan,
part of the plan.
When costs was alive,
you're going to break Patterson's reg.
He broke it,
he became the youngest
heavyweight champion.
And so when you float that out there,
if you will,
and,
and tempt a guy with that,
even a great guy like cause some
things are going to be pushed aside.
And Ethan,
yeah,
compromised.
And he did.
Do you think if he didn't do that the
Tyson would have been a different person?
Okay,
I'm going to use his words there
was told to me by great promoter,
Mickey toppy passed away.
It was close to Jim Jacobs who was close
to cause and he was up there sometimes
after I left and all that.
And Mickey wanted me to train all those
fighters and he was a great promoter.
Mickey.
He had great sayings.
He was a very witty guy,
but he was a sharp guy.
Boxing was his life too.
And he ran everything in
London with three partners.
One of them was Java sustain
who owned Wembley Stadium.
So they were powerful.
They ran everything.
They were the cartel in
London back in those days.
He told me that before cost died,
that cause had said some nice
things about teddy atlas,
but he said and loads,
I know there's a danger
that this can be convenient.
You know what it means self serving crap.
Sometimes you got to trust whatever.
I was told by Mickey that he said that
Teddy Atlas was right by the way,
was wrong,
was who's going to get in a way of the
possibility of making a great fighter.
Um,
if he did things his way as
far as the disciplining in the,
you know,
whatever.
Um,
eve,
in other words,
whether he left it like that,
so I don't know.
So I know what I think it meant that
Thaisa wouldn't have been around if you
did,
if discipline,
that he would have laughed.
I don't know because I don't know that
he had those options because he was a
ward of the state and,
uh,
you know,
it was coming out of obviously a
criminal situation who's coming out of a
juvenile detention center
called Trion up outside of old,
30 miles outside Albany.
Um,
you know,
so I don't know that he had,
but basically that if
teddy did it his way,
he was right.
But he was wrong because it would have
ruined the possibility of a great fighter
and I couldn't let that happen.
So I don't think that it's,
I don't know if it's true,
actually.
I don't know.
You know what I was about to say?
I don't think that's true
because of course it's me,
right?
I want to make myself feel good.
So I want to say you could
have the best of both worlds.
We good.
We had maybe a better person or
within the realm of a better person,
right.
Boundaries,
There were no boundaries.
Maybe there would have those boundaries
would have made a difference.
Right.
And you still would have had the talent.
He was so at the talent wasn't going to
dissipate because I have to discipline,
you know,
that you put on them as a human being.
That wasn't going to change.
But um,
because because we're saying
that it wasn't going to happen.
Maybe you'll lose them.
Maybe it goes to someone else at a
certain point in his development.
Maybe that's what he meant.
I don't know.
Well,
you had that with Shannon kitchen.
Shannon Briggs.
Yeah.
Shannon brings,
came from Brownsville and he was,
I had him as a young developing program.
We got to a certain point.
Oh,
you also had that situation with him
where you felt like he wasn't 100% in,
he wasn't doing the things
you wanted him to do.
He was,
he was lacking in a certain amount of
discipline or he was distracted in a
certain amount of ways that bothered you
to the point where you didn't want to
work with them anymore.
It wasn't committed,
I didn't think completely.
But,
uh,
he was a smart kid.
Take your kid.
Talented,
talented,
very talented,
smart,
you know,
he knew how to market himself.
He had to dreadlocks and he
made them orange and you know,
nobody was doing that back then and he
could punch it was talented and he looked
good,
you know?
Yeah.
Um,
but it's real commitment.
I didn't think because then,
and maybe in the two to
his credit he had other,
he was smart and he
thought of other things,
but
he never really bought in
that this is the end all was boxing that,
that,
that was the complete,
I don't want to use just as average,
same standard word.
Commitment,
right?
Like what the figures that
sometimes like commitment,
but
more than commitment.
He said all the right things because
they had investors and they had different
people.
It's their bad thing.
Everyone does.
If you're talented enough,
you draw those kinds of things.
To his credit,
he deserved it.
He did something to bring
investors and people to back them,
but he got so used to saying
what they needed to hear
that he never knew what he needed to hear.
He never,
he and what he needed to hear and
believe was that I'm really gonna do
it.
He got so good at selling it that
he never got good at buying it.
He never really,
he just thought that I
ride this train and tool
I write is trained to,
I fall off or tore comes off
to track or to comes to stop,
but it is going to come to a stop and
I'm not saying everyone can have that
confidence.
Everyone can have that belief.
I'm not saying that,
but you have to get it somewhere.
Sometime he didn't believe that
the train was really going here.
He believed that it was just going to
go to a place where it was going to be
better than where he was and
that that he'll ride it as long,
but he,
he's not committed to staying on it.
It when,
when,
uh,
when it turns come up and
it gets a little fast,
he doesn't believe that he's
really going to get there.
He believes that when that first turn,
second turn,
third turn,
whatever on a rails coms
that that's going to be it,
but it's going to be,
it took a better place than he was at it.
Earned him some money and
got him some things and,
and it was good,
but he never really,
there's that word committed,
but he never really believed
and a lot of people don't.
They find their way along the way,
but he never believed that what he told
the people around them that he was going
to be,
he never believed that his
personality was too good.
His personality was too sharp.
He,
he,
he could say all the right things and
became easier to say the right things then
to believe the right thing.
Does that make sense?
It does make sense.
This uncompromising
psychology of combat sports,
this uncompromising philosophy.
Is this something that you got from
costs as is something that you inherently
understood from working closely with these
guys and taking them to these smokers
in the South Bronx?
Where does this come from?
Okay.
Just raw honesty scene at all.
Listen,
the comes from,
again,
you don't want to be Corny,
but it comes from live in a certain way.
Life was seeing things
traveling today as part of it.
Definitely.
But the,
the articulation of it,
the blueprint or map of it to seeing of
the visualization of it on paper comes
from costs.
Who's a genius?
Who was Devon's his world.
The,
the theory of it,
that's the better way.
The theory of it comes
from [inaudible] to living.
The doing of it comes from my father.
I had a father that most box
and people don't come from,
although parroted great Mexican fighter,
but he came from something like that.
He was,
he wanted to be a lawyer actually.
But anyway,
and you'd think Mexico,
you'd think why he came from the,
you know,
the,
the dirt floors and the stuff which
a lot of guys come from and you know,
they pull them cell phone
and that's part of the,
obviously the motivation.
But
my father was a doctor.
It was a GP practice,
55 years.
Stan,
our New York,
again from the Bronx Santa,
he founded two hospitals.
He built a house for 22 beds in,
it was called sunny side some,
I don't know if that stuff even
existed in Google back then,
but anyway,
with Sunnyside hospital
and he built it so that
all people,
I listened,
he builds it.
So poor people,
he was,
he grew up very poor.
He,
he just,
he was in that kind of
allow is because he just,
he built his hospital so that the less
of people with less could get hospital
care because back in those
days there were no HR moles.
There was no Obamacare,
there was no,
you know,
whether you think it's good,
it's bad.
It said it doesn't matter.
There was nothing he wound up
in a clinic may be you got,
well,
unless you had a doctor
that that took k and he was,
and who are the doctors?
He wasn't the only one,
but he was the only one I know.
And he founded Sunnyside hospital for 22
beds in her lesson about 25 years until
the Verrazano Bridge was built.
The city put the highway in there.
It changed,
sat down.
Obviously,
if it connected pro-Clinton stand out
and you didn't have to take a ferry boat.
And He,
um,
the city border farmer and then he went
and found a doctor's hospital with 60
other doctors,
but he was the original founder,
him and a guy named doctor Tim Pawn Sr.
He founded doctors,
which was a big hospital.
I said 30 years.
There was a big hospital,
but,
so he was a guy that he didn't waste
time telling me how to live and how all
that stuff,
the only thing I remember
was you say some do.
It
was,
I mean,
and then I watched him as a kid.
He was my hero.
I mean,
I liked Mickey Mann.
Oh.
And I liked Cholo is,
you know,
all those things and
it's like any other kid.
But if I had a hero,
I didn't know what a hero was.
Am I going to make believe I knew,
but I know now what it's supposed to mean.
Right.
So he was my,
and I just,
I watched him,
you know,
when I went in his room one
time when he graduated Nyu,
they didn't have money,
so he had to get scholarship.
He had to get help from different teams,
whatever they had to do.
But he got,
he went to Nyu medical school,
Nyu Undergrad,
and then he interned at Bellevue,
which he wasn't a big talker,
but he told me,
he did tell me,
when you graduated Bellevue,
you were ready thing.
So of later in my life,
I took that as the South Bronx.
You graduated to South Bronx to smokers.
You were very funny thing.
You learned that you're
ready for anything.
You learn how to match,
make you ready.
You'll learn how to be a trainer.
You ready fairy thing.
So he,
you know,
he,
he came,
I did knock on his door when he was,
what it was in turning
a Bellevue of young guy.
You know,
apparently he saved some obese woman's
life that had a heart attack in the
street.
He dragged,
dragged her off the street,
whatever,
the,
you never get the whole story,
but he saved a life and
he developed a hernia at a
grown to a double hernia.
And my father was a kind of guy.
He didn't let anything
interfere with his patients,
his work,
he didn't take time to get it.
So he carried it for 30
years and he finally got it,
you know,
and so it become a double hernia.
I know hernia is now.
They do the mash and
they do lays in there.
But in those days it was
a more serious thing.
He was evasive surgery.
Um,
it was different.
It was,
and it was painful apparently.
And uh,
I did knock on a door as a young kid,
you know,
very young,
but I still remember,
and it was a mirror here and he was over
there near his bed when the mirror was
here.
So I opened the door and in the
huck should have knocked obviously.
And um,
I saw he was bent over in pain.
I mean,
I could recognize and
he was wearing a thing.
I had no idea.
It was like,
I didn't know what the figures that,
but it was probably not as
you are probably need you
again to give me the proper
pronounciation thank you for,
but it was trust,
I think it was,
yeah.
Suck as gutsy.
Yeah.
It was leather.
Things like this and you know,
I was like,
I don't know what the
figures that you know could,
but I could see he was in pain and
he had this thing on and he got mad,
told me to get out.
And um,
for the rest of my young life
I knew there was some wall.
I knew he was in pain every
day and he never showed it.
He never uses juice.
He worked every day,
including Sunday has office hours,
word joke because if
it's said on the thing,
you know,
four 30,
he stayed till nine 30 because he
didn't leave till the last patient left.
And most of them Warren panel.
Okay.
You know,
he,
he took the patients that
other doctors didn't take,
took all the Medicare,
Medicaid,
whatever was whatever the
right one is basically welfare.
He took all of them and you know,
he made the,
he had the biggest practice on Stan arm,
maybe the biggest in New York.
So all the,
all the,
all the drug salesmen,
they,
they all migrated to his place.
You want to get his account
to sell the new stuff,
to sell the drugs,
to sell the pills.
And he used them.
He didn't hide it,
but he made them,
he made them give them
huge amount of samples.
You know why?
Because his patients couldn't
afford to fill the prescriptions.
So we would give him the free samples.
I used to always wonder
what the free call,
he said,
I know how to open up a closet.
There was like things falling on you,
you know,
like pills and stuff as
like what is hot and,
but it was so he could give it to
them so they didn't have to fill a
prescription because they didn't,
there was,
again,
there was none of those things that
pay for your prescriptions that they do
today.
And they couldn't afford it.
They couldn't afford to go to him,
but he charged them $3 $5,
whatever,
whatever it was that they could afford.
And you know,
he made money.
I mean,
he was a doctor,
but he didn't make the money
that other doctors will make it.
But he was a real doctor.
Right.
For me at least.
And,
but more importantly,
he didn't talk about it.
He did it.
And he,
every day he was in pain.
Later on,
I was a little older,
but I was still a young teenager.
I saw him put a white
pill onto his tongue.
I didn't know what the freak that was.
I later on I found out it was nitrile.
That is hardwoods put skipped beats.
But he still didn't say a word.
Didn't talk about it in all of,
he didn't have a son who
thought he was his hero.
He,
I wouldn't have known because
I looked at everything he did.
And you know,
he,
um,
he did house calls.
He did house calls,
who is 80 years old,
charging $5,
whatever.
Nothing.
He had patients that could
not get to an emergency room.
They didn't have the ability to get there.
They didn't have a car,
they wouldn't shape
where they couldn't get,
they couldn't take a bus,
whatever.
But so he did house calls
and a patient when he died,
they all said,
hey Lou,
you sometimes you had to
wait to one in the morning.
But he got there.
That was the thing.
He always got there.
He always delivered.
And with all those things that I knew was,
you know,
his,
his kid,
he never used it,
made an excuse.
And he was a fighter.
Yeah.
You know,
in,
in their own way.
He was to,
you know,
he was the best fighter of his
sore and he didn't talk about it.
He didn't articulate it,
you know,
he didn't wax poetic about it,
like cause state and
cause was a great man,
but he did it.
He did right in front of my face.
Okay.
And,
uh,
and it stayed with me.
You know,
I didn't understand a lot of it too.
I got Olga,
but then suddenly I understood all of it.
Okay.
And,
um,
so if somebody says,
hey,
you know,
I can't do this because you know,
last night my girlfriend,
my wife yelled at me and she
caught me with a girl and she did.
I mean,
I don't want to hear it.
I don't want to eat,
I don't want to hear it
and listen,
it was of course to me too,
in some ways it's not perfect
because when my father died,
I went to the,
I went to the funeral and then I went
to the gym and I didn't tell nobody.
And listen,
I probably shouldn't.
A lot of people would probably say he
can't live your life to weight by what
people say.
I get it.
But I'm just saying I'm aware of it.
All right?
A lot of people who say you
shouldn't have went to the gym.
My father,
we lost a kid.
He just five years old,
and I wasn't going to say this because
I don't know how some people say it,
but if it is,
it is.
Right.
So you could take it the
way you want to take it.
I know the kind of man he was.
But
you talked about commitment absolute
as you talked about certain things,
right.
Maybe this explains some of it.
We had little Todd,
he was all proud of,
he was born with foot problems.
Who's retarded?
You don't use that word anymore.
But in those days it was
okay to use that word.
That's what he was.
Okay.
Now of course you say
that it was impaired,
mentally impaired,
whatever.
Okay,
so beautiful kid.
I remember
I was older,
I was the oldest.
He was very loving.
I remember used to jump into
my arms when I come home,
so I know he was very trusting because
I would walk up the steps and it would
jump from the steps if
I didn't catch them,
obviously would have fell.
So it was part of his condition,
but it was part of his
lovingness and has his trust.
So when he was five years old,
he had to get surgery.
He had a problem,
was hot,
it was open house,
her,
hers.
We opened ours.
Heard who's old?
Different story back then.
Right.
And where did he get out of probation?
Yeah,
he did.
And my father's hospital,
my father did not perform the surgery,
of course,
that you're not going to do that.
But it was there.
So it was this,
a few sergeants might've been five,
whatever it was.
And um,
okay.
My mother was the opposite.
I have,
my father was a Hungarian
Jewish background,
you know,
uh,
he,
he had no father.
He died young.
His mother,
they were very poor.
My mother grew up poor too.
Shoes,
Irish,
Irish Catholic,
different lakes.
And my father didn't
have time for religion.
My time for that time for
living and for healing people.
So he let us be brought up Catholic.
That was up to my mother.
And,
uh,
so he,
yeah,
they were different.
They would the opposites.
When mother was beautiful,
she was Miss Staten Island.
A Mother didn't let her father died.
Also young,
uh,
her mother was a tough
Irish woman and she,
my grandma,
she,
she did not allow her
from winning Ms. Dot.
[inaudible] she was
supposed to go to them,
obviously to Miss America.
She wouldn't let it go.
Look,
I'd say right out she
thought that was for horse.
Like,
like you go do that.
You know,
even though she wanted,
she led,
that was cute,
but now you're going to go miss America.
You're going to go,
no we're not.
She said,
no,
you're not doing it.
And she had a chance to go
and try out for the rock cats,
which most people are.
They know what they are.
The dance group in Radio
City Music Hall now.
That's for those people told them no.
So she was beautiful and she had
a great personality and she's,
she love social life.
And two is the antithesis of my father
and a lot of ways and I guess opposites
attract and if you want
to make a movie out of it,
she was sick
and he,
she wasn't getting better.
And my father was in the hospital,
he was in,
I guess his patient was in the tool room,
whatever,
whatever.
Then he became a doctor
and a help to get better.
She had a form of hepatitis,
um,
back in the days when you didn't get it
from needles only he could get it from
eating a bad clam,
whatever.
I don't know if it was c whatever it is,
I'm not going to tell you
because I don't know for sure,
but,
and she was very sick and anyway,
he,
he took care of her and they got married.
They fell in love and
in all of that stuff.
So,
you know,
just,
um,
my father was a,
like I said,
my father was,
he,
he was dedicated to,
uh,
to that life.
Uh,
but the thing that he did
that I started to say,
and I don't want to give that background,
I guess,
but
my,
my mother was very emotional.
My father's a doctor.
He hid his emotions.
Okay.
And when Todd one for surgery,
he died on the operating table.
He had told my mother,
my father never lied.
Okay.
He told her the risk,
but my mother want to believe
what you want to believe.
My mother said,
you said it would be okay.
No,
he didn't say that,
but,
you know,
but of course my mother,
my father was high level to,
you know,
made her better.
I can't make you sound better.
So he died.
We all got split up.
I had to live with an uncle that was
single and it was a very handsome guy,
just like want.
So he had girlfriend coming in
and out all the time and you know,
he was,
uh,
and you know,
he was a young,
good looking guy and liked to go out.
I'd wind up sitting in
a bar waiting for them.
I get a lot of bags of potato chips,
a lot of cokes,
you know,
he could finally come back.
I have eight cooks in front of me,
maybe 10,
you know.
And,
um,
we got split up from,
my mother was sleeping in a cemetery.
She had a nervous breakdown,
but you know,
she got herself together.
She overcame it.
But,
um,
she never forgave him.
Yeah.
You know,
and,
um,
you know,
she was Irish and then the easy thing
is to Irish curse and all that stuff,
but you know,
she drank.
But,
um,
she,
uh,
she's a great woman,
but she was tragically hurt and you know,
everyone copes with things
differently and she,
uh,
it was,
it was difficult.
And that day with all of the,
what I just described,
and again,
I'm always afraid to say it,
but you say it because it's part of it,
right?
Maybe it explains,
maybe,
maybe some people hold it
against him when I say this,
but he got a phone call that
day on his answer and surface.
And you didn't have pages in those days.
He had an answer and surface.
He told them to call him when
he had requests for house calls.
Two in the morning as a kid,
I used to hear the phone ring.
It was tuna morning.
I started getting dressed.
I came out and I was on the
stairs waiting for the golf.
He looked at me,
what were you doing?
I'm going,
which now,
you know,
get back in the mall.
You know,
sometimes you let me go with them.
And,
um,
anyway,
this day,
obviously it was a different
day and there was a,
his patient has patient's
daughter had a child who was very,
very sick.
She did not know that has some,
the mother,
no,
but the daughter didn't know
that his son died that day.
That his son was buried that day,
I should say.
So she called,
he went and did a house
call on a day that is,
you know,
that his son got Barry.
You know,
that's tough.
But that was what,
you know,
that's what his,
um,
so when people tell me that
they can't keep a commitment,
this happened,
it doesn't go with me.
That's all.
And that day after I buried my father,
I went to the gym
and I trained Michael Moore
because I was,
you know,
that's what I was doing.
That was my job,
character,
real character.
I mean,
whatever it is,
it is.
But whatever it is,
that's trend,
you know,
call it whatever name,
whatever noise you want to make.
There's not a lot of people like that.
That explains a lot,
explains a lot about your on yielding,
understanding and appreciation
of real commitment.
Yeah.
I mean,
I mean that's,
that's,
yeah,
and it's,
we almost don't have a choice,
you know,
because to not
listen,
you just do it.
But to not follow that,
in some ways it's,
it's like you're not honoring your father
because your father's leave.
Just certain things,
you know,
they leave you,
something in the,
well maybe they'd leave your whatever.
They might leave your special trinket
of something that he always remember a
car,
a little thing,
whatever,
but they leave you something.
If you're fortunate
enough to have a father.
I know not everyone is,
I get it.
But when they leave you that you,
you got to,
you got to cherish it.
You should.
And that's what he left me.
So to be,
it's not that I'm a good guy or bad
guy or great guy or less or anything.
I'm not,
I'm not any of that.
But I'm loyal to that because
you should be loyal to that,
if that makes sense.
I mean,
you know,
I'm loyal to that idea.
I'm loyal to that living.
I'm a loyal to that,
that
[inaudible] stance that he
took and living his life,
that belief that,
you know,
principle of living,
whatever you want to call
code of whatever you were,
all those words that make it,
you know,
sound better.
But
I would feel that I,
by not doing it that way,
when you're lucky enough to have a man
that kind of taught you what he taught
you without talking too much.
Um,
and that might be the greatest
teacher is by seeing right
examples of it.
But if you don't honor that,
then you're not honoring your father
what he stood for.
And at the end of the
day I was pissed because
for everything that he did,
there's nothing,
there's no,
I know that sounds foolish,
but there's no statue of him.
And so
for me,
there should be something
because he did it his whole life.
You know,
we all have moments of,
uh,
of light,
of moments of
where we maybe worry about what's,
what's there,
when we're gone and where we're going.
And maybe we change and I've seen it,
I've seen it with friends.
I get it,
I understand that.
But where we start trying to
live differently because we,
we start wondering about
what's coming next,
when we're gone death,
whatever,
you know,
but what's there.
And so we start thinking
about that a little bit.
Maybe I've seen people influenced by that.
I have,
you have to,
I'm sure.
And he was not influenced by that.
It was just what he was.
He was that his whole life.
And the only thing that I can think,
because I try to put pieces
together a little bit of what he,
how he got that way and
all I know from people when he died,
you know,
patients come up to you,
they're great and they
want to tell you something,
you know,
and they,
they told me,
you know,
that they were pouring on the
neighborhood and everything.
A neighborhood called Mirin is Harper
down by the water in stat now and rough
place,
you know.
And um,
they told me that his
mother was a tough woman.
She didn't have a tough woman
and they was three sons.
You know when they were
originally from day one born,
they were born here but she,
they were from,
from Europe,
you know,
and they had,
uh,
you had to be with the modded.
The mother told them what they had to be.
She told each one what you're going to be.
The oldest was my father.
Like I was the oldest and Eugene,
you're going to be an orthodontist.
He became an orthodontist.
Very successful Grad.
Old.
You're going to be an engineer.
Boeing aircraft,
unbelievably successful.
Lived in Seattle.
Theodore,
the oldest,
her favorite and all.
You're not supposed to have a favorite,
but it's real.
Right?
You have favorites.
You're going to be a doctor.
My oldest son,
you're going to be a doctor.
He wanted to be a builder.
He wanted to build.
He did both.
He built over 150 households that own,
he built tiff and things.
And how the fuck did he do that?
He did it as he was a doctor.
How did he have the time he bought,
he had contractor,
you know,
guy that did it.
But he,
he did that cause that was his passion.
Well he did,
but no,
no.
She was smarter than him.
She was smarter than anyone.
He was supposed to be a doctor.
He was one of the greatest
diagnose cystic doctors ever.
I know it's my father.
I know the whole thing.
I get it,
but he really was.
You walked in,
he knew what was wrong with you.
There's a great,
again,
we don't know like the Babe Ruth thing,
we don't know the complete truth to it,
but there's a great legendary
story that a guy walked in,
he had been to Mayo Clinic,
he had been to John Hopkins,
he had been everywhere and was dying.
That's all they know.
Who's dying,
losing weight,
foreign apart,
dying,
and nobody could diagnose him.
He walked into this place where you had
to wait five hours to see him because
the line was out the door because he was,
had all the poor people and there were
cigarette burns in all the rugs and she
was like,
where am I?
But when you got to them,
you know where you are,
and he went there.
Somebody sent them,
they went there and my father may all
the patients leave and he gave himself an
injection.
That's the legendary story.
And I asked him about it
and I as it was a name,
I couldn't tell you the name,
whatever.
He made it real simple.
He said,
because he knew I watched movies and we
all watch movies and we owe her things
from different times.
And he said back in those days it
would have been called leprosy.
It was some kind of cancer
and against,
there was a contagious part tool,
whatever.
And he got everyone out of the office
and he diagnosed the guy came sofas shot.
He would give himself a shot.
Yeah,
too,
I guess.
I guess so.
I mean,
that's the story,
right.
And um,
he said to me though,
the only definitive thing
I know about that story,
and it was a million of them,
you know,
similar,
but was that I bragged to my fault,
you're smarter than all
these other doctors.
And he said,
Norma
and I said,
but you found it and these other places,
big hospital,
big problem.
I'm not a big hospital.
Big hospitals,
bigger problems.
I said,
what do you mean they have to do things
fast and with large numbers I don't.
So they have to.
It has to make sense.
Some things don't make sense.
That's what he told me.
He said,
so this particular day,
they are smarter than me.
They knew the characteristics
of the disease.
They knew the symptoms,
they knew that it fit in here,
but that hadn't been around for 40 years
and in the continental United States,
whenever he said to me,
but I remember it was something like that.
It hadn't been around for 40
maybe it was 60 but whatever.
It hadn't been around.
So they move right past
that because they had to go.
It's a big hearts,
but all they got to go quick
because I don't have to,
he says it didn't make sense to
them because it was around 40 years,
but he says if it is almost
like of walks like a duck,
quacks like a duck,
maybe it's a doc.
So he just stayed.
He could stay with that.
They couldn't stay with that and
he stayed with and who was right.
And um,
he did a lot of things like that.
He was famous for that.
He was famous for people coming from
Brooklyn coming from Manhattan common over
there to see this diagnosis,
cystic genius and his little basement
office where people opt out the block,
like the Wayne for Mcdonald's or pizza.
And I'm going,
it cost less than Mcdonald's
to a certain extent,
you know,
because if we didn't have money
to in charge of like I said,
but he uh,
but he made money of course,
but he didn't make the money of the end.
He was a,
I tell you a great story to be a,
to have a nursing home.
Maybe this explains in the
best to have a nursing home.
You had to have open on stand on it,
I guess anywhere in New York you had
to have a doctor who's signed on as the
medical director.
The problem was they couldn't
pay it because the nursing
homes won't really make
money.
So you just had to have
a doctor would be there.
None of them really wanted to do it.
So my father was a
medical director and just,
just bear with me,
I'm going to say of eight nursing homes,
might have been five,
it might have been nine.
So I would go with them on house calls.
That's how I hung out with them.
So I go with them or nursing homes.
So of course he didn't get paid.
He was directed,
but he figured if he was that,
he never told me this,
but I think it's okay to say it.
He figured if I'm going to be there,
I'm going to go see the patients.
I'm not sure he didn't have to,
but he went once a week and he went into
each nursing home and I went with them
when I was with them
and he saw the patients.
So there's one day we
go win and he's like,
he gets treated like royalty.
I mean he comes in,
the staff comes running out
from all the nurse stays.
They all come on data,
you know?
And it made me feel good.
I was like,
wow,
I'm,
I'm with a man.
So I'm following them around.
We've gone down the hallway
and he's very humble.
He really truly is.
That word is overused,
but this guy was beyond the
humble like directed thing.
We'd go this way,
the the needle,
it was ridiculous.
He get mad if you said
some good about him.
So
they all colonies where he,
uh,
hey,
you have to charge.
Yeah,
come on.
So he's looking at the charge
to change his medicine,
give him 100 million,
you know,
the typical stuff that I know from
watching Dr Kildare or something.
Right.
So
He's,
you know,
and
he's doing his thing and he's going down.
I'm following them around.
I'm old.
I don't know how old I was,
but young,
11 so I'm found more
of a sudden this woman.
Do you ever see,
I don't know,
I jumped around with these things,
but you ever see the movie?
It was comedy guy that was around
back then and he said like a bride of
Frankenstein.
And he did Brooks.
Yeah.
It was one of his movies and
the bride of Frankenstein,
the white hair was like,
well,
this woman was the bride of Frankenstein.
She comes running out and she was the
shelf and she was like half nude and,
and her gown was fallen off and she's an
older lady and her white hair was like
that.
And she comes running and she's yelling
incoherent and screaming and they jump
and they jump.
When they started putting
straps around the,
I guess like the old white coat I guess.
And they go,
apparently she was tied up to a bed,
you know,
obviously back in those days they
didn't know how to deal with,
see now people the way,
you know,
it was a whole different thing.
I mean,
we're talking a lot of years ago.
And so they had a tied up and she got
loose and her gown was fallen off in.
She's,
and uh,
so they jump up on her and they're tying
her up and I'm watching this woman get
mugged in the nursing home than my
father is the medical director of.
And all of a sudden he said,
leave alone.
And he's still looking at his charts.
He's not like,
hey,
Yo,
a
illegal,
but it's okay.
She's fine.
She'll be all right.
And she calmed down.
She was a little nuts,
but
she was not spank.
Right?
Yeah.
That's a fair,
that's it's okay to say it's realistic.
And
she comes over with my father,
she says,
Hey,
and he's writing and he starts walking,
she starts falling.
And I'm a kid so I can figure it
all out the way I could later.
Right.
But she becomes his assistant basically.
She's following him around and she,
he's going to room to room and she's,
I think he gave her,
if I remember correctly,
he gave us like the,
the,
the thing that you write on a billboard,
you know the thing,
uh,
yeah.
Clipboard to hold.
So she's holding a clipboard and she's
looking like she's making believe she's
reading stuff and,
and,
and I don't like looking
at the scene like,
you know,
but I'm a kid,
like I haven't seen all the movies yet
that I can compare it that this is,
this is out there,
you know what I mean?
This is freaking nuts.
And,
and she found around,
she's looking at the thing
and I think she's like saying,
yeah,
yes.
She said,
and he's going and he's,
he's basically not even
paying attention.
He's just,
every once in a while I said,
let me have to,
and he's doing and all of a sudden,
and this is the part again,
just like the other thing I
think about leaving it out,
but if I leave it out,
it's not a story.
It's not a story because
if I left it like that,
it's a beautiful story,
but this is a beautiful story in its
own way because it is what it is.
It's a real,
he's in front of a,
and my mother was,
I described as she was his gorgeous,
beautiful woman that like good things.
My father could give a crap.
My father had ink stains exploding
in his white shirt pockets.
My mother would go crazy.
He went to Kmart and avi,
remember Kmart,
he went to Kmart and borders
all shoes for four 99 each,
maybe three 90 I plastic shoes.
And my mother was buying
him leather shoes.
He never warned him.
If he knew what she paid for me,
he would have went nuts.
Waste waste for what?
That was his,
that was him.
So he's got these plants and shoes and
you know he's got the inks blow up in his
pockets and everything else.
And My mother would always get upset,
always mad.
Why do you wear those shoes?
I,
yeah,
but he does.
So he's walking in front of her and
all of a sudden everything changes.
The woman goes,
he's neither doctor
she'd see.
She flipped on him.
Can you imagine this?
She could have to be in so great to her.
He's not a barely gets his
attention still walking.
He's not a doctor.
Everybody.
He's got holes in his shoes.
I looked down,
his foot goes up,
he's got a whole new shoes,
socks to canal,
the shoe.
She was right.
It's got a hole of his freaking
shoe and his plastic shoe.
He doesn't care.
She,
he,
he can't be a doctor.
He's got holes in his shoes
now.
He turns around,
he looks at her,
I never forget this.
He pats her on the head says,
you're not so crazy.
Pats her on the head just like this.
And now they're in a demeaning way.
Like you might think,
you know what I mean?
Really?
He touched her on her head and said,
you're not,
you're not so crazy.
Turned around,
took the billboard and kept walking.
She didn't say another word.
My mother was freaking embarrassed and
mad because I told the story when I got
home and of course he would never tell it.
And I said,
you know dad,
you know,
I said like a kid would say,
there's ladies said,
you know,
he's got a horse.
Oh my God.
You know,
Jesus,
you know?
Right.
Didn't meet anything.
Yeah.
Well that makes
just this,
your description,
your understanding of your father.
It just makes so much sense now.
So much sense of who you are and why you,
why your principles are so rigid,
why you,
you're intolerant of any bullshit.
Just makes so much sense
as a fight trainer and as a guy who
understands finders as a commentator and
make so much sense that you,
you have this just unyielding
need for 100% commitment.
Yeah.
I mean,
okay.
So just told her,
listen,
it doesn't make me a better
person or anything else to say,
but I don't have a tolerance.
I don't have tolerance for the BS.
Right.
Because I know to be bs.
You know,
I,
I say to we,
we were running these gyms
in la for the last nine.
You're 22 years.
I've listened.
When he died,
I started to ducktail this foundation
again,
there was no statute.
Okay.
So I really,
I went to a supreme court judge who was
a friend on stand down because I used to
be in front of the judge is
when I was young and a bad way.
And,
uh,
because I got myself in a little trouble,
stupid,
you know,
but I got to the right place.
That's what counts,
right.
I think.
And um,
but I always got a kick out of it that
I could hang out with the judge and I
didn't have to be in a court to do it,
you know?
Right.
And I didn't have to be
standing like in front of them.
I could be on the side of like,
hey,
so,
um,
I've got a few people together and I
started the doc that was foundation to 22
years ago and uh,
we've grown quite a bit,
but just a little grassroots thing,
but it's grown.
Um,
we probably give away a real help.
We have one paid person and
one office has 1400 a month.
That's it.
Um,
so no administrative costs
other than Knowles and um,
that's it.
Nobody could salaries to start one person
and all the money goes to the cases
and uh,
we probably give away.
Okay.
600,000,
700,000 a year.
Um,
but direct help,
um,
we don't,
we don't give to the,
you know,
we don't give to march of dimes.
We don't give it to them.
We don't give it to patients.
Again,
Red Cross,
we give it directly.
We've,
we,
they come to us now because we were
out there to an extent where people all
know,
but they come to us,
they have a kid with cerebral palsy,
needs a certain bike,
the bike cause $1,500,
bang,
boom,
got the bike.
We got another way.
It needs a machine that
circulates the blood in his legs.
Of course,
25 hour bang.
You got it.
[inaudible] obviously we,
we make sure it's legitimate.
We research it,
we do that.
We have a board,
we make sure drill or we do do make sure
it really is real because you do get
people to take advantage of a little bit,
but,
and we do it.
We act on it because my father never
made people feel less when they were poor
or when they needed something.
That was the greatest thing he did.
He never made them lose
more than they lost already.
Their integrity.
Never,
never,
never.
He never made him feel,
he didn't show it.
I remember one time,
it was Christmas Eve when it was
I hanging out and I was a kid.
I was in,
um,
I was at my father's office
because I want her to be with them.
And it was Christmas Eve and it was late
and we were still in the office and a
woman,
I remember,
she was a Spanish woman.
She came in,
she has six kids and and she was nervous
and I remember watching how nervous she
was.
I was like,
even though I was young,
it was like she's really
nervous and I found out,
I learned about human behavior.
I learned about what it was and
I'm watching her and sure enough,
she was getting ready.
When the last kid got taken care of,
she was going to dot out of there.
She didn't have money and the poor woman,
she was she,
she had to take care of her kids.
She didn't want to do that,
but she was going to run out of there
because she did not have money and he
recognized me take announced.
I didn't know what it was,
so I'm not going to say
I thought I was smart,
but I recognize something.
All this motion or there's nervousness.
It was a normal,
he recognized at all and
before he got to the last kid,
so he wouldn't embarrass her,
so she wouldn't run out of there and do
that to itself and lose something more
than she lost already.
He said,
this one's on me.
And the nervousness went away.
She said,
there's no charge today.
He said,
And I don't know if she spoke English,
but she understood it and he made her
understand it and there was no charge
today.
And soon as he said that,
everything changed.
Everything changed.
He wasn't nervous,
he wasn't looking at doors and she,
she cried
and she left.
And when she left,
the place was packed
because that was his office.
And all of a sudden he's,
I've talked to himself a little bit,
just just for a second.
I mean,
he didn't do this on where,
you know,
but he just like said,
yeah,
it wasn't like that.
You know,
I wasn't thinking,
of course he wasn't taking it.
He didn't know it was Christmas Eve.
Right.
So he turns to me and
he gives me a mission,
a job he opens,
it takes out as,
and it gives me a $50 bill.
He says,
go find that she's probably on a bus stop.
I ran out that door like I like I was
given the greatest mission in the world
high felt so proud I could,
I ran,
I knew where the bus stop was fabulous.
I was going to run all of them,
but she was at the first
one down on Bay street,
right around the corner,
down block two blocks and I,
she's there and showing off stage.
She has done a post.
I went up to,
I said,
the doctor said it gives
you this and you know,
she looked at it.
She,
you know,
she,
she couldn't,
she was shocked,
but she,
she started crying again.
But I felt so good because like
I felt like I was part of it,
you know.
And um,
so I started this foundation and I said,
you know,
I needed help.
And he said,
look,
we're going to do what he did.
No red tape.
No losing your pride.
People that fall through the cracks.
That's my father.
He was,
he was,
he had a phd in that.
All the people to fell to the cracks.
He took care of more.
I said,
we're going to take care of
the ones you know much good.
This fee,
great organization.
But two people out there,
no,
not a bad way,
but did you know like 87% goes to
administrative costs and like 4% goes to
research.
These people don't need
research in their life.
They've told me that.
I know it,
I recognize it.
You know what they need?
They need a wheelchair.
You know they need a handicap ramp.
Do you know what they need?
They can't.
Cancer Medication paid for.
You know what?
They need the utilities to be kept on
when they're being shut off because they
can't afford,
you know what they need?
They need the back rent paid because
someone got sick and one of the people
working there had to quit the job and
they were going to be put into a shelter
with six kids.
So we pay the back rent,
we paid the utility costs,
we pay the cancer Medicaid,
we put the wheelchair
ramp up and we do those.
That's what we do and I'm
researching part of their life.
It's great.
That's hope it comes.
So we could close all these places
down and our close mine down first,
but right now they don't need research.
They need that.
They need help for their way of life
now for the quality of life for that kid
now.
So that's what we do.
How can someone donate to
this or if they want to,
it's the dark that was said.
I'm real bad on website
stuff on wake up caveman.
But it's the doctor.
Atlas Foundation W.
Dot.
www.atlasfoundation.com Daca.
Yeah.
And M seven one eight nine eight Oh,
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Seven 1898070371 person.
Yeah,
there it is.
That's it.
There it is.
All right.
We got it up there.
One time with the phone number is
(718) 980-7037 (718) 980-7037 and um,
so Dr atlas.com.
There we go there and donate.
I'm sold.
Thank you.
Yeah,
this is a beautiful conversation man.
And know not just about boxing.
And,
uh,
I think this,
this,
like I said,
it speaks so much to who you are and why
you are who you are and why you won't
tolerate any bullshit.
Yeah.
It's like when you've
seen a guy like that,
it's Kinda like,
makes sense.
Are you still working with fighters?
You know,
it's funny.
Um,
no was the word and to a few
minutes ago to a few minutes ago,
well,
I'm saying a few minutes,
but until a week ago,
maybe less,
maybe five days ago,
I've,
I've decided to train a fighter.
He's going to fight for the world
light heavyweight title to sample first
against the second
hardest puncher in boxing,
unfortunately,
which he wasn't.
And um,
it's going to be,
I think it's on showtime,
I think.
I don't even know because I
didn't even find those details.
How when they asked me to train
them first I was saying no,
and then my kids said,
dad,
at least give it a chance.
So I flew out to where he is in Oxnard,
California to meet him.
His name is Alexander.
He's a,
he's a Ukrainian Alexander Volocyk.
I learned that you don't
pronounce the G it's voltage,
but it starts with a g he 15 and old 12
nine calories finding the second hardest
puncher in boxing donors to
Stevenson in Montreal way.
It's a tough fight.
Um,
they asked me if I would
train him at first,
like I said,
I would say no 20 things the
hardest punch your inbox.
Wilder,
wilder,
the old times would say he hit you on
top of the head and fractured ankles
that hard.
And um,
Donna Stevenson is a hell of a puncher,
is the second hardest puncher in
boxing lefthand southpaw on top of it.
And um,
when I flew out talks not to two nights,
if I'm going to say I'm
either going to say no,
which my kids asked me not to.
So I said,
then I'll get a fly out and I got to meet
him and when we had lunch with him and
the manager to,
you know,
anyway,
I'm sitting with them.
I don't know what they are for sure.
You know,
the manager I knew for
a while and a business,
but for sure you don't know to,
you know.
And um,
I wanted to try to find out.
So the thinking was like,
you know,
you're here to find out things probably
tomorrow in the gym and post we watch
tape.
So those are the things.
But,
so I said to him right out,
I said,
well,
I'm here to see one thing first.
If you're a decent person and they will,
you know,
they were like,
that sounds,
you know,
maybe different,
because you know.
But I said,
I just want to have your decent perfect
cause I don't want to be around people.
I just want to be around and
there's bad people out there.
I'm sure it's the way it is,
but I don't want to be around bear people.
I never did,
but now I definitely don't.
I want to be,
if I'm going to spend two months,
it's not easy in camp.
I want to be around someone.
I feel good about being around.
And so that's the first thing.
The second thing is too,
I think I can help them.
That was the second thing.
Yeah.
And Kenny be helped.
So when you go to talk
to someone like that,
do you watch a move?
What you,
her family,
first thing I do,
I want to wind up meeting his family.
He's got three young
kids and he's a husband.
And of course,
and I see a decent person.
And then now my watch film.
And um,
I see a guy that has ideas
that need to be added to that.
I think that's the best word.
Eyes.
They've got good ideas technically,
but they need to be advanced.
They need to be added to polished,
polished,
edited,
yes.
And taking down the road a little bit.
And,
um,
I see a guy who behaves like a fighter.
That's where it starts for me.
Besides being a decent person.
He behaves like a fighter.
He got hurt.
He got dropped in a fiery
behave like a fighter.
You have to be able to a
fighter to be a fighter,
you have to be a fighter.
Right.
And,
um,
well you would know that better than most.
So He um,
and,
and there's one problem.
Every fight he gets hit at
least once really clean.
You can't do that with this guy.
Right.
He gets it more than once,
but he gets it clean.
You know,
I one time I to to fight him when I
was trying to Bradley actually was,
I said,
you religious.
Yeah,
I am.
And my own way.
I said,
listen,
I'm not into that.
I'm say I'm just using it as an example,
my way of saying,
I said I was brought up a Catholic,
I forget half the things they told me,
but I remember about,
they used to teach you've,
I'm probably pronouncing her what
I'm going to need your help again.
But venial sins and mortal since the renew
or the little ones you can live with,
you don't go and see the guy
that's read the moral ones.
You've got a problem.
I said,
the way you box you've,
you make it moral sense it
the venial sins domain crap.
Right?
But you make it more once
you get in the hit clean,
unblocked,
clean,
solid punches that sometimes you don't
even see like the providing the crop by.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
So I said that's going to be corrected,
right?
So we corrected it.
So how do you correct something like that.
You know what it is,
right?
You have to know what it is.
You have to see why he's getting hit
change and you've got to change the
technique of way everything.
There's rules.
You got to it's life.
It's when you work with the garlic,
then you only have two months.
How much change can
you affect in too much?
Well,
I worked with Bradley for the right wheels
fight and he and he couldn't stand in
front of the guy and he went out and
he moved around the guy and you know we
were,
we were fortunate.
We did okay.
We made some change.
But I mean a little things like,
I'll give you an example.
[inaudible] rules,
rules,
simple things like where
are you at 12 punch from?
I
know I just got here.
I told her,
No,
don't throw jab from there
because if you're too close,
he could time you were right in and we,
everyone heard jabbers
to beginning of things.
Jeff has to the,
you know,
it leads to good things.
It's a great point.
Yeah,
it is.
It's a terrible ponch and so it's
a horrible punch of your throat.
The wrong distance you drove
from a little too close.
Bang.
You get her.
We're right in no way.
You throw punches from love
talking to all of level.
He got here,
we're right here and we'll
provide the god he didn't.
All he knew was he got hit,
but he didn't know why you threw the lab.
Took in front,
right hand is there.
Boom.
Get on his side.
Troll punches from certain positions,
not allowed to draw punches are less.
They're from the right position
now you have to,
cos would tell me you have to
co over and over and over and over word
again til they can't do it
wrong if they want it to.
It's got to become a habit.
Right,
but you're not thinking
about it where it's a habit.
And that takes a lot of work and that
takes understanding what it is and it
takes a lot of work.
You've got to be on him every time.
And it takes a guy,
they can put his ego in a pocket.
It's why you want to know,
do I have a good guy here?
Do I have a decent guy?
Because you're telling a guy who's
already made it to a certain level without
you.
He has,
and now you're telling them
this things that he don't know.
So he's got to be willing
to be able to accept that.
And I'm
one of the things I like people
that are unselfish and local,
all selfish to a certain degree.
But again,
it's degrees.
How tough are your degrees?
All fighters are tough degrees.
How does,
how selfish are your degrees?
Right.
And I,
the whole understanding was I
would go to Oxnard for eight weeks,
you know,
to train them,
but maybe I don't want to go to oxide,
but I'll go wherever I
take it gives to fight it.
The best chance to win the weather,
the time zone.
But the main thing why I go there,
he's got three young kids.
I'm not in a rocky movie.
I don't want to take them away from
those kids for those eight weeks.
Right.
That's not good.
So how many,
so I took two weeks to decide to them.
He kept calling to manage up.
He's a good kid.
He is.
And he kept calling him,
manage up and saying,
did you hear yet?
And of course he had,
so he's thinking like
a good person or like,
I shouldn't say good part.
He's taking like a person that
wants to get what he wants to get,
but at the same time,
here's where the good part
comes in or the self less pot.
He says,
if I have to go to New York,
I'll go to New York.
A lot of fighters don't do that.
They want help,
but they want it on their terms.
Right.
He said,
if I have to go to New York,
I go to New York.
I have to go to Montreal
called the Montreal.
Please tell them that,
that that spoke to me,
that I had this kid that selfless too.
To that extent and I could
see was training him before.
Um,
I don't know the name,
but it was uh,
you know,
were decent.
He's 15 at all.
But uh,
but he felt like when,
you know,
when he got dropped in a fight and we
went back to the gym immediately that
should be dealt with,
you know,
but it was back to just basic training.
I can rather than that specific,
you know,
it doesn't mean that the guy's not good.
Doesn't mean it just that he,
everyone deals with things.
Definitely.
That's all.
I mean it doesn't make me this or that,
but I just can do it the way I do it.
And I do it.
I look at film,
when I went to see him,
I had a couple of pages
written out already on things
I saw on film that he does
wrong that daddy would have to correct.
And the one thing that he has to correct
for this fight will be good if you
don't get hit,
I mean that'd be a damn good thing.
But the one really thing is you can't
keep coming back in front of the guy at a
certain distance and given them a shot
at your winning components like that.
And that's one thing.
He always winds up localized
right back in front of the guy.
And there's gotta be other options,
other places to go.
You know,
I joke around,
I used to fund,
you know,
different examples of different analogies.
I say,
listen,
whether you had a mother or grandmother
and had somebody when you were growing
up told you don't hang out on the corner.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
Why?
Because nothing good can happen.
Well,
don't hang out in front of the guy.
Nothing good can happen or can happen.
So we go from there.
You know,
it's a lot more to it.
Yeah,
he does.
He's a smart guy.
He's got beautiful family.
And like I said,
it's a,
I'm,
so when do you start,
because December 1st is,
you said the referral sources to fight.
I have to make a decision.
I have to,
it's either going to be an
eight or a seven week camp.
Uh,
I,
I'm trying to feel,
I'm trying to find out
by asking them questions,
how quickly his body gets in shape because
I know it sounds funny to the average
guy out there,
but if it's a week too
long it could be bad.
Yeah.
You know?
So,
and he's overtrained in his career.
So I wanted Friday try.
It's not an exact science to have
a feel for be to seven weeks.
Did you monitor their heart rate?
The resting I have.
So we have that stuff that we do that um,
to see if there were 10 of pain
when they wake up in the yes.
But you know what?
I depend on B.
I'm not going to stay and be asked your,
I depend on my eye more
than any three cm song down.
He seemed struggle and the
trick is to not get there,
to try not to get there.
What are you doing?
You tell them to take a few days,
but I try to see it before I see what,
what I mean is if he had
a hard day of training,
I will just automatically
give him a light day or maybe
off the next day.
Right.
And like a lot of people won't because
they're afraid like you got to work,
got to work.
Right.
And,
but I learned not to be afraid of that.
Right.
So,
so if I see he had a
real and he looked great,
you know what,
take off to wall or you sure take
off tomorrow so we don't get there.
Right.
To try to kind of like my father,
like preventative meant,
I said this is a new
way of thinking though.
And it's such a smart way of thinking
because for the longest time everybody
just wanted to be tough.
Yeah.
They just wanted to work harder.
But you got to work smarter.
Yeah.
You do.
Less is more,
you know that saying,
but sometimes,
but it really is sometimes sometimes,
but sometimes not because some people
are fucking lazy and they're looking for
that easy way out.
You have to gauge that Jack to see it.
You have to know what you got to,
you know what I mean?
And sometimes the real discipline driven
guys are their own worst enemy in that
regard.
That has pushed too far.
Yes.
And this kid has been,
again,
I'm not here to say what was,
but the kid has been in that place
and that's why they're coming to me.
And again,
I'm no better than anyone,
but I will understand that.
So when you were,
when you were saying seven
weeks or eight weeks,
so either one,
it's either going to be,
so my first day it's going to be a Monday.
So the first day in camp in Oxnard will
either be October 8th or October 15th,
October 8th,
we represent eight weeks.
October 15,
seven weeks.
And that would mean I
would fly in on a Saturday,
get myself settled Sunday,
watch tape with him,
um,
uh,
and then start Monday with
a structured schedule,
you know,
with the ability to change it anytime.
Because again,
Ui,
you see?
Right.
You know,
I remember years ago I
was training fighters.
You know,
I've been around 40 years already.
I remember been Gleason's when
I moved down to Gleason's,
you know,
many years ago,
30,
whatever it was,
maybe more 35.
Um,
so Gleason's was in Manhattan,
it's in Brooklyn output.
It was a man,
it was the place,
you know,
and it was two blocks from
Madison Square Garden.
It was kind of cool,
you know.
So,
um,
I'm trying to find it and I remember I
was the first guy there and not bragging
or not,
but I mean you just,
I w I would make my guys drink
water and he old time guys,
10 guys,
not because they knew it from scientific
evidence to say other than it was
passed down to them.
It was taboo.
It was just passed down
to the tall drink water.
It makes you weak,
you know,
you've got to be tough.
Don't drink wine.
So I was making my guys
not only drink water,
drink a half a gallon,
I mean drink a lot of water.
So I remember some of the old timers,
would they be like talking about me?
They'd be like,
it's a fixed this guy.
Don't drink or don't follow what he's
doing because some of the fighters who was
psychiatry and some water
and get that water and,
and,
and know what it gives you,
cramps.
It'll make you a,
you now don't give you cramps
if you drink a large amount.
Very cold and yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You could go.
But now if we hydrates you,
it allows you to stay strong.
Try to drive a car because the
desert with no water in the radiator,
you might have a problem.
You might and,
and,
but I'm telling you and I'm not,
so I was afraid.
No,
but I'm saying that that place,
the thing was nobody drank water,
spit it out.
Right.
And I was making my guys drink
and right in front of me.
Do you know though,
what was the difference?
I knew by learning.
I knew my father,
my father,
um,
talked about the importance of water.
You know,
he was proud.
I was training.
He thought it was going to be a lawyer.
He went a little different,
but a,
he was proud that a it.
So he would talk to me like,
he was like,
I just got a two osmosis,
if that makes sense.
I just,
I knew,
I knew water was healthy.
I knew it was important that you had to
rehydrate yourself and yet you had to,
my father had a thing with water to my
father would make my father got involved
in my training in different ways.
Like if my fight,
it was feeling a little weak or he had
a cut and he was healing from the cut by
father would say set
them down in the ocean.
Why Dad?
We're not taking a vacate.
Pardon me in the ocean.
I said,
all right.
Okay.
Let them go in the ocean,
let them soak,
cause his scar,
whatever you know is called,
let them soak it in the ocean and uh,
don't go to clay out and
thought that might not be good,
but I won't work.
Now that might not heal you
but change it might change.
It might be green when you come out,
you got something going on with the hulk.
But,
um,
no,
but so no.
He would tell me in a
series where he said 30,
um,
send you fighter.
If he's a little,
he needs to be revitalized a little,
set them to the ocean
that was swimming ocean,
let them be in the sun and uh,
let them so whatever,
concealing the notion and,
and if he happens to swallow some water,
it's okay because I have no
one wanted to swallow seawater.
Right.
And the worst thing in the world,
my father said,
it's okay,
not the worst thing.
So one day,
I guess I got around to asking him why
he was so into sending my fighters to the
ocean.
And he told me he just,
that's how my father would say things.
He would just tell me things
and that's where I would learn.
And he just said to me,
ocean is where all life came from.
All Life on earth started in the ocean,
microcosms,
whatever you want to call.
They didn't get into all technical stuff,
but he said it started in the
ocean and it came out onto land.
He says,
all percentage of salt in our blood
is the exact same percentage per skew
begins.
Q begins,
you know,
whatever it was.
I'm,
I'm just saying,
probably not close to what he said,
but close enough,
um,
is the exact amount cubic
inch as it is in the ocean.
We come from the ocean,
all life comes from the ocean.
Go back to where life came from.
That was enough for me.
My father was telling me anything.
My father told me that was it.
So I said,
all right.
So,
um,
a matter of fact,
he told me his story.
I remember I was going out with a girl,
um,
that,
that had a little baby
that had a bowl lakes.
And he told me,
he said,
and he was serious.
He wouldn't say it otherwise,
but he said send it down.
He had a condominium and they
told the beach and he said,
send it down to Daytona beach.
Let him stay there for the summer
and let her boy be in the ocean.
And the sun vitamin A,
vitamin D.
Right.
I didn't know that.
Um,
and it is street in his legs out.
Yeah,
his legs or get straight.
They won't crazy,
you know,
but you know,
there was a cook in this to him.
His legs are good street and he was
right because by being in the ocean,
by being in the sun,
vitamin A and d healthy of course.
I guess part of it was the swimming and
part of it was the ocean and part of it
was the sun,
but it was straight in his legs.
Now looked at he need them to the
point where you had to put braces.
No,
but was there was a slight issue was
the initial it was a dramatic no,
but did,
but he say work.
Yeah.
Was it right?
You know,
but we just think of braces,
you know,
obviously.
And um,
but yeah,
and it would heal.
He would say Glen [inaudible],
Coney Ocean is salt water.
He owes the cut.
It will heal the client.
A lot of fighters used to
soak their facing Brian,
right?
Yes.
Yeah.
Well Joe Frazier did.
Did that really keep you that your skin
tough and protect you from cuts or is
that an old wives
that,
that's a little bit of that old stuff,
you know,
where we don't know.
Right.
But they believed it and so,
you know,
it smelled like a pickle when he was,
when he was following with you,
get hungry in any hit
you a lot of talking.
What about other controversial
training methods?
Like a weightlifting for the
longest time was start the taboo.
Taboo.
Holy feel.
The Mackie.
She'll stone.
Yeah.
Maggie shell stones training or Holyfield
and moving him up from a cruiser way
to a heavyweight.
He true and very,
it was a very light heavy
weight at the beginning.
Right.
Cruiserweight yeah,
we really essentially was and
they just pack some meat on them.
Michael Spinks with Yup,
that's right.
Michael Spinks was really the first.
Yeah.
When he fought Larry Holmes and Mackey
shall stone worked with Holyfield after
that.
That's right.
Um,
yeah.
Listen and Gleason,
I'm going to go back to Gleason's.
The epicenter,
you know,
to place
no water,
no weights.
Right.
I got,
I used to have my fighters
to wait if I felt,
if I felt that a fighter wasn't
physically strong enough,
I put him on a weight program,
but I do it myself.
I I,
there was no strength coaches back then.
But,
but just the common sense
program says three days a week,
you know,
eat protein.
Of course you have to replenish yourself
with the proper diet and all that
stuff,
but,
and do it at the right time in between
the training where you're not killing,
you say overtraining
know go spar and tire.
That's right.
You don't have to separation of workouts.
But if I had a slightly built guy that I
taught two things and the second one is
one where probably sounds a
little that you wouldn't have,
wouldn't normally connect to it.
But the first thing was if I thought he
could physically be a little stronger,
not that he had to be fighting inside,
but when he did fight inside,
because let's face it,
you're a fighter,
you're going to wind up and walk quarters.
You are,
even though you say,
well,
I'm going to live on the outside.
Okay.
Until that day that the Guy
Slips Your Jab and again,
now you live in any insight.
Are you ready to live on
the inside for a minute?
So I believe that.
So I would make my guys two
weights if I do it physically,
they could get help and
improvement in those areas,
but I also did it for
the psychological reason.
I felt that it's all psychological battle.
It's 75% psychological,
mental,
and you have to do any gene you can
to help to fight her in that area.
Anything,
anything,
grab anything.
That's if there's something floating
over your head are grabbing anything and
the mental part.
If if you make them feel stronger,
he'll be stronger.
If that's something that,
that just gives him a little I
older more of confidence and belief.
Now listen,
here's the,
here's the catch 22 maybe you
don't want the guy fighting inside.
Maybe his style,
his makeup is the fight I get to because
of the smart guys out there listening.
I'm sure there are.
They're going to think
that before he said it.
Yeah,
I still want him to feel strong.
Okay.
I'm not going to make,
I'm not going to make a
guide that should box,
like pinel would go was
your box like Muhammad Ali.
I'm not going to let them Mike
and fight like Jake Lamata.
Oh,
I,
I'm okay with that.
But I want them to feel stronger.
I fought them.
So what kind of weightlifting
would you have them do?
Because you're,
do you have a background in
lifting weights yourself?
No,
no.
Other than I played football,
so he was around it and,
and I,
I've been around Jim's my whole life and,
and fitness people all my life.
So I understand the plyometrics.
I understood all the advancements,
all the new stuff that came out,
the bands that,
you know,
the,
Hey,
listen,
you've got to remember there was
a guy named Charles Atlas that,
that started with resistance training.
He was,
uh,
somebody kicked sand in his
face and his comic book.
Right.
And,
and you know,
I don't know if it was related or not,
but,
um,
but you know,
he,
he did isometrics.
I believed in Isometrix.
I did isometrics for the whole camp with,
but Michael Morell for
the Holyfield fight,
believe it or not.
Yeah.
I used to put my hand here and I used
to make him push against my hand,
but ways that we can push it,
I would design all kinds of different
exercises in ways to do it where I just
gave him resistance with my own body,
sometimes push against my shoulder,
you know,
and be careful to join.
She won't in the,
you know,
all common sense stuff.
Yeah.
But,
um,
so we,
we,
this is something that
you thought of yourself,
you were trying to figure out how to
do it and then you just implemented it.
Yeah.
This is something that a Michael Moore
man when he was a light heavyweight was a
murderous puncher.
Murder murderous boy.
Oh boy.
Whoo.
He was dangerous.
He was so scary.
But though it seemed like the
weight cut was too brutal.
Yeah.
It was brutal.
And um,
he was a terrifying light heavyweight.
Yeah,
he was,
I forgot about him.
They forgot about him
as a light heavyweight.
He'd knocked everyone out.
Just,
I mean,
I don't think he went the
distance with anybody.
He was murdering people.
Yeah.
He was really something.
And a first heavyweight,
uh,
first sal point heavyweight
champ of whole time first.
Is that true?
Wow.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that'd be true.
I've been saying,
I'm sure it is.
I didn't know.
Yeah,
no,
he was,
it could make him a good person.
Very good guy.
Yeah.
He's like all of us,
we get lost and we get confused.
All of us,
but he's a good,
you know,
you're good or you're not good,
right?
Yeah.
He's you,
you want to hear crazy thing.
Um,
some people might,
I hope they don't.
Whatever.
I hope they don't take it the wrong way,
but anyway,
it's meant to be the good way.
Um,
I have a friend,
a very close for,
I hate politicians.
I did.
They're phony,
but I have one that's,
he,
he makes a live in a politician,
but he don't live as a politician.
Does that make sense?
He's the president of stand on,
his name is Jimmy Hall,
and I'm probably go crazy,
but here's this put anyway.
It's okay.
He's a little crazy.
Anyway,
that's why we get along.
But he's a good man.
And,
uh,
like my father was born to be a doctor.
He was,
his mother knew it.
He was born to be,
I don't know,
I don't want to use the word politician.
Seems like a dirty word leader.
Yeah.
Aliyah.
Uh,
a carer of people.
All right.
I'm a public servant,
maybe whatever.
But anyway,
so he's the bowl
president of Sinai and he,
he really does things and um,
anyway,
we're close and he just gave is $94,000
for the foundation like a week ago.
He does that.
He finds the money and you know,
he knows,
he says is the greatest compliment.
He goes,
I know.
It's called,
I know where it's going.
And um,
thank you.
He says to me,
I said,
what do you think of me for?
Thank you.
I can't help these people without you.
You know,
I get all the help.
We do fundraisers and we do things.
We do a big dinner,
thousand people a week before Thanksgiving
where we are people like Tony Dancer
and Phil Sims and bill
pause cells use to calm.
He don't come no more.
He don't leave Florida anymore.
But,
but,
um,
you know,
we,
I mean Patrick Ewing
to Campbell Mutombo uh,
uh,
I mean we're,
we're blessed.
We're blessed with Voz Perez.
She loved pork.
She loves me.
Yeah.
I mean we were blessed.
Um,
Brandon Marshall from
the giants last year,
they come and they allow me to have a
successful dinner because they come and
they don't get a sense
because nobody gets a sense.
And um,
so with all that in with Jimmy,
so anyway,
I have these things that
I just say sometimes.
So he caught me one time,
but I was just saying it,
I didn't realize that it
was going to register,
you know,
because it's just something,
so I just said,
I said people bad.
So he said,
why?
I said,
well,
because what you say?
I said no,
I said two words to live by people bad.
So I've choking her,
but he said people bed.
So he said,
what do you mean?
I said,
people bad.
He said,
but you help,
you're in the business.
I said,
just good people too.
So anyway,
about a month ago,
two months ago,
whatever,
he comes up to me and he says,
you've got to think I'm out of my mind.
I said,
well,
no,
I know,
but for what?
What's the matter?
He said,
with your permission,
I want to take a domain,
which I barely know what that means.
Copyright,
the phrase people bad.
And
if I told you I wanted to start a
business with you and me and the proceeds,
some of the proceeds will
go to the foundation.
We sell shorts would do that.
And you have these different sayings.
So to start with people,
bad resiliency,
good people,
bad forgiveness,
bad be better people,
bad parks,
good
people,
bad,
you know,
redemption,
good people bad.
That's be bad,
you know,
whatever.
But the whole idea is to be unapologetic
and to say we got a problem.
I don't know if you want to
say we're at a tilting point,
but we got a problem.
If my a social genius,
no,
am I a saint?
No,
but I got kids.
I care about what the world is.
You know,
maybe if I didn't have
kids that still care
and I have grandchildren now,
I have to often,
they're beautiful.
And you know what,
there's a lot of bad people out there.
I'm not apologize or about saying that.
There's a lot of great people,
there's more good people,
but it's,
it's like turning a battle line,
a line of resistance,
really where I want to
call people out on it.
I want to remind us
that we could be better.
I want to remind us that
people bad selfishness,
worse.
And,
and I,
I just want to,
to what he brought my attention to it,
because I used to use that phrase so
frequently when I was mad and he said,
that's turn your med
into something better,
teddy.
That's debts because I
know what you stand for.
I know I,
that's why I give you
what I give you 22 years.
So people are bad,
but they,
they're good.
They're good.
That remind people that
we need to be good,
that remind people,
that's call a monocrop.
That's,
that's freaking say,
hey,
we got to be better.
We've got to care about the right things.
We've got to stop getting
caught up in our crap,
you know,
and we gotta be stronger people.
Bed,
don't be weak,
you know.
But in other words,
we're using it to,
to remind people that sometimes
we'll go into in a bad direction.
We are looking at the world.
Look at that.
You know,
when I was flying here was
reading the New York Post,
do you know how want people
think I'm weak or something?
But I didn't want to read some of the
stories about some of these kids that got
killed.
There was a story about a parent that
someone at a hospital in Manhattan that
decided to slice up a bunch of infants,
um,
just ran to the hallway of his place was
for Chinese immigrants that they go to
this place where now young mothers where
they think it's a safe haven for the
children to be there for like a month.
And so they infants two days,
all five days or 10 days
old and they're all in.
It was all Chinese immigrants
and they're all in there.
These babies and this woman walks in there
with a knife and start stabbing these
kids.
Now listen,
I know a lot of people,
are they going to say teddy?
That's psychotic.
That's different.
I,
yes,
yes.
It's evil.
Yeah,
there's evil in the world.
but I'm just,
I'm just calling to arms.
I'm not the guy,
but I'm just saying in my
small way called arms that
we can be better.
That just remind people that,
you know what?
We have so much promise.
There's so much to be
grateful for in this country,
particularly in the world,
but not always.
And we have so much here that's be better.
If people bed that's help them be better.
That's lead the way to be better.
Uh,
that's,
that's take a stance.
So we're going to,
I don't know how the freak,
we're going to do it,
but we're going to start this company.
People bear.
But then we're going to have
all these inspirational,
if you will.
But all these positive,
positive,
positive
things to say that,
to remind you that in know where
you can be anything you want to be.
You know,
that old saying you could
be anything you want to be,
but some people choose to be bad.
Let's choose to be better.
And,
um,
so we're going to do some,
the,
some of the proceeds go to the father.
I don't know how the freak were
probably whatever is going on,
but we,
we're going to figure it out.
Um,
he's going to do it all
because I only know boxing.
I think you know more than that.
Listen,
Teddy,
there's been three hours.
Oh,
I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry.
It was great.
I really appreciate you being here,
man.
Wow.
I know.
It's actually a little bit
more than three hours and,
uh,
thanks for that was beautiful.
Thanks man.
Thank you.
Appreciate you.
Appreciate you and Teddy Alice.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Hm.