The joe rogan experience,
is that you and Rodney Dangerfield?
Did you double as Rodney?
I did double Hib a few times.
What movie was this?
Oh God,
a couple of TV shows I had.
This is a picture of you guys up there.
What's that guide?
Can you say it?
Ah,
yeah,
we,
I was doing sword fighting then sword
fighting.
Oh yeah,
definitely him.
And uh,
he was quite a character,
quite a character.
He would always leave his pants zip.
And um,
I had,
uh,
one of the actors in them.
I'm saying,
Hey,
his pants inside zip.
He'd go up and he says,
I'm getting air conditioning.
Don't bother me.
And he just did it as a swerve,
a joke.
He wants to write with like the robes
and stuff.
[inaudible] like balls and why?
I've talked about this before,
but I worked at Great Woods,
Concert Center and Mansfield,
Massachusetts.
When I was a kid,
I was a,
amongst the security personnel there.
And so I was backstage and I got to see
Rodney as he was preparing for a show.
He would just have a robe on and nothing
else.
And we were wearing slippers and he had
a robe on and he was walking around back
there.
This is before I'd ever done standup
comedy,
but I was like,
that guy is the shit.
Like,
look at him.
He's just,
he's literally as comfortable as you can
get.
He's wearing a bathrobe on purpose and
it's because he could,
you know,
he was like,
cause I can whatever,
I'm just gonna wear a bathrobe.
It's comfortable.
I liked the way,
I love the way he does it because he
can,
because he keeps fucking Ronnie did.
He knew he was Rodney dangerfield.
Hell,
he didn't have any said anything and he
played it straight.
And apparently a super nice guy.
Like everybody I know that did business
with them or had any interactions with
them,
always came away from it.
Same Rodney,
he's a great guy.
My friend Jeff,
my manager Jeff,
he was with,
uh,
one of,
one of his clients was one of Rodney's
original,
um,
uh,
comics on the Hbo Comedy Series that he
did.
And uh,
he said that Rodney was just the best,
just the coolest,
nicest guy.
But it happens all the time.
I know.
But what's worse than that are fucking
your sister having sex with your sister.
That's worse.
I think so.
I victim there.
Where's your sister wants it?
You want it?
I thought about that.
There's one I will go to my grave saying
I've never had sexual my sister.
That's a good move.
Yeah,
there's some things you want to keep off
the resume.
Yeah,
that would be,
well you don't even want to do it and
then go while I was a mistake.
Never do that again cause you can't
really erase it.
Which is kind of fucked man.
Because like isn't it like learning like
one of the most important parts of life?
Like shouldn't you be allowed to fuck up
but you can't.
There's certain fuck ups you can't make.
Like you can't be like,
you know a baby.
I want to marry you,
I want to marry you too.
But I gotta tell you this one thing I
don't,
I know this is not going to change
anything cause we're meant to be with
each other,
but I fucked my cousin.
Your wife's going to be like,
what?
Why did you fuck your cousin?
Wait a minute.
Which cousin?
Guy.
How far,
wait,
whoa.
I fucked my cousin Mike.
Huh?
How far was the,
is it a first cousin or is it uh,
uh,
yeah,
it'd be,
have to be a first guy then it was a
second cousin.
Well if it's gay sex,
um,
I think no one's going to be happy with
you.
You know your wife's not happy that you
fucked your cousin.
But it,
this is the,
that was a joke brody.
But if it's a straight ranch,
my aunt works.
If it's straight
it's straight sex.
I think.
Um,
the second cousin is actually like
legal.
Like you can not only fuck them,
you can marry him,
right?
Yeah.
First cousin.
Can I ask you a question?
Joel?
You're not,
you're not supposed to.
It's been on my mind and I know you
probably don't want to talk about it
cause it was broad.
Oh well thanks for bringing it up on the
Internet.
What was brought up?
Well I'm just being real.
Who's brought up in,
not you.
I think you are uneasy with it.
It was an ice house chronical.
Um,
why would you bring it up again?
Well,
cause I heard Joe talked about gay sex.
Like I have to make it clear.
I'm not into that.
Oh,
why do you have to make that clear?
Because I get hassled for it.
Sometimes it goes back to you again,
brody notice,
well it's going back to him and gay sex.
Apparently you can have sex with your
cousin.
It's legal.
What else of your cousins?
A transsexual then?
Uh,
it's even more legal.
Depends if you're,
if you're telling someone who writes for
salon,
you're in a few girls that have been
attracted to their cousins,
but they always use the excuse.
They're not blood related and they've
all done.
Yeah,
that's not real.
I wouldn't have sex with a relative,
just not into it.
But I think people who have done it
throughout history,
I think it's kind of sick.
Why would,
if you don't see them that often?
I just sick.
It's sick.
I think incest is a sickening thing and
I'm sorry it's happened to some young
girls or kids or whatever.
Made it would if it's a really good name
thing.
What if it's a cousin that you really
enjoy?
I think it cousin is too close.
But what if it look,
what if that cousin is the perfect
person for you?
What did you know it does.
It doesn't make sense.
But you know what the heart wants what
it wants,
Brodie and then one good and that's not
normal.
And so if you look at the way we treat
orchids,
why the fuck would we ever expect
anybody to
be nice to us?
I used to exercise the analogy of um,
of aliens with the younger trainers all
the time.
I'd say,
look,
we're aliens to these animals.
You need to make this animal's
environment as comfortable as possible.
Bearing in mind always we are aliens.
Just,
you know what I mean?
That's part of relating to the animals,
which is,
are thinking like that.
You're just like,
wait a second.
Like I got it.
Start being nicer because if an alien
comes down,
I don't want that.
I don't want to be sounds as,
it's a stupid thing to say.
It's one of those,
are you talking about aliens?
Again,
people like automatically go goofy with
it,
but the reality is it's actually,
it's the right analogy because we really
are aliens in their world and we're
obviously supposedly intelligent where
obviously intelligent enough to figure
out how to get them when intelligent
enough to figure out how to train them,
put them in tents,
put them in tanks,
rather have all these people come to see
him.
We're obviously intelligent enough to
film them.
Theirs,
they
can tell there's a lot of shit going on
that they don't do,
but they've gotta be like,
God,
you guys are decks.
Like,
why are you holding on to me?
Like we don't hold on it.
We don't.
We don't do that.
I think we kill things,
but we don't hold onto them.
I think that's when the frustration
levels started boiling for these
animals.
Cause when they're first there,
when they first arrived,
he has a green animal if there,
I mean the bottom line is,
it depends if they're a good candidate
for captivity,
but they've learned real fast that,
okay,
that's the hand that feeds me.
Like I wanna,
I wanna I want to develop this
relationship,
if you will,
which is in relationship of like abiding
by this person's,
right,
right.
So then again,
goodwill,
the animals and the other ones that are
just like the same for me.
There,
they're there,
they're cutting out and there's nothing
you can do.
I mean,
you pull blood from them,
you checked up blood.
There's nothing wrong with them.
This animal's not sick.
Why isn't it eating?
And then days later,
why is the Sanama debt did not want to
be in captivity.
They just starve themselves to death.
I've seen it so many times.
Wow.
The will to live Lawson.
Okay.