The joe rogan experience.
I wants it thing the idea crazy.
Eddie,
do you remember Crazy Eddie?
His prices are insane.
Crazy,
crazy.
It was crazy.
It was a guy that had stores in all five
boroughs of New York wholesale outlets,
TV's,
stereos,
tvs and everything like that.
I saw,
I was watching them and some BC greed.
They have a series called
give us,
let me hear this mother fucker
[inaudible]
crazy.
He's wearing a Santa Claus outfit.
He's going fucking crazy with fake snow
in the background.
He fucking like just this,
like he like hit it out of the park.
Didn't he go to Israel?
But the most brilliant thing he did was
he took it either don't,
don't fucking,
you know,
check back me on this.
He took it either his nephew,
his son in law,
somebody that he was related to two
blood,
put them through college so he could get
a job at the irs so they could figure
out how to rob from the irs.
This is how fucking and saying this guy
was.
I'm watching this diet and how they got
crazy,
right.
Crazy.
Eddie fled after he started.
Just by boxes.
You know how you let me use it.
Go you,
you would be driving in New York and
there was some guy selling stereo
speakers.
Yeah.
And then you'd take them home and it was
two bricks.
Yep.
Well he did the same thing to investors.
He took boxes,
filled them up with bricks and just
stuck them in a warehouse.
And then he went public.
So he got everybody to come down and
look at all his inventory and all these
fact checkers that checking boxes or
bricks and them,
whoa.
And he had,
I mean five fucking warehouses all
around.
They will all fake.
And he got all this money.
He fled to Israel and he fled for a
while,
but they knew he was a pussy hound.
Right.
So they got him like Escobar style.
They've got,
I'm like,
you know,
on the phone,
like I'm going to the store or something
crazy.
And what they did was they put a blonde
on the side of the road with a mini
skirt and they knew eventually he would
drive by and stopped and he stopped.
That's how they nailed them.
What is that?
Did you google the,
the richest women in the world where
they got their money from?
He's a bad motherfucker,
paramus,
syosset long island
and he had commercials.
He was the first one that pushed to
commercial barrier.
I mean,
I would like to look at how many on the
left
we'll attack others for not being
progressive enough,
not being left enough.
So I think it's a panic,
right?
You see this is the kind of behavior you
see in a panic,
a moral panic for example.
And so helen and I,
the third person who worked on the
project with us,
Helen and I wrote an essay about a year
and a half ago and talking about how the
extremism on both sides is really the
problem.
And most people reject it and should
fight it.
Most of us are sensible people in the
middle who hate this.
In fact,
data just came out showing that it's 80%
of the population date hate the fringes,
both sides.
So,
and only 8% are on the left and 12% are
on the right of the fringe.
However,
that works out.
And so we wrote this thing and we said
that what's going on actually we called
an existential polarization.
So you have this idea that everything's
an existential crisis.
So the the far right,
we'll start with them,
sees that if the Democrats get power,
oh,
it's open borders.
The terrorists are coming in our entire
way of life is going to be destroyed.
Catastrophe,
catastrophe,
Ono.
Judith Butler is going to be 95 genders.
Quick Stop the Democrats no matter what.
And then you have the left.
Oh my God.
If they get power that everything's
going to be racist,
we are going to be beating gays in the
snow.
It's going to just be the worst thing in
the,
that's actually kind of a joke,
but,
but it's,
it's for real though,
that they think that the world is going
to fall apart if the other side gets
power.
And so when you have that kind of a
situation,
you have a panic and you see the
slightest bit of advantage happening on
the other side is just something to
completely freak out about.
And then what do you do?
You say,
oh,
well the only possible recipe to balance
the scale is to turn further our way.
If we go toward the middle,
that puts the balance,
say if the right goes really far right,
and we on the left,
moved toward the middle,
now the whole balance has moved,
right?
So the only way to keep the balance
close to the middle as if they go right,
we go left,
right,
right.
So then that's going to keep the
balance.
But what that actually does is it,
this is going to get nerdy.
Hang on.
That actually puts all of the weight on
the outsides and you think about a
spinning thing,
right?
It's got centrifugal forces happening.
What's that trying to do is going to rip
the spinning thing apart?
Well,
if you have all the weight crammed in
the middle,
like a wheel,
it doesn't come apart right?
Now imagine if you had like two billiard
balls and you have like this big long
stick and there's two holes for the
builder bars.
They don't go in at like locked in
there,
just sitting there and you spend that.
What's going to happen there?
Fly Right off,
right.
So if you have all the way down the
outside and you start spinning a thing,
so that's like the political
conversations,
that dynamic is going to rip the thing
apart.
The more weight gets to the outside.
So one side go into the fringe doesn't
mean the other side should go to the
fringe.
That's how you tear a nation apart.
And uh,
I,
I pass out to 30 hits,
two 30 in the morning heads and I'm
just,
uh,
I'm just,
you know,
I wake up because I hear the alarm,
kind of pop off at the,
at the hotel said,
now I'm hearing these alarms starting to
go off.
And I've,
you know,
I checked out,
I checked out on front,
I checked out through the window and I
checked out the lobby.
Nobody was moving.
So I was like,
it's a false alarm.
So I grabbed the pillow,
put over my head and every can slap to
the alarm.
And that happened about two 30.
Now four 30 comes about on this time I
don't wake up,
I don't wake up because of the alarm.
I wake up because of the smoke,
I'm like coffee and I'm,
I'm like coughing on the smog.
And at first I thought I was dreaming.
So I wake up and I,
at that time I had,
I had,
uh,
you know,
I slept in my town.
That's how tired I was and I got up and
I'm going to turn the lights in,
the light tank turning down and then I
go through the window and a check the
window and next,
you know,
and I see the car right in front of me
on fire.
Uh,
three fourths of the hotels,
like I was probably about five rooms
away from like getting hit hard.
Like I'm talking about like,
like fire coming out the window like
that.
And I'm waking up to this,
like thinking I'm dreaming,
you know,
in a towel.
And then the lights,
everything was dark,
but I could see everything like it.
Like the room started getting hot and I
couldn't,
I couldn't hold my breath and the more I
started looking for my shoes,
I couldn't find my shoes.
And I bumped into my slacks that I left
them on the ironing board that the night
before and I put them on and I grabbed,
I grabbed the,
I grabbed my phone and I jumped out the
window.
I jumped out the one that jumped out the
wound on my right foot,
catches on fire,
I right foot catches on fire fast and
I'm looking to kind of,
I'm,
I'm Kinda,
you know,
trying to put it out and it's crazy how
I can see how people could catch on fire
real quick.
Cause my,
my right leg was like food.
It was crazy.
Wow.
So I jumped out and I started walking.
I says I'm walking them seeing like
this,
the hotel in front of us was all in
sticks through like the whole thing was
just in sticks,
like the,
the fire had just ate that thing up.
There's a building in front of me on,
on fire.
Like I'm just walking through the
streets going up the hill and just
thinking like God can be a horrible way
to die.
Horrible way to die.
Fuck.
And I got to,
I got a bird's eye view when it was on
top of the,
uh,
when I was on top of the hill and then I
saw there's a cop down there,
there was a cop down,
uh,
and in the middle of the free ones just
like,
you know,
that's,
that's where I got to go.
So now I'm running fast and I've seen at
this brush fire kind of come along and
just,
I'm seeing like California like just
catch on fire like completely like
through my eyes.
I jump over the first fence to get to
the freeway,
you know,
no problem.
Jump over the second fence.
And then the third fence,
it was a,
it was a very like a flimsy,
a kind of fence.
And I remember I as I,
as I jumped out in rich snag,
like part of my snacks to keep in mind,
I was,
I had,
the only thing I had on was slacks.
I W I got what's commando slacks,
no shirt,
no shoes,
like out in the cold in California.
And as I,
that flimsy fence has,
as I jumped out that last fence,
it like cut it like a part of the fence.
I grabbed my butt and it just,
it cut me open hard and a tour like half
the leg.
So now I'm full,
I'm full,
I'm full of smoke on my right foot's
burn.
And uh,
um,
I'm pretty much half naked in the middle
of for you.
So I see the cop car and I go up to the
cop car and as I'm going up to it,
I'm sorry,
the freaking cop car leaves like fucking
just scrambles and just like,
oh my God.
And as soon as that cop car left,
uh,
I remember seeing like this big as
diesel,
like coming towards me and every get
into the middle of the freeway and kind
of,
you know,
waving my hands like,
you gonna take me,
I die like this,
like hit me dude.
And a,
as it got closer to,
so I was a fire truck and I,
and I get Raskin,
I get rescued by the fireman.
It put me in the fire truck and then
just kind of like looking at him.
He's like down,
do you just,
you just survived death.
Oh,
this is it.
This is the video sent to me on that.
Oh,
here it is.
It's on Worldstar.
Poom watch this.
He gets it with the leg kick.
The guy gets up.
Now watch this.
Showing it on.
Watch this.
Okay.
Boom.
Strong liquor.
Perfectly time.
Watch this.
Ah,
out.
Wow.
Go from the beginning though.
In the beginning.
You see it's long.
It's two minutes long.
Yeah,
but at the beginning you see how the
fight starts to this guy.
Um,
the guys are,
come on motherfucker.
You want some of this?
Get his shirt off.
And the guys like trying,
he's by himself and he's like,
dough.
We'll do one on one.
One on one.
You fought another dude first.
Did he?
Yeah.
This guy,
this guy,
this is the guy legs kicks and after he
leg kicks is dude.
The other guy says,
come on,
keep it over here.
Who doesn't have a wife beater on gimme
some volume on this.
What's going to take it down?
Rondo.
Just how he gonna put up.
Is it going to get taken down from
youtube?
Oh,
okay.
Okay.
Till you turn it down.
Yeah.
So the guy was like,
come on man.
So like this just one dude by himself
with a bunch of other dudes,
but he steps in.
This guy knows how to fight.
Look at it as throwing a jab and the
wash,
this leg kick.
Oh,
so there's quite a bit first whole
different guy.
No,
no,
no.
Yeah,
but that's it right there.
Leg kick,
boom.
Then he cracks him.
And so then the guys like realizing he's
in trouble and so he starts backing away
and the guys coming forward,
he's like,
come on bitch.
And so then the other guy afterwards
goes,
oh,
you think you got load kick in the leg
kick.
So he comes back,
he's like tired of this dude walking
away from him and he's like,
I fucked this dude up with one punch and
he wants a backup and this and this guy
goes,
you want to Luke kick?
You want to Luke kick here.
Right here.
Okay
dog.
Cool.
You don't want to fucking kick
kick home.
Boy,
it takes out.
What is this?
He's like,
I'm gonna try you sticks a drag of a
cigarette first
and it takes his shirt off.
Guy has no idea how to fight,
which is hilarious.
Fat,
not in shape.
Tome leg kick guys.
But people are so ridiculous with this
idea that they think they know how to
fight.
Yeah,
Bang out cold.
But that's dark man.
The banging the head,
the back of the head off the concrete is
dark.
Okay.