Hello Freak bitches are pussies.
Pussies comes up with black lung.
She's smoking cigarettes.
Get dated a girl.
Worried about our bills.
Our date a girl.
One time I had one of her pussy lips
like ran all the way down to her
butthole.
Hello?
Weird.
That's definitely weird.
Not,
it wasn't like Pussy Lips,
the wrong word for it,
but like the line that her pussy lip was
on how much you fan came around the hole
and then it can tick the wrinkle
continued all the way to where bud hall.
I thought that was weird.
That's definitely weird.
Yeah.
Otherwise we would all be gone.
Oh,
I've seen that somewhere.
Someone out there.
It's like I posted up down the rabbit
hole.
Yeah,
that's a weird thing,
huh?
The bottle and the pussy are so close
together.
Yeah,
but bizarre design of nature.
Nature,
such a bizarre fucking creator.
Let's look at nature.
It's the Lord.
Hello.
Because you keep saying nature created.
You won't evidence.
You have the nature created it.
The same proof.
Do you have that?
Yeah.
God created it.
Well,
this is a different type of vagina for
every guy out there.
I think we can all safely say that
saying testimonies of people leaving a
chick cause I just just didn't like to
wear a pussy low.
I've definitely heard of that before.
Yeah,
I have a friend and her ex boyfriend
told her a story about getting together
with some girl going down on her,
pulling her panties off and she has a
clip that's like a pinky.
Any panic had a male.
He panicked and he made up some story
about picking up his brother,
the airport and he ran away and he said
that he knew that the girl knew that he
was bullshitting and they both just sort
of agreed to go along with the charade.
She'd probably had seen other guys like
look at her Dick,
her vagina or whatever.
Her clit clit deck freak out.
She just unfortunately had an enormous,
according to him,
I mean he might've just been a baby,
you know,
it might've been like a little tiny
little baby thumb.
You're like,
come on,
I get over the baby thumb deal.
Does it really bother you?
That wouldn't shake me as much as like
really awful tits.
Isn't it funny though that like there's
a line that you cross as far as like
inches wise,
like here,
like this,
like let's,
let's go with this finger.
Like this is no big deal.
Somebody deals a big clip.
Hey,
what's going on there?
Yeah,
yeah,
yes.
Everything.
Okay.
How you have to do is just move it like
not even a whole finger joint.
Not a whole lot in my face.
Like this is okay.
What the fuck is that?
What is this?
What is that?
And then that's insane.
Yeah.
If you got up to the next knuckle you're
doing like,
I mean,
what is that like an inch.
If it's an inch clit,
fuck that bed.
And then she was a runaway and if it's a
whole finger,
you,
it's a Dick,
you gotta go.
That's great.
Queens.
I've got pictures of huge Klich.
That's why they show will never be on a
network.
I'm so curious how big they get all
things.
I have google.
I've never googled that.
Bodybuilders,
when girls take testosterone,
I used to be,
so Jamie's freaked out.
I'm not going to share it on Youtube.
Okay.
Don't sharing Jesus Christ.
See those are decks or the decks.
That one with the girl's tongue on it
down.
Uh,
on the bottom and the left hand side.
That might as well be a dick.
Yeah.
Well this is the one up top there.
Those ones up top are dicks.
That's a dick.
Dude.
Look at that one.
That where the girls spreading it out.
Okay.
What?
Now did they say,
is this a bodybuilder?
Cause that we're looking at blue.
It looks like a two inch Dick,
but I'm to talking about a train wreck.
My stepfather.
Oh Jesus Christ.
That's a dick.
Okay.
That's a deck that is 100% of the ball's
coming off of it.
Yeah.
What is going on?
But below that monster,
what is that?
Very big clits.
See,
how do we know that this is real?
We just might be,
well that's fake,
but I mean there's some pretty,
it's fake.
I think there's some genetic difference.
Abominations.
Yeah.
What's that one?
The upper right hand corner where it's a
snail laying on a table.
Go large with that please.
What the fuck is happening?
That is not real is it?
She got her pussy eaten by a frog.
Oh,
that's a rubber Dick that's attached to
a table and she's rubbing it on her
giant clip.
That's what that is,
but it looks like she's like giving
birth to a snail.
That's the way hard to explain.
Yeah,
there's okay.
That's her.
Her math has such faith.
That's a,
it's a fake picture.
It might not be,
man.
That's what's weird because some of
these clips are cooler.
Like what that,
what was that one?
The upper,
just feel like we would know who that
person's name is,
if that was a real thing.
Where you ever,
I wish my Dick have that kind of hang.
It's rod number five on the upper upper
level.
Okay.
What is that real?
It's hard to say what's real.
The problem is with the Internet,
you just don't know what's real.
Did you,
did you look up doing,
did you google the word real big list
it?
No,
just huge.
Clits real huge.
Clits.
Oh Jeez.
We're going to hit another law.
Oh God.
Those are dicks.
There's a lot of dicks in there.
Well,
you got to wonder how many of these
people are hermaphrodites.
No wait.
You said you don't mind him.
He puts,
he could cope.
Picture five on the top row.
Well,
that's not meaty.
That's a,
that's like a butcher shop.
See,
but then again,
is that for real?
Is it 100% could be real because it's
got that,
that inside Pussy feel to it.
Just that a gritty skin feeling.
She got dragged by a truck on her pussy
is on her way here.
Like tripe.
It's got a texture.
What is that thing that's got,
that's got three levels of Pussy Lips.
Like aliens mouth to movie aliens with
the little mouth comes out.
It's got eyebrows look,
fall the eyebrows down to the face.
I mean that is like a,
that's an orangutan.
I said,
right.
Does that look like an orangutan?
It does,
right?
It looks like a duck bill.
It's really a wow.
Pussies can be ugly.
Huh?
Look at that and go.
We all thought,
man,
there's no pussy.
I'm running away from Liz is diseased.
Turns out I could just be misshapen.
Well,
if you look at like wc fields nose and
you apply that sort of morphing
possibility and potential to a vagina,
you got a lot of,
it could be ugly.
Can that be our secret code?
If we had a girl say she had a nice
chat,
chat.
That was Jimmy Durante though.
Yeah.
Same thing.
That's actually better.
We'll go with Jimmy Duranti did WC
fields that are fucked up nose,
but I think Jimmy Duranti probably had a
more,
fuck you up.
Knows what does that knows come from
alcoholism.
Always thing.
My Dad's not a drinker at all.
My Dad started to get a little bit of a
bulb.
They'll look at that.
No,
I mean,
not like.
Gotcha.
That's a big one.
Okay.