It's just a perfect situation and we're
live.
Yeah.
And what?
And it's a UFC.
Yeah.
We're talking about UFC fight companion
podcast.
There is so ridiculously fun.
More fun than doing it live.
Yeah.
And then what I was saying is what makes
him super crazy special for me.
I look forward to them so much as it's
not just the best possible podcast
situation.
The most fun at the funniest shit.
We could talk about anything we could
talk about gay shit.
It doesn't matter.
We can do anything.
You can talk about sucking Dick.
We could talk and we totally get away
with it and people started getting sick
of it though.
So we should probably pull back.
I don't know.
Give them more deck.
No,
they,
I don't give a fuck.
People are getting pissed this and some
people are getting past those people you
can't worry about.
But the coolest thing.
Well not the whole assemble it makes it
extra cool is it's the best possible
podcast situation period.
Yeah.
And there's a UFC going on at the same
fucking time and we're all having fun.
It's like you can't take it.
It's like you were doing a podcast,
the funniest shit ever while the
greatest show that's ever been invented
on at the same time,
a combination of those things and it's
the fica is boring.
If for whatever reason it's stagnant,
we just start talking about fucking
owls,
EMC,
but if people get upset talking about
dicks lik that's just where the
conversation goes sometimes.
Don't worry about that.
We're trying the best we can to be
entertaining.
That's all we're trying to.
There's gonna be some slip ups.
If you feel like we're getting too much
dick in there,
you're allowed to express yourself.
I must have that.
We might have a pretty strong gay
following now.
I hope we do.
Probably know.
We're making them feel comfortable.
I hope they do feel comfortable.
I'm just keeping it real.
I see a guy like Alan on.
I just keep it real.
He's a beautiful man,
but even more important than who gives a
fuck,
you know,
this is the thing like that.
It's even remotely controversial that we
would have a gay following.
Probably have a following of Irish
people to.
You know what I mean?
Who Cares?
Who gives a fuck taking of the Irish
speaking.
I've got them right here.
Oh Man.
Hey listen,
man,
this guy has balls.
This is why I respect the fuck out of
conor Mcgregor.
Not just because he's an awesome fighter
and yeah,
he lost Nate Diaz who's also an awesome
fighter,
but who the fuck will fight anybody who
will just jump up.
Alaska was Bj.
Bj tried it and you know what?
Even though a Bj didn't,
he had success once.
At least at one 70 he beat Matt Hughes,
but at the end of the day,
there's a really good reason why all
elite boxers,
wrestlers,
fighters,
weight cutting is so massively
important.
Virtually everybody.
There are some crazy people out there
like Anthony Johnson.
That's the exception,
but generally there's a really good
reason most people are torturing
themselves to get as light as possible
because at the elite level,
five pounds makes a big fucking
difference.
It makes a big difference.
Just five pounds,
10 pounds,
10 pounds.
Different
elite level,
man.
Even the best guys aren't going up.
Went looking for Mendez,
no doubt.
Probably pound for pound.
The best guy in Jujitsu,
probably him and Marcello's.
John.
Jack,
they're all up there.
Bam,
pound for pound.
There's so many good guys.
Now Jesus.
It's incredible.
Now.
You know what I mean?
Uh,
you know,
even Marcello is trying to go up in
weight.
When I was trying to go,
let me this year,
I'm going to try the weight category
above me.
Know everybody's on the craziest died.
They need three months to get serious
about it.
Then on instagram posts in there,
fucking Broccoli every day.
The chicken,
fucking selfies of their,
of their and you know,
the killing themselves because now
because it feels good.
It feels like shit.
They all love eating.
It means it's so important.
Uh,
so everybody knows you just can't go up
and Goddamn.
Wait,
Jay was.
Pj was the one that said fuck it.
He went up to light heavyweight and
shit.
Five foot eight.
No,
it wasn't even light heavyweight bro.
It was heavyweight because Livida
Machida was like two.
Oh,
eight.
Okay.
I think that fight was like technically
a heavyweight fight.
Find that out.
But with Bj Penn Cheetah,
you know what I mean,
he was fat that's out of shape,
but you ever see when he used to fight
like kickbox fat,
his first UFC fight,
that's not as real weight.
His real weight is 205,
185.
So,
uh,
but Bj did it and I always admired him.
I,
to me and to me I looked,
I'll always look at Bj as a living
legend.
Yeah,
the guy didn't.
He's not undefeated.
He got his ass beat a few times.
Who gives a fuck?
Look what Bj did.
He had the balls to step up and really
he was a 45 or just like,
just like there's no.
The whole time he was a foreigner.
And in Jujitsu he was a 45.
He was always a 45 or fighting at 55 70.
Nobody else was doing it.
And you know,
Connor,
here he comes.
this guy
has so much power in his hands.
He had that courage to think he could
finish what Bj started,
you know,
let me go up there and do that.
Do what Bj did.
But,
you know,
he felt like he could fucking knock
anybody out.
He really,
really believed he could fucking,
he will be lanced you're going down and
you know what he was doing great against
Nate Diaz.
I mean,
this is my,
this is how I found out I'm watching.
I'm at a party slam Lee's house.
And uh,
I didn't realize we were behind by a
minute and a half.
We were live.
I thought we were alive,
but we were behind biomineral.
Everyone's going nuts.
I'm watching going.
Oh Shit.
Lizzie borden.
Sit next to me.
My childhood idol.
He's one of my greatest favorite lead
singers of all time.
We sit next to him more watching
everyone's going nuts.
It looks like Connor's to me.
I was like,
Connor's to win this thing man.
He was light nate up cutting them all
up.
He was connecting.
He looked really confident.
Like Carla called that whole first
round.
I was gone.
It's,
it's,
uh,
it was,
it was over in the forest.
Second second.
It was a second.
So at in that round,
I get a call from Joey,
Joey's,
I go,
oh,
you know how much I want to know how
much I told you.
I told you you never bet against Diaz.
I go,
what are you talking about?
I thought it was watching.
Are you talking about the Meesha fight?
He goes,
no motherfucker.
He got choked.
Go.
Who got choked up?
Called the home,
got choked out.
I'm watching the data as we know.
Motherfucker.
What thought of you watching right now?
I'm watching the conor pipe as it's
going on.
He goes,
he choked him out.
I'm like,
dude,
fuck.
And he goes,
by boom.
He realized he fucked up and I'm like,
I knew that Diaz was gonna win a minute.
You've lost pee or something.
We were at a party and it was just
behind someone for awhile and shit.
And you didn't fast forward it.
So we thought it was live.
So Joey Joey called me hysterical and he
gave it away.
And then once he realized he gave it
away,
he hung up and said,
oh shit.
And I said,
Oh shit.
He just fucked up the greatest fight
ever,
but the fight was so crazy and so
fucking insane that even though I knew
better,
even though I knew I go,
okay,
somehow nate is going to take him down
and choke him out,
but it doesn't look good right here.
I'm like,
how is he going to take connor down?
That's not going to bz fuck.
He's going to pull this off.
How is he going to do it?
I had no idea that may.
It hurts connor.
Connor takes him down,
you know?
That's how it went down.
The place I was at was going fucking
nuts.
Everybody was screaming at the top of
the fucking longs.
Everyone's and then when he choked him
out,
dude,
I'd never been in a party where everyone
was going so crazy before everybody was
losing their fucking mind.
I was too holy Shit blind.
Everybody was going crazy.
I almost had a.
I never screamed so loud in my
motherfucking life at any fight ever.
That was shocking.
It was.
It looked like Karma was just had his
hands down because I got this mother
fucker.
He was landon.
He was tagging them,
it looked like you heard them a couple
times.
He tagged them,
you know what I mean?
It looked like he was.
I thought it was,
it was over for nate.
I really did.
And when he turned it around and the way
it finished and,
and when he put that fucking rear naked
choke and he put that motherfucker in
like a Super Ninja,
the weight,
first of all,
the way he mounted,
if you don't do Jujitsu,
you would never know the way he fucking
mounted and his balance.
You could see the balance.
You could see the beauty in that mound
and the way he was riding him,
like a professional fucking a champion
Rodeo.
Fucking reiner on his balances.
All beautiful.
And then when he took his back,
the way he put that fucking Hook in
there was,
it was so efficient.
There wasn't a hiccup where he hit the,
you know,
this jaw and then if you have a set up
and then to feel it just went.
It was fucking insanity.
So perfect.
And so fucking like that technique was
about is flawless and as beautiful as
you can get,
two big points was that we had never
seen conor face adversity and we had
never seen him on the ground with a real
Brazilian Jiu Jitsu black belt.
Like nate.
Nate's got a nasty ground game man.
His name,
but I.
People are talking to a lot of shit on
connor's Jujitsu.
I know connor.
Jujitsu is good.
He's coming to my school.
That guys good?
Just cause he got mountain down.
Yeah,
he was already here.
But even if he wasn't her,
I get mounted by my purple belt
sometimes and I get my bag.
There's some shit going on and at
punches and fucking all this height.
Just because he got mountain and got us
back taking does not mean connor's
Jujitsu sucks.
Don't get it twisted.
He was a little hurt.
Nate Diaz is really good stuff.
Really good.
You know what I mean?
Like Nate Diaz could probably do that to
me.
Doesn't mean I suck.
You know what I mean?
He could probably get my back.
Doesn't mean I suck.
I'm a high,
you know so.
Well,
he got hurt him.
It's real simple.
When you get tagged the way he got
tagged trying to take Nate Diaz down.
He got hurt.
He probably had no idea what the fuck he
was doing.
You know,
I haven't had an MMA fight,
but sharp was telling me about when
Travis Browne hit him and that he was
like,
dude,
I know how to get out of the mountain,
but when travis hit me,
he's like,
I didn't know what I was doing.
It was.
I was out of it.
I think that we should get punched in
the face,
but I can't judge his Jujitsu.
You're judging is walking if you get
head kicked.
Commerce.
Jujitsu is good.
Nate Diaz.
Jujitsu is just way better.
You know what I'm saying?
If that's all it is,
suddenly punches you in the face and
then you walk funny.
I'm like,
man,
you need to work on your walking.
Funny memes of Connor,
like add in like a kids Jujitsu class.
They put a slice.
That's one that's going around that.
I think that's hurt.
You know what he's heard?
He is good.
Trust me.
Connors.
Jujitsu is very,
very standard to me.
He's not a joke,
especially in that first round was nasty
standup,
like very good.
He's just a look.
First of all,
he's not a real one.
70 old lady did fight one 70 twice.
He fought a stun gun.
Kim and fought rory.
Rory Macdonald,
remember that?
Fought those guys at one 70.
So he did have to fight at one 70,
but he's a 1:50 fiber.
These are big one.
50th five or he's big and long.
I don't know if he could ever make 1:45.
I just don't think he could do it.
Connor barely can do it.
You know,
connor apparently can do it.
When you see conor at the weigh ins,
I mean those photos from the winds are
pretty legendary.
I think it's insane that we do this,
that we let these guys dehydrate
themselves like that.
I think whatever nature walks that,
that's what he should fight.
And I don't know if connor really walks
around at one slash 68,
which would he weighed in and nate raid
one 69.
There were only one pound different.
And Nate,
you know,
nate had some body fat on him because he
wasn't,
it wasn't preparing for this at all.
I think connor,
connor could make some noise at 1:55
shrink down to see the two of those
together.
Can we look at the difference between
how we weighed in before and how he
weighed in this time?
I mean,
my God,
he looks like he has some fucking crazy
disease that like won't let food
absorbent his body on the top one,
you know,
like he's got some crazy illness and
then on the bottom he looks great full
faced.
But you know,
if you can make 1:45,
he's going to continue to do it.
Can you think gets in.
The girls are like sitting right there.
Is that an accident is perfect for the
pictures.
That's why they stand their ultimate
man.
It's to balance out that dude in
underwear
put chips in there.
So that's exactly what it was.
That's funny.
That's what I think he could completely
dominate.
Continue to dominate the 1:45 division
and I think he could make a lot of epic
fights at 1:55,
five.
Went beat some big names but then lose
to some other big names,
like he'll be one of the top guys at 55.
I don't know if he'll just clean house
like he did at 45,
but I believe if he stayed at 55 he
would do some serious damage.
He's a bad motherfucker.
Yeah.
He's a shitty saying after the fight.
That's perfect ship.
Perfect Shit.
I love what he's doing.
I love how he's handling it.
I think he handled it his last better
than anybody ever,
ever.
He said children victory and I'm be
humbling defeat.
No matter what happened in that fight.
His next fight,
whoever he's fighting,
he's going to get fucked up.
You know what I mean?
Maybe.
I mean,
would it be fights?
Dos Anjos,
you know
he's going to cut them up.
I bet it tags them a few times.
I bet you're right.
I bet he tags and I bet you're asking
tag everybody to hit some people and
just because he got knocked out a lot of
people,
every half the people get knocked out
and fights.
He got knocked out,
he got,
he got cracked and he got choked,
but I'm,
I'm interested in to see how he handles
the physicality of Dos Anjos who's a lot
more physical than nate.
You know,
dos Anjos is a beast.
I want to.
I want to know if he could do to connor
what he was able to do to nate,
but he was able to do to a lot of guys
like pedis,
what he did to pedis,
you know that God is strong as shit,
but I was so bummed out when he broke
his foot,
I was like,
God,
that's a crazy fight and so it's going
to be there,
but fucking nate,
all of a sudden they start
that little stoner is going to be.
He's dude,
he's,
he's super famous now.
Everybody knows,
dude,
he has the greatest all time.
Post-Fight line.
I got to say,
I'm not surprised.
Motherfuckers know what's funny.
You know what's due in the beginning,
conor won the verbal.
That battles the first couple press
commerce.
He kinda did.
Connor came full blown and then nate,
nate one towards the end,
I felt that nate was in connor's had,
I think it reversed at bay.
I think he was pissing connor off that
he kept saying,
fuck you.
He just wouldn't gangster on them.
Every time my crew will fuck up your
crew.
Like I said,
if you want to make this fucking serious
week,
we're going to pass by you guys
somewhere in the small fucking hotel
will jump.
You will do that.
You guys want to do that will actually
jump you guys and it'll be all over
fucking shirt on the ship.
You know that a pen.
Dania and gotten a full blown street
fight on the set of tough head kicks.
Everything.
You know,
those two bad ass chicks.
Cologic a Dahlia is a bad ass bitch.
You've seen her fight,
right?
She's nasty.
You know what?
She's one that I have zero images in my
shoes.
Nasty.
Her and Joan Jett check had a,
um,
they had a really close first fight
split decision when for you on Jay
check.
So they coached opposite side each
other.
She's the number one contender.
When does that ferocious?
She's ferocious.
I liked the ultimate fighter Bolus will.
Sounds good.
One to John Jay.
Check is ferocious.
And Claudia good.
Dahlia?
Yeah,
there it is in Brazil fight.
Yeah man,
she's a Nova on yow girl.
She's good.
She's a fuck Ya.
Real good.
Jujitsu and strong as shit.
Strong as shit.
When they fought the first time where
she was winning was on the ground and
she was doing well on the feet too.
But you on a corner with a big upper cut
I think in the first round of rocked
her,
but when she's trying to take her down
I'd have to go back and watch it again.
I remember specifics that you want a
cracker with a big upper cut and hurt
her,
but that Claudia had overwhelmed her and
some of the ground exchanges and a lot
of people were thinking that you and Jay
check was going to have more problems
with grapplers.
Like Carla Esparza or like,
um,
you know,
Carl was a wrestler or like,
um,
uh,
Juliana pinay.
What's now?
No,
Jessica.
Jessica Panay,
the second title defense that she had.
These girls try to wrestle with her
though.
She can.
You can't wrestle with her anymore.
She's.
She got better.
She's nasty.
She's really fucking slick.
Standing up.
And apparently they just went to war.
They just on the set,
beat the shit out of each other.
You're Dana White.
What do you do with a Misha Dude?
Pillow her up.
She's huge,
but who have regis?
I don't know,
man,
but give her a world tour first.
She,
she won one of the greatest victories in
the history of mma down down on the
score cards in the fourth round with two
minutes to go.
She hits a take down,
takes her back,
almost gets shook over the top,
hangs on,
hangs on.
That was so dramatic.
That was like the end of.
She fought so smart.
She did everything that all the experts
were saying she was going to need to do.
She did everything.
She didn't rush in Russian and she had
to pull it off.
And like,
what was our minute left?
Tom?
Like somewhere around two minutes to go
when she went for the take down.
When she,
when she got ahold of her.
So you're down to last round.
Last round.
Enjoy wasn't winning the round.
Nothing really had happened.
That was like big and significant.
She had a takedown,
probably lose it on the cards.
Crappy.
I didn't look at the cards,
but you know,
she won that one round for sure.
When she take her down and that went
made everybody go,
oh shit.
Is that the second was at the second
round that she took her down?
This was dominating her.
Um,
yeah,
I think it was the second her was
wrestling.
Surprisingly.
Her wrestling is a lot better than
before.
Before she's hustling to.
She hustled,
she keeps getting better.
And Holly Holm and easy to take down.
Take down the fence.
That's like her main shit too.
Probably works on her takedown defense
more than her Jujitsu.
So this is the cards.
Yeah.
So what does it say in basically what
are we going in here?
Me,
you should take this hard to do.
These are confusing.
White,
blue,
pink.
There's a pink card.
I get the.
Oh,
the different people.
Just as the referee's names.
Okay.
So round nine.
So 10,
nine.
Well,
who's reading?
Who's blue?
Blue.
Blue on the left.
Okay.
So how.
Yeah.
So it must've been the.
Hmm.
That's interesting.
Wait,
wait a minute.
All three at 10.
Nine for the first.
All three had 10.
Eight for the second,
right.
That makes sense.
And all three at 10.
Nine for the third and for the fourth.
So does that make it a draw?
No,
that means holly was ahead.
Well how do they judge the fourth and
then the fifth?
And she would say head in the fourth.
So holly was ahead by one point,
right?
Yep.
Even though she'd won three rounds.
Yes.
I mean,
if she would have won that round,
it would have been a draw I guess.
Wow.
She was.
She wasn't really willing around right
there.
I'm surprised that they all gave him a
10.
Eight.
That's good.
That's very good.
Good to hear.
Their name is Marcos for solids.
Good job.
That was a.
That was a real tenant.
That's how it should look.
Someone takes you down and beat the shit
out of you.
But just what an what a finish.
That was.
What was amazing about it and you know
holly fought smart.
She used that side kick a lot.
She's so good with her movement.
She caught me with a lot of punches to
man,
but she wasn't.
She wasn't going after her.
She would catch her with punches and
stay on the outside.
She was fighting a smart fight and she
got taken down.
She got dominated on the ground by
Meesha and that's when I was like,
wow,
me,
she's fucking top game is solid as a
rock.
Like her control is excellent and her,
she's fucking strong man.
She's drunk because holly strong.
Holly Holm is strong.
I was really impressed with their ground
and pound really impressed with our top
game.
But then you know what man,
the next round,
Holly Holm got right back on her fucking
bicycle and,
and,
and probably in everyone's eyes when
that round,
right.
All those judges eyes to me.
It was a,
if that would have wanted a decision,
now I would've given it to holly just
based on,
uh,
you know,
depending upon how that no real damage.
She never knocked me down.
She never hurt me shit.
Right.
That was the shepherd.
Her never heard her.
She tagged her a couple times where,
you know,
she snapped her head back a little bit,
but it wasn't anything like what she was
legs giving out.
No.
So it,
it was,
it was about to be a semi boring
decision overall.
Like who would want to watch that fight
again?
The second round is kind of cool.
It was going to be one of those fights,
but just like that,
she turned it into one of the greatest
fights ever.
Amazing comeback that last second.
That's like a grand slam and the bottom
of the ninth and the scramble to get to
the back,
her scramble,
the way she held on as Hollywood kept
moving and changing and adjusting.
She kept holding on.
Then finally the Hail Mary Hollie tries
to flip her over the top and she hangs
on,
hangs onto the choke and sinks it in and
it gets the hooks in and,
and when holly goes to sleep,
punching in the air,
you know those old nfl films,
like when you watch those superbowl from
1978 or something to have that voice and
they're together.
They're doing the slow mo and these all
these old,
you know,
memorable place like epic plays in 20
years.
When they look back at that and they
have some old like Orson Welles type a
narrator talking about,
about going through all that transition.
There was a lot of drama going on there,
man.
She didn't just take her back and choke
her.
There was a lot of shit.
There was a lot of shit to handle what's
going on and watch what's happening.
It was incredible to.
We're naked chokes.
The scrambled though to scramble was
just so epic because the drama building
up,
he.
She's down on the cards.
Most likely.
You can't watch that were watched?
No,
we can never.
Once she down on the car,
it's most likely she's about to.
She's about to lose a decision probably.
Oh my God.
She's got ahold of her.
She's on her back.
Oh my God.
She got that job,
kept going and going back and then when
holly went to sleep,
it was like she didn't even tap.
She went out.
She went out punching.
She was throwing punches.
When she went out to your bad ass,
you have to be to go out throwing
punches.
Oh,
bad ass.
That girl is.
She went out.
She went out like throwing punches.
She didn't want to tap.
Fuck.
That was a good fight.
Woo.
It's amazing.
Back the best fight of the night.
That was that the biggest UFC ever.
I mean,
Jesus.
That was the biggest UFC ever.
I mean,
I would sat that night,
but he's not the fight of the night.
It's the same.
The both equally insane.
There's no like one better finale or one
better.
Uh,
and I think the conor fight was more
excited because all the way through that
was a lot of damage going on.
There was a lot of fire going on with
the holly fight.
There was a lot of dancing around taking
shots.
I was a lot of,
you know,
definitely it was,
there was a lot less action overall.
Yeah.
But if you compress those,
if you take out a couple of those rounds
and compress it all into one round,
then yeah,
I see.
I don't think you got to be pleased by
it through the whole thing.
I think what's most important is that
after it ends you have some definitive
conclusion and if it takes a while to
get that definitive conclusion,
I mean it's going to fly.
Fighters are tactical.
You're right.
But it was because of that that made the
end so good.
Without that.
Then it wouldn't have been so juicy at
the end.
Exactly.
Because she had gone through the full
five or when they were in the fifth
round and there was like,
we've got to see.
She's trying things and not working.
She tries this.
It works really good.
Okay.
Now how he's trying this that's working
meets is trying that.
That's not working.
Okay.
Now she's started to kick.
When she got,
she got to do something different to get
close to her.
How's she going to figure it out?
Down on the score.
Shoots for the fucking take down.
Grabs a hold of her kitchen.
Chokes or unconscious.
Oh my God.
Because yeah,
you wouldn't have been that low from
that stuff.
Yeah.
To the place went insane.
It was insane.
It was so epic.
Then Dalmatia Tate,
man.
God Damn.
She was so happy.
She's so nice.
You know?
She's such a like her and holly.
They're both so nice.
It's so nice to see nice people like
that do really well in such a brutal
savage sport.
You know?
She's really nice.
Like when have you ever use or Misha
Tate's?
Never like raised her voice at anybody.
She never yelled at anybody.
She's like real friendly.
She's real sweet to see her.
The UFC bantamweight champion.
I was like,
wow,
this is crazy.
Well performance.
I think holly is a little bit nicer
though.
She's super nice.
She seems like there's some country like
wife.
You know what I mean?
She's the preacher's daughter.
She really did.
She really is.
Wow.
And she's tough as fuck,
dude.
She went out punching a cold.
She was like throwing punches.
She just wants to get the interposed.
She just want her to get back into it.
She was like,
when do you.
She just wants to get back in.
I know what I loved about the preflight
speech when she was talking about the
fight itself,
she was like,
you know what?
Rhonda is going to be out for awhile.
She was,
I'm not fighting for money.
I'm not fighting for fame.
I want the action.
I want to fight like,
Whoa,
wild with you.
That's how you got to think.
If you want to be great,
right?
It's something to focus on.
Yeah.
If you want to be a holly Holm,
I guess you have to be like that.
We want to be a 19 time world's women
boxing champion.
You've got to be a crazy motivated
person.
She's got to.
She's got to fall in love with Jujitsu
though,
because she's not the biggest fan of Jiu
Jitsu.
She really needs that.
You had said before that I know that.
I know that's hard to swallow,
you know,
but you got to,
you can't be one of those fighters that.
And there's a bunch of them out there,
uh,
that uh,
they didn't really want to get
offensively good at Jujitsu.
They didn't really have a,
they weren't attracted to passing the
garden,
taking
the back and choke and PPI.
There's a lot of wrestlers out there
that just wanted to keep it on the feet,
do a little to defense and if you have
to take them down,
stay in half guard and pound them out
and just keep it simple and keep it like
that.
You know,
if,
um,
there's a lot of wrestlers like that.
Now that she's the restaurant,
they're strikers.
They're strikers like that too.
There's been a quite a few throughout
the years,
champions that didn't really want to
work on their Jujitsu the right way,
the right way,
which is sparring with everybody and not
picking her up sparring upon.
And just jumping into the fire,
that's how in O'connor's good,
because connor does that and he's going
to get way better.
He's actually good at Jujitsu.
Just nate is a lot better,
but I think holly needs to have somehow,
somehow it needs to happen.
I don't know how,
but she needs to fall in love with
Jujitsu in and uh,
because I think that's where people
know.
I mean that,
that's the spot we were already.
We haven't really seen her on her back.
We haven't seen a reactive Jujitsu now
we have and Mischa just exposed her and
she needs to take that.
She needs to take care of that and fall
in love with Jujitsu and start getting
on Instagram,
taking pictures with her.
Gee,
you know what I mean?
And she's got a blue belt and be all
happy.
She's got to be really happy about it
because she needs a,
there's a,
there's a hole right there.
And that's where people are going to try
to take her.
She's not that hard to take down.
After all,
I thought she'd be harder to take down,
but you know me.
She took her down.
Well,
Misha mixes up or take Dante.
She goes to
up and she goes down,
download.
Whereas Ronda is like upper body clench.
She's really an upper body clench,
so all holly had to do also Rondon.
That fight was so insanely aggressive.
Her charging after made it so much
easier for counters.
Misha was super crafty.
She liked very patient,
very patient,
varied.
Her movement varied or timing didn't do
any like,
like she didn't continue any patterns
with this.
Her stand up.
She moved around a lot and she did a lot
of Juke in and a lot of.
She did a lot of different stuff.
Stayed on the outside,
made holly come after her.
Like if you,
if you're.
If you're a really good counter striker
like holly is for her,
the best thing is a Rhonda,
like someone's going to run at her.
The best thing is someone running out or
she's.
She's so fleet like her footwork,
so excellent.
She sold light on her feet that she's so
good at just sliding out of the way and
cracking you while you're coming in.
It's like one of the things she's best
at.
So if you fight that,
we're against her.
That's the kind of fight that happens.
You'll look,
she looks like a master,
but if you look at her fight in the very
first UFC fight with Raquel Pennington,
she wanted a split decision.
Yeah.
You know,
and that was a fight where raquel fought
more cautious,
a little smarter,
new new holly's background coming in,
you know,
if you don't like,
if you don't engage with her.
It's like,
remember when Anderson was in,
his prime guys came after him.
He just butchered him.
But if guys hung back,
sometimes the fight was boring,
right?
Like,
um,
talus latest.
Remember tonsillitis,
like hung back and he kind of waited for
Anderson.
Same thing with Patrick.
Patrick de hung back,
he just fought smart.
He's like,
I'm going to charge it,
run it in anything.
Come,
come,
get me,
come get me.
And coach k like,
oh,
he's had a big right hand.
So everybody had to be real careful.
You always have to be careful because a
guy,
if you're coming at him,
he could always catch you.
And if a guy like [inaudible] catches
you,
he just had that stupid power in his
hand.
He could just knock.
He knocked out Tito at two.
Oh five.
Do you remember that?
He knocked him out down,
knocked him down to take a shot.
But he knocked him down at two.
Oh five.
And he fights it one 70.
No,
no.
I mean Patrick Ho taken crack.
So Anderson never want Patrick Blues
Neon.
That fight.
Yeah.
He like went to throw a kick and his
knee just gave out.
It's really exploded.
Yeah.
He fought a very smart fight to.
And that's that stain when you,
you find a killer counter striker like
that.
The big thing is like,
let them lead.
They don't,
they don't want to lead.
Make it a boring fight.
Let it be boring.
Move around,
be patient me.
She did everything right,
man.
It's amazing.
Rhonda.
Meesha three would be nice,
right?
That's probably what it's going to
happen.
It's probably what's going to happen
next according to what I've read on the
Internet because I have here,
I wonder what Rhonda would want.
Would she want to.
She probably a rematch with her after a
loss or a title shot if I was her
thought it was a tough choice.
Rather if I was her,
if I was a tough choice,
right?
Boy,
uh,
can be her.
If I was her,
honestly I would probably,
I would imagine if I was her,
I'd want to avenge the loss because
Hollywood,
uh,
her first loss and she doesn't feel like
she did her best and I'm fight and that
fight was just too much going on.
If you hear her talk about it,
it was like there was just overwhelmed
with obligations and shit and just
fought wrong.
Just didn't,
didn't fight correctly.
Just had real problems going into that.
And then you have like her approach like
kitten in Holly's face the way in trying
to make it real emotional,
you know,
you fake ass bitch and all that stuff.
And then all that emotions when she
fought in the ranks just running after
holly and holly just fall like a master,
that was one of the best performances
you'll ever see of a striker and the
gating a person's aggression.
Like she just did it so brilliantly.
Cash.
No,
with elbows coming in,
catching it with straight lefts.
And then that fucking set up for the
head kick when Rhonda is all stumbling
and she just catches her with that head
kick him.
And just a spectacular mixed martial
arts performance overall.
Like one of the best,
like title winning efforts in any weight
class as far as like a sheer domination.
It's right up there with Tj dillashaw
Hanan Barao one but more,
probably more scary.
And it's one of the most spectacular
highlight clips ever where she's getting
clipped.
Yup.
Wow.
Amazing.
It's like she's a bad ass,
you know.
So what I think about holly is,
you know,
holly get back on track and uh,
I,
I really hope that she takes that advice
that you just gave.
I think that'd be real smart.
You've got to somehow fall in love and
not fight it no more.
Well,
I don't know if she fights it.
I don't know what the deal is.
Who knows?
She's just so good at kickboxing.
I think she just wants to stay sharp in
that and that's what she wants to do to
girls because she feels like she has
this big advantage of them against them
in that.
But obviously she needs a little work on
it and I think she'll get better.
Man.
She,
she can,
she can still improve,
you know,
and I think maybe there's also the
overwhelming pressure that must come
from being a champ,
like that experience probably takes a
while to learn how to navigate it.
I hope I'm wrong and she's already in
love with it.
That would be awesome if I was wrong,
you know,
I'm rooting for Holly.
I like holly.
I think.
Holly,
could you not agree with a course?
How could I not like it?
I'm just being real.
I'm sorry if that hurts anybody.
Three.
No,
no,
no.
I think what you're saying is important
and I hope and I hope that I'm wrong.
I hope that you have no idea.
She's totally into it.
She's been.
She just hasn't worked on it,
that loan or whatever what I'm saying,
but I would love to see Holly Hall with
an aggressive offer back and dangerous
offer back.
There's no reason why she couldn't be.
She's super athletic.
She has a crazy work ethic,
a car by her designer and I'm Brendan
batch.
There was a fight on the undercard
batches,
a super talented guy,
man,
super talented karate guy,
but a bar does.
Auto was able to take him down.
He didn't have any answers off his back.
It's like one of those examples of a guy
who's a really talented striker where
you're not getting to see the full
extent of his talent because he has a
difficult time fighting off his back and
has a difficult time keeping guys from
taking them down.
So just,
you know,
he's guys are figuring that out with him
and a couple guys have dominated him on
the ground and it's just unfortunate
because he's so talented with his
striking.
Like when you see a guy like that,
you just want to go,
man,
if you could figure out a way to find
balance in your skill set,
how good would he be?
You know,
he's so good standing up,
but by her does auto man.
My God,
that guy hits hard.
He's got one of those weird punching
power bodies like you,
like make familiar with him.
He's from Afghanistan who was born in
Afghanistan and grew up in Holland I
think.
Um,
but he is a,
I want to say he did.
I don't think he.
Who did he trained with?
Um.
Oh,
Greg Jackson,
who was at Greg Jackson's camp for this,
but he's been out for like 800 days.
He had some serious injuries,
both the rooms almost three years.
Two and A.
Yeah,
a little bit more than two years.
He had both his Labor rooms had to be
operated on and broke his hand fucked
up.
Which one's the labor room and say your
shoulder.
Oh Shit.
He had a bunch of shit operated on.
And so he was out for a long time.
So to see him come back and see,
like in the beginning you see them on
his back and he tries to,
he almost catches a triangle who's
throws up his legs and you know,
if someone who had a really good
triangle,
nate,
nate was in that same position,
he would got it.
You've got the triangle for sure.
I mean it was all there or at least he
would have secured it and by her desire
with how to defend it,
but he couldn't secure it and I was
like,
man,
that's just.
It was right there.
I out of the leg over the other.
Like here it was over like this.
There wasn't that much resistance.
I grab your fucking ankle,
lock that in like what he do and he just
didn't.
And then you see them for the rest of
the fight was having a real hard time
fighting off his back.
We see a guy that's good.
He's so talented standing up,
man.
You watch them throw knees and punches
you like Jesus.
This could be,
this kid could be a fucking force.
She's got to really Polish up that
ground game and especially off of his
back.
No,
this is a crazy sport,
man.
You can't just have one way to go
anymore.
You got to have the whole thing.
You can't.
There's,
there's very few people that are going
to exist in this sport at the upper
echelons with just one way to go.
You know,
one of the things that's so scary about
a guy like nate that nate's needs.
Boxing is just as good as his Jujitsu.
You know,
his.
And sometimes you don't see the Jujitsu
that much because he's so confident as
boxing and he throws down with guys,
but guys go to the ground with them.
I mean,
he's choked out some good dude's fucking
good.
You've got to have some serious
finishing power on the ground.
Whether it's on your back.
Are you on top?
You have,
at least with you on top,
you'd better have finishing.
Maybe you just use your bottom game for
sweeps.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Uh,
you don't,
you don't have to finish the guy off
your back.
But it's always good.
It,
it's better.
If you could find it,
if you're known to finish people off
your back,
that's anytime I roll with anybody
that's even a purple belt,
who his specialty is finishing people
off his back end.
If there's always those students.
When I'm on a roll,
Jeremiah,
I almost rather have the mounting me
hang up.
I ended up in,
has got him a fuck.
That mount made easier to get out of the
mountain.
It is his rubber guard.
Serious craze.
And there's few guys like that,
like a Boogie at anytime.
Boogie put me in his garden.
I go right to the mountain.
I gotta check out this week.
You're a bad motherfucker
go crazy because that goes against
conventional.
Oh yeah.
But uh,
my,
I don't have the greatest,
the greatest posture in the world.
And My,
my lower back's all fucked up so I don't
try to posture out of shit.
I just,
I go with everything man.
Like you want to go that way?
Let's go and let me see if I could hold
on and get a little clench and then go
back this way.
You know,
I don't,
I don't.
I'm too old to a forced my way through
anything.
That's probably the smart way to do it
though,
right?
That's my Jujitsu is becoming very
survival now.
My guys are fucking me up.
Now.
There's this phase where I'm getting
tapped out all the goddamn time.
Now,
man,
am I.
If I'm the only way I can cap out
certain purple belts as if I have gas.
If I'm tired and I take around with one
of my purple belts,
I'll be fucking on,
on a survival mode the whole time,
man.
My guys are coming with fire now.
Throwing leg locks.
You leave your feet out.
Damn.
Uh,
it's,
it's pretty crazy not getting any leg
injuries.
No,
no,
no.
Just my back.
Finally getting a district meeting.
Other people in class getting any knee
injuries or anything?
No,
no.
It's a myth.
It's a myth that you hurt your arm or
your shoulder at the same rate.
You'll hurt your knee.
We do leg locks all the goddamn time.
That's so interesting because I was
always.
The word planning has always been that
way.
We never banned reaping.
We never,
I never frowned upon heel hooks.
I personally never got really heavy on
heel hooks.
I was always heavy on lead compressions,
a different style leg lock.
I was always doing those.
Not really.
He'll hook so much.
Uh,
but uh,
we've always had heel hook masters.
No,
I wouldn't,
I probably wouldn't have asked that if
that wasn't something that comes up all
the time.
People talk about Lego blocks,
you know,
I kind of know the answer because if it
was,
I would've heard about it that you would
have told me.
I think it's a myth that leg locks are
when we were brought up in Jujitsu,
the whole Brazilian Jiu Jitsu community
band,
heel hooks and,
and frowned upon them.
And,
and do you remember that time you were
at a tournament and they started booing
and screaming when you went for guy's
leg?
Yes.
When I first,
during my white belt years and into my
blue belt years,
I saw Ken shamrock instructional.
He's wearing jeans and shit and it's got
no shirt.
He was wearing jeans and he's like small
little gentleman.
He's got this Japanese guy and he's
doing this.
Told from the top,
from top half,
and I was always playing half garlic
right away as a white belt because
that's like the worst guard every
quarter guard.
I mean it doesn't get any worse than
that.
Anything worse as you got your guard
pass.
So I was always playing the worst shit
because I was small and weak.
But uh,
um,
you would go up to toe holt?
Yeah,
I learned from Ken shamrock started
going after toehold and I got pretty
good at them.
I was tapping motherfuckers with them
and I,
I did this tournament.
It was the first Pan Am's and it was an
la and Elsa Gundo.
Nineteen 96 or 97.
The first pan ams I went for a toehold
and there was about $500 Brazilians that
they shipped in because it was the first
Pan Am's and there was like this big
retreat and they took me.
They had them all in this,
this hotel right down the street from
the gym.
And it was man and shit.
I'll never forget that.
And this.
We're an Elsa Gundo la and there was 500
Brazilians that got shipped in for the
Pan Ams and of course they dominated and
they killed everybody in Jujitsu,
but I did Russell,
Brazilian and I put them in a toll.
Then as soon as I put them in the toll,
the whole crowd went nuts.
It was a riot.
Almost happened was just a riot.
I Dunno what,
what stopped them,
but they were throwing shoes at the math
that were throwing bottles at,
at the,
uh,
water bottles at me and I was sitting
there holding a toehold and everyone's
screaming and under,
I forget Johnny Machado comes running
like slow motion and he slacked because
you got to let it go,
let it go.
And I was like,
fuck.
And I let it go and then the guy beat me
on points,
but I'm.
So John Machado slid in and told you,
you gotta let it go.
Because everybody was going crazy.
Everyone was gone crazy.
Or let him contact the legs.
But you weren't supposed to tie.
It was dirty.
It was dirty back then.
And then in the parking lot like that,
that mean Joe Green commercial,
remember that old,
mean Joe Green commercial where he's
drinking a coke and there's like a
little kid.
Well,
I felt like a little kid because I ran
into Eric Paulson in the parking lot and
he was getting the same reaction when he
was gone for like blocks and he was like
a blue belt at the time and he,
he and uh,
I think we're the same age,
but for some reason I felt always felt
like a little kid and he had all this
knowledge.
He was a blue belt in Jujitsu,
buddy,
uh,
trained in Japan and fought and shooto
and shit.
He was already like a professional
fighter and an expert at leg locks who
just got into Jujitsu.
So he's competing,
competing on a blue belt.
Fucking everybody up,
put leg locks,
right?
Is there a Paulson,
Paulson in 24.
And we're in the parking lot and he
showed me this leg lock and he goes,
listen,
check this out man.
Don't forget this.
Because he,
he,
he saw a little of him in me because I
was going for a toll because I'll fuck,
look at that dude.
He's getting a lot of heat to because
he's going for a leg lock so right away.
But it was totally legal.
That's what's crazy.
You could have tapped the guy out and it
would have been illegal.
I don't know.
I don't remember what the rule set.
I don't remember.
But.
So my thought,
I thought they were legal and maybe it's
illegal,
but even if it was illegal,
the crowd erupted.
The Brazilians with nuts and throwing
shoes and screaming and shit for some,
some belt ranks.
Right?
Like in some tournaments.
Yeah.
Uh,
you can do heal hooks,
gracie nationals and Gracie worlds.
You can do heal hooks at purple belt and
above.
White Belt and blue belt.
No heel hooks.
You can do straight ankle and knee bars
at blue enough.
No legs at all at white,
zero legs at White,
straight ankle locks,
knee bars,
leg compression at blue.
And then they allow heel hooks for
reaping everything purple belt on.
Those are the best rules.
I love those ones.
You don't need heel hooks for blue
belts,
but like Naga,
they let everybody,
he'll hook so,
and it's not this like,
you know,
big epidemic going on where people are
just getting,
their knees is ripped out to not at any
10th planet school.
Every now and then someone does get a
knee injury,
just like they do get an arm injury or
shoulder injury.
Sometimes people get put on a heel hook
and a there any up sometimes,
but sometimes it happens with the arm at
the same rate.
We do heal hooks all the time.
No one's getting every now and then
someone gets hurt,
but it's just part of the gang,
but it's every now and then someone gets
hurt from everything.
Yeah.
It's not know if people were get trust
me as a businessman,
if,
if I saw that I'm walking around every
night and I'm looking at what's going
on,
I know exactly how my.
I know who's playing what and what
everyone's different style,
you know,
especially like the purple belt level.
I,
I pretty much know where they're coming
from.
No one's getting hurt.
Everyone's doing the hawks and you just
you a man.
It's a different mother fucking world
when you're going against leg lock
experts to know Jujitsu,
like guys like Eddie Cummings and Gary
tone and black belt in Jujitsu that are
fucking hyper super ultra leg lucky.
Holy Shit.
You better watch Yo Shit.
So if you are not training,
leg locks,
leg locks when everything goes when it's
submission only when there's not all
these stupid rules when dangerous,
when it's just like that Jujitsu that
you fell in love with.
Everybody falls in love with the Jujitsu
that they walk into their Dojo and then
they train for the first day and they're
fucking love it.
They love it and they fell.
They fell in love with what happened and
what goes on.
Every night in that class,
there's no points.
People are just rolling in there trying
to get the submission.
That's what you fall in love with.
What you see at a tournament that's on
what you fall in love.
No one goes to what you just to
tournament for the first fucking time
and I'm going to fuck it.
I love this.
I'm going to do this.
They fucking run the garden.
That's the that.
That's how you turn people off to
Jujitsu.
The first experience is appoints
tournament where there's 12 matches
going on at the same time.
We'll see how long that lasts.
People that like Jujitsu can't even hang
well,
especially when it's with the game.
Exactly.
They'll,
they'll be like,
fuck this.
They're playing tug of war and Jacques
thinks it's boring.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
John.
John is so boring,
so
guys are just trying to get advantages
and trying to like just score a point
and hold on.
I think the rules that you've set up for
Ebi are the best rules.
They're the rules because you go a
certain amount of time.
What is it?
Ten minutes,
10 minute match.
16 Man Tournament,
a 10 minute matches with overtime.
If there was no points,
no advantages.
All submission.
Only like you'd have to get the
submission,
you know?
Yeah.
What's really interesting is you've got
this idea that uh,
you know,
until I saw it,
I was not sure what to think of it.
I was like,
all right.
I don't know.
I don't know how it was going to do this
the other time.
Over time.
Sounds crazy.
It sounds crazy,
but in practice it's the best thing.
Since if you watch a Jujitsu match,
one of the things that happens if you're
a casual observer,
if you watch like a Marcello Garcia,
some guy just attacks and strangle
somebody like,
Whoa,
that was amazing.
I.
That guy's awesome.
Like I've showed some people that don't
ever do Jujitsu.
I showed them Marcello Garcia match and
you watch him choke somebody and it's so
spectacular to watch because his
movements are so impressive.
There's whole fast and lethal,
you know,
but a lot of Jujitsu matches will end in
nothing.
Some guy gets on top and then he
reverses the guy.
Guy Used to go.
It goes for a leg lock,
he doesn't get it and God goes to choke.
He doesn't get it.
The other guy winds up on top.
They reverse positions and you run out
of time.
So when you run out of time like that,
for a lot of people,
feel is inconclusive.
So you decide you're going to have how
many different rounds of it did they do?
Four rounds?
What's the most amount of rounds of
overtime?
Well,
well first off,
let me say that,
uh,
you know,
if there's nothing wrong with the point
game,
if you like the plank game,
there's fucking nothing and you get
really good at it.
You know what?
You're going to get good at passing and
you're going to get good at sweeping and
you're wrestling is going to be good.
It's just,
it's like a,
it's like a little,
a subculture,
cerebral type thing.
Positional thing,
fucking nothing wrong with it.
You could use that as a training tool,
like getting good at points tournaments
just because you're going to work on,
you're passing and you're sweeping and
you might as well do points
lethal with punches and you
like to do that.
It's not a bad strategy.
There's nothing wrong with that.
I'm not trying to stomp that out.
I want to make it clear.
I'm not trying to compete against that
at all.
It's beautiful thing.
What you just,
you just.
My goal has always been to put a to
create a Jujitsu show and I thought it
would have been done by now and a lot of
people have tried to put a Jujitsu show
together on a.
it's so exciting that it can compete
with on the overall entertainment value
with an nma show like your average mma
show.
I go to just so,
so beautiful.
We were obsessed with it.
Why can't we see what's going wrong?
What's going on?
There's been a professional submission
league,
uh,
Hicks and even had a show there.
Metamorris.
There's Polaris.
I mean,
none of these shows,
including mine,
including mine.
None of these shows are making any
money.
I haven't made any goddamn money with my
show.
We all know that in the Jujitsu
community there's,
there's no money there.
The shows fail constantly,
but what is it about works of passion
when,
when you go to an Ebi and you're in the
audience that has an audience of Jujitsu
enthusiasts,
like everybody is pumped.
They're all very excited to be there.
And there's a feeling of comradery in
that kind of a crowd that's very
different than a crowd that just comes
out to see like a UFC.
Because a lot of people in the audience
at a UFC are gigantic fans.
A lot of them are fucking fanatical.
A lot of them are like you and me.
A lot of them.
But there's a lot of other people that
are just there because it's an event.
There's a lot of other people that goes
there because it's a scene.
There's a lot of people that are on
their phone and half the time they're
not even paying attention to the fights.
This is that to add an Ebi,
because none of that shit.
You freaks and everybody's clapping for
everything.
Everybody knows when a heel hooks close.
Everybody knows when a choke is closed.
Everybody knows.
Everybody knows what's going on.
Everybody knows when you guys sent.
She's up at triangle.
Everybody knows.
So there's a beauty to that.
But let me explain what you do because
we didn't finish it.
You have overtime.
So when a fight goes to a draw,
like at the end of it,
the time runs out,
will you do is you take these guys and
you forced them into dangerous
positions?
Yeah.
So you force a guy on a guy's back with
over under and you start from there,
you say ready,
go.
And when you do that,
then the guy on the bottom tries to get
out.
The guy in the top in the good position
tries to finish.
If the guy finishes,
you move on to the to another round and
the other guy tries to do it.
If he can't finish them,
the guy who finished one but he gets his
chance in a bad position as well.
But if you have a stalemate over the
rounds of that,
you just count out the time who got out
the quickest,
which guy escaped from the other guy's
bad positions the quickest and you
calculate the time.
Well traditionally it overtime with
Jujitsu matches it usually when it came
down to wrestling who had the better
wrestling because if there would be
overtime,
there's no points or whatever.
They go into overtime as three minute
overtime and overtime or sudden death,
whoever gets the first points when it's
really gonna come down to who has the
best Ruslan [inaudible],
they're all that overtime period.
They both start on their feet.
So what's the most,
the most important thing on your feet as
the wrestling here?
That's gonna.
Determine overall the superior wrestlers
are going,
uh,
that's always been the case really in
all the overtime is it always comes down
to the wrestling generally.
So I never really was a fan of that
because I've seen plenty of wrestlers
and submission tournaments.
Not know anything about submitting,
but they'll,
they'll run away with the gold medal
just based on the wrestling.
And that's a beautiful thing.
I wish I had that wrestling,
but when it's a submission or a Jujitsu
tournament,
we should,
the best Jujitsu should win.
Not the best wrestler.
Arresting the best Jujitsu,
the best,
the best it's submitting should win.
Like a guy like Marcella Garcia should
win.
The overtime's should make it so the
best wins who generally.
So,
um,
instead of starting on the feet,
my overtime rounds,
we start in terrible positions like,
and it's like extra innings you get out
of like if we were going to add it and
we went into overtime,
you'd get a shot at my back and then I'd
get a shot at your bank.
If you've finished me,
it's not over yet.
I get a shot at gear back by finish you.
We die,
we go an extra ending.
It's an extra round three MACs,
three MACs,
but it could end that first round.
It could end in the second round if it
goes all three rounds and we're still
tie,
whether it's to submission,
a submission each or an escape each and
another escape.
And it's three total or all escapes.
We add all the combined escape and
submission times together and whoever
had the quickest or shortest time winds.
So it encourages that when you're on my
back that I'm not going to just sit
there and just hold the choke out.
You should try to get the fuck out
because if this goes to a triple
overtime,
this is gonna matter.
So what it does is it opens up a
submission for the gas because gas
escape.
Yeah.
If it's.
If it's confusing,
I'm just.
You can go see it live on a.
You can see it on Youtube,
right?
You UFC fight pass.
You could see Ebi for.
That's where we're at.
We're the ones that you have now.
Like there are some matches online.
If somebody wanted to go and look at it
right now,
right?
Yes.
And then the new one,
the next one,
the absolute one.
This big crazy one is going to be in
April.
In La Sunday,
April 24th,
the fourth,
April 24th.
And that's an absolute one,
right?
Where you have all sorts of different
weight classes represented.
Yes.
I'm sorry.
It did.
What are you doing?
Make sure I've got the day right?
Yeah.
Sunday,
April Sunday,
April 24th.
Downtown la at the orpheum.
It's going to be streamed live on UFC
fight pass.
Orpheum is an awesome theater too.
If you've never been.
It's one of those old classic downtown
La Theaters.
It's probably be from the thirties or
something.
Right?
Like when did they build that?
I don't know.
It's awesome.
So to watch your show there,
dude,
it's so cool.
It's so cool to see it blowing up.
Like last time we were there,
we're sitting in the audience like,
Whoa,
this is amazing.
It's crazy,
right?
It's amazing.
And it's always been done without my
partner Victor Divey like he's the one
guy,
he's the.
I never wanted to be a promoter man.
That's not something I ever ever thought
I'd ever be like a promoter for a show.
That's not what I was trying to do.
I was trying to come up with an idea
that like,
give it to another promoter to do it,
like do this,
but nobody.
Everyone thought it was the dumbest idea
they thought I was losing my mind when
they put.
They thought I smoked too much weed.
So then,
uh,
I thought,
you know what,
I'm going to try to do it.
And Victor Vic.
But the problem was it was too much
work.
I looked into it,
I'm like,
I can't do this shit.
I'm,
I was.
But victor came in.
Victor Davi,
he's the Spanish commentator for the
UFC.
Came up to me and he said,
hey,
listen,
let me do all the work years.
It'll be your idea.
You,
you run the show as an executive
producer,
let me produce it.
I'll make it all happen.
And I'm like fuck.
And he makes it really easy for me.
He does all like when you walked in and
saw the stage,
I didn't have anything to do with that
patient in production.
I mean working on television.
He knows a lot of shit and he's such a
good dude,
man.
Victor's awesome.
He's one of my greatest friends ever.
Man.
The best.
Yeah.
So he's.
We've known him forever to men,
whether we meet victor working at the
UFC,
but when.
What year was it?
Whew.
That must've been 2008 ish.
Two thousand nine ish.
Something like that.
I think it was even earlier than that
thought he was lying thing.
It was like six,
2000,
six or seven.
I want to say he thought he was four
years old.
Little Kid.
Brock Lesnar Hanna was back in the Brock
Lesnar Das.
That's,
that's what I remember for sure.
Yeah,
there was definitely some kids.
Awesome man.
And he's training a lot now too,
right?
Yes.
He,
he broke his arm.
So He's been out a little while and
stuff,
but he helps.
He's a an Ebi.
I'm associate producer.
Did he broke his arm training?
Yep.
Just don't crash.
Oh,
I'm drawn.
Crushed,
crushed with scary.
That's a scary one.
So that's one of our favorite bone
favorite.
It's.
You rarely see it in mma,
you know,
rarely.
So unusual.
You know.
When was the last time you saw a bicep
crushed?
I think George Sada Roblis did it.
Did I think so?
Back back in the day when we used to
work together.
I think he did it on a George Group.
I don't know.
I get the names all mixed up,
but a
crazy sport man.
There's nothing crazier than MMA.
When you watch the combination of
punching,
kicking and you're seeing,
you're seeing a lot more guys go for the
leg locks.
Now notice that you have seen there was
a guy,
he didn't pull anything off though,
but forget he was,
but he was all over dude's legs and
then.
But then he was,
couldn't get hit and a lot of angles,
you know,
back you talking about,
uh,
um.
Was it a Darren Elkins fight?
Maybe?
Maybe it was.
Um,
fuck.
Who was he fighting?
Maybe?
God dammit.
It was a great fight for Elkins.
Why don't,
why can't I remember who the hell he was
fighting too many people.
And that last card this weekend.
Yeah,
that's right.
Chad skelly.
I think Chaz was like foreign one.
The UFC and Elkins is dominated them.
Elkins move to um,
to um,
Sacramento train with Alpha male moved
his family.
Said fuck it.
I gotta make a run at that fight that
I'm talking about.
Yeah.
Thanks.
So yeah,
he and Elkins just grounded,
pounded him.
There was a couple times where he's
going for elkins legs,
but elkins just grounded cognition.
I think you're gonna see a lot more leg
locks down the hall and there is no
matter what,
you got to watch your legs.
You could punch a guy in,
in this,
in his face or not.
You got to watch your legs.
Ryan Hall take you.
Get laid off real quick.
And then everybody's aware too,
of the trend in Jujitsu and Gary Tony
was talking about,
I mean he's going to do mma.
It's strange seeing Ryan Hall in there,
you know,
it's strange because he's always been
the Jujitsu guy,
you know,
and,
and then we're going to see them.
Then we would do the man he's in there
now and he's throwing down and he's,
he's making some waves.
Yeah.
Gary Tonin is going to be really
interesting because he's,
he's been striking for quite a while,
like really trying to tighten it up.
Really working on getting that in order.
And he's a smart guy.
He's not going to jump into anything
like Kinda halfassed.
He'll have his striking in order for you
as his first fight.
You'll get some blocks.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
And we'll get a lot of chokes.
We'll get all everything he says he's a
bad motherfucker when it comes to
Jujitsu and only getting better.
Yep.
I think the MMA fighters are always
aware of trends.
You know,
in the big trend in Jujitsu,
it's not like they're not going to pay
attention to that.
There's,
there's obviously a leg lock bias going
on right now in Jujitsu where people
training that really heavily.
They realized,
I think there's a bunch of people kind
of knew leg locks and we're good at like
locks,
but it seems like once Donna,
her and that crew got involved in it,
it became like a whole new level of
intensity when it comes to Lego blocks.
Danaher's crew,
Gary Tonin,
Eddie come into now,
Gordon Ryan.
He just got his black belt from tonin
and that all started.
That all started from Dean lister.
Yup.
Dean lister went down a hens those for a
couple of weeks,
hung out with Danaher,
showed them on a lot of leg luck.
Shit.
I'm sure it probably lagged,
locked a lot of the upper level guys and
made an impression.
And uh,
and then Danaher being like,
you know,
he's like a astrophysicist.
He got,
he probably took that shit.
The Dean lister told him and just,
uh,
just blew it up.
He's such a wizard and just added so
much stuff.
And then Eddie coming to super smart
too.
So he's taken all the Shit Danner showed
him and he's adding a lot of shit.
That's it all onto gary telling her and
Gary told him he already had rear naked
choke.
She already had great defense because
you just did a solid as fuck.
He added leg locks over the last few
years and now fuck is the fucking.
You want to hear something even crazier
than that.
I go to donner,
go,
how did Eddie coming to hurt his leg?
He goes,
well,
he's was rolling with some of the other
students that we have in the gym that
might be a little bit more advanced in
him with leg locks.
They just don't use them yet.
Just don't.
They don't compete.
I was like,
what?
You got guys in your gym that don't
compete,
that are better than any companies that
lead locks and that was scary.
He says,
oh,
how scary that is.
But the way he.
John,
Donna Harris says it very definitive.
Yeah.
Perhaps we have guys that are maybe a
little bit more advanced than him.
They don't compete.
There's two kinds of games now,
ma'am.
There's that because you can shut down a
leg lock game,
but you gotta have a solid clenching top
heavy game.
You've got to have that slow smashing,
destroying game to stop those lead.
Who's the best at stopping leg locks
right now with our game?
Well,
when I'd have to say,
um,
I don't know who the best is,
but I would say,
uh,
in Abu Dhabi,
Lucas,
the pre Lucas Le Prix,
he went against Gary Tone and,
and um,
he,
he just hit him with the straight meet,
caused me cut paths with that under hook
and just didn't finish them,
but he stayed out of leg locked danger
and anyone on points one was,
this was last year was last year.
That's impressive.
So I mean,
technically he be Gary Tone and
technically he avoided all the shit.
Smash them down.
I think he passes guard may have even
took his back even to tell you the
truth.
I don't remember.
I shouldn't say that.
But,
um,
nonetheless though he,
uh,
that is,
that's one kind of game right there
because he for sure it wasn't going to
start playing leg locks with character
one.
Fuck.
No,
he knew the game was like,
we got to stay away from that shit.
And you gotta be,
you gotTa know how to stay away and
you've got to be able to put some heat
on someone's leg locks.
You gotta know how to get out of Lego
blocks.
If you're not working leg locks all the
goddamn time,
you're going to be so far behind.
You really,
really are.
It's a whole new world growing out
there.
And in the sub only world submission
only community if it's,
if you don't know leg locks,
she will never survive in an
interesting.
We'll never survive.
So it go back just to when you were
competing in the tournament as a white
belt and people screaming and bullying
when you're going for a leg lock,
could you imagine what it's like today?
Two thousand 16.
Nobody saw this coming.
Yeah.
But there's still tons of resistance.
Unlike lock still.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
There still are.
Still a Jujitsu instructors out there
posting the anti leg lock stuff.
You know what the problem is?
It's the legs are the strongest muscles
in the body,
right?
The legs are attached to the longest
limbs you can.
You can move them in ways that you can
never move your arms.
You realize how limited your arms are
when you're not using your legs to go
after legs and to hold positions.
You realize like how it's kind of silly
almost to use your arms as opposed to
most of the community looks at it like
in a negative way.
It's a positive thing.
We'll have.
You have a whole nother game to learn.
They don't.
It's a whole nother game.
That's the problem.
They don't want to learn the whole new
game.
They,
you know,
people get really good at one thing.
They get really good at one thing and
then they want to stick with that shift.
Yeah.
That's really what you got to get
through that.
Isn't that amazing though,
that the very thing that made you Jitsu
so popular in the first place was that
it had figured out a way to make
something the most technically
effective.
We're a small guy,
like hoists can be a big guy like Dan
severn like and it was the using the
techniques that work,
but then these new techniques at work,
they're like,
no,
I don't know those.
You got to stick to the old.
The old ones like,
no,
that's bullshit.
We just got to figure out how to defend
against these blocks.
Let's get them out of the boys.
Let's work this through kickbox and
shit.
That's never going to catch on.
I mean there a lot of trends.
Like there was a point in time where
people weren't throwing any head kicks.
Deemed Lester's going to do this next
Ebi,
Vinnie.
My glass is one of those,
one of those rare Brazilians who's
really into Samo too.
He has been preaching like locks and
he's very good at leg lateri amongst
many other things,
so it is good at everything.
One,
we got a Uri Samoas.
He's awesome.
He's dobby,
right?
He's.
He was,
I don't know,
I don't remember.
I mean that's a shitty answer for
someone who's putting them on the show.
All I know.
All I know is he's really good and he
fought in Abu Dhabi.
Right?
To find that out.
Jamie,
yours.
Why you are someones why you are I s I m
o e s Uri Somos.
Yeah.
There's not much high level talent.
Now.
Mark Martinez Dnas.
He's from Marcello Garcia.
He's in it.
A Bruno bosstones isn't it?
These are like high level dudes,
man.
Yeah.
So if you listen,
if you're thinking about like,
man,
I never watched the tournament before
with the way these guys are talking
about something about Dick hard.
This is what you do.
You go on UFC fight pass.
If you don't have UFC pipe pass.
If you like fights,
man,
this is the.
What is this him?
Yeah.
Does it happen?
The best guys in the world?
We're stacking on us.
We're stacked now,
man.
He won the Abu Dhabi,
right?
Does it say?
Yeah?
Did he win?
I'll be debi champion.
First thing.
Oh Shit.
Two Thousand 15.
I'm an idiot.
He's a bad motherfucker.
Anyway,
multiple time world champion as a purple
belt and it absolute,
he's just a bad mother fucker all
around,
but what I'm saying is if you,
if you've never watched a submission
tournament,
I've never seen guys try to submit each
other like this sounds kind of
interesting.
Get UFC fight pass.
I'm telling you,
I don't want it to be.
I don't want to sound like a shill.
I wish UFC would offer up a free month
of UFC fight pass so people would get
addicted to it.
But if you're at home and you're bored
and you're like,
ah,
I don't know what to watch what's on tv,
you just feel like vegging out in front
of the television.
UFC fight pass will occupy your fucking
time.
You can find the greatest fights of all
All of them.
And we're doing five shows a year with
them.
They want five least,
so we got to pump them out every two
months or so.
And on top of that,
you know,
you got the people that are UFC fans
that are going to leak into it,
you know,
that's a big one.
And they have a ton of different
organizations as well,
even of glory now.
Yup.
Cool.
I'm Gary Tone in an eddy.
Come into both in this.
Absolutely.
A Dj Jackson.
I'm Richard Martinez.
Amir alum,
a rust them chizzy of.
He's in Abu Dhabi.
He,
I think he was second or third.
This guys is.
Fuck.
That's a huge wrestler.
Rustam Chessy of he's got hair on his
back.
He just fucking spell his name to Jamie
at r u s t a m I c h a s e e s c h a s e
I e v.
It was this guy and I'm all.
Yeah,
he's like,
what everyone is afraid of.
When you think about Rustin wrestlers
that everybody's afraid of a guy,
looks like he looks like a real live
wolverine.
Hugh see the hair on his back.
He's got it on his back.
How big is he?
He's dude.
He is one of the.
Everyone's afraid of this dude.
Very hard to do anything to this guy.
He keeps getting better and better.
He wasn't.
I think he was second or third in Abu
Dhabi.
He's got hair on his back like a
werewolf.
Look at his fucking back.
Nobody wants him to.
No one wants to be.
No one wants to be paired up with that
guy.
I couldn't imagine.
He's really good too.
So passing is getting spectacular.
I wonder how long I like that can
compete with that style.
We have like a good.
No,
I was just going say it like that kind
of smashing.
Crushing power style.
Boy,
that's so taxing.
He used to.
He didn't used to pass as much.
You should just throw people around and
get on top of malaria,
but now he's really good at passing and
finishing.
Now we got to Lucas roadshow.
Who's from Gracie Baha.
One of the top guys.
This,
this.
This is the most stacked we've ever been
mad.
This is super,
super stacked.
So awesome.
Way To kick it off.
Yeah.
It's going to be a way to kick it off on
fight pass.
It's going to be fucking fun.
It's so fun.
Isn't it amazing that it just became
something?
You know,
it just.
I never planned on it,
man.
Hasn't though.
That's how it works.
That shit.
That's this thing,
this podcast.
Never again more shit.
Like 10th planet wasn't even playing.
I know I'm 32 years old.
I don't know nothing about no 10 planet.
How crazy.
The 32,
how crazy is it that we were like in
love with that Zechariah's hitching guys
books now they think they might have
actually found this planet.
Is that for real?
Oh yeah.
I don't even pay attention to that and
they have no photographs of it,
but they were pretty sure to the point
where they're stepping out and saying
there's a large planet probably about
four times the size of earth that's
outside of our theories.
No,
not anymore.
It's real.
Now it's mainstream.
Scientists are saying this.
I think Tyson is addressed it.
People keep sending me shit,
but I'm like,
oh,
it's another one of those things.
They're going to.
Jamie will pull it up for real.
Yeah.
Well,
Eddie,
Eddie turned me onto this.
He's like,
dude,
you ever heard her is extra Zacharias
hitchin and we got so deep ways to do
bong hits her and and talk about the
Annunaki,
watched documentaries on it.
Some crazy stripper told me about it.
She was like,
do you know that we used in mind world
for gold?
And I'm like,
Gina,
what are you talking about?
Because why do you think we like gold so
much?
We used to be slaves and like,
oh my God,
I just thought she was the craziest
person ever.
And then I thought about it for five
minutes.
I used to make music with her and I'm
like,
wait a minute.
It is kind of weird that the one fucking
thing we all agree on is a gold is money
has to one thing.
We all agree on nothing else.
Then I asked Regina,
who is this guy who told,
told,
told you about this,
what is this guy's name?
And so she gave me his name.
I called him up.
I said,
hey,
I'm gina's friend.
She said you were talking about some
crazy motherfucker who,
who wrote books about a us being slaves
and all that shit because Oh yeah,
some guy named will to a situation or
Zacharias itching.
And I'm like,
okay.
And I wrote it down that I looked into
them and that's how.
This is all pre internet.
It was a sheet that 99 slash 2000,
2000 you had the internet,
but it was harder to find shit back
then.
The ninth planet does it exist a 10,000
year orbit in outer reaches of our solar
system.
So they're trying to figure it out right
now.
But um,
what they believe is,
and this is,
they've been believing this for awhile
as it apparently there's,
where the reason why they declassified
pluto,
they said it is on a planet anymore.
It's because Pluto is a large body in
the Kuyper belt.
The kuiper belt is a belt of just large
asteroids and round things and shit
floating around out there,
which is really weird because the photos
of Pluto that they've released recently,
the really up close photos they just
released.
It's a fucking planet.
We're nitpicking here,
that's a goddamn planet,
but they don't think it's big enough to
be a planet.
Alright.
Whatever it looks like a fucking planet.
Pull up the photos of Pluto.
The newest food.
The amazing.
Yeah,
exactly.
Have you seen him?
No,
I haven't seen him,
but to me it's like it's there,
right?
It's there.
You call it a planet.
You call her dwarf you call,
they call,
you think they're going to call it a
dwarf,
you know,
10,000 years ago.
Who cares what you call it?
It's something,
it isn't like,
oh no,
it never existed.
It was a black hole.
No,
it's a body of mass data.
What they think is that there's so many
of these out there.
They found another one.
Do you remember this?
You and I were at a bar having a drink
one day.
Oh,
here it goes.
These are the photos.
Yeah,
fine.
There's,
this is some of the photos.
I think those are color corrected to
show like different things,
but there's some of the,
uh,
the actual surface.
I think the far right one that you,
This is the moon,
Jamie.
There was some,
some from the far right.
One that's Pluto,
but that looks like the,
the ones from that.
All images right
there.
That's Pluto.
The one down below.
Above Planet X.
That's moon though.
Yeah.
But look,
there's all these different planets on
this earth.
Moon
squared.
Yeah.
That's Google search though,
right?
I'm just go to go to the web,
search the web search and then just
write recent photos of Pluto.
What is it?
New Cassini?
Is that what it is?
It took the photographs.
What was the um,
the Cassini.
So there's a bunch of Pluto says what
they're saying,
right?
Yeah.
There's a bunch of.
So they found another one.
You and I were at a bar once.
I remember this because I saw it on my
phone,
so it had to be an iphone.
Um,
someone had sent this to me.
Dude,
you gotta check this out.
I clicked on the link and went to a
website that showed that there was a new
planet and I was like,
dude,
they found it,
but it turned out it was right before
they declassified pullo.
They went,
wait a minute,
there's a bunch of these fucking things
out there.
These aren't really planets,
and so they think,
to make a long story short,
there's a bunch of these things out
there and then behind that is a thing
called the galactic shelf where it just
drops off and that would indicate that
there's a large,
high,
large,
massive object out there,
another planet.
What if they like?
There's nothing there,
there's nothing that's this blackness
would have like,
who knows,
like really what's out there,
you know,
like scientists.
What do you mean?
The astronomers,
they have some pretty insane fucking
telescopes now.
They can see some wild,
wild shit.
They've identified hundreds of planets
now,
which is really weird because just a
decade or so ago they hadn't identified
any outside of our solar system.
It's only a hundred seats.
I think it's probably hundreds.
Yeah,
look at that.
Woo.
Look at the surface of that thing,
man.
That's crazy.
You can take a picture of Pluto.
Yeah,
but look at it.
That is a circular round thing that
looks like a planet.
So,
but whatever nitpicky that that's not a
planet.
It's because there's a gang of those out
there,
dude,
there's a gang of them.
They don't know how many there are.
They're going to find new ones.
This kaiper belt,
there's a bunch of little tiny objects
out there that are like Pluto size
smaller than Pluto and I think they
assume that they're going to find more
because this object,
whatever it is,
it's outside outside.
Like in the 10,000 year orbit around
Earth is big way bigger than us.
Four times outside of that,
those little side,
all the little ones that's.
There's apparently there's a dropoff,
there's like the belt.
I might be butchering this and if I am,
I apologize,
but what I've read and try to remember
was that there is something called the
galactic shelf and that would indicate
something that has a lot of mass,
something that has a lot of gravity,
something that's big,
and so they think it's bigger than.
I mean they're,
they're saying it's four times the size
of earth,
so something really big.
Just fucking nuts,
man.
It's just nuts to think there's another
planet out there
and what's even more not says what if
there's fucking life forms on it.
What if this thing in this 10,000 orbit
around Earth is heated by its core would
have it gets its heat instead of from
the sun would have.
It gets its heat internally and it's
life forces are all from an internally.
Maybe that's where the auto Nakia.
Imagine if that was a real story.
Imagine this Annunaki thing and
everybody laughs at it.
Everybody thinks it's funny,
but like when the 10,000 years rolls
around,
that motherfucker gets close.
They really are a bunch of aliens living
on that thing.
Who made us.
Could you fucking imagine?
Nothing would ever mean anything.
Again,
your credit cards,
how much gas is.
Nobody would give a fuck.
It would all be so,
so back of your mind.
Everything would be in the back of your
mind except,
oh my God,
there's a planet out there is a bunch of
fucking people who made us out of
monkeys.
They came down,
they did genetic engineering experiments
on monkeys just like we would do.
Just like we would do if we,
we've,
we've found some planet in outer space,
especially if we were like scientists
that were like thousands of years
removed from us today,
like way,
way,
way in the future.
Maybe millions,
like a million years more evolved.
They look at these monkeys like we'll
just get help them out here to help them
out.
We know where this is going.
Anyway.
Just grabbed them.
Shoot some fucking woman where her.
That'd be the greatest thing to
experience ever.
Like what could you imagine how earth
shattering it would be if there was a
real life form from another planet that
we could absolutely identify a real
civilization and they were super
advanced and they were coming by to
visit
Jesus Christ.
Sorry,
I'd have some questions.
We have no idea what,
what we're inside of like,
we're just.
It's in.
You can't.
Even if it's
aliens and space is man,
remember how we were so into him like in
the,
in the late 90 [inaudible] or the early
two thousands.
Aliens were like fucking always on my
mind.
Not Anymore though.
I think it's because the history channel
killed that,
that ancient aliens.
Maybe that was the plan all along is you
know what,
let's kill this whole fucking alien
movement by putting it on history
channel over and over again,
but what is called me up?
Dude,
you called me up once.
He was a hilarious conversation.
You go to.
I'm just not in a fucking aliens
anymore.
History Channel clucking.
How cool was that?
First Season of ancient aliens?
Awesome.
Fuck.
He was going to mainstream and
mainstream.
It was awesome,
man.
Then they did another season.
Just ran out of shit to
talk about.
Unfortunately they special.
You just start off as a special maybe.
Maybe.
Then it turned into a series of fuck.
Those first funds are awesome.
He's awesome.
Oh Man.
What was the last time we talked to him?
Have you talked to him in a while?
Man.
I wonder about the overall industry is
kinda down like he got upset when I was
honest.
I think about some of the stuff.
I just think that,
but some of it is just to bullshitty.
It's just too.
It's like could be.
It was aliens,
like I'll come on,
man.
They went to.
They're selling.
Yeah.
There's a certain amount of that stuff
that is absolutely fascinating.
When you look at some of the,
um,
depictions of like aircraft.
So like the Egyptians used to do.
They used to make like these little
model aircraft,
compelling evidence for you for if you
had like a Ufo was a skeptic right here
and you got like five minutes.
What's your go to?
Almost nothing.
Nothing right now.
That's what's fucked up.
Nothing was nothing.
There's that one thing you can put
disclosure project all the witnesses and
stuff.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
The other mind you just never know.
You just never know.
There's all sorts of experiences that
people can have.
Two that are very,
very unusual weather condition.
Things like ball,
lightning ball,
lightning is one that's really crazy
because apparently there's a swamp gas.
Well,
this ball lightning apparently moves
like some alien space craft and
apparently if you saw a ball lightning
and they've identified it,
it's like this really rare form of
lightning that instead of coming down
like really fast,
like a,
a line,
it can move around and it's the same
sort of idea.
It's like an electrical charge that
breaks free,
you know,
I don't,
I'm not doing a good job of explaining
it,
but I've seen videos on and I've seen it
explained and I think if you were flying
around man and you saw that,
you'd probably think that was a Ufo and
if you saw a lot of the experimental
aircraft that they did,
I talked about it with schermer before
you got here.
I think there's a lot of that stuff
was just people seeing this shit for
sure.
Most of the,
probably the more,
the more um,
the more you get into
how I'm fucked up like corporations are
and how fucked up like we've been for so
long.
The more you look at aliens like Ah,
they are just as distracting us.
They want us to pick them up fucking
areas.
You know what I mean?
It seems like a big distraction.
Distraction.
I think people love it.
That's why it's on.
I think it sells.
I don't even think they're trying to
distract us.
I think it appeals to that archetype and
it's one of the things that schermer
talked about before you got here in the
earlier podcast.
We were talking about how it's like for
a lot of people that are atheist,
that becomes their God and it kind of
makes sense.
It's like,
well,
I don't believe in fairy tales,
but I believe maybe we are created by
aliens who ran experiments
on monkeys and they're all written like,
how can we won't believe the Bible?
But we believed the Sumerian texts.
Well,
that's funny.
That is too easy question is that we.
We don't.
We're not into the Bible,
but we're into some with that.
Those people were dummies,
but these people 2000 years before them
do,
they had it nailed what it is.
It's not God's.
It's aliens,
man.
They came from another planet.
Depends on the story because an alien
story actually kind of makes sense
because we're.
We're just,
we're in space and shit.
There's a lot of.
It's.
I always think of it as would we do it?
Would we do it,
do what would we run experiments on some
life form that we saw on some other
form.
Of course,
what do we do to.
Monkeys were doing emotional testing
aids medicine on monkeys and shit.
We would do some weird shit with some
monkeys from another planet to heal.
Probably doing some weird ass shit on
this planet.
We don't know about.
Oh,
for sure.
There's kind of a clone.
Humans everywhere.
Especially not in America where you
don't have any rules,
you know you can go to some countries
don't do anything like China's started
doing experiments on human embryos,
genetic experiments on human embryos.
Raise it men.
You know what I mean?
Just genetically modified Superman.
Yeah.
I mean it's just a matter of time before
they do something like that.
If they can do this genetic engineering
and get through a few generations of it
to the fact they get the kinks ironed
out and start making a series of super
along with the Einstein brain.
Yeah.
Can you imagine if they can have a brain
beyond Einstein?
If you could create a human or a clone,
but you could do something so the brain
develops like 10 times stronger and
you're just like,
yeah,
I'm going to read minds and probably
going to happen.
It's definitely gonna happen.
And then when that does happen and we
see some poor monkey on some other
planet and we've fucking flying around
out there in space and be like,
that's fixed.
That dude skim a little charges.
Just squirt in there and see if he could
figure it out from here.
Take that monkey reengineer it,
give it a language.
It probably would've figured out
language given enough time.
Do you know they think that chips are
starting to enter into the stone age.
It looks like I was just watching a
documentary of a monkey and everyone's
seen those,
those,
uh,
videos of monkeys with sticks and they
using it to eat ants and shit like that.
I was watching.
I was watching a video of a monkey who
broke off a stick and started banging
the bark to get some money that was
under the bark,
but the stick wasn't big enough,
so he throws it and he helps him,
grabs another one,
carbs at all help and then start to.
He should probably be using that as a
weapon at this point.
If he's doing that,
you know what I mean?
What happens then when when they learn
how to use it as a weapon on each other
and shit?
Well,
what's amazing is what if what we're
seeing is them learning it.
What if what we're seeing is like when
they're just starting to observe this
now,
what if in our lifetime they start using
tools like it seems like that's what's
going on because they don't either.
It's one of two things.
Either they just didn't have enough
video of them back then and they didn't
have enough people observing them,
but to really realize they've probably
been these tools for 100 years or so,
or they just started doing it in our
lifetime.
You know?
That's.
That could be possible if you ever seen
snopes.
Snopes is because I don't know if this
is true.
There's an orangutan that's fishing with
a spear.
He's hanging off of a fucking branch
over this river.
He needs got a spirit.
There's a photo of it.
I just don't know if it's true.
It looks so good and it's always one of
those things.
It's one of those things I've always
wanted to google it.
I'm just,
I'll get to that tomorrow and I just
never get to it.
I got other shit in my life to worry
about,
but now these people out these days,
but I remember I just remembered I have
to get.
Do you see A.
Jamie does.
I don't see it on snopes,
but it says it's true.
Although the eight didn't sufficiently
didn't develop the skill enough to catch
fish,
whatever.
Show the picture.
This is what's crazy.
Look at this.
Come on son.
Are you fucking kidding me?
This is true.
Okay.
If this is true,
that's a goddamn weapon that orangutan
is sticking a long stick into the water.
Trying to.
It's true.
Although ape did not develop sufficient
skill to catch any fish yet he's trends.
This is insane.
You would think he borneo would speed up
that evolution,
right?
If he's actually,
man,
they're probably learning from watching
fishermen and shit.
Yeah.
I have to learn that watery refraction
thing and that might not be capable of
doing now.
Oh right.
Yeah,
that's right.
Water refraction is.
It's a big factor in both fishing.
These people with fish,
with bows and arrows.
When you look at a wall,
like if you look at a fish,
say if you look down in the water and
you see like the fish will be where this
laptop is.
It's not really there.
It's like six inches lower than that,
but there's this weird refraction thing
going on because you're looking through
water,
so it's like looking through all the
funhouse mirror kind of.
So you have to learn how to shoot under
and the grant tank might not be able to
figure that out.
Very smart.
Jamie,
did you figure that out on your own?
He fucking wizard powerful Jamie.
Yeah,
that's.
That's.
That makes a lot of sense.
But how crazy is it?
Seen him try that.
A ranked him by himself with a pole.
I mean these not as.
He's not like at the circus.
Nobody taught them that.
Those things are smart as fuck,
man.
Who's going to be a crazy fucking karate
dude who goes out to the jungle?
Starts Teaching Monkey.
How do Kendo get them?
Give them swords and shaky.
Imagine if they got,
oh my God.
Supplied the gorillas with sword,
Samurai swords.
Bump bump,
bump.
I mean,
that's planet of the apes is not that
far off it would it be the teacher?
I'm like,
Jane Goodall got all evil and shit
started teaching on that fucking cut.
Jane Goodall believes in bigfoot.
Does she?
Yeah.
She might come back for bigfoot right
there.
She's not.
Not.
Not only just,
she believes she is certain.
She cert is talking about a,
a pull up Jane Goodall.
Jane Goodall believes in big.
It's insane when you listen to it.
Like she's way smarter than me and she
knows way more about primates than I do.
So I talk shit.
I say I don't think big foot's real.
He might be,
but I don't think it's real,
but when I hear someone as smart as her
who basically lives in the jungle,
I mean she's in the jungle,
so God damn much.
You might as well live in the jungle and
this is what she says.
Listen to this,
not be her talking and we'll see.
No,
I'm pretty sure it is
what you now I know you do wonderful
chimp calls.
Well,
I'm going to do the greeting.
That's the kind of sound you'd hear if
you went to Gombe and you climbed up
onto the ridge.
How long is this video and if you're
lucky you chimpanzee who's calling out
saying,
here I am.
It's a wonderful day.
Where are you?
Ooh,
Ooh.
Each one has his own individual voice.
You know exactly who's calling.
Where's bigfoot,
Bro?
I'm going to probably have to speak with
you
undiscovered.
You're talking about Yeti or big photos.
Is that what he's talking about?
Yes,
he is.
He is pretty much out of the loop.
Well,
now you will be amazed when I tell you
that I'm sure that they exist.
I've talked to so many native Americans
who've all described the same sound too,
who've seen them and there was little
tiny snippet in the newspaper just last
week,
which says the British scientists have
found what they believed to be a Yeti
hair and that the scientists and the
natural history museum in London
couldn't identify it as any known
animal.
Did you always have this belief that I'm
a romantic,
so I always wanted them to assist
animals.
Will my passion from even before I could
speak.
I think that's it.
Oh,
a couple of,
a couple of people told her that they
solid
so
she didn't see it,
but he's been in the jungle for 75
years,
but that was supposed to be in the
jungle where she goes,
you're supposed to be in the woods.
Where is,
um,
what did she say?
The University of what?
Uh,
see,
see if you could figure out what she
said.
Like what university is that is testing
a Yeti hair because I think that's
bullshit.
I would have heard about that.
They don't,
it's not A.
No.
Like when I was on the Scifi show,
we tested some stuff.
We tested hair.
We talked with this guy,
todd desoto from,
um,
I'm someone big university in New York
City.
I forget which one and why you,
I guess?
Yeah,
I guess he's an Nyu guy and I'm hope I'm
not wrong todd,
but he's,
I'm a geneticist and so we ran tests on
a feces and on hair and the hair was
bear hair and the bear shit too.
And maybe some dog hairs to give a shit.
Shit got him.
He didn't think it was at all.
No,
no,
he's,
he's dedicated to disproving it.
But there was other scientists that gave
us.
That's,
that's the one I'm talking about.
Like what made him think
it was big?
Bigfoot shit.
Shit Bro.
Smell it.
Maybe the bear had fucking bad fish or
something.
They couldn't even agree on what it
eats.
There were so sure as shit.
They can't agree.
They can agree on what big foot eats
good.
Who the fuck discovered that big foot
shit?
We gotta find that.
Did I met?
I met that dude,
the guy that found the shit.
Yeah.
I had a conversation with him too.
He's a nice guy.
He's a teacher in a school.
Where did he find teacher in Oregon?
Funding out in the woods.
It was like,
this got to be big foot shut.
I'm going to take it with me.
I would think big food would lay logs
like this big as my thigh.
Just giant.
Ever see a elephant?
Take Shit.
And you see his ass hole open up and
he'd go,
good Lord.
I'm
just flopping out of there.
This giant asshole.
That's what I imagined from pig foot.
Do you believe that there?
Um,
you know,
some people believe in bigfoot but they
also believe in a different kind of big
foot.
It's like a different kind of like a
Christian church,
like a Lutheran.
They believe.
Yes.
We believe in bigfoot,
but we believe it's an interdimensional
being.
I've heard that one.
What do you think the chances of that
pain rail?
Probably 100 percent.
Not just big foot.
I don't believe.
I believe it's real.
Okay.
I to stop right here,
Bro.
I'm one eighth native American,
um,
my grandmother's side and uh,
those are our people.
Our people have long known of the
existence of what we call the Alma.
I have a bunch of different names for
it.
You know,
what the new name,
every time I go up to Oregon or
Washington or do a seminar,
I asked the guys by show of hands who
believes in bigfoot and most of them do.
Most of them do.
Yeah.
Well,
most of them that I've heard stories,
you know,
I believed in it for the longest time
and I don't disbelieve in it today.
I don't disbelieve in it,
but that's one you can make fun of.
But if it,
if they found big foot,
I wouldn't be like,
oh,
I'd be like,
Oh shit,
that's real.
I definitely don't disbelieve in it.
And you know what?
And I'll,
I'll just say it.
I think maybe he isn't or dimensional,
you know what I mean?
That's how,
that's my gut feeling
sticks.
You know,
you can take your science,
but at the end of the day it's all about
faith,
Bro.
It's all about knowing in your heart and
make sense.
That's why you can't find them.
Motherfuckers just disappears.
I know in my heart,
no defendant with my life.
That's the only fucking answer I know,
bro.
It's interdimensional press what I'm
thinking.
That's why they can't find them.
You can't put pig foot on camera,
bro.
He knows about cameras.
I start going to happen,
man.
It's not going to appear.
Where's the camera or disbelief?
Just because he doesn't want a closed
isn't mean these primitive
superintelligent.
They know you don't believe Bro.
He's at one with nature.
He's not going to be near you have,
unless you're pure superintelligent.
You can't find.
You've got to live with the sasquatch
for them.
Take a foot,
don't shake you in.
There's a bunch of dudes who have
claimed to have had friendships with
sasquatches like to move into the woods
and they stayed there for months at a
time.
And then they,
uh,
they,
they tell people they had these stories
and there's video,
there's audio recordings of what they
call Samurai talk.
You want to hear audio recordings that
people think is a sasquatch.
You want to laugh?
Oh,
you're ready to laugh hard.
I,
I could do sasquatch.
She didn't say it was at a university.
It's the natural history museum in
London.
No,
Kim Christ that up.
You can't just make a noise.
They have a us.
It's the dumbest recording ever.
Samurai chatter.
Listen to this.
Get ready for this shit.
You gonna you gonna blow a gasket.
We had to analyze this on the show.
This is how when I knew my show is
retarded,
Sierra's listen to this.
And he was there one time with a friend
and every evening they used to have some
absolutely bizarre noises and cool.
So they couldn't figure out what the
hell it was.
And um,
so they took a tape recorder one time.
And this is what they recorded.
Okay.
It is very bazaar.
Indeed.
We decided to record the sound.
I'm available to people.
Oh,
what a good mood.
Do you believe these creatures are
trying to communicate with us?
So.
And we as we speak or having the
linguistics people look into it,
they are very encouraged by what they're
saying so far.
Is it human
shit?
The range that supersedes what a human
can do.
The range supersedes the human by a
previous study at the University of
Wyoming to be spontaneous and no signs
of being rerecorded or prerecorded
altered speeds.
So the idea of a hopes.
It's very unprobable as far as
professionals are concerned at this
time.
Well you reduce.
They made this video got uploaded,
2013.
Have you that?
Is there anything look more like a man
in a monkey suit in that picture,
but here's the thing.
Imagine if they really did sound like
that.
I mean,
what does chimps sound stupid to work if
you heard that,
but more complicated
with an actual language like dolphin
noises,
sound stupid of dolphins,
didn't make those noises and you heard
the dolphin noises.
He'd be like,
that's not a language.
What is that?
How weird.
Imagine that Shit's real.
Imagine there's like 20 of them.
I'll just live in deep,
deep,
deep in the woods.
What's more believable?
Big Foot or Loch Ness?
I think loch ness is probably a really
big fish,
like some kind of really big fish,
like a sturgeon or some shit.
Something something really big that
there's not that many of them.
You see that video of that guy petting a
great white shark,
a great white sharks.
Just.
Yeah,
it's on my instagram.
Oh really?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Maybe I saw it on instagram.
You might have.
Yeah.
That's one of the weirdest fucking
videos.
Adversity in my life plan.
It's like,
Eh,
it's coming out of the water and he's
touching his nose.
No,
no wonder pirates of fucking scared and
shit.
They probably dealt with that shit on
the daily.
You can you imagine.
Can you imagine a pirate fucking ends up
on,
on the coast of South Africa?
Oh my God.
The stories there.
Yeah.
That's great.
Let's just hang out there.
They're just.
They're just a shitload of them.
How insane this is.
This is so insane.
He just keeps opening its mouth and
those gums.
Look at the gums and on these fucking
destructor teeth.
They are scarier than any monster in any
movie ever,
and they're 100 percent real.
Look at the fucking teeth on that thing,
man.
I mean,
what the hell?
And they fly out of the water.
Oh my God,
Oh my God.
Those things are so insane.
Just imagine that clamping down on you.
I mean it's.
It's cartoonish.
A shark's teeth are cartoonish.
They're giants swords,
cerated edge swords,
and there's rows of them in their mouth.
So if one snaps off,
another one moves forward.
What are just spec tire killer animal.
Just that one of the craziest creations
of nature
or thor.
Did he make sharks?
Was it Odin?
Who makes the sharks?
Who makes sure it was a god which God
would make sharks.
Oh,
I don't know.
That's a good question.
That fucking thing.
I can't watch this,
Jamie.
I'm freaking out.
If I had,
if I had $100,000,000,000,000,
I built this fucking instead of an
octagon.
It's just this giant fucking ocean and
put great white and killer whale in
there to fight killer whales when every
time you think so.
Every time.
Great whites and not smart and they're
not nearly as mobile.
They're not smart.
They just swim around.
How do you.
How did you dump them in the tank?
How?
What would you never seen videos of?
How long would you think it would take
before the killer whale attack?
The great white.
You just don't big a quick.
Would you pay to watch sound?
Um,
you can watch on youtube and I'm like
this.
No,
but can.
There's never any good video of it.
I would never push no good video of a
killer whale jacket.
It's like splash.
I would say yes,
but you can never put a killer whale in
tank.
I think putting a killer whale on tank
is just beyond 10 minutes.
No,
no,
no.
You can't do that.
You can't force it to fight.
I think it's like forcing a person to
fight.
It's like picking up the money.
He could do anything.
Okay.
Were you going to go in a helicopter and
pick up some guy from the middle of the
fucking Bornean jungle and make them
fight in a cage fight?
What'd you do that?
Would you drop them in there with the
guy who's trying to kick his ass?
Dropped
that a dog?
That wouldn't.
That wouldn't be that excited.
I'm talking about the most exciting
possible match.
I know,
but what I'm saying is dolphins and
whales and killer whales are too smart.
It's fucked up to do that to them.
Oh,
see,
smart.
I see what you're saying.
That's why I would never do it the right
way.
Would never have a shot.
Maybe they get a fucking rabid one from
south that they got to find a good one.
We found that good.
We found a Gamer.
Killer whales,
I think.
I think they could definitely get the
babies.
Maybe you get a killer whale or a baby
killer whale and a fucking full grown,
ferocious,
great.
Probably the great white would bite
right through it,
right?
If it was a baby.
When they're grown.
Fully grown adults.
I think killer whales are bigger and
they were way smarter.
They're just wastes martyr and they just
go right after the sharks.
They go after him.
We decided to fuck them up.
There's a,
um,
the video is this.
Apparently they were watching a mother
and her daughter or son,
the mother and her baby,
and a killer whale.
The killer whale was swimming around
with this baby and the shark showed up.
And the killer whale was like,
hold on,
be right back.
Just went.
Fuck that thing up.
They got that on video.
Yeah.
They got an a video and then I think the
killer whale shark up,
didn't it bring the shark and display
it?
I'm trying to look it up now.
They're like at a recreated thing of it.
Oh really?
Because it wasn't that.
They couldn't get the camera down there.
Look how much bigger it is.
See this is the dead shark at the end.
So this is the killer whale.
Biting the fucking shit out of that
shark.
They just don't have real good footage
of how it went down.
Was footage from some discovery channel.
So they faced in probably,
right.
It's Gleiss.
They do that now when I'm watching them
fucking discovery channel.
It's like,
you're like,
dude,
there's no way you got that shot.
Right?
You've got that whole thing happening.
You see it.
It seems.
It seems to make now it seems like you
see it now,
but killer whales versus sharks.
I think unless the shark is really big
and the killer whales really young and
then killer was just way too smart.
They're like,
like a person almost just they don't
move like us,
so we don't consider them like us,
but they have crazy language.
White versus dolphin to killed dolphins.
They eat them.
Great whites killed dolphins.
The Itam.
Fuck,
I didn't know that shit.
Like Jello.
I thought.
I thought they fuck sharks up.
They do.
They fucked off chips.
Remember?
Let me make sure I'm correct about them
eating them.
I know they kill them,
but how could they catch a dolphin?
Maybe that I don't eat them.
They kill them,
dude.
I'm telling great whites killed off and
they'd kill whales to.
No,
not great whites.
No orcas.
Did we say great wines?
St.
Oh.
Oh,
killer whales.
Killer whales.
Dolphins,
for sure.
Great whites do to.
If they can.
If they keep talking about great whites.
I'm tired.
I thought you said that's so stupid.
I thought you said killer whales,
but for sure a great white.
Ain't gonna kill my dolphin.
Right?
A great white can.
Yeah.
If they bite him.
Yeah,
they can get them if they fuck up if
somebody fucks up,
but I think that the size difference
between killer whales and great whites
are just too big,
but it's a very disappointed when you
find out the great whites are the killer
whales rather not great whites.
I keep,
I keep saying great wines that killer
whales are killing dolphins and they
kill other whales to like,
uh,
you know,
the Arctic to the North Pole is melting.
Well,
there's like a,
these whales killer whales can't get to
because the ice,
they can hang on the ice because don't
have the dorsal fin or something and
they can swim through the ice,
but now that all ice is gone kilo.
Whereas we're coming up to eat them.
Yeah.
Isn't that crazy?
So that they're eating other whales so
much that it's fucking up the Eskimo
economy because they rely on those
because they killed those whales,
but now the killer whales and killing
the whales,
they kill.
Isn't that nuts?
They rely on whales.
They kill
God,
so they need help.
So I'll need to do something about the
killer whale problem.
How many people were up there?
Did they like it up there?
There's people that are living off
Wales.
Are they enjoying themselves?
What is it?
What keeps about that?
I've never been there as fence.
Right.
It's funny.
You should come to Phoenix hundred below
zero.
They're like,
we're just going to tough it out.
Just not good too.
It's not good.
Like as far as like the way their,
their,
their health is.
Well it doesn't.
The population doesn't grow at their
kids ended up graduating and saying fuck
that.
Like curtis hambre alcohol.
Boston hadn't structured from Alaska.
They all get the fuck out.
They don't stay well.
Alaska is one thing,
like anchorage is bad ass,
but this is like the where the people
are eating whales and shit.
They're like north of that now.
They're like way up there.
They like in the frozen parts there's
the anchorage is actually close to the
coast so it's not a bad place to live.
Yeah.
I've never been to anchorage.
Fucking great man.
Is this like a Vancouver,
like a colder Vancouver where it's only
dark out for like an hour in the summer.
It's weird.
You go outside at like 4:00 in the
morning,
it's bright out,
write out like 5:00 at night,
bright out,
and it's like four in the morning.
You're like,
what the fuck is going on?
A little of that in Sweden because
Sweden,
it's kind of north,
so it's like the sun's still out and
it's 11:00 at night and on the sun is
stove on your face.
But I didn't.
Uh,
I've never been that north.
Never been to Alaska.
It's crazy.
Up Live comedy up there to comedy in
Anchorage.
Ari is beautiful as you get a bad ass to
get in some,
a bow and arrow.
When we were fishing we went salmon
fishing while we're up there.
It's beautiful man.
Just beautiful.
That was the first time I saw an actual
live in the flesh eagle,
like outside of the zoo,
like watching a big ass eagle fly right
over your head is a trip.
We had an eagle fly,
you know,
shit,
hundred yards over our head.
They'll take a baby won't,
uh,
they probably avoid people.
But if you leave your kid out in the
lawn,
yeah,
yeah.
If you just stand back and let you,
if they're hungry.
Oh,
especially if there's something wrong
with them,
like they're too tired to go get a
salmon.
Like getting old.
I mean equals get old too.
That's when like a lot of animals get
dangerous when they get older.
Like cats,
big cats.
They get dangerous thing to get older.
They can't catch dogs anymore.
You know?
They're fucking hungry,
man.
They gotta going to figure something
out.
Fucking Eagle.
Taking your baby can imagine how you'd
feel if are you looking at seeing an
eagle fly off with your kid?
There's that video,
right?
It's fake.
Believed it.
I believed it.
I believed that.
I believed that Orangutang fishing
video.
Then I wait a minute so it's not real.
It is real.
He just didn't.
I didn't pull it off,
but it really was trying to do it.
He rang Tang was.
Yeah man.
There's just so many videos like that
and so many.
It's hard to know what is right and
what's not with the photoshopping skills
like photoshop.
Steve.
Oh my God.
Oh Man.
That guy is obsessed.
He's so good.
Like things like that,
right?
Like you look at those pictures like
okay,
that could be.
That could be real or not real.
Yeah.
No,
it's so good.
Some other.
I don't mean Shit.
Yeah.
Thought about it.
It's really,
really well.
When is it going to be?
How long is it going to be before we.
I guess it's probably already happened,
right?
Where they've proven that photographs
that are used in propaganda or are
faked.
Must've happened.
Didn't happen.
Like during the Iraq war.
Wasn't there like some faked fake photos
of missiles or something like that.
God Damn it.
Why didn't they do that shit all the
time.
The green screen and they pretend
they're in Lebanon and shit when they're
really in Virginia,
they've been busted pretending they're
in the Iraq war and bombs are going off
and they got helmets on and shit.
They bust to do with that.
Yeah.
They had on youtube.
They left.
The camera's rolling for the tape is
like an hour.
You can go on Youtube during the 91
operation.
Freedom war there were faking the news.
So ridiculous.
You know what?
Good for them.
They're supposed to be doing that shit.
You run that empire.
You know what I mean?
I don't think that's what they're doing
there.
They're trying to put together.
They're saving money.
Did tainment trying to put together an
entertainment.
Hey,
what about operation?
What about Operation Mockingbird?
You take that,
that was real.
And uh,
that was a real.
Which one was that?
The CIA infiltrating a broadcasting and
journalism and that they take for
propaganda purposes.
This was a real operation.
Well,
there's been some real operations that
are undeniable that are pretty fucking
crazy.
And then how crazy is it that a who,
CNN,
you know,
that's this rumor that based on how they
present stuff like that,
based on how it's going down to what
they show and what they're pushing.
And based on the agenda,
you know,
any,
any retard will say,
now you can't believe Fox News.
Even retard say that.
Even retard say you can't believe Fox
News.
Everybody knows that.
Well,
CNN just like that.
It's just the other side.
So that's easy to bleed in.
The Anderson Cooper was in the CIA.
He denied it for a long time.
Then he came out and said I was just
there for a summer intern.
Right.
Is that what you said?
Once you're in,
you're in,
you know,
at first,
and then his family comes from super,
super wealthy background.
The vanderbilts and all that should have
taught me.
It's like,
I don't know.
I was going to say,
um,
the other one that's really crazy.
His operation midnight climax.
You ever hear about that one?
Nope.
The government ran brothels in San
Francisco,
in New York and they got guys who came
in to get laid and they dosed them with
Lsd so they could study them because a
conspiracy theory.
No,
no,
that's real.
That's 100 percent real freedom of
information act operation midnight.
Climax how the CIA dose San Francisco
citizens with Lsd and how crazy does
that sound?
How Craig,
if we said that happened today,
like what is going on today?
It would be.
You would be thought as a crazy man,
but it's happened before and unless
that's not true.
No,
no,
this is true.
Well then it happened before
so I could read it.
Here it goes.
You're crazy.
If you think through it again,
lifts it up so you're considered nuts.
That's crazier than any conspiracy
theory I believe,
and that's the craziest one.
Listen to what it says.
It's been over 50 years,
but Wayne,
Richie says he can still remember how it
felt to be dosed with acid.
He was drinking Bourbon and soda with
other federal officers on a holiday
party in 1957 at the US post office
building on seventh and mission streets.
They were cracking jokes and swapping
stories.
Suddenly the room began to spin.
The Red and green lights on the
Christmas tree in the corner spiraled
wildly.
Richie's body temperature rose,
his gaze fixed on the dizzying colors
around it.
It got jagged.
Somebody dosed them,
but that's not.
This is in this.
This guy is not the guy I think this is.
He's talking about being dosed at a
party.
He's not talking about operation
midnight climax
because midnight climax was about
brothels.
That's why they were calling it
operation midnight climax and they found
this guy about getting feeling.
Yeah,
he definitely,
well he's a,
let's see here,
say when he was high they were
participating against their will in
these studies is what it was
essentially,
whatever.
Just go google into it,
look into it folks Google into it.
I don't think that's a real term,
but it's really interesting because what
had happened was they were doing these
studies on soldiers and they just
couldn't get people to do it anymore.
People like get the fuck Outta here.
Like they didn't want to do it anymore.
So then they started to figure,
let's just try it on some other people.
They figured if they did it in a
whorehouse,
nobody would say anything.
You know,
guys don't want to admit they were there
in the first place.
Just dose them up with an asset.
They walk out of there all crazy.
Not Stupid Smart.
Goddammit.
They do a lot of smart fucking shit.
God Damn it.
It's all setup so brilliant.
Brilliantly.
I mean,
just the fact everybody knows that the.
There's a corruption at the,
at the,
at the top levels and the CIA.
Not on everybody,
but there's a lot of corrupt.
Everybody knows that and it's okay.
It's like the,
the people that are really running shit
like the corporations and the
international bankers like they blew the
CIA is right there with nobody to a sue.
No one to throw in jail.
No one's accountable.
It's just right there.
Just that they're involved in all this
shit.
Just like what you just posted.
They're involved in.
I shouldn't.
No one's accountable.
Well,
you know what I think is going to
happen.
What I think what I see as possible to
The same thing that's happening with a
performance enhancing drugs in the UFC.
That was someone like Jeff Novitsky when
they have these Usada guys that are just
showing up at your house,
4:00 in the morning,
take random tests.
They have all these crazy things they
could test for that no one even knew
about.
You know,
so slowly but surely,
everybody's forced to be natural and
compete naturally and that's what we're
seeing right now in the UFC.
You just,
just,
just too,
it's too risky.
They are too good for too sophisticated.
Right?
So as far as we know,
everybody's fighting natural,
but we also know that they definitely
didn't.
They cheated like a motherfucker.
Everybody did in other organizations.
We know that.
We know guys who did it,
we know guys that would just be juiced
out of their fucking mind and everybody
else was juiced out of their mind to.
And that's how the game was being done.
Everybody was competing on that level.
So we know that.
So in a lot of ways,
I think that's because of something
like,
you know,
the,
the new understanding of how to test
people and something like the UFC high
Reno Wicki to go after this.
Right?
But that's data,
right?
It's information,
all that information as it does come
out,
they're forced to do it straight and
narrow.
I think that's going to be the case with
government at a certain point in time.
I think the people that are making a
fuck load of money and corporations,
they're going to make a fuck load of
money anyway,
but they're not going to be able to
manipulate environmental law the way
they're doing now and get away with it.
It'll be more transparent.
They're not be able to influence
politicians to influence laws to make it
favor their business.
It just won't able to do it so easily.
I think there's always going to be money
to be made.
There's always going to be people buying
cars and buildings and they're almost
always going to be commerce,
but I think there'll be less fuckery in
the future.
I think corporate fuckery,
they're still going.
I don't think.
I don't think you can hide things
forever when it comes to like some of
the practices that some corporations
that are unscrupulous will engage in
that aren't necessarily ethical.
Like how about the BP oil spill,
right?
Like how about how the other,
you know,
the way they cleaned it up and the um,
they made people.
There's people in that town that mean
what does,
how much of a loss was that to them?
How could you possibly compensate them
for?
I don't know too much about the BP oil
spill.
BP oil spill is pretty fucking crazy.
I know it killed the Gulf and all that,
but I don't know the details.
I don't know.
There was some kind of,
you know,
of the report.
I don't know anything about having
looked into it.
It was one of those,
um,
things that they pull the oil out of the
ground,
those bloated.
She had a lot of animals and it's just a
lot of industry and oil into the ocean.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
It's amazing how many gallons were being
pumped into the ocean and even more
amazing how the ocean just sort of
absorbs it.
What do you think a trump.
That's a long question.
I think it's,
uh,
it's,
this is a strange time.
It's strange to see a president that is
okay,
whatever.
What do you like him or don't like him?
Whether you support his beliefs or you
think he's the worst thing ever?
I'm just looking at it as objectively,
like as a performance piece.
There's never been a guy that
understands how to manipulate the media
the way he does.
Never.
No one even close.
He made everything he does is a big
story.
He says outrageous things and because he
says outrageous things,
they tune in to make sure he says more
outrageous things.
The more outrageous things he says,
the more people go.
He's saying outrageous things.
Let's tune in.
He's the biggest show in town,
like it's not even close,
so I'm in close.
Who generates more attention?
Who's got people more riled up about it?
People are bored as fuck.
They're bored,
they're bored.
They hired Obama,
they thought everything was gonna change
and it,
I guess did a little on some fronts and
it was good socially and the world's
evolving in that way,
in that direction anyway,
so that's all good.
But Guantanamo Bay still open.
People are still in Afghanistan.
Seems like the,
you know,
it's still.
It's still chaos everywhere.
I don't know if anybody could have ever
fixed it,
right?
We're,
we're just bored.
We're bored.
What is this?
What are we doing?
What is this world?
Why are we in the Middle East?
What is going on?
Why?
I'd have to worry about war,
why don't have to worry about gas?
Why don't have to worry about global
warming?
What's going to happen with the polar
bears?
God Damn it.
And then all of a sudden this guy comes
along and telling you how big his dick
is.
He says,
I'm going to build up a fucking
wall,
a million miles high Mexicans out joey
the first of all they built,
they didn't finish already put up a
wall.
It's crazy.
And everybody cheers,
you know.
And the Mexican president calls me up
and says,
who's going to pay for that wall?
You're going to pay for that wall.
And the wall just got 10 feet higher and
hangs up the phone and everybody's
cheering.
Pulls his dick just off.
Yes.
Yeah.
He told the guy the wall just got 10
feet higher.
You know what I told him?
The Wall just got 10 feet higher.
And everybody goes,
Oh,
I'd love to see that cloud.
Could you find that class?
Like he's like a,
a movie from the eighties.
And yesterday the top person,
president of Mexico said,
we will never ever pay for that wall.
And the press called me up and they
said,
call her on the head,
man,
top person.
He said he won't pay.
He won't pay for it.
And you know what I said,
I said the wall just got 10 feet higher.
Right?
He fucked it up.
I keep saying it's true.
It's true.
He's so strange is it's just so bizarre.
I feel like I feel like almost like I'm
watching like one of them late night
televangelists shows somebody wants,
wants your money.
Like you can have my money.
Look at you.
You do already have money.
You can't get money.
It's feels like
fake.
It feels like this is the final piece of
the simulation theory.
Yeah.
The final piece of the show where it's
going to reveal that this has all been a
comedy all along.
I've been a strange comedy.
I mean,
what do you think?
He's really a.
he's better than the other ones except
for Bernie.
He's better than all the other people on
the Republican side.
I mean,
Marco Rubio seems like a,
a,
a reasonable guy.
And a lot of ways the way talks.
I don't know exactly what he's uh,
his beliefs are,
but him and trunk,
they get into these insult competitions
and it looked so foolish.
So like just because trump does it,
just don't do it better than him.
Don't do it better than him.
Talk about how ridiculous it is and
don't allow that guy to like you.
They're talking about a big as hands are
and they're going back and forth with
each other and insulting his hair and
insulting a spray tan I like.
They're like,
it's like the roasting against each
other.
Like this is not presidential.
I understand you guys have a limited
amount of time and this with
the fake Tan and trump was bagging on
rubio wearing makeup.
The whole thing is ridiculous.
Like this is a terrible way to have
these people together.
Like to have these people all competing.
Then what you're going to get is who's
the best at giving you a sound byte
under pressure.
You're not going to get who's the best
leader you're going to get to.
Who's the best at doing that debate
thing that's you're going to get because
it's a weird thing.
You're standing up there on a podium,
you're right next to a guy was talking
shit about you.
What he's saying is not even true and
you're like,
you can even respond.
You've gotta wait like fuck you man.
It's a stupid way to talk,
and the fact that they time them,
they give them like ready,
go.
No,
this is what you do.
You let them talk for long period of
time.
If they're long winded and boring,
people don't like them anymore.
That's what happens.
You put them in a long form,
have them talk for hours and hours.
Let him talk on a podcast.
Every fucking presidential candidate
should have a long form podcasts that
they have to do every day and we see
whether or not people want to listen to
you.
Not like have someone barking at you on
the left and bar.
Tell me what the fuck you can do and
then have someone talk to them that
understands what can and can't be done.
Have someone who's a real political
expert sitting down and asking them some
hard questions and do it all the time
and that end based on that and their
qualifications,
but based on like back and forth,
bullshit.
Bickering with each other and insulting
each other on our spray tans and your.
That's so crazy.
This is the,
you guys are going to run the greatest
army the world has ever known and you're
acting like assholes.
This is so stupid.
Like this isn't just like a bunch of
guys,
uh,
you know,
trying to win a game show.
This is,
if you,
when you run the world,
like in your,
you're insulting each other on makeup
and Tan.
You should be saying,
do you know how fucking stupid it is
that we're talking about?
We have a five minute time period that
you get to talk in or whatever the fuck
it is.
And you're going to spend your time
assaulting each other on hand size.
And you guys are babies.
You know,
you can't be the king.
No,
you guys are not the,
there's no way you could be the best.
So like he ends involved in that.
And Ted Cruz is like super religious,
which always makes me go,
man,
I don't know about that.
Ben Carson is super reasonable,
but super religious.
This,
he's the trump is the guy that stands
out is at least he's a rich guy.
That doesn't give a fuck.
Are there anything,
uh,
any good things that trump says that you
agree with?
Um,
you know what,
man,
I honestly have been so blown away by
the bad things that he said that I
barely paid attention to the good
things,
but the shit that he said about Mexico,
like someone's doing all the raping,
like bringing over a murderers and
rapists.
And I was like,
oh my God,
like you just,
that's a whole country.
You're talking about millions of people
you're talking about,
you know,
like most someone's doing the raping.
He says some crazy shit and it works
man.
It works as far as like,
if it's all a pr campaign.
And he just gets in there and he says,
ladies and gentlemen,
look,
I said what I said,
and I did what I did to prove a point
that our media system is corrupt.
This whole system is broken.
It needs to be fixed.
It's like a,
it's like a bad computer.
It needs to be rebuilt.
This is not good.
Like you can't have a guy just juke the
system like I just did.
That's what would be the most amazing
thing if he gets into office and said
this is a very important position,
so no more insults,
no more bullshit,
and now that I'm here,
I'm going to hide,
just hire the best people and we try to
figure out what the fuck's wrong with
this country.
How amazing would that be?
He said,
look,
I had an insult,
these dummies in order to get in there,
I couldn't let Hillary Talk Shit.
I had to go in there guns blazing and I
had to take out Ben Sanders and fucking
Ted Cruz and Marco Rubio.
But now that all that's done,
we can all work together.
What do you think,
Hillary?
What is your.
I don't know.
I don't know how you can be entrenched
in the system for as long as she's been
entrenched in the system and not be not
be the,
the past.
That's the system,
right?
The system is these special interest
groups and lobbyists and making deals
and having,
you know,
sitting down with all these people at
these tables.
In one hand she knows more about
government than any of them.
She knows more about government than for
sure trump,
right?
I mean he knows about influence.
He knows how to influence politicians.
He donates money to politicians,
he understands all that,
but as far as like being in the board
rooms,
when the shit goes down,
Hillary's like,
she's been like right in there.
So as far as like qualifications,
no one's got more qualifications for
president than Hillary does.
The problem is do you.
Here's here.
We all agree.
I think we all agree,
and this is not a knock against Hillary.
This is.
We all agree that this system is fucked.
It's ridiculous.
Representative government,
it's kind of crazy.
The idea that you can have a bunch of
people.
They vote and they vote for one person.
That person represents that state and
then the state,
they'll get the gun and they try to pick
the president of the electoral college
and all of its wackiness.
We all agree that that's kind of crazy,
right?
We all agree it doesn't make much sense.
There's a lot of things we don't get to
vote on.
There's a lot of decisions.
The country goes one way or another way
that we were really unhappy with and it
would be nice if we had like a giant
public debate.
So the only person that's going to
change that,
the only person who's going to knock
that off its ass is trump because he's
the only guy who's got his own money
like that from the Republican side.
He's the only guy in the,
the in the democratic side.
Hillary's got a shitload of money,
but she's kind of a part of the system.
And Bernie Sanders,
you know,
he's got some good ideas socially wants
to make marijuana legal,
you know,
he wants to,
wants to help people,
wants to,
wants to unite us,
wants to pay for student education,
which I think is a great idea.
Wants to raise up the minimum wage.
I think that's a great idea to.
Even though I don't know shit about
economics,
so it's like there's not a lot of great
choices,
I guess.
Like Hillary would be the best choice on
paper.
She's been there right on paper or
She's a crook.
I think she's a crook.
Do you know where on the air,
like when I was that bad?
This is live isn't a debate talking,
right?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
But you can't say just a crutch.
Got To say allegedly.
Allegedly.
What?
What makes you say allegedly she's a
criminal man.
Let's that.
The documentary,
the Clinton chronicles and all the stuff
that,
you know,
the Whitewater scandal and all that
stuff.
I mean,
she's,
she's in the Bilderberg group.
Come on.
She,
she,
she's deep and bill are deep,
deep,
deep.
That's not a conspiracy.
If they're raising the Bilderberg group.
Bilderberg group is not a conspiracy
anymore.
The Rothschild's or the.
The rockefellers referred to it as the
Bilderberg group.
They started it.
It's,
they flaunt it now and she's at her and
bill.
They're very powerful and they're deep,
deep,
deep in the top there way up there.
They needed bill to run everything
through Arkansas.
They had to bring them in to
run everything through Arkansas.
That's not a conspiracy theory.
They ran all their stuff through
Arkansas.
They needed the governor to cooperate
and that was Bill Clinton and to show
their appreciation to became the next
president.
He went from Arkansas obscure.
Then he went to.
Now he's part of the Bilderberg group
just like that.
Some Arkansas governor.
Just like that dude.
That a narcos on Netflix.
Yeah.
I finally finished.
It.
Did come on.
God,
I wouldn't have.
I wouldn't have gotten into it if it
wasn't for you.
I really wasn't interested in it.
Oh,
I just was like,
oh yeah.
More drug stuff.
You got to trust me more.
Oh my God.
I trust you.
Tell land is area cartel.
Land is next hole.
The only one sounds.
It sounds like a generic run of the mill
documentary.
It's not,
it's special.
It's special documentary that sort of
blow your mind and again that uh,
how big oil conquered the world.
Like the history of the rockefellers.
Fuck
man.
The craziest shit.
Netflix.
That's where it all came through right
now.
That's where it all.
It's like,
you know what I mean,
conspiracy there.
So wherever you want to call now they
claim that it's all connected.
Nine slash 11,
and JFK,
like it's the same people and they're
all connected with the same families.
The same secret society that goes back.
Well,
it's most of it.
Most of it started with John d
Rockefeller and standard oil.
When you learn that shit,
holy fuck the history.
And you know,
the craziest thing about the whole thing
is he was so into monopolizing oil and
everything.
Once it was,
it wasn't just oil banking.
He got into everything,
big farm and he had controlled
everything he was showed.
John Rockefeller was so dominant,
he was playing with the first
billionaire.
He was ruling the world man.
And uh,
the one thing is that all hemp or
marijuana conspiracy theories,
they all are aware of the reefer madness
propaganda.
We all know that as,
as we'd uh,
enthusiasts,
we know about the propaganda that the
government,
you know,
and then finally they worked after 10
years of all this,
uh,
propaganda that made we'd look like a
killer deal and stuff and made you do
crazy shit.
They made it illegal and we all know
that that's from big industry like
dupont and the rockefellers and all
that.
We all know that,
that they were trying to shut down the
industry,
that we're blaming it on this Mexican
smoking weed.
But we all know that as we'd
enthusiasts,
but you know what,
you don't know,
you alcohol prohibition was also a
because of John Rockefeller.
He was,
he supported anti alcohol groups and
blew them up and donated millions to
blow them up to get to outlaw alcohol
because he thought this is a threat to
gasoline.
Oh yes.
And this is not a conspiracy theory.
Alcohol prohibition was all backed by a
John d Dot Rockefeller who was a threat
to gasoline.
Yes.
Alcohol,
because they thought people are gonna
make like ethanol.
No,
no,
they,
he just wanted a band at the.
He didn't want her to crush the ethanol
business.
Right,
right.
So,
but the way he did it is to create this
hysteria with drink.
We,
everyone has a drinking problem and
killing each other.
So he did the same thing.
He did both of them.
You're going to find out about this.
This is not a conspiracy theory.
So He.
So they made a,
they wore their worship.
Yes.
Quickly how big oil conquered the world.
But,
but he,
he funded a,
the Anti Saloon League.
It was run by one of his good friends
and that was took and you know what
ended up happening,
the same thing.
They outlawed alcohol,
you can drink alcohol,
but they said what about the alcohol for
cars?
And they wrote in the law that you could
still make alcohol for cars,
but you got to put petroleum in it so
that people don't drink it.
So it made it killed the business.
So now they got to put oil in it if you
want to sell it and then it killed it
killed off.
He do.
He killed everything and he got busted
for everything.
John D Dot Rockefeller.
His Dad was named,
they called them devil bill.
His Dad,
they know all about is that this is not
a conspiracy theory or their family.
Historians will tell you about his
father.
He created him.
He was a rapist snake oil salesman
running from the law changed his name
Bill Devil Bill.
That was his name,
so he had a bunch of sons and John d
Rockefeller was one and he was known he
wanted to.
He was quoted as saying,
I cheap my sons every day.
I want them to see a sharp as can be.
He just beat the living fuck,
trust out of them and just drowned all
their trust.
So he,
John D Rockefeller,
grew up not trusting anybody will do
this.
Rockefeller,
Ford and the secret history of alcohol.
Wow.
The secret history regarding alcohol
that you won't hear on the 6:00 news
cars and everything else running on
internal combustion engines can run on
alcohol at least as well as they can run
on gasoline.
Indeed,
engines were built back in 1870.
That could run using alcohol or
gasoline.
A New York Times article from 19.
Oh,
eight enthusiastically states auto is
discussed alcohol as fuel.
Great future ahead for use in commercial
wagons.
Has Professor Lock,
lock,
lock.
What does it say that look,
look,
I'm tests with motor truck.
Er Hewitt
tells engineers of his results with
gasoline and alcohol and the same
engine.
Henry Ford said that alcohol was a
cleaner,
nicer,
better fuel for automobiles than
gasoline.
Wow.
Holy Shit.
This is nuts,
man.
Yeah,
it's the same thing.
It's.
It's a fucking banana propaganda.
Alcohol propaganda.
That is so crazy because you can make
alcohol without fossil fuels.
So if you made alcohol today,
you could fuel
mean.
People can make alcohol,
right?
People make apple apparently anything,
any vegetable that ferments you can use
as fuel.
It's really simple.
Anything.
Do you know Neil Young has that?
Well,
he has diesel though.
He doesn't make alcohol fueled,
but he makes diesel.
He makes.
Biodiesel is a giant ranch.
I think it's northern California at the
same thing.
If it ferments,
it's maybe you call it diesel,
but it's fermented vegetable matter.
I don't know.
I'm just guessing.
I don't know,
but that's what Henry Ford said.
Henry Ford said anything that you could
ferment apples,
anything.
You could turn it into biofuel.
That's crazy.
John D Dot Rockefeller.
That's what he was all about.
He's the richest man in the world,
was raised by a psychopath,
and he did.
He got busted for monopolizing or are
they finally indicted him?
He had a break out,
a break apart standard oil,
and it made him a billionaire.
That's what made him rich is when he got
busted.
When he got to sell everything off,
he just.
He took over education do.
When you learn how to a documentary,
what is it?
How big oil conquer the world on
Youtube?
I'm scared.
Scared you,
you.
You actually learn what it all comes
from a hundred percent,
hundred percent.
One hundred percent.
It's psycho.
Yeah.
One dude with his sons,
his sons and his grandson and kind of
makes sense,
right?
I mean,
if you think about it,
I mean the really super ambitious people
in business are a lot of times.
The most cutthroat than most.
You mean how competitive you got to be
to be like a William Randolph hearst or
one of these motherfuckers?
You know,
it took over a universities did.
He wanted to take over the world.
He wasn't just trying to sell gas.
He's trying to take over the world.
Our education system is all based on
Rockefeller Foundation.
Shit,
like key strategically wanted to make
school so that we got people just smart
enough.
Just this conspiracy to.
They're just smart enough to work.
They didn't want anybody to smart.
That's how the school system is designed
to be safe.
It's watched the documentary and then
you come to.
You've seen in Jamie,
now you just opened up,
this is how we did it.
This is how he did it.
He would just donate.
He said he'd go to a university like the
University of Chicago and just how I'm
going to give you millions of dollars.
And they said,
Oh shit.
He goes,
but I got to have a couple of my people
on your board dementia.
It spent.
Right?
And they're like,
okay.
So he gets his people in and then they
just take over and they designed,
they designed history.
John d Dot Rockefeller got 2020
historians and designed the history.
They designed it.
That's why when people,
you know,
you make fun of history in ninth grade
books,
you make fun of that history.
It's a joke,
right?
It was put together by the,
by a Rockefeller to look at that number
is peak wealth was 318 point
$3,000,000,000 based on the 2007 US
dollar.
Oh my God.
He lived to 98.
He was a motherfucker bro.
Look at his dad lived to be 98 years
old.
Oh my God.
His Dad,
big bill rocket was the devil bill.
They called them a lot of things,
but definitely this man who spent most
of his times thinking of schemes to
avoid actual work.
Nevertheless,
thanks to the guidelines,
I was swallow.
My lies.
A homemaker and devout baptist.
John d grew up to be quite a hard work
man.
Okay,
interesting man.
Interesting Shit.
Check that out.
What's called big oil wet.
What is it?
How big oil conquered the world.
That's if you're a conspiracy theorist,
you know,
most people don't go beyond a jfk.
There's so much in just jfk and then all
the,
you know,
if you want to enter the water gate in
the Iran Contra and all of the nine
slash 11,
there's so much information that's,
it's so hard to get into multiple
things.
But once you,
once you got that covered,
go back and find out how it all started
and you learned when you go,
when you find out that,
that uh,
George Senior's dad,
Prescott Bush started the CIA and then
you'd go back and his dad,
Samuel Bush was,
was uh,
uh,
Frank Rockefeller's right hand man and
how the bushes and the rockefellers have
have always ran shit.
When you go back,
Samuel Bush,
George senior,
think about how old he is.
His grandfather ran with Rockefeller.
You have to do a podcast.
You and Michael Shermer.
Who's that guy who just left?
Oh Man,
I still wanted to.
He didn't want to talk.
I just want to talk from the moment he
walked in.
You think tower seven went down on its
own.
The moment you don't ignore tower seven,
people say,
I don't want to wrap up.
I do have to end you.
GotTa.
Get the fuck out of here.
I'm so sorry.
I would love to talk about it's way
late.
Okay.
I gotta get Outta here.
Alright.
But we sort of broke down the UFC.
We did for awhile.
We totally did.
Conor and nate are both fucking legends
right now.
Both of them.
Holly Holm,
Misha Tate,
both legends right now.
We're gonna.
Look back at this 20 years from now and
have an old man narrate the highlights
and it's going to be fucking saying,
sitting in a wheelchair thinking about
this shit.
Yeah,
it was classic classic shit.
I think it was the greatest two fights
ever in UFC history.
I think that was the greatest ufc ever.
That was the greatest ufc ever know.
You know,
people keep saying,
oh,
cheap,
screwed,
greatest over because they keep getting
better.
This,
that was.
Those were the two highlights to me that
made me.
I mean it was bananas.
Chaos.
Even in Connor's defeat.
He looked like a fucking,
just like that global barberry and he
handled the last leg a champ right after
the loss.
Yeah,
right after loss.
He handled it like a champ.
Alright,
you Fox will be back tomorrow.
Tomorrow's Chris Bell,
right from a prescription.
Thugs.
You ever want to see that?
I heard about that.
I want to see them.
I'm watching it tonight.
That's all Rockefeller to.
That's all.
Thank you.
Bye.
Big Kiss.