Lakes. Winter. All right. We're
live. All right. Yeah. Nice
to meet you, man. You too.
Um, I knew of you as an actor, uh,
and I knew of your work as a director,
but, uh, I didn't know that
you were into serious shit,
like this deep web documentary.
This is really fascinating.
I was watching it just
before you got here,
so it's all fresh and crackling in
my mind. Cool. And um, first of all,
how'd you get involved in this?
Uh, well it's a couple of
things. One is, first of all,
it's great to be on the show and that
big fan for a long time, but uh, uh,
I uh, got online pretty heavily
in the sort of late eighties,
early nineties, and in what was
known as the bbs use net era.
And in those days you,
uh,
I was really interested in sort
of burgeoning online communities,
people who were the sort of the growth of,
of Internet based communities.
And in those days you could get on and
you would sort of create sort of clubs or
groups or rooms as they were called
with all kinds of likeminded people.
And then you started finding all
kinds of stuff that was going on. Uh,
and it wasn't by any means just
illegal stuff. It was just,
it was sort of rarefied,
specialized, whatever. Politics,
activism,
people who are interested in drugs,
people who are interested in sort of,
you know,
pushing boundaries and
all these different ways.
And at that point I discovered encryption,
uh,
people who are using the Internet
for anonymity and privacy.
Some of them were like,
parts of, you know,
self help groups are like rape counseling,
any number of things.
It was also people who were selling drugs.
So I first encountered the drug,
the online drug markets,
and probably 90 91.
And that's when I first
discovered encrypted emails
or to this whole notion of
like people who really were building
encryption technologies for a number of
reasons.
And so I found that interesting.
And I spent some years
working on the Napster story.
I made a doc about the rise and fall
of Napster called downloaded. Uh,
and I met Fannick,
Shawn fanning and Sean Parker back in
2000 when Nafta was being decimated,
shot at by all sides. And, uh,
I set out about telling their story that
took me a while to get done and made.
But I'd met a lot of people in the
technology sector working on that movie,
both and kind of the public
face of technology and the
sort of privacy anonymity
side, the sort of hackers,
activists, crypto cryptographers. So
it was one of the things that I've
found interesting about the documentary
initially is that it wasn't,
it's Silk Road wasn't necessarily for
folks who don't know it's Silkroad is silk
road is this website that was taken down
by the government because people were
exchanging,
buying and selling illegal drugs from
it and amongst other things that are
illegal. Um, but it,
it was more of a community
it seems than anything.
I've had a message board on my website
since 1998 and it's got millions of posts
and it's, it's, it's just this
weird community of likeminded,
odd human beings and a lot of really
fascinating, intelligent human beings.
And I've had some really great
exchanges and interactions with them.
And what I really got from what they were
saying in the documentary was like the
community that they had created was in
many ways like better than any community,
any of them knew in real life.
So it was much more than just
drugs are being sold there.
We have to shut it down.
Was like if drugs were being sold there,
it was a small part of what
that thing was all about.
Yeah.
I think that's,
I think that's true and I think that
that's a very hard thing for people to
understand. You know? And if you're not,
like you're saying or you
got online at that point, um,
and you started to see in those days,
like in the late nineties that the
communities are beginning to grow on the
Internet.
And they were really interesting.
And like I remember we're talking
to Shawn fanning about this,
that his biggest regret about the downfall
of Napster was not that the service
got taken online, but that the
community got scattered. You know,
because it was this,
when I discovered Napster and 99 what
blew my mind about it wasn't about,
I mean music was interesting,
but it wasn't about the music
was about the community.
It was like meeting all these people
we were communicating in real time.
What had changed before then
was really kind of cumbersome.
The message boards you're talking
about in the late nineties,
now I'm like in real time with some guy
in Russia, China, Germany, whatever.
And they're in my hard drive.
I'm in their hard drive.
It just got kicked to
this whole other level.
And then you're talking about 100
million people on the internet at once.
A lot of people didn't look at Napster
as a community and they still don't.
They just can't get past the piracy
issue in their minds. Uh, were demeaning.
Nafta wasn't, uh, wasn't created for file
sharing, was created to build community.
The Silk Road.
In this case you have a manifesto cause
you had like all these people who built
and created the thing who were
writing all these manifestos.
So it was very evident that the Silk Road
was created for this political kind of
movement, this communal movement,
that that was its agenda.
The Napster thing is
interesting because Napster,
although it was a file sharing program,
the community that was attached
to it, what the idea was, I, I,
I think about all of
this file sharing stuff.
My feeling on it and my feeling from
being connected to the Internet was like,
we're entering this
entirely new era of art,
of digital stuff,
digital creations where it's,
this is going to be slippery. You're
not going to be able to just like he,
you know, this guy stole a
thousand cds and copied them.
We found his CD copier and we know, you
know, that this guy's making illegal,
you know, uh, uh, what were
those a bootleg cds. I mean,
we used to have those in New York City.
Sure. Yeah. All the VHS tapes, you know,
of movies that had just come out and
this was a different thing. Yeah.
This is like the actual digital
and that everybody was like, oh,
what do you do about that?
Like, oh, there's a, a program.
And you could just download these things
and anybody can upload them and then
download them.
And then how are you gonna stop?
Yeah, it's, and it's
true that it's slippery.
And that's why I like telling these
stories is it isn't black and white people
had, their brains can't really
handle it. Sometimes they just,
they want to go to one side of the,
of the issue in the way they see
it in their mind or the other.
And they don't have,
for whatever reason,
the capacity to stay in
the gray in the middle.
And the stories are always about what's
going on in the gray because it's silk
road is the same thing. You know,
you can say, this is really bad.
This is drugs online.
This is flouting the law and all
this stuff that you got one side,
the predominant side or were there,
you've got the other side.
The radical alternative to
that would be to say, yeah,
but the drug war is a complete failure.
It's been four decades of destructive. Um,
you know,
it's mostly about putting nonviolent
minority offenders in prison by the
millions and it's killing people and
it's not helping people who need help in
the drug world. It's making the drug
issues criminal and not about health.
Um,
and you've got those people over there
who are saying this is all good and you
got all this room in the
middle, the slippery reality,
which is just as you said,
I agree with that perspective.
This is a really big moment
in human history, right?
It's too big for most of us
to wrap our heads around.
These are huge changes that are afoot,
you know,
but what Napster represented
wasn't a couple of kids who
wanted to create piracy.
Whether you can accept that reality or
not, it's true. You may not like it.
You may feel like the end result of
what they did caused x, Y, and z.
But the reality is, is there
their minds, their, their visions,
their goals were way beyond that.
And we're still not in the
future that those guys saw.
We're still kind of back in the back
and let's look at what we're seeing with
title and other service.
People are still trying to wrench the
world back to where it was before Napster
or they're still trying to sort of undo
the changes that have happened because
it's scary,
right?
But we probably will end up in a world
in the next 10 2030 years has drug laws
become more relaxed in the mandatory
minimums, start getting lowered.
Where we do see on let legitimate online
drug services are going to become,
they're not going to go
away. They're going to stick
around. Just like, you know,
file sharing.
You didn't go anywhere.
And my guess is that it probably will
be somewhat the norm down the road and
we'll look back at this time and go,
wow,
this thing we thought was so hardcore
actually was a very messy sort of movement
towards where we needed to get to or
towards the future will towards freedom.
You know?
I mean,
I'm one of the ones that thinks
that there should be no drug laws.
I think as long as alcohol's legal and
as long as he can get a prescription for
Oxycontin,
it's completely ridiculous to lock people
up for mushrooms or the lock people up
for pot or what it name your drug
pot being the most innocuous,
evolve them and changing
daily as far as the,
the way it's the way it's
treated by law enforcement.
But I think the digital world, um,
that you're, you're dealing with WIC,
with Napster or with,
uh,
with the Silk Road is this
world of connectivity.
And that's the big change.
It's not just the,
the things that are being exchanged,
it's the,
it's the way that people
can talk to people. The,
the information can go so quickly now
and these communities can form and they
can say, yeah, I've, I've always
thought these laws are bullshit.
Like the explain to me why alcohol is
legal and marijuana's not explained to me
why it's stealing to take a record that
you paid for and share it with a bunch
of people. It's, I had Paul Stanley on the
podcast from kiss and he's a great guy.
I really enjoyed talking to him,
but he's got this sort of really
archaic idea of stealing that,
you know, you didn't pay for it.
It's stealing, but it's your,
your copies still there. Yeah. You
know, like it's, it's a different thing.
It's not like someone stole your car,
right. Like, and they try to make that,
that sort of comparison. Yes. You
know, if someone stole your car,
they stole your car, right. That's, that
was your car. And now they have a bull.
If they just copied my car, why do I
give a shit? Yeah, exactly. You know?
You know what I mean?
If you just press a button,
if you see someone driving down the
street and say, I love that car,
let me just press a button and my three
d computer or my three d printer makes
it an exact duplicate of that car. Does
that somehow or another diminish my car?
I don't. It's scary territory.
Right. I mean, people,
people don't understand the technology.
They don't agree with the movements.
You know? I think that people
look at technology. I had
a long talk with a, a very,
very important reporter from
a major publication that
Dolan and name and I spent
a really long time trying to explain to
her how the deep web worked and why it
was like no different than
the door on your bathroom.
Like just because there an area of the
Internet that's private and anonymous
doesn't mean it's bad. Just like you're
not bad because you go to the bathroom,
you close the door, and now when
you close the door to your bathroom,
you may open the lid and go to
the bathroom or you may shoot up.
I don't know what you're doing in there.
Right.
But that doesn't give me a right
to take the door off your bathroom.
You know what I mean? It's just
about anonymity. We as human beings,
we deserve privacy in an anonymity.
It's a basic human right. However,
most people go deep web bad. They just
go right there. It's just, it's bad.
It's filled with creeps is filled with
child with pedophiles and drug dealers
and it's all bad and we should
shut it down and would Napster.
We saw the same thing where to this day
people are still like, oh, I'm really,
really feel guilty that I downloaded
that album. It's like I don't,
it was one of the greatest
moments of my life that,
that the walls of culture for this brief
moment just completely came down and
it's like I didn't become
a thief. I've, you know,
I buy lots of music and you know,
I've continued to make a lot of purchases,
but it was an incredible time.
You were getting music you could never
hear anywhere else stuff that wasn't
recorded.
You know,
I was turning people on to stuff
because it was so democratized.
I was like going back like I had to
like stop liking Bob Dylan like along,
I just was like, thought Dylan was
kind of overrated or something.
And then because of Napster I just could
listen to anything so easily that my
own judgment kind of dissipated and I
found myself reconnecting to stuff that I
hadn't really appreciated. So the
point is, is no, it wasn't bad,
but it did certainly ramp
ahead of existing laws and
businesses that are still
trying to catch up.
And the is,
we need new business models that work
with these new technologies that doesn't
make those technologies bad.
Well,
everybody got addicted to selling that
music at exorbitant rates. I mean,
that's really what happened,
especially the,
the record companies and the record
companies are notoriously shitty with the
artists. I mean the, the
contracts and when you read them,
you ever read the Courtney love
breakdown? Yeah. Yeah. It's amazing. Yeah.
And if you read that, you
go, fuck man. Or what's the,
Jared Leto won that, the documentary that
he did, in fact, what's it called? The,
the documentary's called artifact.
Yeah. It's about his band.
And their battles is great.
It's a, it's a crazy,
creepy fucking business that is losing
its legs and they're scrambling along the
way.
And I think that that's one of the big
pushes pushes the big push backs because
of the commerce aspect of it. Right. But
as far as the information aspect of it,
what you brought up about the bathroom
is a really good point because how come
you can have a private club?
Like you could have a club where you,
you and your friends go to play poker,
whatever.
You rent out an office somewhere
and it's yours. You lock the door,
you bring in booze, you have fun, you
play the music, you like to listen to.
When you guys have a good time.
Does everyone,
there's the cops I think going
to fucking just scan the door.
Are they going to put a bug inside the
room to make sure you're not doing any
habit? You close called your cell
phone. I know, but isn't that amazing?
Like that's the same thing.
I mean a physical room,
a physical room that you have,
that's a club house that's been going
around since the beginning of time. Yeah.
No one has a problem with that. That's a
normal part of human beings. But uh, uh,
private digital room where your
physical body isn't even there,
that becomes problematic.
Yeah. And scarier than that,
I think it is that, you know,
now there is such a,
such a direct link between the physical
space in the digital space, meaning,
you know,
there's the Supreme Court recently passed
a law that doesn't allow officers to
uh, go into your cell phone without a
warrant on a search of basic search and
seizure. Right? So your cell phone,
thinking about what that connects to
that connects to your bank account and
connects to your medical records,
it connects to photographs of your wife,
your kids, whatever. I mean,
that's not your digital life,
that's just your life period. So of
course you do. Of course there has to be,
you know, technology's in place
to keep you protected and private.
And look what happened to those actresses,
you know,
that were exploited through the
four Chan fattening where their,
their photographs were taken off of the
iCloud and sold on four Chan. And it was,
you know, extremely intimate
pictures and people say to me,
this one journalist I was talking to,
it was trying to wrap her head around.
It said, well what if I get hackers?
Like, this is what you don't understand,
you've already been hacked.
All your information is out there.
It's just a question of whether someone
decides to exploit it or not. You know,
your social security number, your
medical records, your life is out there.
So we need to be able to be protected
and right now there's this battle to
remove protections and what we need to
be doing is actually implementing more
protections.
It,
it seems like to me that when
the world becomes digital
and then digital
information, the, the, the,
those ones and Zeros become accessible.
We're going to get to a point in time
where privacy seems ridiculous. Yeah.
And that's it.
It sounds so crazy because 20
years ago it was a hard photograph.
You know,
someone had to come over your house to
look at your photo album and now your
photo album isn't even in your phone.
It's on the cloud and upload to it and
it's going to get weirder from there with
the new technology that we don't even,
we can't even predict the
20 year from now technology,
but it's going to get more and more
bizarre to the point where we're going to
have,
we're going to have to have
a real restructuring of
what we expect in terms of
privacy, personal
sovereignty, what, you know,
what do you expect from
your fellow citizens? Yeah,
because we're going to,
I mean it's almost going to be like,
you're going to have to trust me to
not look at your shit. Right, exactly.
Cause you're, your shit is out there.
Yeah. You know, so what we look at them,
what we done, it's like it's, and we need,
there are ways to have a bathroom door,
but we need to be able to have them.
We need to be able to have encryption
that's baked into our email,
that's baked into our browsers. There
has to be, basically we need to go dark.
You know the,
what the dark net does is it provides
technologies that allow you to have
privacy and anonymity.
A lot of people are trying to break
those walls down and say they're bad.
The truth is we actually need
more of that. We need that
to be pervasive. We need,
we need your browser to
automatically anonymize so it
can't be so easily tracked.
And we're not just talking about the
government, we're talking about hackers,
we're talking about people who will
steal your stuff and sell it or use it
against you in some way. So it,
again, it isn't some, you know,
giant anti government thing.
It's a basic right to privacy issue.
And that privacy again is
probably temporary. I mean we're,
when we're looking at 50 years from now,
it's probably going to be hilarious.
Yeah. You look back on the idea that
someone couldn't read your email. Yeah.
And you know what? We're already
the, the sad truth is where there,
that's not the technology you're talking
about is here right now. I mean your,
your information is transparent to
anyone with half a an ability to,
to handle technologies.
Your laptop, your phone,
all of that stuff is accessible to anybody
who's halfway interested in using it.
And that was one of the really disturbing
things that was revealed during the
whole Edward Snowden incident was that
the government is not just able to tap
into your stuff and checking
on you. Hey, this Alex Guy,
he seems a little shifty.
How do you think he might be involved
in some nefarious activities?
Let's look into him.
No,
let's just download everyone's fucking
phone numbers and everyone's emails and
everyone's voice mails and constantly
monitor everything all the time.
And by the way,
let's build a huge facility in Utah that
consists of hundreds of trillions of
terabytes of storage and
just store everything. Fuck
it. We'll just store it off.
And if Alex starts talking, Shit would
just say, oh yeah, Alex, check this.
And we'd go look at all
these big black dicks.
You've been looking at sun and we just
didn't go to you. How did you, Hey,
I'm a fucking talking to me.
And they go and they download all
your stuff and they present it to you.
And they say, look, you
know, you have a choice.
Either we can make this public or
we can, you know, fill in the blank,
whatever they would like to get from you.
Yeah.
And what's scary is that what we
recently discovered the last week or so,
there was the revelations that,
you know, it's always been a,
the excuse has always been, you
know, terrorism, the Patriot Act,
it's always been since nine
11 we have to do this because,
and what was revealed as they've been
doing this long before nine 11 and it was
mostly because of the drug war.
So it's,
it's kind of commonly known that a lot
of the surveillance implementations that
occurred occurred because of the
drug war. Yeah. Isn't that adorable?
The drug war is the thing and it's this
whole drug war is such a joke because
there's not a war on drugs.
It's a lie. It's a flat out lie.
There's no war on drugs.
There never will be a war on drugs.
There will always be drugs.
There's not a war.
There's a war on some drugs
and it's not even a war.
It's a mad money grab.
It's a mad money grab
from privatized prisons.
from the guard unions,
the prison guard unions
from law enforcement,
from all these people that
profit off drugs being legal.
It has zero to do with public safety.
Zero to do with public health.
It's a lie. Yeah. I mean the film goes
into that in detail. So, uh, I mean I,
I totally agree with that
and it, it isn't, you know,
to say that we don't need things to be,
you know, we don't need law enforcement,
we don't need certain types of regulation.
But the question is why,
why do we need them and what
purpose are they serving?
And making sure that they
serve an accurate purpose.
But when they're primarily
being used to felonies,
minorities in fill prisons for profit,
then you've got something that probably
needs to be changed without a doubt.
I mean, and there's, there's
also some talk recently,
and I know some states
have recently passed this.
We're asset forfeiture laws
are being rescinded. Like,
you can no longer just steal people
shit because you pulled them over,
they pull you over and say,
what if you were going to buy a car
somewhere and they pull you over and you
Alex, what are you doing with
$5,000 cash? And you're like, oh,
I was going to go buy a car. Can you
prove that we're going to take that?
You're gonna have to prove that in court.
They could take that.
And they were taking it and they
were using it to fund parties.
They bought a fucking Margarita machine,
which is so ironic.
They were so serving drugs with money
that they took from people who they
suspected of selling drugs. Yeah.
They just were selling this.
They were just dealing with the
sanction drugs. If they're party,
the sanction Margarita's yeah, it's
human nature. Disgusting. I know,
but it's just if you give people law,
like if you write things
down on paper, like you, uh,
you law enforcement officer because of
this thing that's written down his paper,
you have the right to take this fellow
human being and put them in a cage
because they've decided to alter their
consciousness in a way that we don't deem
to be worthy. Right? Yeah. It's
a hell of a thing. It's retarded,
you know, it does. You
said it allows, you know,
people to be arrested for all
kinds of reasons and that's,
that's not helpful even to people
who need help who are on drugs.
And the parallel with the record
industry is that they're addicted to that
money. They are addicted to
taking that money from people.
They're addicted to the private
prisons are addicted to it.
The law enforcement officers are addicted.
There's a real issue with,
with drugs in this country in that if
marijuana was made legal, just marijuana,
some ungodly number of drug arrests
would no longer be necessary.
And that would make thousands of law
enforcement officers all over the country
out of a job. Yeah. And they don't
want that. Nobody wants, I mean, look,
there's a way to do it where they would
be put into a better position in society,
but it wouldn't be locking people
up for a plant. Right? Yup.
And they're addicted to it. They're
addicted to it, and it's a mad scramble.
I mean, it's not the same situation as
what's going on with the record industry.
The record industry makes far less
sense to me than the movie industry.
The movie industry makes sense. If you
want to make a movie like the Hobbit,
fuck that taught, that costs
a lot of money. You know?
And if you want to download that God damn
thing for free and you're not going to
go see it in the movie now and they're
not going to get your money right.
That to me seems a little bit unfair just
because you're dealing with something
that requires some
exorbitant amount of money.
And once you see it at
home on your television,
if you can download it
and play it on your TV,
there's really no reason
to go to the movies. Right.
But if you download Paul Stanley Solo
album, you might want to go see him live.
Yeah, the, you know,
the hobbits not going to do a live
show in woodland hills anytime soon.
Maybe they'll bring back like
the ice capades still, you know,
like we get that stuff gone again.
But I mean it's true except for I
still maintain, like you said earlier,
that pleasant or unpleasant. We're in
a transitional period and the consumer,
you can't brand the consumer as being
sort of morally repellent or thieves
because they are using a technology that
gives them what they want the way they
want it. It isn't just, it isn't
to them. It isn't about money.
I've always maintained that.
It's like this is really
easy. It's super convenient.
This is, why would I bend myself around
to go like, wait for your window.
Like a hobbit is going to come
out when you know I live here.
I'm not going to get that.
Like all my friends have seen it over
there and I can't see it here. It's like,
no, I'm going to circumvent that because
I want it now. It's like the windowing,
the way in which consumers want.
Their entertainment is changing
because of the way technology works,
no matter what that does
to your business model.
You have to change your business model to
fit what the consumer wants. You can't,
you can't just keep branding and pirates
and just staying in the old way of
doing things. Cause if that ship
has sailed, I'm a huge fan of games,
game of Thrones, and I haven't seen the
new, the first episode of the new season,
but somebody sent me a fucking tweet.
I don't know if you know,
but the first five episodes have
been leaked on mother fuckers.
How dare you. Yeah, and but that's
not going to hurt game of Thrones.
I'm not going to not have HBO.
Maybe somebody won't,
you know there's going to be shrinkage
because of the change in technologies.
I mean just like, just like the
car replaced the horse and buggy,
just like refrigeration
killed, you know, ice delivery.
It's like the other is it's,
it's not to be pollyannish and say
this is all great for everybody.
It's just to be realistic
and say the ship has sailed,
technology is changing the
world and all these ways.
One of them happens to be the
way we listen to music. You know?
It's like that's just the
fact of the way we live.
We can't look at our society and blame
them all for being pirates. These, this,
this world is evolving.
We have to move with that world
and it is going to be painful.
There are going to be casualties, but we
will come out. Okay on the other side.
That's how it's always been that way.
I mean he imagine how pissed
off the blacksmith swore
when cars came along. Yeah.
Like dude, my fucking shit. I'm making
horse shoes. That's my shit. Yeah.
Nobody wants horse shoes anymore.
But that's a part of the evolution of,
of culture.
Do you know how they fought cars?
The way they fought cars was the same way.
They're fighting the deep web
and the records and the Napster,
they said that cars are bad because you
can't see what's in the trunk and you
can be used to move contraband across
state lines when they tried to use that as
a way to prevent the automobile from
becoming more popularized. So it's,
it's always the same argument that you're
going to do something very bad with
that you can't have it.
And of course that was probably going
on during prohibition. Of course,
the invention of the car, it was within
a decade or two of that. So yeah,
that's the hope.
I mean they were,
they were trying to keep people
from drinking booze. They,
I mean they were trying to say,
look, no drugs, no nothing. Yeah.
What a fucked up time.
That must have been.
People who want some is so God damn angry.
Yeah. Look what came out of it. Yeah.
Fucking Al Capone organized crime to same
shit we're seeing in Mexico right now.
The cartels,
all of it comes about.
It's like at what point in time to these
dummies not look at history and go,
look, this is going to happen.
History's going to repeat itself.
When you create a vacuum,
it will be filled. Yeah.
When you have a desire that people
have undeniable desire to alter their
consciousness and you have a
method that everyone's aware of,
but then you deny them
access to that method,
someone's going to provide it for
sure. If they're gonna step in. Yeah,
the money's big now. It's just you
look at it on paper, where's the Blas?
Where's the benefit? Like what?
What is the loss to society?
Organized crime. That's the
loss. That's the number one.
All the murders and the craziness and
the chaos that comes from not from
businesses that you can regulate and
understand and look at their profits and
see what their practices are and decide
whether or not you want to boycott this
company as opposed to that company
which behaves more ethically.
This company is organic in this company
is self sustaining and look at it. No,
it's you're,
you're,
you're making it illegal and you're
creating a organized crime ring.
It's like instantly you're going to
create that and destroying economies.
And I mean, the reverberations
are huge all over the world. Yeah.
And the reverberations I think of just
denying people freedom. There's, there's,
uh, it's, uh,
a very deteriorating effect on human
beings when another human being denies a
person of any inalienable right.
You're, you're right to sleep.
They'll keep waking you up in
the middle of the night. You get,
you're going to get fucking furious.
They say you can't drink more than a glass
of water a day. Who the fuck are you?
There's this,
this thing that people have when someone
tries to keep them from doing something
that doesn't make any sense.
Totally.
And talking private on a website
is one of those things. Yeah.
And if they're exchanging drugs
and you know, they're selling,
buying and selling drugs,
like wow,
that's a minor consequence of freedom.
Yeah.
And it's also revolutionary.
It also means that people are trying
to find new ways to do something that
there's going to be easier for them
or more, uh, done in a more healthy,
functional way than the
current way that exists.
And that's what I think is blowing
people's minds because that maybe this
actually is reducing crime and
violence in the street trade.
Maybe it is causing a
problem for the cartels.
Maybe it is making it easier for someone
who has a habit to be in a community
that may be able to help them as opposed
to throw them in jail. I mean it's, it's,
there's, it's, and again, it's
not to say these are all good.
It's not to me a black and white issue,
but there was just a lot of gray here.
There's always going to be,
then there's,
that's just a part of being a human
being. You know, you give people freedom,
they're going to do things that you
might not necessarily agree with. Yeah.
I mean, how many people agree with
people tattooing their face? You know,
a lot of people think that's a terrible
choice, but if you make it illegal,
you'll probably,
the number of people tattooing their face
would probably go through the roof for
sure. This is no way to stop people
from doing what they want to do.
And when you try,
it makes them,
it's just a thing about human beings.
When you want us to not do something,
we ordinarily want to do it.
That's why Catholic school girls were
always so ridiculously promiscuous. Right.
Why? Because they're always told like
don't, don't go anywhere near boys. No,
I can wait to get here. Like I have
a friend who went to Catholic school,
she was just talking about it yesterday.
She was like,
everybody in my class was boy crazy
cause there was no boys and they were the
forbidden fruit.
Right.
It's like everything their parents
were trying to protect them from.
They were just ramping it up. Yeah,
totally. Yeah. There's your motivator.
So this was created,
um,
originally the software that was used to,
to power the deep rip,
the deep web and Silk Road was all
initially used or created for good.
Yeah. And it's still largely
used for good. Again,
you have to think about it like a,
like a city. It's an environment. Like,
if you look at it under a terrarium,
it's just this place now and any city,
you're going to have all kinds
of good stuff going on and you're
going to have bad stuff going on and
you're gonna have everything in between is
literally just a place it gets demonized,
but as no different than
any other environment.
It's just a privacy oriented environment.
It was created by the navy. Torah was,
anyway,
that's one way into the tor.
Tor is a browser that anonymizes
meaning, uh, you don't,
no one can track your,
um, your IP address.
No one can see what sites you're visiting.
I use tor like you to
use Amazon for instance,
because it's really easy to get
hacked online using a regular browser.
I don't want my credit card number
being plugged into a regular browser.
So I use tour. If I'm a banking online,
I use tour cause it anonymizes. Um,
it runs through a network that doesn't
allow people to track what you're
inputting into it doesn't
know where you are.
And this is Tori program or a browser,
or is it browser,
but then it goes further than,
that tour also has a component
called tor hidden services,
and that is actually a kind of a separate
internet that operates within the dark
net. And the TOR hidden services don't
end with Dotcom. The end would dot.
Dot. Onion tours. Tours stands
for the onion router. It was,
and it was created by the navy primarily
to be used for agents to communicate
with each other anonymously. It's, I mean,
the NSA uses it, law enforcement uses it.
So it's always been used
largely for good to this day,
it's still used by a lot of government
agencies to this day. So it's t o r, yeah.
Yeah. Well, it'd be whatever it is. It'll
be like a string of numbers dot onion, uh,
to get to pull tore down. You just go to,
I think it's toward out org or whatever.
You can get that from the Clearnet. The
surface one. Is that restricted? No,
it's totally illegal. I mean, it's, again,
it's used a lot of people who use tor
journalists use it, dissidence, use it.
They're like, you know, rape counseling
organizations that use it. Like, okay,
we're going to do,
we're going to talk online,
let's all pull down tour and then
we can get on our forum, you know,
in the tor hidden services and you can
feel comfortable talking about being
raped or whatever happens. It's, it's
an anonymized corner of the Internet.
And how does it work? Well, I don't want
to bore your, your audience but, but the,
it's,
it involves pretty intense math and um,
a lot of this stuff grew out of the,
the sort of early creators of the
Internet that we're using cryptography and
ways of a bouncing, uh, or rerouting,
it's very similar to a peer to peer
technology where your signal or your input
gets rerouted and bounced
around a bunch of others.
So it gets scrambled and then it will
find itself on some other end having gone
through a bunch of other, uh, routers.
Right? So that's how the, the,
the sort of surface browser area works.
The,
the hidden service is
actually operating within a,
an area of the Internet
called the deep web.
And the deep web is just like
everything online that is an index.
It's basically like looking
under the hood of your car.
It's just all the junk online,
like banks communicating crap to
each other. It's just mostly just,
just a code,
right?
That doesn't need to be indexed by Google
cause it's a bunch of code and people
figured out how to get down into that
area and create an actual environment.
So they have have built,
um,
space within the deep web that you
can use. You can access through Tor.
So it's unindexed so you can't find it by,
by using Google.
It never shows up in the surface
web. Whoa. It's pretty interesting.
And it's been there forever.
It's just been growing over time.
And then tor was developed over
the last 15 years or so. Um,
but there are other ways to get into
that area as well that are growing.
So the problem with that would be,
of course, if someone say like,
if someone was harassing, say an ex
girlfriend or something like that,
sending someone threatening messages,
you couldn't track it. Yeah.
But you couldn't if you could because if
I'm sending my ex girlfriend it hidden
messages,
I'd have to be sending them to her on
the surface web or she wouldn't see them.
Uh,
you know,
I mean unless she's hanging out in the
deep web with me in case what's what she
doing down there and I mean but if like
if I send an email to her through my
tour browser to her email address,
you're going to f you can track me through
her email address cause she's in the
clear. But that's why it always has to
be an alternative then because honestly,
because if it was like chrome,
if chrome had these type of capabilities
right then someone could harass someone
on Facebook or something like that
and you wouldn't be able to track it.
We are going to get to,
this is where it gets into an interesting
gray area because it's a little of
both. There we, we are
going to be building,
there are going to be browser technologies
that do randomize your location.
There's already VPN, sort of virtual
networks that, that mask your IP address.
You can use those every day. A
lot of people do. Um, and again,
they're not doing that so they
can hide for doing contraband.
They're doing that to prevent
being hacked most of the time. Um,
and that already will,
will sort of preclude people from
knowing exactly what computer you sent
something from. But you know, in
general it's pretty easy to trace.
The digital world is a trackable world
and at that, at the end of the day,
usually contract somebody,
unless they're in a completely alternative
space talking to someone else who has
willingly joined that alternate space,
then all bets are kind of off.
So if you were a member of one of
these communities and you joined up,
someone could harass you then.
And there's really not a lot you could
be saying user x, y double d slash zero,
you're a piece of shit.
If they found out who you were though,
well then your randomized number.
Yeah, you, you create a user name and,
and no one's gonna know who you are in
that space and there's nothing connecting
you to the surface.
But if you reveal who you are in that,
then you'd have to get a new randomized
number. Yeah. Which you'd take it.
It's like a username. It would take, you
all have three seconds to do that. That's,
yeah,
that would be smart.
It's interesting that because we're kind
of making the argument that you need
some transparency online that you,
you kind of have to be
traceable to a certain extent.
And that's what we're making the
argument. Yeah. Yes and no though.
I still maintained Steve
Wasniak, you know, the, the,
the great apple computer genius a set
and I think he was talking about file
sharing. Um, you know,
we're all like on this highway and the
highway has all of these lanes on it and
we're all moving along and just
like kind of regular highway,
most of us during the day aren't like
shooting each other and driving each other
off the road.
The highway tends to function day in,
day out with millions of people on it.
Just fine. Even with the road rage,
it's fine.
There may be one or two bad apples that
do something that's really crazy or
dangerous. But you don't shut
the entire highway down. Right.
You figured out ways to police that and
we're in the same boat like just like
with Napster.
People are trying to use old world
ways of policing this new terrain.
It isn't to say that we should have know
that it should be completely private in,
there should be no transparency as to say,
hey guys,
those are massive human
revolution going on right now.
Or an evolution or a cultural change,
whatever you want to call it.
This move from the industrial age
to the technological or digital age.
It's not going to be, it's going to be
a bumpy ride. There's no easy answer,
but we need to come up with new laws
that affect how we convene in the space.
Not just say, nobody can get on this
highway. That's never, like you said,
that's never going to happen.
It's never going to happen,
and the g force that's
involved in this change,
the change is so powerful and so rapid.
You're going to have some screw ups,
no way around it. It's going so fast
and we're going to stumble. We have to,
there's no way it's going to be smooth
and we're going to go backwards.
We're going to make
mistakes. I mean, you know,
I don't fault my kids when they were
like listening to music on Youtube.
I mean we're kind of past the days of
my kids don't like use bittorrent for,
for um, for um, you know, file sharing.
But you don't think they do well.
Yeah, actually that's, yeah,
it's completely nonsensical. My,
my older team does all the time.
I keep talking to them about it, but
uh, yeah, he's a massive folder on us,
but it's mostly, yeah, I'm going, I'm not
going to shame shame him on the podcast,
but uh, uh, but the reality of it is he,
he loves by music and he loves, you know,
being part of the process
with bands like they've,
like there almost was a middle generation
that just went hog wild on just file
sharing all their music.
But most people like being part of the,
that's why we have currency.
That's why we have money and we
exchange cause it's like a human need.
So I think that a lot of this stuff will
iron itself out over time. I hate to,
but it will. I mean a lot
of people will be like, Oh,
here's how we monetize
the music. Oh, here's how,
how I can actually pay to help support
the bands I like and I'm still use the
technology I like and we'll be okay.
I think time is actually
going to fix a lot of this,
but we're definitely in a crazy
wild west right now. Yeah, I agree.
I just think,
think that the disparity of income is
probably never going to be the same again
unless it comes from you don't spend
$20 on a CD with one good song on it
everywhere. What a drag.
That's true. Right.
There was always the thing.
Do you remember going to
was at virgin that would,
they would have those listening booths.
There was the first time you would ever
get a chance to listen to the show to
shut that,
shut that sucker down and then probably
did more for killing the record.
Was it Brittany Spears? Whether
what? Wait, what? Oh Man. Yeah.
Like you would listen to the hit and
then you listen to the Osa. Very,
I'm not buying this fucking
thing. Yeah, yeah. That, that
was a big scam, right? Like,
look, I'm a huge rolling stones fan. Huge
Rolling Stones Fan. But let's be honest,
a good percentage of their
songs suck a fat deck.
If you go back and do some
girls. Yeah. Just some girls.
Pretty much every track is gold,
but it's the sound girl.
There's some great fucking songs, but
there's also some songs that you just go,
oh yeah. Right. What
did you guys get high?
And just slap this together when you're
on coke. Like does this, yeah, probably.
But they can't do that
anymore. Yeah. You can't now.
And then you're seeing like bands or
being forced into this position where you
are, you're represented by
your entire piece of work.
It's not just like a hit that you send
out that's sort of a bait to get you to
buy the CD that's been sort of loosely
slapped together with shitty songs.
Totally. I mean, it's a cultural
thing. You can also look at the, uh,
the golden age of music being mega
profitable as a cultural moment.
You know, it was very brief, even in the
annals of, of the record industry itself,
most for most of the history of
recorded music, it was about singles.
It wasn't about albums, it was the
artists only made their money by touring.
You know, it was a very short period
of time historically actually,
where you had this like 20
million sellers, 40 million.
So these units being moved to these
enormous numbers that was never going to
last. And it wasn't necessarily even
an organic thing anyway. And again,
it's not to condone what happened,
it's just to say that sometimes we lose
perspective and think it was always like
this until those, those damn meddling
kids on their computers came along. Yeah.
That's interesting.
You're not sure because like
file sharing really is like this,
like blip, but record sales
are the real blip. Yeah.
I mean out of the thousands of years of
people creating music and musical art,
yeah. Look at this tiny brief window
where people were selling these things and
anything,
that amount of money we're talking
about probably no more than 25 years.
I mean it's a really small window even
within the record industry's history.
That's fascinating when you
think about it that way.
Oh Donnie Einer and download it
talks about that quite a bit.
A really clear eye view of it
cause he really came up through,
he was like the youngest president
of Columbia. Really Amazing Guy.
Just had a very interesting perspective
on, on the bubble as it were. The side,
the other side of it.
What is the,
what's the view of the music or
the movie business? Have the,
has the movie business taken a big hit
from file sharing? Um, I mean it, it,
I think the game of Thrones thing is, is
really been the question. Um, you know,
there was a lot of uproar about the
amount of piracy that was going on in the
amount of file sharing that was
going on around the game of Thrones.
And then at a certain point HPO sort of
changed, shifted position from saying,
this is really terrible and you're
all criminals to wait a minute.
You guys all really love what we have.
This is becoming the
most popular show on TV.
Let's figure out how to get it to you.
You know?
And they started coming up with
alternatives like HBO go. To me,
that's really the right way to
look at it. And I know it's, again,
I'm not being Glib. It's not fun
to lose lots of money when you're,
when you're putting so much money
and time into doing these works.
But it's being realistic that
people all over the world,
they want their content at the same time.
They wanted a certain way.
It isn't gonna Change. So I think
people have to change with the times.
And some are,
and some aren't.
Hbo Ceo doesn't care that you
are sharing your HBO go pass.
And that took a, that took some time.
I mean, he had the opposite viewpoint.
Look at that, that quote, we're in the
business of creating addicts. Yeah. Wow.
Good for you. You smart
bastard. Yeah. Richard Plepler.
Richard Go, go Richard.
You Go, boy. Yeah. Yeah,
that's a, don't say it. Try saying
his name 10 times in a row. Quickly.
Smart fellow.
Yeah,
and that's smart because like there's 350
goddamn million people in this country.
If you can get 350 million people
to watch your show, that's amazing.
And then just global, like game
of Thrones is all over the world,
so you're going to get a lot.
But that's a show that
requires an exorbitant amount
of money to create. Yeah,
the special effects are crazy and
huge and the production is enormous.
The reality of it is,
is it's always been on the
onus of business to figure
out how to make a profit.
And that's what drives them crazy because
right now they're in a period where
the consumers have taken back the power
and they're scratching their heads going,
oh shit.
Now what do we do?
We've got to figure out how to create a
system where we can get maximum profit.
Again, they've, they've
taken a knock back,
but on what I don't respond too well
is when they retaliate against their
consumers and go,
it's your fault that we got knocked back.
You guys are criminals
and we're going to eat.
This is bad and we have to educate you
that you need to give us profit again. No,
I mean we have to educate
you that this is wrong.
I mean their motive is purely profit
based, so I get that it's a drag,
but it's up to you to figure out a way to
make a profit out of what you're doing.
They also don't have a stranglehold on
the promotional aspect to anymore because
of the Internet,
because of Youtube and Twitter and
Facebook and people sharing links.
A band king become really
popular really quickly.
Like someone could pass something along
and then it becomes a viral hit on
youtube and you go, wow. It's things
like that. Fucking Gangnam style. Right.
That's a perfect example. The greatest
song ever written that song? Not yet.
That did not get popular because it was
on the radio or because it was good.
Some people in dry though.
That's how you have many minds of people
in my fucking six year old and my four
year old go crazy on the teletubbies is
has some kind of weird primordial sort
of trigger switch. You
know, it's a silly video.
It's silly and it's videos.
What works if you were a little kid,
would love to show it. Yeah,
for sure. But the perfect,
it's a perfect example in that like
did that didn't require any promotional
vehicle other than people enjoying it
and sharing it with other people and then
it spread like wildfire. Totally.
And it used to be, look at that.
Oh my God, look at that number.
Yeah, that's 8 million. Yeah, no,
that's 2 billion. Oh, here we go along
number. I was looking at subscribers.
His subscribers are almost 8 million,
but his number of use is 2 billion.
That's a billion.
Yeah. What the fuck? That's
crazy. See, and that's all. Yeah,
just viral. That's community. That's
community that used to require,
you used to have to have a radio station.
Yeah.
He used to have and used to have to be
in bed with that radio station record
company would put a gun to your head
physically and make you play a single to
give it that kind of juice and
yeah and they had these deals,
these under the table deals with record
companies where they would not pay play
certain people because they were black
ball and that was a real issue in your
hands. Yeah. Payola yeah and just
the, they, they were in control.
They had the power and the
record companies being these
huge organizations with
a massive amount of money behind them.
They were able to sort of create stars
and there was a lot of artificial stars
that they created this by mouth.
Fucking everybody with this music
just forcing it into your ears.
They can't do that anymore.
No that's the,
that that ship has definitely sailed and
they're going to have to come up with
alternative ways to, to get back
to some degree of where they were.
And it may take time that I
actually believe they'll get there.
Cause people are very, very clever at
figuring out how to make money. Well,
I think they will try,
but I do not believe they will.
I think that music will always be big.
Yeah.
But I think the era of record
companies having to kind of influence,
they used to having the
face of it be the same.
I agree it's going to be something else.
We just don't know what that is yet.
Yeah,
because music the way it is now,
one of the weird things about music now
is there's no longer deejays anymore.
You know what I mean? When I was
a kid there was like, you know,
there was all these radio d,
do you remember that show?
Wk Irp and Cincinnati and a lot of
that show was about these personality.
I grew up with those people.
All the popular djs. Yeah.
Like when I was a kid who was Charles
Laquidara and Boston, the big mattress.
Dave Sherman in New York. Yeah.
There's all these morning DJ guys.
Of course the big one was always Howard
stern morning, but he was, you know,
he went from music originally and
then just went to straight talk.
Probably the first guy ever to
do that on FM the way he did it.
But those guys don't even exist anymore.
They don't those morning Dj guys,
they have a tiny window where
they're allowed to talk and you know,
there's not that many of them
anymore and they're dying.
They're just disappearing and they're
being replaced by these weird programs.
Stations. Yeah, no, it's true. The
radio is really changing dramatically.
I mean I think, you know, kind of what
you're driving at is like curation,
this whole idea that that that people
would cure rate and you could go to a
place in here, something that
is evolving much more quickly.
Like I think that's been the next phase
of digital music is now we're finding
more curation on online, whether it's
through Spotify or other services.
Pitchfork, you know, where you can go,
oh, I want to get certain kinds of music.
I'm going to go here.
And what's cool about the internet is
that you can pull like the best rock
critics together or the best whatever
kind of music you like and you can
aggregate that are sort of compile it
through Spotify or some service and just
check out what they want. You know, you
can choose who your DJ is in a way. Right.
And that's what a Dj used to be like.
A Dj was kind of an
artist in a way for sure.
Because a DJ would turn you on to some
stuff that you'd never heard before. Yeah.
They would, they would have the ability
to play with, they wanted to play. Yeah.
Yeah. The notion of
gatekeepers has changed a lot.
And on most of the gatekeepers that
existed are no longer gatekeepers. Well,
the word sort of concentrating
on one aspect of this issue,
which is sort of a file sharing
and the digital reality of,
of songs and things along those lines.
But this,
the Silk Road story was a lot
more about drugs and infiltration.
Yeah. And there was a lot going
on. Yeah. Yeah. There was a,
it was actually a political movement.
I mean the,
the Silk Road was whether you agree with
it or not and the movie is not about
taking a side as much as trying to show
what it actually was as opposed to what
we heard about in the media.
Um, it was a political movement.
I mean it was a community that was,
that was put together with certain
political ideals and they weren't all the
same. That's the, the, some
of them were libertarian,
some of them were hardcore leftwing
people, more socialist oriented,
some of them were in the middle.
But what unify them was this desire to
have individual freedom and privacy and
anonymity.
And there was a lot of people in that
community and a lot of people were there
for the community.
And that's a very,
I think a very threatening thing as well
as being an interesting moment in time.
And a lot of people were
there for the community,
but there was some weird shit
that went down at first of all,
some people at infiltrated this
community, right? Like law enforcement.
I mean of course law enforcement
was there from day one.
I mean they want the law enforcement.
I mean,
of course if you see that there's a
market online that's selling heroin,
you know,
via the postal service and you're in any
number of three letter law enforcement
agencies, you're going to be showing up
at that. How'd they find out about it?
Well, I mean in order to sell
drugs you have to advertise.
So it sort of went out on the
wire enough to enough people.
So if like if I'm afraid in Ohio and
I know to buy my drugs on online,
some cop somewhere is going to know.
And once one cop knows,
they all know and it
was on, you know, to do,
to credit the FBI and the DEA, they
knew what was going on, you know,
pretty early on.
And they installed undercover operatives
with fictitious user accounts.
It just turned out some of
them were dirty. Um, you know,
that's what came out a couple of weeks
ago was that two of the lead agents on
the Silk Road case out of Baltimore,
Dea agents and secret service where were
extorting tons of money off the Silk
Road and putting it into
personal accounts and you know,
creating murder for hire
entrapment schemes. I mean it was,
they were kind of off the rails. But of
course when you're dealing with, you know,
alternative communities
that are that radical,
of course they are going to
be bad things that happen.
And of course there's going to
be things that are, you know, uh,
not on the up and up.
And this cop thing happened after that.
You got done finishing? Well, it
was revealed. I actually knew some,
something about it,
but I was,
it was like I was kind of gag
ordered and that it wasn't,
it was a grand jury indictment,
um, investigation going on.
So we weren't allowed to
talk about it. The, uh,
Russell Burk's defense attorney wasn't
allowed to bring it up in the trial.
I knew that something was going
on involving rogue agents.
I didn't know exactly what it was,
but I kind of put two and two together
that that's what it was. But um, you know,
it came out, uh, after
the trial. I mean I have,
I've now gone back and addressed it
slightly in the movie, but you know,
it only has so much relevance because
the film again isn't, you know,
saying that the guys who built the Silk
Road or heroes and that these guys are
just bad.
The point is that you have all kinds
of people mixed up and things like this
good and bad.
There are plenty of good law enforcement
agents just like there were a rogue
ones.
There are plenty of good people on the
Silk Road just like there were bad ones
and there was probably the, the ones
who went bad, they were probably like,
there's nobody that can figure
out what I'm doing here.
This is all craziness
under this web thing.
I think that you can get
a false sense of security,
that if you're using an anonymous browser,
if you're using a fictitious user name,
if you're using a cryptocurrency like
bitcoin that doesn't have your name
attached to it,
you can have this false sense of
security that you're untouchable,
which you know, as I
said earlier, you know,
everything that happens in the digital
world tends to be very traceable.
On some level it's,
it's hard to be truly anonymous online.
You have to go through,
you can do it,
but you have to go through an enormous
lengths to remain truly anonymous on the,
you know, one little slip
and you're done. And you can,
the thing about the Internet is one
friend of mine within the Silk Road, um,
said to me,
he's like,
the Internet never forgets so you
could make a slip five years ago.
But if I'm a federal agent and I'm like
winding met way through your fictitious
user history and I get
to that one slip your,
if that door has been opened once
and the light shone on your face,
that's all they need is once. And whether
that's law enforcement or a hacker,
anybody, if there's a vulnerability
they're going to get in.
So these guys who were
the bad undercover agents,
they had diverted hundreds of
thousands of dollars in Bitcoin,
really over a million, over $1
million and they got caught. Yeah.
How'd they get caught?
They um,
well it's not totally known
because to be fair it was an under,
it was a sting operation from
within the DEA and other agencies.
So they're not completely telling
everyone how they got caught,
but they were known as Mike's got a new
boat. There was, there was some of that.
There was like people paying off their
mortgages when they're only making 150
before taxes. There were, there were
some dumb mistakes that got made.
There were accounts set up
with a lot of money in them.
There were too many user fictitious user
names, you know that eventually again,
one tiny slip of one email account that
you use to connect yourself to one. It's,
it's, that's the thing about the digital
world as you can. It's like a flow chart.
You can just sit and look at it and go,
oh,
it went from here to here
to here and then that's it.
So those guys got busted.
Um,
were they involved in any of
the cases that were Oh yeah.
And is that being looked at now as like
potential corruption that maybe the
cases are tainted? Indictments might
be thrown out totally. Oh, that's big.
Yeah.
Now the,
there was also some murder for hire
stuff if you were talking about, yeah,
it was it real murder for hire or what?
We don't know. See, here's the thing is,
is that one of the agents that was
arrested was the, was the undercover,
um, who was sort of at the heart of
that first murder for hire. Stang.
So he basically actually framed
somebody else in the Silk Road,
said that person stole money when
actually he was the one who is,
who took the money and said we should do,
you know,
instigated doing something to that person
who was just one of the vendors on the
Silk Road. And that turns out to not only
be a cop, which we've known all along,
but a dirty cop,
a cop who was,
who was stealing money and blackmailing
people within the Silk Road. So the,
the murder for hire, there were no
bodies that were, there were no,
there had been no murders,
there were no bodies that were ever found.
A No one appears to have
been hurt, um, on any level.
And what we still don't totally know is
what their antibody and who that was, um,
actually originally instigated
those murders for hire, the,
just to bring you up to speed quickly.
The,
the prosecution claimed they had a lot
of hard evidence against Ross all break.
They said they have his laptop,
they said on that laptop they found a
journal that he wrote that in which a key
clearly laid out what he did on
the Silk Road the whole time.
They believe it attributes him
to the dread pirate Roberts,
who they showed a dread
pirate Roberts records saying,
I want to take a hit out on this person.
I'm going to send you the x amount
of bitcoin. Um, so they're saying,
here's Ross's journal. It's on his laptop.
It's talking about murders for hire.
But the other thing you have
to keep in mind is two things.
One is he wasn't charged with murder.
That was not an indictment.
That was even part of his case.
They didn't charge him for murder.
They just talked about it.
They didn't have to prove it because
he wasn't being charged with it.
He's only being trudged primarily the
drug kingpin conspiracy and hacking
charges, which carry a
potentially life in prison. Now,
the drug conspiracy charges,
was it directly related to him
distributing drugs? No, it was,
it was him being at the
center of the website.
So that gets into transfer of intent,
internet issues as well. But no, he was,
he was being charged with creating
a service that allowed the,
the selling of,
of you know,
millions of dollars worth of drugs to
millions of people. That seems so shifty.
It's like as far as charging someone
for that, because in that case,
can't you charge Twitter? Can't you
charge Facebook? I, I mean, I don't know.
I don't have any personal information of
people selling drugs through Facebook,
but I gotta imagine someone has sent a
Facebook message to someone saying, Hey,
you want to buy some coke? Well,
yeah, I think the argument is this,
this site was specifically created
for selling illegal drugs. The,
the, the, uh, defendant, well,
that's the claim, right? You know,
um, the defense's argument is
twofold. They say a, um, you know,
this person, uh, the dread pirate
Roberts wasn't even selling drugs.
They were just, you know, the creator
of this politically oriented freedom,
you know, dark website and people will
be, do whatever they wanted to on it.
And he was anti-drug Warren.
You mean you can't deny that there was
a big drug component to the Silk Road by
its very nature, it was
a big, this sort of,
the motivation of the Silk Road via the
dread pirate Roberts writing was about
removing harm and crying from the drug,
drug trade and,
and helping to bring
the drug war to an end.
But they also claimed that the journal
and all that stuff in the bit coin found
on Ross is a computer,
aren't his.
They claim that he was hacked and that
the whole silk road was filled with all
kinds of people like these murky DEA
agents that we're using other people's
usernames and accounts, which they
were, that the Internet world is so, um,
uh,
hard to pin down once you get behind
fictitious usernames that they're saying
that none of this stuff was actually his,
and that's what they're
taking into an appeal.
Like they feel so strongly about that
they're moving forward with appeal.
Prosecution said that's nonsense. This
stuff was all on his, on his laptop.
And in the current trial that just ended,
the jury sided with the prosecution
and Ross was found guilty on all seven
counts.
He's being sentenced in a few weeks,
but they are moving to an appeal and
maybe we'll find out more and maybe that
will turn out to be the truth.
We, we don't know what it was.
He found guilty before it was revealed
that there was these dirty yes.
Yeah, they, and they did.
And they knew that this case existed
and they didn't allow like the, the,
the lawyer Ross,
his defense was trying to postpone the
trial a couple of months so that the
grand jury investigation,
the criminal charges that you knew
were going to drop the complaint. Um,
but they were not allowed to postpone the
trial and that seems like a slam dunk.
If you can prove that these cops are
using other people's usernames and they
were hacking into people's accounts
and that, that seems like right there.
Like you, you can't prove anybody
that's a trial. I would certainly,
I'd like to see that trial.
Like my perspective on it is,
is I'm fine with whatever
the truth turns out to be.
I would just love to see both sides have
their day and I was at that trial and
the defense did not have a day.
That's always how it is though, man.
Mean the idea that you get a fair trial
is such a fucking joke because there's
so much railroading going on.
Yeah.
Especially when there's an agenda like
this to prosecute someone in a, in a,
an important case, a landmark case. They
think is going to establish a precedent.
They will fuck you. Yeah.
That's kind of how it is. Yeah.
And they will fuck you.
And that's what they did to this guy.
Now this dread pirate Roberts character.
What's his name? Dread Pirate Roberts. Oh,
I mean the guy that was accused of being
diff because they think Russell Brook
and he's denying that he was dread
pirate Roberts. Yeah. He's saying,
here's what we know about him.
We know that he had these like hardcore
libertarian values. He wasn't a hacker.
He was not a computer guy. Didn't
know anything about coding at all. Um,
he was a physics major,
you know, he was a,
he'd put himself through two
universities on full scholarship.
You had a master's degree in mechanical
engineering from Penn State. Very Bright.
Um, we know that he had hardcore
libertarian politics. We know that much.
He admitted to creating the Silk Road,
said he did it to create it like an
economic simulation where he would combine
tour and Bitcoin to allow
a marketplace to exist.
It would be free for everybody to use.
However they wanted to use it.
He claims he say he built it with the
help of a lot of other people was he
doesn't really know how to
code and he just let it run.
And he took off and he was done and he
moved on. And that's what his family,
his mom and dad back him on that.
And that's what the,
his family claims they given being around
him because they're very tight knit
family. All this time they
were like, this was not,
someone was on his laptop all the time.
I don't know how he could
have been running a, you know,
a almost a billion dollar drug
empire. He wasn't, you know, that guy.
He wasn't, the guy just sat on his
monitors keyboard all the time. Um,
so he claimed he's not dread
pirate Roberts prosecution
claims that he was and,
and uh, and that was what
that first trial was about.
What is their proof that he was of,
they did find a journal on his laptop
and the journal on his laptop is like,
you know, today I'm setting up a
dread pirate Roberts account today.
I'm going to do this today.
Fuck does that fuck writes a journal
on their laptop of all the shit they're
going to do today, I will take over the
world. Just kind of how it was that,
that seems so silly. Yeah. I mean
it's, it's, you know, it again,
I would love to see, like I went
to the trial thinking, okay,
now we're going to see what happened.
Right.
And I would love to see the defense
really have time to sort of talk through
their end and have expert witnesses
and get into the nitty gritty of it.
Because I mean, I would side with where
the, wherever the truth lies, but,
but to be in the courtroom and to
hear all that and just think, okay,
if this is true, this is like
the most naive, you know,
criminal mastermind in the history of,
could you imagine to be breaking
bad would've lasted like,
wouldn't have lasted half a season if
they had Walter White, like, you know,
so today I'll plant a bomb and the
courthouse today I'm going to blow up that
bomb. Yeah. And if you're reading this,
don't tell anyone from law enforcement,
you know.
Yeah.
It's not like he knows a lot
about computers and those
computer could be hacked
into or anything. Yeah. That's so stupid.
They didn't plant that on his laptop.
When you're dealing with all this other
shit that these cops planted information
and the fake hit man for hire shit.
Yeah, it's, it's really murky. I mean,
to be honest with you, the film goes
to certain degree into that stuff. I'm,
I'm very interested in looking at
all the issues at the movies raised,
but I have to be careful of how far
I go into that material. You know,
there's almost a whole other movie
and there really is, right? Yeah.
There's a whole under,
well,
I think there's a movie in
and guys getting rare or
people getting railroaded in
trials too. You know,
what makes it look like?
I have a friend who went
to jail for growing medical
marijuana that was legal in
California and when he went to jail
because the federal government tried them,
the federal government doesn't
even recognize medical marijuana,
so they refuse to even allow him say
the term medical marijuana. Right.
They also refuse to allow into court
the fact that it was passed into law in
California. You could not bring that
up at all because it was irrelevant.
This is a state issue.
We're talking about a federal issue.
It's totally irrelevant. Yeah. So this
guy went to jail for drug trafficking,
right when he was a legal medical provider
by the law of the state of California.
Yeah.
And that's like those are the people
that are going to get caught up in the
wheels of, of this transition, you know,
because in 10 years that's going to be
unheard of. Yeah. It's, it's so tragic.
And then it's creepy.
It's creepy that they can do that and
they can keep you from to communicating
all the facts of the case.
It's you. You're not granted
the right to a fair trial.
You re granted the right to a fair,
fair trial by the standard
of the people who are trying.
You want very desperately to convict you.
Correct. Yeah, yeah. That's fair enough.
Fuckface yeah, exactly. Yeah.
As I give this very little narrow path
that you're allowed to go down and you
can't stray on either side of that path
and that path basically leads to your
jail cell.
So they can't prove that this
guy actually sold any drugs.
But because he created this forum
that allowed other people to do it,
like they're not saying that he was
involved in any of these tracks,
transactions? No. And there they
can send it to him for fucking,
he's up for life I
think as minimum is the,
is 30 20 to 30 years minimum without
parole. And how long has he been in jail?
Waiting? A year and a half.
Oh, solitary confinement.
Oh my God. Yeah. And is any,
is there any hope? Um, you
know, I hope that they get an,
I really just hope to see the other
side talk. You know what I mean?
That's the part that was very chilling
and frustrating when I was in the
courtroom was just like,
it just ended like it was just Bam.
Prosecution said their piece defense was
about two. They got blocked. It was over.
They got blocked. Yeah. You can watch
the film, but basically they were,
they were just like you just talked about
with your friend. They were unable to,
they were unable to call expert witnesses
to talk about the complexities of
Bitcoin and how bitcoin wallets work
and how you can hack into these.
It was all, it was very much
only one side. And look,
let's say at the end of the day, it turned
out that that side is right. We just,
I just don't know, like we
don't know because we never
heard the other side talk.
So I would very much like to see the
defense have its day and if you come all
the way around. And the other problem
that I have is that, you know,
the media for the most part just sort
of swallows the party line. Like,
we're going to, we're going
to see silkroad movies and
they're all going to be,
they're going to totally just take the
prosecutorial position and they're going
to be,
you know,
news reports and movies and TV shows
and they're all going to be this roguish
hacker kid who tried to kill people
on the Internet. And, uh, again,
I maintain,
I know a fair amount about this case that
we don't totally know what happened in
the movie. He'll probably be sweaty and
doing math. He'll be Robert Pattinson,
you know, shave for a
while and yeah. Megan,
all such a terrible evil
choices. Yeah. Execute. Enter.
It wasn't that like a thing?
Like he,
they were saying like
at one point they were,
they wanted to beat this guy up because
he was going to talk and then they
decided to say execute him instead.
And so they faked the murder and they
showed a photo of the body. Well,
who did all that?
The person who did that was the undercover
agent who turns out to be corrupt.
Oh my God.
And he's the one who stole the money
that they were trying to sup allegedly
execute this person for stealing.
This guy had stolen money out
of fucking tangled web. It is.
Oh my God.
So this guy sets up a fake murder
for hire then does a fake murder,
has a fake body Yup.
All to punish this fake person
for stealing money that he stole.
Yes. And you need to go further. That
person that was supposedly killed,
who was one of the
vendors on the Silk Road,
was then arrested as being part
of the sting operation for this,
for this drug deal that was put together
by the crooked undercover cop who took
all the money and is now,
I mean,
his life is over and he's had to
return over and become a witness.
He's still has indictments pending.
They could throw him in jail at any point.
I mean it's, it did nothing. You know,
he was part of the Silk Road, but he,
this entire operation for which he was
arrested was all constructed by a corrupt
Da.
I guess in order to be an undercover
deh and you got to have some ability to
work in secrecy. Yeah. But when people
start working in secrecy, they can't,
a little slimy. They can go rogue. Yeah.
So you've got to keep
an eye on those people.
I wonder if they could put a percentage
on what percentage of the transactions
exchanges of the conversations on Silk
Road were about illegal activities and
what we're not, well, I've
actually seen some pie charts, um,
just cause I have access to some
of the metrics on this stuff. Um,
that show like how much was hard
drug. Like originally, you know,
the Silk Road had a very strict
ethics code. There was like,
there was no child pornography,
a lot of them silk road,
there were no counterfeit, there's no kind
of money, a lot of them silk road. Um,
it, when silkroad started, it was mostly
softer drugs. It was mostly mushrooms,
marijuana, things like that. It grew
harder as the silk road went along,
but also grew harder as
more law enforcement became
involved in the undercover
operations is Silk Road.
And there was a certain amount
of a complicity between the,
sort of the increasing law enforcement
presence on Silk Road and the severity of
the drugs and the, and that
kind of activity. So, I mean,
and that's just, I mean,
and to be fair to law enforcement,
that's often how they work anyway, right?
I mean,
if they're going to infiltrate a cartel,
they're going to start moving big
amounts of heroin or whatever. I mean,
that's how they get in.
So it's not,
but it has to be looked at in terms of
the corruption of the Silk Road itself.
Um, it didn't start with
those kinds of intentions.
What a twisted web, what a
twisted web. And unfortunately,
if people don't watch your documentary,
what are they going to get?
The mainstream news narrative,
the dark web is bad.
As bad as this guy.
Pirate Roberts is a drug dealer.
Murder for hire. That's
it. Back to you, Bob.
That's what you're going to get shady
stuff. Yeah. Anyway, here in Pasadena,
there was a Mickey mouse parade
today. Yeah. I mean, as I said,
I spent several hours when I was at south
by talking to a reporter from a major
newspaper who wanted to know what this
thing was and I talked to her for hours
and explain it in detail. And then
when she wrote her thing, it was like,
this thing is filled with criminals and
it's horrible and these people are bad
chick out around. Man, I can not
going to say what publication.
I can't say. What does it rhyme with? Uh,
dimes crimes in New York Times.
So a cup to New York to find that
article. Jamie signed it. You know,
it's, it's, that's bullshit. Nice. Why you
so nice? He want, I would be the first.
That's a problem. A personal life. That's
a problem. I pretended to be a reporter.
It's what we face.
I think that we face an inherent lack
of understanding and a fear and a
reactionary fear around these,
around technologies.
I think a lot of the story that's
being told about new technologies is
automatically criminalizing
or demonizing it.
And then when you tell stories
that sort of sit in the middle,
you're accused of being sort of
pollyannish and saying, oh, it's all good.
It's like, no, we're not saying that.
We're saying this is what's going on.
Whether you like it or not. Let's at
least examine it for what it is. Well,
how could anybody who watches your
documentary or at least listens to this
conversation on this podcast?
Not think that there's a bunch of twisted
shit going on with these undercover
agents that were obviously doing things
in implicating people and things that
they had no involvement in stealing
drugs or stealing money and blaming it on
others pretending to have a,
or how could someone not see all the gray?
Because they don't want,
I don't,
I don't think they want gray lady
doesn't want to see that gray.
That's outrageous. I don't think
they, you know, they don't want to,
but why don't they want to?
Cause they fucking suck as journalists
and they should be removed.
Replaced with independent
bloggers. Yeah. For real man. You,
you know, until you get a, uh,
Glenn Greenwald type character
who doesn't have a stake in any,
John wants to tell the whole
fucking story. What do you
get? And even, you know, he,
who knows, man, fuck yeah. This is,
this is God damn confusing to me.
Yeah. And it's like in a way of, you
have to like, in order to understand it,
you got to really educate yourself.
There's a lot of moving parts.
There really are.
I mean if you really,
and in most people like it's much easier
just to demonize something and say, oh,
it's bad and isn't this a situation
where the Silk Road is essentially the
Napster of the deep 100% and
there's going to be so already are.
Yeah, so I mean the, the,
the toothpaste is well out of the two
of these proliferating now there's just
hundreds of these drug markets and
there we will just say the names and the
highs are so say yeah, and they're
using decentralized technologies,
which means there's no, just like
exactly what happened with Napster.
Napster was a central database, so it
was easy to, to target and shutdown.
Then you had a bunch of copycats like
cassava and all these other ones that were
also central database and
they were easy to shut down.
Then bit torrent came along and it was
decentralized and what that means is
there is no central server. The, the,
the system operates
through the way it's coded.
It works through every single user
that's online. There's nobody to target.
That's the reason bit torrent
never went away. Right?
And that's what's happening in the drug
markets now as you started with these
central server markets, they get
clobbered that you find the server you,
you see as the server game over.
And they've done it over and over
again for these copycat drug markets.
But now decentralized markets
are beginning to proliferate.
You can't shut those down. It's very,
very difficult. And there's going to be,
there were already hundreds and
hundreds of them all over the world.
They are going to be thousands.
It's just gonna grow and grow and
grow because the technology works.
And because as you said,
there's a demand.
So the real issue is going to be the
delivery of these illegal substances.
Like you're having a hard address.
These things get delivered to them,
but they come through, they
come through, you know,
camouflage Fedex and ups packages and
these people know what they're doing and
they know how to game the postal
[inaudible] system. I mean,
I've talked to a bunch of dealers who
are using these online services and
they're very,
very good at working the postal system.
So like when you hear about
kids getting popped for having,
you know,
500 movies on their hard drive there,
they're distributing through
bittorrent and they get caught.
This is mostly because they were one
of the ones who were uploading them,
right? Yeah, they got tracked.
I mean you're, if you're,
if or if you're like a really dumb 13
year old and you're just pulling this
stuff down on your browser and you know
they find your Internet service provider
and they find your IP address and
they connect that to person who's,
who's broadband is sucking down and
ridiculous amounts of media every day,
then they can find you that way too.
There's ways of tracking you that way now,
but if you're buying
drugs on the internet,
on an anonymous browser and the dark
net with bitcoin and you've kept your
anonymity tight working,
it's very,
very difficult to find you unless they
literally pop you because you're the guy
who sent you stuff. The packaging
wasn't well camouflage. And they go, oh,
look at this,
let's find out where that's going.
And they trace it back to its
address and they pop you. Otherwise,
it's very hard to check sending a,
you're not showing a signal like that
technology they have now where they drive
by people's homes and they,
um,
they use a scanner and they
can tell whether or not
you're using massive amounts
of electricity. Right.
And they believe you're,
this is a grow house in the building or
the inside a plane over your house and
check for infrared. They'd been doing that
from hot farmers for, for decades. Yeah.
They broke into this guy's house
who was a retired NSA agent.
Uh,
him and his wife were growing tomatoes
in their basement and they fucking locked
him up, boots to the neck,
the whole deal. Right. And
they're like, oh, whoops. Sorry.
You know, and this guy got a taste of what
he's a part of. Right. Like, look, hey,
look at this. Yeah. Well that's,
that's the problem is you said
before when they're, you know,
my argument when people say,
well, if you have nothing to hide,
you have nothing to fear. The problem
is a lot of mistakes get made. A, B,
of course I should have privacy whether
I have something to hide or not.
It's none of your business what I'm doing,
unless to a certain degree I'm creating
a crime on a level that that should be
enforced.
But there's so many laws,
there are thousands and thousands
of laws and they get very,
very tangled and it's very easy to,
to pop somebody for almost anything.
And that's where this gets
tricky when people are,
are infiltrating your private life with
the ability to either mistakenly or
through a law that you may feel like
what happened to your friend with the
marijuana issue or what happened to the
guy who just got shot in the Carolinas
who had a broken tail light,
which isn't even against the law and
isn't really even a reason to legally stop
somebody. And he didn't have a prior
and he didn't have a warrant. You know,
that's the world we live in,
where these mistakes can happen
and where things can go very,
very wrong for people and you have to
have some protections against that.
What I was getting at was of this signal
doesn't exist like a signal where you
like passing by someone's house and you
see all this electricity being used,
all this heat being generated.
Okay, this is a grow house. Well,
if you're involved in one of these many,
now hundreds of different
services, there's no signal.
No, there's no downloads.
Like if you're a guy who's
downloading massive amounts of media,
they look at your,
your uh,
the amount of data that's going
through your computer everyday.
Look at this mother fucker right now.
He's got a terabyte, an hour. Yeah.
Banging into his house.
What's happening?
That's why law enforcement has
been trying to break tour. Um,
and what's been going on is that,
is that tor has,
there's a conflict there because tourists
is still created and maintained by a
lot of government agencies and or
utilized let's say by a lot of government
agencies who need toward and you
were to communicate with each other.
I mean Anna say a lot of different
agencies need to communicate privately,
but then on the same floor of
the law enforcement building,
you may have some guy in office a WHO's
working to help make tore stronger four
doors down.
You've got somebody in the same building
on the same floor trying to break tour.
So you have this huge conflict of interest
going on where they don't even really
know what to do with it.
And the people who want to break tour
when it break it for the reason you just
said, how else do we identify,
how do we find these people?
Even if tor is mostly being
used for good purposes,
unless we demonize the whole thing. And
that's when I get my, my hackles up.
When people just say
this whole world is bad,
they're just saying that because it's
just easier just to throw a kind of a
blanket over this entire world and go,
well now we know where all
the bad people are there.
Everybody who are using tour,
which is like saying anybody
who's got a bathroom door is bad.
It's so irresponsible to demonize the
entire Silk Road like that and demonize
the entire movement without looking
at the nuances. We're looking at the,
the unbelievable complexity involved
in freedom and digital freedom and
exchanging information online.
And even the complexities involved
in the drug war. I mean the, the,
the idea that just because it's a law
that you shouldn't examine that law very
closely and using your own personal
morals and ethics, apply them to that law.
And tell me whether or not
this law has just, yeah,
cause I guarantee you most intelligent
people will not agree with it.
Even Republicans completely. Yeah. It's a
nonpartisan issue. It really is. It isn't.
People go, oh they're just crazy
libertarian. And I'm like, no they're not.
They really aren't. It's all stripes.
I mean it's every different po,
every kind of political configuration
as is involved in this movement on some
level or another cause who doesn't
want privacy? This, this documentary?
Where can people see it and
when can people see it? Um,
while we're touring festivals
right now all over it,
we just did south by and we're doing
festivals. So if you go to a deep web,
the movie.com, you can see which
festivals we're coming up on.
But the movies is going to be on epix.
Uh, the epics network on premium cable,
regular cable, right. So regular cable.
So it will be on epics on May 31st.
Um, you can see it there and then it will
be out all over after that. And Netflix,
Amazon, iTunes everywhere. And
we'll at Gen Norton who is, uh,
our buddy, we'll be here on Wednesday
also has a special coming out on epic,
so fucking go epics, epics is
awesome. Um, was there anything, this,
it seems like to put a such an intense
and complex issue into a 90 minute piece,
it seems like it'd be really hard to edit.
Yeah.
It was really challenging and download.
It was challenging too.
You have to really pick your battles,
you know,
and also you have to decide what is
it most important for the audience to
understand.
That's the way I come at them.
It's like their very core
issues that matter here.
You don't need to understand
how bitcoin works.
how tor works, what it needs.
You need to understand.
Thankfully the these issues to me are
not about technology. There are about,
they're about human nature and community.
So I always stressed the sort of
human side. What is the motivation?
Why did they start this thing? Who
are they? What are their ideals?
What kind of community do they want
to create and that you can convey to
somebody in 90 minutes.
Did you have a chance to talk to this
dude that's in solitary and did you have,
what's his name again? Russell brick.
I have exclusive access to that family.
The Mom, the dad, their defense
attorney. I had access to Ross,
but he's behind bars and a federal trial.
He couldn't be interviewed
by me or 60 minutes.
I was doing interviews with him via his,
his parents.
So they would give him questions, like
he's very aware of the film. He would,
they would give him questions, uh,
and then he would answer them for me,
um, in written form and, uh,
you know, and in some cases,
you know, that that was
it. Um, but, uh, uh,
so I was able to communicate with him
that way and sort of get, you know,
the information that I needed to,
but what,
what is the rationale for not allowing him
to talk? I mean, he's, he's, uh, you know,
it was a big federal case and they,
they, they kept them under lock and key,
but isn't that insane? It is pretty,
it's cool. It was chilling. Yeah.
I was expecting to go talk
to him, like, you know,
at a table and vis visitation
or something that, none of that,
but then that's really disturbing to
me because you're not talking about a
murderer. Yeah. You're not talking about
a guy who was even contemplating martyr.
He not talking about a guy
who stole a ton of money.
You're not talking about a guy wrecked
the government who was planning an Archi
wanted to blow up the federal courthouse.
You're not talking about that. No.
But the way that,
you know,
the way the prosecution looks at him
to be fair is as all those things they
believe that they believe that Ross
intended tab people kill whether those
murders happened or not.
They believe that he made a lot of money
off of the Silk Road via bitcoin. Um,
they believe that,
you know,
this sort of antigovernment libertarian
ethos that they believe he espoused to
was very anarchistic and dangerous.
So, you know, they did view him as a,
as a major threat.
That's a slippery slope to say that an
anti government libertarian ethos is
dangerous because why?
There's a lot of fucking people you're
going to have to lock up with that.
I know.
How about Rand Paul and this
mother fuckers running for
president and that's his
main platform. I know. Good
luck with all that. You know,
the guy running for government office,
the top government office has a dad who's
pretty goddamn libertarian for being a
Rep Republican. Yeah, yeah. No, it's true.
And, and I, you know, I maintained that,
that whatever the truth ends up being,
um,
and I really do hope we categorically get
to the bottom of that at some point in
a way, you know, and not to write
him off at all, but in a way,
regardless of Russell Ulbricht
I think that, you know, the,
the idea of these anonymous
marketplaces on the Internet with,
with these communities,
that is the greatest threat.
I think that's what poses
the greatest threat. Well,
I think the Internet itself is,
is the greatest threat to the
system that we have in place.
And it's the biggest exposer of the shell
game of the two party system as well.
Yeah. It's not, it's not viable.
And because it's not viable,
the data just keeps getting examined
and examined exam by so many people and
they keep coming to the same conclusion.
This is a fucking shell game. Yeah.
Give the same corporations that are
there supporting the same people.
They get into office,
they never do what they said they were
going to do and they do a bunch of shit
that you would never want them to do.
Yeah.
So it's the same thing
over and over again.
And I think that ultimately
that's going to be their demise.
Their demise is going to be their
unwillingness to accept the new digital
reality. Yeah. That they're
exposed. Everything is exposed.
It means we're exposed to, but it
doesn't mean every that the upside is,
everything is, well we're not doing
anything. You're making documentaries.
I'm telling jokes,
but this,
this guy is losing a giant chunk of his
life and he's in been in jail for a year
and a half now. Yeah. Well he may
lose his and he may get life mean.
We'll know in mid May. I mean he may get
life fucking Christ and if he gets live,
no one can talk to him.
No. Like Chelsea Manning,
the artist formerly known as Bradley
Manning now has a Twitter. Yeah,
but how does she do that?
Yeah, it was actually what,
cause I started following her a couple
of days ago. I'm not until you can't,
there are certain people who do get like
Barrett Brown, um, had access to email.
He had it recently revoked so they will
claim why did he get it revoked? Oh,
they claimed that he was talking
to a journalist and it's all,
they shouldn't have revoked
it and my opinion, but um,
he hasn't been treated fairly from the
beginning, but that's another documentary.
Right. Um, but uh, uh,
it's in Ross's case,
um, it's very difficult to
interview people under that, uh,
who were sort of convicted
of those kinds of chargers.
They often get sent to pretty
Max oriented facilities. Um,
but I'm still working on it. I'm still
hoping to get an interview with him.
It's basically a civilized form.
A Siberian
gulags. Yeah. I mean it's like you just
locking you away and throw in the key.
They just not throwing away the key and
they're locking you away and you can't
talk to anybody. You're,
you're in solitary confinement,
which makes people go fucking
crazy. Certainly does. Yeah. I mean,
that's what they did with
Chelsea manning as well. Naked,
no clothes locked in solitary for years.
Tell me that won't make you nuts.
It will,
it,
it removes so much of what you
are as a human being completely.
All your personal freedom is gone
and this is legal and this is morally
acceptable. And this is, this is a
part of the law. I mean that's insane.
That's fucking insane that they can
do that to this guy. So when is his,
when did they get to see whether or
not there'll be able to appeal? Well,
appeals often can take about a year,
um,
the process of sort of dealing
with the apple at court.
So he's going to get sent I believe.
And again, you know, they may change,
but currently it's going to be sentenced
on May 15th. Um, and that's pretty cool.
It's around the corner.
And then an appeal would occur sometime
hopefully this year or at some point
early next year. Well,
that'll least, um, the,
we'll give some publicity to the
premiere of your documentary,
which is May 31st May 31st.
So that'll be a couple of weeks out so
that I'm sure the buzz will still be
bound by. That really disturbs
me, man. I mean it really,
it gets me creeped out. It, it
disturbs me in a very personal level.
Just the idea that you could take some
young person and do that to them and not
let him speak. That's the key. Was
he ever able to speak on his behalf?
Did he get a statement or
anything? No, you have to,
if you have to be very careful about
testifying to, you know, it's a,
it's a very tricky position to
put yourself in. So, um, you know,
it'd be interesting to see what
happens with the appeal process.
Are they hopeful? They have
to be? What else can, what
else can you be but hopeful.
But legal analysts, when they look
at it from an objective standpoint,
people that don't have a vested
interest in success or fail,
they say that it's a very, they have a
very steep hill to climb to get anywhere.
Fuck yeah.
There's,
how much did this bug you when
you were doing this? I mean this,
it got pretty depressing. I mean, there
was a point I stayed pretty neutral. Um,
and again, as I say, I don't know the
whole truth, I just am very eager to,
to either find out or to
not make proclamations about
things that I don't think
I've been proven, which doesn't seem
to be stopping anybody else. But, um,
there was a point when I was
sitting in the federal trial and,
and just watching them get blocked and
blocked and blocked and in everyone in
that room just wanted to hear at
least something from the other side.
And you know, at the point at which
I suddenly realized that was it,
the trial was over. It was very,
I mean, I, I said to, to Ross,
his mom, you know, later that day I
was like, I don't know how, I mean,
I've always wondered how you've
survived the last year, but like,
I barely made it through
this week and it's
not my son in jail.
And even if he's guilty of everything and
just on a pure emotional level just to
watch, you know, the machinery and
the way that it works. And, and, uh,
it was just very, it's very, very sad.
I mean, the whole, the whole case is, I,
I find extremely sad.
Whatever the truth turns out to be,
just on a basic human level,
it was a pretty emotional experience.
And is there any movement whatsoever to
try to reform this kind of railroading
of people? I mean, to be honest with you,
a few things are going on as you know,
that it's mostly state level, mandatory
minimums are starting to get reduced.
I mean,
the world,
the world is moving slowly
towards w beyond this prohibition.
Right.
And I think that we're getting there and
I think that the Internet has actually
been really helpful in sort of creating
grassroots movement that then attack
things that are, you know, a Byzantine,
like the gay marriage laws or the
marijuana laws or these things that are
beginning to shift in our culture.
And I think that the net is
absolutely a power there. Um,
but there's a very big battle,
you know, against that tide.
Um, and that's largely at
the federal level. And, um,
and so I think we have a long way
to go before we're having, um,
conversations that are sane and balanced
and nuanced about any of those stuff,
which very black and white,
you go out into the world and you say
things about this world that aren't
completely party line and you're just
branded as being a tin foil hat wearing
crackpot. And is that how you've been
branded? No, I mean not. I think, well a,
the movie hasn't come out yet,
but you know,
I sort of comically caught
some heat on downloaded as,
I don't think I talked enough about piracy
for some people's liking on download.
Yeah. That was the Napster movie that I
made. And I think that people, you know,
they expected to have a much more
about like how bad it was to pull down
Metallica. And I was just with not
that interested in that stuff. Um,
and I think that that if you don't
follow the sort of, you know,
standard narrative, um, you take some
heat. I don't care. I like you said,
I'm the guy who makes documentaries.
I have, I'm not going to jail.
I'm not selling anything on the
unit. You know what I mean? I'm, I'm,
I'm objectively removed from that world.
But of course you take heat because
people get really pissed off at the idea
that you're not just saying, you
know, hiding bad piracy, bad drugs,
bad, you know, it says you have
to just take that party line.
Like that reporter I talked to
and it's just, it's disappointing.
But that's the prevailing narrative and
it's not just the narrative from the
right. You get that from the
left, you get it from the center.
Everyone just sort of marches in line.
Yeah.
They've watched dragnet when they were
kids and this idea that is good and evil
and good guys and bad guys
just catch the bad guys.
This is a freedom issue and in my opinion,
if you look at the worst
thing that happened,
people distributed drugs to each
other that wanted those drugs.
That's the worst thing that happened.
Obviously if they're,
the murders were faked and
it's quite possible, in fact,
likely that no one ever wanted
anybody murdered in the first place.
This guy just was setting the whole thing
to cover up the fact that he stole all
this money. It's like, where's the crime?
Where's the crime that you're protecting
the world from that you've got this
fucking guy locked up in jail and is a
part of the reason why they're able to
keep him in solitary? The murder for hire.
Yeah. He's having to be clear. He was,
he's no longer in solitary.
He wasn't set when they first caught him,
and it's not uncommon, it's called
the shoe he was put into the shoe,
which is a solitary confinement.
It's a nasty sort of environment to be,
and he was in solitary for six weeks.
He has not been in solitary for the
bulk of his confinement. Oh, I was kids,
not like Chelsea manning in that way.
He's been in a holding a prison
in Brooklyn for over a year.
He did,
uh,
some solitary and stay in Oakland and
then he did some solitary in New York.
He's been primarily part of the regular
prison system and in the regular prison
prison system. What type of security
does or they have because it's intense.
It's intense, but z locked up with
murderers or is he? Yeah, he's in,
he's in the general these in the general
population far he's done. I mean,
you know, again, you know, not
to exonerate him, but he's,
he's been a pretty interesting inmate.
He's been teaching like physics
and Yoga and presenting,
but teaching math and helping the guys
with the GDS like you know, again,
this is just who he is. He, he may have
done horrible other things that we,
you know, we'll learn about
more detail at some point, but,
but what we know about what
he has exactly. He seems
like a pretty, God damn cool.
He's an interesting guy. Yeah. That's just
drives me nuts man. How do you, when you,
when you were done with this,
when you did the final edit and you
a step back and you, you, you know,
you're done. Now it's just about
talking it about it, promoting it.
And what does this leave you feeling when
you make a documentary about something
like this? You go through
withdrawal. You know, I'm,
I'm actually through it now cause
I've been done for a minute, but, um,
you go through a little withdrawal
because it's, it, I was, I was living,
eating and sleeping this world for
almost two years and, and as you know,
I was dealing with a lot of people on
all sides, on the law enforcement side,
on the cyber side, the whole,
his family, the whole thing.
You got to go through withdrawal.
But pardon me? And I said this,
I was very blunt with Lynn, his mom, um,
and I like being able to talk about it.
So that's kind of the easy part cause
that's kind of the why you do it part.
Right. Um, but I said to
Lynn, I was like, you know, I,
I really am glad I'm done. You
know, it's like I get to gut,
you don't get to go home.
You know,
I got a family and kids and like I get
to go home and I'm done and it's a very,
I really,
you know,
you'd go outside and you smell the air
and you get in your car and you go about
your day and you take your kids to school.
And I think, you know, I just, I don't,
I am done with that world.
Well that's this really scary part about
the threat of keeping in line is that
they can remove that from you.
They can take that right away from you
to just drive. Right now he can go,
go get a burrito. I want to drive down
the street to the Mexican restaurant.
I want to, you know, do this. I want to
go to big bear and just take a day off.
You can't do that. None of that. None
of those are options anymore. Yeah.
And even if you're, even if you're
the family or whoever, you know,
your life is shattered too.
I mean,
Lynn doesn't get to go home and have
a regular life anymore now on her son.
Her baby is always going to
be in a cage somewhere. Yeah.
Was there any sympathy from people that
you talk to even off the record in law
enforcement that, yeah. Oh,
sure. Yeah, absolutely. Um,
I mean a lot of the law enforcement people
that I spoke to and some of whom are
in the movie, we're really the same
thing I went through with Nafta,
with the labels. It's like Tim, like
again, to me it's not black and white.
It's not good guys and bad guys.
Most of the label guys you had talked
to were really clear eyed and smart and
had a really good view of like,
here's where we screwed up.
Here's where we taking too much money.
Here's where this happened,
here's what the technology fucked us,
whatever it was on law enforcement.
Most of the law enforcement guys I talked
to don't agree with this notion that
there should be no encryption. They're
like, of course. It's like, yes,
it's going to make our job harder. But
yes, you have a right to privacy. No,
we should not have warrantless
search and seizure. That makes,
that makes no sense. And
you know the, so there is,
there's a lot of people
caught up in the grades.
There was another guy I
spoke to in the movie,
a named Neil Franklin who is the
director of an organization called law
enforcement against prohibition.
And Neil was a homicide major on the
streets of Baltimore for 20 years and saw
everything there was to see about the
drug wars ravages and now his life,
his work is about getting rid of
the drug war from the officer side,
from the Dea, FBI, Dea side.
So I just feel like in the future it's
going to be looked back the same way
prohibition was,
it's just going to be looked back at
like some ridiculous part of our history
that we should have been intelligent
enough to realize it was a foolhardy
pursuit. And Yeah, we've abandoned that.
Yeah, no, there's fucking bars everywhere.
I mean you just drive down the street.
Everywhere you go,
you can buy booze and those, those
bars have parking lots. Yeah.
And a boot pay taxes go to them
so it supports the economy.
The whole thing is bizarre.
It's is,
it's such a weird thing when you look at
our culture and you look at these just
glaring flaws and how we operate and the
justice system in this respect is one
of those glaring flaws. When you tell
me about that trial, it makes me sick.
Like I physically feel sick. Yeah. It
was sick making. It really was. He just,
it was kind of dizzying.
You just thought really it was like being
in a Kafka novel. You're like, really?
That's it? That's it. We
go home. It makes no sense.
It almost makes sense when you hear
about that judge and penalty Pennsylvania
that was sensing those kids for profit.
Like you kind of get it now. Yeah. I go,
well, if you guys are just used to doing
this and that becomes just another step
removed from the normal
operating procedure. Like, Hey,
what's the big deal? Yeah,
I need a pool. You know,
ah, what's the big deal?
I'd like to go on vacation and
fuck some kid's life up. Yeah.
And there's also the general
aspect of like, we need, you know,
to punish the drug war. We need
to do it in a big way. We need to,
we need to do it in a public way.
You know,
we need to do it with maximum
punishment where the, you know,
extreme prejudice as it were.
So there's that.
You watched that machinery
just at work too.
They get to go back in front
of the teak DV cameras and go,
we have another big drug war trophy
and this dread pirate Roberts.
He started,
whether it's this Guy Ross or not,
he started talking because there's another
competing sort of deep web service.
Yeah. Well the, at back at the time
there was, um, there was another,
there was one called Atlantis
that had shown up that was used.
Now there's tons of them, but this was
in the early days. And you know, the,
the journalist from wire where
the journalist from wired,
Andy Greenberg who sort of
the main kind of, you know,
he's our every man in the film who
takes us through this world. Um,
he was the only the first person to
interview really the only person to
interview dread pirate Roberts.
And that's how he got the
interview was just by saying, look,
I'll cover these other guys.
And Dread Pirate Roberts knew that the
silkroad needed more exposure in order to
get more customers. So he talked.
Wow. And so no one from Atlanta was,
Eric got popped. Atlanta has got
complete, like Atlanta disappeared.
Atlanta Scott popped
in evaporated ages ago.
So the government came in and full
training, we don't know, just to just,
it just disappeared. Like a lot of what
happens with a lot of these services is,
is they'll just take all of the,
they'll extort people, they'll,
they'll collect all their money and then
they'll, they'll just hightail it. Oh,
so the guys who own the
service can be shady. Yeah. Oh,
completely think, yeah, that,
that happens, that it just happened
with one called evolution recently.
And it happened with another one called
sheet market and it happens from time to
time. I'm confused where,
how are they getting money?
It's what you do is you set up an
account and get bitcoin when you can use
bitcoin, you know overstock.com takes
Bitcoin, you can use bitcoin like paypal.
Sure. Um, and you set up an account,
then you go to that site through tour,
through some other way into the dark net.
You set up a username and an account
just like you do with Ebay, right?
And now you have a bitcoin account and
you've got your account on this site just
like you've Ebay.
So it's just like using paypal to
pay to pay for your Ebay purchases.
You're using bitcoin to pay for your
online services and they have access
somehow or another to your bitcoin.
Because bitcoin is,
is anonymous in the sense that
you can set up a bitcoin address,
but all they're getting is the code
for your bitcoin. And it gives removed.
Like there's ways to remove it from you
even further. It was called tumbling,
but basically you,
you pay using this bitcoin code,
they get that transaction,
they send you the drugs via an
oftentimes now it works. There's,
they don't even know who you are,
like it's done through a third party
to separate you from the course site.
So there's ways of keeping it,
you know,
they basically was like an
escrow account or sending,
there's ways of of key creating
barriers between you and them.
So somehow or another,
the people that own this site are able
to access the people who have membership
on the site, their bitcoin wallet.
Exactly. So they just steal from them? No,
it doesn't work that way. They don't
have access to their bitcoin wallet.
What they're doing is,
let's say we're buying,
let's say we're buying
lots of stuff on your site.
All of these different people
are buying stuff on your site.
You're the middleman, right? Because
you're connecting buyer to seller. Right.
You give me money for me,
just like Amazon that I'm
supposed to give to the seller.
I wait until that money collects,
collects, collects, collects,
and then I just close up shop. I just cut
both of you guys off. Buyer and seller.
Bye. I've got all the cash that's
sitting here in the middle.
So you're the third party middle man
that's supposed to hand it over. Exam one,
handed it over, you just grab
it and run first I shut down.
They shut the whole thing down. And so
is there a delay in transactional runs?
Exactly. Yeah. Cause you're taking a fee.
So there's, there's that whole space.
So people are creating decentralized
systems now that are not about that,
but don't even have fee based
structures where that won't be possible.
We're basically all I've done,
it's more like bit torn is all
I've done is created the service.
I put it out in the world, it's
decentralized. There is no middleman,
the bitcoins or travels from one
area through directly to that buyer.
There was nobody in the middle
that can take the money and run.
And that's the direction
it's currently going in.
So these people that did it like
for Atlantis or these other organs,
do they ever get caught or does everybody
have to shut up because they were
talking about illegal drugs. But they get,
most of them don't get caught. I mean,
the interesting thing is there's
a lot of, you know, full blown,
unsurprisingly full on
cyber criminals out there.
Like these DEA agents that got caught.
They were actually,
or this singular DEA agent singular
see secret service guy. You know,
they were very sophisticated.
They were more sophisticated than some
of the guys who created these sites.
They knew how to use bitcoin.
They were creating,
they were actually
creating bitcoin exchanges.
They were very technologically together.
So you have people like that, um,
on the cyber side as well,
who were like hackers and really know
how to manipulate these technologies.
They've been in the game a long time.
And they'll create fictitious users.
They'll create markets, they'll buy their
time. Then they'll steal people's money.
It's the wild west.
Wow.
So now the way they're doing it is
how decentralized and centralized.
Yeah. So what that is, is he's basically,
there is no central point of control.
There's no central servers.
So there is no guy in the middle who's
whole means there's no profit either.
There's no one taking a fee.
It's really a gala Terrian.
There's one technology that's on
the rise now called open bazaar.
And this is not,
was not created for drug use.
There may be drugs and end up getting cell
in a bizarre, bizarre, bizarre, bizarre,
bizarre. And Open bazaar is you can
buy shoes that you could buy whatever,
but it's decentralized.
There's no central point of control.
So it's not a profit
based entity in that way.
Eventually if they wanted to create like
some kind of like what bit torrent is
trying to do. Yeah. If they wanted to
create some kind of advertising model or,
or legitimize himself and other ways,
there's ways to eventually create profit.
So, and they're also saying that not
only are people using this for drugs,
but they're also using this for illegal
firearms and the distribution of illegal
firearm. That's really uncommon. The,
it's really hard to sell drugs
on the dark on the dark net.
People have tried ones. Y'All
guns, I'm sorry. Um, it's,
it's very difficult given the way.
There's a number of issues,
but given the difficulty of moving,
moving drugs or guns around through the
postal system is extremely difficult.
The one thing that did happen,
I'm on the Internet,
is what Cody Wilson was doing and
he created the three d printed gun,
which you may have heard
of Cody's in my movie. And,
and Cody again is coming
from a purely perspective.
He is just trying to say,
look,
technology is allowing people
to do whatever they want,
screw your laws. Right.
So that's the way that, that some
of that stuff has happened online,
but the way Cody's technologies work
is you're able to create one piece of a
weapon that you could sort of build
the rest of the weapon around. Um,
so that's been a big thorn in
people's sides as well. Yeah.
He, what he's done is
very interesting. Um,
because his plans or the,
whatever it is for the three d gun,
you could download hundreds of thousands
of people have downloaded this and
traded it back and forth. Yeah.
And if you have a three d printer,
all you have to do is
enter that information in.
And it can build you this
gun. Yeah. I mean you need a
Miller. You need like some,
he's the,
the next wave of his technology was
actually selling the milling machine that
would allow it to be metal.
Um, so it's, it's definitely,
he's a very provocative guy.
Well,
it seems like that's kind of where we're
going as human beings with technology
in this is not stores where you
have to go and pick something up,
but you just print it. You just make
it. Yeah. That seems to happen. Yeah.
Even with food. Yeah. You can
three d print food. Whoa. Yeah.
You're getting ingredients and
you can literally make food,
like what kind of food?
All kinds of stuff.
And it just going to get more
advanced all the time. I mean,
there's organic elements to this.
It's not just like plastic stuff.
So it's so strange. Yeah. I remember
when I was talking to Shawn Fanning,
the guy who created an APP store, and I
was talking to Sean about 10 years ago,
this is a 10 years ago. I was like,
okay, what's the next big thing?
It was like three d printing.
He goes,
people have no idea how much that's going
to change our culture once it really
gets going. It seems like it is. It seems
like you, when you buy a new iPhone,
you're gonna, you're gonna download
the directions for the iPhone.
They don't even have to do that. Yeah.
You just stick the code and your,
it'll just make it, you know,
Jesus Christ. It seems like the,
the real issue will be raw materials then
at that. I think the world is really,
I mean that's the thing
I maintain is that,
that's why I get so frustrated by how
slow we're dragging our feet with these
changes. It's like you said it
earlier, the real changes are coming.
Like the things that are really going
to shift into high gear over the next 10
2030 years with driverless cars and
more advanced bio technology. I mean,
things are really going to change.
They're so weird because we're,
we're in the middle of it.
I think it's so difficult to gain a really
objective perspective while you were
in the middle of it.
Yeah,
because everyone's used to just looking
at their phone and checking their text
messages, but since 30 years
ago, that wasn't even a dream.
Now completely, their computer in your
hand was unheard of. It's all weird. Yeah.
It's all weird and it's shifting,
but what it is to be a person is going
to be very different. It is. Yeah, it is.
I just wonder how they're going
to look back on things like this,
like this silk road thing
or Napster. Well, you've,
you've really kind of captured with both
of these documentaries with downloaded
in with his deep web documentary,
you really kind of captured two
very pivotal blips culturally.
Yeah, that's been my interest is
like where's the gray? Where are the,
where are the uneasy where you know,
what's not the low hanging fruit,
like that's what's been interest.
That's what I've been,
that's been my agenda in and going
after these stories is like what are,
what doesn't have easy answers?
Has it been really frustrating though?
Like especially like this New York Times
person that you don't want to name,
we'll find her or him,
whoever they are.
You said it was her too late.
I just think that it's,
if I was me I would be going crazy.
I mean it would just keep me up at night.
I would be like,
how is it that someone could
not understand that this
is so complex that this
is, this is not just one
issue of a law being broken.
This is not one issue of an underground
marketplace of nefarious people doing
dastardly deeds.
This is an aspect of
human cultural evolution.
Yeah, it is. It's a little frustrating,
but I, you know, I also, like I said,
a lot of the people that I interview
are more sensible than sometimes what
the prevailing narrative is. You know,
you do encounter people that are
just really have their, their,
their heads planted in the sand that
just don't want to think about things
differently than the
way they perceive them.
I actually encountered that a lot with
the Napster story or people who are just
adamantly, no, it was only about stealing.
No is not about something other
than piracy and they just could not,
could not see it. And I think that
we're still there with the Napster,
which I think people still just cannot
get their heads around what actually
happened. But you know,
I still think it's,
there's value in just telling the stories
and shining a light on them and trying
to provide some nuance.
And you know,
when I tour around with the festivals
and we have these great Q and A's and
people are really, they either know more
about it than I do or they know less,
or there's somewhere in the
middle and conversation start.
And I think that's really, that's
helpful on some level. Well,
it's a generational issue as well.
I mean,
if you're talking to people that are in
their 50s they're going to be less than
two and then people in their
forties who are less than two,
unless they're like really
actively pursuing it,
but the kids in our twenties
they're almost all in tuned to,
at least the ones that are smart
aren't obsessed with Justin Bieber.
They're tuned in to what's going on here.
Yeah.
They literally are a part of a generation
that will go down as being the first
generation that grew up entirely
with the Internet. Yeah.
And these are people who are
utilizing these technologies.
It's such a fundamental level that they
don't think that that's the whole thing
with the Napster thing and I,
and it certainly works in the
Silk Road case to some degree,
is these people did not view
themselves as criminals. That was the,
that was the pushback.
And it happened to me.
I was using Napster and suddenly we were
all being branded as pirates and I kind
of was like, wait a minute, I know
I'm not a pirate. So I was like,
I know I'm not a criminal.
Legally you were right. Exactly.
But I'm being branded as one and I did
not respond well to that. I thought, Whoa,
well, you know like don't,
don't leap to calling me that.
And then your branding an entire
generation, like your new consumers,
you're branding them as criminals.
Like how is that going to help you
or your cause in the end? Well,
that was the Lars Earl rich thing
where it was everybody. I mean,
it really was really because he was
a really wealthy guy and the head of,
he stuck his neck out.
I mean,
the thing about Lars and actually have
sympathy for Lars, I feel like with Lars,
what happened with large as he was
like, you know, he had his song, um,
you know, put out on Napster before
they'd finished it. It was, I disappear.
And then it was, it got put on k rock.
So he's like an artist and he's like,
Oh God, this version with the crappy
drum track is on fucking k rock. Oh Man.
His head exploded. Right. And that's,
that was his reaction was like the
pure artists, like holy shit reaction,
which I as an artist, I get
that. And then he was like,
we got to lead a charge
against these guys.
And he ran out and he looked back
and nobody else was at his back.
Nobody like all the other
artists were like, yeah,
none of them had the balls to give
him some credit to come out and say,
wait a minute, we need to have
better discussions about this.
So they totally stuck his ass out
in the forefront and then they ran.
Well the fans felt like you greedy.
Fuck right.
Like you're a multimillionaire and you're
complaining that you're going to lose
some money off of this. Right. And they
just felt betrayed. Yeah, I think they,
I think they did and I felt for him to
the degree that as an artist I felt like
his reaction, whatever you want to say
about the politics of it, his initial gut,
oh my God, reaction is would have
been my, you know what I mean?
When you make something and it's in
rough cut form or it's not, you know,
the idea that like that's out there. Like
someone stuck in a movie theater. Okay.
Rock and make sure that's like you lose
sleep on that kind of stuff at night.
Yeah.
Comics have this with Youtube,
with bits like you're working on a new
bit and someone shows up at a comedy club
and records you when you're on stage and
then releases it on youtube and then it
gets downloaded by 100,000 people.
Like that bit's sucks. It's not,
that bit's a baby. You know, you
can't, it's not done yet. Yeah. When I,
when I'm done, I'll put it on a fucking
DVD. I'll put it on a comedy special.
Right. And the, the truth though
is as I think you've been saying,
is that it isn't to brand them.
It's like you have,
it's incumbent upon us to
change the way we do business.
Like we can't say you can't, we can't
just wag our finger at them and say,
you stop doing that. Of course
they're going to do it. Right.
It's this amazing new technology
that that's, you know,
communal and fast and democratized and
they're not going to stop doing it.
We have to change. Yeah. It's,
it's going to be very weird when
it hits whatever the next stage is,
whatever the next stage
is. Cause I'm, I'm,
I'm imagining with very little
technological expertise of course.
Well how about zero? Half of none.
I've just, I'm a user. Come on.
You had a website in [inaudible]
98 with a message board. That's,
that's way farther along than most people.
I hired somebody, I don't even know.
Still you had the cheese? Yeah.
You had the foresight to do it.
That's still different. Well maybe.
Okay. But my point being you,
if you try to imagine what
the next stage is going to be,
I would imagine that it would be
something virtual and I'm, I'm
imagining that what we're looking at
now when you're looking at a website,
even when you're looking at message
boards and you're looking at Twitter,
Facebook,
social media is akin to those,
those boards that existed back in the
day before there was any like real,
like there was a wet, yeah, we're
talking about 93 yeah. Before the,
what would those things called?
Like beat bulletin boards that
you use net and the bbs era. Yeah.
You'd have to log on.
It would take you an hour and he'd go
there and check to see if anybody left
anything there and then you'd
have to screw off for a while.
And those are looked at as a joke
now when you can get, you know,
New York Times will give you a instant
messages on your phone and let you know
when there's alerts when
anything's happening. Yeah.
You check Twitter anytime anything's
going down. Like anytime someone dies or,
and I find out about it on Twitter
before I ever see it on the news.
It seems like it's almost instantaneous,
but even more so than that,
things like youtube, youtube is very
two dimensional. We look at it, it's,
it's awesome. You could watch
stuff on it, you know, or you know,
a even HBO go.
Any of these things where you're seeing
things online, it's very two dimensional.
I think virtual is going
to be the next step.
Oculus rift type technology and the
way that's progressing right now is,
is kind of frightening. It's really
getting unbelievably realistic. It is.
Yeah. Yeah. It's getting super advanced
and the fluidity, the ability to use it,
like how that stuff can get
projected and how that's going to,
I mean things are gonna change across
the board in a lot of ways and like
driverless cars, certain things that
are going to cause huge changes are,
are literally around the corner.
I mean that's, we're just only,
we're years away from driverless cars,
not like decades away from driverless car.
It's a very exciting time,
but it's also a very woo Jesus don't know,
challenging time. I mean that's
the reason I make these stories.
It's not because I think, oh,
this is so awesome. You know?
I just want to like pick up my camera and
shoot all this awesome stuff. You know?
It is challenging.
It's challenging morally,
ethically it's challenging on
all of these levels. It is.
That's part of why I think we need to
be having conversations about this stuff
that they were more sane.
Yeah. I couldn't agree more.
I also think that as as a a giant
super organism, the human race,
which w w what we really are really
think about it were some sort of a giant
super organism.
The organism that works together to
create these things and fund these things
and push things forward.
We were kind of just moving along,
not considering the implications
of what we're doing,
but just continuing along the same path.
Like if you can't,
if you step back and say, you know what
is virtual reality is just too fucked up,
we should really stop and
consider it. Well, guess what?
Sony's going to come along and they're
going to just take the fucking rug out
from under you and they're going to
have a better thing that you're making
Spiderman reboots forever
on your virtual reality.
You'll never be able to
stop them. Well, porn,
which is at the forefront of all
technology, that that pushes,
that pushed html five or flash and
paypal everything. Yeah, yeah. Well,
what they're going to do with that
virtual reality stuff is going to be very,
very, very bizarre right now. And
you're going to have what you've seen,
you have a problem with people being
addicted to porn now. I mean, yeah.
No one was addicted to
literature porn. Right. You know,
back when they look at my
vera type on my stereo graph,
when they had those books that
people are write by hand. Yeah.
Nobody was addicted to beating
off to those things. I mean, God,
how many of them even were
there. Yeah. And then the
printing press came along. Oh,
maybe things a little bit
more interesting. Yeah. And
then magazines came along.
Whoa. Girly magazines that used to
have to get stuck under your bed. Yeah.
He used to hide them and shit and
squirrel them away. Like nuts. I know.
And then it became VHS tapes.
Whoa.
And then DVDs Wa and then
online. Oh. And then it became,
you could get it on your phone
when I phones came along. Yeah.
The screen's got bigger. It was very nice
of them. Yeah. It's going to get very,
very strange.
Yeah.
There's going to come some sort of a
neural interface inside of our lifetime
where you're going to be able to enter
into worlds that have been created that
seem indistinguishable from the world
that we're currently in. Right? Yeah.
There's no doubt. There's no
doubt that, I mean that's I,
that's within our lifetime
and when that does happen,
they look back on things like the Silk
Road was controversies can seem so
preposterous. So primitive. Yeah.
I mean I think that the idea,
I think online drug markets
are going to be ubiquitous.
They and they may very likely be the
thing that takes major cartels down in the
long run.
Well,
I was listening to this radio lab
podcast where they were talking about the
placebo effect.
I think that might be the name of
the podcast for anyone is interested.
I think it's just called placebo.
But they were talking about the,
the various times where placebo
effect has worked and has not worked.
And one of the things that they said that
was so incredible is that like you're
the reason why drugs work,
that every drug that works on the human
mind works because there is a receptor,
there's a biological
receptor in the brain,
so essentially the brain
produces all of these effects,
just not reliably. Opioid
effects, opiate effects,
cannabis affects all
these different drugs.
We know the brain produces various
chemicals, dopamine, Serotonin,
psychedelic chemicals.
Your brain produces all of these things.
If they can figure out how to
do with no drugs, something,
some virtual things,
something,
some chip that just stimulates those
aspects of your brain and produces those
feelings of euphoria, love, hate, loss,
sadness,
and does so inside of a virtual world.
I mean they're going to take you on a
real live drug ride and no drugs would be
involved.
You mean then?
Then what do you do with your drug war
when all the drugs are produced by the
mind, you're going to stop people from
producing and dodginess chemicals that the
brain naturally produces me.
You're already doing that with movies.
What do you think the adrenaline effect
you get from a crazy thriller is, right?
Why are people into horror movies? It's
not because they have no effect on you.
They're producing drugs. When you
watched Jason, he's coming up behind,
somebody got the fucking
machete. Oh, you're scared.
You're scared of those movies.
That's a drug.
They're giving you drugs.
It's just they're making you
produce it with your own mind. Yeah.
It's going to happen in a
very bizarre way. It is.
I think that is going to have an
impact. And I think that, you know,
the other issue that I think is
important is just like, you know,
for those people that do need help there,
that needs to be decriminalized
to a degree where they
can actually get the help
in a way that isn't stigmatized or they're
not just felonies ISED immediately.
So that's an issue as well at any
needs to get addressed. Oh, 100%.
And also the reason why people
get addicted in the first place.
Just the trauma that people experience
as young children that causes these
receptors to open up these
causes, these drug addiction, um,
processes to take place.
And you talk to people that have counseled
folks that have massive drug problems
and then understand where,
how these genes get addressed
and it's all very, very complex.
And who gets addicted and
who doesn't get addicted.
A lot of that has to do with your
response to childhood trauma.
That's hard for people to relate to.
That's hard for people to understand.
Genetics and the genetic disease component
and like there's no way to have a
really thorough conversation about
this stuff if it's just criminalized.
You can't just drag net it.
Yeah. Lock 'em up. Yeah.
Black on Deno you can't do that.
It's just like we have this simplistic
view of the world and that view is being
challenged constantly by fax.
Yeah. Constantly by data.
And there's some people that, like you
said, want to bury their head in the sand.
They don't want to look at it.
They don't want to because it
doesn't fit the narrative. Yeah.
And that's getting harder and
harder to do in any corner.
Even like geopolitics of the world
was at our doorstep every day now.
And whether you like it or not,
is that right there in front of you?
So it also seems like people are doing
that because it's easier to live that way
because you can't know
everything about everything.
There's too much going on right now.
I totally agree with that,
that people are just like, look, I've
got to take this course cause what?
What are you asking me to do?
You're asking me to veer off and
really do I really want to know about
cryptography? Do I really want to know
about how this stuff works? You know,
it's like you don't have to,
provided you're not taking a counter
narrative that's causing harm somewhere
down the line. Yeah. You don't
have to, you really don't have.
But the counter narrative is really
assure the people that are burying their
head in the sand and trying to
shove your face in as well. Exactly.
That's really what it is, right? Yeah.
Yeah. That's the problem. Well, Alex,
thank you very much.
Thanks.
Barely really appreciated this
conversation and I really appreciate your
documentary. Deep Web. It's on Epix on
May 31st will it eventually be available?
Itunes, Amazon, Netflix, everything like
that after it, after it's on Netflix,
on epics for a little while to
be available everywhere. And uh,
Alex is available on Twitter.
You can follow him.
It's a l x winter on Twitter.
And is there anything else you want?
That's it, man. Yeah, it's deep web,
the movie and I'm a.com but you know,
you can sign up for a newsletter.
I sort of send out information and Cole
ancillary stuff, but thank you so much,
man. Thanks for making this too.
Really, really appreciate. Thank you.
Appreciate the conversation.
Yeah. All right, my friends.
We'll be back on Wednesday with
Abby Martin and Jim Norton.
Until then go fuck yourself.
Okay. Bye. Bye. Big Kiss.
Okay.