Start Broadcast Shazamm bitches.
I think it's on where we live.
Yeah.
Excellent type fuckers.
We're getting a little better.
Three.
Oh seven.
Now that's a little bit better right?
There we go.
Zoom.
What's happening?
Five years?
Everybody can hear us.
So good.
Let's leave it sideways.
I believe it would a gangsta lean.
Uh,
hello everybody.
Welcome to the.
What is it?
The fucking ninth weekly one or
something company.
We have continued.
Motherfucking saga continues.
Let's jump.
This is how you drink coffee.
Okay.
Like a fucking man.
See that's your right there.
That's what's called a French Press.
You can get it at tarbox.
Starbucks.
Starbucks for like 20 bucks or something
or you know,
I target for 20 bucks.
That's what I was in the middle saying
target and starbucks at the same time.
You just grind up your coffee.
The report in this motherfucker,
you pour the hot water,
you push down the plunger,
but Bam.
You Got Coffee?
Yeah.
It's gritty and it's got like little
pieces of stuff in it.
But.
So what you fucking pussy man up man up
man up and drink your coffee.
How is Australia?
Australia?
Is the shits if you've never been to
It's fucking spectacular.
It's beautiful.
The people are cool as fuck.
It's really bizarre man.
It's way the fuck on the other side of
the world,
like literally on the other side of the
world to where it's a 19 hour time
difference between Los Angeles in
Australia.
What's.
What's the laws like out there?
Is there any.
The weed is not very legal there.
Yeah,
but it's everywhere.
Everybody's got wheat.
Yeah.
So because I got a text from mayhem
right before we left because my mom got
there before us and he said,
Yo,
this is the exact test.
The exact text yo costumes.
Here is a motherfucker.
Don't bring any weed to kangaroo island.
Which have you known mayhem.
That's a,
that's a hand quote right there.
I'm so ladies and gentlemen,
a fucking trainer yesterday got killed
by an work off.
Do you hear about that shit?
You didn't hear about that killer whale
killed a trainer at seaworld.
Wow.
And what's amazing to me is how they
haven't been killing people up to this
point.
Could you imagine if whales,
killer whales,
and it's supposed to be super
intelligent.
I mean,
they're like as intelligent as humans,
they're cousins of dolphins and we put
them in a fucking fish tank and make
them do tricks for mackerels,
you know,
can you imagine what kind of hell that
life is?
This a whale had killed a homeless man
that snuck into the fucking tank in 1991
and he had also a,
or it might be a sheet,
I'm not sure he or she had also,
I think it's also,
uh,
almost drowned a trainer.
What do you remember that video where
the killer whale was playing with the
person dunking him under that same same
whale?
Wow.
Same Way.
Yeah.
So,
I mean,
it's not like the warning fucking signs
weren't there.
It's like,
you know,
you,
you hear Mike Tyson's punch somebody.
You couldn't be shocked.
Like,
how'd he die?
He,
oh,
it's a woman that died.
He,
uh,
he grabbed her by the waist and just
fucking ripped her up in the middle of a
live show at the beginning of the live
videos and said,
well,
that's a good question.
I bet they confiscated everybody's
cameras and shit as they were leaving
the SD cards or system or you think you
would learn to shove it up your ass or
something like this guy.
If he was there for sure there will be a
video of it.
1,000
percent.
We need everybody's camera's SD card up
as save two.
You would have vetted,
uploaded to youtube already.
I'd already been Bluetooth.
Can use stream.
Yeah.
There's no fucking way.
I mean,
could you imagine what that must've
looked like?
You're,
you're there and all of a sudden the
killer,
he grabbed her about the waste and just
started smashing her back and forth.
Just ragdoll here.
He just had enough.
He just said,
that's it.
That's it motherfuckers,
you know,
it's really incredible that we think
it's cool to do that.
And then we go and watch them.
You know,
it's really like,
zoos bums me the fuck out.
We went to a zoo in um,
Australia while we were there and there
was a cool part of it was the crocodile
cage because I don't think that
crocodile gives a fuck where it is.
I think crocodiles are so dumb.
I mean they seem third mind seemed so
dead.
They just lay there with their eyes
closed underwater for like hours at a
time where they don't have to breathe
and I can brief for like an hour.
So they just lay underwater and just do
nothing and just sit there.
They don't run around and play like when
you pass like the monkey cage at a zoo,
that shit's depressing because they
don't want to be there.
When I was in Denver,
there's a zoo in Denver and uh,
the monkey gun in his fucking cage and
was howling this horrible howl and it
wasn't a big cage.
This monkey was screaming out like a
tortured soul.
It was like a man in prison,
you know,
let me out of the monkey was just
screaming at the top of his lungs.
And I was like,
this is not good.
Like this is not cool to do them for
what?
So people can stare at them.
I mean that shit.
She might've flown in the 19 thirties,
you know,
back when there was no zoos are back,
there's no videos,
but we have videos now,
man.
You don't have to put them in a zoo,
you know?
But,
but that's the only time we would ever
be able to see most of those animals.
That's the only thing that makes me go
well,
I see the reason for zoom because I'm
not going to Africa and hunting down a
white tiger,
you know?
Right.
Worth it for them to struggle.
Just so you could stare at them.
Yeah.
But you know,
it could also be like,
dude,
wait,
I don't have to hunt my food.
There's just a stake here.
Every morning when I wake up,
I could sleep.
No,
no,
no.
For like tigers.
That shit is orgasmic to chase down an
animal,
chase it and move it.
You ever see a cap?
Like if you roll a ball,
a string in front of them,
they can't help themselves.
Man,
you should know that you have cats.
Cats can't help it.
They live for chasing shit,
so it's just like,
like you know,
a guy with a hard dick lives to fuck
right now.
It's really the same thing,
man.
There it's nature rewards them for being
a good Predator and I think,
you know,
the same way food tastes good for us and
sex feels good for us.
They love to kill that nature that
rewards them with some crazy rush of
energy and an endorphins when they kill
something,
you know?
So you give them a cold plate of meat
just pushing aluminum tray under the
fucking cage.
That's not the same.
And that's not fun.
Guaranteed,
you know,
but that doesn't that the killing thing
bothers me.
But what really bothers me is the
fucking amount of room that they have to
move around the kangaroo.
The kangaroo cage was fucked up.
Have you ever read the San Diego Zoo
though?
That's a whole.
I mean,
that's what I was there.
I was like,
man,
I would like to be an animal in this
case.
Oh No.
We went down this serious fucking
deliver between what we're saying.
What we're saying was that it.
We got it.
Okay.
Um,
yeah,
San Diego is the shit.
The way they have it as nice.
They have a big giant ass place that,
that makes sense.
But that's fucking expensive,
you know.
But that's how it should be.
They places like the La Zoo just
shouldn't exist because that's just
wrong.
You go to the Lsu,
that's just depressing as fuck,
but there is just like the Columbus
state where I'm from.
It's one of the biggest news Jack
Hanna's from it and it's nice.
They may have just acres and acres and
acres of land and they,
you know,
I don't know if they maybe throw out
some goats once in a while for the
Tigers or something.
It just don't talk about it.
And you know,
they don't do that.
Don't ever do that.
They do that in Iraq.
There's video in Iraq,
have a little donkey loose and this is
how they do it every day.
And the dog,
because just walking around eating and
they open up the gate and these tigers
come running out of the gate and just
pick,
slept at docie to the ground and fucking
Jack.
Um,
it's really kind of wild to see.
And it's really shocking.
These gis filmed it when they were in
Iraq at the zoo.
It's,
it's shocking to see.
But that's really the way they're
supposed to eat.
Like though,
that's how you should do it.
If you're going to feed animals,
you're going to have wild animals.
You should have them eat what they
normally eat,
man.
I mean like,
what's with this feeding fucking snakes.
Frozen mice.
Give them a fucking mouse,
you know?
I mean,
that's what they're supposed to do.
We're,
we're trying to like,
enforce our own ideas of,
of,
of morality and predation on fucking
monsters.
You know what I mean?
Like,
like a snake is a monster dude.
You know,
tigers.
That's a monster.
Those are all monsters.
Their,
their,
their national monsters.
They,
there's a whole natural cycle of things.
And to take them out of that,
there's a,
there was a kangaroo cage that was the
most depressing thing because those
kangaroos are just sitting there.
They didn't
shit.
There's human beings.
There could be considered monster.
So like if you're,
if you put somebody in prison that's a
mass murder,
we're doing the same thing.
You know,
we're,
we should let that mass murder go out on
his way and just murder a shitload of
people,
you know,
dumb ass logic as well.
I mean,
if you're saying like,
you know,
like a tiger that tiger or whatever,
like a snake should kill its own prey
and we should,
you know,
do what,
what,
what?
No,
we're feeding them killed.
Pray.
We kill it first.
That's what's the most ridiculous thing
is that we kill what they,
they eat first so that it's not as
brutal for us.
Somehow or another,
someone else kills it.
You buy it,
killed,
then you feed it to them.
That's ridiculous.
Yeah.
That's not a mass murderer,
dude.
Mass murderers or just fucked in the
head.
They're not.
They're not killing for food is a part
of a natural cycle.
They're just nuts,
you know.
Then when you get a naughty person,
the problem is human consciousness is so
more complex supposedly than animal
consciousness because we have the
ability to alter our environment so you
can't have someone whose consciousness
is haywire because that's.
That's what when you have like serial
killers or mass murderers will you have
someone whose consciousness is just gone
off the tracks and into the woods and
you have just chaos and if a society is
aware of itself,
it has to realize that there's certain
issues are going to come up when you
have crazy people running around killing
your family and your friends,
so you got to kill them.
What you're supposed to do with someone
like a mass murder of.
You're absolutely convinced.
That's the problem.
Really.
The problem is the court system,
the court system,
so fucking corrupt and so many times das
and prosecutors are just trying to get
a.
they're just kind of trying to get a
guilty verdict and they don't give a
fuck if someone is guilty or not.
There's many,
many,
many instances where cops have framed
guys that were innocent.
People have gone to jail for years.
It turns out the DNA evidence,
they were framed.
I mean that's happened many,
many,
many.
That's the real fucking problem.
But if we could be absolutely sure that
we knew that somebody was a mass
murderer or a rapist or anyone with no
remorse,
who hurt other people and could hurt
someone that you care,
you've got to kill him.
Why?
Why keep them around?
There's too many fucking people,
you know.
I mean,
look,
it's not like they're not going to die
eventually anyway.
It's not like if you don't tell them,
you know,
they're gonna fucking to cure cancer and
live forever.
No,
they're not going to do anything.
They're not a mass murderer is not going
to contribute to society.
You know,
they're,
they're just not.
There's nothing is going to.
Nothing good is going to come out of
that.
It should just line them up and like,
oh,
you need a new liver?
Bam.
You're on death row,
row.
There should be no,
like,
you know,
time period and they're going to
electrocute you.
They should just shoot.
You.
Take all the parts that they could use
your corneas,
are your livers best?
An interesting topic because there was a
threat on the board and the message
board on my website where people were
talking about Oregon's having a memory
and uh,
there are all these people who have
gotten transplants when people,
all of a sudden they knew things that
couldn't have possibly known as people
who don't even know,
but you know,
it's like that.
Yeah.
I mean,
I've,
I've heard of many things like that
where people sudden had cravings for
certain types of foods and they had no
idea that the.
I mean,
this is not just one instance.
And see the thing is about memory.
Like we don't know where memory is
stored.
Exactly.
We don't.
I mean,
they know an incredible amount more than
the average person about the way the
human body works much more than people
knew 100 years ago,
much more than you know,
even a decade ago,
but they don't know everything.
There's a lot of questions,
Matt.
First of all,
when human body,
your cells regenerate every seven to 10
years.
I think it's seven years,
so literally every cell in your body
changes and becomes a new one like you
are.
You're a new version of you every seven
to 10 years.
Yes.
There's not the same anymore.
So if that's the case,
where the fuck are your memories?
Because I have memories that are way
more than seven years old,
you know,
so where the memory is stored,
if you have a completely new cell,
I mean are the memories like transferred
back and forth between the cells when
the new one is born?
Is it born with the same memories?
I mean,
what?
Where's the memory?
Where's it stored?
We don't fucking know.
The other idea is that the memories are
stored in the neurons.
Well,
if that's the case,
because the neurons are the only thing
that stay the neurons or not.
You get the neurons you get or the
neurons you get forever.
You don't get new ones.
You know,
they don't regenerate every seven years,
but the heart is filled with neurons.
You know?
It's like one of the biggest clusters of
neurons in the body.
It's like right up there with the brain.
And I think people who have had heart
transplants,
I don't think it's that preposterous
that they would have memories.
I don't think that that's.
Is that preposterous at all?
I think it is.
And I think that that these people that
say that they're having dreams stuff,
they probably would have had that same
exact dream with or without it.
Why would you say that,
Brian?
They're talking about things that
couldn't possibly have known about
people have this little girl gave up the
exact identity and location of the
woman.
Who of the man who murdered the girl who
gave her the heart.
Do you know that story?
No,
but it started there.
It sounds far fetched,
but it doesn't mean it's not good.
There's some things that I read that
when it like that,
that it's kind of like to me is seeing
you for.
It's either somebody that wants
attention,
that's just dumb and they're going,
no,
I had my arm transplant and now I can.
I'm thinking having all these dreams are
people.
I don't know.
It's okay.
That's possible.
I know,
I know.
It's also possible that toilet,
it's real.
That's the problem with skepticism.
What skepticism.
This isn't
my comes to something that we don't
understand.
That's the problems that you know,
you run the possibility of a excluding
something because it seems,
but the reality is we don't have enough
information to decide what's rational,
what's irrational.
Just the idea that you have memories at
all.
It's fucking nuts.
You know the,
the idea that you can.
How about the idea that you can change
people's memories?
You know,
they say that especially like right
after something shocking.
If you start talking to someone and
introducing new ideas to them,
they'll,
they'll have,
they'll remember the whole situation.
They'll change the whole way.
They remember things like,
have you ever thought of something was
in some way,
and then you go back and you watch the
video,
you're like,
God damn.
It wasn't like that at all.
Like I had a fucking.
I don't trust my memory that much.
I trust some things.
There's some things that I know are
recording in there forever for real and
no doubt about it.
There's some things because I've made
sure that have kept that memory.
Like I've had some pretty intense
experiences where I made sure like I am
going to make sure that I record this
one,
but other ones are like fucking blur
man.
You know,
there's a lot of them that are blurring,
you know,
you look back on your,
your high school years like Jesus
Christ,
it's like a slideshows and I barely
remember any of it.
Do you remember?
Like it's getting worse and worse.
I,
I'm actually pretty good with a lot of
weird memories.
But then I,
the other day I was trying to think of
somebody and that I actually hung out
with for three years when I was a kid
and don't remember his face at all.
Came up with like,
my sister's like,
you don't remember him?
We out all the time.
Like I remember him but I don't know.
Have any idea what he looks like.
Yeah,
I've had that happen to me before for
sure.
That's fucking weird.
It is weird.
It's so weird.
I wonder where,
where all that shit goes.
Bin Smoke.
Why is it that someone can pull it back
though?
Like someone will say something that you
go,
yes,
and then all of a sudden,
boom.
The memory like blossoms in your mind.
Like what is that?
It's like you're given CPR to the
memories.
It's like they're almost dead.
Yeah.
It's like a branch of the tree was hit
and nerve of that memory was hit and it
woke up that,
that section of memory or whatever.
Yeah.
Something along those lines with.
What is that?
What the fuck is that?
Somebody's phone.
What happened?
Oh Dude,
you had a spider on your face.
Look.
Oh Shit.
That's a daddy long legs.
How the fuck did that get on your house?
Fear factor.
Oh,
I'm not on.
I'm not on Opie and Anthony this week.
It's not this week.
They made a mistake.
I'm there March 26th,
not February 26 is the Friday,
Friday before the UFC.
Next Month in Dallas.
This weekend.
I'm not in New York this weekend,
so I'm going to be at the Addison
Improv,
uh,
this weekend,
Friday,
Saturday,
and Sunday with my man Joey Diaz and
Brian will be there as well if we get
Brian drunk who might have to talk them
into going on stage
chat.
Brian
is actually funny comedian.
He's done standup a couple of times.
He did it in,
uh,
Atlanta.
He did it.
Um,
what else would you do it,
you know,
I was going to try to go up on stage
before this weekend just in case if,
if I get too drunk and he put me on
stage,
but I really,
it really hurts me to go back and spend
three hours of my life for like five
minutes in front of two people.
The open mic nights,
it is a grind,
you know,
people ask me questions all the time
like,
Hey,
I'm thinking about doing comedy.
What's the best advice?
I'm like,
man,
you gotta be willing to put your whole
life aside.
You've got to be willing to do.
You got to be willing to.
Especially if you have a job during the
day,
you have a job on the day,
man,
your nighttime,
you now,
that's your social life.
It's going to be standup comedy,
you're going to be going to clubs and
you're going to be performing and you
have to do it all the time.
If you don't do it all the time,
you're going to forget all your
material.
The whatever comfort you gain on stage
will be eroded very quickly.
You know,
it's a God damn long ask Ryan,
man.
Yeah.
I think if I was younger I would tell
libby and do it,
but it's really hard to be an adult and
waste that much time.
It is,
it is hard.
You know,
I did it.
I started doing standup when I was a 21.
That's how I did it right after my 21st
birthday and I was,
I had shit going on back then,
man.
You know,
I mean,
I was doing things.
I have,
you know,
I had a life sort of,
but it wasn't like I had a family or a
mortgage or a,
you know,
uh,
no obligations,
no Internet,
no obligations.
You know,
so it wasn't,
it's hard when you have a girlfriend and
you have a life and you have a life and
you have children and a mortgage.
Fuck man.
You know,
when I talked to dudes that are like 40
and they're thinking about doing comedy,
I'm like,
you know,
okay,
that's like saying I'm thinking about
getting into brain surgery.
When we think about brand surgery,
not saying that comedy is as hard as
brain surgery because it's first of all,
it's not as.
It's not as difficult to remember all
the things you need to remember with
brain surgeries,
but it's,
it is just as difficult in a way because
there was no real path.
I mean you could suck as a comedian.
You can't suck as a brain surgeon.
You're fucking going to jail.
So it's obviously a lot more discipline
involved in brain surgery because you
have to do it correctly,
but both are equally difficult to
actually fucking do and put anything in
this life is difficult if you're,
if you're gonna really do it.
I mean,
just think about if you started tomorrow
and you wanted to be a computer
programmer,
you don't know shit about computers,
you just,
you're starting from scratch and you
want to be a computer programmer.
Fuck.
Imagine the fucking work that's involved
in that.
A lot of reading now,
you know,
it's a lot of reading nowadays.
Like I mean you can pretty much teach
myself some programming by just looking
at it.
You know,
how to type,
you know about computers,
you know,
a lot of shit about computers,
a lot of shit about,
about code,
you know,
to it,
to a person that has no experience and
decides I want to take on a new career.
I want to be a computer programmer.
I want to see code for video games.
Good fucking luck man.
How about I want to create video game
engines.
I just,
I don't know where I want to be the next
John Carmack.
You're fucked man.
You're fucked.
That shit will take forever.
Anything that's worth doing takes
fucking forever to get good at.
You know,
and comedy is no different.
Comedy.
Music is no different.
You know,
I often look at people playing piano or
playing guitar or something like that.
I go,
how cool would that be to be able to
just fucking jam on the cash.
But God damn,
that's a lot of fucking time.
I've tried to learn that though.
If it's,
it's a,
it's a coordination thing for me though,
for that.
That's something.
Think you're just born with being able
to understand,
be able to coordinate each finger a
certain way.
Well it's also cultivation.
It's also if you do things like with
your fingers like that early on in life,
you know,
it becomes much easier as you get older.
They say that um,
the army now is using,
um,
they're using xbox controllers for their
drones because he's fucking kids are so
used to it.
Yeah.
And they're encouraging people to play
video games.
I mean it's just a matter of time before
they start record a recruiting,
like the baddest motherfuckers in video
games like the priority do.
I mean like if you could play like war
games with like a keyboard and a mouse.
Like there's these dudes that play
quake,
like professionally,
those motherfuckers can move that mouse
cursor and put it on an object like
instantaneously.
You know,
they know exactly where that cursor's
going.
They play so much that when they move
that mouse,
the mouse and the keyboard is way more
accurate than that.
A joystick thing.
The Georgia thing is kind of difficult
to manipulate the like the toggles and
exactly where the cross.
Here it goes.
But if you have a mouse you can put a
mouse if you understand like how quick
you know.
It all depends on,
you know,
everybody likes a different.
Some people like high sensitivity,
some people like low sensitivity,
but the bottom line is once you get used
to whatever it is,
you move the mouse,
the cursor goes in a certain directions.
They can put it like exactly where they
want to instantly.
So it's not like in you're in a
helicopter,
you see the insurgents,
you gotta move the crosshairs and get
them in line.
We haven't been lying me,
I'm in like,
no,
it's fine.
I mean they could do it so fucking
quick.
I mean that would be some crazy shit if
you could have drones and have like that
guy fatality and fatality is like the
baddest motherfucking quake player ever.
This dude is just ridiculously accurate
with his mind and a cool guy too.
Met Him.
Very nice guy.
But if you've got that guy playing for
your army and you got drones with
missiles in it from that fucking guy,
holy shit.
You know,
that's the future man.
Welcome to the new world.
It's pretty crazy how how video games
have exploded from something that used
to be like,
like Little Ping pongs.
Now people have like amazing video games
on their phones.
Credible man.
Just look at what you can do with your
iphone playing all these different
racing games and shit.
We were working on the new UFC.
A fight game.
Fuck.
It's amazing man.
When you watch some of the graphics and
Shit,
like they dive for knee bars,
they get triangles,
they throw head kicks and punches,
flying knees and shit.
You see all this crazy shit.
All these different techniques they can
do just like in real fighting and it's
like it's so close to being like a video
that you like on an actual UFC fight
that you can manipulate,
you know the the limit is in the
controller.
I think what eventually is going to
happen as you're going to have a god
damn suit on,
you're going to have a fucking suit on
or you're just gonna have this little
wire plugged in on your forehead and
you're just gonna think that could
happen,
but Microsoft is very close to
developing the whole system where you
interact with the game.
What's it called?
Nitel.
It comes out like I think November or it
might have got pushed to spell it and in
a t a l and it's pretty much just like a
camera or something that sits on top of
your TV and in readership motion range
of motion.
That's.
That's incredible because that's going
to be fucking cool.
Imagine having like a UFC game where you
could learn how to fight without
actually fighting.
My problem with that whole thing is I
think maybe if I was a kid I would've
loved it,
but when I'm playing a video game like I
don't want to have to be doing shit.
What you say that doing with right now
we just wack.
It's this little thing and you're
playing ping pong and it sort of moves
the way you want it to.
I did a week hard game once and I was
like,
this is not specific at all.
It's not.
It's not rewarding.
Yeah,
but it's something about having to like
get up.
Like I want to do a lazy fuck.
If I was a kid it might've been better,
but like nowadays I want to play video
games.
I just want to sit there and smoke weed,
but that's dependent on the graphics.
What if the graphics were like 3d
fucking super dope virtual reality type
shit and you had a virtual gun and
you're running down a hallway shooting
at all because it's like you have a gun
in your hand and it reads this gun.
Come on man.
That will be this shit.
And the actual running that you take
place,
like maybe that would be the shit if you
had a fucking warehouse,
like a virtual reality warehouse,
like you enter into the door,
you put on this helmet and it's just a
flat or tag.
Yeah.
But complete three d,
virtual reality,
you know?
Yeah.
And if you get close to the walls,
like a little light goes on,
you are getting close to the wall.
That would be good to turn.
Right.
You know?
Yeah.
Come on man.
I just,
I,
I've just gotten to the point where I
did this.
Nintendo we shit just drives me crazy as
boring man.
The we is like playing pool,
but there's no pool cue you're just
going like.
And you're just no feedback either
feedback man.
Like I want to click a button and see a
gun,
go off,
you know,
and a click the mouse button and see the
rocket,
you know,
take off,
right?
That this whole moving an arm through
the air that's fucking weak.
That's stupid.
There's this,
I forget what it was.
They just said the other data in the
future that they're going to use,
like Google maps and street view and
Google maps and you're going to be
playing video games.
Have like your street,
you're going around in your house.
You know what I mean?
You should be able to find out if
someone is playing like fucking doom on
your street and rolling up your house to
be like,
Hey,
just want you to know they should send
you an email.
It should be like the sims where it's
like your house is the house in the
video game and so like if you try to
break in your house,
they're trying to break into your house.
Like everyone should have their own
house in the video game.
Yeah.
That will be kind of cool.
That would be correct.
Then you would know where everybody,
everyone lives.
Killed them.
Video Games have access to I for like 24
hours or something like that and you can
run away.
I'm kind kinda shocked.
The virtual reality kind of hit like A.
They,
they.
The technology never really developed
the way I thought it was going to.
Like,
you know,
you heard about that shit like way back
in the eighties and I thought wow,
like there was movies based on that and
I was like,
I thought like wow,
I remember like um,
well sorta dagger.
I don't remember what movie you
remember.
Total recall with a fucking make you
could dream.
Yeah,
that Shit's coming.
It's a total recall.
What was the one with the chick with the
red hair in Puerto Rico.
They've already been able to take images
and implant them in people's minds and
they been able to read images from
people's minds,
like read what you're thinking about.
Like you can look at something and the
computer,
like there's some sort of sensors that
they hook up to your brain and then it
sends the image to a computer and it's,
it can tell what you're looking at.
Like that's nuts man.
Because eventually,
I mean this is in a very rudimentary
stages of the technology where they can
only pick out shapes and shit,
but eventually they're going to be able
to fucking see what you're seeing.
That the element is that what was the
ticket to red hair?
And fulfillment is that the Bruce Willis
movie?
And it had like memories like I'm moving
to the cloud,
like memories in your head how,
how bad ass was Chris Tucker in that
moment?
Remember?
Who was that crazy alien?
Lawnmower man was a good movie too.
That's another nutty movie.
But a retard.
The one crazy,
right?
Right.
Put a computer in his brain or something
right now.
The Stephen King Book.
Stephen King.
Oh No,
it's strange days.
Was it strange days?
Was another virtual reality.
Something crazy ass.
I think it was strange days.
Strange days.
Let's go right here.
Just sit here.
I can't wait for strategies become true
if that's what it was.
It was strange.
That was Angela Bassett,
right?
She'll forever be Tina Turner.
Sorry.
Do any other movies.
I don't.
You're your Tina Turner.
Um,
was going to say,
oh,
this fucking Ms Dot Beverly Hills Chair
about this.
Another one of these beauty pageant
checks came out saying that she doesn't
believe that gays should be married.
And she,
she quoted Leviticus and the Old
Testament saying that the,
uh,
you know,
the Bible says that it's some stupid
quote like any man who lays down with a
man,
as if,
uh,
you know,
the same way lays down with a woman
that's an abomination,
should be put to death.
So she came out and said that gays
Lucy supporting the Old Testament,
which by the way,
I mean,
whatever you fucking want to believe
about religion,
that's all well and good.
You know,
who,
who knows?
If God is real,
I mean,
it could be that,
you know,
the Bible is completely ridiculous
because God wants things confusing,
but it gets a certain point where you
read certain things and you got to go,
alright,
every people are full of shit.
And there was no internet back then.
It's not like,
you know,
there was a copy of the,
the Bible on Wikipedia and people kept
altering it.
But everybody was like,
no,
that's not what it says.
And they went back and changed it.
You know,
they didn't.
The Old Testament,
they didn't even write that fucking
thing down for like a thousand years.
It was just stories,
you know,
and the idea that those stories you
can't tell,
I can't tell a story to him and he tells
it to his girlfriend.
His girlfriend writes it in her blog and
it's the same story.
It'll be fucked up for sure.
I can't tell you how many times someone
has gone to one of my gigs and I've said
something and then a guy like will quote
on twitter like I'll do.
That was so funny last night when you
said this about them,
like,
Tim,
I didn't say that.
Like you're saying something fucked up.
What I said was a lot nicer,
you know,
but when w,
when you realize that memories are so
fucking,
there's no way,
there's no way you can be that accurate.
Over a thousand years were people
talking about it.
And then on top of it,
the original,
uh,
the Old Testament Bible was written in
ancient Hebrew.
And to this day,
the only know three out of four words in
ancient Hebrew,
25 percent of the words,
they don't have a clue as to what they
mean.
Not only that,
letters and numbers were the same thing.
Back then there were no numbers.
So the letter a was also the number one.
So there was like numerical value in
words like the word love in the word
God.
They have the same numerical value in
ancient Hebrew.
But as soon as they translated that to
Latin and Greek,
that shit was all gone.
Let's see.
It was all lost.
So for this dumb bitch to sit and think
that God wants people to put,
put the depth of their gay.
Like this is what the Ms Beverly Hills.
It's beverly.
This is a new one,
new Ms Dot California.
And California is supposed to be so
liberal.
It ain't Miss Texas.
Do you know who Carrie Anne can't?
She is or whatever her name is.
She's from celebrity Rehab Niche.
Can each.
She was the one that had the threesome
with a guy from grey's anatomy.
Anyways,
on this show,
celebrity rehab.
She.
You just want to strangle her now.
I think it's almost with these like
pageant people,
because I know a couple of these girls
that did the pageants and stuff like
that.
They're fucked up in their head and you
know,
they've been doing it all their life.
These little kids have grown up.
You remember last time?
Not last time.
I went to Dallas for the time before
when there was that little girl pageant
going on in the hotel,
so you remember that.
That was scary as.
That was the weirdest fucking thing
ever.
We're hanging out the hotel and there's
all these little girls.
I mean little like six.
Yeah,
six years old with high heels and makeup
on with their hair done and jewelry and
dresses and you're like,
what the fuck is going on here?
That shit is an abomination.
All right.
That is a fucking.
That is a travesty.
I feel like somebody was going wrong in
the elevator because I was in an
elevator with two of them and I looked
at her and I'm like,
oh my God,
look like if they were making finger
themselves in front of you,
something's not right there.
Sometimes my daughter will play with.
They're posting just other.
No,
I don't want to say this.
That's true.
I mean you were to,
if you have one,
but some the other day she was lying
there and she had her little feet up in
the air,
which is rocking back and forth and she
just,
two hands just grabs it,
you know?
And uh,
you know,
I don't know what to say.
Like,
what do you say that you go,
don't do that.
You can't tell her not to do that.
That's,
you know,
you don't want to suppress her and get
her
crazy as I don't want her to be like,
like in kindergarten going,
hey,
anybody,
they all do it anyway.
Dude,
I got news for you.
They all do it.
Don't you remember doing weird shit with
kids when you were a little bit.
I played doctor,
me and my friend played soccer with all
the girls in our neighborhood and I
remember the only time I remember the
most,
we had three girls lined up and we're
like,
okay,
we're going to be putting pencils and
your vagina's take off chance it took
off other pants and we just went back to
each one.
Then would pull it out and smell it.
And it goes,
oh fuck.
But we were all like,
fine,
you can girls lead poisoning.
I know they might be retarded now
because they're all on my facebook too.
So totally,
they're not watching what you shit.
It was nice,
but I thought we should ask them all
questions.
Does anybody remember anything about
pencils?
So you remember me putting up things.
So in your crowd,
this was.
So this beauty pageant thing that we saw
at the hotel,
it was dark.
I mean it was really dark because there
was all these Weirdo fucking religious
people with their kids dressed like
horse and made no fucking sense.
I mean,
no sense because there were,
there were,
it was,
um,
we were there on a Sunday and they were
talking about church,
there was all this church talk and you
got your girl dressed as a fucking
prostitute.
Here's a six year old dresses,
a prostitute,
and you're talking about church.
They had high heeled shoes on.
I mean like this high,
which the only reason why shoes have
heels like that.
And so that women's legs look longer so
that guys think about them when they're
pushing these long legs back and fucking
the shit out of you.
That's what,
that's for those,
that long leg thing.
Why,
why you think?
What do you think that's there for you?
Sacrificing how you can walk.
How about that?
Just so that men want to fuck you more
than we already do,
which is wait,
wait,
what the fuck you to have sex with a
girl that has her shoes on like high
heels and ever got to know what is up
with that though.
That's just a porno stuff.
That's ridiculous.
I mean,
I'm sure it's somewhere in my life,
you know,
somebody who's not,
taking everything off that's it's
possible,
but the,
that someone would like that.
But the whole,
I don't like them in the first place.
I think it was ugly and it seems to me
like you're doing something stupid,
you know?
I don't want to be like,
you're getting tricked and you don't
need to do it for me.
Like,
you know,
like my wife always wants to wear these
high heels when she leaves the house.
I'm like,
okay,
if you want to do that,
that's all good.
But to me it seems like you can't walk
right?
I'd rather you wear tennis shoes,
but women love them,
man.
They love shoes.
They what they love how they look,
they love.
It's like how dudes love cars,
you know,
how you know,
like you see like a 69 mustang or
something like that and you go whoa.
And he like pull up to a dude,
look at that motherfucker.
You know what I'm saying?
Like there's something that men have,
like women can go,
wow,
that's a pretty car,
but it's not the same as how a dude
looks at a car.
Well,
for girls,
the shoe thing is just,
they really fucking love shoes,
man.
Like makeup and shoes.
It looks like there's the opposite sides
of the body because they're so ashamed
of the middle.
I think it bleeds.
It's gross to look it up and running
naturally long.
It's probably something like that.
Look how long my legs are and where do
they go to look up there?
Well,
the,
you know,
that's one thing.
If you're a woman,
you know,
if you're a grown woman,
that's what you like and what the fuck
ever.
Who gives a shit?
You want to go pierce your balls,
go do it.
Who gives a shit?
But for little kids that's not,
that's not cool man.
To have a six year old dress like a
derby and it is disturbing.
It felt very wrong.
You know?
And you know,
like their whole Jon Benet Ramsey case,
man,
that shit disturbed that case yet.
They don't know.
We're going to find out the mother is
still alive.
I believe the moms dad died.
Maybe the dad's dead too.
It's possible.
Anyway,
no twitter verse.
Yeah.
Twitter versus not cool.
And I agree.
No,
I heels are just as much an
establishment as a male's ty is both are
silly.
That's true.
Raun Kaiser.
Goddamn these just twitter shit goes too
fast.
Yeah,
no,
you're absolutely right.
I think ties are completely ridiculous.
I didn't even,
I,
I haven't worn a tie in a long.
I did a documentary recently on Dmt and
uh,
well I had to wear a tie because I
played like a rod sterling type
narrator.
It's a really interesting documentary on
DMT.
It'll be out sometime this spring,
but I had to wear a tie.
I had no idea how to tie this fucking
thing.
I had no idea.
The last time I wore a tie was um,
my,
my first album grabbed that thing off
the wall real quick.
My first album in 1999,
you know,
just as a goof,
one of the things I always said that I
love about being a comedian is that you,
you don't have to wear a fucking tie.
And so just my first CD for whatever
reason,
I just thought it would be funny if I
wore a tie.
It doesn't make any sense.
Just look strange.
I had to wear a tie for like 10 years
everyday.
Yeah.
If you want to like work in businessman,
it's like there's an agreement,
like everyone has to know that you are
willing to wear something completely
ridiculous because you're following by
the very obvious rules of behavior.
It's going to be really easy to predict
what you're doing.
That's what people like.
Like I'm a gentleman,
you know,
like as a gentleman,
while I feel this,
I'm a gentleman who's got a tie on Hello
Gentlemen,
Gentlemen.
You know,
it's like there's this like this
agreement that you're not going to get
too crazy.
You're not going to.
It's like my Dr Phil Impression,
you know,
bottom of are showing we are very
slippery.
I'm not chasing after anybody,
you know,
it's like there's something to that.
There's something to this is silly
outfit that you wear that's
uncomfortable.
Like if people started doing business
and they had like rash guards on like,
like road rash guards.
I like,
they're ready to go do Jujitsu and shit,
you know,
like why,
why would that be bad?
But it is bad.
You know,
you can't have like board shorts and you
know what I'm saying?
You know,
running shoes on and you look like
you're ready to pounce on people that
nobody wants that in business.
You can have.
When you go to business you have to be
dressed uncomfortable.
Your button has to be all the way up
here,
you know,
it's fucking ridiculous.
You know?
Do,
do,
do you remember he used to work at this
architect firm for my stepfather and
this was when I was big into acid and
stuff like that.
So every time I would come to work I was
either hung over a,
still tripping on acid,
been,
you know,
or something like that.
It was such a boring job that it was
acceptable because all that I had to do
is make copies of architect plans.
You fucked up your brain on acid.
Do you think you have fucked up your
brain?
Okay.
Um,
no,
no.
I,
I think,
I think if when I was doing it,
I was,
yeah.
Was there any point that like,
you know,
you ever heard Howard stern talks about
is acid trip know Howard stern talks
about it on the radio and I guess he did
like a giant dose of acid,
like way too much.
And uh,
he was all fucked up for like a long
time,
like he was hearing voices and it was
just like a,
like a real psychotic episode and um,
you know,
that's a really,
that's a thing about psychedelics.
So you gotta make sure you don't fuck
around and do too much.
Like Dennis Mckenna had an experience
like that to Dennis Mckenna,
who's Terence Mckenna's brother.
They're both famous psychonauts for
psychedelic pioneers in the seventies.
They went to Brazil and he took like way
too much mushrooms and he lost his mind
for like two weeks.
Like he couldn't communicate with
people,
you know,
and the last time I did DMT,
I was fucking whacked out for like two
solid weeks.
Not totally.
You wouldn't guess if you were talking
to me.
I was totally normal.
I did shows the shows went great.
I W I went to work.
I did fear fire.
Did that one great.
Uh,
you know,
nothing.
Nothing got fucked up in my.
But my head was like,
I've felt very,
you know,
you feel like your consciousness is like
in a foundation.
Your consciousness is like,
you know,
like it's like boom,
solid.
This is me the morning you wake up in
the morning,
hi honey,
kiss your girlfriend,
brush your teeth.
This is fucking solid.
When I did the DMT,
my consciousness was like a little tiny
raft in a fucked up ocean.
It's like,
you know,
like nothing seemed like I kept having
these ideas that cars were going to come
launching themselves over the boundaries
and hit my car while I was driving.
And I'm like,
I'm like,
why am I thinking so Mike,
what is this about?
And then I realized that what it was was
these are this idea of worrying about
possible disasters was my ego's way of
regaining ground and letting me know
that it has to have a certain amount of
real estate in reality and that if you
want to do crazy,
crazy psychedelics and go into other
dimensions,
communicate with entities and reevaluate
your,
you know,
your whole position in the world.
And then humankind's positioned with
each other.
That's all well and good,
but there's some real shit in the world
that the ego has to be there for.
And the ego was like sending me a
message.
I'm dude.
But if a fucking car launched itself
out,
you better be fucking paying attention.
Like there was a certain amount of,
of where it was such a mind blowing
experience that there was like a
wrestling match going on in my head
between my ego in between this new
information and accepting all this new
information from the psychedelic trip
and,
and incorporating it into the way I look
at everyday life.
You know.
And like,
you know,
you think about someone who's like a
real,
like a shaman.
You know,
they're living in the jungle and they're
all at peace in the world.
They're not calling people douche bags
on the Internet.
You know,
there's a certain amount of
enlightenment that if you achieve it,
it's going to make it very hard for you
to function in the regular world and I
think that's one of the most important
things about psychedelic trips.
Like there's a lot of cripples in the
psychedelic world and then the weed
world too.
There's a lot of people that they're.
They're so into these experiences that
they can't incorporate it into their
everyday life and they're almost
crippled in their everyday life because
of it and no psychedelic experiences
worth anything.
Unless you can take what you've learned
from it and enhance regular life,
enhance your communication with people,
your relationships with people you know,
enhance the way you look at the world,
enhance your career path.
You know the kind of friends you hang
around with,
unless it can enhance you.
The reality is we live in this world for
eight hours a day or 12 hours a day or
however long you're awake.
This world,
this shit,
this concrete world is real and you have
to manage your way through this and
psychedelic drugs make it very difficult
to do that.
If you want to have a regular job.
I think psychedelics,
what's the main thing with psychedelics
is that opens up a door and like,
like in the past,
like I've been offered dmt but I won't
do it because I like when I first did
mushrooms that opened up to a door or
things I never thought of or saw before.
And it's never gonna go away.
It's,
it didn't damage my head,
but now that I know that exists,
I know it's there and so when acid,
the same thing,
but there's a point where I have to go,
okay,
is this door,
does this store need to be open?
Is this anything positive with this door
being open?
And some drugs are like that for me
because like a Salvia was the closest to
the point where I was like,
okay,
that is a scary door that I opened up
because that just pretty much made
everything seem fake.
Like,
like it was like this world is fake.
Everything is fake and I know that's not
true,
but it opened up that door where I'm
like,
okay,
that's almost too much of a door.
I shouldn't have opened up that door.
I'm never going to get back.
That.
That thought of not knowing that was,
that's pretty more pretty much saying
the same thing.
It may if you can't bring it back and
incorporated into your everyday life and
like sometimes you open up these doors,
you're like,
the fuck am I going to do with this in
your everyday life is just whacked out.
Some people like going back to that,
that fake world so much though,
and that's where it gets fucking scared.
You know what I think most of those
people,
their real world is not so hot,
you know?
And that's one of the reasons why it
becomes an escape,
you know?
And I don't think it should be an
escape.
I don't think you should ever escape
reality.
You're here.
This is,
this is life.
You know,
there's life can be magical.
Fucking intense,
fantastic experience if you manage it
correctly.
But if you just want to escape all the
time,
I've got to think that you're probably
fucking up in this life and that's
imbalanced.
You know the people that always want to
go.
And it's like,
like the same thing with like video
games.
I remember I told you about this dude.
There's this dude who used to be a
manager at the comedy store that was
addicted to everquest.
Just completely addicted.
Eight,
10,
12 hours a day,
lost everything,
lost his job,
lost his life.
He just was so pale you would see him.
He was so pale,
looked like he never saw sunlight,
like he would order in food and never
leave the fucking house for days.
And he came down to the comedy store one
night.
And then of those,
it's so weird.
I'm so good at making money in my online
life and so bad in my real life.
It was starting to realize that like
he's a fucking loser in this life
because he's.
He's excited and puts all of his passion
and energy into this other life.
But that's just really because this
other life is a new and exciting thing.
You know,
a new and artificial thing and he can
control it from his computer without
dealing with emotions and dealing with
all the,
you know,
the fears and anxieties and the real
world presents.
But the reality is if we live the life
in a computer screen and we were offered
the real world as a video game,
the real world will be so much more
fantastic.
You know,
we just don't think of it as being
fantastic because we're so goddamn used
to it.
You know,
if we lived life in a computer,
in a computer monitor and that's how you
were when you were born.
And then one day someone said,
you know,
hey,
we've developed this new game that
allows you to go outside and you go
outside and you'd actually get laid and
they can go and have a real drink and
you feel it.
You do a real shot of Jack Daniels would
go,
Holy Shit,
this is real.
I can't believe it.
You know,
you'd go get laid for real and you drive
a car for rail.
You'd really like to the world stuff,
fucking shit.
You would never want to play video
games.
The reason why we want to play video
games is because it's a world that we
can control completely independent from
all the,
the,
the like the pros and cons of this solid
world,
completely independent of the emotions
and the insecurities and all the shit
that we all experience but we don't
like,
but the reason why we experienced
insecurities and anxiety and anger,
these are all like little chemical
signals to guide you through towards a
proper life.
Like when I've found in life,
most importantly more than anything is
that the one,
the way that I'm the most happiest is if
I'm putting out positive energy.
I'm putting out positive energy to
people,
two friends,
positive energy on stage,
positive energy with my writing and my
work with,
with anything I'm doing,
it's all friendly and positive and
happy,
and if you do that,
you know you can.
You can have a fucking fantastic life.
The problem is it's just difficult to
do.
It's hard to keep your shit together.
It's hard not to lose your temper.
It's hard not to be obsessed with
something and get sidetracked and that's
where like gambling addictions and
masturbation addictions and all that
shit,
that's what that's all about.
It's like you're trying to distract
yourself from,
from all the pain of being a human,
you know?
I mean,
I think fucking hunter s Thompson had a
quote like that,
like a man making himself a beast to,
to get away from the pain of being a
man.
I forget exactly what the quote was,
but something along those lines,
like we distract the shit of ourselves
because the game of life is fucking hard
to do.
It's just like a video game is hard to
do.
You know,
you remember like back when I used to
play quake like all the time I played
quake like hours and hours a day and you
and I played quake online.
We played against each other and like
you can tell the difference between
someone who's playing all the time
because you,
you,
you get really good at it.
You know,
you know where the rockets are going to
go.
And I was sticking rail guns up your ass
and electric.
I think you want 120 games.
And I won one.
Maybe not,
hopefully not fair.
And like.
And believe me,
there's dudes online that would do that
to me.
Just raped me.
Why?
Because they had put so much time in
this fucking crazy game.
They would get good at it.
But since you hadn't put time,
how frustrating was it?
So she didn't want to play right now I'm
want to shut it off.
Yeah,
that's exactly the same as life.
If you get good at life with the game,
then it's fun as fuck.
It's awesome.
You know,
if you're Leonardo Dicaprio,
life must be the shit.
You know what I'm saying?
He started in movies driving a Ferrari
for models.
What?
He's got a gigantic fucking mansion.
I mean he's a,
he's a movie.
Had been.
Must be so fun for him.
But not everybody can be Leonardo
Dicaprio.
So if you're the fucking garbage man
who's,
you know,
came home and his wife is fucking the
newspaper Guy.
You know,
that's not a fun life.
That's a,
that's,
that's just like a guy who's not good at
quick getting murdered in a game.
It's not fun,
man.
It's like playing pool.
If you're good.
Like I played pool,
I love pull up,
I get obsessed with it,
but I have a friend,
my friend Max eberly,
he's a professional and he's a top
professional.
I mean he's capable of winning when he's
in stroke,
capable of winning any tournament in the
world.
I mean he's really fucking good and when
I play against him sometimes it's so
frustrating and I played pretty good.
Like for a regular person I played good
but for like a pro,
not even fucking close.
So when I play Max it's just getting my
ass handed to me it's just getting
fucked.
The only time it's fun is when we play
on a really,
really tight table,
so occasion when he misses and then I'd
be like,
oh,
I get to shoot,
you know?
So he's much better at that game.
We used to give him a handicap.
Sorry,
sorry.
Well we know,
we just,
we don't play for anything.
It's good for me.
It's good for me because you get used to
playing against a guy like that.
It's not as fun as playing against a guy
who's like your speed,
but it's really good for your game
because it makes sure that you
capitalize on every mistake.
Sometimes you'll play a guy who's not as
good as you and you're like,
I don't worry about this because,
uh,
if I miss this guys gonna Miss,
and I'll have another shot with Max.
Every time you miss,
you're like,
fuck,
I better,
I better sit down for awhile.
Anyway,
I believe that I'm.
The hunter asked quote is actually from
Samuel Johnson and English author.
Thank you very much sir.
I thought it was 100 thompson quote.
Thank you.
Cj.
Mic L Hiney mcelhinney.
It's what about words and names like
Swartz and anger.
How the fuck did that ever get through?
Like what culture ran out of sounds?
People string together.
Something nutty like that.
People that like to write in cursive is
that is going to be the best cursive
writing I've ever seen.
Manuscripts.
Slaves to write it on a page and they
didn't have lines in the paper.
They just had paper and they would write
it.
Exactly.
Have you ever heard of the Voynich
manuscript?
The voynich manuscript?
I don't know if I'm saying it right,
is this ancient manuscript that was a
found a ton,
hundreds,
hundreds of years old and they have no
fucking idea what it says.
They don't know the language covered
under any.
Think about it.
They don't know if it's just nonsense.
If some guy was just practicing
scribble,
but it's like really long and it's A.
Yeah,
and his consistency in how it's written,
but they can't decode it.
They've had like top encryption experts
and it's like it's very divided.
Some people believe it's a hoax and some
people believe that it's some fucking
lost language and some people think that
it's gloss gloss of Lelea,
like when someone talks in tongues and
that they just went into a fucking
trans.
Some retired with a pennant now because
it's got really good writing.
It's got diagrams in it and really good,
really good illustrations rather and
diagrams and it's like a weird.
Yeah,
it's really complicated,
you know,
and they found that uh,
that temple and Turkey that is 7,000
years older than the Pyramids are very
complex stone temple carved out of stone
and shit and now they have to like
rewrite,
like human history because like 7,000
years before Egypt has 9,000,
10,000
BC and 10,000
BC,
they were already like had temples and
we're worshiping shit.
And like that throws a monkey wrench
into the whole gears of,
of the,
the,
the idea of a cultural evolution,
you know.
And there's this been this Guy John
Anthony West,
John Anthony West,
look that up on Google because this guy
is fascinating.
He's got an awesome DVD series called
magical Egypt and this guy is obsessed
with Egypt.
He spent his entire life studying Egypt
and he believes that the Egyptian
culture goes back way,
way,
way before the established timelines.
Like the established timelines for
Egyptian culture is like 2,500
BC.
That's when they think like the pyramids
were built and that the culture goes
back a little bit before that,
but not much.
And he thinks it goes back like 35,000
years,
he thinks that people have been around
way,
way longer and that there was some big
break somewhere along the line,
like probably some sort of a natural
cataclysmic disaster,
like a meteor impact or something like
that,
you know,
and it could be,
10,000,
15,000
years ago,
like they don't know when it was,
but they think that there was like an
advanced culture and then boom,
it got fucked up and then culture
rebuilds,
society rebuilds and then what's left is
like they're living in the shit that was
made thousands and thousands of years
ago and they tried to imitate it and
recreate it and they can't.
And he believes that that's what it is.
Like these,
these fucked up here,
man.
So they have in Egypt.
It's not that these pyramids were like
the first pyramids,
he thinks much,
much more likely.
These pyramids were probably like,
people were like trying to duplicate
other shit,
duplicate shit that was already there.
You know,
they believe that that's don't actually,
that's not his theory.
That's someone else's theory.
His theory is I'm,
one of the things is about the Sphinx.
They brought in geologists,
the geologists have like documented the
erosion on the sphinx and they say
there's water or roadnet like thousands
of years of rainfall,
of cut deep fissures in the whole entire
enclosure with a sphinxes.
And the problem with that is the last
time there was rainfall in the Nile
Valley was like $709,000
BC.
So that would mean that the,
the,
the Pyramids and the Sphinx rather would
have to be like 7,000
years older than the established
timeline.
And so of course,
none of the,
uh,
the egyptologists like the guys who have
been teaching forever,
that the Pyramids and the Sphinx and all
that was built about 2,500
BC.
They never want.
They don't want to accept it.
They go,
well,
where's the evidence for this culture?
Like,
it's right there,
man.
There's fucking rainfall for thousands
of years have created this.
And geologists are universal about that.
There's no one is disputing that.
The geologists are all saying he's got
hung.
This guy ron shock,
who's a,
uh,
I'm a professor at Boston University,
has got over 100 professional,
uh,
professors geologists to sign off on the
fact that this is undoubtedly water
erosion,
which completely changes the timeline
for when the,
the,
uh,
the Sphinx was built and there's a bunch
of that shit going on in,
in Egypt.
They believe that it's like probably,
you know,
maybe even 30,000
years old,
there's a mass extinction took place on
the earth somewhere around 10,000
years ago.
And uh,
that's when the woolly mammoth died
instantaneously.
That's when the saber tooth tigers died.
Noah's Ark now this before,
but the,
the um,
like 10,000
years ago,
North America,
like half of North America was under a
mile high sheet of ice.
Like there was an ice age going on and
something killed it and ended it like
instantaneously and they don't know what
it was.
And it's very,
very likely that it was a fucking
natural disaster.
It's very likely that it was a fucking
meat here impacted some what happened.
That guys are distracting the shit out
of me.
So I don't look at me,
well,
don't fucking have a monitor open in
front of me,
Dude Surf and he's not even paying
attention.
We do one week podcast.
This dude is so addicted to the
Internet.
He can't even talk for one week.
I've heard you talk before,
you've heard me talk about this is
online,
dude,
there's 675 people,
but have not heard this story.
Don't look at him.
Shut up,
faggot.
Anyway,
I think people have been around way
longer.
I think it's much more likely that it's
just really ridiculous that people still
don't believe in and how long this
world's been around.
You know what I mean?
Oh,
like people have believed the earth,
10,000
years old.
It just drives me crazy.
Well,
you know,
that's how not monster number more than
50 percent of America,
according to a Gallup poll,
which is not the same because I'm the.
Here's the thing about poles.
You can't say like according to a recent
poll,
50 percent of Americans believe this
because,
no,
no.
According to your recent poll,
50 percent of Americans who are fucking
retarded enough to answer your poll,
believe in that.
That's the reality of polls are never
representative of anybody intelligent
because you can't get me to answer a
fucking pole.
We can't get you.
You got shit to do.
Don't you have a hobby?
You hear somebody calls you.
May I have five minutes of your time?
No,
that's for like old ladies who have no
friends.
So that's what that is.
A mom.
Look at this glitter more.
I'm fucking super baked and I just don't
want to hang up from a person and I'm
like,
I'm okay.
Five minutes.
Okay.
I'm trying to be nice.
But the reality is polls.
Polls represent the retards.
You know,
you're,
you're a fucking,
you're a dollar.
You're answering polls.
Goddammit.
Anytime I do a poll as if I think I'm
going to win something,
if I answer,
20 percent of Americans can't fund the
United States on a globe.
Is that True Joe?
Beef don't be lying.
Job is line job.
If it didn't make that shit up.
Solar flares up in 2012,
bro.
We're clashing the galactic equator than
you know what?
You know,
there's a guy which is Richard Tyson.
Is that his name as a.
What is that guy's name?
The astronomer.
Really?
Neil Tyson.
Very,
very intelligent guy and I really like
listening to them talk and one of the
things he said about this whole crossing
the aquatic whatever.
What is it?
What is the exact way this guy,
galactic equator.
I think that's what this guy said.
I'm the.
Yeah,
like we're crossing the center of the
galaxy.
We were.
Everything's in line on December 21st
2012.
You know what he says?
He says that happens all the time.
Says he says that like that,
like line up with the center of the
galaxy.
That's it doesn't,
it doesn't happen then because goes,
it happens all the time and nothing
happens.
So who knows if he's right or if he's
one of those guys.
It's like super skeptical,
but I think what's much more likely it's
going to happen in 2012 or something
technological.
Something technological,
some crazy invention,
you know,
like I don't think it be anything.
It could be that too.
It could be that 2012.
What really happens is nothing happens
and then people realize,
oh,
we have to actually manage this life.
We can't just rely on fucking aliens
landing.
I was more scared about 2000 just
because if that makes sense.
All the computers,
planes dropping from the sky.
I was scared to.
I didn't.
Um,
I didn't do a Gig in 2000.
I stayed home.
I thought for sure there was at least
going to be something small when
thousand dollars.
Isn't it crazy that that's 10 years ago
now.
Time is just fucking flying by man.
It's crazy fast.
Too Weird.
It almost feels like it's quicker every
year and everybody says that.
But what time really is quicker would if
like clocks are moving quicker to.
We just can't really establish it
because that wouldn't make sense because
what about digital clocks?
They all exist in,
in this fucking dimension.
Maybe there's a dimension is moving
quicker.
Units of timer know almost.
I think we're forgetting more so it
feels like we're forgetting more than
the day because we have more
information.
Maybe thoughts on those guys movement,
you know,
what I think about zeitgeists and all
that stuff.
There's a lot of.
It's poorly researched like the stuff
that he said about Mithra and different,
different gods and stuff that,
that are just like Jesus loved was
really poorly researched and incorrect
and been proven wrong.
There's a website that says,
uh,
I think it's a common debunkings I guys
or something like that.
I forget what the,
uh,
what the website is titled,
but I mean the guy just breaks down all
the errors that the dude who made the
movie made and it's just,
you know,
he's,
he's quoting references and showing very
clearly that,
uh,
the,
the guys guys made some big problem,
big,
big fuck ups and I think his whole,
how sure he is.
That's September 11th was,
was,
um,
designed and the,
you know,
the uh,
and perpetrated by the US government and
that tower one tower two fell because
they were,
there were detonated.
Like,
you're sure that,
you know,
look,
no one's sure that that's crazy.
You can't say free spot.
Now.
All this talk of free fall speed and the
towers fell at free.
Fall speed.
Yeah,
they fell pretty fucking fast.
But that's what happens when shit falls
apart,
it falls apart pretty fucking fast,
especially shit that's super heavy and
gigantic and all that weight is on and
it's all just collapsing.
Who the fuck knows what happens when you
build a building that way and you fly a
fucking giant plane filled with jet fuel
into it.
The only way to really know.
I mean you can have theories,
but the only way to really know is to
build another building and fly another
jet into exactly the same way and see
what happens and if it falls down
exactly like that one,
then the argument's pretty much over.
And if it doesn't then you have to go,
well,
okay,
well what was inside the building?
Did it all burn the same was a,
was it exactly constructed the same?
You know,
and then you got to try it again.
I mean,
you have to have more than two buildings
to go on and everybody's like buildings
I've never fallen before and the
government does some nasty evil shit.
That is absolutely a fact,
but you don't know.
You don't know what happened there.
And to say that you know is just as bad
as people who blindly trust in the US
government.
The thing that question that I have a
big question about when it comes to
September 11th is tower seven and if you
watch video online,
there's video of tower seven falling and
it falls just like a controlled
demolition.
I mean it just goes straight down all at
once and it's,
it's really crazy to watch man,
you know,
because like it implodes from the
basement down in every level falls apart
including like jets of,
of energy,
like spraying out of windows.
Like there's blasts.
I mean maybe that could be because it's
collapsing.
I mean that's a whole floor of error
being registered.
That one.
But the problem is it all falls the
exact same time in that building wasn't
even hit by a plane.
It was on fire and it had a whole minute
from like debris and stuff and I could
see it falling down,
but there was a hole in one corner and
the whole,
if it's a hole there and the building's
going to collapse when it collapsed
towards the whole.
I mean,
doesn't that make sense?
Maybe the.
It also makes sense.
The whole poc,
standing on a pop can thing.
Wherever you stand on a pop,
can you knock a little bit off the side?
It's not,
you're not falling over,
you're going straight down the wave.
You know,
meaning it's so heavy.
Even if there's a hole on it,
it doesn't matter.
It's just going straight down and that's
maybe,
maybe I,
I think with all that shit,
I'm like,
yeah,
I'm glad there's people that freak out
about and care about it because without
them,
you know,
the government's going to get away with
a bunch of shit.
But in my opinion,
you know,
I don't care if the government didn't
fuck they did it,
you know,
I'm still waking up eating cereal.
Well that is one thing you have to
consider.
I mean,
it's like you,
you,
you mean,
how is this going to help you?
How's this going to help you in your
life?
I know if you get obsessed with this
much tears,
here's the bottom line people to think
the government wouldn't kill people and
nobody died and tower seven supposedly,
but the people don't believe people
think the government would not kill
people.
This is all you need to know for sure.
They start wars.
Then don't need to be started.
That's 100 percent fact for sure.
The Gulf of Tonkin incident that got us
into the Vietnam war,
that was a fake fucking attack on
Americans.
They faked it and they faked it and made
this big deal about it so that everybody
would get fired up and realize we have
to go to Vietnam.
That's fact.
This is history.
You know,
and the fact that they wrote up a thing
called operation northwoods.
The northwoods document in the
northwoods document was they were
planning attacks on Americans and they
were going to.
This is in 1962 and they were going,
this was signed by the Joint Chiefs of
Staff.
By the way,
and vetoed by Kennedy,
they were going to attack one time,
obey there.
We're going to lob grenades into and
mortars and to Guantanamo Bay and
possibly kill American soldiers.
They were going to blow up a jetliner
and blame it on the Cubans and they were
going to tell Americans,
we have to go to war with Cuba.
Well,
people are going to fucking die in a war
for sure and people are going to die in
a war that Americans didn't want.
And so they decided to do what's called
a false flag and make attacks on
Americans and blame it on the Cubans and
that's a fact.
They're willing to kill people.
And only 3000 people died in September
11 for sure.
That's a lot of people.
I'm not making light of it,
but think comparison to how many people
have died in Iraq during the fucking
war.
They're talking about like a million
civilians have died in Iraq since the
invasion.
A million.
I mean,
that's fucking right.
Haiti.
I mean millions of people die from that
earthquake in Haiti,
but we didn't have it.
Hd video fucking,
you know.
Seeing it,
yeah,
but we didn't.
We're not responsible for that.
No,
no,
no.
I know,
but I think the reason why is that
they're willing to kill people.
Right,
right.
I think the reason why we were focused
on it though,
it's just because of that,
that we all watched it live where,
you know,
if we saw these people in a racket shot,
live on tv would probably be just as big
as nine slash 11.
You now.
Well,
I don't know about that.
You know,
I think,
I think.
Well I think the idea was it was an
attack on American soil.
I mean that's really what was such a big
deal.
And then all mean.
I remember how everybody gets so
patriotic after afterwards.
Do you remember after September 11th,
everybody had fucking American flags on
their car.
Remember that weird feeling?
You were you still in Ohio back then?
Right?
Right.
Did they have them in Ohio?
It was crazy bad.
I left,
I went to work one day.
I don't even think I was doing fear
factor at the time.
I might've been,
but I was driving down down the street
near my house and every fucking car had
an American flag on it.
It was crazy and I was like,
this is just weird.
It's a weird feeling.
It's like,
like people are blowing up,
like they're ready to just go to fucking
war.
You don't realize like how war,
like this fucking culture really is and,
and how sheep like and how people would
just immediately willing to fight and
fight who don't.
The people who did it are dead.
I think it was a suicide attack.
So the people that were responsible for
the deaths of those people are all dead.
I mean,
unless you're one of those crazy
motherfuckers that doesn't believe that
it was a real plane.
And then.
And then there's people that believe
that they were piloted by remote control
on the planes were emptying.
Who the fuck knows shit happened.
Almost wait is this almost 10 years,
10 years,
and I'm still talking about it.
Oh my God.
It's so frustrating talking to people
who claim to know.
That's when it's really frustrating,
man.
It wasn't a plane hit the Pentagon.
It was a missile,
whereas all the people that died in the
fucking plane crash then did they.
They took them.
And why would they say it's a plane?
Why would they shoot a missile and say
it's a plane.
Why we're there.
All the plane parts on the lawn.
I mean,
come on,
man.
You're talking about this before this
the plane.
Can we actually last week or two weeks
ago?
It's fear factor real.
Nothing is real.
Depends on how much acid you take.
Joe Rogan hates Bruce springsteen is so
not true.
It's not true.
You're just trying to get attention,
motherfucker.
No.
Hey Bruce springsteen born to run.
That's a great fucking brilliant
disguise.
That's a great fucking song.
Do I don't love all bruce springsteen.
I'm not going to sit through a three
hour concert of anybody's.
It would have to be like Richard Pryor
would have to come back from the dead.
And Floyd do three.
I might sit through three hours of pink
Floyd's.
No,
I wouldn't.
I'd get bored.
They don't have three hours of good
songs,
but.
But I love some,
some,
uh,
Bruce springsteen songs?
No.
Some of them are the fucking shit.
No one is gonna like I bought an old
rolling stone album the other day
because it had one song on it that I
really liked.
I forgot what it was,
but the rest of the album was dog shit.
And that's the rolling stones.
You know,
you think about how many great songs
they have.
They have a lot of fucking albums,
you know,
if you go back into some of those older
albums and listen to some of those songs
that you don't know shit,
you know,
not now.
Nobody puts out something that everybody
loves,
you know?
And if I like,
I mean it's very rare that I like a
whole album from a band are real
orangey,
like with more than 10 people having sex
in the same room.
It's like you walk in and you're like,
what the fuck is going on here at
origin?
Yanik?
A real unknown.
I've never been on religion of,
you know,
I,
I just,
it seems like Tampa,
Tampa,
Florida.
So when I was trying to get us to go to
a sex club,
whereas he got,
had a swingers club that happened again
with me and Ari in,
um,
I think it was Nashville,
me and already we're in Nashville.
We had a saint.
This driver who drove us to the UFC,
drove us to the comedy club,
the same driver all week and then
filing.
He's dropping us off at the airport and
he's like,
as he's dropping us off,
I was like,
well,
if you're ever back in town,
no,
I have a fucking swingers club that I
belonged to me.
And I go,
what?
And it was a swingers.
Like,
yeah,
me and my wife were swingers.
Swingers.
So you let dudes fuck your wife who's
like,
well,
you know,
she lets me and I have to let her.
What will we get to choose though?
We have veto power.
That's what we said.
We got veto power like I go.
So if some dude,
you feel like you can't follow them.
Oh yeah.
No,
no,
no big young studs.
Like he's getting old bald fucking
vacuum salesman.
Band is wide mouth.
I'm like,
do watch.
He goes down,
I don't want to watch.
You don't want to watch,
you don't want to watch your,
your wife is getting fucking stuffed in
another room.
How crazy is that bitch?
You know how crazy it she,
you know,
whenever I hear about chicks that want
to fuck like a bunch of different dudes
at the same time like that.
Is there something.
I mean,
look,
we're all wired differently and you
know,
I like hot sauce.
You like hot sauce,
like spicy food.
I like really spicy food.
Like I fucked myself up.
I bought like Dave's insanity sauce on,
on Burritos and I'm sweating.
Pouring sweat is pouring down my face,
my tongue is on fire now.
The most people they wouldn't like that.
But I liked that for some weird reason.
Maybe some girls just like Dixon
everywhere,
you know?
And maybe they like it.
Maybe it's just like they're just going
crazy.
Maybe it's not,
but maybe maybe they're broken,
you know,
it depends on the person.
Some of them are for sure fucked up.
There was this girl on the Howard Stern
show Saturday night got fuck so hard in
the ass that it tore a hole in her
intestines.
It's.
He sewed it back up and then she was
talking about how she's just the other
day had to dixon her ass.
I'm like,
what didn't you once your intestines rip
open?
My God,
what is this girl?
She's in the New Jersey Shore Porn
Jersey whore or something like that.
Someone who knows.
You guys know there's a bunch of you
fucking perverts.
Goddammit.
You people know who it is.
I forget her name,
theresa or something like that,
or whoever was listening to the stern
show today and I heard that.
Yeah,
Mr Han's,
that sounds just like Mr Hanson,
but that,
that a regular Dick doing that too is
that's even more impressive.
The Horse Dick.
You look at it and you go,
how does it not kill you?
The most amazing thing about that Mr
Han's thing,
if you don't know what Mr Hans's,
so the guy who got fucked to death by a
horse and there's a video of it online,
you can watch the guy getting fucked by
the horse,
but the amazing thing is Tom,
they did it tear and Thomas.
Beautiful.
Thank you very much,
Marty Hubris.
You fucking pervert.
But I'm.
The amazing thing about the horse
fucking video is that apparently this
guy had gotten fucked by a horse a bunch
of times and nothing happened.
Like he was okay.
Like how's that even happened?
Mr Hans is year nine slash 11.
You talk about that shit every day,
you know?
Is there a.
is there a point where you're like,
man,
I do talk about fucking horse found a
whole lot more than I know because it's
a bit of my back,
but no,
it's like part of my job.
You remember that Shit.
The face I used to go behind you and
always make the faces all the time.
Well,
I found myself doing it on normal faces,
so like it'd be my mom,
like,
hey mom,
let's take a photo and then back and I'm
like,
Oh,
I'm doing this all the time.
Now I have to stop.
So that's why I stopped in the face
because it was something that was like
in my head.
If you don't know what faces,
and this is a thing that went on for
literally like five years.
Every time I took a picture with someone
like,
you know,
someone came to a show and they want to
take a picture with me.
Every time Brian was behind them like
this and there's,
we have to organize them and put them
on,
on my space.
But a lot of them are.
But the other one of them,
we're talking about no bullshit.
Five years worth of shows.
Thousands and thousands and thousands
and thousands of pictures.
All with Brian behind it making crazy
fucking faces.
I have a picture of me and David Lee
Roth and you're behind it.
You're going to fuck though.
I think the last one I did or the one
that made me realize I need to stop
doing it,
but when I did the brock lesnar and I
was so drunk and then next day and I'm
like with them,
I did not do it with Brock Lesnar did
with Dana Cookman oh yeah.
And I did to take tank,
but no,
the brock lesnar one,
like I was like,
oh I need to stop.
He could've easily kicked my ass right
then and oh my God,
I,
I don't have that picture.
You've got to send that to me.
I'm going to put this up.
All right.
That's awesome.
I'm going to do it right now because.
Wow,
I've never seen that photo before
or I'll put that shit up and put it on
flicker.
Okay.
I do whatever I.
I can't believe I bought David Lee Roth.
I can't wait to.
Well No,
I shouldn't say this,
but I can't wait to one day where David
Lee rocked
won't
be around.
Maybe so we can release that video or
you won't be at this video of us all
hanging out with David Lee Roth.
I don't mean die,
I mean like he doesn't kill him to say
about it right now because he told us
not to talk about it.
Oh,
all right.
I mean he doesn't want the video coming
out.
So the last thing we should do is talk
about what's on the video.
I just say we all sat around and talked,
but we love bullshit,
man.
You were saying you can't wait until he
dies.
You can release it and then then just so
we can show it to people because it was
so awesome.
It was awesome.
Yeah.
Right?
Yes,
it was,
it was just cool talking to him.
It was basically just David Lee Roth
talking about crazy road stories and
there's nothing scandalous.
It was just a mean fucking David Lee
Roth,
you know?
It's just weird hanging out with
somebody that you grew up as a kid
listening to his albums at gold circle
and yeah,
it's amazing.
Hanging out with David Lee Roth was a
shit.
All right,
hold on.
I'm going to choose the photo.
We'll put that shit online.
So.
Yeah.
But this,
this picture of Brian Going nutty behind
David Lee Roth is just indicative of one
of fucking.
You probably have some of you guys
probably have photos of me in the
background and even know people would
get so mad with me before.
Just get so mad.
They go,
you'll joe Bro.
Fuck or doing behind you.
And I'm like,
no,
no.
He's my friend.
He's actually get paid to do that.
Hempy memory came back twice because he
was so pissed off or mad.
Well there's weird people that like,
there's weird people that fucking like
take pictures that they take with you
and like put them like in their living
room.
I went to this guy's house once we did
this fear factor thing.
Please don't tell me that firefox is
fucking crashing against dirty can't.
Oh my God.
You fucking piece of shit.
Are we still on?
Come on
dude.
Come on.
I don't know.
Oh my God.
You fucking piece of shit.
God Damn it dude.
We're going to lose this [inaudible]
recording too.
I don't think we're to.
What are we doing?
Go to the show.
What are you trying to.
We froze,
Huh?
Yeah.