Yes,
we're live
modified brody brody with somebody else.
Who's the other person.
It was like I copied to people's voices
there.
Brody's more.
Yes.
Positive,
right.
That's Mahlik brody.
Yes.
Buffer.
A little drawn out.
Maybe a little buffer in there.
It's time that dude blew his knee out
once doing that.
He blew his acl.
That's how much he explodes and do that
jump when he goes,
it's done.
I'm not bullshitting.
Did he do it live?
Yes.
He popped his fucking acl.
Ow.
Fuck.
Did he fall or did he just kind of like
catches,
walked it off,
walked it off and then got surgery.
Wow.
Yeah,
and he had to be like ginger on it for a
while cause he should do crazy shit man.
You know when you,
when you filmed them doing the buffer,
three 60 a lot of people forgot about
that.
He's a madman.
That guy.
Did He,
do you remember what UFC it was 100?
No,
no,
I mean it,
I wonder if he had to do it like,
you know,
after he tore it,
like he had to go back on in the ring on
a torn acl.
I think if he did it wasn't for very
long.
I think he just went ahead and got it
fixed real quick.
And then,
you know,
cause if you get,
you get your acl fixed and they'll give
you like these um,
pretty,
uh,
lightweight carbon fiber braces,
you could walk around in it like,
okay,
like it's not cool.
Like it's not,
you don't,
you don't want to go long distances,
but they can kind of brace you up pretty
good with a minimal brace.
Postsurgery you just gotta be real
careful with it.
You know,
you don't want to hurt it again.
Right.
When I hurt my knee recently,
I had to go to cvs and get like one of
those knee things for my knee and had to
buy like a cane.
And so I have all these like neat to how
bad you hurt your knee pretty bad.
I couldn't walk on it to the point where
I bought it.
Cane the same name that you had problems
with.
What was your original problem with it?
I have this problem where my knee pops
out of place and like it for like a week
or so I could almost not even walk on
it.
It pops back in.
Okay.
It's only happened a few times but it
happened to recently and it was so bad
that I couldn't walk.
I had to go to see him.
When you go to cvs to buy a cane,
all the canes or like feminine,
like there's,
they all have glitter on them like a old
man came that's gray or something?
No,
it's all like sparkly blue,
sparkly Kane.
What do you think that is?
Is that a marketing move?
Is there like a lot of ladies that are
hurting themselves?
I think,
I don't know.
I think it's just so old.
People can see it like they're like,
oh,
a sparkly canes or I don't know.
I guess when you get old you don't care
about if it's sparkly,
maybe.
I don't know how you can see it.
I have no idea.
It was weird.
Hurting your knees is not good man.
It's not.
And I constantly think about it too
because it's,
it always happens when I'm just like
doing something mild like all turned to
the side,
but I'll pivot on it or something that
just pops out.
You probably have at the very least like
something with your meniscus.
It could be like a,
I used to have this thing called a
bucket handle tear and a,
what it would be is,
you know how like a bucket handle like
flip over,
you know,
one way or the other.
Well it gets stuck like flipped like a
piece tears and then it gets stuck like
wedged up.
It's terrible.
Yeah.
And uh,
I had that where it was,
it was bad for a while,
which is kind of give out on me.
And then one day in Jujitsu class,
it just,
it just got wrapped up the wrong way.
Like upside down.
Like my leg got to get yanked in some
way.
My leg completely locked up.
It was brutal,
but it was a pretty quick fix.
It's a way easier fix than a nacl
because with an acl they have to replace
your ligament and it takes a long time
to heal.
But with the meniscus,
like six weeks later you can do Jujitsu
again.
Hmm.
Yeah.
My old roommate had this thing where
like his,
his,
uh,
shoulder would always pop out of place
and he'll be like,
oh my God,
oh out.
But then he would have to like hit it
against a wall to pop it back in like
Mel Gibson and lethal weapon and style.
Exactly like that.
That's not good.
Yeah.
See like stuff like that,
they can fix that.
You should get that fixed.
Yeah.
I don't talk to anymore.
And that surgery suck sucks.
It's all the rehab.
Uh,
yeah.
People that have a serious shoulder
surgery or a pretty universal in saying
it sucks depending upon how badly fuck
it up.
But like,
you know,
like a guy like Cain Velasquez,
he's had it and uh,
he came back from it,
but it took a long ass time before he
was fighting again.
You know,
those,
those are bad surgeries.
Yeah.
And the knee one though,
man,
they might be able to just trim that
shit like you should find out what it is
because if it's just a meniscus tear,
dude,
I'm telling you,
they'd go in there,
they scope it,
and if it's not that aggressive,
it's not a gigantic tear,
you'll,
you'll be fine.
It's only happened like three or four
times my whole life,
so it's like I'm 41 it's fine if it
happens as long as you just don't move
along.
Right.
Exactly.
Kitchen in 10 years,
sedentary lifestyle seminar.
I said,
and Terry,
are you still doing your losing weight
thing?
Yeah,
I just did my first month finished my
first month that it was 17.3 pounds.
I think it was incredible in one month.
That's incredible.
Yeah,
it's incredible.
But then I think,
all right,
I still have a 23 pounds.
Don't think like that.
Think that you're committed.
Dude.
That's amazing.
That's a,
that's,
that's a very impressive accomplishment.
It's hard to do.
It is.
I Miss Bread so much though.
I haven't had any breads since then.
I haven't had any like cheese or
anything like that.
And I almost snapped the other day.
I was just so hungry.
I was like,
I just can't eat chicken or vegetables
anymore.
Well this is what it's like.
It's like as you get older,
your body just sucks more and more a
processing,
the kind of food you love,
your body is like dude,
enough with the fucking split getty,
Jesus Christ.
It's just like glue.
Just it tastes so good though.
Oh God.
Damn.
It's good.
One thing I noticed though,
immediately all my acid reflex gone,
like all that,
like burping and,
and just like stomach acid completely
gone from that.
I don't know if it's the cheese or if
it's the bread or Dotson.
That's fascinating man.
You know,
and we had this guy on Mark Sisson the
other day and he's the author of the
primal blueprint and he was talking
about,
he had irritable bowel syndrome,
which whenever I hear that,
I don't even know want to know what that
is.
I feel like I have that.
What does it mean?
It means like,
yeah,
ibs gets shitty.
You get diarrhea all the way all the
time,
all day.
I usually have that,
but that's from drinking.
That's not ibs.
That's just
making its way through your veins,
the evil alcohol.
Um,
yeah.
Well he told me that he,
uh,
he cured it all by just eliminating
grains.
He doesn't,
he doesn't take in very many,
um,
carbohydrates at all.
Like he doesn't do any breads or pastas
or things like that.
Most of it comes from,
um,
from fruits and vegetables,
mostly vegetables.
Right.
And meet like he was,
it was essentially saying that he had
all these issues and obviously what
works for one person might not nit
necessarily even be as good for another
person.
They say that there's different styles
of human,
you know,
that people who are your ancestors come
from specific backgrounds.
Your diet is going to be like,
uh,
some I should find out.
That's bullshit though.
Cause you know,
I've heard that before that that always
seemed like bullshit.
You know.
You know what that was like a recent
study they were talking about it that
there was like,
um,
to,
to eat like your DNA.
You know what I'm talking about?
Remember that thing you would like your
genetic,
yeah,
they were trying to like say,
oh you're a specific type and that type
needs a lot of red meat.
You know,
you're this type,
that type of needs a lot of carbs.
It seems like that makes sense.
Getting some kind of like,
you know,
scan of your body of what your body
needs or lacks or needs more of than
other people.
It just makes sense.
Right.
Yeah,
totally makes sense.
Especially if you're,
your body's like developed like your
ancestors developed in an area where
they needed specific types of foods.
The ancestral diet,
that's it.
Should you eat?
Look your ancestors is that it?
Pretty recently?
This was just at the nlf but I think is
this saying that there's more than one
type of person,
the more than one type of diet?
I think this is just talking about a
specific ancient diet.
That's what I think this is.
Cause,
I think that's what the ancestral diet
ideas,
the idea mark sisson guy was talking
about,
that's really fascinating to me is that,
um,
when you're taking in all these carbs,
you're taking in a lot
of sugar and that when you eliminate
sugar and a eliminate inflammatory
foods,
you are,
your body operates more efficiently.
It's just healthier.
It has more resources to,
um,
fight off illness and inflammation and
things like that.
It's a fascinating concept.
So I think might not work for everybody.
I don't know what a,
what the fuck do I know,
but I'm going to give it a shot for a
little while.
I'm gonna see what it's like.
It's pretty interesting because I,
I,
my,
my diet went from,
you know,
like Mcdonald's to Wendy's everyday to
pizza every day.
Like I really had the worst diet ever
and now it's just tons of vegetables,
a little protein and I don't feel tired
anymore.
I feel like I can feel the food work
almost.
It's,
it's interesting how,
how just changing your diet from just
crap too.
That's super healthy.
How,
how much you can feel it immediately
almost.
Yeah.
It's incredible.
Right.
And working out.
It's getting the doorframes.
I've never had that in my life where
like where I like two hours later I'd be
like,
why am I so happy?
Like I'm like,
like bouncing around.
Ha.
I've never felt that before.
I've worked out,
but for,
I've never felt that,
but for some reason this time around,
I'm just like,
what?
Oh my God,
I'm happy for no reason.
I'm happy.
It's a weird,
they've sent it,
they've done studies that show that
depression can be cured just as easily
with the alcohol with,
with alcohol.
Thanks Joe and Matt with the Exercise
Rather.
Yeah.
Um,
then,
uh,
they were,
they were comparing it to people that
got on an Ssri and they were saying
they're,
they're pretty similar results and a lot
of people,
people that really started doing a lot
of cardio,
doing a lot of running and things along
those lines.
Like that's like something that's
supposed to be specifically good like
you,
but you need kind of like both kinds of
things for your life.
You need like some kind of strenuous
stuff,
whether it's body weight stuff,
pushups or something like that or a
anything that just really gets your,
you know,
your strength going and then you need
some,
something that's just cardiovascular.
And when you do those things together,
man,
it's just you,
your body's relaxes.
You know,
it's more,
it's more um,
adaptable.
It's more just loose.
Do you have it,
is your bedroom completely blacked out?
Like dark and like,
like when you wake up is you see
sunlight when you wake up in the morning
or is there a little,
very little,
I mean,
yeah,
why?
I just blacked out my room recently
because I've just got out like I,
my window is like right next to the side
and you're like,
when you wake up,
it's just right there is that.
She's done that and hotel rooms and I've
always felt like a creep.
I feel like when you're in vegas or
something like that,
like,
well I always feel like what?
I'm in a hotel room close like all the
windows and closing all the curtains.
There's something about locking yourself
in a totally dark room.
And a strange place.
It's just bizarre.
It is.
And I took like,
I found like there was a little crack
where I couldn't like it,
like my blinds didn't fix or anything.
So then
I went to the store,
the hardware store,
and they had like these decals where you
can like put it on your windows.
I made my windows like a stained glass
thinking that way.
So now it's like I have this weird like
blue room that that just closed blue.
But it sucks though.
I had like,
I was like,
why did I do this?
Because now I have no Ita.
If it's daylight or nighttime,
anytime my,
I remember immigrant,
it's not good.
You need a circadian rhythm thing going
on.
Yeah.
Blue.
Did you see that thing that I posted
today?
Um,
I retweeted rather.
It was about,
um,
some,
some blue lava.
There's a place in the world that has
blue lava.
Oh Dude.
Why is it blue?
I don't know.
It's fucking Avatar.
That's,
that's Narnia or wherever the fuck those
people are from.
Where were they from?
Unobtainium island or something.
Wait,
where the fuck were they from?
I can't remember the planet.
Maybe we think of something.
Have you ever heard the Kentucky blue
people are some somewhat,
yeah.
While I'm looking this up,
I'm gonna look,
okay.
Take it.
Blew people told me about that and I
didn't believe him.
The Jersey Devil.
Have you ever heard of the Jersey Devil?
Yeah.
It's supposed to be like a flying demon
that lives in the woods in New Jersey.
Maybe that guy that got poisoning it was
all blue.
I wonder if it,
what's his name?
The Russian.
A Russian guy.
And he got placed.
The guy that got poisoned.
Yeah.
His face changed color turned into Papa
smurf.
Well,
he had all that scar tissue all over his
face.
Remember that too?
That guy.
Well that was the crazy guy that did
the,
um,
that guy was using that colloidal silver
shit.
He was on Oprah.
He passed away recently,
unfortunately.
But um,
that guy specifically,
the guy that was on oprah,
that was blue,
he passed away recently.
I'm pretty sure I read a story about it
somewhere.
Um,
an entire family.
Oh,
that's different than this is a
different guy.
I wonder if that was their diet to a
blood disorder.
Why don't have to repeat that.
Like we don't speak the same language.
Hello?
Yes.
Blood disorder.
No,
the other guy was d there's the blue
lava,
but the other guy was blue because,
uh,
he,
he drank colloidal silver every day
cause he thought it would like,
he'll know,
like fix diseases or something like
that.
And um,
someone explained,
some scientists explained,
it might've been Neil degrasse Tyson,
I forget who it was,
but they explained why drinking
colloidal silver would have that effect
on your body.
I don't think it was neil degrasse
Tyson.
I can't remember who it was.
But anyway,
they went into this scientific
explanation of why drinking coital
silver can permanently stain your body
purple.
Like that guy,
he must've drank like massive quantities
of it,
but I forget what the reaction is,
but the reactions permanent.
Hmm.
Like fucking what the fuck Jesus.
Oh my God.
I wonder if the blue is just like,
like almost kind of like a fire that's
around the lava that looks blue.
Kind of like a flame.
Oh,
in this pit thing.
That's,
wow.
No,
it isn't.
Okay.
What is that?
It makes no sense.
Hmm.
Awesome.
Cool.
Fumaroles glossed wholesale sulfur gas
staying the surrounding landscape of
bright yellow and ignited sulfur burns
with a blue thing.
Oh Wow.
My name is Ruben.
I'm a photographer and a filmmaker from
Liverpool,
UK.
The currently based in Chicago.
The blue flame is too dim to be seen him
the day lights.
So I had to wait until dusk for it to be
seen.
And the moonlight was dull enough to
show the claims as well as reveal the
surrounding landscape.
I also use long exposures in many of my
images,
which allows for pictures,
which show an extended period of time
rather than a split second.
I'm playing a horrible instrument while
talking,
but wait a minute is actually,
why does that look so fake?
He used well,
like he used a photo trick to that.
Is that a real,
no.
Real felt photo was that real that we
were just looking at?
Really?
Yeah.
Low Gas.
Why does it look almost like a comic
book ish.
Yeah.
It does want exposure.
It's allowing that fog.
Okay.
Wow.
These pictures are incredible.
Hmm.
This is incredible.
This photographer is fucking amazing.
He has a good camera nowadays.
Nowadays I look at this,
the fact that he's captured this shit,
is he the first guy to ever capture this
stuff?
Is this something that people don't
about?
I want to see video of it live though.
See,
that's the problem.
I wonder if this is just a photo trick
like yeah,
there's a little blue flame to it,
so I might keep the exposure open a
little so it looks a little bit more
blue than it would if with your naked
eye.
This is video.
Oh yeah,
I guess you're right.
That just looks like fire or something.
Yeah,
that's kind of what he said it was.
It was like the methane.
It's an sulfur head and all our,
yeah,
it's incredible.
It's incredible.
They have software problems here in Los
Angeles.
So you,
you go through some of these,
you know,
places.
It just smells like farts everywhere
because of the sulfur.
Sulfur.
Yeah.
I think it's software.
Uh,
in Calabasas when I lived there,
it would sometimes it would just smell
like eggs everywhere and it's because of
sulfur.
We said what it,
what is like a natural software that
comes out of the ground and comes out of
it.
Yeah.
It comes out of the ground.
And uh,
speaking of that,
like what is up with that gas leak?
Yeah.
Apparently it's horrific.
It's,
it's really bad.
It's going to take them months to,
uh,
to try to figure it out and uh,
and close it off.
It could get worse.
Right.
They like something could happen.
It seems like somebody could
accidentally smoke a cigarette down,
you know,
and like we blow up all of my dog.
I don't know how flammable it is.
I don't know if it's something like
that.
I don't,
don't know if it's something that's easy
to ignite.
I don't know.
But I know it's health concern.
Um,
I mean I think there's a concern too
that it might collapse further.
Wow.
Like,
um,
they don't know exactly how to shut that
thing off quick.
It's going to take them some time and
some engineering couldn't they just pour
a shitload of concrete all over it and
just walk away and man,
it's gas.
I don't know how they do this.
I really,
I couldn't even begin to wrap my mind,
my puny little mind around what kind of
knowledge it takes to stop a fucking gas
leak in a pipe natural gas to,
it's different than like,
is it car?
I'm guy.
I'm kind of asking,
I don't know.
I thought it was type California gas
hasn't dropped like it has all over the
country.
It gets pretty,
it's like almost,
it was under a dollar for a little while
in Ohio.
Well three almost $4.
Some places people love to hear that
we're going back to the seventies man is
great.
But what do you think?
Um,
I think it's a methane though,
isn't it?
That's what I would think it's car gas.
If I was kind of wondering.
Yeah,
I think it is a natural gas.
I think that's the whole point that day.
So it's a,
but it's a pipe,
right?
Right.
Pipe that pumps gas to all these people
and it broke and they,
they say that the whole is really big
now cause it's like they,
this fucking eight foot wide hole.
I think there's people that live around
there that can't go home like they had
to replace.
I like a whole neighborhoods of people
and they can't,
they still can't go home.
To this day.
They can't go home.
It's crazy.
No,
they had evacuated 2.5 million pounds of
methane every day.
Oh,
let's be honest.
Methane's air.
So it doesn't really weigh anything.
So it could be £1 billion.
Well,
but it's an 8 billion pounds of meth.
True.
How did they measure what's maybe it
actually has weight to it.
That's how it gets how you get to a
pound.
It's like measuring a pounds.
That's a lot.
Then it has to be a ways and nothing.
It's a lot slower.
Ton of feathers in a ton of bricks.
Like it's still a ton.
Yeah,
but this is 2.5 million pounds of Shit.
So light,
it can float.
So it's like the individual particles
are very light.
They're floating right there.
Gases.
Maybe we're getting scammed and we don't
even know it.
This Jackson guys like we need more
money to get this all this pounds of
gas.
Yeah,
that's a very good point.
Bp can go to where the kid to grow.
Maybe that's what it pumps into things
and then now it's like just blowing out
into the air.
Maybe that's how they're measuring it.
I think that's what it,
that's what pumps through there.
The whole thing is nuts,
man.
That says they tried to use in mud,
but they tried doing concrete.
God,
you know what?
When I hear they tried to do it but it
didn't work.
I fucking freak out.
I really do.
That is like the last thing
I ever want to hear when there's a
national crisis,
you know?
Well,
they tried to do this,
but it didn't work like,
oh Christ.
I th they they,
this is a hard one.
This is not easy.
We're just so lucky.
They're smart people out there.
We'd be so fucked.
We would be so fucked.
We're so lucky.
There's engineers at work on this kind
of shit.
Like you don't even think about it.
We don't think about the streets.
Think about the fucking highway system
and you complain.
You know,
you'll let go the fuck and work in Jesus
Christ to got this lane cut off so they
could fix the road.
What the FOC.
But think about how in general,
how fucking cool it is that we've
hardened the ground and smoothed it out.
All look cross this mother fucker.
You know,
and everybody's like,
man,
the fucking rubes ruin the landscape.
Absolutely.
And a lot of places and this place is
one of them,
right?
And it looks like shit.
It's just a bunch of roads.
We over did it,
we overdid it.
We've got crazy.
We put too many roads in one spot,
too many buildings.
We ignored the rules of having food
nearby and vegetables and stuff.
We ignored all that.
We just said no,
it's just fucking piled on top of each
other.
Woo.
And,
and that's what we did.
But the idea is fucking amazing.
The idea that when you're in a place
like Montana and you're driving through
these mountain ranges,
the,
the roads don't bother you,
man.
They don't bother you.
You don't care if there's a road there.
Cause you're looking up at this insane
natural beauty.
And you're just like,
just fuck.
This is crazy.
This is,
this is like the most insane artwork you
could ever buy.
Could never look as beautiful as this.
Like really amazing artwork is always
amazing to see someone's expression and
when someone does something that's
really dope,
it's cool.
It gives every,
all this good feeling like,
wow,
that was amazing.
That's a cool piece of art.
That's a beautiful sculpture.
God,
that's a pretty painting.
But when you see the mountains,
man,
there's something about those things
like a snow cap mountain.
You're like,
fuck.
And it's limited if you think about it.
Yeah,
like that.
Let's look at that fucking view.
That's not going to exist in a hundred
years.
That view right there,
there's going to be so many drones
flying around Amazon prime crap.
There's going to be people with their
hover boards up in the air like it
that's not going to exist in a hundred
years.
That view.
Well that we would have to preserve it.
That's what the idea of having,
um,
public wilderness public a forests to
the stuff that it's supposed to be ours.
That's what Teddy Roosevelt wanted to do
way back in the dame.
And when they instituted these ideas and
got a public land,
um,
like signed off to to us so that like
there's,
there's giant swaths of this country
that are ours as American taxpayers and
camping.
And what's that?
Does that include the sky in the future?
That's probably not like that shit.
That shit's going to be filled with
advertising and stuff.
There's going to be a drone that just
sits there that just for a year,
probably try to make some laws against
that if it becomes a real problem.
But like yellowstone,
like,
look at Yellowstone National Park,
a place is fucking amazing man.
And it's,
it's an incredible place to visit.
It's incredible.
Like you have a real good chance of
seeing like bisons and shit.
You got a good chance to see in a
fucking bear too.
You gotta be real careful because um,
they've killed hikers like more than I
think it was more than one attack.
And I know at least one dead over the
last like five or six years,
because they think that these bears are
getting too accustomed to being around
people.
They know that if you break into
someone's car,
they usually have food in there.
They know that coolers usually have food
in them.
They get smart.
And so once they come around,
people once like,
fuck,
then they start coming around all the
time.
There's a,
I've been fucking with my neighbor like
eight,
he got a new one.
It's not,
want to admit this.
It's all funny.
Uh,
he's from,
I don't know,
but he,
he must got a new router because I have
nowhere.
I got a new Wifi,
like,
uh,
like network to join and it's unlocked.
Right.
So,
uh,
I just used it the other day just to see
like how fast it was just in case if I
needed to use it or whatever.
I forgot that I had it.
That's illegal,
isn't it?
Especially
you can't be let go and go.
This was my router's other name.
This is all a dream.
But I used to read word up magazine.
Exactly.
But I,
I,
uh,
I forgot that I had done it on my phone
and I been at connecting to it every
time I come home it just connects to his
Wifi.
But you know what I mean?
So the other day I was,
if you have apple tv you can like play
things on your apple tv from your phone.
It's called air place.
So I wanted to show a video to somebody
and I did it and I'm like,
why is this not working?
And I'm like,
wait a second one Wifi Martin.
I'm like,
I'm on the other guy's Wifi apple TV.
So like I've just been going like a
porn,
you know?
And the other day
you better stop right now.
It's so fun to do though.
I was just like,
yeah,
but it's really super illegal.
Yeah,
I guess it is.
What if you had kids in there?
I'm just playing gay porn.
That's exactly what I'm saying.
Get a bike is just so you could see you,
right?
Yeah,
exactly.
Wow.
I love that shit.
That that in printers like it when
people have printers on their Wifi and
you just print out dick pics all day on
their printers,
that's rude as well.
That was rude as well.
Let me ask you this,
have you ever wondered if like we can
feel Wifi and have you ever wondered
like if we can feel electricity in the
room,
like maybe it's not enough where we
could tell for sure if it was happening
or if it's not happening but enough
where there's like there's just like a
subtle underlying thing that your body
is experiencing.
It doesn't really make sense.
Like a radio wave,
like radio waves.
Why Fi's satellites,
satellite radio and TV,
satellite signals,
w gps signals,
what's all this.
We're sure for sure as it's not doing
anything to us cause we haven't really
been doing that for that long.
Is that something to be worried about?
You know,
if you take a cat who's most sensitive
animal ever that gave you that cats like
just sitting there and you turn on
something right next to it that has wifi
right next to his little whiskers,
you would think it would even maybe
twitch just a teeny bit.
You know,
and I'm sure it doesn't,
I'm sure.
Do you think so man,
when you like your remote control,
your cat,
if you like remote controlled your cat
like they were cat would like,
hey,
what the fuck you doing?
You Man.
I think if there's anything the cat
would feel it.
I think if any animal,
the cat would be the first thing that,
I mean the cats can tripping on ghost.
You know,
it's the cat.
Cats have amazing senses except the
sense like they're not intelligent.
They're not intelligent like a person.
They have amazing census,
like their senses are off the charts for
sure.
Yeah.
I would think that if anything a cat,
but I would think that their senses are
only around to do what they need to do
in the natural world.
I mean that's why the sense is a
sensitive smell.
They can feel things,
you know the it can like feel the ground
moving.
Their pads on their paws are like really
soft.
You know when they can,
they can walk like really quietly when
they're sneaking up on shit.
Like cats are fascinating little animals
man.
If you watched it and the cucumber
videos,
the cats,
it's probably one of my favorite thing
for some reason.
If you'd take,
don't do this to your cat.
Supposedly it it's mean,
but if you take a cucumber,
put it behind your cat when it's not
looking.
If the cat turns around and looks at the
cucumber,
it will freak the fuck out.
Like something in its DNA.
It makes it think it's a snake or
something.
But there's videos,
thousands of videos on youtube,
but people trying it almost all the
time.
If a cat sees a cucumber just laying up
behind it,
it will jump up and run away or great
things.
Have you seen these videos?
Why a cucumber?
I think it's something in their DNA that
that just thinks it's like,
oh,
dangerous snake or or,
but for whatever reason somebody just
found out by mistake that you put a
cucumber behind a cat,
it'll freak it out.
And then there's all these animal people
that are like,
don't do that.
You're stressing her cat out.
And I could see because all the cats
reactions are like death.
Like get the fuck out of here
immediately.
You know?
It's pretty funny though.
It's some of the funniest videos.
Do you ever see his and cucumber
on Youtube?
Yeah.
You don't want to freak cats out man.
This are pissing all over the place.
Yeah,
right,
exactly.
You Freak your cat out.
They will fucking piss in your pillow.
I told him.
Sure I don't,
I haven't had a cat and almost a year
and I don't miss the litter box.
I don't miss that smell.
I don't think I might.
I might never get a cat again.
The litter box things a fucking real
issue.
You have a box of shit in your house.
Yeah.
Fox is shit and cat piss from ungrateful
roommate.
That doesn't pay shit,
then it gets mad at you when he tried to
trim their hair.
Yeah.
My cat scan,
they get trimmed and they freak out
about it and it doesn't hurt them and I
pet him the whole time when the lady's
grooming him.
But uh,
one of my daughters is allergic to cats
and it makes a big difference if you,
we trim the cat's hair.
She doesn't have a bad allergy,
but it's certainly an hour change.
She's been tested for it.
So when I'm doing this,
I have to fucking just hang out with the
cat the entire time.
Like,
just chill,
man.
I'm telling you,
that ain't nothing.
I was just a little massage with a
little thing.
Do you trim it or do you have somebody
to call?
The lady does it.
She's a professional,
but it's a,
it's weird to see them fucking freaking
out about it.
I had a cat once.
It loved it.
She loved it.
Spazz spas would just chill like you,
you would do it and she'd,
she just hang out.
It's pass.
It's not around anymore.
I'm sorry.
She was 19.
Damn.
She made it a long time.
That was a cool cat.
She's a very cool cat.
I've been thinking though,
cause I mean I've lived with cats in my
whole entire life.
I've been thinking of getting one,
but I don't.
That kind of a thing is a real problem.
They'd get mad at you.
They pee places.
Yeah,
for whatever reason.
And if you have another animal,
it's just a lottery.
If it gets,
it gets along with the other hand.
The more now it's a total lottery.
Especially cats.
Cats usually don't get along with other
cats like it took my 19 year old cat,
a solid five years to get used to Oliver
Oliver.
It's like the easiest going guy too.
I love cats,
man.
They're cool.
They're like having these weird little
things that live with you.
You know the these weird little warm
love buckets.
It's just come over and just want love.
They just want to cuddle with you.
Like my cat oliver is brutal man.
I can't watch TV without this
motherfucker demand and massages.
He just like literally like headbutts
me,
drops his body into my lap,
rolls around.
He like demands massages.
He's hilarious.
You got a cucumber that cat?
Yeah,
he's a funny cat man.
My cat is funny as fuck.
He's so smart.
He's just still like,
just likes to chill and hang out.
And the other cat of the fluff at the
white one,
that one is um,
she's a little bit more assertive.
Like she,
it's funny like she attacks him like,
you know,
cats like we'll play fight.
It's always heard Jack and him it.
So it's always her like around a corner
and like he'll be like hanging out and
she'll be like,
he doesn't know that she's back there.
So she knows.
He doesn't know.
So her little legs start shaking and her
tail starts flickering and she's moving
real close and then she pounces on him
and fucks him up and then he put the
fuck bitch and he backs up and they
chase each other for a couple of feet.
It's hilarious man.
But they're both such pussies cause
they're both rag dolls like they're the
nicest cats.
Even when they fight,
they don't even fight.
Even when they fight like fucking,
they barely do anything to each other.
They're like fake fighting.
You know?
They like each other.
They're there.
They have fun together.
Yeah.
I mean that's cancer.
Some of the funniest,
funniest animals that
that exist.
She didn't get let him outside the shit
though.
Look,
a dog.
Just gross.
He's work.
The training.
Yeah,
they actually work pretty,
yeah.
Well actually you would think that that
wouldn't work,
but I know like three people that do it
and it worked almost immediately.
The Great.
Robert Schimmel had a bit about it.
I bet he does.
He goes,
you don't,
they can drink.
How's it go?
He goes,
you know,
they can train cats to use your toilet.
He goes,
yeah,
great.
Now when you don't have to go the
fucking cats in there.
Well fuck it.
I'll use this litter box and it goes.
Then your friend comes over.
We show a fucking mountain lion for a
bat.
Robert Schimmel,
God damn,
I miss that guy.
One of the first people I ever saw do
comedy.
He was so nice.
God Damn,
that guy was nice.
He was like one of the nicest people
I've ever met.
He was so friendly,
like every time I saw him.
So he's just happy,
like warm moment was so sad when that
guy got sick.
And then to recover from that and then
the car accident as fuck man.
Ooh.
There's a lot
people that,
that uh,
you know,
like when you go to the comedy store and
you look at the walls of how many,
you know,
great comics that just fucking
disappeared.
And I'll sit there sometimes and just
google everybody's name that's on the
wall.
Like what,
you know,
to see where they're at now.
And it's amazing how they just fall off,
like,
just disappear and never do anything.
Like what happened to the,
this person,
this person and this person.
Yeah.
I mean,
people get lost in life and people move
on to other shit too though.
You know,
sometimes people just decide they don't
want the stress of performing anymore.
Maybe they like other creative
endeavors.
You know,
you and I talked about that for a while
when you weren't doing stand up,
you know,
you were making these funny videos and
you're like,
well,
you know,
I'm,
I'm already kind of a comedian.
You know,
it's just my audience is the Internet.
When you were doing videos,
which that was an excuse because I
didn't want to do standup.
I mean,
after I did that Bob hope joke,
I'm like,
I'm good,
I'm
done.
I don't want to ever feel that pain ever
again.
Yeah.
And some people,
the risk of that pain,
it's just not,
it's not worth it.
It's not worth it to do that to your
life.
When you maybe also like painting or
maybe also like writing books or maybe
you know,
some people you don't have to do it.
You know,
like that's the thing about standups
tell.
Like if you do it and you don't want to
do it anymore,
everybody's like,
you don't even want to do it anymore.
Like,
yeah,
you fucking sell out.
Like people will say that about 80
murphy,
you know,
like,
man,
he's not real stand up.
He doesn't do standup anymore.
It'll get here,
like the hardcore bros talking like
that.
I can see it's hard because to be a
standup you really still,
even though how rich you get,
if you become a movie star,
you're a millionaire.
You still have to go and in practice and
go to the comedy clubs.
So I can see where it's easy to quit.
If you get to a certain point where
you're like,
you know what,
I don't,
I'm a grown adult,
am rich.
I have a wife and kids.
I don't want to go through this little
shitty club and practice these new
chokes,
you know,
so I can see how it's easy to get out of
comedy,
you know?
Yeah.
You just don't want the pain of it.
You don't want,
it's like exhausting cause like safe.
You started some pursuit in your life.
Like if you started off and you are a
painter when a painting school and all
that Shit and you got through it and you
became a,
you know,
a respected artist and you're painting
all the time,
but you fucking hated painting.
Like you were done with it like you had
done with it.
You want to go build sailboats,
you wanted to,
you have these other ideas in your head
that you want to pursue,
like happens to people,
you know,
so.
So if they quit doing,
stand up,
you know,
that's okay.
Did you ever think you ever see me,
I'm off hills home.
Do you ever think there's like something
that you haven't started yet?
Like,
like,
you know,
I'm just,
I'm going to learn how to play guitar
this year.
Like is there anything that you've in
the back of your head that you've kind
of fucked around with?
Like the idea of
no,
because I suck so hard at the new things
that I'm doing already.
Is that true?
You started becoming an archer and now
you're fucking Robin Hood and you're
like,
what are they like?
Well,
it's,
I'm not good at all.
I'm constantly practicing at archery,
but as you compare it to me,
to somebody who's really good,
like I'm,
I put a lot of hours in,
I practice a lot.
I,
I'll shoot like sometimes a hundred
hours in a day.
Wow.
Yeah.
But um,
it's,
cause I kind of obsessed with it.
And some sort of a weird way,
you know,
it's fascinating to me.
So that's one thing I already obsessed
with that I suck at.
And when I meet you like compare me to
someone like Cameron Hanes or a
professional archer that you like might
see on,
like a friend of mine just sent me this
photo of my friend Johnny Rivet sent me
this photo of this young girl.
She's like 20 years old and she's won
like I think he said three world
championships in a row and she's an
archer.
They don't like those people were like
really good with bows and arrows.
Like there's a total next level when
it's like they're shooting at like 50
yards and they're hitting the bullseye
every time.
And the on the acts itself at 50 yards,
they're just dead calm and just dead on
the inside.
And then when they released that string,
nothing moves and that Arrow goes
sailing right into that acts.
And they can do it repeatedly.
They can do it like 10 times in a row
sometimes.
I mean,
these people were freaks.
It's really interesting to watch.
We used to do archery,
an elementary school that was a part of
our physical education and I'm sure you
can't do that anymore.
Like I,
I probably,
yeah,
I bet not.
Is it illegal to walk around Robin Hood
style with the arch you like,
you know,
like a bow and Arrow?
Like is like,
can I walk into like an old guard and
not get kicked out if I have a
no,
they wouldn't let you in.
It's a weapon.
Yeah,
it's a weapon.
It's a slingshot to like,
I had some friends who brought their
bows to Vegas and they,
uh,
the,
the hotel wouldn't let them take him up
to their room.
Wow.
Really?
Yeah.
They had to check them.
They had to check in with the hotel.
It didn't seem right.
No,
it's seemed well,
yeah though it does like what some
fucking asshole is going to be on your
elevator with a bow and Arrow,
but you have a shooting people in the
area,
but you can't like trust these people.
You don't know him.
These people,
they come in,
they're not even Americans.
They got a bow and arrow.
They're crazy.
I mean,
what?
No,
you can't have this in your room.
Give us,
give me that thing.
You know,
like you come to the saloon,
put your fucking gun in the bucket,
sir.
You know hotel,
but give me your fucking bow and arrow.
No,
you can't practice it in your room and
accidentally shoot the fucking
television.
I don't know you.
What if you get whiskey it up and you're
working on your fucking draw length in
your hotel room and you send your Arrow
flying through the middle of the
electrical box.
It caused a fucking 13 story fire that
killed a thousand people.
Yeah,
but what have you used the steak night
from your state?
Can you just start stabbing everybody?
You know,
it's like,
I think of that a steak knife would be
way more dangerous than a bow.
You got to stop putting ideas in
people's heads.
It's like airplanes.
It's like I always freak out word like,
oh,
you can't have a razor blade on the
airplane,
but yet you could have a Mac book pro
that you can smack over the head of
somebody and probably kill him.
It's hard to grip though.
Sure.
Like real impact,
but a skateboard,
he's if fuck somebody up on a
skateboard,
you know,
you can,
I don't think they were going to change
it,
but I don't think they did.
They were going to make it so that it's
legal to bring pool cues on.
But uh,
I think they made it so that it's not
anymore
cause like they thought that you beat
people up with a pool cue but you,
uh,
skateboards,
probably a better weapon than a pool cue
maybe.
Hmm.
More distance.
Certainly more distance she knew.
And the person you're trying to hit with
a skateboard,
which makes it more effective in a lot
of places because you could hit somebody
in,
they can't hit you yet.
Poke,
he's going to break pretty quick,
right though.
One good hit and maybe that's
skateboards,
got trucks that hands on what it's out
of.
But,
uh,
most pool cues have multiple pieces and
that's,
that's part of the problem.
It's not one gigantic piece of wood
because for most,
for the most part,
like if you'd see like a,
a beautiful pool cue,
what a lot of players,
like they liked the queue to be 19
ounces.
So,
um,
they,
they work on making this a few people
that like 20,
20 is rare.
Like sometimes you'll find the outliers
that like something heavy,
but they're pretty specifically between
18 and 20 ounces.
Now for a normal person that would seem
like,
well what's the difference?
Well to the pool players,
like it's uh,
the professionals and it's a touch that
they develop where they know the exact
weight of their queue and so the exact
impact in half,
so they have to balance it out.
And a lot of times the way they bounce
it out is by using different kinds of
woods leaves one kind of wood for what
you see,
but another kind of wood for under the
wrap.
And it'll be a lighter,
like a maple,
like similar to like maybe shaft would
even like.
And then on the outsides of the,
um,
the front and the back,
it might even just be cord where they
drill through the actual hardwood and
they stuff a core in there of a softer
would.
So the cue achieves the desired look and
may be uniform field,
but it has a lower mass,
lower weight so he can get it down to
like maybe even below 19 ounces or you
know,
for reasonably,
uh,
well done.
Cute.
But if you hit somebody the head with
that,
it's going to break for the most part.
Yeah.
But if you get one of those fucking
house cues,
like those full splice house cues and
you grab the,
the hard end,
the dark end,
you could beat the fuck out of somebody
with one of those.
That's a different animal because that's
an one solid piece of wood,
especially those old school ones.
Those are like the Dufferin blanks,
you know,
it's like a,
uh,
like a rosewood on the bottom and a
maple on the top and right from the
splice where it's white,
that stuff's going to break.
But the stuff above it,
you could beat the fuck out of somebody
with the stuff above it.
That hard shit.
You could,
you could hit them as hard as you want.
You probably wouldn't break it.
Probably be pretty hard.
Yeah.
People were like all four could do it
bro.
Okay.
Maybe you can,
but maybe like a normal person would be.
It would be very hard to break that on
somebody.
You can do it.
You could be some fucking,
you know,
incredible hulk type character and just
smash it on the first attempt.
But I would imagine like it's a much
harder and denser,
uh,
like weapon than a,
like a standard,
like very pretty pool cue or someone
like a lot of Pokios or like artistic.
It's really interesting because people
outside the pool world,
they would,
they would think like,
what are you talking about?
There's a,
there's like a collectors like group of
pool cue addicts and they're addicted to
pool cues.
They collect cues.
But Dude,
you'd be,
there's guys out there
that have collections.
They're worth 1 million bucks and more
and pool cues.
Yeah.
There's people that have coin
collections of butterfly things like
people that collect butterflies.
That's the creepiest shit head.
You got a dead bug pins all over it.
I've gotten a new one.
I'm cautious.
Knew who won.
There was um,
uh,
Terence Mckenna and an old lecture was
talking about,
um,
catching bugs and that there's something
like,
because we used to eat bugs a lot when
we were like primates,
that there's almost like this genetic
excitement thing that comes when you
catch a bug.
So it's similar to what happens when you
catch a fish.
You know,
that thing that happens when you catch a
fish,
if you fish for it,
um,
if you're a fish and then ate it,
uh,
once,
yes,
just once.
Yeah.
You haven't been fishing since dad,
like 14,
15.
He would always take me fishing.
That's wow.
Yeah,
that's fish since then.
Fishing's fun,
man.
It's awesome.
It's a great way to catch a meal to
right.
And um,
but there's some weird fucking primal
thing that happens when you pull it out
of the water.
Oh he feel like smeagol like or
something,
you know,
it's like he gets like,
it's flopping around,
attack me.
You know,
there's something weird about it.
There's something weird about a fish.
You catching something and some alien
world yanking it out of their lives in
the water.
There's a living thing in the water and
you can see him down there fucking cast
to them and you throw a piece of meat
that's covered by a hook and he bites
the meat and you will fucking,
you guys,
dad hooked through the top of his mouth,
a giant steel barb digs into his face
and then he's still fighting like hard,
like polling left and right and left and
the rod is pulling the real is fucking
the,
what is that thing called?
The clicky thing on the wheel.
The drag,
the drag and the real is it's peeling
cause it's fucking fish pulling outline
and you finally get him in there and you
suck them out of his dementia and he's
flopping around your boat.
That is a crazy experience to crazy.
You just pulled some alien creature.
It's like lives in the water.
500 years from now,
let's say 500 years.
They're definitely going to figure out
how to take animals and make them be
able to communicate to us.
They're going to make that crossover.
500 years.
Fuck yeah,
maybe not even 500 years.
Right?
But when that happens,
we're not going to go fishing anymore
cause you're going to be like talking to
fucking fish are all going to die.
We're all going to be vegans.
We're going to be forced to be vegans
because of technology.
Well if we do know for sure what an
animal's feeling when it dies,
it would definitely be way hard.
Eat me
way harder.
That's um,
that's the argument of like the,
the Vegan movement.
That makes the most sense because if
we'd really knew,
but here's the thing,
a lot of these motherfuckers didn't even
care about each other.
Like those deer that I eat,
they kill each other all the time.
They fucking stab each other with the
horns and to their heads.
Bears,
bears early.
Cannibals,
they're all cannibals.
People get angry.
Like if you eat black bear,
like first of all,
black bears,
delicious and bears are fucking
monsters.
They're cannibals.
It's,
that doesn't mean we don't want to kill
them or don't want,
um,
uh,
let them live or wanting to extinguish
all of them.
No,
no.
They're cool.
It's cool having these animals,
but they don't give a fuck about you get
it.
Kinda recognize that they do not give a
fuck about you until they start talking
to us and then we find out they're just
very hard to get to know.
But they were really loving it.
He just got to take it.
Imagine if you found out what they were
thinking.
Could you imagine if you could read
minds and you just looked out into a
pack of wolves?
There was chasing elk up to the top of a
mountain.
Do you know how terrified you would be
if you could read the mind of a wolf?
He'd be like,
Oh my God,
we've got to kill them all.
we got to kill them all to the,
all these you want to do is kill.
I told the one and two Kale if we could
read them,
but we don't read their minds.
So we look at him like,
oh,
listen to him.
How
there's just jack that they got to kill
again today.
You know,
they have a problem with these elk that
they find where a wolves get into these
a elk elk populations and they decimate
the hertz.
They,
they don't even eat everything they
kill.
It's crazy.
They'll kill like many elk and just
leave half the body behind her more.
They don't just sit and eat it until
they're done.
They kill again.
Just like dogs.
Do you know?
You ever,
you ever heard of it?
Like my dog got it.
My chickens.
Once my dog is killed,
two of my chickens.
It's a,
it's a fucking real drag,
but it's instinct.
You know?
It's not a bad dog.
It's just nobody told he can't talk.
He doesn't know in his mind,
chickens or death.
You've got to kill that fucking thing.
There it is.
Go get it.
It's like it's programmed in him,
so he's a dog.
It's like you literally cannot take it
out of them.
I mean,
you could grow them up with from the
time they're puppies with chickens,
just like I did with my cats or the dogs
don't think of the cats is the enemy,
but if they don't grow up with them,
they don't just accept chickens into the
fucking yard and the dog is seven years
old.
He's like,
what the fuck it is?
Oh,
the chickens live with us.
They're our friends.
Oh yeah,
your friends.
Yeah.
Your friends.
Okay.
Yeah,
I'll just leave me alone.
When your friends want to talk to them,
just Jack Them.
He was just Jack and check.
It's not his fault,
it's his dog instincts.
Me Never knew that.
You're not supposed to eat chickens
before.
He's a grown dog.
Wolves are very similar in that way.
They want to kill things and they're
beautiful and they're amazing.
I'm not saying we shouldn't have wolves,
but people have this idea that we
shouldn't keep an eye on those fucking
things.
I'm Tom,
I'm tired of talking to people about
this.
Like yeah,
wolves are awesome.
It's like there was a,
um,
in Canada they're using helicopters to
shoot wolves.
Yeah.
Cause the Caribou population is getting
decimated because they just go on a jack
and spree,
Eh,
the wolves just take over.
They just run rampant when they're get
to a sufficient population where they
can just dominate herds and surround
them.
And they're like raising them like
cattle.
They're monsters.
Matt and the Jack Gigantic numbers of a,
if they want to,
they're not conservationists.
Have you heard about the people taking
dogs in the New York City at night to
take an hunt out?
Rats.
Well look,
good luck with that little dogs too.
Like little,
like fun,
loving,
like leaving like shit too.
And they just fucking,
just,
you made me picture it cause I remember
hearing a,
like Mike Rowe,
the guy from dirty jobs talking on,
uh,
the OPN,
Jimmy show one day about it.
Like if he went out,
I didn't think he went out with these
people for a few nights in a row and
made a little documentary online trying
to find it right now.
But uh,
they said it was crazy.
Like the guard for their backs and just
break their backs and toss them around
and just throw them and go after another
one.
Oh my God.
Hundreds will come out of a rap pile or
like in a dumpster and shit.
Like that dog just jacking him.
Oh my God,
that's so crazy though.
But they just do that.
That's their instinct.
Yeah.
As an adult,
I've never haven't looked at it.
Chicken,
the chickens,
but,
but like is it like an asshole and
vagina like every other animal and it's
a no,
it,
it is a,
I forget the word egg whole succulent.
What does the word,
there's a word of the opening.
I forget,
forget what the word for the,
for the opening rather.
I forget what it is,
but uh,
it's a,
it's a whole that everything comes out
of Piss,
shit,
babies,
everything.
That seems like an upgrade.
But what's the name of that?
Do you know what the name of that hole
is?
I just find out what a chicken's hole.
I just remember that.
Oh,
that old porn video
we're looking at is the chicken wearing
sweatpants and it's fucking adorable.
So funny.
It's really funny.
It's adorable.
I just remember that old video of that
dude fucking that chicken and I just
wondered,
you know,
if that's legit,
like if,
you know,
if people definitely fuck chickens
fender,
it just seems sort of like,
well,
if you think about it,
this may know better.
It's like a event or event.
Colloquia that's the fun,
that's the,
that's the word I was trying to,
uh,
the technical word,
but vent sounds like I can remember
that.
But yeah,
everything comes out of one hall.
It's interesting.
It's like it can't be,
it has to be pretty dirty in there.
Is this the,
Oh my God,
these dogs are just letting it loose on
rats.
Oh God.
Oh,
this is so crazy.
Oh my gosh.
Oh my God.
This is so crazy.
This doesn't show a ton of it.
Portion of it.
There's more of it online.
If you want to look it up.
Powerful.
Mike Rowe.
That's pretty funny.
Mike Rowe has some cool ass subjects.
His show is fascinating.
That's the dirty jobs guy,
right?
Yeah,
he does.
Uh,
he did another one too,
right?
Did dirty jobs and another one.
This is fucked up.
These dogs jacket rats.
Oh,
it's just so fucked up.
Wow.
That's fucked up.
That's what he says on here.
It's unlike anything he's ever seen.
Which after doing all the dirty jobs,
that's,
that's pretty fucked up.
I've talked to about this I believe
before,
once,
um,
at least,
but there was one time where I was in
New York and uh,
yet I had to use a pay phone.
I didn't have a cell phone at the time
and it was,
uh,
early nineties.
I guess real early nineties and I parked
my car at this gas station.
I was pumping the gas,
I set the pump on it,
and then I went over to the payphone and
in the time it took me to walk from that
car to the pay phone,
put the coins in and turnaround.
There was three rats on my car.
They were running over the top of my
wheel wells.
They were running over the top where the
wheel is and then down under,
and then another one would come up and
jump up and go down under.
And I was like,
what the fuck?
Like they were everywhere,
man.
There was so many of them.
It's so creepy because I was watching it
going through.
You can't,
you can't stop these things.
Who's got many of them?
There are.
I know.
It was just thinking like,
what is it like to sleep in these
buildings and hear those things running
through your walls.
Oh yeah,
this is fun.
What did these,
but,
but these rats can have like rabies and
one of them made it,
one of them made it into the sewer.
Huh?
Wow.
Fuck.
Yeah.
Oh God.
Killer rap.
Awful.
Uh,
that was junk.
They give the dog a rabies shot.
Simple.
I do.
I did this podcast with tiffany the
other day in my back in a wreck,
like ran right over foot.
I think it might've ran in my house
though.
And so now I'd be like freaked out
thing.
There's a rat in my house,
my,
my cat fluff fat.
We were uh,
eating and a cat walks over to the
fucking table with a dried out rat,
like an old dead rat.
Oh crap.
Like dude,
like I have,
I have some work done on my basement and
I'm just thinking maybe there was like
something trapped in the wall that life
as a,
they were cutting to the wall.
She got the old dead rata.
I don't,
I have no idea where the fuck came from,
but it was in my house and it was like a
mummy man.
Oh,
maybe it was under like a couch or
something or maybe it doesn't make
sense.
We've tried to figure it out.
We try to figure this fucking say
dismissed.
I hate this,
but cats will find shit,
you know,
I,
cats will find shit.
They bring it to you like a,
yeah.
So weird.
It's so weird.
They do that.
So weird,
delicate little fucking massage.
Demanders that's what they are.
Little tiny massage demanders I like,
I make the mistake sometimes it's trying
to write on the couch,
like with the laptops,
try write shit and um,
this motherfucker just relentless.
He'll come up and just bang,
headbutting my hand,
step on the keys.
He doesn't give a fuck and you push him
off.
He's like,
yeah,
I know you pushed me off and now I'm
back and I want the exact same thing I
wanted a couple of seconds ago.
But uh,
it was going to try and do a little
slower.
Maybe.
Like he doesn't give a fuck.
He just wants massages,
period.
Give it to me.
I would have to spray him with water to
get them off me.
That's the only one.
Even that just the sound,
but I don't want it to,
I don't want to do that.
I just want them to chill out.
Just once you just relax,
just hang out with me,
man.
I don't have to demand attention.
You fucker.
You know?
Did you see that there's a,
I guess a new either movie or series Oj
Simpson versus the people?
Yeah.
You know,
I was talking about this with
someone and uh,
it was a good point,
um,
that the people that are growing up
today,
like the 20 year olds,
they don't even know that story.
I think for us it was a part of our life
growing up.
Could we were like,
Holy Shit,
he got off.
He got off.
Oh my God.
Everybody was pretty much convinced he
was guilty except those people that
needed to be convinced
the lead up to it.
Some of the most popular movies,
the naked gun series,
we all kind of fell in love with this
like guy,
you know,
it was kind of like
what not that guy and have nowhere that
took two years of everyone's life
following this guy's story.
And still,
it's still fascinating to this day when
you see him on tv,
when there's like some sort of a prison
thing going on.
And then you see they have photos of
them and they're moving them around or
something like that.
So like,
Whoa,
whew.
There's a strange to see man.
I wonder if there's any way to do any
new evidence using today's DNA
technology to find out if he,
you know,
like this,
this making the murder,
you know,
you haven't watched it yet.
Just making this murder things
interesting cause of like,
you know,
like the technology that they're using
and stuff like jumping a Ramsey.
Like they,
it seems like they should be able to
find who killed her now you using
today's technology.
Yeah.
I don't know how much evidence they
still have that they have saved.
I don't know how that works.
Yeah.
Do you know how that works?
I'm sure they have evidence.
I mean,
I would imagine.
Yeah,
right.
They can go back in there and find,
you know,
use this.
I don't know,
man.
I think the real problem with that John
Benet things that they had fucked up the
evidence.
One of the parts of the,
the murder case that was fucked up as it
was like fresh snow and uh,
these people would have been able to
find footprints and the fresh snow and
these cops tread all over everything and
that
that was a big mistake.
And that the way they investigated it,
apparently there were a bunch of
criticisms about the way they handle it.
They just had never handled a case like
that before as the boulder police
department,
Boulder's a small town and the Johan,
we got a lot of fucking crazy people
murdering their kids or in I'll
allegedly,
they don't even know who did it.
Right.
They never figured out who did it.
Yeah.
I still think it's the family.
Well,
everybody thinks it's the family,
but that's a fucking crazy indictment if
you're wrong.
You bought that crazy conspiracy theory
the other day that they think there's,
the online world thinks there's some,
uh,
crazy con,
a serial killer that's tied to this.
Oh my God.
They've linked him to that Jon Benet
Ramsey thing to the same serial killer.
Like he's done these crazy stories that
have no explanation for who did what and
someone else's got blamed for it.
It's a,
it's a crazy story too,
but who knows if there's anything,
anything in there.
Wow.
Well,
I dunno man,
but it's the point being like if they
wanted to try to figure out who the
murderer was today,
you would have a real problem.
I think with the evidence being
contaminated.
I mean,
how much evidence they have.
What about there?
How long does the body last before you
can zoom it and examine it?
You know,
what can you get from that?
Who the fuck knows?
I don't have those answers.
Remember those Hbo Shows?
Uh,
the,
the real autopsy series.
You can't watch it,
dude,
that guy,
that guy used to freak me out that
Michael Baden,
you know that guy.
The autopsy.
Got It.
Yeah.
I couldn't watch those shows,
but who,
I'm not into that like,
like I do,
I don't know if we talked about this,
but there's like this bridge in Pasadena
called suicide bridge and it was made in
like,
I believe the 30s and like people die
all the time off the spreads.
They just go there and kill themselves.
I know somebody that was hiking and he
was just hiking and there's this a girl
dead on the,
on the,
on the trail because there's like a
trail that goes on the bottom of it.
Oh my God.
And then somebody told me,
I know if this is true,
but somebody told me that like when they
have huge rain storms,
that all these bones just kind of washed
down from this big or that sounds like
some skin.
Oh.
But yeah,
this is the balls down the mountain.
And then like in the trail that you just
like see like little bone here and there
that,
uh,
from bodies that like jumped and were
never found in this side of this.
Wow.
There's that many people have done it.
I mean,
it's totally,
it's not like they're going to do a
thorough job of cleaning you if he
jumped off a bridge and splatter all
over the rocks.
Yeah.
I think how much can they clean up?
I think it's over a hundred people
though.
She jumped off the last girl,
that girl that,
that my friend took it.
He like,
he sent me a photo of her body just
laying there,
but he,
he's,
I guess that girl,
uh,
lived in woodland hills and she was like
38 and she just,
that's it.
I'm just going to go to this suicide
bridge and do it.
Oh my God.
That's awful.
Yeah.
Fuck man.
Falling.
Just not seem like poop proper way.
It's fucking real though.
I bet the rush,
when you realize you've pulled that
trigger and done that.
I saw that video you posted the Andy
Stumpf just teasing you guys to go jump
with them.
They'll look like he landed on the
ground at the end of it,
but I think it was triggering his
parachute parachute.
Oh,
he's terrifying.
I don't know.
I don't know what it's called,
but there's this thing in Mexico where
it's a restaurant that's up in the air
where you're sitting glass bottom in the
middle of the air,
just eating a hot air balloon.
No,
it's uh,
it's like,
uh,
I don't know if you can find it,
but like,
like a,
it's like you sit down on these chairs
and the whole thing is just kind of like
way up in the air.
I don't know.
There it is.
And you eat like super high up.
Oh my fuck.
Oh,
dinner in the sky.
It's 150 feet in the air.
Why would you ever want to do that dude?
Seriously.
Fuck that.
But if you have to go to the bathroom,
what if you do?
What if you're eating with Mike
Goldberg?
Yeah,
but you have to like,
sorry,
we're going to have to lower this.
Like you eat with this.
Oh fuck.
Fuck Outta here.
Oh my God.
It's on Crane Ladies and gentlemen.
It's in Mexico so you don't even know
you're strapped in and they're giving
you food while this whole thing fucking
sways back and forth and the breeze,
they're taking selfies.
All my God,
you people are freaking me out.
I'm nowhere near that thing and I'm
freaking out.
My toes are clenched up.
My fingers are crunched up.
I heights,
man,
I can't do it.
Oh my God.
The Shit you used to do on fear factor,
man,
I don't even understand how those people
couldn't do it.
I am so glad that nobody ever got hurt
doing that.
You could do a show up there if you
want.
Oh,
marriage in the sky.
This guy.
Wow.
Let's just promote other people doing
it.
Coco in the sky.
I'll promote a joey diaz performance
cock suckers walking from the clouds.
Dude,
last time I did his podcast,
him in lead,
just dropped acid and,
and then he gave us these stars and I
knew I wasn't going to eat one,
but I ate one.
George,
I was with George Perez.
George couldn't feel his whole entire
face,
the whole thing.
And then near the end maybe he's like,
that song,
I can't feel my face when
I look over at Lido and his eyes are
rolled back in his head and like that
guy,
man,
he like Joey.
Really?
He's an animal.
He's not here to play games.
Who?
Trops acid?
The like nine at night on a Sunday
soldier.
Like a fucking soldier.
He's an original.
You got to let him be him.
He knows what he's doing.
Oh yeah,
I know he does.
Where Lito spent the night at the studio
though and I'm just like,
man,
if you eat ass,
that's like a 10 to 11 hour trip
usually.
So Joey after the podcast is probably
like,
all right,
great.
Take care.
And this port,
Lisa's neither tripping on acid and it's
this random office building somewhere.
Oh,
how long is acid typically last?
It used to last,
I would say about 11 hours too.
You're like,
all right,
I think I could go to bed now.
Oh my gosh.
Yeah,
it's not cool.
It's like,
uh,
it's like Mush,
like mushrooms times five.
It used to be,
I don't know if it's the same.
My friend just did a payoti ceremony.
Oh,
hollow and native American.
Would you ever do that?
Would you ever do the,
here's the problem with ceremonies,
you doing them with a bunch of people
who don't even know,
and there were some times she gets
around,
we're just going to freak out.
You know,
when you want to do your payoti manage,
probably be alone or be with someone you
trust.
I think,
you know,
if you get lucky and catch a good group,
you might have to Tom your life at a
payload,
a ceremony,
or you could,
uh,
you could just be hanging out with
people who are completely out of their
fucking mind and also do drugs.
That's possible too.
Like you don't have any control.
You're just guessing whether or not this
is going to make sense.
No,
thank you.
I think pay is,
that's the one where you puke all the
time and then the last days or
something,
right.
You,
it is a tricky one,
man.
It's some sort of a,
um,
like it's from a Cactus,
right?
And there's another drug that's just
like pod that's also from a cactus that
uh,
that,
that I think you can also get similar
effects from it.
I can't remember the name of the Cactus,
but I guess in Mexico it's,
you can find them all over the place.
There's a movie about,
about it too.
I forget the name of the movie,
but there's a movie about this guy
that's just trying to get this cactus
and trip on.
I forget what is the active ingredient
pot,
right?
Isn't there a masculine mask?
When I was in high school,
it was mask.
I think I was,
the kid dropped two hits a mask and
they'd say Mush Mush.
The kid dropped two hits,
a mask.
He was fucked.
Like I remember like dropping Maskelyne
like people would talk about dropping
mask and I'd be like,
you gotta be out of your fucking mind.
There's no way you people,
animals.
There's a future looks like in the early
eighties,
seventies that it seems like people used
to always talk about that.
Like that don't exist in like masculine.
Yeah.
This is good land.
And there was something that [inaudible]
has showed me a bottle of recently that
it was like,
what the fuck?
I didn't even know that existed.
Quite lids.
Yeah.
That's the bill cosby drugged is that,
yeah,
we'll allegedly that's what he allegedly
was in trouble for was a procuring or
giving these girls this stuff allegedly,
you know,
they're saying now that,
uh,
there was a been some problems with the
trial.
It's like the first day,
there was some article that was written
today that are red.
They were saying that the one of the key
witnesses doesn't think that it's legal
to,
uh,
to prosecute based on the deal that
cosby got back down.
I think that's Oh yeah,
he made
a deal.
Yeah,
I heard,
yeah.
That it was that bill cosby was about to
buy NBC and I earned the Illuminati.
Yeah,
man.
Illuminati.
Don't try to take him down,
man.
I've heard that too.
Yeah.
Where did I read that?
So,
uh,
so this guy was essentially saying that
he's not on bill cosby side,
but the actual law,
the way the law is written,
he gave them some sort of a deal in,
um,
though the reason why he was willing to,
uh,
give out the statement that he made,
you know,
what's that called?
Declaration or whatever the fuck it is
when they,
when you're,
um,
anyway,
in court,
he,
he deposition.
So he was willing to do the deposition
based on the fact that he couldn't get
prosecuted,
prosecuted for it.
So now that they want to prosecute him
for the same case,
this guy thinks that that is not legal.
Hmm.
How old evidence about,
I don't know.
We're talking about the same case just
because there's so many cases.
Yeah.
It's another smoke and fire.
That's a,
that's a terrifying one though,
that this guy was doing that to people.
We all know that.
People like that though.
Just unfortunately dps guys.
Yeah,
but that's such a deep level,
man.
That's such a scary level.
Scary level of a tattooed cause.
The scariest.
I mean,
you're watching,
you're looking at people lying
unconscious,
you know,
and then you're fucking them.
Is it lying on conscious or just not
remembering is lacking out?
Who knows?
Man,
I don't know.
I think a lot of them are saying it's
blacking out.
You know,
man,
the trauma of that.
You imagine if you just thought that guy
was really cool and you want her to hang
out with them and you woke up with one,
one shoe on and your,
your panties are down by your ankles and
you realize what happened,
what,
and you don't even know what to say.
You know what I mean?
You don't even know what to say.
You're like,
what happened?
What?
And especially if you're drinking
together and you're having fun having a
couple of cocktails,
you don't think anything's going wrong.
I this diet,
now I have one drink,
I'm wasted.
And uh,
the other day,
luckily I didn't drive.
The other day I had like two or three
drinks and Black Super Bravo blackout.
Like,
like I had no idea how I got home.
I did.
It had no idea I would like anything
that happened.
But that Shit's scary because I existed
as a human for at least three to four
hours.
I even like I checked my phone,
I was texting people,
well they ciro honestly when you drink a
lot that's,
it starts happening like later in your
life that like people that um,
are
there getting drunk like five,
six a week and I'm not saying you
necessarily wear,
but they're,
their tolerance starts to like drop off
their body's ability to fight it off,
starts to like drop off and the
propensity towards blackouts,
it's when,
the way it's been explained to me by
someone who had a problem with it,
that it gets to this point where it's
just like super common to blackout or it
didn't use to be.
So it just wears on you over time.
It's definitely where I've been like,
oh I don't remember.
I talked to you last night and I like
that stuff but it's just like you
remember pieces,
this is,
this is the first time I that I can
remember that it was so such a straight
blackout.
Like I was freaked out.
Like I just sat there and it was just
trying to remember anything that
happened and like the last for four
hours or whatever,
cut to was my bathroom covered with
blood.
Oh yeah,
man.
Blackouts a terrifying because people,
they black out and they get behind a
wheel.
Yeah.
It is so insane that we have a culture
that sells alcohol everywhere.
You can buy guns everywhere.
You can do all this crazy shit,
but you still can't openly by,
we'd
like the,
if the,
as,
if that's going to be the tipping point
is if we just,
this whole country just says,
all right,
let's all just relax and,
we're going to let it through.
Like as if that,
that would somehow another
make this whole thing fall apart.
I'm sorry,
go ahead.
No,
no,
that's it.
I,
I just,
you know,
the whole marijuana thing recently,
I,
uh,
I keep on forgetting that,
that it's illegal.
Like about the other day,
I was just like,
wow,
this is actually illegal.
What I'm doing right now.
You just kind of forget that marijuana
is still illegal.
Well,
Brian,
you have a prescription,
right?
Right.
But the number one thing that cops are
being trained for and,
and the work cases is marijuana duis
now.
Like,
really?
Yeah,
like my friend's a lawyer and he goes,
dude,
it's surpassing drunk driving now as far
as like the money,
uh,
just how many,
how many,
uh,
people they catch for marijuana duis and
it's the same Dui driving under the
influence is the same as alcohol.
How do they prove it?
They have tests now that they can
immediately just test you and they're
not the most accurate.
So that's the only,
that's the only thing that the,
that you have going for you.
But if they,
if they pull you over and there's smoke
coming out of your window or they see a
joint on you,
you know,
that just got burned.
They can,
they can,
they can test you now and go,
Oh yeah,
you have marijuana in your system.
You got a Dui.
No matter if you have a license,
no matter if you have anything.
And it's totally like one of those
things.
And he's telling me,
I'm like,
she's just Christ.
You know,
like you don't think about that is still
illegal and if it wasn't
illegal,
okay,
let's just say it's legal,
right?
I think we can all
point to like at least one or two people
that we know that probably shouldn't
drive high.
Yeah,
yeah,
absolutely.
So they're impaired,
right?
But it's a fucking way different kind of
impairment than the kind of impairment
that you would get from alcohol.
Like it's not like a muscular
coordination type of impairment.
It's a different impairment.
It's like a judgment impairment perhaps
or just freak out the anxiety like that,
that kind of impairment and the
inability to recognize when to merge
when not the merge.
Oh,
I'm fucking freaking out,
man.
That could happen for sure.
That can definitely happen and that
should be taken into consideration
whenever you make it legal to do
anything.
We agree that it's all legal to drink
caffeine and getting your car.
We all agree that it's speed.
You could have a monster energy drink
sitting in your cup holder when a cop
pulls you over.
That's math,
man.
It's an awesome math.
It's delicious,
but it's obviously not math,
but it's,
it's like probably like how much
caffeine is in one of those monster
energy drinks
a lot.
Dude.
Those things,
if you don't want to play games,
if you want to just kick crazy,
just chug one of those big ones.
Like the ones that looked like a,
the lemonade cancels giant lemonade cans
like chuck,
one of those fucking things.
Monster energy drink those big giant
tall boys.
Those things are ridiculous.
Not that much.
Really says it says 160 milligrams per
16 ounce cane.
Wow.
What about starbucks?
That's interesting.
Yeah.
So what else is in there that uh,
well there's probably a lot of sugar for
sure.
Fuck.
What about sugar free?
The will have sugar free ones.
That's interesting.
I would've thought it was way more.
I was going to add to what you're just
saying though,
but there's a certain amount of people
you know that shouldn't be driving
anyway,
even when they're stone sober.
They just,
they can't handle all the inputs.
We have a winner,
Jamie van and with a,
when I,
yeah,
I know a girl that,
that I'm sure,
I don't think she knows she's driving
when she's driving.
You know what I mean?
Like,
like I'm constantly like,
you know,
the lights,
red lights,
right.
Like if I wasn't here,
you would have just ran that.
Uh,
like I was watching this lady texted him
drive yesterday completely in the wrong
lane.
I was like,
look at this bitch completely in the
oncoming lane just over crossing over,
right
to double yellow lines,
phone in her hand,
texting,
looking up swerves back in.
I was like,
oh my God,
she's crossed right over into this
oncoming street.
Have you had an every ever had a,
any kind of panic attack or panic,
panicky feeling from we'd recently?
No.
If I have any panic attacks I've had
from,
we'd have been,
uh,
the big ones have all been from edibles.
Yeah.
And the panic attacks have been more
like
just a super hard introspective,
objective view of life and death and the
cycle of things and the son running out
of fuel eventually.
This is planet no longer being viable
for life,
that all those things are gonna happen
millions and millions of years in the
future for you.
Not so much time.
Everybody,
not so much time.
If you're born today,
well congratulations.
You only have a hundred years or if
you're,
you're really,
really,
really lucky.
So for all of us,
this whole thing is a quick flash where
we try to figure out what's going on.
It's a quick flash,
it's happening right in front of our
faces and we're living it and while
we're living it,
we're going,
what is going on here?
Like what?
What are we exactly doing?
What are we exactly doing or working and
sleeping and eating and fucking and
going to the movies.
But what are we doing?
What is this?
What is this race?
What does this race of people doing?
What does this weird thing that only has
a hundred years of life?
It just starts to figure out the how
bizarre and weird this whole thing is
before it's snuffed out and the new
ones,
what they're similarly short lifespan
benefit from all the information passed
on by the ones before them,
but still go through life like it's a
dream.
Still do everything you do and thank
you.
Is this real?
What,
what is this life like?
What does the sky,
what is this infinity above my head that
no one talks about every day?
Infinity is above your head.
What do you do?
You pull the visor down,
put your fucking shades og.
God,
it's fucking,
it's so bright.
Uh,
let's see.
You're looking at the reflection of the
sun off gases in the atmosphere above
your head that you need to sustain life
and we're just so used to it.
We're doing it.
Think of it as interesting.
It takes a hundred years to stop you.
You could do your best,
but you hit a hundred years.
It's over.
It's not enough time.
She just just start,
start to recognize the hustle as you get
older,
I think.
I think,
you know,
if you had kids today,
I think there a little bit luckier
because I feel like we're on the cuff of
being able to download us,
you know,
very seren and I don't think it might,
we might miss it just probably like a
couple of years.
I think we will become incredibly
annoying spammers of ourselves.
That's what we're going to do.
We're going to be able to download
ourselves.
Then we're just going to fucking shoot
ourselves in the bit torrent and mega
upload.
We're going to put ourselves everywhere.
Like I want to go everywhere.
I want to go to fucking Europe,
I want to be in Turkey and there'd be
doubles and triples of people all
throughout the the this,
this artificial world that we've created
of hyperspace.
We're going to have like a hyperspace
cloud drive of humanity that's going to
be just as fucking crowded as earth and
we're going to go,
shit,
we don't have hard drive space in the
fucking cloud and these assholes keep
copying themselves cause they want to be
a mortal.
So like rich guys would have like a
cloud serve reflect 200 trillion
terabytes and it would just be filled
with copies of themselves and then they
would just send out fucking like fake
emails,
Click here to see some Dick.
Whoa,
I want to see some Dick.
And you click there,
boom.
He,
it's an exploit.
It gets into your server.
Bang.
Makes copies of himself everywhere.
Yeah.
You'll be able to like get Joe Rogan in
your cars.
Your car has your brain in all your,
your past and all your memories,
but your cars talking to you and it's
due.
It's like you're my bro
to imagine if they figure out a way to
not just download your consciousness but
take parts out you don't need.
Yeah.
Like take parts out that you don't need,
like your ego.
Take the ego out and have,
have this consciousness be completely
compliant.
We figured out a way to isolate the ego.
We're going to remove it and we're going
to put this brain in cars.
So he get in your car and you're talking
to you,
but you don't have your own ego.
We go,
hey man,
I fucking,
I want to have a say or where we drive.
You can't have that shit coming out of
your car.
Like your car has to be completely
compliant.
Right.
That's how I drive.
I don't,
I don't take advice from my fucking car.
I'm driving bitch,
relax.
But if you could download your
consciousness,
your own conscious in your car,
your car would be literally an extension
of you.
And the car thinks it's you.
Yeah,
it's card.
Totally thinks it's you.
I can't see,
well the car,
the car knows that you in it or one.
And then when you're together you're the
same.
But his,
his legs place in life is to be your car
fuck up.
And you can start downloading you and
everything so you could download you in
the toilet.
Microwave.
You just have little Joe Rogan.
Like who thinks it's a real person?
Yeah,
you get invaded.
Like someone would break your door and
opting Dong,
you open the door.
A million bill burroughs compiling and
your house this,
someone decided to just copy bill burn
and put all the bill burr files out into
the Internet.
You have to kill them all because you
don't want to a bunch of bill burrs
talking all day.
So you have to be like,
I'm sorry,
Bill Byrd,
toaster.
Well,
I'm going to kill you.
And it would be like wolves.
They're really cool,
but you have to control the numbers.
You know
that many of,
many of us and might if there's 100
million Jamie vernors,
you would go listen dude enough,
it's too many of you fuckers.
If people don't think about that Shit,
man,
if it's possible to download
consciousness,
it's possible to copy it.
It's possible to copy it.
It's possible.
Spam it.
We're fucked.
Chill,
broken dildos.
Don't put that dare.
No.
Get me out of here.
What do you remember when we were
talking a long time ago about being able
to recreate like a celebrity and some
sort of an artificial life that will
have sex with you,
that you could do that?
Like you could make your own,
you know,
fill in the blank.
Um,
you could make your own.
Hillary swank
maybe got a hilary swank fetish.
You could literally have a robot sex
doll that is her right like it is her.
I'll give you become Mike,
some super billionaire Donald Trump type
character and you've got long paper and
I'm saying what I'm saying.
I'm saying that guy could,
he has the cash or one of those things
when they,
when they first start get designed,
he could do that.
He could do whatever he wants.
He can make like this.
We're going to get there within the
next,
I'd say a hundred years where they're
going to have these artificial people
that you can have sex with that or
you're not going to be able to,
they're going to be like blade runner
things.
You're starting to describe an episode
of Black Mirror that you haven't seen
yet.
Listen,
folks,
swear to God.
I haven't seen that show.
I'm not stealing.
It's so weird.
Yeah,
I have to see it.
I only saw the pig fucker one.
It was good.
I liked talking about the really cool,
interesting idea and the way they like
show you how it works is cool.
Wow.
I need to say they're starting it up
again too.
I think it's coming up while Netflix,
there's only at their six and then
there's like a special Christmas when
they made a little after and now they're
going to start some more.
What's the name of the one I need to
see?
Uh,
the name of it.
I'm not sure.
Like I said,
there's only six of them,
so,
okay.
It's not that hard to find it.
Uh,
dammit.
I had the picture of it here.
Business here,
the name.
I think it's totally possible that we're
gonna be able to replicate what we are.
It might not happen in our lifetime or
even our children's lifetime,
but it just seems to me that they just
keep getting better and better at fic,
fixing things and using like Willie
Nelson just had a stem cell operation to
fix his lungs.
Willie fucking Nelson,
you know.
Do you think
like Obama recently said something about
how he's putting out,
you know,
putting an end to cancer and into
cancer?
Uh,
like he's like,
like we're,
we are going to solve this shit.
Like he was kind of weird cause it's
like,
oh yeah,
no one's talked about cancer recently.
Why is that not cured?
Because they don't want it to let us
know that the Zika virus cause it's
coming.
Yeah.
Sounds like an old school,
high school football coach and it's
ready to fuck up the world.
Does Zika virus the second though?
You can cure cancer by taking a shot or
whatever.
Eating a pill.
Do you think cigarettes smoking?
We'll come back and I think everybody
that's been bitching about it and it's
all everyone's just gonna start smoking.
Yeah.
If they figured out a way,
well listen,
it's super possible.
They're going to be able to figure out a
way to make tissue healthier than it is
now.
Right?
This for how long?
How,
what,
what at what price do you pay?
You're always gonna pay a price if you
use something abrasive on your lungs,
like cigarette smoke,
like even joints.
I've got to imagine that if you're like
one of those hardened leather lung hash
hash heads,
that's just dude,
just constantly dabbing it.
I just gotta think that there's gotta be
at least some irritation of your lungs
from the hot smoke.
Just some vaporizers.
None.
Vaporizer doesn't do any of that,
but I would think that just smoke in
general is not the best idea for you to
take in.
But so cigarette smoke is real bad
because there's all these chemicals so
they might be able to figure out
something that can regenerate healthy
tissue and get rid of the bad tissue you
that maybe they could give you some sort
of a flush,
you know,
whether it would fill your lungs up with
something and it would just eradicate
all the bad tissue.
Who the fuck knows?
They'll figure it out though,
Dude.
Whatever it is,
they'll fix everything we're going,
it's going to be so many people.
It's going to be such a problem because
they're going to be able to fix
everything within like another.
How many?
Um,
oh,
let me make a guess
again.
Totally unqualified guesses.
That's why airplanes do I have ashtrays
cause they're like waiting for it to
come back.
Airplane's still have ash trays just for
nostalgia sake.
You think they don't have the new ones
don't.
Some new ones do.
And the haven put him in the bath.
They put them in that bathroom and
you're going to smoke.
They want you to be able to put it out.
What?
They don't want you.
There was no country.
You can still do.
It's not like it's just an American
thing.
Right.
It's,
I don't know.
That's a good question.
Is that true?
I bet.
And Vietnam or some shit.
Yeah.
Get out and play with it.
With one of those,
uh,
fat stogies off flights in Philly or
something.
Do you remember,
do you remember cigarettes on planes?
Uh,
yeah.
No,
I went,
I didn't fly until I was a freshman in
high school and my first time was flying
to Chicago and it was when aol first
came out and I,
it was the first girl I've ever met on
the computer and I met her in Chicago
and I took all these photos of her and I
found the camera the other day.
I'd never got developed all these photos
that are on it.
I should do that.
But,
um,
that was the first time I ever fly,
fly,
fly them.
And that was already passed a cigarette
thing.
He used to be really strange.
They used to be this section.
Sometimes the,
this is the only place you get a seat on
the plane was in that section,
so you'd have to be in the smoking
section.
It was like a joke,
like a hack joke,
like a reuse premise over and over
again.
The smoking section on a plane like a
dice.
Clay had the best take on it.
You in a fucking tube.
She's like,
you're in a tube.
The fucking smokes go whenever.
Oh,
it's true.
It's the preposterous idea that you
could smoke in one area and it wouldn't
affect the rest of the plane.
I just googled it.
Apparently there's still a rule in the
federal code of regulations that they
have to have an ashtray,
and I think it's a poll only because in
1973 a flight crashed and killed 123
people and they're attributed reason was
because of cigarette was improperly
disposed of.
Right.
Someone still asks.
The light went up because they break the
rule.
They still have to have somewhere to put
it out.
Right.
Wow.
What a crazy concession to the most
bizarre fucking habit we,
we accept.
It's so,
so common.
It's one of the most common
bad health habits.
It's such a strange one,
man.
It's so persistent that so many people
are willing to sell their health short
and the the the wide range of their
life,
all the bad ears.
You can just get him read and write out
them and enjoy your life is cigarettes.
People say that's what they always say,
right?
That's the excuse.
I mean I have a bit about it but there's
like some kind of science where they say
like every tie,
every pack of cigarettes takes off like
30 minutes off of your life or something
like that.
They figured out what the averages and
then so then if you figure out how many
years you smoke,
then you were like,
yeah,
I don't want to live to be 100 so I'll
live to be 77 that's fine.
Dot.
There's a bunch of those bits out there.
Yeah.
That are exactly the same as that.
But right now might be my bit was a,
yeah,
it takes 30 minutes off your life.
Fuck that.
I'll just wake up an hour early every
day and have two packs,
you know,
red band man,
that's funny.
But um,
the um,
the other premise though,
I was like,
well that's a beat and premise,
the premise of it,
but what,
what am I going to miss?
Drooling and shitting myself and I'm
bummed.
That was one of those things.
It's the last 20,
like there was a bunch of people that
did that.
Yeah,
there's a,
there's a few bits that,
that I have retired and it's just
amazing how,
you know,
with this all this amy Schumer stuff and
all that.
I saw a girl,
I met a girl the other day,
I didn't even know she was a comic and
she told me her website.
And so later after I hung out with her,
I went home,
went to our website and she's just a new
comic.
Opened up her front page on the front
page yet a video press play.
It was almost word for word,
one of my bits.
And I was just like,
wow,
that's how easy it is.
She's never seen me.
I've never seen her,
you know,
we've never met,
I've only done that bit a few times.
But how she said it was almost exactly
how I wrote it.
There's definitely going to be cases
that there's no way around it and it's
totally normal.
You know,
Kurt Metzger had a real good point about
it and he's one of the guys who's
involved in this whole thing,
who's the head writer of amy show and he
said that there's oftentimes,
and it's,
it's,
it's a fact that people write the exact
same premise and they have no idea.
They write a completely independently.
They know,
they wrote it independently and then
they'll see it on something and it'd
already been done.
Oh No.
Happens all the time.
Because if you can see funny in
something other people could see funny
or something,
it's not,
we're not talking about some insane,
bizarre,
Esoteric,
um,
Mr show with bob and Dave sketch.
Like they had some really busy,
if you stole one of those sketches,
like dude,
it's pretty obvious that this,
they had like really bizarre original
subjects.
It's very strange show and the way it's
seamless,
it goes from one scene to the next and
one each show is like an entire piece.
It's all connected.
It's,
if you're seeing the new show,
the Netflix one,
it's amazing.
It's great,
it's really,
really good.
But if you're just dealing with like
standard subjects like sex and,
and marriage and diseases and work and
drinking and you know,
whatever the fuck his sketches on just
normal stuff,
normal life stuff.
If you other people talk about that too.
And especially with sketches.
Do you have any fucking sketches had
been put out?
I,
we were thinking about this because of
this whole thing.
Think about all the,
as of Saturday night live,
Saturday night live has been on for how
many years?
What is it like 30,
30,
30 years.
Okay,
so 30 years of 52 weeks a year.
How many weeks are they up though?
They were up every week.
Now they do seasons.
Just seasons.
Okay.
Um,
so just whatever the number is,
33 or something like that and probably
more,
probably more to think of all those
years of sketches in each one of them is
what?
How long has it an hour and a half so I
don't live as long.
Right Aaron?
Half hour and a half.
How many fucking sketches is that over
all those years?
It's hundreds and hundreds of premises
and then you have mad tv which went on
forever.
People Forgot Mad TV went on forever and
they had some great fucking premises.
Think about how many premises they
burned or used,
you know,
you know they burned off meaning you
can't use them anymore because the
sketch has already been done.
Like there's so many of them and you can
come up with the same ideas completely
independently and you think that you're,
you're a fucking trailblazer.
You're like,
Oh man,
I don't think that's the case of Amy
Schumer's stuff though.
You don't know because there were
multiple sketches from the same sketch.
You know what I mean?
Like there's like the slap thing.
The other thing that what I think should
should find out if Kurtz headed
brighter,
he said she find out who's the one that
took that are wrote that sketch and you
know what I mean?
And maybe hold that person responsible.
You know?
And it is entirely possible that people
could come up with either one of those
things independently and it's entirely
possible.
Absolutely.
Where it gets weird is that they're both
back to back in the exact same order and
that's where it gets weird.
So is it possible for that to happen?
Yeah,
it's totally possible.
It's all,
I think he put it best when he was
criticizing his own show.
He's like,
if we're guilty of anything,
we're guilty of being hacky.
He goes,
it's Kinda a lot of the stuff's kind of
hacky.
It's true though that some of those
sketches,
I mean,
yeah,
it's true.
It's hacking bag.
That's not true of what happened in this
case because these are multiple
incidences of this same like as an
example,
the slap shep and the shake.
You think that's too right?
That's not the thing is that they're
back to back.
They're back to makes it weird because
you've seen the flintstones thing,
right?
Yes.
So the slap chef,
um,
the,
uh,
the Kathleen Madigan joke,
although I know Kathleen,
she's hilarious and I'm sure she came up
with it on her own.
She probably didn't know that that had
been a part of the flintstones probably
forgot it or never saw it or who knows.
That magician thing almost copied
exactly.
Almost exactly the same order.
The black girl in or that black person
at the retail store where the,
you know,
that Keenan Peele or whatever,
it doesn't look good.
Yeah.
No,
it wasn't a key and Peele,
it was her,
they were on mad tv actually at the
time.
Yeah.
No,
it doesn't look good.
No.
I mean it doesn't look good,
but,
but what I think I,
you know,
she's,
I don't think she's guilty.
I think she did.
It was writers and I think she needs to,
you know,
kind of stand up and be like,
look,
it wasn't me and this guy stole two bits
and this guy stole two bits and we're,
we're assuming it did.
But allegedly the problem is like,
first of all for her,
she's in the worst position,
right?
Because,
um,
it's her show,
she's got her name on it.
But if I was this,
I've looked at this like completely,
honestly,
I,
there's little,
as I watched sketch comedy,
I didn't know that any of those bits had
been done before.
I didn't know that the,
um,
all of them,
so pretty much all of them I didn't
know.
So if somebody has tried to sell those
to me,
I'd be like,
oh,
that's a good sketch.
Like,
so I guess every time a sketch comes up,
you got to enter that premise into
google.
A Jim Norton and I were just talking
about this weekend.
Like how do you,
like if you,
if you're writing like hundreds and
hundreds of sketches,
you know,
if you're,
if you're doing like a siren lime or
something like that,
how do you find out whether or not this
premise has been done before?
It's it,
you don't have to worry about it.
What you have to do is do your own
version of that premise.
But like in this case if you'd like the
magician was exact rim off.
It was,
it was like buying a fake iphone from
Korea or China.
It wasn't a premise that they both
played around and it was an exact rip
off.
You know,
it was almost filmed.
Exactly.
Let's say it was the exact same sketch
and the exact same order,
whether it was a rip off those,
it's hard to say whether someone,
unless they come out and say,
Hey,
I saw that guy do it and that's where I
came up with a bed.
And uh,
I tried to pretend that I wrote it
myself.
Unless they come out and say that it's
so hard to figure out what's going on.
Just being completely fair.
It's always hard.
The problem is is there's multiple
instances.
I get it.
I agree.
Those premises though.
Hmm.
There's a few of them that,
that are pretty original.
I thought the counter guy,
you'll like her not being able to talk
to the black guy was pretty original
but,
but
who the fuck knows?
Man?
Who knows?
It just sits possible.
If one person came up with that,
another person could come up with the
same thing,
just you don't know.
And the,
the real problem lies.
And when people lie and steal and then
pretend they didn't.
So if someone is,
you know,
you,
you have bit,
it's a killer bit.
And this guy just swipes it and starts
doing it.
He goes,
dude,
I came up with the exact same bed.
I'm so sorry.
And then starts doing it.
Well then you've got an ethical problem,
then you've got a real problem.
But if you both come up with the same
bit,
like a tell is probably the best at it.
And uh,
one of the things to Norton and I were
talking about like a tail will go up to
everybody when he has a a new bit.
If it seems like it came too easy,
if he's like,
where'd that come from?
Is that,
if I heard this before,
he'll like,
he'll text you,
hey man,
have you heard this before?
He'll call you like,
he's real diligent about that.
And if somebody else already has one,
just chucks it aside.
And I think,
um,
that's the probably the best way to be.
Just do what you think is original and,
uh,
try to find out if anybody's already
done,
I guess.
But how the fuck do you do that?
See what I do is,
or what I try to do,
I,
I've always tried to do this,
you know,
except for you or,
or gone barris or brody Stevens,
theirs.
I don't watch comedy.
I don't like watching other comics.
I don't want to be influenced by it.
And I think if you has a comic,
if you follow that kind of rural where
you're not really watching comedy,
even if he did come up at the same
presence,
you could,
you could say with a straight face,
look,
I've never seen you.
I don't watch comedy.
I,
that's what I thought of.
You know,
that's true.
But you definitely look at it that way.
And there's,
but there's other comics that you always
see in the back of the room.
They love comedy,
like watching comedy.
Right.
You know,
and so if that happened to somebody like
that,
you'd be like,
Dude,
you've watched me do that.
Joke 500 times.
Right.
But that's why I would have to tell you
like in certain circumstances like jokes
that are like really common,
like um,
like the one that you did know that was
really common about,
um,
uh,
the last 20 years.
Like what do you like,
what years are you missing?
Like what if you smoke cigarettes?
It 20 years off your life.
Yeah.
I like your take on it though.
You're taking on,
it's pretty funny cause it's,
it's a ridiculous red band math
equation.
It's like 30 minutes a day.
Just wake up an hour early,
you know?
Exactly.
It's a ridiculous read bad math
equation.
But um,
can you,
can you copy write jokes?
I mean I know you can't,
I'm looking at it right now.
You can.
But like what'd you have?
You are like,
have you heard of someone doing it?
I think,
look,
there's a lot of us,
man.
I mean if you,
if you think about all the standup
comics in the world,
there's probably thousands of us,
right?
And for the most part there's very few
problems.
And one of the reasons why there's very
few problems is cause we kind of police
ourselves and we make it a big point
about being fair and about,
you know,
supporting artists that don't do it.
And,
uh,
not supporting artists who do do it.
And it doesn't mean just because someone
has done it in the past too,
it doesn't mean that they're a terrible
person that can never redeem themselves.
They can never know.
It doesn't mean that at all.
It means they fucked up.
People fuck up.
People make mistakes.
He doesn't it,
there were police itself,
kind of like the comedians that'll take
care of itself.
I think more than anything,
man.
It's comedy fans that are policing it
now.
It's a really interesting,
and,
and I say fans and I use it in a loose
term possible cause some of them are
actual fans.
The person they're going after and some
of them are just not,
you know,
some of 'em,
uh,
they've been looking some reason why
this person is no good for awhile.
And then when they find this,
they just go wild with it and they love
it.
Um,
so they're not necessarily fans of the
person.
So if they're making a video about her,
they're not necessarily fans of her,
but they might call themselves comedy
fans,
you know?
And so they see something like this
happen and they get furious.
Just have to be real careful because
it's theirs.
It's,
it's,
there's a giant issue with it being a
bunch of people writing on a show and
doing sketches,
it's so fucking hard to know where those
things are coming from.
It's just real hard to know.
It's interesting though that it always
seems to happen,
you know,
like,
like yeah,
the mind Admin,
Sia,
you got amy Schumer's show you,
I saw the other day at John Heffron bit
that made it up in keene peel.
Like it was almost,
yeah.
And
it seems like that maybe that the people
that write for these kinds of shows
don't think it's that bad,
especially since it's all the same
network.
Well,
I think first of all,
there's some people that,
right.
And this isn't meant to hold standup
comics and some crazy high form of
ethics and morality.
But there's some people that write on
shows that are not standup comedians.
And their ideas about ideas are
different than our ideas about our ideas
without,
what I mean by that is if they can get
away with it,
some of them will pill for an idea,
whether it's take it from a book and
rearrange it,
uh,
take it from a video and transcribe it
and don't give the person credit who
said it the first time when,
when people are taking jokes from
comedians and using them to create
sketches with them and pretending that
they came up with them on their own,
it's,
um,
no,
it's not,
it's not cool.
Right?
It's fucking gross.
But they're not,
they probably aren't comedians.
So it's like if you had like a really
funny line for a joke that was a lyric
of a song,
you know,
and you heard a song and you're like,
Ooh,
I'm going to put this in my act that's
going to,
I'm going to have this amazing punchline
in my act that is from this song.
So like the joke in the song,
now I'm going to pretend I came up with
it on my own,
putting my act.
It's like similar in that kind of a way.
You know what I'm saying?
Absolutely.
So like someone who's not a comic,
they,
I don't want to think,
I wonder if they would then not even a
part of the comedy community,
they were a writer like fuck,
this dude is going to gang get shit.
Yeah.
Just going to fill it.
Just going to become productive.
What are the odds these people going to
watch an old 20 years episode of what's
happening?
You know,
our 40 years,
how long ago was that on a long time
ago,
right?
Who the fuck's gonna Watch what's
happening and to go over all those
premises?
No,
there might be a hilarious premise that
they could pull out of that.
Why did I say what's happening?
What's happening with that terrible.
Your sketches.
I was trying to think of something like
a old Sitcom,
Huh?
True.
One thing I always thought was
interesting is because it just from
watching so many roast battles and stuff
like that is how roast jokes are like
the same jokes that they've used for
years and years and years and years just
kind of rebranded and like,
and it used to be totally acceptable.
Before there was internet,
before there was TV shows,
you know,
like the friars club and all that stuff
like that.
They're all kind of like taken from each
other and reusing shit that Charlie
Chaplin may have said.
You know?
And it's just interesting that that's
like one of the few things in comedy
that it's kind of like an unspoken
thing,
but who cares?
You know,
like it's,
it's no one's getting mad if you reuse a
roast joke that,
that Milton Berle mom made,
you know,
like around.
But they probably would if there were
roast fans,
like Hinchcliffe would probably be mad
because he's a roast fan.
Yeah.
When now with TV and stuff like that.
It's interesting because like if they
have like a roast,
like show on comedy central,
like,
so like amy or somebody does a joke on
that and they reuse it and that roast
few years later that now it's like,
oh,
you can't do that anymore.
Even though he used to be able to do it.
And that was the whole thing,
you know,
I wonder if that's what the whole thing
was.
Um,
I mean that's what it was in the
catskills days.
Right.
And the um,
the old days,
they would,
uh,
have these resorts like from dirty
dancing.
That was the catskills.
Right.
Other than it,
man,
that's how fucked up cigarettes are.
Man.
Cigarettes took Patrick swayze.
Yeah.
Dude,
we lost Patrick swayze to cigarettes.
We lost the dude from roadhouse with the
flowing locks.
You know how to invest just alone.
Fluxes in the mirror every day.
He's still alive.
He's like 70.
He looks great.
Yeah.
Popular dirty dancing was and how
popular that soundtrack was that they
released a soundtrack like two months
after that had none of the music from
the movie,
but it was just called like dirty
dancing soundtrack part too.
It was just a way to sell another.
But that is every girl's dream.
A beautiful man who can dance.
There's a really manly man who will
fight to defend his right to dance.
Is that correct?
Perfect cheekbones.
If I say that to any other girl,
are you kidding me?
This guy got God.
Get out of here.
If I was a girl,
I'd have babies with that dude bodily.
That's your guy a,
you're on vacation.
You meet this guy.
He's dangerous.
He's got perfect hair,
beautiful features.
He's supple.
He knows how to move,
smoked cigarettes.
He looks cool.
Cigarettes caught them.
Dude,
Patrick swayze,
he's not that old.
Do you understand like this,
this fucking guy died from cigarettes
and he's not that old.
There's a lot of people that are way
older than him that are doing great.
And then there's women that have been
smoking two packs of cigarettes every
day,
spent their whole life and her 102.
Right.
But they look like monsters.
It'll become monster.
I could just be come to their body
morphs and changes to accept the
cigarettes.
When you're like a hundred and you're
still small,
you're like some fucking cigarette
burning beast.
Some thing that's in inhaling these,
this chemical that's a new part of your
system.
I've been spoken for about 26 years and
I look at like a fresh little baby.
You're a part of the system.
You're in the matrix.
My by NBC.
By him.
How many do you,
how many do you do every day?
Like I'm like a pack.
A pack.
Hold back a day.
Wow.
But you know,
sometimes it's more,
sometimes it's less.
Uh,
I think that's another thing that made
you on my podcast.
He's one of my neck that was him in the
bitter and he was still smoking.
His body was rotting away and he had a
cigarette hanging out of his mouth.
It doesn't seem like a good idea to
continue to smoke.
Look at that.
Look at him.
Wow.
That's craziness.
But it's weird because it was still
getting treatment.
It's weird man.
I wonder if like he laid off of it for a
while,
man.
It's sad one.
And he did a television show because he
was hot.
He was hot.
Wallace was all happening.
So he did a TV show and I'm sure that
didn't help him at the long hours and
the stress of that TV show.
I forgot about that TV show.
Well what I don't remember,
but um,
he uh,
he went out the hard way.
Shit's real.
That's what it was.
It was called the beast.
2009.
Wow.
Patrick swayze.
Dan,
it's weird.
Roadhouse.
Rest in peace.
He's a mother Fucker,
dude.
Roadhouses the shit to this day,
right?
It's this date.
If you're flipping channels and
roadhouses on,
just watch it.
Just watch it.
It's on.
It's perfect.
It's a pretty classic movie.
It's a slice of Americana.
It's like a piece of,
it's a piece of like civilization just
strapped into some cultural,
iconic,
ridiculous.
They just made another movie that was a
good one of his called point break,
which I heard.
I didn't see it,
but I heard it wasn't like great.
The premise wasn't even the same movie
though.
But are you worried about roadhouse
coming back out and being totally
different kinds of things,
isn't it?
Rhonda?
Rhonda is going to do roadhouses it's
going to be different.
She has a vagina.
It's totally different.
You see her on Saturday night live?
No,
I didn't see her.
It was good though.
Did you hear it was good?
Uh,
you know,
certain people really invest in,
in making it their own,
I think.
And then there's other people that kind
of just go through the motions.
Uh,
from what I saw,
it just seemed like the,
the ladder.
Then it just seemed,
I don't know.
She seemed like she did great job,
but she didn't like,
she's not a public speaker.
Yeah.
Probably hard as fuck to do someone that
isn't a public
speaker.
Can you imagine?
You know?
Yeah.
I mean,
I wonder definitely,
especially if you're not used to it,
but yeah,
it's an iconic thing to do,
man.
I'd be nervous as fuck all years I've
done stand up.
If I had a host site live,
I'd be nervous as far.
Yeah.
Did you try?
No.
Every assay we wouldn't do it.
I'm not,
I'm not interested in working at beach.
Just interesting though.
I've done,
I think I've done too much work.
I really do.
I'm interested in enjoying myself.
I just think at this stage of my life,
like the one I'm becoming more and more
cognizant of as I get older is you can
work too much.
It's not good.
It's not good to work too much.
Like there's a good amount of work you
should do,
but there's a lot of people that like
pride themselves and working too much
and working the,
wearing themselves out.
Like it's something they carry around
like a shield,
you know that?
Hmm.
Probably not.
If you don't have to do it.
I understand if you have to do it,
but if you don't have to do it,
she'd probably like have some fun.
You know,
like don't,
don't get overwhelmed with the desire to
succeed cause that your whole life could
pass you by.
If you're one of those Gordon Gekko
assholes,
you know,
your whole life can pass you by for some
crazy hedge funds.
Sociopath on the loose,
just sucking numbers out of the,
out of the matrix with his fucking
computer algorithms.
Like that guy is just connected to it.
He's a,
he's a part of it.
So He's successful.
But along the way,
he's not even having any fun.
You know,
he's just living life in this constantly
stressed adderall induced s like speedy
fucking decision making ass kicking
fucking mode all the time.
You know,
that guy ain't happening.
It's um,
it's so weird way to live life.
So funny that somebody asked me the
other day if I can find them at all and
I was like,
no,
I don't know anyone.
But if you need cocaine,
I can get that.
Like,
like how weird is it that it is weird
backwards you've ever been?
Why Whitewater rafting?
No,
that's something that you should try
some type that's crazy.
Gone canoeing down the white waters.
Not White waters.
I shouldn't even say white waters down a
river.
Um,
there were some tricky spots,
like some spots near rocks and stuff
like that,
but nothing like real fast.
The Whitewater stuff looks a phone.
A newsroom.
Yeah.
My,
my dad almost died doing it once because
he got caught underneath the raft and he
said he couldn't breathe and he just
gave up.
And then they're at the last second.
We just floating down.
Somebody just grabbed him out of the
water.
My Friend Remy Warren,
uh,
who's done the podcast a few times,
not the last time that he was on,
but the time before that,
I think the first time he was on,
he,
um,
told me a story about,
he was a,
in the woods and he saw a body come down
the river and the guy's face down in the
water.
He saw some clothes and uh,
then he saw a,
like,
you saw some gear,
you know,
floating down.
And then he saw a body and he realized,
Oh shit.
And then he saw a woman and the woman
was bobbing her head up in the air and
trying to survive and getting caught up
in the current,
and he ran into that fucking water
thinking that he was going to die
thinking like this.
I just made the biggest mistake.
I'm going to try to help us,
lady,
I'm going to wind up dying like,
and he's a strong guy and he's a really,
he's in really good shape.
He hikes a lot in the mountains.
He's very fit.
Like they,
uh,
for his television show.
Um,
it's called us.
uh,
what's it called?
Apex Predator.
Um,
he did these vo two Max tests where they
made them do like sprints and find out,
they find out,
he's like,
get a very high level of endurance just
cause he's constantly hiking in the
mountains,
but still he'd jump into the water and
you grab a hold of somebody,
they can drown you,
they could flail and you might not
recover and you,
while you're flailing around,
you might hit a log.
You're going down this water,
it's going really fast.
And what happened to these people was
they were doing that in a raft and the
current got really fast and they hit a
down tree and they got fucked up and the
dude drown and he died and the woman's
survived,
but barely,
and she was freezing to death.
The water was insanely cold.
So this dude jumped in the water,
pulled them out.
Um,
finally,
what number podcast is,
so we could tell people that are
listening to this right now,
but it's remy Warren.
I'm pretty sure it was the first time he
was on.
It's a constant famous country singer
just died.
Kind of the same kind of situation for
39 with Dan duty,
episode four 39 with Dan Dodi.
That's the one.
Yeah.
We also have it re uploaded.
How many times did he come on by
himself?
Oh,
it's up.
The stories uploaded.
Oh,
beautiful.
Beautiful episode four 39.
He's awesome.
That guy's a good dude.
Um,
what was the question about this country
singer and the country singer?
Like they found his,
uh,
his body and it seem like the kind of
like a similar thing.
He,
um,
yeah,
he died of hypothermia.
They,
um,
they,
they have,
they were in a boat apparently,
and it just overturned and it was in the
water and the storm was insane.
And you know,
they uh,
they tried to risk it.
They tried to go out there and he even
made a tweet about it the night before,
you know,
saying he hopes it doesn't die.
Like,
man,
there's the storms are no fucking
bullshit.
They're no bullshit.
Like there's a video that I posted today
that I retweeted,
that someone sent my way about
lightening striking.
Oh,
it was a matt stags.
One Maths tag sent it to me.
Um,
lightning striking in the middle of
this,
like these,
the storm going on,
these guys are out on the patio.
And they were like,
wow,
this is crazy.
And the guy's like,
I wouldn't go out there and now with
this weather.
And then boom,
the lightning hits the ground right in
front of them.
Play this shit.
Where do you see this?
Hold on.
Don't go outside.
Oh my God,
Dude.
Shit myself.
First of all,
fuck lightning.
Fuck lightning.
Lightning is an asshole force of nature.
That is a shitty,
dirty,
cheap shot and motherfucker,
lightning is crazy.
There's no rules either.
Remy Warren got hit by lightening too.
How about that?
I got to remy Warren Stories,
remy than when he was a kid in high
school.
Got Hit by lightning,
woke up with his fucking ears going,
hey,
like he told that story on the podcast
as well.
I think that was the same story.
Goddamn Rami probably warrants amazing.
That's,
that's what it all boils down to.
Remy is amazing.
Lightening hit right in front of me once
I was in the basement,
that's not the same as getting him
right.
You know,
it was going to hit and he was fucked
up.
I was in the basement and they have
those windows in the basement.
Uh,
like within that window wells and stuff
like that.
And I was doing my laundry or something
and uh,
lightening hit right in front of me
outside though.
And then like the arms,
a electricity like went all over there,
like everything.
And it's scary.
The shit out of me.
Maybe it was actually an evil villain.
Teleporting from the future terminator
style.
Maybe you thought it was a lightening,
right?
Remember that scene when Arnold was
naked?
Is giant Austrian schlonged hanging out
and give me all close.
Remember that that movie was the shit
be.
Meanwhile,
that's about to happen.
Automated cars.
Fucking drones.
Look at this.
That's what it was.
He just appears in that bubble.
That cut right through everything.
It was around it.
Remember like it was like a little
circle and it popped up and that red
bag,
old deck,
especially like metal.
Why couldn't they give him some clothes?
Why do you got to pretend that you can't
cut teleport close?
You fucks.
You know,
is it gotta be naked?
get Outta here.
What the fuck out of here with that?
That's probably what it's going to be
though,
right?
It is probably going to be,
once they figured out teleporting,
you'd have to buy herself the first day
someone gets scrambled because there's a
glitch in the matrix when a teleporting
someone and they come out of bucket of
feet,
eyeballs,
balls and,
and Dick's in their mouth and their
twisted like a pretzel.
The first time that happens,
whoa,
that's going to be a tough day.
But we accept a certain amount of car
accidents.
You know,
we accept thousands and thousands of car
accidents every year.
If you just think about how many people
die if we were thinking like our real
enemy is the automobile.
Automobiles are killing people with know
people driving them,
but God won't be hitting into people,
people hitting things in their
automobiles.
That's what's killing people.
If you really looked at it that way,
the numbers are pretty high.
I think it's like 30,000 people or
something crazy die in automobile
accidents every year.
Yeah.
Mean if that was a,
uh,
an enemy,
you know,
robot enemy,
I came from space,
it was killing him.
30,000 people a day.
We wouldn't be so fucking nonchalant it,
you know,
but because we're driving around,
oh,
the fly he doing teleportation and that
way you ask.
Yes.
Well that was he,
this was actually a remake of a really
old movie from the black and white days.
It was awesome.
It was really awesome.
Go find the old fly.
Yeah,
I need to rewatch that.
It's but the fly,
the 19 it was at 86 88 86 for that first
one.
But here's the other one.
Oh,
okay.
So for the Jeff Goldbloom one,
it's fucking awesome.
It's really good.
I loved it.
Jeff Goldbloom was such a bad
motherfucker when he was young man.
Especially in that movie.
Like I really believed that's the
original is that Vincent Price.
That's amazing.
Look at that.
That's a crazy look at the fucking
picture.
Oh my God.
Vincent Price.
He was the man when it came to old
school monster movies.
But like Jeff Goldbloom and that fly
movie,
you believe that he was really a mad
scientist.
Like I believe like this guy,
the way he talks,
he's just so,
do you have friend and interesting.
He the,
he had a way of talking about and be
like,
this guy could be some hyper human who
could figure something like this out.
I totally bought it.
Hook,
line and sinker.
Like there's some people that play,
they play scientists and I'm like,
bitch,
you ain't fucking some right.
Come on son.
You ever see that movie sunset
boulevard?
We have that.
Where's this dog?
Yeah,
way different.
I bet he's got a giant dog.
Look at his conference.
We look at his face.
Large hands,
but it's a hog.
Yeah.
He's got a huge tick.
You can tell it's crazy in a fly.
Let a fly in there.
You ever see sunset boulevard?
No.
What was a,
that's a great movie.
I highly recommend I watch it.
That's my go to like I put on every
night before I go to bed.
That's not the,
uh,
the document documentary or a drama
mentoree or whatever they're calling it.
[inaudible] no,
this is a movie,
but yeah,
this is an old school classic.
Maybe school.
Wasn't there a recent movie about
sunset?
Yeah,
that was the documentary about sunset.
It was a documentary.
It was documentary.
Okay.
So there was no acting in it at all.
I got confused.
There's more than one that was out at
the same time.
One was a,
a film.
Uh,
no,
I think it's the same one.
I think it's,
I keep hearing I have to check that out
though.
The documentary.
Yeah.
It's good.
It's interesting you really learned
about the sunset boulevard.
You know,
I was talking,
I was on Frasier's a radio show the
other day,
and we raise your Smith.
Yeah,
I love frazier since great guy.
Uh,
he,
uh,
you know,
there's not much left on sunset.
We were talking,
you know,
besides the rainbow and the comedy
story,
there's not much.
Uh,
that's it.
Everything's getting torn down and
become condos now.
It's almost dead.
Dita von Teese rat slabs.
Let's get,
go.
Go for the first time on Friday.
Oh,
really?
Pricing really small and like,
yeah,
I mean,
it would have been awesome to see Motley
crue and Jimi Hendrix or anyone in the
doors back in the day.
But I saw a band saw for the time when I
was a teenager in high school orgy.
And Whoa,
I saw there on the billboard.
So I went and saw him and it was a,
I probably should have just stayed home.
That's where it led me.
Birthday party was great.
Before you do that,
the roxy and the,
um,
the place next to it,
the rainbow,
that's,
those are icons span.
You have rainbows,
an icon.
The rainbow feels like it was made by
the same person as the comedy store.
You go in there and you go like,
I feel like insane.
It's a legit old school,
Hollywood place.
You ever eat at Dantanna's Dantanna's on
Santa Monica.
Dude.
So you'll go into the past like the
menus,
the way the waiters are dressed.
Well,
it's all really small,
but it's not giant.
One side's more of a bar,
but there's tables on that side.
But the food is amazing.
The food is incredible and it's like so
old school man.
The whole place is just,
it feels it.
When you get in there,
you feel like you got class.
Like you want to order a Martini age to
be an asshole.
Like C'mon gentlemen.
That's right next to the shipping door
on sunset.
Coolest place I've ever seen a concert
and my really,
really been to red rocks,
which I've heard is also a cool,
that's a big place to see in Denver.
But as far as small venue where you can
see like a real awesome concert with
maybe 200 people,
but real big names play there
frequently.
It just for fun.
That's like where they work out.
That's awesome man.
God Damn.
Yeah,
it's a crazy spot.
That sunset strip.
Yeah,
but you know,
it's on the way out.
It's becoming something different for
sure.
Like that giant billboard that's right
in front of store.
That's it's,
it's movies like who's idea is it could
take a fucking road that already has
plenty of accidents and put up a giant
fucking multicolored,
super bright billboard that you almost
need sunglasses to look at.
And it's playing videos.
So you're watching videos as you're
driving.
Well,
what is this?
what's he doing?
Well that's wacky.
He just do a flip crash.
Yeah.
It should be so illegal to people.
You're not even allowed to text if
you're not a lot of texts.
Why are you allowed to read?
Why you got,
why do you have a gigantic 100 foot
fucking TV screen?
That's not a billboard asshole.
If you want to have a billboard,
have a billboard,
that's a movie theater.
You're,
you get a movie screen up there,
the fuck it should be so illegal.
Well they let it be legal.
It's there.
So as we're driving we're,
we're watching shit.
And what do they do is it's still images
that they keep changing.
It's moving images cause he's like
you'll,
you'll see like crystal leave like
undateable this Thursday and they're not
moving around like throwing things and
stuff.
Like it's completely just commercial.
Sure.
Yeah,
sure,
sure.
Definitely.
Sure.
Yeah.
You guys can see it everyday.
It's caught.
Even if it's still when still images or
moving like changing them every couple
seconds or soil.
Like what are you doing?
Why are you distracting people?
I think they've made it illegal in a lot
of cases.
I think.
I think that for some,
some reason has like a get out of free
jail card or something.
Get out of free jail.
Like Times Square Times Square has got
that passed to like,
it's almost like part,
the charm of the place
that you go there.
You're just going to be,
wow,
look at all the lights.
This is crazy.
But the idea at times square as you
getting out of a cab,
are you climbing off the subway and you
look at around you?
You're not driving in that fucking
thing.
How many people go visit New York and
drive in Times Square?
I go,
Jesus Christ.
It's a,
that's a giant ball of neon.
It's chaos.
Like Vegas is the same way he received
some of those casinos.
They've got damn a huge movie screens
play on the outside of their casino
showing you people sang in fucking
rocking out carrot top and pass all this
shit's going on.
As you're driving down the street and
you're on coke and you try and drive
slow,
try to keep it together.
What's his fucking movie?
Why they show me that Cirque du Solei?
You know,
that's,
that's something that's pretty fucking
specific.
Think about that.
That show I'll give you go to Cirque de
Solei.
You need to see like almost superhuman
feats of physical fitness.
Like they had one of those Cirque de
Solei dudes.
This is like a perfect contrast to what
we were doing.
We were,
we were eating over it.
I guess it's like Wolfgang Puck's is
right over by the circus Solei place we
were eating and this dude was a coming
from the Cirque de Solei like he had
been working there and in the middle of
the hallway while we were stuffing our
face with food,
this dude just starts doing back flips.
He did like one,
two,
three,
four,
five back lifts and Landon and laughed
and laughed with his friend and fucking
button up shirt and get out of there.
But like this dude like just flip
through the air and then it started
going feet,
the hands,
feet,
the hands jump and we were like,
Whoa,
whoa.
We got a mouthful of linguine with
clams,
trying to put a fucking damper on this
buzz before I go to sleep.
You know this dude is flipping,
doing flips down the hallway.
It,
what does that park core?
Yeah,
this guy's a there.
There was,
I saw a video the other day.
This guy is just like on top of this
building and just jumps down through
this thing like go and jumps in through
a window.
It's amazing what those guys do.
Like that's,
that's craziness.
I'm becoming a grumpy old man cause this
uh,
this,
this lady was like,
her son broke his arm doing par corp and
I wrote,
Oh,
is that what they're calling it these
days?
It was when I was a kid that was called
being an asshole.
That's what I wanted to say.
I didn't say that.
Well why was he okay?
That's what I said.
Yeah.
I said,
why was he okay?
But like why is it,
why,
why?
How come it has to have a French name?
How come it has to be international?
What you're doing is you're crazy
fucker.
You're running and g doing flips off of
a railings.
Shit.
All right.
Be careful.
This kid,
I know that for his birthday he does
that.
That's what kids do nowadays.
They rent out rooms that just looked
like I pass by this place and right.
Actually the place I was going there was
a park core studio.
I was like,
what is this?
They're teaching people how to do this
and apparently they're all right
now it's super popular and they had
like,
like ones that looked like super mario
brothers or like they have like,
like uh,
yeah the,
yeah,
this one.
Oh my God,
this one's in I in Los Angeles and it's
just like,
that's grown adults fucking jumping
around like kids,
man,
that's a cat to kids.
A little boy,
a little child is doing flips.
Wow.
These kids are freaks.
That's pretty impressive though.
Cause who's gonna pay for their acl
surgeries?
Exactly.
Damn.
That is really impressive.
That shit though.
The shit that kid is doing that flip off
the building,
you know,
that is a really impressive stuff.
Come on man.
And they did just doing it to look cool
I guess.
Right.
Are there competitions,
I mean a little bit that American and
this has really picked up and that's
kind of what these,
that's the main competition.
I think these guys can go do what that
guy just did was exactly what that dude
the dude did in front back like back it
up like a little bit
like to the dude is doing no.
Before that,
the dude that was doing the flips right
there,
look at this.
That's what the guy was doing in the
hotel.
Like no bullshit.
Hand Feed Tan.
Have you ever even tried to do that?
Like,
like on a diving board or water?
Yeah,
I don't,
I've never even,
it's no consequences to back.
You gotta be careful.
I've heard my back and neck before too,
so I'm very wary about things that might
potentially be horrible for my fucking
spine.
Whoa.
These people are crazy.
It seems so strange to watch people move
their bodies in ways you know you can't
move yours.
Like how,
what?
How mine don't like if you saw yourself
doing that,
you're like,
how can I do this?
What do I have superhero powers now?
I find it more interesting watching
people doing any of these,
this kind of stuff in real life
situations like around the streets
because it's like they're ninjas.
They can like break into like buildings
just by doing this park horse shit
like no.
Right,
like double jump.
I know.
It's weird.
They can do things with their bodies at
rego.
People just can't,
you just keep practicing.
But the,
these are all like cement things are
jumping around on are they,
what are these things made out of?
Drywall?
Yeah.
[inaudible] I don't know.
They're running around on dry wall like
that.
That Shit has to be super flimsy.
They would have to be more than drywall.
Floyd.
It's probably like what they make a
skate ramps and stuff out of.
Yeah.
This is crazy.
What it just keeps going.
Was that a girl or a guy with a long ass
ponytail?
So the girl,
yeah.
Whoa.
She's doing flips and shit.
The future of like UFC and shit.
It's like a room like this and that.
Both fighters just start on each side of
the room and they're allowed to like
walk around.
And do you like nature moves?
That's actually a great idea.
Like her weight room?
Yeah.
Like a quaker entering into a quick
Rome.
Yeah.
Wow.
Imagine if that would be,
um,
the more sophisticated high level
version of it
and I may,
when we do it virtual reality style that
two guys start out in a building and you
know,
they don't know where the other person
is in the building and so you have to
like be real sneaky
and walk around and you're allowed to
hit the person if they don't see you.
Exactly.
It gets more realistic.
It's more realistic.
Look at look at house,
look back at boxing and you're like,
look how dumb it is.
They can't jump on the ground and they
can't do it.
Now imagine doing this and be like look
how dumb that is.
We're going to like an octagon.
What the fuck?
No hop up a building and this guy is
trying to rape you and,
and you're using shadows on walls and
like
I wonder if people would give up weight
classes if they were willing to use
weapons.
Like if the like a,
okay look,
I'll take a a 50 pound weight
disadvantage,
but I want brass knuckles.
You know,
I'm remembering this TV show,
I really cannot remember the name of it,
but it's almost like that.
No,
it was like a real life really was fake,
but it was like real life mortal Kombat
and the shot around universal studios
and they'd go to different sets and it'd
be like an essential area.
Like this team versus team in the first
fight is going to be here and they'd go
like off to the lake and they'd go fight
at the lake and then come back
trying to look for it.
I have no idea what,
I totally forgot about that.
It's almost like you're saying,
but I mean that was the wrestling wwe
version of
wow,
that's right.
See,
there you go.
I'm a thief.
That's how easy it is to be a thief.
That shit.
We were talking about something at a we
that's completely out of the ether.
Yeah,
but I liked the idea of like what if,
what if it was like the real world.
Every,
there's a camera in every room and you
know,
one person's is started in the attic,
one person started in the basement and
you're trying to kill the other,
you know,
like beat up.
But I think there's gotta be an element
of virtual [inaudible]
reality like to,
for to watch it.
Like,
cause we can't be there.
Right.
But to watch it and get the best angles,
you should be able to watch the
perspective of both people.
Yeah.
The perspective of the guy doing the
beating up and their perspective.
The Guy Getting beat up,
the perspective of the guy that doesn't
know the guys behind him and the
perspective of the guy who knows that
the guy doesn't know and he's sneaking
up on them,
ready to Jack Them.
That would be wild,
man.
Be Wild.
I see something like that and UFC mixed
with like a horror movie.
Well,
imagine if you could like see the
punches coming your way and see yourself
getting knocked unconscious like poom.
Like how is he seeing it?
Like you see it,
you see the sparks that he sees in front
of his eyes.
You know,
you're fucking consciousness dims in and
out just like he does.
It might be a way that they could like
almost experience getting fucked up and
beat up to know how bad it is.
Whatever.
Reboot.
Yeah.
How dare,
Ladies and gentlemen,
do not panic if you're just listening to
the audio version of this podcast.
Only you know what happened?
What happened is
this God damn tri caster shit out again.
Is that like a normal thing with the
[inaudible]?
It's happened a couple times,
but it hasn't happened for a long time.
It's just,
it's happened multiple times over our
pod and versions of it.
This was a complete pc for eas.
Otherwise,
other times it's been just a internet
disconnection.
Do we have to make an upgrade?
Is there anything we need to do?
Uh,
uh,
I don't know.
Should we upgrade our system the best
you can get you,
he really can't get any better than I
could try castor.
Seriously,
man,
we can do it at the level that he's been
doing it right now with something like
that.
You don't want it to be more complicated
than that.
It's perfect.
Yeah.
That thing's perfect.
It's just fucks up every now and then
and then it makes,
it gives us something to bitch about.
Fucking truck.
[inaudible]
I don't know man.
Those things a,
they're complicated as fuck.
They're going to shit out on you every
now and then.
I think it's just,
you're,
we're streaming things and h d
uh,
Mkbhd he stopped by here one time he's
making,
he makes those cool uh,
youtube videos sort of like unbox
therapy.
I think he's friends with them.
He made a cool video recently talking
about four k and the state of it now and
kind of like where we are.
And like you can watch four K on a TV
like that.
Uh,
you can watch some of it on your phone,
but really you can only get it from like
Netflix and youtube and it's going to
take a long time before,
like it would take what happened for us
to get really good Internet here.
You have to dig up the ground but in
some new cables to get the bandwidth to
go.
Cause it's a lot of,
it's a lot of information you're trying
to send even were like fixed the math of
it.
That compression can easily be fixed by
like,
like a jpeg version of four,
four K,
you know,
like something that compresses fourcade
down into something that you know,
but it would have the same image
quality.
Yeah.
I mean like look at bitmaps and jpegs.
He can't tell the difference between
those two but one with the naked eye.
But can you tell if you're looking at it
through a lens or anything like that?
Like the people that are really a t
mobile just got in trouble recently
because uh,
because unlimited data or whatever for
that unlimited,
no,
they,
what they do is they downgrade it to for
ADP.
So when you're on your phone watching
for 80 p you're not going to know the
fucking difference between 7:20 PM four
eight
I wouldn't know for life,
Bro.
For most people's phones through I was
real life bro.
Fucking sprint for the win.
Fuck Verizon's tank for the wound 18 t
yes.
Who was it that gives you a Timo Fluke?
Do you know?
[inaudible] my friends like four
eighties bullshit bro.
Who Do you have right now?
This one is verizon.
Verizon and then the same phones for the
studio.
Yeah.
I liked the,
um,
the new galaxy phones.
I think this is the,
the first series of galaxy phones or
they have features that are sort of
built in that make you go,
wow,
I don't,
they all have charging a wireless
charging now.
Uh,
yeah.
Any of them do,
right?
Yes.
But you know,
what I've noticed with white,
with wireless charging is that it
charges slow and sometimes you'll put
your phone on the little dock thing and
it doesn't sit right.
Then you don't have a charge.
And so then you're like,
what the fuck?
I don't know.
It's still there right now.
There's a company,
I forget who it is,
I think it's apple that just filed a
patent for wireless charging for like,
like going to die.
Yeah.
We like to be able to breathe the air
and it's going to be filled with
electrical currents.
How's that possible about dude?
250,
50 billion gallons of methane are being
pumped in the air.
Okay.
And that's floating.
How many pounds of Wifi we eating right
now while we're eating this podcast?
Maybe that's what's going on with
America.
We're so overweight because we're eating
wifi.
No,
my new theory or eating Wifi and four g
lte,
the only thing it's doing is making more
autistic people.
We were okay with three g up to three g
and then we fell apart.
We're just eating too much.
It's weight
and autism.
What do you think it gives people autism
series?
Yeah.
I think there's something to,
or autism is just on the rise at cry
like so hot right now.
Like,
no,
I mean,
but yeah,
I think there's a bunch of different
causes that they think,
uh,
I think they think genetics.
They think people when they get older
and have children much more likely,
uh,
that the children are going to have
autism becomes,
they become much more susceptible as the
parents get like older and older.
It's like directly proportionate they
think.
But there's a lot of questions.
But what causes it or and whether or not
it's more prevalent today or whether the
diagnosing of it is more prevalent.
I believe that's,
that's debatable.
Well,
you know when there's more people today,
so obviously there's going to be more
cases of it,
but are they the same percentage of
cases?
Like one of the things that they've
always tried to correlate is marijuana
with schizophrenia and the problems that
were exposed.
I think in the culture high they had
this where they were saying that the
instances of schizophrenia have been
uniform throughout history.
When we,
we monitoring it,
it's like 1% of the population,
100% of the population skids phrenic.
Like just because that 1% may or may not
have smoked marijuana,
it's,
it doesn't raise it.
When marijuana becomes more popular.
When it gets used more,
it's still stays at 1% it doesn't seem
to vary from one person.
It's just 1% deviation.
It's like the quality control of God is
not the best in the world.
Yeah,
I don't think it's weird.
I think it's mushrooms is an acid and
psychedelics,
I would actually speed ups,
that kind of stuff.
I,
I mean,
I know so many people that have tripped
it never came back and you have mental
health issues.
Anything is not good for you.
Alcohol,
certainly not good for you.
Mental health issues.
You,
you're,
you have a hard enough time just
remaining,
stay stable when you're sober,
if you're one of those bad,
some of them unfortunately,
unfortunately.
Hi is that,
you know,
Tony Tony's era from Columbus number
Tony Krantz a turtle turtle had always
the best fucking explanation for that.
He,
he like,
he made some play of words with
psychotic and neurotic and Louise always
talk about it,
but it's so true.
Like it's,
it's the common theme that everybody
always says,
like the crazy girls are the best in
bed.
True.
And probably girls think crazy guys are
the best in bed,
which is why dirty dancing was so
appealing to young ladies in the 1980s.
Patrick swayze,
smooth,
hairless chess,
sleek body moves like a dancer,
flies across the room.
Uh,
is that I had at the time of my life.
Is that the one?
Well listen bitch,
you're only 18.
Okay.
There's plenty of years coming.
Don't get so crazy about nostalgia.
Oh my God.
The good old days when I was 18,
the fuck is wrong with you.
How about you keep running it?
Don't,
don't get us to sign of a bitch.
How
have you ever had a clip that I like
something pops out of it.
Like it like almost like a,
like a tongue.
Like a cow tongue comes out clitoris.
Yeah.
Like that.
But it pops up randomly in the middle of
talking about dirty dancing.
We were supposed to know what the fuck
you just said like a pussy boner.
But like when it actually comes out like
sticks out and goes in.
It's called a deck.
Brian,
fuck,
you're fucking a guy.
Fucking a guy again.
Is it a bodybuilder?
No.
That does happen with bodybuilders.
Yeah,
with female bodybuilders.
If they take steroids,
but it was like a girl.
It was like a boner that was in the
pussy.
They just came out.
I've never seen it before.
He would freaked me out.
There's some crazy fucking videos like
you're well,
you're grabbing it like it's a fucking
giraffe.
No,
the hand,
the hand gestures you're making are not
polite.
Not like dainty did a penis.
It was a tiny nothing to be offended by.
It was nothing that's going to scare
children.
It's nothing's going to hurt anybody's
feelings.
Just a little tiny penis.
It's inside a woman's vagina.
I don't know why it's there.
Maybe fuck the hermaphrodite.
Is that how it works?
No.
I was eating it and it just started
hitting me in the chin.
Okay,
you're still going to duck.
You're sucking Dick and you're on a
Mescalin.
You okay?
Volumes.
You were talking about volumes.
I get it.
Do it.
Somebody drugged you and major bomb like
you was fucking noise Dick and said my
posts you wrote and you're like,
Yo,
pussy so hot.
You don't know why you're gagging.
I'm just eating pussy to it feels like
I'm talking to day
about pussy smell and that dude's,
but you're like,
that is a lot of girls,
but there's no way
that big dick inside of that pussy todd.
Meanwhile you wake up all clay looted
out.
What the fuck happened?
Who?
Who dosed me?
I just never saw it that violent before.
Like it actually come down to getting
just choked.
It looked like a fat fucking look like,
like a small boxers arm,
like 135 pound champion arm.
You know,
like a fucking one of them Mexican
dudes.
It throws a nasty left hook to the body
like a Salvador Sanchez arm roping.
Fucking send you in.
It's just slamming in the back of your
throat.
Fucking quileutes.
Okay,
so an asterix and asteroids coming and
you have 10 minutes to do the run out in
the street and you do what?
Just fuck everyone else in the street
taking off their clothes.
I don't think anybody's getting it up
and it's going to be the saddest thing
in the world.
Did they hit in the head by a rock and
you're too nervous to get it up.
The why.
Why is it you're ready to Bang your
sister?
Finally we get to see each other for 35
years.
It's fucking do this.
She's like,
fuck yeah,
I was wanting to fuck my brother.
You know he spits on his dick and he's
trying to get it hard in that fucking
thank,
he's getting closer and closer and she's
like,
come on,
we're going to die.
You're such a fucking loser.
I always knew you were a loser.
I give you a chance to fuck me.
Right is common and you fucking blew it.
Charlie Brown,
and you see that asteroid getting bigger
and bigger in the last remembering this
guy has is he trans forms and changes in
in connects with hyperspace as him not
being able to get it up while sister
screamed at him in the street staring at
an asteroid.
It makes me wonder though,
because I feel like there was going to
be a large amount of people.
If that happens,
that will run into the street.
Be like,
that's it.
Fuck people that no one wants to fuck.
They're like,
no,
they're going to run past you and
they're going to bang that hot MILF,
that fucking Moser Alon in high heels,
heels,
shoes,
every,
every fucking street has that.
One crazy lady does is puts out the
scent,
puts that heat sent out in the air.
It is probably going to be mass rapes
and that's all it is.
Like people just busting down doors
trying to that girl.
Ooh,
that's what I'm talking about.
That's what I'm saying.
Go for it from Friday.
Who that?
That's Parker.
Ms. Parker.
Famous park.
Oh,
please go full screen with this.
Let me see.
Whoa.
God Damn.
Oh sit day.
I stickley,
they asteroid flies by asteroid flies by
it and there's all these people that
fuck that shit in a fuck.
Then they have babies like Kanye and
Katelyn have a kid together and it's
called the asteroid.
I don't mean in a race rectify this
young lady,
but that is a very strong part of her
anatomy.
Very strong.
I'm needed.
Objectifier but congratulations on
hitting the genetic lottery.
Like the height of that ass.
You go hot,
you know in that position it should like
retain like a little flatness.
The thing must be,
look when she stands straight up,
let's see it now it's here now.
No,
no,
don't do,
don't blow this whole thing.
But shadow don't be so mean about the
universe and time.
Is there a photo of her?
Her,
but just standing there.
Is that right above her?
Right above is it?
No.
Does that her down there to watering
right there.
Oh good Lord.
What is it about hip to waist ratio?
You know?
Oh my goodness.
What a good kid.
The genetic mother fucking lottery.
That's why it must fucking suck.
It must fucking suck.
If you wished you looked like that and
you didn't just looking at her go.
I said,
especially if you're a guy like save
your guy and you,
you feel like you identify being a
woman,
but you really want to look like that.
But meanwhile you look like Ralphie May.
Well you look like Joey Diaz.
I think I'd be as sexy as fuck woman.
I think if I've never dressed up,
I think I've beat,
I'm just clicking right now.
That's not true.
You definitely have womanly hips.
You would look like you already shut
out.
All your kids though.
Did we should dress up as a woman.
One episode.
She used to be a barker,
but apparently to back in the back of it
then we should see who could it be was a
playboy.
What's that?
Right there.
It wasn't say playboy.
She's got naked pictures.
Good for her.
You know?
That's another thing I think is not
nothing wrong with playboy folks.
Nothing wrong with naked bodies,
but there's nothing wrong with porn
either,
but we're not there yet.
Right.
Getting close.
People are getting closer for sure,
but more acceptable nowadays.
The kids know what it is nowadays.
I didn't know that.
They always stay all this crap.
Yeah.
Anyone can just look at porn.
Do you think that vr stuff could save
porn?
Where does it go?
I mean that's like,
do you think that better cooking can
save food?
They won't give it away for free.
So like you have to buy it,
they will give it away for free.
They don't.
Yeah,
but see dude,
this,
I think in a lot of ways what's going to
happen with some of the artists that
kind of use the most respectful term
possible is a,
they can make personal appearances,
they can make a ton of money doing that.
Like sort of like a,
like almost like musicians that don't
sell too many cds now.
Like it's hard other than apple maybe to
apple should get in the porn business,
say fuck it,
stop being pussies about it.
Just get in,
sit down.
And if apple just decides to go whole
hog and has an adult APP,
okay.
And you opened up their adult app,
it comes in the opera,
it just called adult and you enter in
all your information that shows that
you're a certain age and you,
you know,
he'd do the thumbprint thing.
You have to do the thumb printing to
activate so they know it's you and not
someone using your phone that knows your
code that isn't of age.
And then you watch as much fucking porn
as you want
it.
They shouldn't.
They should do it.
I know they're stupid not to do it.
You could buy it then the actors can get
paid.
Exactly.
Notice I said actors,
actors,
models,
Lucky's,
everything that bill hicks bail about
models like here's,
here's Debbie modeling a 12 inch Dick in
her mouth.
I'm like,
I did it.
No justice.
I'm trying to remember.
It was,
I'm saying it.
You know Bill Hicks is a is Alex Jones,
right?
That's what I heard.
What does this,
your iphone can be hacked with a photo
of your thumb.
Chase us.
Of course.
It could be your iphone could be hacked
by you're asleep.
Yeah.
The government,
the government is already reading your
tweets.
I twitter messages.
I tried that though.
Like my,
I was dating a girl and I did the whole
thumb to see if it would work and it
did.
It did.
I'll wash it asleep.
That's so rude.
So rude.
It's rude.
It's wet.
Esther does.
Little esther goes while it let her
boyfriend's in the bathroom and turns on
location shit where it so she could just
track all day long.
Weird.
That's an option in your phone that a
lot of people don't know is I can turn
on my location tracking and send it to
you so you can just track me for life.
What is so weird,
the people you want to do that and they
want to like fall people.
What pill?
Fuck you up to Jamie.
How about people that would do that?
Their employees.
It makes it employees stay within a
certain range.
I don't want you to going out on the
road this weekend and getting all tired.
I want you to be fresh for work Monday,
but Mr. Wilson,
you can't tell me where to go on in the
world this weekend.
Well,
if you want a promotion,
you'll be the guy that stays in and get
some arrest.
Is that possible?
I mean if,
if bosses can tell you that you can't
have that,
you have to have a piss test.
Okay.
If they could piss test you.
Well they're saying is they want to make
sure you didn't smoke some pot on the
weekend.
Right?
Have you get there Monday?
Like I know guys who won't smoke pot
because they worried they're going to
get tested randomly at work and it would
cost them their job.
You get fired,
so if you get,
you've smoked a joint on Friday after
work,
then you know the fights are on.
You get a pizza with your friends,
you guys smoke a joint,
you have a laugh,
you watch pizza and then you show up
Monday morning.
Do you really think they're going to be
affected by that joint?
Nope.
Not at all.
But they'll test positive.
They're going to test positive.
That's,
that's the same thing.
It's not,
it's just like your boss is telling you
mentally to stay put.
I mean that's the same thing.
That's what they're doing.
I used to have to do that.
I remember I would smoke weed and I'm
like,
Goddamn,
I smoked weed.
Now I better not get tested in the next
couple of weeks.
I would like freaking out looking at the
calendar like shit and they can have a
zero tolerance policy I think of write
it into their contract cause it's an
illegal drug and they just fire you man
and you,
you,
you could have totally non-psychoactive
levels in your system.
Doesn't matter.
Totally sober.
And also there's no science that backs
that.
There's long term effects of you know
you smoke a joint on Friday night and
you know on Monday morning some sort of
a long term it does nothing and,
and by eight and if there is judge the
person based on their performance at
work,
don't you know,
you,
you can't,
if someone's not doing their job at
work,
I mean that's why they check each other
out and that's why they have assessments
and stuff and that's why you have
meetings with your supervisors.
That's what that's for.
Okay.
It doesn't nothing to do with what,
like one person could be a fucking moron
and never touch a drop of alcohol and
never smoke and never do anything their
whole life.
And they can be a fucking moron.
You don't get Brownie points,
you'll get extra points for not doing
drugs.
You just don't.
It's like what happens when the guy
does?
Is he okay?
What if he has a couple of drinks on
Friday and,
uh,
he shows up Monday morning,
fresh as a daisy.
He worked out at the gym at five 30 and
he's fucking here ready to rock and
roll.
What do you,
what do you give a fuck?
Like it's stupid.
It's a stupid like distinction to put on
someone to think that somehow or another
it's bad.
Yeah.
This weekend about Netflix,
they offer unlimited vacation time to
their work.
As long as they get their work done.
So like,
and theoretically,
I guess you'd go get high and take two
weeks off and come back and be fuck
yeah.
Mean Netflix
killing it again.
Right.
I'm addicted to Narcos,
man.
I'm like seven episodes in now.
I did the seventh one last night.
Fuck,
that shows good.
God Damn.
It's good.
It's a fucking wellmade show.
It's like a movie every week,
you know?
And I like,
it's crazy that it's all based on a true
story.
Pablo Escobar was insane.
Like you got to watch this series folks,
you got to watch this series because
it's all based on real events and you
realize how unbelievably insane Escobar
was and the amount of power and money
that guy at.
It's incredible.
It's beyond imagination and they did
such a great job of building up the
production of showing like how they
started making it and selling it and
showing the impact of it and fuck.
It's good.
Fuck it.
Good.
Did you hear about the guy in Miami who
recently bought a house and when they
were excavating some of the property,
they found a safe and it was Pablo
Escobar's former house.
Oh Shit.
The press and the first safe got stolen
and they found a second safe and they
told the press again.
I don't think it's not being kept
somewhere so they can,
I don't think they've opened it or found
out what's in it,
but as an asshole,
keep your mouth shut son.
Don't you have friends?
Where do you get a friend?
Pickup truck.
It's time to get rich.
I wonder if that money's flagged.
You know,
probably if there's money in it,
it's gold.
Open up the safe.
And it's just,
who knows?
Mother saves heads.
All people that Pablo Escobar hated safe
found within concrete of the late truck
king.
Wow.
That's amazing.
Fuck man.
They said the management was believed to
just to be used the stash cash.
So
Dude,
you gotta watch this series.
It's incredible.
It's incredible when you realize how
much money that guy had and how much
power and how much havoc he caused.
And then it wasn't that long ago.
And now they say Columbia is like really
safe and really
nice.
I Columbia is a totally different place
now.
Now that all that shit's done with it.
They're like,
no,
it's nice.
Like they figured it out.
Like bourdain went there for a show and
you a,
you see what it's like now.
It's like,
it's really beautiful.
So they actually worked our way through
this issue.
It's crazy cause people think of
Columbia and you think of the,
the metagene cartel,
you think of the drug killings of him.
It's like one of the most iconic things
about it.
Right?
And then coffee.
Yeah.
Right.
Also saw the drones being used to carry
drugs over the border.
Yeah.
I said,
go this weekend.
And two prisons even there,
people are using drones to do things to
madness.
God dammit.
All right.
I gotta get the fuck out of here.
It's four 17 right now.
Wednesday.
Brian Red Ban.
I believe there's a show we're doing a
death squad secret show at the U and R
are a shift far.
How's it a secret if you're telling
everybody,
because there's a secret cast,
but I'm not going to tell you about,
oh,
you're so tricky.
But John Heffron,
Rory Scovel,
Dean del Rey.
Nice.
Okay.
And that starts at eight 30 comedy
store.
Main rooms were full and a,
I'm doing don my rare show today at the
laugh factory at eight.
And then,
um,
the Dean Delray Show after that,
the 50th birthday show that's at the El
Rey theater.
And that's Brian Red band.
Chris,
who else?
Who else is with Chris Delea?
Berge,
Joe,
Joe Barton,
Nick,
uh,
Bill Burr,
Kristala and me.
We're going to have some fun.
And Dean del Rey,
of course,
who's turning 50.
All right.
You fucking animals.
Thank you very much.
Appreciate the hell out of you people.
The hell,
hell um,
the heck about that.
I want to say fuck,
but I want to say fuck twice in a row.
That accurate.
It sounds ignorant.
Goodnight.
Goodbye.
Much love big kids.