Hello Freak bitches culture.
She worked with this girl Susan,
for years that help you get a different
perspective.
Oh,
you know what,
I didn't think of that.
I didn't take that well.
Yeah,
you're right.
So that kind of shit.
Now look,
ultimately you get on the set,
you're going to do it.
You're doing the director's gonna Hey
Steve,
you know,
you shouldn't be so angry they or
whatever,
you know,
he thinks and the guy that wrote it,
you know what I mean?
But I worked very hard at it and I
worked for years now.
Now don't forget I'm making a living for
16 years as an actor and I left the
Riviera in 2000.
Isn't that crazy?
Yeah.
Sixteen years.
So,
and I've done a lot of shit.
This is,
you saying that 2016 years ago makes me
go,
what is that?
Right?
Unless they,
I started on the Sopranos in 99.
I went back and forth for a year,
you know,
I didn't quit.
The judge did six episodes.
I was still at the river.
What is it like the how?
It must've been fucking strange.
Was still at the river.
Then I booked it for 10 years.
I,
you know,
I booked the river till 2010.
Chris Rock said you're still dipping
your toe in that shit.
I said,
why not?
They're paying me.
What the fuck?
How hard is it hard?
Is it to book three comics a week?
I could do it in three days.
Book up six months.
That's hilarious.
You know the book I book guys that,
you know,
that didn't work much,
you know.
Well I think your point is a really
important part of what you're saying is
like the getting a different perspective
or a guy like Kendall feeney.
You would,
you'd imagine he was so good.
You would imagine that he probably
looked at it from all sorts of different
angles.
So yes he did.
And you saw a lot of different colors,
but he,
you know,
he would work 16 hours.
Okay.
Sixteen hour days on the Sopranos.
He's in,
he's there.
So I mean the guy gets up,
whatever time he got up,
then he's got to go home and learn
tomorrow stuff.
So sometimes he told me he'd be sitting
in the chair.
He Fall Asleep for two hours.
He wakes up,
she's still there,
just waiting for him to wake up and
they're going to work on the stuff for
tomorrow.
Whoa.
Yeah.
And,
and,
and nine months of that,
don't forget,
you know the Sopranos,
Joe,
they were,
when I got on the show was like eight
days.
I came on the second season,
so it was like eight days for an episode
that nine and 10 at the last season it
was,
we shot nine shows in nine months.
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
You know,
it was like shooting a movie.
There's no commercials.
So it's a full hour,
but you know,
that's what it was,
man.
It was long.
It was like shooting a movie.
Wow.
I mean month and episodes.
The first episode was 17,
18 working days.
Lorraine Brock was said to me,
you're going to work more in this
episode that I will the whole season
because she only worked one day in
episode.
She had the greatest job in show
business.
Wow.
They shot that in one day.
Oh,
that's beautiful.
For her.
Was a great part two.
Yeah,
it was great.
You know,
but I,
I think the coaching wise,
and I think a lot of it is you focus and
concentrate,
know your stuff,
know your lines.
I mean,
you're an actor,
you know,
know your shit.
Don't come in and be like a smart ass.
Yeah.
Maybe I paraphrase.
Know your stuff.
Respect what's on the page,
you know that I'm a,
I'm a big believer in that.
The Sopranos,
you didn't Ad Lib the word thought and
I'm not joking you.
There was a,
there was a time that I had to say,
uh,
I got to go and the line was I have to
go.
And they kept correcting me and correct
me.
Correct.
Because I just,
you know,
I gotta go home.
I have to go.
I don't know why,
why,
when I didn't question it.
I mean,
you know,
but that's a crazy amount of work when
you're talking about Gandolfini.
That's really,
that's still fucking with my head.
Now listen,
Jim was one of my closest friends,
couldn't find a better guy.
He worked hardly stories.
Kids,
you know,
his kids,
uh,
his daughter wasn't born,
you know,
uh,
while he was on the Sopranos.
But it was like no life.
You could completely gave up your life,
not the rest of us because there was so
many characters,
you know,
I didn't want.
I had a couple of episodes where I
worked the real APP,
but you know,
otherwise this can't be good for your
health.
There was a lot of guys.
I mean,
I think Jimmy Smits I read years ago and
ypd he said he couldn't take,
it was 18,
18 hour days and yeah,
it was making a fortune.
He said I couldn't do it anymore.
Yeah,
no,
I've,
I've had friends that had been on dramas
before,
and this is the same thing.
They would tell me that they just,
they just couldn't do it.
They just with would.
And they would just,
would be,
when the season would wrap there to go,
this has got to be my last season.
I mean,
you know,
it's,
it's a point with the money now.
You know,
the thing,
what I love about blue bloods is there's
a lot of character.
So there's different stories.
So it's not like that.
I'm like signature.
Whoa.
He's hanging up.
It's,
it's,
you know,
like seven of us.
But it's not my signature.
How crazy is that?
Someone's going to fake the signature
hanging up in a nice restaurant.
Bobby voc a lot with the fat stomach
from the days when I wore the fat stone.
Oh,
they made you put like a prosthesis.
Then I got fat enough.
You get
fat enough just so you don't have to
wear that thing one day.
Chase.
Uh,
you know,
I,
when I first got the role,
I was seeing all these jokes,
like you're counseling with legs and you
fat.
Fuck.
And you think,
and I'm going,
I'm not that much fatter than getting
the Fini.
I'm just starting to think that maybe
they catch the wrong guy.
I'm not joking.
I'm saying P,
I mean these jokes don't make sense and
then they call all you got to come in
for a fat suit.
So I was ridiculous thing.
Then the second year they made it like a
really nice one that costs like a
costume shop.
It had like tits and
a costume shop in like a Broadway
costume thing.
And uh,
and then one year I was going back and I
was at a fitting for the fourth year,
you know,
worked in the next year and he looked at
me and he meant,
and you don't have to wait at anymore.
I said,
all right,
so I'm assuming it was pretty
embarrassing at first I was prancing
around that they had an ass on me til
like a big ass fake ass.
And he was gone too big and I was like
going walking back and forth like crazy.
It's fucking,
you will eat
Steve Landesberg comment.
He said to me,
did they actually have permission to do
that?
And I said,
no,
Steve,
he's,
I want him to fucking there that I want.
Well,
I want to get the job,
you know,
that was a weird time when the sopranos
came out because all the sudden it was
like a lot of fake mob guys.
A lot of fake connected.
Got Fake Italian,
you know what I mean?
It's still around.
I call it Gig Guinea actors guild,
but you know what I mean?
It's like that acting that way became in
fashion.
Taste started to taste.
They used to hang around wherever we
weren't around.
They were extras.
It was still around.
But there was,
you know,
we did a appearance in the Kachina.
We do a lot of that stuff.
You know,
they were everywhere.
They were everywhere.
They were hoping to get on the show.
He come out and you did the shot.
It doesn't have to do the show.
I remember Michael Imperioli one time,
we were up in Reno and there's one of
them guys and he was playing blackjack
and you know,
and uh,
except come on,
put me on the show.
I could do,
you do.
I just went off on him.
I've been fucking drive for 20 years,
you know,
blah,
blah.
And then he got,
he hit Michael and Michael was right.
He got really pissed off.
This is just one of those fucking
Goombas,
you know,
Nigga,
I could do the worst.
Exactly.
This like this.
There's wannabes.
But there's something about Guinea
wannabes.
Just a handful out of here.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
And the thing here,
they congregate together when they try
to like climb out tying
together.
What's the last thing?
Rogan.
How come you got Rogan?
I kinda,
I kinda.
And I try to navigate away from even in
New York,
I kinda,
that's not my thing.
And Sopranos was so good that it almost
killed the genre.
I think so I think you're right about
that because you know what,
unless,
and I get a lot of scripts,
Joe,
you know of that crap.
You know,
they make these,
I call them backyard movies,
you know,
you're never gonna see him,
whatever they're getting paid.
I'm not interested.
It's that same thing.
I'll fuck you up.
You know I am,
you know,
my uncle is my rarest gets
but it's true.
But they write this and I say how people
give them the money.
How do you get the money to make these
movies?
Well,
I think for awhile people were making
them just because it's sopranos was so
popular now.
Unless you're going to beat Sopranos
Goodfellas,
you know,
what's the great mob movies?
Some Sopranos,
Goodfellas Casino,
a raging bull had marbella,
right.
Great movie.
Uh,
one of my mission.
It was going to be a few of them,
you know,
some great,
great,
great mob movies.
But right now it was after the Sopranos.
I mean,
you don't see.
No.
The Godfather,
godfather to know that there was some,
but you're to have to beat that.
And they tried,
they tried to do some mobby stuff
already.
Donovan's work.
And that's a good trail.
That's a good show.
That's from an Irish perspective.
Well,
I think what happened with those movies
was,
or,
uh,
that show rather is,
it was those,
you had a movie every week.
Exactly.
So like every subject was covered.
But trail gambling,
it was funny.
Was funny,
funny,
funny elements.
It was very smart.
That was something,
you know,
I would go,
I would be around and people go,
I don't like that show you.
And I'm tired.
Have you ever seen the show?
No,
I haven't seen it.
It's like,
it's actually somebody.
I don't.
I don't watch porn.
I hate putting.
Have you ever seen it?
No.
Well then how do you know you don't like
it?
Or did you see it?
Oh,
do you watch it?
You know what I mean?
But Hey,
they're holding signs of,
I know porn.
That was a big thing,
right?
The Italian American boss society was
telling you,
testing against it.
How about this story?
I wrote a kids book,
Nikki Deuce.
Okay.
Uh,
it took place in Brooklyn and we turned
it into a movie for Nickelodeon,
you know,
we'll try.
We didn't just want to get into treating
installation movies and I had Michael
Imperioli in it and so rico and uh,
uh,
and Nickelodeon made the movie.
But when I was,
when I wrote the book,
I was doing book signings and you know,
it's about a kid fish out of water.
Who goes back to Brooklyn and grew up in
the suburbs and he winds up with a kid,
Italian neighborhood venture nurse in
Brooklyn,
and then it gets into some mischief.
I don't even call it trouble,
but so is guy kept writing letters and
shit and killing me on the Internet and
writing letters to the bookstores are
ahead of me getting there,
you know,
like saying that he's a,
derogatory against the Italians and he's
now he's bringing kids into it and blah,
blah,
blah blah.
So finally I get the guy's number and I
called the guy.
I swear to you.
I say to him,
listen,
I think his name is Zane.
I think his name is anthony.
I said,
listen,
Anthony,
blah,
blah.
This is the world I know,
like rappers rap about what they know.
This is what I know,
you know.
And uh,
he said to me,
I said,
you know,
what can I do?
Tell me what I can do.
Let's fix this.
I mean,
because you know,
you up papa.
He said,
well,
you can make a donation to my
organization.
It was the Italian American bullshit.
I said,
you got to be kidding me.
Hundred
true story.
Trying to shake me down.
There's a whole bunch of.
When the movie came out,
we got some heat for the Nicky deuce
movie.
Really?
And it's not really about mob.
It's intention.
I mean,
exactly.
You know,
and they did that with the cement,
but people would say all the time,
you know,
Joe,
uh,
yeah,
I don't want you to think I'm an
Italian.
You guys talked bad about the times.
You know,
they didn't,
they,
they showed what really was.
I thought it was very authentic.
You know,
oh,
well,
this apprentices is authentic,
is a guess.
If you know anybody like that,
you know,
those people exist.
10,
they don't exist.
Is that fencing?
Exactly.
I think it was a story that needs to be
told.
I don't think in stone this is what it
is.
But it was such a fascinating show
because Gandel feeney was a bad guy.
Like his character.
You're rooted for a bad guy,
a murder for a murderer or cheated on.
His wife stole.
Rob shook people down slowly,
but he was your guy.
He was,
I think the first.
I think I could be wrong,
the first like anti hero that people
will default to.
I think you're right.
I can't imagine before that it was,
you know,
your,
your roof for the guy,
you know,
he was a real anti hero murderer,
a con man.
I mean all of the above
to people in the mob.
They did it to people,
you know,
like on the show.
There wasn't just within each other.
They went outside,
they were robbing people and busting up,
uh,
you know,
businesses and doing all this stuff that
they do.
Yeah,
it was great.
Show was good.
It was very small.
It was a very smart show.
And if it was,
if they put it back on now,
they would get higher ratings than some
of these shows now.
I bet.
Well,
it was so good.
I think a lot of people forgot how good
it was and it also changed a lot.
If you go to the first episode,
the first episode was essentially like a
slapstick comedy.
You remember that?
I'm not in the rain brought out with the
rain Brocco a who was the woman that
played a his wife Edi file community.
Falco and Falco had a fucking machine
gun and like the doctor was trying to
come down and see that and she's outside
with a machine gun point matter.
It was way more slapsticky.
It was weird.
It was like a comedy.
They shot.
Got The show aired in [inaudible] 99,
right.
I think they shot that like in
[inaudible] 98,
if I'm not mistaken,
really,
if I'm not mistaken at 98,
I believe [inaudible] 97 even.
They go back and then it took six months
and then they started shooting them.
You know how,
how David Chase did it?
He didn't do it like a regular show
where you shoot it and then in three
weeks it's on the air.
You know,
he put them all in the can.
They were finished and locked and you
know,
you know what I mean?
Like you,
you know,
you finished your,
your whatever.
It took nine months and then he edited
them and Blah Blah Blah Blah Blah.
And then they added,
you know,
it was done a completely different way
while also they would,
uh,
they would,
you know,
if they didn't like what you did,
I mean he replaced you and you never
even knew it really.
It was placed here,
you know,
like I had a scene with a guy and they
called back,
you know,
a month or so later and said,
you got to shoot the scene again with a
different actor for whatever reason,
whether you know the guy didn't do a
good job or a,
he looked too young or too old or just
didn't fit.
He had the,
he had the capacity to just shoot it
again if it,
if it scene,
didn't he rewrite the scene?
You shoot the scene again three months
later.
What's interesting about those kinds of
shows too,
is that they're so big and so popular
that you become that character.
Whoever that character is,
you become that guy.
You're that guy forever.
Of course.
I mean,
that's part of the deal.
That's okay.
I had no career before that.
So it's not.
I'm not saying with you what I'm saying,
like there's some people that you've
worked since then you'll continue to
work,
but there's some people that were on
that show that we're really famous when
that show was on the air and the
vanished.
Yeah.
Well you're in the,
you know,
you got people all over the world
watching.
I mean,
I've been stopped with people literally
from all over the world that have
watched the show.
It was like a cult hit,
like nothing that ever hit before,
like big pussies,
big pussy for the rest of his fucking.
He's also,
he,
he embraces that too,
you know what I mean?
For him it works and he's okay.
He works.
He does his things.
Know he's always going to work.
He's a very good actor.
He's got his music.
He's a musician and stuff,
but I,
I hear Ya know,
especially the name,
big pussy.
That was a big thing.
People like to say that.
Yeah.
They do like to say that,
but also his,
you know the scene in the movie when
they kill him,
like the whole,
the whole way it plays out.
It was very intense.
It was like,
Whoa,
I can't believe they killed big pussy.
That was the big thing.
It was the first time,
uh,
to have regular cast member gets killed.
I mean,
they're not killing the,
you know,
uh,
the guy from friends.
Exactly.
David Schwimmer and getting killed,
you know,
whole one,
one Friday night.
Oh my God,
they killed David.
Tremendous five friends now,
you know.
So that was a big character that gets
killed and then big carried this kept
getting killed,
which is why guys will worry.
I mean,
there was a real concern that you
weren't going to get killed off the
show.
The material they gave you,
the more of shot you're getting killed.
Yeah.
I mean,
you know,
and let's not kid ourselves.
It's not just,
you know,
you're out of work.
They just put you out of work.
And the biggest show that Glenn,
when Gandolfini killed him periodically,
I was like,
Whoa,
Holy Shit.
His knows.
They're like,
what?
But,
but you know what,
once you made it into the last season,
it was like,
hey listen,
you know,
we've done paid however the story ends.
It's probably better if I would have got
killed early on,
I would've felt really Shitty,
I'll tell Ya.
So all the stuff that happened because
you know,
you know what I mean.
And plus,
you know,
we didn't mention we started making
money towards the middle and the end,
you know,
not the guys at the beginning,
I'm making a lot of money while those
shows are hard to make money like hbo
and Hbo Pace and they pay now even
better than just shows off the end nine
years.
Wow.
Now,
you know,
we went into,
and then there was other money coming in
because he had opportunities to do other
shit,
you know.
Well that show was also groundbreaking
in that it was one of the first shows
like that and now hbo specializes in
those kinds of shows.
And so the show time.
Yup.
Yeah.
I mean,
you know,
it all kind of connected in the soprano
is the first time they,
they're hiring a,
you know,
a fat,
bald guy.
You know,
Jim wasn't a leading man,
right?
They,
they wanted,
you know,
you figure it's a good look at mob guy.
You know what I mean?
But he was intense and charismatic and
one of the girls loved them and we used
to joke,
you know,
they say TV puts 10 pounds on the.
I say it takes 50 off.
Yeah.
Well he was just,
it was such an interesting character.
He was so intense and like when he got
into that murderous rage,
like you fucking bought it,
hook,
line and sinker.
When you acted with him,
you didn't have to,
uh,
you know,
you didn't have to act scared.
Like if it was a scene,
I got to be scared.
You got to yell at me,
you know,
he was fucking,
he gave you the whole thing,
you know,
we had that fight,
me and him had that fight in the first
episode of that list.
So,
you know what I mean.
You know that.
We shot that for a day and a half.
Whoa.
That was tough.
He was choking me.
He said,
listen,
you know,
let's try to take this as far as we can
and we can turn it.
I was pulling his hair.
He was fucking choking me that I was
getting cut from the.
I was wearing a necklace,
you know,
I was getting cut from that.
I mean we've all banged up,
banged up for real and that's why I look
real.
It was like two fat out of shape guys.
Find the fuck out of,
you know guys,
it's not Steven Seagal where we look,
you know,
what the hell this was like a fight
like.
So when you do something like that,
like how hard you hit each other,
you know,
as hard as she could without really
hurting.
And he had said that,
let's go as far as we could and we will
pull my hair,
put my hair,
fucking a stroking me,
go ahead.
Go further.
You know,
like I said,
we were good friends.
You know,
if you do it with a stranger you could
get a little funky.
You know what I mean?
Like,
Hey,
well,
you know,
you know.