Some cool Bosco,
Gino and aj from La speed weed.
You a la live.
Are you tweeting?
Joe just recorded a jingle for us.
So that's your jingle.
New Ringtone.
Um,
first of all,
Gina has been my friend for a long time
and he's basically a,
he's the guy that turned me onto this
whole la marijuana delivery scene that
is going on in La,
which was amazing for Comedians and for
anybody who has a medical card where you
could just call this cool dude and he
would tell you what the great stuff is
and you hang out with them and talk with
them and you could buy it and there's
all totally legal and above board.
It was all good.
But somewhere along the line some
fuckery ran afoot.
They,
uh,
they came up with some new political
rules that keep marijuana delivery
services from operating busy.
Keep explaining it because essentially
the way they've set it up,
it's like you would have to have had a
license to operate in each one of the
houses that you're delivering to.
Is that how it works?
Well,
it used to be called the wild west.
You know,
out here in California for medical
marijuana,
um,
and it,
it very much was until they wanted to
regulate it and most of the people
wanted it regulated because they wanted
marijuana.
So yes,
let's take,
let's have marijuana.
Yes,
let's regulate it.
However it will hold on.
People think that marijuana is legal in
California,
but it is,
it is not.
Absolutely not.
What we have is protection from
prosecution.
That's what we have,
which means that law enforcement can
knock your door down,
take your stuff,
take your,
we'd take your cash,
take whatever you got there,
and you can show them all the papers in
the world and they're like,
that's great.
That's cool.
We're glad you're legal.
Bring it to the judge and you'll be good
to go and you'll get your stuff back in
a year and you guys will be fine.
And that's happened to us.
So.
But do you get your stuff back?
Because I've heard there's a lot of
people that have never gotten their
sleep,
but we always have.
We.
So how long have they kept your stuff
for?
A little over a year.
Year.
So if you have,
if you have weed over a year,
they're not,
they're not taking care of it.
It's done a weeds.
Useless.
It's useless.
So you lose how much money that cost
like that.
Well,
you don't have to set it a substantial
amount of money of course.
And so they give you the cash back,
they'll give it.
They can actually cut you a check.
Yes.
Check for the cash from the district
attorney's office.
Um,
I have one,
uh,
hanging on his wall in his office of
them returning thousands,
a few thousand dollars to us,
which,
because again,
when there was any sort of trouble,
it was all right,
you have to go see a judge,
you go see the judge and the judge looks
at the paperwork.
And in our first case,
the judge said,
we've never seen a more compliant
company in California and dismissed
without
prejudice.
And our lawyer asked,
instead of dismissing without prejudice,
we actually would like that entered in
to the record that you're calling la
speed.
We the most compliant marijuana company
you've ever,
ever dealt with.
So we had an entered into,
into um,
into the record.
Didn't translate though it didn't you
guy have a lawsuit on my desk that I'm
holding my hands 18 inches apart by the
way,
that is that high,
just lawsuit from the city.
It's just super unfortunate because it's
obviously not the will of the people,
you know,
whenever something is not the will of
the people I could see it's clear by all
the gentlemen in this room,
we're all grown adults and we all enjoy
marijuana.
We all have responsible lives,
we all do stuff,
we all get things done and we all enjoy
it and we're taxpayer.
So we're normal people.
We're not freaks.
We're not like Ne'er do wells or someone
who's clinging off the system and,
and fucking up,
you know,
a social systems that we've set up for
people that are trying to get by in this
world.
No,
we're just guys.
And let's talk about what you said just
before the will of the people when they
voted on this,
this proposition d,
which is a zoning law.
Hold on.
Have any of you guys even ever heard of
Zoning Ordinance Measure d?
Has anyone heard of that?
That's.
No,
of course not.
Of course not.
Has anyone heard of it,
but hold on.
We haven't heard of any zoning.
Nobody does.
That's the thing is nobody pays
attention to zoning laws,
so now speed,
weed and services like ours that are
doing things the right way are closed
and in the city,
because of the zoning ordinance that was
passed because all these pot shops are
opening up,
so they said they're opening near
schools and churches got to protect the
children.
Got Every hilarious that opening them
near churches is an issue.
It shouldn't be politics in church and
state.
It's politics.
They.
They say that during the old days of the
Catholic church,
when they would walk down the aisle with
that incense thing,
they will be burning marijuana.
That's what they would be burning and
there'll be wafting it through the room
as they walk by your mountain.
You know those things,
they get around those things,
had weed in them.
There's a pamphlet online about them.
I want to end up.
Might not be true,
but it seems like it's not sure.
Let's just run with it.
Like Jamie,
genesis 1:47.
That's probably one of them.
Todd mccord.
I'm in quotes,
but probably told me that and I'm like,
oh,
that's a fact.
For sure.
I'm not even going to bother looking
that up.
It sounds so good,
but certainly cannabis has been part of
the human record since the beginning.
It's a bizarre time we live in and it's
a long,
complicated explanation.
If someone who's never heard it before,
it's like,
well,
how did it get illegal?
Most of it got illegal because of
William Randolph hearst,
which is bananas that here we are in
2016 and this fucking crazy man from the
19 thirties who's running all these
running
everything and the the man that citizen
Kanes based on the Western welles movie,
he was just a maniac and he decided to
get marijuana eat to make it illegal so
that hemp would be illegal.
Correct?
Yeah.
The tax papers,
timber industry,
and it is insane that the propaganda
that this guy created,
the 19 thirties,
even though we recognize that everyone
knows it,
it's a fact.
You can watch it.
You can watch reefer madness.
You can see what's written down,
what they were they were attempting to
do to make it illegal.
The fact that it still sticks in 2016
and you couldn't smoke that stuff that
they,
that they had any.
No,
no.
It's not psychoactive.
Well,
that is the craziest part.
Like we added on it.
We sell him,
but we have to buy it from Canada.
Yes.
Buy It from Canada and bring it down to
the United States because even though
it's legal and it's not psychoactive,
these farmers can't grow it major.
They're starting to try to change those
laws,
but as far as I know,
I mean I don't know of any large scale
hemp growing operations here in the
United States.
Not yet.
Not yet dangerous.
Like China's just dedicated millions of
acres.
You're on your own.
You will have to worry about your own
government when you're growing a plant
that you make clothes out of.
You make paper.
That's all they're doing with it.
Like,
let's be really clear on that,
that the Hamptons,
they're growing.
He can't get high off of it.
It's totally non psychoactive.
Yet it's federally illegal.
There's a fucking plant that makes the
best clothes.
It makes way stronger fabric,
way stronger paper.
You can eat it.
It has all the essential amino acids.
It's like a full complete amino acid
profile.
It's one of the very few plans that's
like that.
You can make bio fuel out of it.
You can make fucking livestock.
Could you look at old ironsides,
the USS Constitution,
the flag,
and,
and the,
and the sales are made of hemp and there
are still.
Those are the original things for
hundreds of years ago.
One of the best things that nature has
ever created.
This fucking fiber.
It has this incredibly powerful fiber.
Like who the fuck was at?
One of my friends has an actual hemp
stalk.
And uh,
I was over his house and I picked it up
and I was like,
Whoa,
this is like a fucking alien plant
because it's hard as a hardwood tensile
strength.
The stronger than steel when it's wound.
Yeah.
So it feels hard like oak,
but it's light like Balsa Wood.
Yeah,
it's really weird.
You can make spaceships out of this
shit.
It feels like it's light and strong and
we're not using it because it's illegal.
It's fucking crazy.
Crazy.
Parachutes used to be made out of it.
Uh,
I know George Bush senior jumped out of
a plane in a with a hemp parachute,
you know,
so.
So all canvases,
all canvases.
The Mona Lisa was painted on,
cannabis was unhappy.
Our founding fathers had hempfields in
their farms because the head cleans the
fallow fields after wheat fucks up your
fields and corn fucks up your fields.
Hip goes in there,
cleans it all out.
It's.
So,
it's such an identifier of how goofy
people are here in 2016,
that that's an issue that we're dealing
with this weird hemp thing because it's
related to marijuana.
Does anyone hear this though?
I mean,
did people really with,
with trump and hillary and Bernie,
do people really care that they do?
They don't know.
I don't know.
Most people have no idea.
Most people think there's some health
related risks and that's the reason why
it was made illegal.
That's why we're.
It's so for such a frustrating time for
us because we start talking about Zoning
Ordinance d and people are like,
I'm so bored.
Can't we just get baked?
What do you mean you're out of business?
Well,
don't you feel like.
How long have you guys been in the
business?
About six years.
Six years.
How much has changed in six years?
So much since I've had a card.
I got my card in.
It was the nineties,
the nineties,
so there is one.
It was just one state here.
When we got in the business there was
about five states that are legal now
there's 24 in Florida is going to go.
That's going to be 25 plus DC.
It's half the country.
That's crazy.
And CBD is at.
If you conclude cbd,
there's only like seven or eight states
that are not participating,
like seven or eight states.
I guess now I'm thinking about it.
I guess it was more like 2001.
It's still way early,
but my,
my point was going to be that it's way
more relaxed now.
It's way more prevalent.
I used to have to go to Inglewood.
I go to Inglewood wellness center is
one of the gentleman that worked there.
Got Shot and that's when I stopped
going.
But that's how it was when we started,
right when we started,
how it wasn't much of a smoker when I
moved out here to California.
Um,
and uh,
you know,
he kinda sending,
now you're being condescending.
You guys fucking with each other.
Right?
So,
so,
you know,
uh,
we were working in technology for the
government before we started speed.
We together because your CIA and
infiltrated,
you know,
um,
don't put me in sturgeon Simpson's
category.
Let me tell you this story.
Real Cook,
sturgill Simpson was onstage and some
dude yells out in the audience,
sturge will please tell me not really a
CIA assassin.
And he just shrugged and went on the
next side.
Wheeler Walker Jr.
How funny is that dude?
Oh my god,
he's hilarious.
So,
so Ha was um,
uh,
we were working in a stressful
environment working for congress,
uh,
at the time.
And he was actually drinking to medicate
himself as we were,
you know,
working,
doing technology,
coding and things like that.
And he started playing with a new world
tropics to say,
you know what?
I'm not going to drink anymore.
And I said,
instead of new world tropics,
why don't you try cannabis?
YOu know what?
I was that guy who had the shelves of
modafinil and annual paps and all and
you're healthy and all these different
crazy thinGs that you can get on off the
market.
And gina was like,
just smoke this.
Just put all that shit away.
Put the booze away and just smoke this.
I'm like,
no,
it's going to make me freak out.
Well,
one thing that nootropics do help,
it helps me to maintain memory while
under the influence because it's one of
the most slippery things while being
under the influence of pot as the memory
is,
the memory gets real slippery.
Sure.
Yeah.
I think I gave him mouth the brain also.
Uh,
when we first first started.
Yeah.
That'll help.
Some people say that nicotine actually
helps in some strange way.
I use nicotine everyday.
Your nicorette.
I've never smoked it.
He started,
he started chewing the nicotine gum,
you know,
a few years ago.
And I said,
so you're on the ball.
I love it.
Yeah.
Well this is what it is.
Like nicotine itself apparently has a
similar effects to a lot of nootropics
and that it does something to stimulate
your brain function,
but smoking is fucking horrible for you.
So like,
it's not really the getting of the
nicotine,
which is so confusing because you
automatically assume nicotine equals
lung cancer.
Everybody dies.
That's so sad.
why do they do it?
And then you,
why are you doing nicotine?
And they go,
no,
it's the smoking of these chemicals
that's fucking up your lungs.
And it's giving you cancer,
it's irritating your lungs.
You know when people cough,
it's harsh.
Fucks your lungs up,
you get cancer,
you die.
That's what's going on.
it's not the nicotine's fault.
No,
it's not.
So nicotine itself is some sort of a
very strange compound that sort of like
stimulates your mind a little bit.
Yeah.
I think it's the drug that just knows,
like if you're wired,
it relaxes you.
If you're a little bit cloudy headed,
it gives you a boost of energy to it.
It sounds like it's in your veins,
your.
That's your friend.
The drug.
Who knows?
man,
who
knows?
A boy has no name the gum.
It's so gross.
I love it,
man.
Look at you.
The drug that knows.
That's hilarious.
The four milligram coated for flavor
from target.
Oh brother.
I was.
I wanted,
I wanted to do what I could to try and
help help this situation.
It wasn't,
didn't really need to be helped that
much,
but I said,
look,
you should just try,
try marijuana.
Um,
it's,
it's what regulates my mood and has
since I was.
I've been smoking almost daily since 15
years old.
Um,
and uh,
so I,
so I said,
let's,
let's go to the doctor.
And uh,
and he didn't want to go to the doCtor
with me.
no,
because this is back in the early days
when everything was sketchy.
So we go to this office building that is
up in san fernando and there's barbed
wire around the building.
We go into sketchy office building and
I'm,
I'm freaking out the whole time,
you know,
our dad's a cop,
we've got clearance from the government
of what do we,
this is crazy and chinos is just like,
chill,
we're fine,
you know,
cheer,
nicotine,
let's go.
And we go into this office,
this doctor's office,
clearly not a doctor's office.
And they say,
you know,
the doctor will see you both now and now
I'm freaking out thinking like what?
I have to get undressed in front of my
brother and sit on the paper with this
doctor.
I don't whAt I'm doing.
And we just go into a room and there's a
table and he sits across from us and he
asked me first.
Unfortunately,
what you need weed,
and I said,
you know,
and I'm staring at him,
my brothers look at me and I could feel
him going,
don't fuck this up,
like don't fuck this up.
So he's like,
oh,
you have stress?
I said,
yes,
you have terrible sleep.
I said,
yes.
It says okay,
you have weed.
And he called it,
we'd,
he called it wheat and then he goes to
my brother,
why do you need we eat?
And my brother goes,
I have stress and trouble sleep.
He the okay you have weed.
And we got these papers and it felt so
sketchy,
but we went to a dispensary that
afternoon and it's like those early
people that started to open dispensary's
like the inglewood wellness center.
Those people who like the pioneers in
the wild,
wild west.
That is a gangster moved.
Well,
it took some of the criminal element to
be in business at that point and that's
why going back to these laws that say
you had to be in business before 2007 in
order to even be considered in these few
that are allowed.
Well let's explain.
Let's explain the whole zoning thing.
So the issue is delivery,
right?
That's where the issue is.
So prop the is what governs all of las
marijuana laws.
That's a zoning law.
Um,
so there's 135 shops that are allowed.
Those are the ones that have been
operating since 2007.
They're called pre ico is any other shop
you go to is illegal.
Any delivery service you use in the city
of la is illegal according to
proposition d,
which we are fighting in court by the
way.
We are fighting that and that law just
came out in,
in uh,
2012,
2013,
2014.
So we had,
we hadn't been in business for years.
We had already been working with the
state government for years on,
on the process of legalization.
we advise the state assembly were the
only retail company on the,
on the board of equalization stakeholder
panel.
I know,
I know I'm in the weeds right now,
but like we are the company that instead
of suing us,
you should have just said,
hey guys,
what's a good way to do this?
You know,
that that's important to talk about
that,
you know,
the board of equalization is kind of
like the irs for the state.
If you're a commercial business,
you pay your taxes to the board of
equalization.
Well,
the board of equalization chose our
company as the one retail company that
they wanted to present to the
legislature,
to,
to the people with,
um,
with we presented with the New York
state.
Uh,
I mean,
uh,
the California state troopers,
the highway patrol,
the teamsters insurance company,
and an app company and us.
Can I just say the board of equalization
that,
that name,
it sounds like some sort of an overseer
in a woody allen movie,
but the future they kind of are the
board of equalization that some like
fucking utopian nightmare mirror the
right theory.
How are you?
I'm just trying to be a good neighbor
and not good enough white man.
See any business owner.
Here's board of equalization and they're
freaking like,
they're laughing,
but they're also afraid.
What is equalization mean?
It would be a word that seems like they
made that word up.
Now that I think of it,
that's kind of fucked up that it's
called equalization.
Like we're going to take the businesses
money and give it to y'all here so we
can all get equalized.
That doesn't,
that doesn't work.
No,
it doesn't.
It.
Some people are lazy.
It doesn't work.
This has got to be a way though.
They think that a universal basic income
that giving people $13,000 though,
like giving everybody through some.
Michael shermer actually just tweeted
this,
who's the really intelligent skeptic
guy,
um,
and they think giving people $13,000 a
year,
like giving it to everybody would reduce
crime,
would reduce poverty.
It would give people chAnces to pursue
other things if they had the universal
basic income.
It's a really strange concept because
it's one of those things that everybody
has an ego reaction to.
I definitely did.
I heard it and I was like,
get outta here.
You can't just give people money.
People are too lazy.
But the more I read about it and the
more I see people who are quite a bit
more educated than me on this subject,
they think that it's possible that doing
something like that would actually cost
less money in the long run because it
would start a cascade of positive events
that giving people enough money to get
by on right.
That,
that would start like a series of events
in a lot of these people's lives were
issues,
would be taken care of,
that are insurmountable.
Otherwise it'll start some momentum in a
positive way and that you're going to
deal with less crime and you're going to
deal with less of violence.
So you're going to deal with less need
to deal with the problems and the
financial repercussions of crime and
violence.
It'll overall cost less money to the
community.
I'm skeptical though.
My knee,
my knee jerked.
Yeah.
When I did mine did too.
And I was first talking about it with my
friend eddie wong from a vice from that
vice show.
What's his fucking chose in world or
something?
Is that what it is?
Um,
but he brought It up and I was like,
why get the fuck out of here?
And then when I realized that there were
a lot of people bringing this up,
I said,
okay,
well let me,
let me put my knee down
with dj,
let's put,
let me just open mindedly look at this.
And I'm like,
oh,
okay.
I'm looking at,
in the port,
like if you give people money,
they're just going to be lazy and then
everything going to get anything done
and you're going to deal with a bunch of
lazy people.
Plateau effect,
right?
So like the worst fears that people have
when they're worried about welfare,
that you create a welfare environment
where people get accustomed to that and
they have no ambition and nothing ever
gets done.
It's Almost a way to poison people's
ambition is to give them money.
Like Switzerland just had thIs thing
where they were going to give everybody,
I think it was like $2,500 a month,
just like free income.
And then hope that that would pay for
everyone to be like a,
just a little bump.
So they would keep their jobs and stuff
like that and they're like,
they're shitty jobs would feel a little
bit better,
but theN they,
uh,
they denied it and yeah,
it didn't pass.
But that would be interesting.
Everybody getting free income.
Well yeah,
that's the idea behind this and
Switzerland is a very inclusive country
where everyone serves in the military
and has To participate.
That would be a good place to try
something like this because America is
obviously a little bit more loosey
goosey with that kind of shit.
We gotta spread that we had dollar
bills.
Y'all.
How much,
how big is Switzerland?
Like how many people live there?
I mean that's,
that would be like given universal basic
income to la,
you know,
really that,
I mean those are the arguments for like
universal healthcare and all that.
Well it works in Finland.
Well Finland is like the size of long
island and westchester county one.
I mean just think about like the stuff
that flies in Canada,
right?
You know,
Canada has a totally different country.
They're connected to us but they're
fucking completely different and they're
right there.
So if anybody says it works for Canada,
like there's only $30,
million of that's right.
Have a huge fucking country and there's
only 30 million people and they're just
nicer.
They are.
You just nice if there's a canadian that
room,
you told it,
you know it immediately.
They're nice.
They're like some of the nicest fucking
human beings on the planet.
It's a one country that I wouldn't think
twice.
I wouldn't think twice about moving to
Canada.
Well,
they're ahead of the curve on cannabis
for sure.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Delivery is the only option in Canada,
right?
And it's government sanctioned.
Yeah.
The government is essentially this new
guy that has gotten in.
What's the new guy's name?
I'm the young guy.
The handsome fella.
I gotta think of the guy from dunes
burdens.
The government is also behind their
alcohol sales also in,
in Canada.
Like you can't buy liquor unless it's
through the government,
but I'm not as a drug dealer in Canada,
Canada.
I kinda,
I,
I'm very,
I'm very libertarian so I don't like the
government involved wherever possible.
Yeah.
That's some interesting rulings about
comedy up there too.
There was,
there was one guy that got heckled by
some women in a nightclub in vancouver
and apparently they were really drunk
and you know,
things happen in comedy clubs.
People get crazy,
they yell things out,
you're serving people drinks,
they're going to get crazy.
They're gonna yell things out.
So he was yelling things at them and he
said a bunch of rude stuff about them
being lesbians,
but you're homophobic stuff and they
suit them and they won $15,000,
$15,000 going down his men would it once
people start hurling insults at each
other,
like the women hurled insults at the
comedian,
the comedian hurled insults at the
woman.
I don't know who started it off.
I think that would be imperative to find
out who started it off.
But,
um,
I know that the guy was on stage doing
stand up.
So they're not supposed to be yelling.
This isn't a conversation.
If they're talking to him,
I guarantee you,
unless he's a crowd worker,
I don't know if he does.
He's a guy that works crowds,
but I guarantee you most likely he was
getting interrupted.
So he's trying to do is act for all the
people in the room who's was getting
interrupted and then it got ugly.
Right?
And what's the answer to have people
sIgned waivers before they walk in the
comedy clubs.
It's silly.
It's just you can't.
You can't
have a monetary reward for someone that
heckled.
You shouldn't be able to extract money.
A comedy club like that because you go
in trying to make it happen.
Because I go,
look,
you go to a baseball game,
you get hit with a foul ball,
you die.
You can't sue anybody because it's kind
of a given.
That dangerous shit is flying around.
Balls are fast and hard.
Fuck baseball.
I didn't know that could happen,
but if you go to a comedy club comedy
club,
first rule is you're in the audience.
Shut the fuck up.
Second rule is let the comics say what
he wants to say and you might get
offended.
That's the chance you take going in
there.
Yeah,
I mean I don't want to stand up for the
headquarters in any way,
but the only way that it could be
different is if it's like rick ingram
works at crowd constantly,
you know,
talks to people and if you have thin
skin,
he's hilarious.
But if you have a thin skin he'll fuck
with you,
you know,
and Maybe you didn't want that.
And so maybe you insult back and you
know,
rick knows how to handle stuff like
that,
but I'm saying if he's one of those
kinds of comedians that,
that works a crowd,
that's cool,
you know,
but it could have been that he insulted
them first.
It's the only time that I could see
where they would get pissed off.
From what I understand,
they had been heckling all night.
That was according to his version of the
story,
which it's not like people wait to
hackle you know,
someone who's a heckler.
If there's four comedians and then the
night and the fourth guy goes up,
that person's probably been tackling all
night.
Right now they're just drunk.
Or does it scare you though?
like,
like doing material in Canada in the
future,
if it gets heated with like you and a
heckler or you gonna be like,
shit,
this is,
can I better step back a little before I
call her this and that humanness and
that kind of,
that kind of opens the door for this to
be able to like,
oh,
now we're allowed to sue if this,
if the comedian is mean to me.
Yeah.
Well it's,
it's a dangerous precedent to set and
does,
does not make me comfortable and
hopefully I'll never have to deal with
it when I'm up there.
But what about though?
I mean there is like makes new orleans
look like blame like provo when she was
a beautiful town too.
I love performing there.
I find crowds and Canada to be really
polite.
I mean I've had some headquarters in
Canada,
but you're going to have hecklers when
you get people drunk.
They're going gonna fuck it up.
I think the only thing you could do is
probably like they're doing in South
Carolina.
You just,
you have to boycott it to make some kind
of change,
you know,
uh,
how they're boycotting South Carolina.
One's he caught going to vancouver
because of this one room that.
No,
no.
The loophole was at the end of heckling.
You could just say,
just kidding.
You're like a fucking do the thing.
So I know what I'll do with a plane
crashes.
I'll just jump out at the last second.
Right before it hits the ground at the
end goal.
Allegedly.
Yeah.
You don't understand physics?
Not that I do,
but yeah.
I don't know,
man.
It's not a good thing.
It's definitely not a good rule.
Then the fact that he lost his very
dangerous for.
Well,
there's another one going on right now.
We're in.
Yeah.
Another guy got in trouble.
What is his name?
Chris?
Something or other is a comic from
montreal?
I think he speaks both languages.
I think he speaks french and english.
Chris wade.
Is that his name you see there?
They don't have the pesky first
amendment to deal with that.
Yes.
Yeah.
So this is what happened with this
gentleman.
Find out this dude's name is a dude
who's getting sued because there was a
sick kid and he made a joke about it.
He,
the joke was,
it was something.
I'm going to paraphrase it.
I'm gonna do a shitty job,
but a lot of people donated money
because this kid was dying.
But then he lived for like several years
and then the joke was,
hey,
you know,
he wasn't even sick or something like
that.
Mike ward.
That's it.
What is,
what is the joke?
Pull up.
Pull up the joke so we could analyze it.
What did he say?
Oh no,
I'm afraid.
What was,
does it say what the joke?
The joke is,
oh,
a kid's got a serious illness.
That's not a snapchat filter.
Hmm.
Um,
we're looking for whatever the joke was.
It doesn't.
Does it show the actual joke or.
No?
No,
I don't think so.
No.
Maybe it might've been too offensive.
That's the thing is in this room where
it's like,
no rules.
I'm afraid to even make a comment on
that.
That's a joke.
You could play the joke.
I'm not going to laugh.
I'm not going to smirk this.
There's a bunch of comedians you know,
that really enjoy saying ridiculous shit
that they don't really mean because it's
funny because it's so shocking.
Ridiculous that it's funny.
there's a real danger in pretending that
those guys are just speaking their
absolute mind and like giving affidavits
and court relaying incidents with a cold
hard disengagement from the facts.
No,
these are comedians trying to say fucked
up shit that they don't really mean and
one of the reasons why it's funny,
it's because you know,
they don't really mean it and they're
saying it and it's ridiculous.
Like briAn holtzman,
right?
He's a great example.
Perfect example.
He's one of my favorite comedians ever
and he's so ridiculous.
He says thinGs that I don't want to give
away any of his material,
but he says things that he absolutely
does not mean.
Right?
And he says it in this character and
it's fucking hilarious,
but it's a landmine for anybody looking
to point to a guy's performance on stage
and try to that somehow or another,
what he's doing is what he really means.
Right.
And if you see audience members getting
angry at it or or something that it's
hard to imagine how they can't see that
it's a character.
Yes.
You know,
that's not hate speech.
It's just a set material.
Maybe think that we're too close to it
honestly because I think if someone
didn't know it might take them a few
minutes,
like say if you're not a savvy comedy
store,
regular type person or someone who
enjoys common and a regular basis,
you could go and watch holtzman and go,
what the fuck is going on here?
And that might be what the fuck is going
on here?
Might last 10 minutes before you catch
on like that.
This guy,
because he'll let you in on it and he'll
smirk and Joke in between his,
his ramblings.
But I could see people not getting it.
Well that's the thing.
He'll,
he'll jerk and I'll make the smirk and
be in between things.
But the people who are already mad,
they skip over that part.
Yes.
They just think he's a crazy person.
He never justifies though.
Because I mean,
I think I've seen in your special.
You say a lot of this is just comedy
people.
Yeah,
but does he ever say no?
No,
no,
he didn't.
He did a 15 minute version of his gay
son the other day.
I have never seen a full 15 minute
version of that.
It was beautiful.
That could be a comedy special.
Just that.
Yeah,
that is the best examPle of his bits
too.
As far as like the most fucked up thing
you could imagine like in joke form,
but it's obviously not true.
It's so preposterous to it.
Oh my god.
It's funny and it could offend people,
you know,
and if it does to live in a punitive
society that,
that he can't perform being an artist
and perform his art because he has to
worry about being sued is already not
making enough money to be sued for no.
Well,
here's the thing.
You have the right to be offended you,
but people don't have to agree with your
opinions on things.
So if you're going to see art,
right,
whether or not you think stand up,
comedy is art,
you're creating it,
right?
You're creating that.
This guy is performing art.
You either like it or you don't like it,
and if you don't like it,
you don't have the right to interrupt
it.
You're supposed to leave.
Just leave that sort of polite person
does.
I've seen some stuff that I didn't like
and I left.
I've gotten to see a movie and I didn't
like it and I left.
That's,
there's nothing wrong with that.
But to interrupt it for everybody else
that's watching the movie,
that's a,
that's a piece of shit move.
So this,
you rewarding someone who did a piece of
shit move.
It's like it's not a good person.
You know,
a good person doesn't heckle me.
It's not that people who were hecklers
are bad people but they're drunk and
fucked up and that makes them a pain.
The ass,
you know.
But a lot of drunk fucked up people were
actually good people.
Right?
But when you reward that kind of
behavior like this,
like you could say that you think that
the comedians not funny,
you could say don't ever go see him.
Could cast judge
me.
You can do whatever the fuck you want.
But to say he owes her $15,000,
then it's like,
okay,
who is the retard in charge?
Who the who the fuck said yes to this
judge?
Is this a group of people?
Can I sit down with you,
fucks and talk to you and try to figure
out what the fuck is going on in your
mind,
right?
You can charge him.
Ha.
What's the punitive rule for,
for the labeling that you know you have
to put the cancer and that's proposition
65.
You have to label all marijuana products
with this,
with this warning label that says this
product is known to contain chemicals
that may cause cancer.
So every,
even though cannabis is knowing that
treat cancer is known to not proven to,
but known to cause we can't do the right
research search.
Every piece of cannabis has to have
this,
this label on it or else you can be
fined for not having the label.
Again,
punitive society.
And we got sued.
We got sued for not having the labeling
on our packaging even though we did so.
So they decided to put a lawsuit against
400,
800,
800.
It just went through weedmaps and just
see what everybody.
Everybody.
No,
they just did it just to try to scrap
some money out of you.
They said we'll make this go away.
Pace the settlement will make it go
away.
Wow.
And this is what this person has done to
hundreds and hundreds of businesses.
That's how they make their living.
And she sued us in 2014 control.
Right?
That's crazy.
And products have it on it.
So we,
we were sued without even one burden of
proof because when we were like,
look,
everything has it on.
So did they just say the lawsuits
invalid or know enough to go through
with it?
Now we still got to go through it
because you can go through with it
wherever you were filing right now and
after it's filed then I got to file a
complaint with the bar and do all this
bullshit because anybody can sue anybody
now.
And it's really,
really hurts businesses that hurts good
people.
So how much did they want to settle?
About $20,000.
Oh my god.
So fucking criminals stealing money from
people from dispensary because they
think they have it.
But where they made their money is a on.
I mean every place has to have it.
If you walk into target,
you walk into walmart,
they all have to have have this thing
because anything that has plastics in it
or anything.
Oh,
I see that sign everywhere now.
Once you get sued,
you're everywhere.
You see.
And that that's the law you got to have
posted.
So it was like you'd never hear the word
lesbian in vancouver again.
That's that.
Those,
the glory days are done.
Is that what he yelled a lesbian?
I don't know what he said.
I don't remember what he said,
but I've heard worse so.
So it's too litigious of our society.
So companies,
bigger companies don't just settle
because it's easier to just settle.
But you know,
a smaller companies I guess they think
because marijuana,
you just have so much money.
However,
our tax burden is almost 70 percent.
There's no real money In it when you're
doing things by the book and they just
passed another 15 percent sales tax on
top of marijuana.
You all in California just got passed
this week through the senate and the
assembly.
The governor signs that another 15
percent tax is coming our way and that
gets passed to the consumer.
Yeah.
I'm on top of the sales tax on top of
the city tax on top of the excise tax
and some of the cities and counties in
California having another,
another 10 or 15 percent on top of it.
You're also texting the growers in our
office so they're taxing anything that
has anything to do with what you get as
a final product.
If that's the case,
why would they be trying to stifle
business?
Wouldn't they want to promote business
because business is going to give them
more tax revenue.
This is the California.
It is.
It's because,
and a lot of it is because of law
enforcement unions and and not just
them,
but prison guard unions and all these.
There's a lot of unions that put
pressure on different politicians to try
to keep the laws in place or to make
them even stricter because they want
more people to get arrested,
privatized prisons,
subsidized presence.
So that is such a dark concept that this
is something that we're really dealing
with it.
We really are.
And the problem is the penalties for the
users,
like having a joint is so very small,
but the penalties for the business for
doing it the wrong way are huge.
Like our business is being crushed right
now over a stupid zoning suit.
Um,
so there's this big gap betWeen the
business penalty and the consumer
penalty so that the business has no
incentive really to do it the right way.
So because the consumer what you're
going to go into a shop and ask them,
hey,
do you pay your people on the books?
You know,
can I see your compliancy packet?
No,
you just go $40 a month.
I love that oj.
I'm buying it,
you know?
So with all these taxes that $40 eight,
it's got to go to $100.
Are we going to pay that or we just
going to go and call our dealer or
whoever that we've been using for 20
years.
So it's gonna.
It's just gonna make the black market
even a broader.
Well that's an issue that they've had in
Colorado for sure,
but people are happy to pay the taxes
because they liked the fact that it's
free.
Like the thing is free.
They're like,
you can go and you can buy pot.
You don't have to have any kind of a
license,
you don't have to any and you can just
go do it and it's working.
So 39 percent is what they have to pay.
Like recreational and medical is much
less,
but people just pay it,
you know,
we're not happy about it,
but regulation is what we want.
We just want to follow.
We just want the path to the way to do
this the correct way.
Just make it fair.
Let's see what's going on in denver
should be the shining light for the rest
of the states because what they've done
is they've,
they've,
they've made money like they have so
much fucking money from tax revenue.
They made more money from tax revenue
than they did from alcohol taxes.
So last year Colorado takes in
$40,000,000 in tax revenue for cannabis.
California takes in $40 million dollars
in tax revenue from cannabis.
We have 30 million people in this state
compared to colorado's,
what?
Five,
6 million.
We're not collecting the taxes here,
so if the companies are not following
the rules as they stand,
why we've thrown all these new rules at
them and setting up these monopolies
like here in la with the monopoly
stifling good businesses,
this doesn't help us and it doesn't
help.
The consumer either doesn't make any
sense.
It doesn't.
It's knowledge.
It would be dangerous.
It's not like if you get more pot out
there,
it's going to flood the streets and the
people are going to jump from the
building.
It's actually less dangerous or that
we've.
We've proven that and again,
that's why we're invited over and over
to places like the board of equalization
and to other places like oakland.
The city of oakland wants to follow our
delivery model.
It's because the way we do things
actually creates less,
um,
less crime,
less opportunity for crime because it's
just,
we're in,
you're in your living room,
you know,
we know who you are,
you,
you sent in your documents.
We know you live at that address.
We know you are.
I went to a doctor,
we know everything matches,
so no one sees me walk in or out of a
place with a commodity that that's more
expensive than diamonds.
You know when,
when you're looking at a,
at a dispensary,
if,
if people are walking in and out of
there with duffle bags,
what do you think's in those duffle
bags?
it's very easy to,
to,
for,
for crime that happened because it's
visible.
Done over 200,000 deliveries,
zero salts,
zero robberies,
zero complaints.
Knock on wood,
bitch.
That's great.
I will just let that go.
Know that
that's an importance to that,
but it is because we are very thoughtful
about how we go about,
um,
when you take a look at business,
making sure the person is who they are.
We do a google search on every single
patient.
We turn down as many patients as we
would take maybe even more just to make
sure they are who they say and,
and uh,
that uh,
uh,
background of easy background check
doesn't pull up anything that says we
shouldn't work with someone like that.
Yeah.
Pedophiles apparently love weed too,
but we don't love pedophile so we don't
let them also like milk know what the
fuck are we doing?
So connecting marijuana with crime.
So stupid,
you know,
there's no facts to back it up anymore
just because just because some people
who use it are criminals,
but that doesn't mean it's causing
anything.
So there's no rationale for any of this.
And you're fighting against the idea of
tax revenue.
Like you're,
you're holding back revenue because
there a lot of people.
If it was,
there's a lot of people that are on the
fence.
Like man,
I think about opening up a pot store,
but fuck,
you know,
would have jeb bush winds,
there's a lot of people that think like
that.
Those people are not going to go in,
but if it becomes completely free and
legal the way up,
you know,
blue jeans store would be blue jeans.
One of my,
my grandma
that I was trying for a reference
anything which is that if that happens,
store's going to open up everywhere and
the money's going to be crazy.
It's going to be a new economy.
Well,
it's still very possible with all the
people here.
yeah.
They'll still have to follow
regulations,
you know?
Um,
it's already billions on the books.
Well,
they should follow regulations because I
don't think that should be available to
everybody.
I think when you're young,
especially like this kind of fucking pop
they have here in la,
you imagine if you were a six year old
kid in detroit and you got a hold of
this shit.
No,
no,
it'S not.
Six year olds are not ready for this.
No,
it was definitely.
You should definitely come of age.
Yeah,
I don't know what that age is.
I think we would have to decide as a
society how old someone should be before
they start drinking,
how it mean there's a lot of countries
that let kids drink like responsibly
with their parents when they're much
younger than 21 and they have less
incidents per capita of alcoholism than
some of the countries that are more
restrictive about it.
So I don't know who's right or who's
wrong.
I don't know.
I know americans,
You know,
it's things that work other places,
like we said before,
don't work here.
You know what?
I remember going to Italy as a 16 year
old school and the first thing we did
was run to like a bodega and buy beer
because you could.
Because we were amerIcan kids and were
dicks and you can have beer,
so we didn't grow up responsibly so we
weren't acting responsibly.
We'd have to shift the whole way.
Our culture is to make those things
work.
Right,
and I don't know how to do that,
but I know that weed is the easy problem
to solve.
Alcohol is a demon.
That needs to be rooted out of our
society.
See,
I disagree with you.
I enjoy alcohol.
No,
I do too.
but I mean like can put the block then.
I mean just to see,
like when we started having the
conversation,
when people say,
let's compare it to alcohol,
I start licking my chops because when
you compare it to alcohol,
alcohol is.
Alcohol is poisonoUs.
Idig drinking.
I drank a lot,
a lot all the time.
Um,
so I'm not saying you did say that
though.
You just misspoke.
Misspelt don't.
I don't mean pull it away.
No,
no,
I understand.
But let's not demonize marijuana
compared to alcohol.
No.
Alcohol definitely ruins more people.
It's definitely way worse for your body.
it's definitely much more dangerous as
far as like operating cars and,
and behavior of the week.
The foolish things that people do in
their drinking.
Yeah.
All that stuff.
There's a lot of stuff that's directly
attributable to alcohol,
but.
So what,
so what,
you know,
look,
we've survived for so long with alcohol,
it's the regulations have worked to at
least to a manageable.
The fact that here's what You can't do,
you can't stop people from doing what
they want to do and not.
ExacTly.
And why is it that you could stop
someone from doing that,
but you can't stop them from practicing
doing flips and bmx bikes.
Right?
What would you.
Can you know?
Is it because they're there?
They're driving and injuring other
people will then take away their right
to drive.
Like that's how we have it set up
though.
They're injuring people getting in
fightS.
What do you lock them in jail yet?
But the rest of the people
leave us alone.
yeah,
we should have the right to choose too
many fucking rights.
We can control our own consciousness.
You can control what we put in our
bodies and here's most important
concept.
We're all just people.
They're all just people to like.
you can call them the government.
You can call them the police.
You can come the dea.
There are a bunch of fucking people.
That's all they are.
When you go behind some big crazy name,
like it's say fbi open up.
People go,
oh shit.
It's the fbi.
If you go,
it's mike and steve and bob and we want
to see what kind of plants are growing.
Right?
Open up,
but who the fuck are you guys?
You guys are just some fucking people.
So when you write something down on
paper,
this is how archaic our our world is.
you write something down on paper that
decreased power to these regular people,
so these regular people the sudden have
the right to fucking shit.
Storm your house,
kIck open your door,
shoot your dog because you have a bag of
pot hidden in your fucking bureau
drawer.
This is the world we create is this is
the.
This is a real world and more people get
killed during those rates.
Then pat would ever kill.
That's for sure.
It doesn't kill anybody.
That's the most ridiculous thing that
they did.
Notice.
Still zero,
zero ever man.
TheY would be parading in front of us
every now and then like the mirror in
the uk or one of those fake newspapers
will put.
A young man dies on marijuana.
First known case,
but it's not true.
It's not true.
He can't.
It doesn't kill you.
It's not toxic.
It might fuck your head up,
fuck your head up,
but you should be allowed to make that
choice.
I'm going to fuck my head up.
Yeah,
and if you're abusing it than the people
around you will help you or whatever.
You know,
whatever needs to be done to just like
monster energy drinks.
I know people who drink those things all
day long and look,
I love the way those fucking things
taste and if you want to stay awake and
you're like,
fuck it,
we're going in.
THat is the way to go,
but you're not supposed to drink like 10
of them in a day.
That dude needs an intervention.
Some people are crazy.
They'll drink 10 of those giant red
bulls.
The big red bull,
you know when they started making red
bull like a beer can now will a bud tall
boy.
People that drink those all day.
It's mostly people that have alcohol
problems that I would want to go to.
Hey,
they could switch to caffeine.
So I was like 20 coffees a day for some
of these guys.
I went to the hospital because of those
energy drinks from heartbeat,
palpitations and stuff like,
oh yeah man,
well,
you know,
they're great if you want one,
and monsters probably actually like less
caffeine and some of them bad monster.
And the monster is one of the better
ones.
The better tasting one's the worst one
that I ever tried as far as like the
jolt that it gives you is that red line
shit you remember.
That was it.
Uh,
when I went to the hospital was the
mountain.
They don't even make that any became
illegal.
Red line is what's red hair?
It was scary.
It was like can and in that kim was like
50 doses and you went down the whole
thing,
but it was um,
see if he could find it.
How safer those five hour energy drinks.
I chose a pretty safe.
It's pretty safe.
Those are mostly vitamin 12,
right?
They only have a,
I want to say like 70 milligrams of
caffeine,
a cup of coffee,
a cup of coffee.
So they're safe.
I don't feel the same drink in that as I
do at red bull.
No,
I like it.
It's better.
I like those be 12 drinks.
I think b,
12 drinks are way better caffeine.
Two hundred 50 milligrams of caffeine.
That doesn't seem like that much.
It doesn't.
Just what?
That's not an eight ounce bottle either.
ThAt is,
it says it says per a fluid ounce
bottle.
Coffee.
Like if coffee is 50 milligrams and the
thInking of the wrong shit.
I swear I thought it was red line.
Maybe I'm just wrong about the,
the uh,
the sheer volume of caffeine and that
thing,
but I thought it was just like
ridiculous.
But anyway,
I,
I drank it.
Whatever it was,
it was this one or the other one that's
like,
it that I mistake the name for it,
but it says starbucks and I remember
thinking,
dude,
I am just way too jacked up right now.
Starbucks,
heavy caffeine.
Yeah.
I especially their cold brew,
I get the,
sometimes they get the trenta hold the
fuck up.
A 20 ounce,
that's a trenta none.
that's a venti.
I get the one above that.
They don't even have the numbers for
that.
But just saying a 20,
a 20 ounce has 415 milligrams of
caffeine in tacky cardia.
Holy shIt.
Is that real iced coffees more?
I believe.
Yo.
Look at this.
Decaf has 30 milligrams.
Yeah.
The fuck is that decaf alWays has a
level.
No,
but 30 milligram.
I thought it was like five or something.
I thought it was like trace amounts to
see what the ice coffee is.
I believe it's a lot more really.
I get the trent usually.
How is that possibLe?
A cold brew
cold brew.
Three 30 where I guess it's not more,
but I get the trend diversion,
so that's probably more.
Yeah.
They can't keep serving you like that.
They're going to have to have to pull
back.
See,
that's the thing is,
is I agree,
but then my libertarian side doesn't
agree.
Why do you think you should drink that
shit all day if you want.
Of course,
my friend dave foley used to drink pots
of coffee pot.
like all day he'd drink pots of coffee.
He had to stop putting cream in because
he realized he was drinking a quart of
ice cream a day.
I think of that every time I put cream
in my coffee,
I think of your stories telling me about
that court cream just from coffee.
yeah.
I like that.
Fresh heady cream.
I constantly.
That's what I'm talking about a year,
like a dark roast hawaiian coffee with
some heavy cream
motherfucker.
You gonna make me feel good.
That's what cool that starbucks is now
doing that they're doing with their cold
brew coffee.
they have like a heavy cream that's like
karma or something.
They mixed through it.
Nice.
Yeah.
It's the cigarettes and coffee thing or
the staples of the alcoholics,
right?
Yeah.
A lot of people enjoy those cigarettes
and they enjoy those,
uh,
those coffees.
But you know,
guys.
Yeah.
But,
but in their eyes they feel like they've
got the alcohol part under wraps now
because this stuff just kind of keeps
them going and this stuff is not ruining
their life.
Right.
I get it.
A lot of alcohol.
She used cannabis the same way.
Um,
and uh,
that's not really accepted by aa.
so I know a lot,
a lot of people who have,
um,
kicked their alcoholism by moving more
towards cannabis,
but again,
uh,
within the gay community that they don't
like that,
that's still considered a drug.
So,
but you can get a degree
good to anything,
you know,
whether it's porn or big macs or where
we can get it a psychologically addicted
to anything.
But jamie didn't.
The guy who created alcoholics
anonymous,
didn't you have positive experiences
with lsd?
That'd be funny.
That would be like,
I feel like you did assets.
The only thing you're allowed to take
guys.
Well I feel like I feel like that was
something that happened like maybe even
a after.
Well I don't want to speak out of
school.
Yeah,
my right.
Yeah.
Hold on.
So what the fuck?
Well that's why the government needs
testing on,
on a lot of things.
So we know.
Scroll that up please.
Alcoholics anonymous for a founder
believed lsd could cure alcoholism.
Wow.
Well you've seen so much research now in
psychedelics that clinics are opening
up.
There's a clinic in,
in la for,
for cattlemen,
you know,
and you're seeing mda clinics opening up
this,
what most of them do not realize that
the program's co founder,
bill wilson,
credited the psychedelic drugs,
lsd for alleviating his alcoholism and
believe the drug could be used to treat
others as well.
Holy shit.
So those friends of bill,
they didn't get all the information.
It's just kind of like friends of bill,
if you're in the alcoholics anonymous,
right?
That's what they call themselves,
like friends of bill.
It's like the cold war,
but they didn't get that experience.
It's kind of like the mushrooms that
quitting cigarettes do,
but do you think they tell them,
I never heard this before today.
How could you not tell these people?
Wilson first became big,
began experimenting with lsd in los
angeles at the veterans administration
back in 1956.
But after taking his first hit of acid,
he realized that it was not the aspect
of terror that could help remedy
alcoholism,
but rather the insight one could obtain
from stepping into a world of simulated
insanity.
Willow wilSon believed that using the
lsd could help.
The alcoholic discover a power greater
than ourselves that in turn could
restore us to sanity.
However,
he was adamant that using acid to combat
the demons of alcoholism was not
something that he could,
that one could expect from a single
dose.
Like more research is required and
snacks.
Wow.
Hmm.
That's interesting man.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
Psychedelics,
I think as we experiment with them
medically are gonna reveal some secrets.
Skies skys a heavy duty tripper.
They're going further down.
He was tripping with aldous huxley.
Like this guy.
This isn't like one experience you had
interesting.
There's documentation that indicates
wilson was involved with many supervise
lsd trials,
including someone's psychology
psychologist,
betty eisner and brave new world author,
aldous huxley,
which led him to believe that the
visions and insights given by lsd could
create a large incentive,
at least in a considerable number of
people,
was with like a leader and in fact they
live left this out of the a pamphlet.
How do they.
How could they leave this out?
It's crazy because it seems like this
had to play a major part in this guy's
ability to kick alcohol.
Well,
it seems like at every major religion
also left out the psychedelics that
probably created them as well.
So I,
I think,
uh,
you know,
you have,
I think a lot of times you got to leave
out the stuff that you think people
aren't going to follow you for.
Wait a minute,
you've seen alcoholics anonymous,
has a religion.
So what you just said,
call you son of a bitch.
I can't even believe you,
gina.
I thought we were friends.
That is um,
that is really wild,
man.
That's really interesting stuff.
But it totally,
it totally makes sense that it could
help you a kick in addiction.
That totally makes sense because the
stark contrast between being intoxicated
on it and what it feels like to be
normal and this rethinking like a reset
button.
That's what all the psychedelics
provide.
That's really beneficial.
Besides being fun.
They all provide that reset that takes
you so far out of who you are right now
that when you come back,
you go,
man,
am I doing this the right way?
Right?
You know,
now that I'm back to sober reality,
do I need to refocus this connection
from your own ego?
Yeah,
probably good idea.
You know,
and yeah,
you have the organization maps.
I had the guy from maps on the podcast
who's that does the psychedelic
research.
Um,
uh,
I forgot what doblin?
Uh,
yes.
so,
so just recently he,
they,
they got um,
uh,
authorized from the federal government
to start doing research on cannabis for
the first time that federal federal ban
was lifted.
And it was because because of maps,
uh,
that they,
they were able to get that they were the
first ones granted that,
that federal research on cannabis.
So,
um,
so it,
it's in,
in very similar ways.
We need to do research on lsd.
We need to do research on psilocybin
because there could be medical effects
that just like cannabis were just
denying because of years of,
um,
you know,
this is the way it was.
They're bad.
Jamie put that back up.
That quote about,
bill,
this is crazy.
look at this.
It says a.
unfortunately,
lsd made its way into the rooms of
alcoholics anonymous.
Simply because others in a hierarchy
hierarchy hierarchy did not support it
as a viable treatment.
In fact,
a document published in 1984 by
alcoholics anonymous world services in
New York explained that the reason the
program does not endorse the use of lsd
as word of bill's activity,
this is all in quotes.
As word of bill's activitiEs reached the
fellowship,
there were inevitable repercussions.
Most aes were violently opposed to his
experimenting with a mind altering
substance.
Lsd was then totally unfamiliar,
poorly researched,
and entirely experimental dot,
dot,
and bill was taking it and quote,
I wonder,
pills there was scared.
They were all scared that this guy was
tripping.
That's hilarious.
So they didn't want to include it even
though the founder of the program found
it massively beneficial and it's almost
ironic that that trying to put it in
there and they kicked him out basically.
Really.
Whereas this apparent resistance to step
down,
I was chastised for.
Wow,
that's hilarious.
Isn't that crazy?
Because timothy,
well,
terrence mckenna attributed this quote
that timothy leary,
but timothy leary said he never said it,
so nobody knows exactly who said it,
but that lsd causes violent reactions to
people who have never tried it.
What?
Good.
YeAh.
Very interesting.
The people that haven't tried it are the
ones that are not the people who were on
it.
Right.
Do you think lsd though for real,
can solve anything?
I.
I've done it maybe over 200 times and
you might not be the best example
when you were taking it 200 times.
A lot of that was recreational,
not,
but I'm sure there was small little
things that I was probably going through
that I could have used lsd to help me.
Like I like as an example,
I took lsd once after a big breakup.
Did it help me get through that breakup?
no.
it did nothing for my breakup,
you know?
Or were you trading on it to try to use
it that way?
Or that's the thing.
It's also going to go with your own
intention probably,
and it's not.
It doesn't work for you.
It's not like,
hey,
clean up my life.
I'm going to take some acid just right.
no,
you got to do the work yourself.
I just don't see it
presents what it will.
All these psychedelics,
like the good experiences,
the bad experiences represent what's the
state of mind when you go into them.
That's why the people that take it
really seriously and they go through
this all meditative ritual and they'll
do yoga,
do breathing exercises and they'll set
like a tone to whatever they would like
to go into this experience with and say
say that they're going into the
experience open and humble and say all
these things out loud and then they
enter into the psychedelic trip.
Like they do it that way because they,
they want to set an intention.
If you just broke up with a girl and you
take asset,
if you like,
really think about it.
The exciting thing,
because you didn't help me when I broke
up my girl.
Like that's really what you're saying.
But you could also be like,
hey,
I want to quit smoking.
Take acid.
Being like,
what happened?
Did you quit smoking?
And like,
and I know I focused on cigarettes and
then the whole place melted and in my
hand turned into a bunch snakes.
So no,
I still went to.
Again,
you don't really want to quit if you
wanted to quit,
you just quit.
Right.
But I don't think they asked the way.
Has anything to do with it?
Doesn't.
It doesn't help you.
It's not going to just decide for you.
Like it depends on what's the intention
that you go into taking any psychedelic,
whether it's mushrooms or whatever.
What's the intention that you go into
this,
this trip with and you can't think like
acid doesn't work because it didn't help
me quit smoking.
Like you didn't help you quit smoking.
Like these are decisions that you make?
Yeah,
I,
I just don't see how acid it.
Unless it's really bad acid that will.
You'll remember anything except melty
stuff in the walls.
Melting and lizards.
I just don't see any kind of help on our
lesser,
lesser level.
Do you feel like cannabis has changed
your personality because you know that
is something you might not go into st.
Alright,
I broke up with tonight,
I'm going to smoke weed for it.
But throughout your lifetime,
has cannabis had an effect on you that
you feel like it's changed your
personality?
I've been smoking since I was like 14,
15,
so I don't even know what my personality
was before,
if anything.
I think marijuana made me more paranoid
and scared,
you know,
I was more freaked out and stuff.
But as a medicine for headaches and I
don't take almost any pills now.
I don't have tylenol in my house
anymore.
If I,
if I have a headache I use weed.
So for that it has helped me
tremendously.
But personality wise probably not.
It probably made me more paranoid and
awful as a person when smoking it
because I'm,
you know,
I get panicky,
if I,
if I'm super stoned in a room of people,
it's not helping me at all.
It's making it worse.
If anything.
What about you joe?
And he started later,
later that you know,
you didn't start as a teenager.
So do you feel like it's made a
difference on who you are?
Yeah,
it changes your perspective.
It,
uh,
it offers you some,
a different frequency of insight I would
say.
I think that,
uh,
one of the things that's done that's
good is it,
it,
it makes me consider things that I might
not be thinking about and uh,
it,
it gives you almost a deliminates areas
of your consciousness that maybe you
weren't paying attention to.
It's mAde me a nicer guy.
Like I'm kind of a type a high strung
guy and like if there's an employee that
I just want to strangle,
I can take a hit of,
of the no ga and suddenly be like,
no.
And he's,
he's,
he's all right.
He's had a hard day.
Exactly.
Instead of accelerating that kind of
behavior and shitty behavior,
it definitely makes you more,
more inclined towards fellowship and
kindness.
It's just a,
it's a really good chemical,
you know,
it's a really good reaction that your
mind has to this natural plant for
creative reasons.
One hundred percent definitely opens up
a different pathway in your head.
I like it for everything.
I like it for a lot of different things.
I like it but it.
But for creative reasons,
it's one of the best things.
Yeah,
yeah,
sure.
You know,
a lot of are a celebrity patients that
are,
you know,
working in comedy or music or
a television or the movies they want
sativas specifically.
So,
um,
they're not down at all because you
sativas are more known for their
creativity and things like that.
So,
so we find people who are working in the
creative field,
theY want to smoke sativas,
you know,
um,
which is an important distinction
between indicas and sativas pizza.
A lot of people don't know that
different parts of different types of
marijuana can affect you differently,
you know,
and um,
there are some people who were
medicating for certain ailments while
they should smoke something that
specifically worked for those elements.
If,
um,
if you're smoking because you're looking
for creativity because you're looking
for,
um,
that uh,
you know,
uh,
you don't want to lay on the couch and
go to sleep,
then you should smoke,
smoke sativas.
Um,
if you are looking for that,
it's nighttime.
I want to relax.
Uh,
you know,
time to go to bed,
you should smoke into cars because
that's going to bring you down and give
you that body high with,
with,
uh,
the cbd chemical that's inside.
Got,
that's what I want.
I'm like,
brian,
I don't,
I get,
I get jumpy with steve.
I get a little bit Freaked out,
a little paranoid.
Pussies move in together.
Hey,
I think we're neighbors actually are.
Yeah,
I know.
Look,
we've all been to high.
No,
everybody's been too high,
you know.
Um,
one of the most famous scientists wasn't
carl sagan.
It was some other famous scientists.
Uh,
it was a theoretical mathematician,
guys,
the rights,
all that crazy scribble shit.
He would just,
he would just talk about how he likes
one hit.
That's what he likes to take.
Just one hit.
Just go for a walk on these ideas would
come to them.
It's like you don't have to get fucking
blasted,
just one hit.
That's why I was so against it at first
is because I thought one hit made you
really fucked up because that's how I
saw gino.
But it turned out,
gina would say you were such a dick to
me when I smoked weed in your house that
I have to go outside,
smoke a whole joint in two minutes and
come in and be a mess.
So that was what I was exposed to.
It was,
I don't want any of that.
I didn't realize you could just take one
hit and just chill out and still work
and still function.
Nobody knows.
And it makes people nicer.
The definitely does.
It did it for me,
you know,
uh,
I think,
um,
you know,
to say that,
uh,
what are the medical facts?
What,
what are you treating yourself for it?
It's almost silly to say because
everyone else who's not really treating
themselves for a cancer or something
like that,
they are getting mood regulation out of
it.
So even if you wanT to call it
recreational smoking,
you're still getting mood regulation out
of it.
And those people who smoke it almost
daily or whatever on whatever schedule
they smoke it on,
they might have,
if they didn't,
they might be on percocet,
they might be on,
you know,
welbutrin and they might be on a million
other other drugs.
So to say that recreational use is
people just getting high.
That's also also not accepting that
people are looking for mood regulation
as a medical effect.
So we already have it with coffee.
Yeah.
Coffee,
nicotine,
booze.
That's all business.
There's so many different things.
We already accept sugar.
Well sugar is the scariest one.
Yeah,
that shit's everywhere.
Once you start paying attention to it.
But the Idea is that you should be able
to do whatever you want.
If you want to eat candy bars all day,
that should be completely up to you.
And that's not where we are,
you know?
And the fact that that's not where we
were,
where we are with one of the most
beneficial plants the world's ever known
because that's really what it is.
Especially since it's connection to him.
It's the most beneficial plant the
world's ever known.
And it's illegal.
I mean,
that doesn't show you how stupid people
are.
I mean,
we're so god damn goofy.
We are and it's gonna.
It's goNna get worse before it gets
better,
unfortunately.
Think because the laws are such a mess
right now.
Listen,
hillary clinton's gonna fix everything.
She gets an offer.
She's going to be great.
She's always been a top shelf.
Well,
who Donald Trump?
is he going to fix it?
He doesn't.
He.
I don't think he cares.
He cares.
I know he doesn't care.
I know that.
Perfect.
Thank you.
With the legalized marijuana nationwide,
I get a lot of stoller.
Switch gears.
Know what scares me.
Is that what if he makes chris christie,
the attorney general?
That would be.
It would be hilarious.
It'd be so bad for my business,
dude.
Have you been?
It'd be hilarious.
That guy is not going to be the attorney
general it.
If he's not.
The attorney general will take anybody
with however you got so full.
He's so foolish.
Has his opinions on marijuana while
consuming copious amounts of sugar and
public.
they're so ridiculous.
Ridiculous.
He put a bag of m and m's inside is m
and m's after,
after he had stomach surgery.
I mean it's a crazy person,
so this guy is addicted to sugar.
One hundred percent,
but that's clear.
So no way you stay that big unless
you're eating terrible.
That's just it.
But he'll go with one thing is legal.
One thing is not saying end of story.
Who's an insane person,
but that's what.
That's what we're fighting with the
city.
Just this is the law.
End of story.
You get the chance.
He can't even win the democratic side
anymore.
still voting for gary,
man.
Gary Johnson.
You got Gary Johnson is a better.
It's almost.
Well it's a more likely vote than bernie
at this point.
I just don't think like physically he
can win,
but could happen though is he and
hillary could team up and would be a
formidable twosomes so great.
I think it'd be hillary and then he
would be the vice president.
I can be crazy though.
That's so left.
If they said any nancy shit to each
other.
It's kind of.
That's where it gets.
Yeah,
you got it.
You got to curb your words when you're
running,
right.
You've got to make sure that you don't
get to negatives so that you could join
forces.
Would they put a socialist on the ticket
in the United States of America?
While it's democratic socialist,
it's not entirely like a socialist to
beat trump.
I think they might be tricky.
It's tricky.
It's tricky,
but he does have the support of the
youth.
You know,
he's,
he's got people fired up socially.
You know,
he sits down with people like killer
mike and as long term interviews.
you know,
he's interesting.
He's an interesting.
He's different.
He doesn't accept money from.
I look,
I like a lot of what he stands for.
I think half of it.
I liked him way better than I like her.
I'm not a big fan of the whole,
like long term politicians.
I'm not a big fan of those kind of
people.
There just seems like You just have too
many compromises along the way.
There's too much lIke weaving in and out
of the system in the morning and toys in
the system.
The more suspicious we should all be.
She's way more intertwined in the
system,
of course,
but here's an example.
I'm speed.
We'd shut down by proposition day,
which was written by a lawyer who
represents a bunch of dispensaries that
are predicted by proposition day.
Those are some dots you can connect
them.
So an attorney writes a law that
protects his clients and it gets passed.
How does that happen?
I don't know,
but I know the career politicians don't
make things better for us.
Yeah.
They only do if it's the will of the
people in the ceiling where they could
stay in office,
but usually it's not really just the
will of the people.
It's people aren't really paying
attention because the goal of these
corporations,
they get involved or donate your money
and the people don't even know what the
fuck is happening while it's happening.
That's right.
Well,
that's what we have.
Exactly.
Going on here.
You know,
there's a lot of those laws,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
we were dealing with a lot of them,
you know,
again,
to say that um,
you know,
business had to be in operation before
2007 in order to be considered a,
you know,
now to be a viable business.
Well,
if you were in operation in 2007,
you learn in that wild west category.
So,
so you were already skating that line.
Do you want the players that were bad
players involved or do you want good
companies that want to put in a
standing,
a standard operating procedures that are
looking for best practices?
Why wouldn't you want companies like
that?
You know,
we just laid off 40 people
well that are now in unemployment.
40 good people that really can't get
decent jobs anywhere that we're paid
well above minimum wage are now just
laid off and going on the government
dollar because it's because of this law
that nobody knows about and nobody read.
You know?
And,
and for us,
it came at a time where we,
we were
so excited about the future of working
with the board of equalization.
We were in,
in our largest expansion at the time,
um,
we were going from the largest market
which was la to expanding throughout all
of California,
which we're still doing that,
but we just now have to not include la,
which was our main base.
So in the law,
what the law pertains to is you
delivering things to people that live in
homes because that home has not been
cleared because as a place to do
business,
because it,
because of the zoning law,
only these 135 pre ico is allowed to
operate at all within the city.
Nobody else can join the club.
It's only that 1:35.
And any marijuana wanna vehicle is an
extension of the marijuana business.
So every car is zoned like a building.
So essentially they've limited the
number of stores that can operate the
number of dispensaries.
And you guys got pushed out because you
didn't have a grandfathered in.
Well that,
that's,
that's number one.
But number two is our base.
Where our business is,
is not in the city limits of la.
So by normal law for any other business,
you follow the laws of the municipality
in,
we just convey through the streets of la
and there's a law on the California
books that says you can't stop someone
if your business is not in one
municipality and you drive to another
municipality to deliver something.
You can't stop that.
So we're not even in la and we have to
have to deal with this.
We're outside the city of la because the
city of la encompasses hollywood and and
a lot of la,
but they're in places that people think
are la,
like beverly hills or west hollywood.
Those are in la.
Lawsuit
says we're operating a sophisticated
delivery company running seven,
about seven hubs out of the la,
out of the la area.
It's like,
well,
where are the addresses on the lawsuit?
There are none because we don't have any
locations inside the city.
We don't roll orders out of there,
but it's not in the paperwork.
Just so
goofy though.
This is what's the problem?
This is the scary problem with big
government.
This is the problem with government that
just has too many regulations,
too much red tape and too much bullshit
stuff like this
and there should be a balance of harm to
our company,
uh,
that,
um,
is trying to work within every
regulation of California working with
the state to create them,
you know.
Well,
let me ask you this,
when is it going to be legal?
Is it an on the books to be in november
to november,
november?
Yes.
Well,
we have to organize like this is an
important thing for the future of
mankind.
It is,
must be done there and unfortunately
there's even infighting within the
cannabis industry.
Yeah.
Well,
you know what the problem that I ran
into when we were talking about the,
uh,
the legalization vote,
the growers didn't want it to be legal
because they would make less money or of
course you guys are growing illegally.
And I was like,
wow.
And he's like,
hey man,
I'm just telling you the truth,
but where we're at
point now that if we don't do that,
they're going to get pushed out anyway
by bigger corporations that will come in
and be able to pay millions of dollars
for licensing and buildings and things
like that.
People are greedy and they're
shortsighted.
You can't be greedy.
You can't be shortsighted.
You can.
This is a,
this is a global issue.
And in these environments where these
people are saying,
we're going to,
we're going to make less money.
Bullshit expand.
It's going to be legal now.
Dummy.
Like,
yeah,
you're going to have competition.
so fucking they were making money.
Why do you care if other people are
making money while you're concentrating
on that?
Just just enjoy life.
You're gonna have a bunch of potheads
mIllionaires around.
Yeah,
right.
And you know,
along those lines,
as we were cultivating for our own
patient base,
we were filed.
We follow the California a.
The law is for California.
The cultivate.
Once a local licensing started becoming
possible for cultivation.
It wasn't before,
uh,
the governor sign this bill last year.
Now it's becoming possible we went out
and we are now participating with desert
hot springs for illegal cultivation,
so it's going to be a place where the
police could come in,
the government could come in and inspect
it.
So,
so we're moving forward with full
legalization on cultivation is as well
paying,
paying everything you got to pay for
making sure that you,
uh,
your,
when you build your building,
it's built to the right specs again,
the governments involved in every part
of it.
So again,
we're moving forward with the
regulations,
even though it's gonna cost us a lot of
money aren't,
you know,
the investment team that's behind it has
already put $2,000,000 in just to buy
the property,
you know,
so,
um,
it's gonna cost a lot of money and we're
not,
you're not going to make the money,
you know,
millions of dollars that you're hoping
for,
but at least you're doing it in a way
that can be regulated and you can open
up your doors and not hide.
Because we don't want to hide everything
we've ever done.
We haven't hidden.
We've said everything in the media.
Hey,
we're following regulations,
we're,
we're trying to do everything the right
way.
We're paying,
paying,
paying the taxes.
We have to pay where we're working.
Well,
that's why we got sued is because if you
sue speed weed that gets your name in
the paper,
you see the display,
you know the delivery that one of the
other 400 delivery services that you can
find operating right now today that are
illegal,
that's not going to get your name in the
paper in an election year.
Maybe It's a conspiracy theory,
but all of the facts in our case are
dated 2014.
We got served in 2016.
I don't know.
Is this a special year to politicians?
Maybe it's a special year.
Hold on for a second.
So there are certain delivery companies
that are allowed to operate inside lno.
Nobody's allowed,
no one that they are what they are,
but they do 400.
The do 400 illegal ones.
Well,
they're all podcasts,
golden snitches.
So we're going to start doing overnight
delivery with medical carriers to the
entire state.
So speed we'd will deliver it to
anywhere in California.
That's allowed not inside the city
limits of la,
but outside the city limits.
You're in fresno,
you were in sacramento or wherever you
are,
a patient meet you at the border of taco
stand at the border and you make a hand
off certain patients.
Maybe burbank in la.
Burbank is nike's not,
not in la.
Oh,
so I can still get delivery.
You could until the.
Until they tell the delivery services to
stop.
But burbank does not like the industry.
Just like glendale and pasadena do not
like the industry was that there's,
it's,
it's the propaganda machine and it's,
you know,
law enforcement shows up.
IT's the city hall and start screaming
about if you have a dispensary is going
to have crime.
Delivery's going to be a lot of cash or
product in the cars.
you're bringing crime.
And they frightened the city council and
the people that vote in saying,
all right,
so we don't want it here.
So leT let it happen in echo park where
the hippies live.
We're here in burbank with,
you know,
with this,
the studios,
we don't want it in the studios.
I would want it because so many of the
actors or private app,
we'd,
I need it to live.
They do,
they do.
They've delivered all like on movie
sets.
Yeah.
That of course they do.
Everybody knows roles that people play
probably have to be as you fucking do
it.
I Wonder if Daniel Day lewis smokes
weed.
Fuck yeah.
Does we can talk about,
uh,
privacy of certain patients
we try and say they're trying to say
anything.
I'm saying a lot of the actors you,
you would think are smoking weed while
they were acting.
They are interesting.
Of course they are.
Whereas here,
I know several who don't have to name
names,
but I know a lot of people get super
high as fuck right before the do a
scene.
Sure.
Kind of makes sense.
Uh,
you know,
uh,
I mean you've introduced me to some,
so certainly certainly,
you know,
um,
and uh,
they're just as many that you would
never suspect that that guy is a
everyday smoker and they are.
And um,
and that's because you know,
there's still stigma and when you're
living in a public life you need
privacy.
And that's one of the reasons you need
delivery because some of my,
my patient basis,
if they walk into a dispensary,
they're gonna lose endorsements and
sponsor money from [inaudible].
They're on family shows,
things like that.
Well,
how is that fair to them?
They need their Medication.
They need safe access to their
medication.
They can't.
You're saying it all granted they're
trying to get high to settle the fuck
down.
I know they need their medication.
They're dying.
We ask them.
We have to protect it to him quickly.
Our disney kids toys,
one of society's seep deep into his
brains.
Joe,
have you been to a denver yet?
Since?
Uh,
since then,
since illegal.
I was just there like four months ago,
five months ago,
something like that.
She's just walking down the street.
Just walk into anything.
Pop places everywhere.
They're all over the place.
Did.
So it's like amsterdam.
It's like some weird new american
amsterdam.
And there's so much money in
real estate.
Prices are skyrocketing.
Real estate prices are up 19 percent.
How's the prices like,
like it's just say like a joint in,
in denver or you have any idea?
It's,
it's,
it's more expensive thAn it is here,
and they do have different pricing for
medical as they do for recreation.
And we went over that with taxes is 39
percent taxes versus think like nine.
Um,
however,
uh,
you know,
I've been there plenty of times and,
and the weed here in southern
California,
it's still past that I've seen possible.
It seems like denver would have the best
climate ever getting it needs to fucking
relax on those big dick measuring
competition between slates and we were
in pittsburgh.
No,
we were in philly and we got high with
this do to the radio station.
Gave us a joint and we were like some
philly,
we'd,
I'll just smoke the fuck out.
His fellow isn't going to do shit.
And like 20 minutes later we were like,
dude,
we made a mistake.
PhIlly we'd is legit.
I think there's an answer to that
though,
is that the best weed in Colorado is
still black market.
Um,
so
maybe.
But
he's so fuckIng strong.
You guys are crazy talk.
This is,
you're talking for the deepest of the
deep and the deep end of the pool.
That's what you're talking all the pot,
whether it's Colorado or California,
we'll put you on fucking pluto.
All of it.
No,
no doubt.
And the difference between two hits of
Colorado pot,
two hits of California pot is if you can
measure that,
write a book at the end.
It's the joy you had.
Like what if you had like three joints?
Those were just the three shittiest
joints in color.
I don't buy it.
Colorado.
I was in Colorado.
I had some other weed.
I'll be there thursday.
Fucking ridiculous.
It's like it's super weed.
It's all the same shit.
All these strains have gotten
everywhere.
You know,
they're all over the country.
They have this shit in New York now.
Does the.
We do get hired because of the elevation
for weed?
Yeah.
You have no air.
So it's probably just shitty weed.
No,
no,
no.
The alcohol gets too drunk or too.
That's a big one.
But uh,
it's,
it's just,
it's just good.
We're great.
It's everywhere.
It's because of social media.
It's becoming to a point where you just
can't deny it.
I thought we were aLready there.
We're very close to it.
And as I'm politicians get older and
pushed out and younger politicians get
in,
the toothpaste is out of the tube,
it's not going backwards.
So,
uh,
you know,
for la to be behind the times of the
rest of the state and for California,
the most progressive state in the
country to be behind the times of states
like Colorado and Alaska who were
making,
making tax money.
It's the money,
the money and the politics is too.
It's too intertwined.
It's too,
it's part of the fabric of our society
and it's broken,
you know,
it is.
And hopefully iT's going to be
eventually pushed out.
But right now,
you know,
you have to deal with one of the most
ridiculous examples of it,
which is marijuana.
It's one of the most ridiculous examples
of all sorts of problems that I'm sure
all sorts of businesses run into all
across the country that we don't
consider because it doesn't play a part
in our lives.
But this one does.
And this one is really a nationwide
freedom issue.
I mean,
that's really what a lot of is about.
It's a freedom of consciousness issue.
And people don't look at it like that.
They will get it.
Like it's law enforcement,
it's this,
it's crime,
it's children,
it's this,
no,
it's not what it is.
It's a freedom of social consciousness.
It's a freedom of being able to express
yourself and the freedom of being able
to intoxicate yourself with a natural
plant and then what comes out of that.
And that's what everybody was worried
about more than anything in the 19
seventies,
what they were worried about.
And then a sixties and the seventies is
what was coming out of this.
They weren't worried about the
consequences of taking this drug.
They were worried about what's coming
out of this.
You're geTting all these people that
just won't tolerate all the usual
standard shit because they're constantly
resetting themselves and then
reconsidering their environment and
they're coming out with this whole new
movement of people like all the haight
ashbury shit and the sixties and you
know,
all the,
the music of the time.
So much of That had to do with pot and
so much of that has to do with lsd.
Sure.
And they were just terrified of that
shit.
They will work when we talk about the
war on drugs and people blame nancy
reagan that started with nixon,
you know,
in the late sixties,
early seventies.
And now the new stuff has come out.
I'm sure you've seen it where they're
saying the nixon administration
purposely targeted marijuana because
they were really going after the civil
rights leaders and the people that were
anti war movement.
Yes.
So they would go arrest them through pot
and that would be the get the back door
to just break up these organizations and
that this was a strategy they had
to the point that they asked a
universities to pull cannabis
information that was positive.
Um,
I,
I mean,
that's.
Yeah,
they do.
They funded studies trying to find
things wrong with pot and they all,
all they found was good shit.
The donald tash can study is one that I
love where he was that study was to find
the connection between lung cancer and
smoking cannabis.
And it turned out he could find no
connection.
It actually showed that there could be
a,
a protective effect of cannabis.
That's how I'm still alive.
Maybe a lot of people like you that
smoke cigarettes and smoke pot.
It might actually even started the same
time.
NO,
I haven't.
I have a patient with double lung
transplant.
He had a
fiber myalgia and myalgia.
Uh,
so that's double lung transplant.
we were doIng an interview with,
uh,
with,
with a magazine and I had him there and
he showed I take these 45 pills a day
for four,
you know,
what I have or I could eat these three
edibles and um,
he's like 45 pills a day.
It's crazy just trying to swallow them.
Um,
and.
But he said these cost me thousands of
dollars,
however I don't pay for them because
it's paid by insurance.
These I pay almost 45,
$50 a day in edibles and,
and I could just eat those instead.
However,
none of this is paid for it.
And I don't have the money to pay $50 a
day for my medication.
So he's one of the patients that we help
out with with a free product and um,
you know,
because he can't afford It
to live pharmaceutical side of the,
of this conversation is just,
that's a whole nother side of it is very
nice of you to give that to him by the
way.
But hearing that he's eaten $45 or the
edibles day makes me want to shit my
pants and scary.
What kind of a tornado of consciousness,
this guy flying around in all day,
how many milligrams we talking for 45
bucks worth of weed.
How many milligrams is this motherfucker
taking in?
You know,
you have no lungs.
You take whatever you need to do to get
through that day.
Oh yeah,
we know for sure.
But I'm thinking $45 where the chiba
chews would put you in another
dimension.
Come on time.
There's a shit hacky sack.
We're talking somewhere around 500
milligrams a day.
Um,
so,
so it's not tremendous.
I mean,
I've seen joey diaz he a thousand
dollars
right time saying,
but if he's getting cheaper,
choose like chiba chews,
which are like a really potent,
an easy way to get them.
40th five bucks is not 500 milligrams.
You can give one 500 milligram one for a
lot less than that,
right?
For 15 bucks.
So spend 45 bucks and he's buying the
good shit.
Jesus louisa's,
he might be on a five,
500 milligram chiba chew a day diet.
I want to meet this student's shake his
hand.
That's a piece of pioneer.
Pioneer live in that world.
That's a good man.
Good man to know.
Whatever.
Don't be a pussy.
All of a sudden you're worried about
sugar.
This fucking guys living in an alternate
dimension.
These are looking at us through a
fucking aquarium window.
Like he's.
He's not even here if he's eating that
much pot.
You're talking about that much,
that many milligrams and then it's
getting processed.
So you gotta think about it way stronger
than just smoking it,
right?
It is.
I mean,
I went,
I had a bad edible strip and I went five
years without even touching it,
even though we had him on the menu,
I was like,
dude,
I w I wouldn't even want to smell one of
those tootsie rolls or whatever the hell
it is.
I didn't want nothing to do with it
because I was in another place for like
two days.
Hi,
just going,
when is it going to end?
I mean,
we started this
an edibles company before,
before we were speed weed and we were
one of the first.
We were the first company to do gummy
bears and um,
when we were making them,
um,
you know,
my brother and my partner with,
with his wife,
jan also has figured out a way to
extract,
um,
extract thc from,
from weed.
This is six years ago before anyone was
doing it because we had a failed crop.
Um,
because when I moved to California,
we got our cards.
I said,
I'm just going to throw up a grow and
now I'm allowed to grow here.
I'm going to throw up a grow.
Ever heard that I need to start saying
shit like that.
Get to go with my friends.
So agent said,
that's great.
Where are we going to do it?
I said I'm going to do it in your living
room.
So I took over his living room with
tents and I put up grown and I think and
since I going back and forth to
New York selling my house,
I'm a every two weeks he was watching it
while I was gone.
Well it was
disaster.
It was the worst experience were growing
pot with all of our money.
And I'm on the phone with gina going,
you know,
the leaves are yellow.
He's like,
all right,
are the veins,
read them and what do I don't know what
we're talking about because It needs
more responsible motherfucker.
You can't just leave this dude with your
plans.
He's like,
go,
go get more nitrogen.
I'm like,
hi baby.
For me,
take my baby.
Just feed it when it cries.
So I,
I got,
I got
back from,
from a trip late leading into my,
my,
uh,
a growth cycle and I opened it up and
you see webs,
well those aren't spiders,
those are spider mites and that's the
worst thing you could ever,
ever get.
I grew in Ohio last,
my whole entire crop spit like months
growing,
this scared of helicopters with a heat
seeking thing and all our money was sunk
into this,
um,
you know,
all of a four months time to make it
happen.
And I was just defeated.
I was like,
I can't believe it.
What are we gonna do?
And so we,
we had the fight it to fight those
spider mites.
We did everything we could,
including buying 10,000 ladybugs which
eat these things and releasing them in
this tent.
A foot from where I'm sleeping on his
couch.
I bought them on amazon.
I bought like a zillion lady bugs on
amazon.
We just released them into my living
room.
Yeah,
we buy them all the time.
Yeah.
They didn't even do a bunch of different
plants that are girls.
So we bought ladybugs.
Yeah.
And they worked.
But they didn't exactly work fast enough
and they were dying because we're.
And uh,
so we had to get predator mites,
which were other little creepy crawly
things that we had to release right
where I was sleeping.
So we released it.
It was,
it,
it's exactly what it was.
It was like,
if you could look at it under a
microscope,
it would be alert,
some sort of a fucking storm troopers,
starship troopers,
you know,
a lord of the rings.
Things were flying down,
eating each other things with crime and
up.
And they were like,
so what happened?
What's the long story?
So,
so,
so we got rid of them and had had bad
weed.
We extracted it,
had re read some papers online.
We extract and I said,
what are we going to do with this?
And we said,
all right,
let's make some edibles.
So his wife,
so hold on,
it's bad.
Weed,
bad.
We'd consider it because you can't smoke
it.
Yeah.
But you can still turn into edibles.
It,
it looked like shit out of,
out of the litter box.
It was garbage bin geno's like fuck it,
I'm smoking it mode.
I'm confused.
Explain like why did it look bad?
Because the mites chewed it up.
Like what?
Yeah,
a lady bug with a lady bug wings.
Here's the thing.
Really.
So,
so there's also things called neem oil,
which is a natural pesticide that that
also helps in killing,
killing these things.
However,
in a growth cycle you shouldn't use it
near the end because then it's going to
be on the flowers that you have to
smoke.
However,
if you extract the thc out of it,
it's no longer on that plant material.
You're getting rid of the plant
material.
The neem oil that's on it won't
translate into an excel.
Oh,
okay.
So you use the pesticide unfortunately,
late in the cycle and it made the pot
bad to smoke,
but you can still extract the thc from.
Right,
right.
It's a natural oil.
I,
it,
it works as a pesticide.
But I was so baffled.
I was like,
how is it bad weed?
And then it's good weed.
So,
so bad.
We'd good gummy bears.
Yeah.
So.
Oh,
so I started going,
what is the process of extracting thc
from the flowers?
It's like breaking bad.
Is that it?
Yeah.
My kitchen looked like a meth lab for
like three months is crazy.
We had a sox.
Lydia,
you had to have you done this before
where you were experimenting?
Did you watch a youtube video?
I had no idea it even existed.
I found a paper from like 1976 or ucla
scientists that multi solvent extraction
academy.
Middle age.
You can find it online now.
Like this is a how to manual and how to
do extraction.
Okay.
Hold on.
Neither one of you guys are scientists.
We're technology guys.
I got scientists,
right?
I know I got married.
No,
I'm techie at homework.
Had you ever done any chemical work like
that?
Using solvents and extracting l elements
from plants?
Not professionally.
He age is humble.
He,
he's a,
he's a member of mensa.
Uh,
I got very blessed to have a brother
who's very intelligent,
um,
you know,
so I was just defeated,
I got a bad crop.
I wasted all oUr money.
I wasted our time.
He turned lemons into lemonade because
luckily he's smart enough to say what
else can we do with this?
And he went out and found a way for us
to.
Did you practice or do you just dive
right in?
Would you do this?
I hadn't.
It was like a six week r and d process.
So.
So we did the extraction through with,
uh,
all kinds of different chemicals,
right?
Ultimately ethanol worked really well
and then every night at 11 I would give
gino a dose,
like on a cookie or something at 11 and
then I would wait 45 minutes in a mocked
up in your basement to pretty much keep
it rubs the lotion on skin every night.
And then finally one day I give gina the
dose,
1145,
is that how you feel?
He goes,
I don't think it's working.
I was like,
boom,
that's it.
That's the recipe.
And it's in my journal.
And that was kind of how we got into the
industry was with that extraction
process,
that recipe,
that day.
Now I've always wondered like this,
when you use all those chemicals and you
extract something from a plant or those
chemicals in any way,
is there a residue on the extraction?
Depends.
We were using ethanol which is alcohol,
but then we were making candy which
burns off the alcohol,
so there's no alcohol in the candy,
but now you have the thc which is inside
the candy and now you can and now we
would.
We would do car box relating the flower
before anybody was doing that and what
that means is you activate the flower,
like you can't just take bud and eat it
and get stoned.
It won't work.
Why is that?
Because you need something fat soluble.
You need to convert it to thc acid.
So you do that with heat,
so you smoke it or you do that with fat
like lipids.
You boil it and butter.
Make brownies,
so fuck.
Did people figure that out?
It's brilliant.
It's genius.
Or you could do it with alcohol and
that's ultimately what we'll use is
alcohol extracts.
Butane works as well,
but what I mean is how the fuck did
people figure out that you had to burn
it in order to use it because they're
probably eating it long before they knew
I could get your high.
Well,
I mean it civilizations amazing.
Like how did they figure out if we eat
this route?
Iowasca works,
but otherwise or nut trees doesn't,
you know,
the trees told us
that was probably true.
They use tobacco in those iowasca
rituals apparently.
Right.
We're right before you go onto their
blow tobacco smoke on your face and was
just to get you ready to vomit.
Well,
I don't even know if it's that.
I think it's a stimulating effect of the
nicotine has some sort of a kickstart
like terence mckenna,
when he would take mushrooms,
what he would do is he would take them
and then you would wait.
They kick in like an hour or so.
So while he was waiting for them to kick
in,
he was just rolled joints as motherfuck
would roll joints for an hour and then
and then go and start going and when the
pot really kicked in,
like when he would get really,
really high,
that would be right when the mushrooms
had come in like a giant tidal wave and
he said he could see it coming,
he could see it coming,
you could feel it in the ground and it
seemed like there's no way no one else
is experiencing this.
It's just like this gigantic wave is
coming and there's nothing you can do to
stop it.
And that's how he would do it.
So he would use marijuana smoke,
just sort of instigate the,
uh,
the mushroom experience,
which totally makes sense.
But that's a warrior that it will do
that kind of experimentation dive dude,
when deep healing deep,
he went deep,
maybe two months.
She died of a brain cancer,
a brain tumor.
I mean,
who knows if that was hereditary,
who knows what that was,
you know,
it related in a way to expanding
consciousness.
We're attempting to expand in
consciousness through drugs,
most likely,
not especially,
but he was really critical of the idea
that marijuana was cure a cure for
cancer because he was like,
look,
I am telling you I have cancer and I
smoked pot all day constantly.
He's like,
I am yoUr poster boy,
because if it was something that cured
cancer,
I would not have cancer because you
cannot smoke more pot than me.
Like mckenna was just high all day.
But there's so many different cancers
and so many different types of weed.
Who knows what's what.
We got to research.
Well,
I think what's really supposed to be the
most effectIve and chino you help my
friend when he,
uh,
his mom had an Issue with this and this
is something about genome who'd never
advertised himself,
but he hooked my friend up with a lot of
this cannabis oil.
What's really expensive stuff and you
did it just to help his mom,
but just to help his dad rather.
Well,
he's a good dude.
And uh,
you know,
we were talking about stage four cancer
at that point.
So there wasn't much a ever hope that it
was going to turn around and cure it.
However,
to ease the last few months of life,
um,
was,
was working and happening there,
there was a lot more quality of life,
which for the patient that,
that was great,
number one,
absolute most important,
but also for our,
our friend that we're talking about,
it was great for him because he got the
last few months of life together with
his loved one in a better way,
not in a comatose a setting,
which he was dealing with for a while
before we got got,
uh,
you know,
on the,
uh,
rick simpson oil regimen.
Well,
it definitely needs to be investigAted
because there's so many people that have
had beneficial effects from it.
It just seems insane to not have some
large scale scientific research being
done right now.
Like just humanity as a whole.
Like we kind of owe it to each other.
Like if you,
you're not thinking about it right now
because your loved ones don't have
cancer.
But if this turns out to be really
legit,
this could be another reason why we need
to reconsider this whole ban on the
illegal sale federally of marijuana.
It's ridiculous if it can do this.
If you really taking this oil and you're
reduce reducing tumors,
which has been reported in just a
shitload of people,
including friends of mine.
I know people that have had cancer and
had their cancer reduced by taking
cannabis oil and I know people whose
parents had it and got their.
Their tumors reduced because of it and
autistic kids like the caesars and stuff
like that.
our friend and his kid was going from
like.
I mean he was having seizures all day.
takes this stuff.
He hasn't had a seizure in six months.
You look at jaden and and charlotte and
ali's,
these kids.
How caN you.
How can you tell the parents?
No,
exactly.
no matter what state you're in,
how can you tell a parent know?
And that's.
I think that's when your politics
changed and when it affects you
personally.
It definitely happens.
It definitely happens and I've seen
quite a few stories of that,
of people that have children that have,
you know,
serious seizure issues and as soon as
they got them on the medical marijuana
and just stopped and we have a lot of
really bad prejudices about marijuana
and we need to expose them like as a
society because they're holding a lot of
people back.
I know they held me back.
They made me until I was 30 years old.
I thought that was for idiots.
So it really did.
a lot of people do and it's,
it's important to let them know.
Not only is it not for idiots,
it's,
it's a tool that you can use it,
you can,
it can benefit you.
Like this is not a benign substance.
It's slippery,
you know,
like all other psychoactive substances,
if you are on the wrong path mentally,
like you could go off the deep end with
it,
like everything else,
like alcohol or anything else.
But
someone who I respect a lot like graham
hancock,
who have you had on the show a lot.
He was a high heavy user and he got to a
point,
um,
where he said,
you know what,
my relationship is not good with
marijuana anymore.
And he took a long break,
I think two to three years.
He took a long break and then said,
you know what,
things have changed in my life now.
I think I could go back and have that
relationShip start again.
And from what I,
what I understand mostly from the
podcast,
uh,
from,
from him being on the podcast last time,
um,
he is now in a better relationship with
marijuana
that he was in an abusive relationship
with himself.
And marijuana was just playing a factor
in that.
Sure.
I'm the one who got them high.
Yeah.
I got,
I'm behind on the show when he was a.
Who was it took two or three years
sober.
I'm like,
too,
you're fine.
Just come on.
You're the smartest dude ever.
He loved it.
And he and he opened up when I,
when I gave it to him,
oh my god.
They opened up like a flower who took
one hit and then he relaxed and he was
smiling and laughing.
We're having a good time and he went on
this rant.
Oh my god.
It was epic rant,
epic rant,
and I remember thinking like,
wow,
that had to be cannabis inspired because
it was so like emotionally connected to
him.
There was essentially like sort of
validating his life work because he was
really heavily criticized many,
many times where people just completely
ignored any of the potentially positive
aspects of what he was saying and just
was trying to shit on all they're trying
to shit on all of these theories,
but as time has gone on,
it's been more and more apparent that he
was right the whole time.
That's all different thingS that just
studies.
Yeah.
Well the big one being that
civilizations have experienced many
diFferent areas and that will.
We're looking at when we looked back,
thousands and thousands of years is the
most latest of arrows,
but there was potentially very advanced
civilizations that had a different kind
of advancement.
Ten thousand,
15,000 years,
maybe as many as 30,000 years ago,
and that there's evidence of this stuff.
There's evidence in the construction of
the old kingdom in Egypt.
There's evidence when they start looking
at certain erosion patterns on the
sphinx and the sphinx compound like
you're talking about,
like something that was built 14,000
years ago plus.
So all these different new discoveries
that they're having when they're having
these new there find these new things
that are like four.
They found evidence of north americans
in a native americans in north America
at 14,000 years ago,
which pushes it way back before they
thought it was.
They found like woolly mammoth bones
with cuts on them and shit super
recently.
So this stuff keeps happening over and
over again and they keep discovering
these structures and you know,
they find things underwater.
They find sunken cities and shit go back
later and yeah,
exactly.
Can carbon date stone.
So that's why I go back to the so unique
because they know that it was covered up
somewhere around 12,000 years ago.
Purposely.
Someone constructed this thing sometime
before that they,
you know,
they get a vague idea within a thousand
years of when this thing was built and
it was built when they thought people
were hunter gatherers,
so this is all stuff that hancock had
already been saying,
so to see him get high and just expand
upon that and see like this is a guy
that like he's been ridiculed,
he's been dragged through the mud people
have taken what you've said out of
context and tried to use it against him.
They've had these really biased opinions
about his Work and they've made little
specials about it to shitting on him and
it turns out he was right about a lot of
things and it's just gathering evidence
and then making,
making his his thoughts and processes
on,
on evidence and he's a really good guy.
Like he doesn't deserve any of that.
He's not a,
he's not a bad guy.
Like he's a really good guy that's taken
a chance that's exploring this really
important subject.
This idea that we've been here many
times.
I can remember reading magicians,
magicians of the gods or fingerprints
that his first,
first one thinking things,
footprints of the gods,
right?
Wasn't fingerprints,
no fingerprints or your parents.
I'm thinking,
thank god there's a dude out there.
I didn't know who he was at the time.
Thank god there's someone doing this
work because I had never heard of any of
this before.
I read that book.
Well,
there's been a bunch of similar like
theorists in the past,
but they always connected it to like
aliens,
like specifically like zachariah
hitchins such and such and stuff.
Yeah.
Well he.
He was gonna bring up that guy from the
chariots of the gods.
What the fuck Is that guy's name?
There was a dude,
von danIken von daniken who wrote
chariots of the gods and a chair to the
gods was like a movie.
They made a documentary movie about it
that played in the movie theaters.
I remember when I was a kid,
it was playing in the movie theaters and
I was freaking out and people would
leave there though to go,
oh my god,
there's aliens.
They visited us like that movie.
If you watch that movie and you smoke
pot and you're young,
it will have a fucking convinced you
will be fucking convinced.
One hundred percent.
I feel like I was convinced and it's a
lot of graham hancock who unconvinced me
by,
um,
because a lot of people think he's part
of the ancient alien theorists,
but he's not really.
He just feels that,
that we have lost technology.
Well,
he leaves the door open.
We've had conversations about it.
He leaves the door open for visitation.
He leaves the door open for that being a
possibility as do why I think everybody
should have a unique moment where an
alien spacecraft came down and ran into
14th century europeans and fucked with
them and you know,
and kidnapped a few and did some science
certificate experiments on some and
erase their memories.
you see that of course that could
happen.
I mean,
if we can go tomorrow so we could send a
robot to zoom around on mars and we
watch it on her iphone,
we can do that right now.
We're idiots.
We can't even make pot legal.
You've got a robot moving around on
mars.
The idea that there's something out
there that's there's no way.
No one is smarter than us.
Dude can't happen.
Like of course there's could be.
If we stay alive for a thousand years,
our technology is going to be
unrecognizable.
It's going to be so beyond anything we
could possibly imagine today.
Just looking how far it's come since we
were kids growing up an eighties.
These things that we see these,
these things that everybody sees iconic
gray creatures with the big black eyes.
Those could be drones percent.
I mean those could be artificially
intelligent creatures that some super
advanced civilization has created to
gather up information on people that's
totally possible and that would,
that would make it so much easier for
them to defy the laws of physics to
five.
The laws,
the laws of physics,
the laws of,
of space travel,
like with human beings being unable to
withstand the kind of pressure that it
would require to go light speed and shit
like that.
These things are some fucking weird
robot creation that doesn't even exist.
You know,
lives off of a lithium ion battery.
It's gotten it's dick,
you know that,
that,
that thing might be able to go forever,
like it might.
Radiation might not bother it.
You might be able to shoot it into a
fucking black hole and it comes out the
other side.
I mean,
who knows what the fuck they can do a
million years from now.
Right.
Because in the avatar is just a robot.
When you all know robots at this point
can be controlled from a remote control.
Yeah.
We,
it just depends how far away is that
remote control,
you know,
where is that written in your control?
So the chariots of the gods guy and even
the people that the ancient aliens guys
that who the fuck knows there might have
been a bunch of visitors.
It's very possible.
It's super possible if we can do it,
of course something out there that's
smarter than us can do it better than we
could for sure of course.
But with graham hancock is proposing is
much more likely because it's backed by
actual science and now that he's,
he's joined efforts with that randall
carlson guy and randall carson,
who's an expert on asteroidal impacts
and it's,
it's the,
the history of them in north America in
the world.
I mean he's a wizard when it comes to
that stuff and he can just quoted off
the top of his head all these different
impact sites that they found and you
realize like,
oh geez,
we can hit all the time and not only do
we get hit all the time,
there's evidence of a massive meteor
shower impacting asia and europe
somewhere around 10,000 plus years ago,
which coincides with the civilization
that they.
Exactly they're talking about.
So somewhere around that era,
the human race got fucking basically
half wiped out.
Yeah.
We had a rebuild and we don't remember.
We didn't have,
there's no electronics back then.
So there's no like computers that we
could look at.
There's no photos.
They didn't have photographs,
they were just basing on people's
memories and things that they could
draw.
I mean,
as far as we know,
they didn't have any cameras.
I mean,
who knows.
I mean all that stuff.
If you,
if you had a camera and you left it on
the ground for a thousand years,
there'd be nothing left and 100 they
would all go away.
It had batteries back then.
They had something like a bat.
They did.
Yeah.
And they found that in one of the
egyptian tombs,
and they found it in Iraq to yet the
little copper and the clay,
they had some kind of computer or
electronics that just doesn't exist
anymore.
Not only that,
the people who made that battery,
they're pretty sure that was 2,500 bc.
So that was way later than this impact.
They're talking about this 11,000,
whatever it was,
year impact.
They think that there's been a series of
these all throughout history and this is
something that's supported by even
mainstream science when they're talking
about super volcanoes.
There's this one super volcano.
We've looked this up three fucking
times.
I can ever remember this goddamned gino
la speed.
We'd bullshit.
Um,
but there's a super volcano that erupted
70,000 years ago and killed almost
everyone on the planet except for a
couple thousand people and we all
descend from those few thousand people
that survived some massive,
super volcano impact.
This is a really openly accepted theory
and mainstream archeology and
anthropology.
They really believed that this is one of
the possibly one of the big disaster
extinction events that happened to human
beings.
There's been several of them,
right?
I know what you're talking about.
That's something that caused like three
or four years of an equivalent of a
nuclear winter.
Well,
here,
look at it this way.
You remember mount st helen's when we
were kids.
Remember that?
Nobody talks about that.
Nobody even thinks about that anymore.
When we were kids,
a fucking volcano in Washington state
erupted and people died.
They got lava.
They got smoked by a volcano,
ash for a month in mash for months,
and it just conveniently goes away.
That was a little baby volcano.
I mean,
obviously no disrespect to anybody who
died,
right?
In comparison to what yellowstone has.
Yellowstone as a super volcano that's
600 miles wide,
something fucking crazy like that.
I mean that's still,
you know,
they don't Call it acted that volcano,
but it's still bubbling.
Well,
they have thousands of earthquakes every
year.
Thousands.
Like so you know,
shit's going on down there.
The guys yours are shooting up boiling
water and the sulfur content in the
water.
It's crazy.
Maybe it's 600 kilometers,
600 kilometers,
300 miles,
whatever it is.
It's so big that it's,
it's a continent killer right there.
Like when that thing blows everything
near it is dead as fuck it.
What it is is what they call a caldera,
which means that it's a volcano that was
so big.
The top blew off of it and then you're
left with this big crater and they
didn't realize that until they started
using sas satellite images.
Once they started using [inaudible],
we've known about old faithful,
you know,
that's it's a cool place to visit and go
check out the geysers and stuff that
sets the ground is boiling like 100 feet
below you is hot lava and every six,
800,000 years that shit blow sky high
and when it blow sky high,
everyone's dead.
We're all dead.
We're all dead and California is dead.
Montana's dead as fuck.
Everything around.
It's just dead.
It's depressing because it really is
just a matter of time before there's
some,
some impact or earthquake or a volcano.
It's just a matter of time and which
ones,
what's it going to be?
Well,
what graham hancock,
because exposing is that when you're
talking about enormous periods of time,
like 10,000 years,
12,000 years,
30,000 years,
people cannot recall those natural
disasters.
They lose the ability to communicate.
Sometimes they're not even using the
same languages anymore.
You're dealing with thousands and
thousands and thousands of years.
I mean,
just think about just a few thousand
years ago,
latin was like a real language,
you know,
joe,
go try finding someone that going to
talk latin for,
you know,
that shit doesn't it?
It's a dead language.
It's,
you know,
that's only a couple thousand years when
you're talking about 30,000 years and
the possibility of all these different
impacts and different things happening
within those 30,000 years.
Like who knows.
So what he's showing is where would he
was showing back then was that this
alternative theory is not preposterous
at all.
Like there's,
there's real good evidence that this is
not gonna stay like this,
right?
Like it's just not preposterous.
It's probable and likely that it's just
what's next.
Will old faithful was called old
faithful because it used to be faithful
and blow at the exact time.
It doesn't do that anymore.
It's no longer on the old faithful type
of a schedule that it,
that it used to be changing.
I don't like that on that air.
I don't like.
It makes me nervous.
I don't like that,
you kNow?
And that's just in our life.
When did that stop?
I only recently heard it heard that,
uh,
you know,
that that's new story.
That old faithful is not as faithful as
a,
as a pinch.
Yeah.
It's weird.
The geysers are hot water water's
boiling.
It shoots up into the sky and we're
like,
ooh,
ah,
well let's get outta here before giant
furry monster eats us.
Yellowstone's crAzy.
That's a crazy goddamn place.
Those people have grizzly bears,
grizzly bears are there all the time.
There's a police in,
I believe it's Ohio,
California,
where they have these big mud pits that
people go in that are real hot and,
you know,
but what,
what do you think is heating those on,
under there?
I mean,
that could also just quickly explode.
I,
I don't know.
I mean,
those,
those hot pits are totally natural and
Ohio.
Is that what it is?
They,
as far as I know they are.
I haven't been in my,
I have a healthy fear of them.
I guess for a,
of just,
just,
you know,
think things like that.
And um,
you know,
in nature that could.
Mother nature just wants to kill us
so many ways.
Just sorta right now we're fine.
I mean no,
no need to totally freak out about it,
but just the awareness that this whole
thing is probably pretty fucking
temporary and we're in the worst state
to live in.
That's so crazy to say.
I don't know why you say that.
Earthquake volcano were definitely
better off where we were in toronto or
something.
Probably you freeze to death in the
winter.
Hits black eyes.
I think this is a really good state,
but a lot of nice people.
More people die in a weather and natural
things in every other state besides
California.
Yeah,
I mean if there's an earthquake,
there's going to be a few issues for
sure.
Yeah.
Earthquakes,
fuck a lot of things up.
But overall man,
like you deal with an earthquake once
every couple of decades.
You deal with winter every fucking year.
If you go back to Ohio,
trying to keep him here
isn't the biggest fault line like
Missouri or that shit doesn't work
though.
That's broken.
So like an old train station that be
broken.
I don't know man.
I mean,
look,
we're worried about stuff that we know
about these,
these spots where the earth could
explode,
but when I fucking rocks in the sky,
that could kill everybody.
They,
they,
they hit all the time.
They hit every few thousand years.
So these spaces of civilization like
10,000,
12,000 years,
these where they find these structures
like go beckley,
tappi,
and they like,
who the fuck?
Where did this,
where's this kind of.
It's so likely that that's just a series
of events.
it's like people build up.
They figured out society to get things
going really well.
They stArted improving upon things and
boom,
everybody's dead rotting bodies in the
street.
Diseases,
wolves,
flee to the mountains,
rebuild civilization first.
Fucking tribes don't make it down to a
few people.
They slowly bond together.
They rebuild.
I bet that shit happens every 20,000
years or so.
One of the theories I heard on gold
beckley tapi is that since that's what
happened,
that there was some devastation at that
point that the theory is that they
blamed it on whatever gods and that's
why I go back to tempe was just covered
at that point.
We just hired this high debt
right away.
Yeah.
Well that makes sense.
If you were like a politician you're
trying to take over after the disaster.
People like these motherfuckers in their
statues ruined everything and we're
going to fill it in with dirt.
No,
it'd be like symbolic because you can't
like run a dope ass city with some
statues that the dude before you made.
Nope.
You got to knock those bitches over.
we still do the same thing today.
Well,
isis is doing it right now.
All throughout asia.
They keep blowing shit up.
You know we yanked down.
Saddam didn't win.
Yeah.
boy,
that shit right there.
Head fell off.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's right.
That statue.
I forgot about that.
But we all do it.
We all want to like hide what was before
us because what?
What we are as good.
What we do is right,
especially when it comes to someone like
saddam hussein.
Yeah,
like we,
we like celebrated it.
When that statue went down.
Yes,
she was dutch folk.
We dId them all that statues kind of
history,
like we really shouldn't have been
fucking with it because like if you
could see what julius caesar did,
like if you could go back and see what
nero did,
like all the atrocities that he did,
he wouldn't want to see a statue of him.
But imagine if someone came along and
smashed a statue of him,
you wouldn't be able to look at it
today.
Like there's something about when you go
to a museum and you look at something
from ancient rome and they go,
wow,
that crazy fucker.
What was life like?
What was this guy's life like?
You know,
these people were nuts.
They were out of their fucking
minds.
They were living at a crazy,
crazy time of taking over the world with
swords and bows and arrows and shit.
But is saddam hussein worse than them?
No,
no,
no.
Not really.
No.
They takIng that shit and put it in a
museum somewhere.
My college had christopher columbus
pointing at the cafeteria.
Right.
Kids.
He was a cool guy.
He just became something over the last
decade or so.
Right.
The christopher columbus was a piece of
shit.
Yeah,
right.
You know,
another thing,
I believe it's from graham hancock,
but um,
the iraqi museum had a lot of material
that just got wiped out during these
wars that will never be able to get
back,
that had to do with ancient art,
ancient societies and Egypt and things
like that.
So,
so during these wars,
you know,
the whole place will just lose it.
You know,
the museum was alluded so they lost all
of those,
you know,
that.
And that's a tragedy.
That's like the birth of modern
civilization is like the tigris and
euphrates,
that little valley there.
You got to keep that,
you know,
I understand the politics,
but you got to keep the history.
Leave it alone,
that there's rules of war that says you
can bomb anything you want,
but the colosseum in rome,
that's not cool.
You do that.
You will going to talk to you in the hey
glenn,
a few years,
you know,
the great wall of China,
you guys leave that alone,
bomb each other,
but there were protected sites in the
world that needs to stay protected.
Isn't that weird?
Like we,
we decide like,
okay,
look,
we don't like you.
This building's pretty dope.
Yeah.
We're not going to fuck up that
building.
And then I got you got it.
Like all right.
No,
no punching in the face.
Okay,
cool.
Because I ever bombed paris.
Like the eiffel tower get bombed or
anything.
Anywhere around paris get bombed.
Yeah.
they just kind of stormed through there
because they did.
There was like,
there's still like a lot of ammunition.
There's like this area outside of paris
and France.
It's like the size of paris that you
can't even go into today because there's
still like ordinances buried under the
ground.
We keep finding stuff there.
They stack it up and these warehouses
and shit.
It's just like a depository for bombs
and bomb chemicals.
They all fucking either launched amount
of.
There are.
They landed there and it didn't go off
or they left behind mines and bombs was
just huge area that you.
You can't even go In.
It's all toxic and it's the size of
parents apparently.
Wow.
Yeah.
So it was wondering like wonder,
was there a conscious decision to not
bomb,
like maybe,
maybe they did and I don't.
I don't know.
I don't think they did.
I think they just kind of rolled through
there because I mean london got the shit
kicked out of it.
See if you cAn find that picture.
Ges,
there's photos of the munitions where
they stack them up.
It's crazy.
Picture of paris getting bombed from the
familiar.
Oh,
well there you go.
Did they lead the.
I look at that.
Holy shit.
Wow.
There goes our,
like the library of alexandria got
destroyed.
That was in Egypt though.
I know,
but I'm just saying that was during the
muslim.
Yeah.
I know it's a different time period,
but I was just,
I was going to ask like that.
Is there something today that contains a
bunch of history that could be destroyed
and ruined and setting?
Yeah,
like
computers.
The problem would be if the power went
out for more than a couple of years,
it's never coming back.
Right.
If the grid got destroyed,
if something happened that was so big
that it destroyed the power grid and we
needed to reestablish a grid,
good luck,
and then we lose.
We lose 50 percent of the population in
the impact.
And then you know what,
we were left with chaos and lawlessness
and fucking people starving to death and
no one knows what to do.
Yeah,
good luck in the power back on that.
All would take is one of those things.
It might take 100 years for the power to
come back on
and that might not even be negative
intent of humans.
That can happen just from the sun in
emp.
We don't know.
We haven't had electric long enough.
We might have had an emp,
you know,
what's an emp explaining a electrode,
a magnetic pulse,
which would take out all of the
electronic.
You just say emp or emp.
We sit around and talk about this all
the time was,
was dog.
But they,
they,
you know,
there's um,
they've tried to make an amp weapons
that that'll take you,
take out a full grid.
But if,
but the son could produce that.
So if the son did that and it could have
been done in history where we just
didn't have electric,
there's evidence of an,
of an emp or a solar flare that hit some
time in the,
in the 19th century,
we only know about it because a
telegraph like went down all the
telegraphs in America went down for like
two days and everyone was like,
what happened?
And then a couple of days later
everything worked again.
And,
and scientists think that it was a solar
flare or their ejection that caused an
enp and just shut down all the power for
a few days here it would be a,
it'd be walking dead if it happened.
Now is so crazy that we rely on that
thing to stay stable.
This giant ball of nuclear power that's
floating in the sky.
It's a million times bigger than the
earth.
And we,
we count on it to stay stable.
We do what the solar flare is still
happening a lot though.
Recently there was something that knock
something out from a solar flare,
but the sun has been weird lately.
It's been really,
really dark and strange.
There's not a lot of activities.
One smokes too much pot.
The sun's been dark and strange.
Not a lot of activity.
Yeah.
I'm,
I'm really talking about being serious.
Oh,
what's going on with the son?
The son normally has a lot of solar
activity,
storms,
ejections,
all that kind of stuff.
The last 12,
15 years,
it's been really qUiet and it's dying.
It's a cycle,
but you know,
everybody freaks out.
It's global warming.
It's a little cooling.
It's climate.
This,
it's,
it's just a solar cycle and it's just.
The sun is just chilled right now,
taking a breather in 10 years and they
say
our cycle,
they're measuring what they've been
measuring over the period of whatever
amount of decades they've been able to
measure solar cycles,
but this thing has been around
measurement.
Yeah.
The sun's like,
oh,
you expect me to behave like I've been
behaving for the last 50 years?
Yeah,
good luck with that dude,
because I got a fucking temper
sometimes.
I like to blow up a whole solar system
turning into a crisp.
I watched this crazy documentary on
hyper nobles and that they initially
thought that they were.
They were witnessing when they saw these
gamma burst in the sky,
they thought they were witnessing war
between alien races.
Like that was the initial reaction to
measuring these gamma burst in the sky
and then they realized somewhere along
the line that you looking at like a
hyper nova,
like an enormous burst,
an explosion.
That's so great that if it was in a
nearby cluster it would kIll us.
Yeah.
That gamma radiation.
I think just the whole lowe's that we
can.
That we can even measure.
Yeah,
and the.
The thing was that it was happening all
day,
all throughout the sky.
Like they would be like measuring this
for the first time and they've seen
cool,
like all these different spots in the
universe.
we're experiencing these gamma burst.
How would you not think it's star wars?
Yeah,
I totally think that's exactly what they
thought.
Like,
oh my god,
what If they come?
What if they come and they have this
kind of power?
They have gamma power,
right?
So we have to band,
we'd,
we have to,
you know,
get society on the right track.
It seems like at least we could like
give them are gold are women and they
might leave us be,
it might be possible to negotiate,
but you can't go.
I'm just kidding about that obviously,
but you can't negotiate with a
supernova.
You know,
when a sun explodes and takes out the
entire surrounding area for billions and
billions of miles,
that's it.
It's like,
it's less,
it's less feared,
but way scarier.
Right?
You can't build an ark to escape a nova,
you know,
like it's just not.
That's just a little water.
It apparently it happens all the time.
you know,
and you probably won't happening right
now somewhere and you can never convince
society of it that,
hey,
we've got bigger problems to worry
about.
Then between me and you hear the pot
delivery services you fuck at
[inaudible] dot com.
[inaudible] dot com delivers
a,
you'll get a little package like this,
just like amazon prime,
although it'll be in a box that you
don't look lIke just a regular delivery.
This is your cue,
etc. You're getting them,
you're sending them through the mail.
It's not through the mail.
A of people during the medical courier?
Yeah.
Oh,
career medical courier.
How high is your medical courier?
Well,
the middle of driving,
going,
what am I doing with my feet?
They actually don't know what medicine
they have because they do all sorts of
medication.
They don't just,
they don't just do pot,
don't meanwhile,
but they're still high as fuck.
So I'm uh,
you know,
uh,
there are regulations that are coming
down for,
for transported as well.
Uh,
the teamsters want to get their,
their hands and transport,
which they are one of the people who are
rallying against legalization of
marijuana.
I'm there with the,
the,
um,
the unions for prisons.
So they're kind of fighting on both
sides.
They want to be involved in
transportation of marijuana,
however they're lobbying for to keep it
illegal.
Did the teamsters,
they're going to be on whatever side
winds are over here now.
Okay.
You're over here now.
Yeah.
Um,
so,
so again,
uh,
you know,
what we were considered was similar to
the dominoes of marijuana here in la.
We,
we,
uh,
are evolving.
That's what we were doing before this
lawsuit happened.
We really want to be considered more
like amazon prime.
So,
uh,
where you're making a lot of money.
And we were dumb now that I be like
circuit city,
well,
governor brown's new laws have changed
so that marijuana companies can be for
profit now.
They don't have to be not for profit,
which is how it's been for the last 20
years here.
So,
um,
and so that has to go into effect by
2018.
So that's something to consider also,
once that happens,
that changes things for a lot of
cannabis businesses,
but that all said,
every cannabis business that's in,
in la,
that's not a dispensary in,
in that whether they're making edibles
or they making vaporizers or,
or anything.
And it's a thriving industry.
They're all illegal.
Every bit of it.
So regulation does need that,
that,
that happened,
uh,
you know,
here in la and what we're asking for
isn't he just overturned this.
We're not saying that we're saying we
know the city attorney does believe that
safe access is important,
but he feels he has to uphold this law
that was put into effect before he was
the city attorney.
So since he knows this is a bad law that
he has to enforce,
he could also affect change by helping
go down the path of legalization for
good businesses.
He'S,
he's not an idiot.
he realizes what a bad law is.
He just knows his job is to enforce it.
Got it.
So hopefully,
hopefully he'll join the fight to find a
path towards legal.
Yeah.
Okay.
What can people do with the people that
are listening the to wrap this all up?
What,
uh,
the people that are listening,
what's a good way to follow this or a
good way to help?
Good way to help.
If you're in California,
good way to help us to join our
collective energy.
You buy anything and we'll keep you in
touch with the politicians and will put
pressure on them.
If you're outside of California,
what dOes that mean?
You politicians,
you put pressure on them joining.
What would that entail?
A joining our collective like if you're
a medical marijuana patient,
join [inaudible] dot com and we are
working actively with the city.
Try to solve this.
It's not.
So we're fighting in court?
Yes,
on one hand,
but on the other hand we are conversing
with the city,
like the city knows this is broken.
Okay,
well what do you mean by joining your
collective?
LIke what?
What does that entail?
Go to go to [inaudible] dot com.
Click join and you put your name,
email address.
That's all they have to do.
That's pretty much it.
Do they have to show you proof of
medical marijuana license?
They do if they want to order
prescription,
but if they could join your collective
without doing that,
they need to show proof that there are
patient to join a collective.
Oh,
okay.
All right.
That's what I was asking.
Yeah,
but we also have are so lackadaisical
with us.
So normal.
it's like,
yeah,
just join a collective.
Like it's,
it's hard to,
you know,
it's hard to be wedding people don't
know what we're even talking about.
What it is trouble you can,
if you don't have your card,
your,
your doctor recommendation,
you could get it right on our website by
doing a skype session with your doctor
and you know,
we told the story about about how,
how we got our cards in.
It's changed so much.
Wait a minute,
a doctor or I have to get my doctor to
do a skype session.
Your own doctor,
right?
yeah.
so now you're a doctor,
you're saying not your doctor,
your doctor.
We have a group of doctors.
RIght.
That's what I'm saying,
that our professional doctors that you
will do a real skype session and
they'll.
And they'll talk to you about what your
ailment is and,
and you could get your card instead of
going somewhere.
You could just do it right in your
living room.
That's an important point.
See,
when you were making it seem like the
guy had to get like,
oh man,
I've got to get my doctorate.
No,
no,
no.
Ten minutes.
I've been at 1:00,
jesus christ.
How many tokens a it takes 10 minutes to
do.
Right?
On our website we hAve this amazing
interactive people waiting that will be
selling point will take you right
through the whole process where we need
to do we need to buy a warehouse in
California and a bunch of people use it
as their mailing address and get people
from other states to become a part of
your collective and they have like a
fake mailing address.
Then we hook them up,
but we are we going to talk more about
that idea?
He goes,
dark city attorneys watching.
I didn't know.
Yes,
it's going to do it that way,
but I think it's just funny that you
know,
you have to be in this patch of dirt in
order to follow those rules.
Like you can't.
You couldn't join the collective.
You couldn't be like from most constant
and decided,
oh,
I want to join one of those California
poc collectives.
I'll skype in with the doctor and no,
you have to actually like have like your
mail delivered here.
It's so stupid.
It's weird.
Like an arbitrary line in the sand
politically across this line.
go to jail,
come back here and get baked and have a
good time.
Well that's what happens with people
that go into Texas.
You fuck up and you're in a tour bus.
You know,
we're this way is the bass and here.
Oh no,
that's a song.
You get pulled over and you're like,
oh no.
We got pulled over for weed in Texas.
This is not like getting pulled over for
weeding California and next thing you
know willie nelson's in jail.
Yeah,
that's a Willie Nelson got arrested,
right?
It's hilarious.
Someone such a piece of shit.
They arrested Willie Nelson.
I'd quit my job so my kids are going
hungry.
Fucked us.
It's actually great.
It's actually pretty scary getting
pulled over with weed in California
nowadays because of dui rate has gone
crazy.
My friend's a lawyer,
dui lawyer and half of his cases now are
just from marijuana and they have a new
test where they do the same kind of
thing with your eye,
but it,
it like goes left and right real fast if
you're high or something like that.
And if they feel like they,
they can smell weed and if,
if you fail this test,
you're getting a dui just like an
alcoholic left to right.
We'll quit.
So you know when,
when,
when you get pulled over,
they do the test with your.
I like fall,
my aunt.
I think with alcohol,
I think it shoots over like your eyes
shoots over to the left or the right
really fast or it's jerky,
uh,
when you're,
when you're high,
your eye reacts different every day.
It's kind of like a jiggly left and
right effect when it,
there can't be any science.
So that's,
that's it right now.
And right now in court they are fighting
just that.
If it's,
if it's a legit test and they don't have
a like a point,
oh,
eight for weed yet.
So they didn't really have any laws.
There's the main problem,
and I think you'll agree with me,
there's never been a study that shows
that any loss of motor skills.
No,
none.
Right?
There wAs one study about driving a
while smoking weed and that they found
that people actually performed better
route.
Well,
that's the problem.
It's not a motor skill thing.
It's not like alcohol.
Everybody knows that if you drink too
much,
you don't drIve good.
Everybody knows that it's bad for your
motor skills.
Pot's not.
It's simple.
So what are they pulling you over for
exactly?
state of mind.
So because if it doesn't affect your
motor skills,
like is it affecting your judgment?
Can you prove that people were
intoxicated on marijuana perform less
intelligently than people that are
intoxicated on caffeine or cigarettes
because you know they're doing that.
A cop could pull a guy over,
he could have a cigarette in the corner
of his mouth drinking a cup of coffee
and no one says a word.
Those are two drugs interact with each
other.
No one has a pro.
So it's a state of mind issue.
So.
And he could have those drugs and still
have a couple of pops at the bar to
really amp up all that aggression and
still legally drive behind what is,
um,
what his intoxication.
I mean,
isn't intoxication is supposed to be a
loss of motor skills?
Well,
right.
But it's sort of arbitrary because wHat,
what is intoxicated?
the swab test just did not pass in
California where they were trying to,
to swab for thc molecules and it's like,
no,
that's totally,
you can't do that because.
Because I'm going to just walk through a
party and then they get swapped and
they're in trouble.
They don't have any of it in their
system.
You can't,
you can't.
Like gino would,
what?
He smokes.
I don't know.
I don't even know when he's high.
I don't know when he's done.
Trust me is high right now.
Trust me.
You wouldn't know.
So mAny people are high right now and
you wouldn't know.
Right?
Of course.
So how can you test for it?
Well,
they're.
The real problem is what can you show is
bad about being high?
I need to see something on your tests
where you show me why you should be able
to pull people over with why you're
wearing a gun and shine a light in their
face and get them out of their vehicle
and make them do things like what is the
worst case you're looking for?
Okay.
What's
the worst case scenario that's going on
with this person that's on the
marijuana?
Are they performing in any way,
shape or form?
Whether they're a danger the people
around them.
So if that's.
If that is true,
I think you have to prove that before
you put people in a fucking cage.
It also varies from person to person.
I believe.
I know a girl that smokes a joint,
she can't drive.
She can barely function as a human,
but jay,
you know,
could do a whole ounce and you'll be
fine to drive as exact same driver as
before,
if not better.
But this girl,
no way.
I wouldn't even let her in the car.
She smoked her that she probably
shouldn't be able to drive anyway.
How about that shit?
Right?
There should be like a test,
we've talked about this before,
like a marijuana test,
like you are a 10,
meaning you could do with marijuana and
anything and you're fine,
but this person's like rated a six.
It's just.
But it's a mind issue.
It's not.
It's not a motor skill issue.
This is where the problem lies.
It's like,
yeah,
I guess some people would freak out when
they're on pot and they will do lose
their mind and maybe they shouldn't be
intoxicated,
but those people probably lose their
mind if someone yelled at them right
now.
Some people would just weak.
They just,
whatever the,
the glue that keeps their reality
together.
It's just really fragile and then throw
some pot in there or a drink.
I mean,
how many people do we know that have one
drink and they get fucking crazy.
That's a person who's reality's really
shaky.
Right?
But that doesn't have anything to do
with me.
You know,
and the idea that cops look towards that
as being the standard is ridiculous.
Right?
So if you like,
if it wasn't going to say,
if you have like a festival,
like a,
a cop's test,
potheads festival,
we would do it.
We would fucking do it.
Look for sure you have go-karts.
Set it up.
What do you want to do?
You want to have a fucking one of those
mud bogger races.
We'll do this.
Let us smoke pot.
We'll do all that.
We'll have jujitsu tournaments where
people smoke pot before they do jujitsu.
It orange cones and clipboards and some
wheat and people will join.
Fuck you.
And we'll learn.
We'll know.
Yeah.
What you need to show some sort of
significant issue because there's a
significant issue with some people,
but you're not even stopping those
people from taking.
Who knows what the fuck they're taking
as far as antidepressants are
psychoactive substances prescribed by
their doctors.
And how many people are on fucking
adderall?
Man,
that's meth.
They're taking meth.
They're driving around.
You know,
I know a bunch of adults that take that
shit on a daily basis yet.
So w,
what you're dealing with is a lot of
different chemicals that could
potentially fuck with a mind.
Like why are you concentrated on pot
given shown any reason to concentrate on
pot.
You know,
the chIef of police in New York city
recently said that every crime could be
tied back to marijuana that's holding
him,
uh,
you know,
which is a criminal outrageous because
it's just trying to give more reach for
police officers to pull you over.
Irresponsible thing to say.
That's like saying every crime can be
tied back to water.
Parents,
we all have 96 of water.
All.
Yeah.
It's all stupid man.
It really is.
It's just something that should be a
joke that We look back on from the 19
thirties.
We look back and like,
oh wow,
look at the craziness that these people
that are dealing with baCk then.
But instead we have to deal with it
today and the age of google and
information,
scientific studies ad nauseum that all
show the same thing.
And none of Them show any negative
effects.
None of them.
There's like some questions about
memory.
That's it.
But it seems to only affect you while
you're on it.
When you get off of it.
It doesn't seem to have any effect on
your memory at all.
I mean,
the head of the dea currently said
medical marijuana.
That's just a joke.
Let let's,
let's get past that.
And I'm the head of the dea before that,
when asked by congress it,
is marijuana a more detrimental than
meth?
She said she can't.
And we played that many times
was on the show because it's so
ridiculous.
That was laying heart,
right?
Yeah.
She was in.
This was a senator or something.
kept grilling her.
If you haven't seen it,
it's fucking infuriating.
It is.
So what's so infuriating also is that we
all know so well.
How come these people who are in power
aren't,
aren't in the know why
not a no,
it's that they are the official
response.
Right?
So they looked at ladies just doing her
job.
She couldn't just speak out of turn.
She couldn't.
She would get fired.
She couldn't just say whatever she
wants.
Even if she doesn't.
Even if she doesn't believe that it
should be illegal,
she's not going to say that because
that's not her job.
Her job is to do whatever the fuck her
superiors tell her to do and to stay
employed and make sure her budget
doesn't get exactly.
That's her job.
So it's not even her fault.
It's the fault of the system that they
accept that the whole thing is
preposterous.
IT doesn't,
doesn't hold up anymore.
Well,
this is why we have to play this game of
politics.
You know,
we,
we just want to want to run a business
and a good business,
but we have to play this game of
politics because if we don't,
from the bottom effect change through
those people who are at the top,
then we didn't and let them continue to
create these laws.
We could just go another 20 years with
these bad laws when there's no reason
for it,
you know?
Yeah.
I think you're right.
I'm just hoping that what's gonna go on
is that,
as you know from the time that I first
got my license up today,
how much more open?
It's been much more relaxed,
people are much more accepting,
people are of it and much more accepting
amongst grown adults.
You just see the attitudes of people.
They're changing and people
understanding how beneficial or how
beneficial it is,
especially for people who need it.
Medically.
Cancer patients,
things,
things along those lines.
Kids with epilepsy add things along
those lines.
There's just so many people that benefit
from it.
It's,
it's hopefully it's on its way out.
All the laws are on their way out.
Yeah.
And,
and you can't just disregard the
experience of,
of the masses.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's not fair and it's because we're,
we're lucky to be in sort of the media
age,
which can be annoying at times,
but it also allows information at move
very quickly.
Yeah.
So it's.
So if your kid is helped by having fewer
seizures,
everybody's gonna know about that in 24
hours,
so.
So you can't really suppress the truth
any longer.
And even Texas is polling positively.
Yeah.
Florida is going to pass it,
you knoW,
Pennsylvania just passed it.
It's the dominoes are falling,
the dominoes are falling.
And people at chris christie or going to
be as amber lyon likes to say on the
wrong side of history and that's just,
there's no other way around it.
It's just this guy's a fool.
He's a fool and he needs to get off the
sugar contact mark sisson bitch.
He'll straighten you out.
Primal blueprint.com.
All right.
That's it.
Goodnight everybody.
Thank you,
gino.
Thank you.
Ha.
Thanks to red band.
Oh,
red band.
You got to show this thursday,
denver comedy works and then regard
there with George Perez and ryan doing
the following week.
We're in New York with the legion of
skanks people.
The skank fest.
Powerful
fast.
So a denver comedy works thursday.
Awesome spot tomorrow night.
I'm at the ice house with ian edwards.
Ian's doing both shows and I think joe
is doing the second show too.
So,
um,
this will be the last show that I do
before I do my comedy specials.
So a fox.
Aja,
thank you.
thank you,
gino.
Always appreciate you guys.
[inaudible] dot com.
Just [inaudible] dot com.
You,
you fucking monster.
Thanks.
Thanks buddy.