It was a thing on our
reality sandwich worked.
I was criticizing the salt stoned ape
theory and it was only based on one point,
the visual acuity point.
They were arguing about Roland Fischer's
work on visual acuity being measurably
improved by who knows?
You could try that.
I looked that up.
I can find that study.
Yeah,
I didn't find it either.
Maybe that's wrong,
but it's still like to,
to chart harp on one.
Okay.
Fairly insignificant
portion of the theory.
The theory never made
sense to me in that regard.
The,
the visual acuity thing,
because that's in low doses.
That's what you're saying.
But they're not eating low doses.
They're eating a lot of that shit.
Why low doses if they could find it,
you know,
they're,
they're eating probably tons of it.
We talked to,
we talked to our primatologists about
it and he said that the time period that
Mckenna has using does not work
for the way he understands,
uh,
climate,
the growth of the neo cortex
and predominance apparently.
Um,
so his theory about the massive
expansion of our brains,
right.
Did it happen way before Mckenna says the
stoned ape theory or what's happening.
But then he might've been confused
about that time period cause they,
I believe Macanta mine at candidate know
Mckenna says the early plasticine error
I think and like,
sorry,
I don't know.
Well the theory for the folks who
don't know what the fuck are they is,
the theory is that at one point in time
monkeys climb down from the trees and
they were experimenting with new food
sources and they started eating suicide as
mushrooms because there was these great
herds of Unpeel it cattle that were,
you know,
hooked cattle that are wandering around
the fields dropping shits and that these
mushrooms grow from these shits and these,
these,
uh,
monkeys and baboons have been dead.
They've demonstrated them lifting up cow
patties and looking for bugs and stuff
on that you think cause
it's all moist and,
and that eating these
mushrooms that grew on these,
these cow shits made them more,
more evolved and made them,
uh,
like doubled the size of the human
brain may have them develop language.
Yeah.
Look,
something happened.
Sure.
Look at us.
And look at them.
It's pretty fucking clear.
Is that a big Goddamn gap?
Why?
What is this gap?
I know.
I really think it's that crazy,
a crazy idea and you know,
most people I talk to you,
they were,
their main response
scientists gave was like,
you know you need a time machine.
It really proved that theory.
So yeah,
don't get your eyes off.
See this gentleman,
one of the greatest podcast cast,
if not the greatest
all time flows.
I don't have an ax.
Okay.
That's the problem I was worried about.
I am sure I was worried about
you being a little too trendy.
It's fun.
Cop breath stretching.
You don't have that ordered.
I worked out with Steve
Maxwell and Toronto and I
ordered an Indian club bells.
There were this big iron
baseball bats and you're like,
oh
the barely do it.
10 pounds,
man.
It's crazy.
It's a crazy exercise.
So I ordered these 15 pounders and
I'm going to build up to 45 pounders.
That's when you're a fucking real ox.
When you're a real animal and
you want to put the squeezed off.
No,
I've been out for almost two months now.
The back injury?
Yeah.
I had a reoccurring thing where
I would pop out a rib head.
So what I decided to do is
just work out a lot of it,
do a lot of cardio,
a lot of hitting the bag and stuff.
Actually I got leaner and um,
uh,
less,
less rolling and more like high
rep kettlebell stuff and a lot,
a lot of like different strength
and conditioning shit cause I,
this,
this injury kept happening.
It can't,
I,
it happened over a course of a few months
over and over again in the same spot.
I was like,
all right,
I need to get in this thing,
some actual real time off
or it's going to be crying.
You got no guy like you and your physique.
You don't really have to worry
about that crest scratch out
the um,
the dance dance or video
you did and it was,
it called,
oh Steve,
what the fuck?
There's a self defense vouch with crepey.
You had no,
you hadn't like,
uh,
fuck.
Not Unintentional Unintentional dancer.
You had a sketch,
the creator,
was it called?
Oh yeah,
I was,
I've buck on and on.
It's not unintentional orthodox stance.
Answer.
Yes.
Well it was that.
I just did the weirdest shit where I'd
show up in like underwear and like get
mask.
I had one of those Bob's
thing and I just come it,
Bam and I hit it and go run and go,
hey,
that's some shit.
He was like the most
absurd shit I'd ever done.
He's helped me.
I think I might have it in my trunk.
I might.
He gave me a DVD.
We were,
we were hanging out.
He goes,
this thing has fucking thing.
I did this.
Go check this out.
Tell me like it.
I get home.
I just talking about computer to run.
The fuck is wrong with this deal.
I get such a good
pink socks and shit
fly by but then run away.
That was so fucking retarded.
Alex Jones,
the Joey d is on the Alex Jones show.
Have you ever seen that?
For those who haven't seen it,
so we might as well
just stick this in here,
put it in or you got to see this.
Well,
we'll edit it in here.
This is the funniest thing that I've ever,
so there's a segment off of the uh,
Austin,
uh,
video that Brian made when we
went to Austin with little year.
Funniest thing that I've ever seen
in my life were in doom and gloom.
Alex Jones,
no
black helicopters and aliens.
The government,
the CIA.
Eugenics is a master race.
It's that layer.
He's all crazy like this.
And Joey Diaz comes in with a story
about some my little weed under his balls
and Alex is trying to stop
him from saying on the air,
but Joey just runs with it.
And it is the single most powerful
performance you've ever seen in your life.
The commitment he has on a
fucking national right way,
not right wing sort of libertarian,
crazy apocalyptic radio show.
This guy wants to talk about,
we ain't go ablations,
gentlemen.
Right now the price of gold is down all
time lows and the neo cons for starting
this up.
No,
he'll tell you about fucking and he'll
sell you for freeze dried food that you
keep on going because
it survives nuclear war.
It's in special aluminum cans and Joanie
is talking about smuggling weed under
his balls and it's the funniest fucking
thing I've ever seen in my life.
It's a humbling can I?
Where can I get it?
It's not book.
Put It on this and we'll say like,
I got to see that.
Boom Schelok log.
I hadn't heard back yet.
I put into my left side.
We're not telling the story
whole bottle right now.
This is freedom.
This is not a control.
There's hope thumping joints worse.
Hold on.
He is worse than any problem.
I love him,
but y'all bring this monster.
Your,
you know,
if people are looking for,
the truth on this show is about the truth.
I I,
I got debt and I had baggy clothes on but
I had a belt on and they sound because
you have baggy clothes on.
They didn't know as well.
Spray pounds.
They said,
we're going to put you
to the x ray machine.
I'm standing there sweating bullets with
this baggy under my fucking God left us
bigger than the right regular
cause I'm a righty stop.
People don't know that.
I thought I had cancer for couple weeks.
You know the opposite hand.
When my legs open stick.
You're like Rodney Dangerfield said stop
talking about that was sticking up a
storm and not to mention my boss.
I'm sweating now,
but I just shook my hand.
I'm like,
Mike,
payers are hard at work.
Don't know.
I know.
Go Fuck Yourself.
You come on.
Hold on one second.
Joey Diaz.
Facebook,
Twitter.
Check yourself before you wreck yourself.
Big Dixon.
Yes,
they black cause that's
the most important.
Ah,
okay.
Okay.
Tell us for a while.
Even talking
old school comedy store veteran.
Steven is easy.
I know Steve Forever.
Back in the day.
Oh,
California.
You guys have the same car.
Did you?
Gay Lords I bought a couple of weeks ago.
What'd he say?
Let's explore.
Oh,
that's an explorer.
But they're both for the new explorers
is supposed to be a shit Fords or a
spaceship.
Yeah.
Touch everything.
I put my,
I hit a button.
I go drive home really driving home Matt
fucking whole thing to call Joe Rogan
because Joe Rogan.
What the air to 75.
75.
Wow.
Yeah.
It's crazy.
We're living in the future.
That's it guys.
It's really going down.
That's right.
So,
uh,
um,
have you,
uh,
ever thought about doing your own podcast?
No.
You know what it is.
I have fun doing other people.
I've only done yours twice.
I didn't Marin's I did Ari's
did you like doing marathons?
I did like doing married.
I did a really early,
I did it like probably when he,
I don't think he would
ask me to do it now.
I did it when he was still like,
he's kind of a bunch
of scrubs on that show.
Who would let you on?
Thank you.
You wouldn't be the only one
that's going to fucking listed,
but way more advanced
here on the actual show.
But it's,
uh,
I enjoy doing them.
I don't really know.
I don't really,
I know it's like,
I like,
I like hanging out with my friends.
It's an awesome tool for
pumping up shows though,
man.
It really is.
People will say to me,
you've got to do Joe Rogan's podcast.
I will.
Yeah,
I want to do Benson's too.
Yeah.
This is great too,
but I mean as far as
like for promoting gigs,
it's,
it makes a huge difference.
Math,
you had your own,
you would really developed,
do you have like a serious website?
Not really.
Now give him a message board.
No.
You should get those yeses.
Yeah.
You develop a little community,
man.
I got a message board that has
almost 4 million posts on it,
more than 4 million.
Right?
4 million posts on it.
All these members and you can communicate
back and forth with these people.
So easy.
You could promote gig.
I mean it's not like anything in the past.
They're your access to your fans.
It's like directly did I feel I
answered tweets and I answered like the
intelligent ones and then
Facebook messages and stuff
and then some stuff on my
website.
But yeah,
I dunno.
Maybe I've never been good
at the marketing side.
Yeah,
but this is the best way because it's fun.
Everything else we've done.
It's like,
wow,
I've got to fucking
promote on [inaudible].
Gotta do this.
You've got to do that.
Everything else has been like work,
but this does not seem like work at all.
This is like fun stuff.
Yeah,
we should do it,
man.
See rosacea.
You can do it with Brian.
Brian Red Bat.
It's Ryan has its own broadcast network.
Dude.
He could immediately get you seen
by hundreds of thousands of people.
Do you have to have an angle?
You have to have an angle.
You can just go get.
We did today.
We didn't talk about what we're going to
do and I don't ever talk about what I'm
going to do.
I mean every now and then someone
will be talking about some shit in the
kitchen.
I'm like,
save it,
save it.
Yeah.
No.
Cool.
That's all I got
here we are alive and Sunny
California with the movie
super high.
Me Star
giving way to describe me.
That's you dude.
I like,
is it like wandering around this life
known everywhere you go as not just a
stoner but a super stoner.
It's pretty great.
It's fun,
you know,
most people leave me alone,
but you know,
the people that know,
they're,
uh,
they're usually pretty friendly about it.
You get,
you get it.
I'm a,
yeah,
you're another above me as far as light,
as far as pacos part goes to me and
started talking to me about fear factor or
UFC.
Yeah,
it's all pot.
We do
lots of podcasts,
listeners and you know,
and my podcast all about movies.
So,
uh,
you know,
people want to talk to you about movies,
so that's a nice change of pace.
Could you live anywhere that didn't have,
we'd like California has now,
isn't that like a prerequisite?
Like if you thought about moving
to some other parts of the country,
like when I moved to Colorado and one of
the first things I thought I was like,
okay,
and Colorado's got medical potlucks.
Who was like,
they're,
oh,
it's just like yell.
Perfect.
Yeah.
Well,
that's the thing is all the places that
I gravitate towards on the road are
either places where the whole state has
medical or a particular city is cooler
than other cities,
you know,
so like it's more decriminalized
in some places than others.
And those tend to be the same cities.
I enjoy performing it.
And you're like,
Austin,
Texas is a great example of
like some places around there.
I'd be in pretty,
you know,
I'd have to be pretty
paranoid about my behavior,
but in Austin you can
sort of get away with,
um,
I know you're doing Ann Arbor,
Michigan,
right?
I love that place.
Yeah,
that place is awesome.
That's a place where you wouldn't realize,
he would know bash,
bash for years before Michigan.
And the medical,
and I think also in was probably the
reason why medical got over the hump and
Michigan because there so into it.
And that one city,
have you ever seen the
four 20 day in Boulder?
Fucking incredible.
They go on the collar on the,
uh,
University of Colorado.
They go on the campus and everyone
smokes out like the whole campus.
Like there's clouds of smoke.
I'll give,
never seen anything black.
A thousands of people
passing joints around.
It's fucking nuts.
Yeah.
If you ever done an amazing,
no,
I haven't ever been there.
I'm always off somewhere doing a show
is I get a good crowd on four 20 we need
you and I need to do a fucking show there
next for 20 April 20th in boulder or
don't you do a thing doe commit me on
camera every April 20th thought you'd do a
thing where you record a new CD.
That's a,
that's what I tried to do.
Yeah.
This year I was in Sacramento at such
a great we town and it was fun to do it
like,
you know,
record a record standing in front of the
Capitol building that they have drawn
there on the wall at the
punchline in Sacramento.
So it was pretty fun.
So you already have coming
out later this year.
But that's what I do is every year.
Like,
you know,
there's a few cities
I'm considering for a,
you know,
for next year,
but it's just like,
it's a great knife.
We are recording an album.
It's a great way for
me to always know you,
you know,
people say for 20 to me so much
that it's always top of mine.
So like I know that like right now I
know I've got like 11 months to get the,
you know,
the next material ready
to go for another album.
And so I'll start ditching the stuff from
this album and replacing it with newer
stuff.
But you know,
it's a whole cycle that I go
through that seems to be working.
So no boulders show bitches.
No,
but I definitely want to boulder event.
I'm definitely working on,
um,
I think I'm going to go
do a show in boulder in,
in uh,
September because that is a great place
to go and I've never done up there.
I lived there,
but I never ever performed there.
I think when I was
living there I was like,
I don't think I should be
doing standup where I live.
It's a little town.
Went a hundred thousand people.
Yeah,
they got a couple of,
they've got a couple of little theaters,
a nice sized theaters in downtown boulder.
Awesome,
awesome town.
One of those rare towns,
the guy that said it best to work for
the local paper said it's a working
utopia.
It's one of the few.
It's like,
it's like a weird,
crazy Whoville town,
you know,
it's got the nicest whole
foods I've ever been in.
Foods are usually pretty awesome.
So this one's like,
wow to Norris has a
restaurant inside of it.
Yeah.
Yeah,
of course.
So friendly there.
It's like one of the friendliest
places I've ever been.
And they're all living like an asshole
in this majestic mountain range.
I mean,
it's all swollen.
Weed is only thing things going on there.
Yeah,
it's cool.
And wait,
that's all you need.
Education and marijuana.
That's a,
that's going to lead
to a nice place to be.
Dot.
Benson,
ladies and gentlemen,
no wiser words have ever been spoken.
That's pretty much,
it's like wine and cheese.
Now look at it.
Marie.
Look.
Asshole liquid.
Well,
let me look at this.
And
what do you think that is,
Sarah?
Well read,
man.
I thought I liked you.