Couple of hours and yeah,
we've got the gun.
What's up gentlemen?
How are you?
Good,
thanks for having people tune into this
podcast.
I got Brendan Burns and Jason Harrington
who have run a company called
[inaudible],
which is the premiere.
If,
if,
if you could look at your company like
in comparison to a lot of other like
sporting good companies and like if he,
if people think about like a hunting
company,
you think about,
oh well it's like some duck dynasty type
shit.
You guys,
what I like about your company is
there's not a lot of people that take
what you guys do,
like make clothing and gear and take it
to the most technical and most
intelligent.
Like what is the best shit you can
possibly make set and go do that.
That's it.
But because of that,
this company has become this gigantic
company I found out about you guys buy
from my friend,
I'm Martine to Patellas,
uh,
who,
works for meat eater.
He was wearing these clothes.
I go,
what's,
what's going on with that?
What do you got there?
And he's like,
this is cool.
This is a new company that's out there,
this feel,
this filled,
that filled this,
this is an ultra light is the best kind
of fabric is.
So he started telling me about your
company and I just love when people go
for it.
I love when people like people wouldn't
think that there's like this big market
to create the most technical,
most ridiculously engineered hunting
clothes.
You would say,
well what the fuck?
Who's doing that?
Like where,
who cares?
Yeah,
exactly.
Who needs it.
But then listening to you guys on a
couple of podcasts,
I'm like,
these guys are fucking sharp dudes.
Super Sharp,
intelligent people who just happened to
be in love with hunting.
And so you've taken this mindset,
this,
this achievement oriented mindset and
put it towards this company.
And it's fascinating to me.
Yeah.
It's um,
you know,
I just got into it because I wanted to
make stuff.
I couldn't find,
I wanted better performing products.
It's what you know,
we created the category was sick of back
of the day is back in 2004 because I was
wearing all mountain their anger and
wondered why I was the only person that
wanted that style,
that type,
that performance level of hunting.
I didn't believe that I was alone and
came up with a concept,
introduced it and oh six to the hunting
market and exploded credit,
the entire technical total category.
And it's just,
it's now what everyone's chasing.
It's with everyone wants to wear and
makes a significant difference for our
customers in the mountains.
Well,
there's a bit of this,
a lot of,
uh,
hunting people are kind of fashion east
does in a way.
Totally.
Like,
Ooh,
what do you got there?
I was an underwriter who was at first
light.
Like they start like looking at your
stuff,
almost like girls look at shoes and
purses and shit.
It's,
it's really kind of interesting that
way.
Well,
no one likes to go to a hunting camp,
be out geared.
Right.
Your buddy's got the coolest,
latest step.
They're like,
what?
Well,
what is that?
One of the reasons why I wanted to have
you guys on is cause I've done the best
job I can of trying to educate people as
to what I see when I talk to people that
are really intelligent,
really ethical,
very,
very involved
people that are fanatics about hunting.
Because I think there people have of
distorted perception of what hunting
really is.
Totally do.
It's like Yahoo's beer drinkers being
Baba Baba banners is above a redneck
striving and drinking beer,
shooting stuff out of the truck.
And it's so not that our customer base
and what we do,
I mean it's a true lifestyle as a
heritage.
It's been passed down in my family.
It's where we live and breathe.
It's why I'm I trained every day.
Uh,
it's what my focus is on my life and,
and what I've done for a career in a
business.
And it's,
there's a lot to it.
And the places we go,
we require that or you're going to pay a
huge,
huge price.
And so it's a way for me to test myself
as a,
as a human being,
as a man,
as a hunter.
And a life.
And it's something that,
uh,
you know,
is a big,
big part of me.
It's been passed down from my father and
I'm passing down to my kids and,
uh,
you know,
we've been hunters for 2 million years
and fricking proud of it.
A lot of people shy away from it.
And it's something that,
uh,
is really,
really obviously very important part of
my life.
Well,
there's not a lot of high performance,
you know,
super skilled things where you also have
a lowest common denominator kind of guy
that you're associated with.
I mean,
if mountaineers,
you know,
had a guy that was wearing a white tank
top and was down at the climbing gym,
fallen,
operate in his head every week,
people would perceive him slightly
different.
He runs,
you know,
the guys that are doing the most extreme
stuff in the world and the purse,
the perceived person that's down here.
So you know what people,
you get lumped in with the lowest common
denominator guy,
which is not not the case at all.
I mean,
yes,
that's a really good point.
Yeah.
And,
uh,
yeah.
I mean it's,
it's uh,
it's certainly what we're doing and
we'll,
we're testing our products.
I mean,
we argue that it's,
it's a different format than even
outdoor gear.
I mean were when the weather's bad and
you're on a climb,
you stay in your tent when the weather's
bad and we're on a hunt,
what do we do?
Yeah.
Especially if you're not bringing much
food and you're counting on killing
something and eating it up,
they're totally,
it's,
it's an endeavor that's a very,
very difficult and misunderstood
endeavor.
He really is and I think companies like
yours and what you guys are doing in the
videos that you release on youtube,
especially when you're going over the
extreme engineering involved in your
packs and your gear and all the
different thing.
To me that stuff's fascinating.
It is because I love people that are
just going for it,
that are just engineering the shit out
of things.
You guys are chopping down toothbrushes
to make them lighter and all this stuff
you're doing.
Like I was listening to one of the
podcasts,
we talk about your excel sheet that you
make a spreadsheet that you made every,
every hunt.
You weigh everything out so you know
exactly what everything,
ways before you're going onto a
mountain,
you have to,
for what we're doing.
Yeah.
I mean you look at any endurance sports
and you look at,
cycling is a great example.
I mean ounces they've proven are huge.
If you're climbing on a bike and the
bike weight and the,
and the bodyweight on all that leads to
better performance.
And we found the same to
be with with what we're doing on
backpack cards.
I mean every ounce over a 10 day hunt
really adds up in calorie burn and
calorie deficit,
which then turns out to be performance
and know well from training.
Well it's also,
you guys have engineered these clothing.
The clothing line is incredibly quiet,
which is also really important thing.
And there's,
there's so many different levels to
getting it right when it comes to
hunting gear,
getting it right when it comes to,
you know,
I mean,
it could be the difference between
success and failure.
And this is one of the things that I
wanted to kind of highlight about this
pursuit.
Um,
and I don't like to call hunting a sport
or a discipline mean call whatever you
want,
but it's not,
you know.
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
it is what it is.
It's weird that you have to lump it into
this other thing,
but I think that people have a distorted
perception of it because of what you
said because of this lowest common
denominator guide,
the,
the Bubba thing.
But the more I've gotten into it,
the more I've met people like you guys
or people like Cam Haynes or Steve
Rinella,
Remy Warren,
and you get deep end.
You realize like this is a really
difficult discipline.
Very,
very difficult.
That has many,
many,
many layers to,
it really does.
I mean,
you look at the,
some of the expeditions we were doing up
north,
you know,
we'd go up to the Yukon or Alaska or
northwest territory's and when we're
going from point a to point b,
like normal exposition with,
but there were hunting,
yeah.
On top of that.
Exactly.
And then we've got to manage the game
that we take out on top of that,
the weight and the extremes and the
conditions and the weather.
I mean,
it adds to,
you have to be really well prepared.
Really.
Um,
physically,
mentally,
and also with the right equipment and
gear.
Yeah.
I mean you had in the mountains on some
of the stuff we're doing.
I mean,
it's not like it's comparable with
mountaineering,
but I mean,
you don't have to,
you know,
it's not a to b.
You just got to survive to ADB.
I mean,
you have to thrive in the mountains.
You have to understand what's going on
with the animals.
You're up early or up late.
I mean,
it's,
it's even more in depth.
And then just getting from point a to
point b.
And a lot of these places were going,
there is no reason to ever go there
unless you were hunting.
I mean,
just some random mountain in the middle
of the ice glacier that not particularly
tall,
not particularly,
but like there's no reason to go there
unless you had something to go there and
look for.
And that's the cool thing we were seeing
stuff that nobody would ever go see.
Yeah.
It's like a to B with a very complex
biological puzzle.
Totally.
Yeah.
It's,
it's so,
it's so different than,
like I said,
a lot of people think of it.
And one of the things I like about your
companies,
you guys are represented by this big
horn sheep.
I mean,
that is like a part of your logo,
which is one of the most difficult
animals to pursue sheep pennings at
pinnacle,
man.
And it's,
uh,
it defines for Brennan and I and for
people in the company and the people who
associate with a brand.
I mean,
it is the ultimate dream.
It's what we all dreamt about growing
up.
As someday I would be a sheep hunter.
I'll earn the right to go sheep hunting
because it's so difficult.
It is.
The opportunities are limited.
The,
and it's an animal that lives in places
that we,
you know,
we can visit,
but we can't live there.
I mean,
they live in places that you just,
you know,
the,
we,
we only get to like a snippet into
their,
into their life.
Cause it's places you can't,
you just,
you just can't live.
I mean,
you can't go there and you can die.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
I mean a Cam Haines,
good buddy Roy Roth died just this past
season fell 700 feet to his death while
she hunting.
I was hunting.
Uh,
I had a tag in Alaska and that you gach
um,
couple a little ways over from there and
we went 37 miles in,
up,
uh,
up to,
to two forks of a glacier.
And I mean,
we got to where you could physically a
human being without climbing gear could
not go any further.
Where I killed my sheep is fall 15 year
old ram living up in the rocks.
And I mean it like that.
That is some of the,
that's some of the most,
that's some of the toughest country in
the world.
It means brushy and ice and nasty.
And you know,
again,
it's not,
it's not pleasurable to go in there like
you have to,
to really go into something like that.
You Do,
you have to have a goal or a reason to
be in there.
It's not like I'm going to go grind out
this miserable brush and you know,
poor,
you know,
shitty rainy weather home.
He,
yeah,
he just like,
why would you be there?
Cause you go there because you want to
see,
you know,
is this is going to test me and you want
to see if you can match wits with this
animal and you know,
you,
you want to go see if you're up for the
challenge.
I mean that's what we've been doing for,
it's the world's oldest and greatest
sport.
I mean,
if you're not,
you know,
you were either a hunter or a berry
picker and the the level of intensity
that's involved in that moment when you
actually try to take that animal after
that incredible hiking after 37 miles of
risking your life to get to that point.
And then that moments there,
just the extreme amount of pressure and
intensity involved in that moment.
That to me is what defines the real
challenge,
the ultimate challenge of hunting and
this idea that it's a bunch of people
that like killing animals or it's a
bunch of fat Yahoos and sit around
drinking beer.
No,
there's way,
there's way more to this thing.
This is more an insane,
like really primal pursuit.
It is.
We always say you're either a hunter,
you're like Brendon mentioned a berry
picker.
It's in our DNA if you're a hunter.
And to be able to test that against the
toughest conditions against the hardest
animals,
to hunt the most remote places is to me
the ultimate test of being a human being
and ultimate test of being a hunter.
And that's what drives me and what we
do.
And why they train year round.
Why,
I'm always thinking about gear,
about food,
about Wade,
about uh,
you know,
what,
how I could improve from what I learned
on last year sent to this coming
seasons.
Um,
and preparation of it is a,
it's fun.
Yeah,
I love it.
I live it and breathe it and uh,
it's,
it's challenging.
It's really challenging.
Well,
it unfolded for me,
uh,
and it still continues to do so because
I've only been doing it for four years.
I mean,
Rinella got me involved and he took me
out to Montana in 2012.
And uh,
you know,
I was like,
oh,
hey,
this is kind of be interesting.
Let's see what this is all about.
Because I had watched shows and I read
some stuff about it,
but one of the things that he said,
he's like,
man,
there's a steep learning curve to this.
There's a steep lines.
Then it goes long.
And I was like,
well,
how long can it go?
He fucking find an animal.
You shoot it and kill it.
Need it seem so hard.
But then as you get into it,
you realize and then of course bow
hunting,
which is the most difficult of the most
difficult pursuits.
And as you get into it,
you realize like,
oh,
this is like some crazy puzzle.
It's like some crazy challenge that you
have to figure that also involves a way
to procure your food.
It does.
And it's a skill set you never quit
learning on every time you go out.
I learned something new.
Yeah,
there's a,
there's a natural progression you go
through.
I mean,
it's like you're just excited to be
there.
Right.
And then your,
and then you see it with people you've
take out through first time.
They're just like,
oh,
kind of what's what's going on here.
And you know,
and then then all of a sudden they get a
little click and it's like,
I want to get one,
you know?
And then,
you know,
that's usually a couple of years.
And then,
and then,
yeah,
I want to get,
I'm going to get a nicer one than one I
got last time and I want,
you want to do something a little more
challenging.
And it just keeps progressing until
like,
you know,
until you get,
wherever it ends and it's,
it's you,
you're hunting the toughest animals,
the biggest animals,
the oldest animals and the toughest
conditions and being successful and know
a lot of people won't get there.
But it's,
it's,
it's always a challenge.
It's something that never gets old.
I mean it's,
it's,
you know,
as comparable to any athletic event only
you can do it for your whole life,
you know,
I mean there's lots of stuff you do
athletic and then in growing up or
whatever and it was like,
but it doesn't really translate,
you know,
a college wrestler that doesn't
translate that well to do the rest of
your life.
If you're that dude down there at the
intermural wrestling like Ah,
you've missed,
you know,
hunting is the one thing that is just
throughout your entire life.
Depending on where you're at.
I mean,
you can,
it's,
you can always continue to learn and
pursue it.
And you know,
sometimes you,
you know,
you don't have a ton of time,
you can do a short on sometimes,
you know,
things are going well,
you can do something that's,
you know,
an epic adventure.
But it's always a challenge.
It never gets easy though.
I mean,
the,
the animal you killed last time does not
care.
The new animal you're hunting does not
care what you got last time.
You have to go out,
you gotta be sharp every single time,
you know?
Yeah.
And
everything has to be done right every
single time.
Yep.
Yeah.
And what I like about guys like youtube
is you take two dudes like yourselves
who are both like real goal oriented
savages.
And you put together a company like this
that pursues that one ultimate
experience and says,
what is the best shit that we can make?
What is the best way we can pursue this?
We do.
Um,
and that's why I built,
could you,
the way it did,
having learned from Sitka selling to
retailers,
the limits of what we can produce.
And I was super frustrated.
The fact that I was walking away from
the best materials and walking away from
the best innovations.
And when we sold that company to Gore
Tex,
I had the freedom to go start something
new and to eliminate the retailers so I
could go build a business platform
specifically.
So I could go out,
take these amazing materials,
amazing designs to mark that I couldn't
do before and get them to market through
this brand Kuya which has made all the
difference.
Well isn't it interesting that this has
all happened at the same time where the
Internet has kind of exploded in this
way that people are doing perfect time,
massive amount of shopping online's
yeah,
I mean I have a one of those uh,
mailboxes where they get your packages
for the company and uh,
you know,
when I used him 10 years ago,
I'd get like a package every couple days
or something like that.
Now every time I go there is stacks and
boxes.
Shit.
Cause I do like all my shopping online.
Everyone does now.
It's a crazy thing how that's happened
for you guys,
like right as your company started was
right at the same time.
It's like you caught that wave right at
the crest.
When I look back it's like we
orchestrated it and timed it perfect and
like we could see the future.
I could see the downfall it he called
it,
I mean Brennan,
I talked about it.
I can see there's a problem with retail
when you can't produce the best products
possible for your customers because they
can't sell it.
They can't have the value any longer
because all zur offering is price and
selection.
So price wins in a see a selection with
no one there to explain why a new
product so much better than the old
product.
There's a problem and I saw it coming
and now you see it,
you know,
getting exacerbated everyday with new
reports about retailers,
failing malls going out of business.
Retail is in big,
big trouble.
Amazons,
you know,
made that happen faster.
The Internet's made it happen and it's
all looking back with [inaudible].
Timing was everything.
I mean,
as you know with business,
you know a lot of it is timing luck and
be in the right place at the right time
with the right concepts and ideas.
And we,
we didn't totally nailed it and we kind
of came in at the exact same time with
on it that you guys did with [inaudible]
and with the same exact model,
selling directly to people getting the
very best shit you can possibly get.
What is the like forget about cost.
What is the best most imp?
Most nutrient dense foods?
Most nutrient dense supplements.
Let's figure out a way to get the best
stuff.
Find who's got the best protein powder?
Who's got the best?
Well it's cost prohibitive because of
this and the retail gets marked down.
Exactly.
That's the issue,
right?
Is like when you sell something to a
retailer,
like a Cabela's or something like that,
they tack on a bunch of money on him a
ton,
right?
Then make a lot more money than we did a
hundred percent so we've made money then
you guys,
no,
no.
I mean they tack on a hundred percent or
percent.
So a jacket I had produced for a hundred
I'd sell the Kybella is for 200 they
sell to you for 400 bucks.
Wow.
For putting on a coat hanger and thrown
it on a rack makes it convenient.
You know,
if you're like in a place and you need a
jacket and you left your jacket at home,
but it's,
it's a faulty model.
It doesn't make sense.
If you're a guy like you that does
research and knows exactly what he wants
and you can put a tape measure on
yourself and know how big you are.
I mean,
I'm roughly an xl and you could save
yourself money and get a better product.
It's a no brainer.
We'll also,
the amount of research that you can do,
like if you go to a store and you talked
to the guy that's behind the counter,
what do you know?
Times I've talked to people
like,
do you go to a place that sells car
parts or something like that and you
ask,
you got a question and he says something
that's totally wrong.
You're like,
well,
I know that's not right,
but if you don't know that and how the
fuck,
do you know where this goes or,
yeah.
I mean you have to be someone who's like
deeply,
deeply involved in the product to be
able to explain it to someone who
becomes obsessed.
Exactly.
Like if someone has like,
like your packs,
the way you guys engineer the carbon
frame your packs.
Like I spent like fucking hour and a
half the other night watching videos of
how you guys make pacts and Nicole.
Yeah.
The first thing he said right off the
bat is like,
we're going to pull the curtain back.
I'm going to tell everybody what
everybody has been afraid to tell
everybody.
I'm,
if,
if you educate the person to know what
they're looking at and you're building
the best stuff,
they'll end up back here and so he's
just like,
no one had ever said,
here's what fabrics we're using.
Here's where we're getting it.
Here's where our factory,
here's what we're doing.
I mean like competitors,
like are people going to seal it?
I don't care.
You build the best stuff and you sell it
at a good value for what you have to and
man.
Yeah.
So the whole transparency thing has been
incredible to watch and be in direct
where you can communicate directly with
your customers as you know,
it's so fricking powerful and they love
it and we're able to build so much
trust.
I mean,
we started,
I started blogging about Ku.
You 18 months before ever launched.
I talked about the fabrics and
materials,
a factories,
the process of building a company.
And I really did it just to keep my name
associated with the next brand.
As I left and transitioned out of the
Sitka,
I had no idea what it would create.
And it created this massive following.
People started engaging with me and
asking me questions and I was,
uh,
listen to their suggestions on products
and educated them on what great fabrics,
what great design was,
and they just ate it up and the consumer
loves it.
The retailer wasn't given it to them any
longer.
You know what,
back in the day,
I used to,
I grew up working at an archery shop in
orange,
California from Bob Fromm is really,
really amazing archery shop owner.
And he was the guy,
right?
I mean you walked in and said,
Bob,
what's the latest,
greatest stuff?
And he can tell you all about it.
You go to Cabela's now,
like you were saying,
the guy on the floor has no clue.
The customer knows more than the,
than the retailer now.
And you know,
by taking with cu,
you would go on directly that customer,
giving them all that information,
giving them the power to make the
decision,
they ate it up and then bail to be
involved them through this process.
You know,
they uh,
they just build a ton of trust with you.
It's like they understand,
they understand the brand,
they understand you,
they understand how you think and why
you're making those decisions.
And then they trust you.
And once you have the consumers trust
and you don't break it,
you know,
you can really build a brand off of
that.
Now.
Well,
a guy like me who loves to geek out on
shit too,
totally obsessed with things.
That's what I love,
that I can go and watch all these videos
and read all this stuff about all the
different engineering that's involved in
creating a product.
And when I do that,
it gets people more excited.
That's why I think it's a brilliant move
to blog about it in between the time of
building the company,
it was,
I mean I look back now and it's like
ahead of blueprint on how to a company
today.
When we did that,
I look back and read the blog posts and
I looked and I just go,
wow,
I can't believe I actually did that
without really knowing I was doing.
Cause it seems like an execute it so
perfectly.
And I was just following my gut and
interacting with,
with the customers.
And it was,
it was so,
so powerful and such a big thing because
as I built this business model,
which is the first of its kind in this
industry,
and even the outdoor market people told
me,
cool idea,
but how are they going to find you?
How are they trust you to buy your
product to begin with?
How are you going to get customers
before soon enough before so you don't
go a business and run out of money?
Because so many companies will go create
a website launch and no one knows about
it,
right?
Well how do you,
how do you create that interest in
advance?
Um,
and create the demand?
We can spend a ton of money.
You look at like a warby parker or a
hairy shave or dollar shave club,
will they spend more money than they're
bringing in and they're burning cash?
Like it's going out of style to create
demand through high levels of marketing
that's very,
very expensive.
Or you can do it like we didn't educate
the customer and,
and be transparent,
build trust in advance and then launch.
And then you've got your best sales
force in the world,
which is your customer base because they
don't understand everything about your
brand.
You guys have this advantage in that
hunting w because it's such a difficult
pursuit because it's sort of gets in
your DNA,
you become obsessed with it.
And when you become obsessed with it and
you find a company that's also obsessed
with making the very best shape
possible,
and then you guys geek out to such a
high level on the videos and on the
these descriptions of what you're
making,
then then these obsessed people become
obsessed with what you're doing.
And they go,
oh,
well if I'm going to do this right,
I got to do this this way.
They do.
And uh,
it,
and it's great.
I mean,
people we meet and hunters we meet in
or,
or a hunting camp or traveling.
I mean they,
it's amazing to me how much they know
about a product and how much to know
about the brand.
I mean they are,
like you said,
they geek out on it and eat all the
little details up and which I love
because that's what I geek out on when
I'm searching for these amazing fabrics
and learning about new technologies and
they share it.
These people eat it up,
they love it.
Well it's really a,
a sort of a master class in how to do
things the right way to foul passion and
being obsessed with something but doing
it to the utmost.
Because if you do that then the word
gets out,
the word gets out,
people talk about it.
And like I said,
I found out about you guys through word
of mouth completely.
Well if you're actually doing it too,
I mean like the customers really see
that,
you know,
like you know,
no one else that's running a company.
This,
I mean,
you know,
multiple haunts every year.
Big study like believes in what he,
what,
what we're building and takes it to the
places that the are at.
Worst place our customers could ever go
and use it and people respect that they
love,
they don't like that.
Not only that,
that's what I wanna do,
but I know that,
you know,
he's already,
he's done it to we,
you know,
we've,
we've used that stuff in those places.
What was it your blog that I read,
which,
which blog was it where you guys were
sucking water out of the top of a rock?
It was one of the blogs for your
company.
One of the early on blogs you guys went
on a hunt and uh,
you,
you were just talking in depth about all
the different,
I don't know who,
who was a wrote it,
but it was all cool.
You stuff.
We were talking in depth about testing
out the products on these like really
remote back country hunts.
Yup.
Yeah.
I mean that's how we figured out the
shortcomings of our product.
You can look at all the laboratory data,
you can look at all the test results of,
of what that's getting back to you,
but you really don't know until you put
it in the conditions that we put it in.
And we've like Toray who is my main
fabric supplier.
This is the most innovative jap.
I mean they are the,
the bomb as far as technical fabrics go
and it's,
is Japanese the Japanese by culture
build the best fabrics in the world?
What do they,
what are they putting in them?
Cause like you guys use a lot of
synthetics,
right?
They do.
I mean they're,
so their quality standards in Japan are
much higher than anywhere else in the
world and they have a really high
quality standard of the raw material.
Then they have a really high quality
standard of the actual yarn and then
they've figured out how to make their
yard stretch and recover with no
elastic.
It's why our stuff so light.
But because of that process and because
of their high quality standards are
incredibly expensive.
Um,
but the Japanese just by their,
their,
their nature and their culture,
they don't do things that cut corners.
You look at the building of a Samurai
sword is a great example.
There is a lot easier ways to build a
sword that a Samurai does.
The Samurai sword is built.
I mean it takes a lot of time.
A lot of patients and it's perfect.
I got one over there from 15,
11.
So you know it right?
Yeah,
that one sitting on the jam.
Real one.
It's the way the Japanese do things and
it's the same way of why they produce
such amazing fabrics and materials and
they're continuously pushing the bar as
far as innovation,
reducing weight.
And it's a partner for us.
That's just amazing.
I found Toray well before I started q
you I couldn't,
I tried to build a Tory product line
with Sitka and it was just price
prohibitive.
I took it to a couple of buyers at
Cabela's,
um,
when at shields sports and they said
beautiful way too expensive.
So what are they doing to make this
stuff so light?
And like it stretches a little bit in it
and it snaps back,
but it's very light.
And so they have a patent on how they
make the yard is called Pram flex yarn.
And if you look under a microscope,
it looks like a spring.
Right?
And so it can stretch out and then
recover without any elastic.
Everybody else has to put spandex or
elastic or Lycra in their fabrics and
lastic super heavy.
It holds moisture and it's also,
you know,
with stretches and doesn't really
recover until you wash it.
Again.
If you were a PA,
a stretch pair of pants with a lot of
lasted,
they can kind of saggy after a period of
time.
You notice with ours they'll fit the
exact same way on day 10 as they did on
day one because of their fabric,
because of how they make the year on the
stretches recover that last.
So why are they making this fabric too?
This is like who are these crazy people
that are out there like super
engineering fabric,
so Japanese and they'll sell it into
Japanese market.
They'll pay for performance,
their pricing on their performance.
Apparel is much higher in Japan,
the European market as well for their
climbing industry.
And some of the ski brands run their,
their uh,
fabrics as well.
Um,
but it's,
nobody's really introduced their product
line like we have the United States
cause it's been cost prohibitive to up
and Teleco,
you business model came out.
So they just decided to essentially the
same thing that you guys are doing.
Just figure out what is the best way to
do this.
It's how they do it.
Yeah.
And there I am,
Tory has ended or as a company,
as a Japanese conglomerate,
which is pretty typical of Japanese
companies and their,
their base,
there's the start of their company was
chemistry.
So there are chemistry based company
that makes chemicals and make carbon
fiber,
but it's chemistry that starts of with
everything they do and understanding how
everything is produced and made and it's
that foundation allows them to,
to put out these amazing innovations to
figure out nanotechnology and how to
waterproof a down feather,
how to make membranes that brief two and
a half times that of Gortex and still
stretch and recover in a more durable,
it's that foundation of who Tory is,
is a chemistry company that allows them
to push these innovations out and then
you add in the Japanese culture of
perfection and making things correct and
having processes that continue to
produce high quality products and
materials over time.
And that's why Toray is so fricking
amazing.
I dork out over shit like,
oh it's so cool.
I just love when someone's trying to
figure out a way to engineer something
to the very finest edge they do.
And then what's great about them is
always pushing.
And so they're coming to us with new
fabric innovations,
new technologies and innovation and
we're able to find their limits because
of our customers and what they use it
for.
And I'm able to go back to their
engineers now cause I've developed a
really big relationship with them where
they are now their largest customer in
the world and worked directly with their
team and say,
hey guys,
your membrane works great except for
these certain situations.
For instance,
they go and they try to figure out how
to run it by that and they will.
Yeah,
I mean they'll commit themselves to
fixing issues that we'll find.
The laboratory tests say they shouldn't
ever fail and we'll find the limits of
it.
I mean,
not necessarily Brendan,
I,
but our guides,
they're spending 200 250 days of their
life every year in the mountains.
They'll come back and say,
hey,
guess what,
this happened in this situation as rare
but lets us go back to the,
their,
their development team and say,
hey,
we found limits on this thing.
And there they listen and they go back
and try to re engineer it to figure out
how to push the bar further.
So those,
those failures don't have,
I was listening to on a podcast
recently,
we were talking about this new
engineering that you're doing on your
packs and how you're testing them.
So like when you,
when you have a new product,
we'll say if you create a new pack or
something like that and you,
before you bring it to market,
do you get it to guides?
Do you have them tested?
Do you test it yourself exclusively?
Yeah,
so it starts as a process in house and
we'll put it through a certain tests
depending on the product.
Like the pack new pack frame we just
introduced today earlier.
It could you live,
I don't know if he just happened to see
my live presentation for now.
Flight down here.
Um,
so you,
you do a live presentation like a
product and you did that today.
Yeah.
Kind of like a keynote thing like jobs
does.
That's hilarious.
I was doing that with hunting.
Nobody,
you guys are savages not doing them.
I'm excited about this.
Not It,
not doing it well.
So you,
you,
you have this product launch and um,
so what did you,
what did you launch?
What is it?
Well,
we introduced a new carbon fiber
technology that just came out on the
market a couple of years ago.
Introduced as far as ability to start
developing product with a new fiber
technology called spread tow carbon
fiber.
You'll love this because you keep you
out and stuff like this.
So carbon fiber,
traditionally the fibers are putting the
yarn,
right?
So they take each individual carbon
fiber,
group them together and make a yarn.
Those yarns are then woven into fabric.
It's what you see of typical carbon
fiber look,
right?
The woven,
uh,
the web and look you see on carbon fiber
what spread toe is instead of round
fibers.
They've figured out that if you flatten
the fibers out,
so instead of being round,
they're flat and instead of weaving
them,
they lay them next to each other and
then so they run so lines across it,
which you can see in our new frame.
And by doing so when you mold it into a
product,
because that fiber is now completely
flat and it's running the length of the,
of the product,
it's much stiffer and stronger than if
you weave it in a has the fiber has to
go up and over other fibers is not as
stiff,
not as strong in the performance level.
You give up quite a bit compared to
spread to spread toes,
all directional fibers.
And then what we've done in our frame is
we now can determine exactly how many
fibers run from the top of the frame to
the bottom of the frame.
And then we,
the fibers of course,
and then lay in on a 45 how much
stiffness we want and flex we want on
the horizontal axis.
So do you want our packs?
You'll,
you'll notice that it carries a load
really well because the vertical
stiffness,
but it's also comfortable like an
internal pack because of how much fiber
we have running on the horizontal access
that controls that flex.
So you want to have a certain amount of
flex?
Yes.
Have to.
But you got to figure out what that
amount is.
And the way to figure that out is by
testing.
We went through 18 versions of our frame
to get to where the formula is that we
now and re reintroduce today.
That's fucking hilarious.
Who does that?
I do work fiber engineers and with our
development team,
Sean and in our office does,
is there any other companies is going
through 18 different versions of a
carbon fiber frame in order to figure
the only one in the world that produces
one.
So it's probably just us.
I've got a patent on our frame design.
I know what carbon fiber is,
but I don't know what carbon fiber is.
You know what I'm saying?
Like my car has,
oh look at this Jamie.
Yeah.
On the ball to killing it.
Jamie's always on the ball.
Um,
so it's a cloth.
I mean it's soft,
it's pliable.
Um,
how does it,
because I have a porsche nine 11 gt,
three Rs that has a carbon fiber rear
wing.
And I'm also like,
it looks bad ass,
but what the fuck is that?
Stay down as a fiber and then you put it
to clock in it.
And that's what connects.
So the epoxy,
so it starts out as a co,
a carbon cloth.
It is pure cloth.
You could feel it,
flexes moves just like the cloth and
okay,
here it is.
This is what it looks as at fabric.
So that spread toe there in a
bi-directional format.
And then from there you turn that
somehow or another into this really hard
stuff with a heat activated resin.
So you saw,
if you go back to the mold with a frame
where lane in there,
um,
right there.
So we're laying that into a,
into a mold.
So we have a bottom molds,
aluminum cut and a top mold.
And we laid that fiber in and the way
he's doing is applying the resin.
And then we'll put the top mold on top.
And then we add a ton of pressure for
you.
How many thousands of pounds of pressure
gets put on top of it and add heat and
time and over.
I think it takes in that little over an
hour,
we will cure that mold or that that
resin into a actual part.
And that becomes our frame.
And one is the advantage of that over
like say any other very stiff or durable
material.
It's half the weight of aluminum.
It's twice as strong as steel and then
by twice as strongest deal.
It is amazing.
It's amazing material and one and then
also how we engineer the mold.
And a big part of the engineering
process of this is understanding how far
apart you separate the fibers create
stiffness.
So we have foam in between the carbon
fibers and them center portion of the
frame that that full uh,
that phone crates and what what they
called modulates,
which is a separation of the fibers.
And that modulates,
creates the overall stiffness within the
center portion of our frame.
And then how much of that we have within
the frame determines how much flex
stiffness.
And then also where we're putting the
fibers and how many,
so there's a lot to it.
The weak point of carbon is the epoxy,
the carbons,
the strongest part.
And so the new spread toe,
what it does is it,
it makes it tighter.
Smaller,
yeah.
Less.
Less epoxy.
Yep.
And so when we got out spread toe,
which who does introduced for no weight
penalty,
we now have a frame that's five times
different,
stronger than what we had previous,
which is still a really good performing
product and we just got five times
better.
That's insane,
isn't it?
And so when,
when you say five times different,
stronger,
how do you know,
is there a too stiff or is it not a
stiffness issue?
It's a flex issue.
Is there,
there,
is there a difference here?
I mean there is and it's a challenge,
right?
It's finding that perfect balance and
you can do that with carbon.
You can't do that with a steel or
aluminum frame pack and you really can't
do that with any other pack frame
design,
which is usually some sort of plastic
sheeting with aluminum stays put in.
The flex is kind of there,
you can add more lumens stays,
but then still is an aluminum stay.
It's the people who listen to this and
understand what's aluminum bar
essentially.
And you can kind of mold in a curve or
whatever and it's sewn to a piece of
plastic,
shoved down the back part of it.
Like an internal frame backpack
has some sort of support,
stiffness,
rigidity.
It's what will pull the weight off
somebody's shoulders that it will help
carry that load versus just a Duffel bag
strapped to your back,
which is uncomfortable as you know.
Well that's where the,
the,
the interesting aspect of the
engineering comes in when it comes to
packs because,
uh,
the same weight with a different pack
feels different.
Totally different.
And that's something that I think a lot
of people are not aware of.
Like you think,
oh,
she carrying a hundred pounds on your
back.
You're carrying a hundred pounds on your
No,
no,
no.
It's,
it's depended entirely upon the
ergonomics,
how it sets on your body.
It does.
And geometry of how that loads
transferred onto your back and the
frame.
And,
and balancing it.
There's a lot to it.
And you know,
in the past,
before our frame came to market,
you either had really stiff frames with
external frame packs and metal or
aluminum.
And then you have this internal frame
which was really comfortable until you
had put weight in it and then it would
wouldn't be stiff Neth and it would end
up putting a lot of pressure and weight
on your shoulders and your hips.
So how,
how do you engineer that?
Do you have to try it out?
Do you have to like take one of these
packs and,
and wear it on a long back country hunt
and they say,
okay,
here's some,
I got a little bit too much weight on my
shoulder,
a little bit too much weight on my hip
or how do you,
how do you discern?
That's essentially that I do a lot of
workouts with weight on my back and a
pack on a treadmill.
Um,
so I'm able,
I'd spend a ton of time in our packs
with various weights and we do that.
Um,
a lot of guys in our office do as well
as,
as well as my uh,
my pack developer,
Shawn and Brendan.
And then we,
once we feel like we're really close,
we then ship them out to Brendan's guys
a bunch of guides and say test it for
us.
But through your world and what you're
using it for,
I mean one of the challenges we have
with our,
with our industry and backpacks is this
huge as you know,
this huge swing of weight.
Yeah.
Cause once we get something down we've
got to get all that out.
So we're going to go from maybe packing
them with 50 or 60 pound back to all
sudden now you've got 100 plus pound
load and need to manage that.
So how do you get a pack that can do
both,
be comfortable with lighter weights and
still have the ability to carry heavy
weights?
It's an engineering problem and it's
also an engineering problem that's
handled to a bunch of different ways.
Like some people pack it inside the bag,
some people the,
the pack separates from the frame.
You pack the meat to your body.
And then put the pack,
the rest of the pack,
strap that down on top of the frame.
How do you decide how to handle that?
Just trial and error as well.
You want the weight closest to your
back,
you can get the better it is and it is
the closest you can get it like flatter
to your back as well.
Like you don't,
you don't want it like bulging out,
right?
Like if you have a large,
yeah.
If you have a hundred pounds and it's
sitting in a two foot square,
the lower part of your back that's not
nearly as good as like flattened out to
six inches and going over the entire
section,
you're going to spread that out,
up and down the frame as close to the
frame of your back as possible.
And how,
where do you,
where do you make it sit on your
shoulders?
How are you strapping it in to make sure
that it's in the right place or you want
to carry the majority of the route with
your hips?
So,
I mean you
start at the waist to put it all in and
then shoulder straps,
all that kind of stuff and stand up and
then your,
your load lifters and all the way up.
But I mean you want it,
I mean it's individual thing,
how how it fits.
But you want to start with,
I mean your hips or your strongest,
your center of gravity,
that's,
that's where you want the majority of
the weight to be carried as close as you
can.
And this is all trial and error stuff
that's been done through mountaineering.
Throw these different guys that are
going on these long backpack hikes.
Yeah it is.
And then it's,
it's fit.
And also,
I mean it's critical that you have the
pack that fits correctly.
Most people have a pack that isn't set
up correct.
And we found that with our pacs are
really easy to adjust shoulder straps so
we can get a perfect fit for each
customer.
And we put an instructional video out
there of making sure the geometry from
your load lifters,
which are the straps that come off the
top of the pack down to your shoulder
straps that geometry has to,
is critical that it's perfect and it has
to be at a 45 degree angle that will
help take that load off your shoulders
and transfer to your hips and help you
manage that weight comfortably over a
long period of time.
So you need like geometry,
you need like you need like a triangle
set up to make sure it's where this is
where the whole bubble thing doesn't
come in real life.
Exactly.
That's why there's a lot,
I mean it starts at mathematics with the
frame and designs and cad and CNC
machines and all that and the math and
all through it.
And then it goes all the way through and
you build it and then all of a sudden,
you know,
it's,
and then it requires testing and,
and,
and taking it,
you know,
in real life settings and,
and,
and people vary on what they like.
I mean there's some guys like to carry
see things a certain way.
Some people like fit,
you know,
some guys like their pack way up high.
I've,
I've fitted guys that like him.
I mean you can only know by,
by,
by testing it,
by doing it,
by carrying some weight and how many
different products are you individually
overseeing and c.
Dot.
Is that,
that's the most daunting aspect of it
because you've got all this different
shit going on at the same time.
And on top of that you're doing a dozen
hunts a year plus and you're,
you're,
you're out there in the field.
Like how the fuck do you find the time
to do all this?
Well,
you know,
it's interesting when you,
when you do something you love and you
have a huge passion for it.
I never stopped working.
I mean I work second,
I get up in the morning until the time I
go to bed.
If I'm not sitting in front of my
computer working on stuff specific for q
you,
I'm thinking about it and that's,
it doesn't feel like it's a lot of work.
Although I look back now and go,
fuck,
it has a lot of work.
We found some amazing products.
Um,
and you know,
it's just,
it's a process and it's solving problems
through finding materials and
technologies and the designs it solve
those problems.
There's a lot to be solved and hunting.
Fortunately it was a big gap from afar.
Brendan pull that sucker up,
close a big gap from,
you know,
some of the other industries are out
there before Sitka and could use come
along.
So there was a lot of work to do and
we've done a lot to take from where
hunting apparel and gear was back in
2004 to where it is today in 2016 is a
massive change.
And not everything's as in depth as the
pack all the way from start to finish.
I mean,
sometimes you have great fit on
something and you have a new fabric.
Well,
you know,
I mean how it,
it's got to get tested.
You got to
see how you like it.
But it's not like 18 models of,
you know,
when you get a superior breathing,
some,
you know,
it's not all as in depth as added to.
It's a lot of it's plugging in the right
product to the right fit and then you
have,
you have a winner right off the bat.
Well I think,
uh,
what you were saying about the amount of
work,
this is also like how we were saying
that hunting isn't really a sport.
Like it gets called a sport.
It's sort of its own thing.
Work is sort of its own thing too
because you can call it,
you can call it work,
but if you love something,
it's not really work.
Like showing up at the garbage depo and,
or the garbage dump and picking up cans,
garbage.
I guess you could love garbage.
There's some,
yeah,
some guy out there screaming
kill it and garbage.
Yeah.
When you find something that you become
obsessed with,
that becomes a passion.
It's like it's a puzzle.
It's,
it's,
it's just like you're doing it again,
a game all day,
almost there.
And it's also in a lot of ways in art
forum did I tell you what brand building
to be as fascinating and it is an art
form and there's no science,
there's no blueprint.
This is how you build this brand and I
think it's the most fascinating work
I've ever done.
It's truly figuring out a craft brand
building is a craft well and never
stops.
You never stop learning from it every
day.
I mean you live it and breathe it every
Yeah,
it reflects you guys.
I mean that's one of the things that
I've found interesting about this.
It's like you can kind of see when
there's someone like you that's at the
head of something like this and you're
this driven focus guy,
you kind of see that when you,
when you see the,
the,
the actual brand itself,
it reflects you.
So this idea of like it being work,
it's really like a passion project.
It is.
It truly is.
Everything from the product to the brand
building to the videos,
to the imagery.
I mean,
I've got my hands in everything and I'm
super particular about the way our image
is presented to the marketplace.
It's got to have it.
I can feel,
I always tell people I can,
I can feel it,
I can taste it,
I can smell it.
Everything was cool.
Well that's a one of the beautiful
things about having a very small center
of operation.
Like you guys deciding how this goes
down.
You don't have to meet with a giant
board of,
you know,
a bunch of different people.
You're not a public company.
You don't,
you don't have to,
there's nobody there to water down the
cheerios.
Does that mean that it's not a democracy
down the cheerios?
I always say everyday it's a
dictatorship.
Yeah.
You know,
it Kinda is and it works well that way.
And you know,
it's interesting cause we get,
you know,
we've,
because of our growth and because of our
business model,
we have,
we approached all the time by private
equity of estimate groups throwing huge
valuations of money at me.
And I'm just,
uh,
just when I look at the opportunity,
yeah,
it's a lot of money.
But I don't want to change what we've
got.
Right.
You know,
as soon as I bring in outside capital or
profession professionals and look in the
business,
they're like,
well,
you need to professionalize.
Like for who?
Right?
What does that mean?
What does professional my
team,
right,
exactly.
Well,
you need a CFO.
You need a cmo.
You need to see,
oh,
I'm like for,
for what?
Right?
So we can slow down our process so we
can change the culture.
That's built a really special,
unique company.
Some bunch of other people give pieces
of the pie away.
It's just such a broken traditional
model as far as growing a business and
we're doing it just the opposite to,
same thing with podcasting.
There's a broken model that's,
there's a lot of podcasters today that
are joining in with these gigantic
networks and they think that being a
part of a network is like being on NBC
or being on CBS,
which it used to be a big deal back in
the day.
Like if you were running,
doing a play and NBC came along and
said,
we want to turn that play into a sitcom.
He be like,
we fucking made it.
Yeah.
But now if you have a successful podcast
and someone comes along and says,
Hey,
we would love you to be a part of our
gigantic corporation.
Like get the fuck Outta here.
We gotta run.
We got to run away from these guys.
They're going to ruin everything.
They can.
They will.
They'll come in,
they'll tell you what to do.
They'll tell you what you can't do.
No more cussing,
no more cussing for short.
You can't bounce around and you got to
pick your,
you gotta pick your topics,
your you're way too spaced out.
What is,
what is water down?
The cheerio is even fucking mean it.
You certainly can't cover hunting.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's was way too excited about twice a
week.
I mean,
I cam hangs on a Monday and you guys on
this way,
it's,
I just don't,
I don't think you should do anything
other than what you want to do.
I think if you could live the best life,
it's like what?
What actually interests you?
What do you actually enjoy doing?
We'll do that.
Is it possible all the time?
No,
you're going to,
there's some obligations you're going to
have to have.
There's a such family stuff,
work stuff,
business stuff.
There's stuff,
stuff you have to deal with,
but do what you want to do the most that
you can do it.
Absolutely.
I always say,
if you can be an expert in something you
love,
you can find a way to make a living in.
I mean,
Brendan's a perfect example.
He freaking loves hunting and he lives
and breathes it.
Studies it.
Look where he is now.
Well,
when I met Brendan,
I met him this past weekend in Bozeman,
and one of the things that struck me is
when you and I were talking,
you have this fucking crazy fire in your
eyes.
You're like,
I want it to be the guy that kills the
biggest bowl every year.
And when I killed one big bowl,
I didn't want it to just be like,
oh,
it was just a fluke.
When now you gotta be consistent.
And I was like,
all right,
this crazy motherfucker.
I see where he's at.
And then when you told me that you had
this gigantic bull down in sneeze,
which is a store on main street in
Bozeman,
I went to the store just to see that
bowl.
I was like,
we've got to stop it.
And I gotta,
I gotta take a look at this thing.
And this is elk that looks like
something out of the Lord of the rings
that doesn't even look like a real
animal.
It's breathtaking.
It's fucking mass,
isn't it?
I mean,
as you walk up to that thing and you
look at it and you literally stopped
shooting attracts explained the weight
of the antlers on that thing.
So I mean,
that's obviously an unusually big,
I mean,
most delk,
given their whole lifespan,
we'll never achieve that.
It's a truly special al can like,
and people like it.
Not just a number,
but I mean it is a Shaquille o'neal of
elk.
That's what it is.
It's that rare and a,
yeah,
the horn.
When when the skull plates sought off,
we'd 54 pounds.
She's a,
so it,
which is to answer,
I mean it's,
it's heavy and John like unusually big.
They're just,
it just mass,
you know,
it was the biggest sell killed in 30
years and stay state Montana.
So it was neon.
Would it look like when it was alive?
Right
away on the huffy thing,
uh,
you know,
a big bull elk will be six to 700
pounds.
Mean they get thrown a thousand pounds a
lot.
But have,
you know,
to wait,
I'm like,
there are a few great big bowls at a
way.
1,000.
It was a thousand pounder.
He was 12 years old,
you know,
he was a,
you're just a monster,
you know.
So the,
the Roosevelt elk,
so the ones that have the biggest
bodies,
right.
The Roosevelt elk have the,
by far the biggest bodies.
Yeah.
But not,
not the biggest,
not the biggest antlers.
Like how big of their bodies get 1200.
It's a really big bulls.
I mean,
you can see in photos of them,
they're just enormous.
I mean,
they are unusually giant.
especially the really big bull,
you know,
and a con,
like not every elk is huge.
I mean,
right.
An old bowl who's had good feed and
lived a long time and was genetically
big to begin with,
we'll be really big.
I mean they're not,
they don't all end up huge,
you know,
they're
just the ones he hunts.
You have,
what's a fascinating pursuit,
you know,
pursuing the,
the,
the apex of the genetics,
you know,
finding the animal.
And it's also one of the things that's
important about this,
like the pursuit of hunting is that this
animal that you shot was probably like
me.
How old do you think he was?
He was 12 years old and that is an old,
old l that is,
that's old age in the world of wild
beasts.
It's the ultimate,
I mean like when you get to the level
where you're consistently killing stuff
and,
and you're,
you know,
you've gotten to the point that the
ultimate level is to kill the biggest,
oldest,
most mature,
you know,
historically significant.
Went on that on a chain of events,
in history of like,
all the guys I've ever killed elk mean,
not ll card design are going to be huge.
But with any animals like when you kill
something is super old,
super big,
super smart.
That is the pinnacle of where your
skills have gotten in,
in a lot of people never get there,
you know,
based on,
they don't have time.
I mean the biggest,
the biggest factor in kill in doing that
and getting to that point is having the
time,
you know,
just just having the time to,
I spent a decade of my life putting a
blue track everywhere.
You could put one finding where every
alk was in my state and looking for the
biggest ones.
I mean it is like,
like the work,
it's consuming you.
You have to love to do it.
It's not fun.
You would just have to be driven to do
it,
to,
to want to want to be able to do it.
But the result is fun.
I mean that the photo that you sent and
he sent me some text messages,
photos of that thing on the ground.
You see the size of the antlers?
No,
that's another one.
That's another one he shot.
Do you?
That's a pretty big one too.
But that's not nearly as big as the one
you want me to send a t?
Jamie,
I'll send it to you,
Jamie.
Um,
should I email it to you?
Either way.
Okay.
Um,
the,
and that was,
you know,
at the,
at that point in time,
actually when I killed that elk,
I wasn't at the skill set I am now.
I mean,
I got pretty lucky that was a third El
cobre killed right place the right time,
did the right thing and you know,
just lit a fire in me.
Like I want to do that more.
Yeah,
that's ridiculous that that was the
third
first started talking to Brenda about
hunting elk.
He would hunt elk and that was so
different for me.
I mean,
I was just trying to find a boulder
hunt,
any bull,
and I would try to get a good one,
but Brendan would hunt and find Anelka
and spend the entire season trying to
kill that single up,
which I thought,
at least my experience,
they'll kind of was fine.
Hard to find that same aisle twice that
I'd maybe see in the morning and I would
never see it again.
Britain had the ability to hunt it down
and kill it.
Well,
it's also the best thing from a
conservation standpoint,
you're talking about an animal that has
spread its genes for at least 10 years.
Right.
For 10 years,
that thing has been spreading those
superior genetics and it's probably been
forced in a lot of other males to get
the fuck off the mountain.
I mean,
when would me,
yeah,
that one did.
I never saw,
I watched him for three days morning and
night before I killed them and he knew
another bull never came near that thing.
You have to beat Brock Lesner of elk
or Alistair overeem.
Yeah,
exactly.
When you're going to a old like ubering
old allister.
Yeah,
allister still on the Mexican
supplements.
Yeah.
The new house,
there might be a better fighter.
Actually.
It's interesting,
uh,
when you see an animal like that and
you,
you realize how difficult it is to reach
12 years of age in the wild with
mountain lions,
wolves.
I mean,
Montana,
it's like he's just got everything after
I'm grizzlies,
everything's after him.
And to be able to be that smart,
to get to this position in life and for
you to solve that puzzle and to get in
and shoot that elk,
that's,
that's one of the things that sort of
embodies the,
the divide,
really intense difficulty in hunting.
It's,
it's one of those things where,
I mean,
it,
it's the ultimate challenge.
I mean,
once you've,
you know,
killed a bunch of elk and you know,
I mean,
it gets to where it is the ultimate
challenge and you're not always going to
win.
I don't always get them.
I mean,
that's,
that's the beauty of it.
I mean,
like you never get to the point where
you're so good.
Well,
I haven't got to the point where I'm so
good where every great big one I get.
I mean,
I,
it's getting there,
I'm getting closer.
But they do,
you know,
like you're learning stuff all the time
and it's one of those things nobody can
tell you about you.
You can't,
you know,
I'm,
I'm basically self taught.
My Dad taught,
taught me how to read maps and until you
figure out,
you know,
why isn't elk here?
What,
what's he doing?
You know,
and not just wandering around like,
oh,
there's some elk over there,
but like,
why is he here?
Why would he be here this time of year?
What is he doing?
Where's he going?
What's his next move?
Like,
I mean,
I've had bulls where I've hunted where I
know what they're going to do before
they do a little worry.
I know what that,
that bowl was down here.
He was doing this and I was like,
I think I know what he's gonna do.
And I go the other direction,
come around the other way.
And that's what he did.
I knew before he was going to do it.
Um,
it just,
it just comes from watching them
spending thousands of hours and tis data
chunking.
Yeah.
And I mean,
you,
you see the picture of the great big
bowls and it's,
that's,
that's great.
But there is worth the time,
the time that goes into that you'd like
nobody ever sees and they don't see
hundreds and hundreds of days in
between.
Um,
yeah,
I was a young guy there,
man.
2022 years old there.
It's amazing.
Yeah,
it is.
It is amazing.
And when you eat that animal,
I mean the amount of satisfaction that
comes from sitting down to a meal that
you procured and the most difficult way
humanly possible.
I mean,
shot the thing with a bow and Arrow in
the mountains and now here you are
eating it.
12 yards snuck right upon.
Yeah.
It's cool.
I mean the,
the,
the thing about trophy hunting that's
not understood.
It's like,
it's the ultimate,
it's the pinnacle of combining,
you know,
what you love to do and then this
incredible skill set that you're
developing to be better than,
you know,
I'm not saying better than anybody else,
but it takes a lot of work,
like better than you used to be.
Better than you used to eat to get
better and better.
Yeah.
And,
and you know,
the funny thing to me is always like
the,
the thing trophy hunting has got this
weird stigma with it or whatever.
And it's like,
man,
I mean,
I eat the whole elk.
I love doing it.
I love the challenge of it.
I don't,
you know,
I don't shy away from saying I love to
kill animals.
I mean like,
I love to hunt them.
I love the challenge of,
you know,
take,
of getting the biggest one.
I find it the most challenging thing
I've ever done,
but,
um,
you don't,
I always eat it.
I eat everything and you know,
and,
and I take the hide and the head,
I mean,
I'm using more than most people are,
you know,
people like I just trophy hunting and
where be like,
hmm,
that's,
it's,
it,
it's the challenge.
I was,
I mean,
the term needs to be changed.
It's the challenge of it.
Well,
the term is kind of screwed up because
it's applied to things that people shoot
where they don't need it.
And which seems to be like a cruelty,
like a,
a pursuit,
a vain pursuit of going out and shooting
lions and shooting things.
You're not going to eat.
The weird thing about that is I was,
I was talking to a guy was doing an
article for the New York Times and he's,
he said,
I don't have a problem with people with
hunting,
you know,
as long as you eat it.
And I just said,
you don't have a problem with hunting.
I mean,
it's,
you legally have to take the meat.
Um,
I mean,
the amount of people that would shoot
something and not take the meat is,
is the same as people that are thieves
out on the street.
I mean,
it's so uncommon.
So like the perception of,
you know,
guys just shooting it and you know,
just because 10 years down the road,
all I have in my garage as the head
doesn't mean that I didn't use it.
And so the perception,
again,
against the lowest common denominator
guy,
you hear about one horrible thing going
on or somebody that doesn't take the
meat and all of a sudden it's
everybody's lumped into it.
I mean,
I grew up in rural Montana.
I never had a beef steak at a restaurant
until I was on a recruiting trip in
college.
I mean,
I grew up eating wild game my entire
life.
I never had my parents never bought meat
ever.
That's probably why he's such a good
wrestler.
Yeah,
I guess,
right.
Get that fucking tear protein kicked
that wild
DNA in your system.
Free Range.
Organic.
Yeah.
That's,
that's the real food.
But it's like a disconnect.
They don't understand like,
oh man that you,
you know,
like you don't need to do that.
It's like I'm not saying we didn't need
to do it.
That's just what we did.
I mean,
I grew up in an area where that's,
that's what we,
that's what I ate.
I don't,
like I said,
I never,
my parents never bought meat.
Yeah.
The math section of hunting today,
so screwed up.
It is,
but it's also because of cities.
I mean,
one of the things that's made us be able
to be so comfortable and have air
conditioning is technology and
advancement,
but it's also allowed us to be
completely disconnected from where food
comes from.
And that's what allows people to stand
up on these pedestals and point down at
people that they think are doing
something wrong.
When they're responsible for just as
much death.
They're responsible for more suffering.
More suffer.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
More suffering than hunters for sure.
Absolutely.
But just as much death too.
And even people that are vegetarians,
even people that are,
they think that by eating vegetables and
plants that they're doing no harm.
The amount of wildlife habitat
displacement that takes place in just
growing Kale is ridiculous.
And all the pesticides and everything
else that goes into it,
it's my knees and the fucking rodents
and all the different death that is
associated with combines and widescale a
grain,
uh,
when you're,
when you're a growing and harvesting
grain,
he does so much death and vulnerable and
there's no getting around that.
I mean,
we are consumers in some sort of a weird
way,
but to me the purest pursuit of it is
what you're talking about.
Archery hunting in the backwoods in the
most difficult environments.
I mean,
it is unbelievably difficult pursuit
that somehow or another it gets lumped
into this idea that it's a bunch of dumb
people in their cruel.
If you're dumb,
you're not going to be successful doing
that.
And if you're lazy,
you're not going to be successful.
You just not.
Yeah,
the,
I mean I've been,
uh,
because a coup,
you had been in New York during a bunch
of media tours over the last year and to
be interviewed by these people that live
in a big city that have no idea of what
hunting is like or what it's about is
really mind blowing to me because it's
been such a big part of my life and
everyone I'm associated with and friends
with typically Hans or understands
hunting,
their perception of it is so amazing to
me that we would just kill an animal,
cut its head off and leave everything.
I don't know anybody that's ever done
it.
It's completely illegal.
And,
but that's what mainstream media is made
out,
hunting,
hunting to be.
And it's like a mission of mine now to
change that perception.
And mine as well.
It's,
it's a lazy,
it's a lazy perception of it.
It's not real.
It doesn't happen.
Not,
not for real hunting.
No.
It absolutely does.
Never happens.
Yeah.
I mean like this New York Times.
I was just like,
yeah,
it's it,
you know,
I took them through like the wanton
waste laws and all that and he was just
like,
he's like,
wow,
that,
I mean you,
you legally have to take it.
Like it's not,
it's not something that's new,
you know,
like it's,
it's always been that way.
And then there is this cool meet
movement that's been going on.
But you know,
one thing it's like,
don't get it lost that,
you know,
guys in the 60s,
seventies all,
you know,
since,
aside from market hunting back in the
day,
which isn't real hunting,
it was just extermination for,
but I mean,
it's,
you know,
people hunt and they consume what they
eat.
Like anything else,
just like eating bread or any,
anything else?
I mean,
you have,
you know,
it's like,
you've got studs in your house.
They came from a tree.
It's where they came from.
Yeah,
exactly.
Um,
I always say if you want to fix the
health problems,
the United States make everybody hunt.
The problem is none of the animals,
there's too many people.
And then to find those,
but it's like obesity,
overweight,
you know,
poor diet,
make them all hunters.
That all goes away.
It does all go away cause they have to
live a lifestyle to actually harvest an
animal.
Yeah.
To change everything in hunting.
You know,
I mean,
God,
it's been our DNA for 2 million years
and just the last hundred that people
had an issue with it.
Not actually the last 50.
Yeah,
it's,
well it's when you see things like the
cecil the lion thing,
and then everybody gets up at arms about
hunting and it just becomes this,
this really distorted version of what it
actually is.
Yeah.
But this stuff with Cecil,
that's not even true.
I mean,
it wasn't,
you know,
he wasn't living full time in the park.
There's a new thing that just came out
in the hunt report about the,
I mean the whole background of it.
I mean it's,
there's a lot more to it than that and
it's all how you,
hey,
how it said too,
it's like,
you know,
all the guy killed cecil line who was
just super old male who had been kicked
out of the pride apparently,
you know,
and,
and it's,
you know,
that whole thing with his brothers and
the family and all that.
It's hilarious.
And at the end of the day it's like,
ah,
you know,
it was shot him and beheaded them.
It's like,
well,
Hey,
that burger you got at Mcdonald's,
guess what?
It died and got beheaded.
It's all how you would word it.
You could also say it was processed.
I mean like it just beheaded.
This is a horrible thing.
And it's like,
yeah,
everything that gets killed and process
gets beheaded.
But don't you think that part of the
reason why people get upset about lions,
because people generally don't eat
lions.
So when someone says that someone goes
and shoots a line,
like why would you shoot this beautiful,
rare,
majestic animal?
Just he could stick it on your wall and,
and just think you're a bad ass because
you've got this thing that could kill
you if you didn't have a weapon and
you've got it on your wall now.
Well,
I mean,
it,
it comes down to like predators need to
be controlled.
I mean,
it's,
it's not one of those things that's
pretty,
and people really love to hear that.
But at the end of the day,
it is true.
I mean,
like,
you know,
you were just down where I grew up.
I grew up in just north of the,
uh,
of the greater yellowstone elk herd,
you know,
between gardener and Livingston.
That's where I grew up.
And when I was in high school,
there was 19,000 elk in that hurt.
You go down there and wintertime is he
1500 bulls.
I mean,
it was,
it was amazing.
And they're down to two to 3000 now
because of,
you know,
the reintroduction of the wolf,
like you have to control predators,
um,
anywhere,
wherever they're at.
I mean it's,
it's,
it's insane to think that we don't exist
and these houses and fences and highways
and stuff are not there and that you can
just turn something loose and just let
it run its course.
And you know what you mean?
People or even appalled by the natural
core.
I mean,
when you see
a young lion take over the pride and
Cecil gets chumped and destroyed by two
other younger lines that came in and
got,
when people don't even like seeing that.
Right.
That's just how it happened.
It's just attachment.
Just detachment from the actual cycle of
life.
It is.
Yeah.
And the other thing that's going on is
that people love to,
they,
they love to broadcast how horrible the
people are that hunt these things and
how these lions are new.
They need to be preserved.
And it's so important.
Like Leonardo Dicaprio had something on
his instagram page the other day where
it was like an anniversary of the death
of Cecil,
and he was talking about how,
you know,
a few of these animals that are left,
they have to be protected.
What he see,
Rick conveniently ignores the fact that
Zimbabwe is going to kill 200 lions now
because no one's going over there to
hunt those lines.
It's just going to talk about,
there's more of them.
So they're decimating the undulate
population,
so now they're going to kill them and
make no money.
So they're gonna lose out on millions of
dollars in revenue.
What would you expect from a guy that
had got attacked by a CGI bear?
I mean,
he doesn't live in reality anyway,
I CGI,
but you probably didn't even ride.
He's probably doing coke and banging
hookers.
Call assists that.
Hey man,
put something eco on my page.
CCS anniversary.
Yeah.
Now they're now they can't.
Now.
That's a ton of money they could
generate to shoot those.
And I know guy,
I mean,
I know booking,
yeah,
talk to him all the time.
There's guy that nobody will touch that
with a 10 foot pole.
Yeah,
it's a great hunt.
It's a cool thing to go see.
They do need to be managed.
I mean,
you know,
like a lot of things like it just is
what it is very,
it's very inconvenient when you look at
the actual facts of,
of hunting over there,
even hunting,
you know,
just quote unquote for trophies.
That is where they get a massive amount
of their revenue.
It feeds a lot of the people that are
over there.
It makes a huge impact on their economy
and a lot of people don't like that.
But I urge people to watch the Louis
Theroux documentary about his trip to
Africa where he spent,
he spent several weeks in this African
hunting camp and you know,
it was the same thing was it was like a
high fence operation where they had
lions and they were throwing like calves
over the fence to feed these lines.
It was like two fences separating him
from the lions and he got to see like in
depth what's going on.
He's essentially saying that these
animals,
the only reason why they're here at all,
like massive amounts of them is because
they're worth something because they
have to come over.
And if it wasn't that like this place is
so poor and so crazy that these animals
would have been wiped out.
They,
and they were on the verge just a couple
of decades ago before the introduced
hunting.
So it's such a catch 22 because they
have more animals than they've ever had
before.
But the reason for that is because
they're worth something to hunt.
Exactly their economic resource.
And because of that they have value.
So they're protected and there's money
to protect him and people get put off by
the fact that people enjoy that pursuit.
Yeah.
And it's,
you know,
it's one of those things like I have a
hard time explaining it to people that,
you know,
I mean what makes a little kid who when
you're in the yard and there's a bird
right there,
like some kids,
you know,
just look at it and some want to chase
that thing
down and it's like 10,000 years where
the genetics at say 2 million actually.
Yeah.
You want to do it like this is something
that is built in,
you want to do,
I mean you felt that you didn't draw up
hunting then all of a sudden now you,
you,
you can't,
I mean you think about it every day.
That's all you want to do,
I'm sure.
And so to explain that to somebody that
doesn't have that,
it's really hard.
I mean,
you know,
especially whether eating a hamburger on
from their pedestal telling you how you
know,
you shouldn't kill anything.
Yeah.
Well I almost think,
I mean I don't think anybody should be
forced to do anything,
but I almost think that it would be good
for everybody to have to kill something
and eat it.
If you do eat meat just to experience it
and I mean that's just killing
something,
but to actually go out and hunt
something down and kill it and eat it,
I think would would open up a lot of of
doors inside your,
your your mind open up a lot of areas of
perception and give you this real
understanding of what it means to
consume life.
It's,
it's,
there's a,
there's a lot to it.
It's a very complex thing that's going
on when you're eating an animal a lot to
it.
It's like you talked about that
disconnect me and there is a massive
disconnect.
Yeah,
it's weird.
It's people think just because it's in a
package at a grocery store in the
cellophane with a styrofoam thing
underneath that is not,
didn't come from an animal or something.
Yeah,
but you should almost have to watch.
Even if you're not going to go,
you should almost have to be there
whether they kill the cow and then
string it up and then cut it on people.
How many people would become vegetarians
at?
Right?
Remember that whole cow thing that went
on a couple of years ago,
I think it was in a slaughter house down
in southern California.
And those cows are sick and they're
falling over and they've got video of it
and it got out there about the
processing of meat and all these people
up in arms about it.
And like that's always been that way.
Yeah.
And it just got public.
People were appalled by it.
But that's the reality of beef and
industrial food complex versus the
animals that we hunt.
I forget.
I have a great life.
You know,
most of them,
like the one Brendan,
the animal is Brendan.
I hunt,
which of the older ones,
they've had a full life and they've had
the opportunity to experience things in
nature and um,
reproduce and have,
you know,
what an animal's life should be like.
We're a cattle or you know,
any type of industrial type of a food
animal like chickens or cows or pigs.
I mean,
that's that.
it's like living in a concentration
camp.
It depends on the situation too.
I mean,
like my,
my wife's,
my wife's father has a big ranch in
eastern Montana and they raise and
process all their own stuff and you
know,
like people talking about,
you know,
like all the beef and meets horrible and
stuff,
not,
weren't know where I come from.
I mean,
they take really good care of those
animals and it's very important and they
don't go to the,
you know,
the giant stock yards and all,
it just,
it just depends.
It's all relative.
You've got to look at everything as it
is.
You know,
what,
you know,
where did that come from?
At least you know where it's more
connected.
Yeah.
When people hear about grass fed beef,
one of the big complaints ago,
God,
it's so expensive,
but yeah,
it's not supposed to be that cheap deet
life,
you know?
Exactly.
You know what I mean?
I mean like,
state can be so cheap.
It's ridiculous.
You think about the amount of effort
that has to go for you to get this $5
steak,
the amount of effort that the animal has
to grow,
it has to be fed and has to be taken
care of.
It then has to be slaughtered,
cut up,
package processed,
send to stores,
put on the shelves and then you go and
buy like what are the prices like,
oh my God,
no shit of yours could try doing it
yourself and you would value it.
You would realize like,
wow,
this is actually a pretty good deal and
all and all the,
all the process,
but it's not all the same either.
Like I said,
I mean there's lots of great ranchers
that,
that care about what they're doing and
and,
and do it right and all that stuff.
And you know,
again,
you lowest common denominator.
You get,
you know,
a place that's got 70 cows packed into
one shoot and people are like,
oh my God,
we're up in arms about it.
It's like,
well that's not,
that's not the norm.
Everything either.
I think it's good though.
The people were being aware of this.
And I think it's good that people are up
in arms because I think there is
something really disgusting about
factory farming.
Undeniably disgusting.
And I think the education of people and
getting to understand like,
yeah,
this is a system that you're a part of.
Even like the really hardcore radical
animal activists that you know,
risk their,
um,
their,
their lives and make these crazy fucking
videos and get inside slaughter houses
and you know,
violate those ag gag laws.
I salute them.
I saw I it too out there.
I do too.
I mean it shows the other side of it.
Yeah.
That,
you know,
the bad side of it.
Yeah.
We don't get to see it.
We shouldn't be shielded from the truth
in any way,
shape or form.
And that's one of the things that's
allowed this factory farm system to get
so disgusting.
It's the fact that people haven't been
able to have their input.
They haven't been able to see it and
protest against it and say like,
Hey,
you,
you shouldn't be treating living things
like this.
Totally agree.
I mean that's,
that story doesn't get told enough.
And I think the reasonable people who
love animals and maybe they don't have
any desire whatsoever to eat them,
that those are the people that I think
respect the pursuit of hunting and
respect.
The idea that you look a person,
it's not something for everybody,
but neither is marathon running.
Neither is weightlifting,
neither is so true.
Football,
Jujitsu,
anything difficult wrestling these,
this is not for everybody.
You know,
everybody's not going to do a lot of
things that are hard to do,
but if you want to procure meat,
that's the best way to do it.
Couldn't agree more and everything that
goes into it.
Yeah,
that's what I love about it.
Well I think it's important to spread
that.
I think that's sort of getting out there
as well as the,
there's this anti meat movement and
anti,
you know,
animal cruelty movement and I respect
that.
I understand where they're coming from.
I also thought,
unless you're driving the lexus with the
leather seats,
I mean honestly it's like,
it's like,
you know,
you see it all the time guy wearing
leather shoes and a leather belt,
you know,
talking about,
his impact and how little,
you know,
being Vegan or whatever.
It's like,
man,
that's just the hypocrisy is insane of
people.
You know,
like living in a house,
like how much is animal biproduct from
from everything you use.
And it's like,
well yeah,
but I just had a salad today.
It's like that's,
I mean 50 rabbits when the harvest is,
it made you feel good,
but in reality you're just bullshitting
yourself.
Yeah.
But they don't even know they're
bullshitting themselves.
If they,
if their perception of what they're
doing was accurate,
then they would have a good point.
But it's a,
it's an ignorance to what was actually
involved.
You know,
don't,
I don't believe in killing anything.
It's like every time you get in your
car,
man.
I mean the most animal,
the most life I've ever taken it.
Every time we take a 500 mile road trip
and I got to wipe those things off my
window.
I mean like,
I mean people,
people are like,
oh,
you can kill the shit out of bugs,
you know,
fish or cool or whatever.
It's like,
Ooh,
we got eyelids involved now.
It's getting weird.
It's like,
wow,
where does it work?
Where is it?
Yeah,
exactly.
I used to live in boulder and uh,
I live next to an osh rom and the lady
that ran the Ashram,
that's a Buddhist Ashram,
she's to poison the aunt
and I said,
do I go,
what are you doing?
I go,
you poisoned the aunts.
She was like,
well,
it's inconvenient.
We really don't like to do it.
But they get in our kitchen and like,
oh shit.
Yeah.
That's where you draw the line.
You,
you guys are,
this is some weird gray area.
You've mentioned you're a murderer later
mass where you've killed fucking
thousands of beans just today,
but in the ant a weird one because like
I've seen people like they'll see an ant
on them,
they'll squish it and then they flick it
on the ground in your house.
Totally.
So little.
They don't care that it hits your
kitchen floor.
Yeah,
exactly.
But if it was a mouse,
if like someone in your house stopped a
mouse in the middle of your kitchen and
be like,
what the fuck dude?
Like Jesus Christ,
this is it.
Cause it makes more of a mess and now
you have to consider what's actually
going on in there until totally people
fucking weird.
They're weird.
Yeah.
It's weird.
I mean,
but that's not really what I wanted to
bring you guys in and out.
That's like a beaten to death subject on
this point.
Talk about ants.
No,
Da began fan.
Yeah,
they're cool.
We wouldn't be amazing to be able to
pick shit up that was that much bigger
than you and walk around within your
mouth.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Well impressive.
When it turns to,
when you start talking about what
they're capable of.
Yeah.
And while it's also,
this isn't like an ant,
the size of a cat could be able to pick
up a house.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
And they no freewill whatsoever.
There's no decision making.
They just do,
have you ever seen those ant death
spirals?
No.
Got to check it out.
You put pull something like that up.
The ants follow.
The firm owns of the queen and when
[inaudible] when something goes,
yeah,
I get it too.
When something goes wrong,
when something goes wrong,
like they're sent gets screwed up or the
queen dies or the queen gets removed.
But the sense still there,
the ants will circle,
they'll circle each other and spires.
Yup.
Like a hurricane until they all die.
And you talking about thousands of
really?
Yep.
And they'll keep circling.
No one knows what the fuck's going on.
That's the True Power of pee right
there.
Yeah.
I mean look at this amazing.
And a few of them are going the wrong
way.
Like there's a few rebels that looks
like that looks,
it looks like the freeways is southern
California.
It looks like a hurricane.
It does.
I mean,
he really does.
That's the eye of the storm in the
center there.
And they're,
they're circling around and they don't
know what the fuck is.
Dead Queen.
Yeah.
Well it's either a dead queen.
I'm not exactly Jamie.
See if he could find out the actual
exact,
they can't release any for it.
Now.
They don't know they're following you
and some sort of a way.
But when they're doing this,
um,
I mean this is,
this is just shows that this,
this being these a aunts have no,
you don't have to just find an actual
explanation for it.
Not a video.
But when these,
um,
these animals are doing this,
like they don't,
they don't have any free will they have
this,
does this,
this sort of directive.
This is what they do.
You know,
they,
they make the nest,
they build a beehive,
they do this,
they change.
Like a friend of mine was a Ben O'brian.
He has no band on Brian from a used to
be worked for Peterson's a fucking 19 he
was telling me about one of his friends
had a queen bee somehow or they get
stuck in their car and this hive of bees
followed them for 20 miles.
They followed the car for 20 miles
because the baby was in the car like
they,
they don't have any like,
man,
she's gone.
Maybe we've got to let her go.
We got to push on because none of that,
like there's no free will.
It's just what they do.
Yeah.
There's no decision making.
It's just what they do.
The cuisine that we follow her,
they never give up.
It's a bizarre form of life and they
have these really weird things that they
do.
If you've seen like,
like videos on different ant species
where the females will chop the males
legs off I think is that leaf cutter
ants to do that.
I forget which one,
but they chop,
they take the mail when they're going to
breed with them and they essentially cut
his legs off so that he can't move and
then they carry him to wherever they
want.
They want to fuck him and then they take
him and breed with them.
I've met a couple of girls like that in
a bad way to go about it.
Like yeah,
like the lion there,
a stub.
All the [inaudible] will come out of
here,
but and again,
no thought process.
There is no meeting.
They don't have a board where they sit
down and decide how to do this with the
mail.
They just go about the way they've
always done it.
Yeah.
What a trip,
Huh?
Yeah.
Here we go.
How to make ants commit suicide going to
happen.
You can make it happen to a potted plant
and they'll just start following each
other and next thing you know,
see what we should bring all down on the
show.
We could put one right here,
it'd be rude and people would be angry.
Did protest.
That's cruel.
But that's the thing,
like certain amount of death is okay.
I mean every time you wash your body,
you're killing flora,
you're killing the living,
living organisms that are on the surface
of your skin.
There's no getting around it.
And there's no way to live a life where
you're not killing other life.
It's,
there's this constant cycle that's going
on in some sort of a weird way that most
of us are detached from way.
It's always been bizarre not to be in
touch with it and or just to deny it.
I mean like,
oh I'm not,
I'm not doing that.
Amen.
I mean,
and there are like,
there are a few people that,
you know,
try as hard as they can and all that.
But most people like they don't give up
though.
They love the idea.
Yeah.
But you know,
implementation is where it complicated I
think is also a problem with
entertainment,
like the anthropomorphizing of animals
and Disney movies and things along those
lines.
So like when you think of an animal,
you think of this big ferry lovable
thing.
You don't think of this,
you know like with an alk is essentially
a warrior.
It's this living warrior that has a
weapons grown out of its head and they
run around the kill each other.
When I was at the home ranch,
you,
you've been to that place,
they found this huge like three 90 class
bowl dead that had been stabbed by
another bowl.
It just random through and he was lying
there dead on the side of the mountain
with holes in his body from the other
bowl.
Just fucking headbutted him to death.
I'm going through it right now.
I've got a four year old son and he
watched this little show called the lion
guard,
which is like in all these animals get
together and they're all friends.
And we started watching,
he would ask questions and stuff and,
and now I'm like,
we watch,
you know,
if you want to watch the lion guard,
that's fine.
But I've explained to them like the
Cheetah and the lion and the hippo,
they don't get along.
They're not buddies.
And we watch discovery channel and he
watched it.
You know,
like the other day we just watched the
willdabeast couple of days ago we
pitched the willdabeast getting eaten by
the crocodile and he was just like,
Whoa,
you know,
it's like,
and now like when it comes up,
he's like,
well that's just pretend but I want to
watch that.
And it's like,
that's fine.
As long as we know,
you know,
that's not really how it goes.
You know,
we'll go discovery channel and watch you
know,
killers on the savannah and you know,
it's like wow,
you know,
the line doesn't get along with anybody.
He eats everybody and you know,
I don't want my kid to to think that you
know,
oh it's just big peaceful thing and
they're all symbiotic relationship and
they all love each other now.
Man,
that ain't what's going on.
It's weird the way we've chosen to
distort these animals.
And like polar bears,
like there was a picture that was going
on in instagram.
A lot of people were posting up of this
enormous polar bear walking around with
a cubs head and its mouth.
You've got everyday occurrence,
they're cannibals.
100% of the males are cannibals and most
people have no idea this.
So they think of a polar Baylor Klondike
bar.
Cocacola salesperson.
Yeah.
There's the photo that's been going on
and this is just food for them.
Absolutely.
I mean,
in a polar bear,
he's not an omnivore.
No.
100% people.
He's whatever he can get ahold of.
Yeah.
I mean,
that's all they eat is meat.
They're not like a black bear or any
other bear that can eat anything.
All they need is flesh.
That's that bear at the zoo is eaten
meat.
Yeah.
You know,
they don't let you see it,
but the,
the polar bear at the zoo just hammering
away at it.
I mean,
they all,
that's one of the darker things about
the zoo too,
is we take them away from their actual
purpose.
I think if you're going to have a zoo,
which he'd be like,
you should have animals that if you ever
see that zoo in Iraq that they had
before we invaded Iraq,
they um,
they had zoos where they used to just
let like a goat loose and then they
would open up the gate and let the lions
come out and Jack the goat and these
soldiers took videos of these things and
people were like aghast.
Like I don't understand why you think
you should be able to keep a lion but
don't let ally and to be lion like
you're going to do all the killing.
Has you giving him some fake meat?
No.
You giving them real meat.
Okay,
so something had to die in order to get,
but you don't want him to do it.
Why don't you want him to do it?
Like what the fuck are you doing?
Yeah,
exactly.
What,
what is the zoo?
Trust me,
the line wants to hear.
Yeah,
that's what they live for.
The,
here,
here's the video.
So they have these goats and these goats
are just wandering around.
They have no idea.
They let them lose and then they open up
the gate and when they open up the gate,
the lions,
apparently they do this all the time.
So they're hip to what's going to go.
They're stretched out and ready to go.
Oh yeah,
tape it to it spreads.
They don't want to pull a Hammy when
they get the goat.
So they open up the gate and as soon as
they open up the gate is just on like
donkey Kong.
I bet they got walk out music and
everything.
They were just ready.
Yeah,
totally.
This queen is playing.
We will,
we will rock you.
Yeah,
it goes boom.
They open up the gate.
I like that too.
It's not that weird to be fascinated by
that.
And for those guys to look at that and
go,
wow,
that's,
you know,
that's lions being lions like that's
pretty well,
I mean they're going to eat today one
way or the other.
And here's another interesting thing.
It's interesting for us to watch.
If we're watching and we're going Whoa,
and were laughing,
oh my God.
But if we were there and we were
laughing,
then people get upset.
Like there's an instinct to like,
listen to those guys laughing while it's
happening because they're filming it
right through the fence and go,
wow,
a bunch of assholes laughing at death.
But meanwhile,
it's okay to laugh at if it's on a
youtube video,
it's totally their kid to throw a bug in
a,
in a,
in a tank and,
and watch a fish eat it.
It's like,
oh,
cool.
Right.
But it's like a goat and a lion.
It's like,
well,
that's good.
Well,
it's like watching a fight.
Yeah.
I mean,
we want to see the guy get knocked out.
Right.
Next step is death.
Right?
It don't take it as close as possible.
Oh yeah.
I mean,
we find thrilling that,
well,
the guy chokes the guy out and he stops
off of him and he's totally unconscious.
The only difference between that and
death is time.
The amount of time really has a chunk.
That's it.
Keep that choke on for another minute.
That guy's dead.
Yup.
You know,
or not even a minute.
And we get millions of people that want
to watch it.
Yeah.
But at least that's,
they make a decision.
They both make a decision.
They're both going to enter into this
and it's an extreme form of a
competition with dire physical
consequences.
And that's why it's so exciting to
watch.
I mean,
I think the parallels when you're
watching something like that,
it was a little different.
A little different,
but it's still sad.
It's a detachment thing.
It is.
Yeah.
It's,
well,
you know,
we watch a movie,
you can watch a movie where 10 people
get shot and they get punched and
kicked.
Everybody gets their ass kicked.
But if they fuck,
if they're naked and they start to go,
what are you showing me?
What is this like?
People are weird.
We're real weird.
I like to draw the line on certain
things for whatever reasons.
It doesn't make any sense whatsoever.
No,
it doesn't.
It doesn't.
That's why we're the Huntington.
You can't win it all.
No,
I mean,
you,
you do,
you do as good a job as you can and
putting forward at an educated,
you know,
opinion of why we do,
and,
and at the same time being,
you know,
where I'm unapologetic about it too.
It's not like so many.
So there's not a conversation that could
convince me that what I'm doing isn't
what I was meant to do,
you know?
No.
When it comes to hunting,
I mean,
you,
you don't,
you put forward,
you know,
we try and tell people about it and
educate people as to what it is and
people are gonna feel how they're gonna
feel.
But at the end of the day,
I mean,
nothing's going to change with us
either.
How did you go from being a guy who is
obsessed with being the best hunter you
could possibly be and wanting to be the
best hunter in the world?
How'd you go from that to working for a
Sitka and apparel company,
a hunting company,
and then going to kill you?
Well,
I,
uh,
so after I killed a big elk,
I was in,
I started writing some stories and like,
like I told you,
I mean,
I,
I really,
you know,
there's a lot of guys that get
something,
have a great stroke of luck in life and
all of a sudden they killed one big
thing or they win one small lottery or
whatever and,
and,
and the,
you never hear from again.
And that was like the,
you know,
growing up in a hunter like to kill this
huge elk was yeah,
it was the right place at the right time
and amazing thing for me.
But I was,
I think time super conscious that I
don't want to be a one hit wonder.
I mean,
I want to do it more.
I want to be really good at what I'm
doing.
I mean,
like I grew up reading,
hunting books and like the,
the best hunters in the world.
I wanna I wanna,
I wanna I wanna get you then this title.
Yeah,
exactly right.
I want to keep the strap after every
year.
Right on.
So,
um,
I just,
you know,
put the work in and then it's doing some
writing.
I was at a trade show when I met him and
I,
I didn't work at sick.
I was a first,
uh,
they had an athlete team and one of the
first for first year,
not really an athlete team.
Yeah,
whatever,
whatever pro staff we were talking about
them,
the phone and it's,
it's a weird term today because of this
sort of buy a hat that says like pro
staff.
The franchise is completely dead.
I mean like I said,
pro staff with everything.
It's like when you can buy a hat that
says that it's,
it's dead.
I mean it means,
it means nothing.
It's,
it's been,
but back in the day it was,
I mean went back when print media and
like at one point in time it meant you
were vouching for our product because
you used it and isn't the right to vouch
for it.
Yeah.
You had a can have the photos,
you have the accomplishments,
you've earned the right,
not so much today,
you have,
you have the credibility to say this is,
this is good stuff or not.
And not because you did social media
reps,
but because you actually had been out
there using it and you don't have big
stuff.
Yeah.
And had the,
had the track record.
So I met him at a trade show and uh,
you know,
like I said,
every now and again in life you have
something that's just right place at the
right time.
And I had killed that big elk and it
kind of was getting known and,
and I met him in the booth and he's
like,
you're that kid that killed that big elk
and exactly the same.
It's still does.
Yeah.
And so we hit it off and I started
helping them test and gear and shot a
commercial for him down and stuff.
And we just became really good friends.
And then,
um,
when the whole deal went down in Sitka,
he,
you know,
it's like when your,
when your guy,
your guy is,
you know,
they're in,
in,
is leaving,
you know,
you have a choice.
You can either go with your guy or you
can,
you know,
stay with,
what's the best thing you think is to
do.
And,
and I was like,
man,
whatever you got going on next,
let me know.
I'm,
I'm down.
What did you think about this pursuit
that he's on to create the most finely
engineered,
like to the extreme products?
Like what he's doing?
It's,
it's fine.
I mean,
he's,
he's hit everything on the head that he
told me.
I mean,
we,
we flew down,
we went to,
uh,
I flew down like,
I don't want to say it was like in
November or something,
a year before he's,
could you start at Ku?
He was already started,
but beforehand,
and he,
he basically is like nostradamus in
hindsight.
I mean,
it was like,
listen,
he breaks out this,
I remember I'll never forget this
briefcase.
And he pulled this thing out and it was
a carbon fiber frame and he's like,
this is,
this is the backpack we're coming out
with and the whole business model,
all of that.
And it's like,
I'm not the smartest guy in the world,
but when I meet a really smart dude
that's got a really good idea,
you know,
I'm not that dumb.
You smart enough to recognize smart
people.
Yeah.
I was like,
and I was like,
man,
I don't,
yeah,
I mean you,
when you see something and you go to,
I want to know more about that and that
seems like it's going to fix a problem.
And uh,
and just,
you know,
the knowledge of what he,
what he knew about everything and you
know,
we were buddies and it's like,
dude,
why wouldn't you want to go,
you know,
work at a company?
Where are you going to be able to hunt
as much as you want?
You're testing gear and,
and I mean,
truly live in the dream and not just
saying it like living the dream.
Like,
you don't wake up every day and you like
what you're doing and you know,
it's,
it's been awesome.
I mean,
that's,
and so,
so yeah,
he said he's been basically,
I'm looking for somebody to run this
part of it and um,
and it's like,
he's like,
you'd be perfect.
I'm like,
well,
perfect.
Well I think people like you were
attracted to the pursuit of excellence.
Yeah.
And when you see the pursuit of
excellence in,
in another form,
you go,
well,
there it is.
Like,
well,
that's how it is with me.
When I started seeing your company and I
see a company that's trying to like
deeply and seriously engineer something,
I Geek out on shit that I'm not even
interested in buying.
Like if someone's making the craziest
grandfather clock in the world and I see
this guy that's engineering these
things,
so it's accurate to like one 18th of one
second over 20 years,
I'm like,
ah,
I want to,
I want to know what's going on this
dude's brain that makes them want to
make this unbelievable grandfather
clock.
Huh?
Like,
I'm fascinated by pursuit.
You know,
when someone's trying to do something
better than the people that had done
before it.
I'm fascinated by that.
So he must've seen that for a guy like
you and I know what I know what I like
and I know what I see a good idea.
Um,
the one thing is like,
I'm not,
I wouldn't say I'm necessarily the best
at doing like super intricate things are
knowing exactly how to get there,
but when you see somebody that knows how
to get there and like it'd be a good
combination and you can,
you know,
assist in that in somebody that when
they're headed on the,
on the,
on the right direction and it's like,
yeah,
I'm down with that.
And,
and,
and then,
you know,
I have my input on what we do,
but you know,
at the end of the day it's,
you know,
a lot of it is,
him,
how he,
how he goes
about stuff.
It's cool to watch.
I mean,
it's like,
it,
it's,
I,
I always tell people like at,
at what we do is it is,
it's exactly what you think it is.
Like there's not like a,
you step in the room and it's like,
oh yeah,
this is some other guy's stuff.
We're going to knock this out.
That's not going on.
But that does happen in some companies.
And you,
you were posting all this,
that's disturbing to me.
When,
when you look at the future of this,
what,
how far can you keep pushing this?
I mean this is a fairly new thing that
people have been like ridiculously
engineering,
hunting and outdoor equipment and
obviously exists in the mountaineering
world and the Rei wise and you know,
they,
they try every year trying to come up
with better and better stuff,
but how,
how far can that go?
Like is there a point where you're going
to have it done?
Like this is the best backpack anybody
could ever possibly make.
These are the best clothes.
I mean,
is there a,
is there a point where that ends?
You know,
today innovation is happening faster
than ever has and with those business
model we can implement those innovations
quickly and we're always looking for the
next greatest thing.
I always am.
I mean,
I searched the globe on a continuous
basis for what's new,
what's next,
aligned myself with the innovation
leaders for every single category,
whether it's marina wool,
whether it's leathers or whether it's
for our gloves or whether it's carbon
fiber for our bat,
our packs.
Um,
we had our designer down at Stanford,
the carbon fiber scientists down there
that's working on some leading edge
technologies around carbon fiber that
won't even get to market for a few
years.
Were that interested in seeing what's
next because we can implement it because
we have no price restrictions.
When we take it away,
it's for us,
it's,
it's a never ending pursuit and there's
always new ways to make things and it's
why I tagged,
tagged the line for the business of
ultra light.
Because if I can find a way to shave an
ounce or a gram,
there's a reason to redo that product.
There's reason to reinvent that product
because that makes a difference.
And that was my focus with this is that,
you know,
Tory's technology and how they make the
yarn carbon fiber,
it all led to ultra light.
Ultra light means performance in the
mountains.
And so my goal is to get our weights
continuously to come down as far as our
product without giving up performance.
And that's through using really
innovative technologies and designs that
are all focused around that.
And I mean from where we started to
where we are now,
I mean we've taken pounds and pounds of
weight out of people's kits and packs
and seeing the results.
And it's been amazing to watch people
that normally would walk into the mounds
with the 70 pound back now leaving with
a 40 pound pack and come back and sand
made all the difference in the world.
I can hunt now and I thought I was done
because of pack weight.
Now have you guys thought about
implementing any sort of a workout
routines or um,
or diet routines or things like that on
your website and it's sort of shaping
people's ideas about getting your body
prepared?
I would like to do more of that,
really would.
Um,
we'd started developing our mountain fit
line come out next year.
So
using all of our fabric innovations into
performance fitness line for our
customer because they're all training
for hunts and I have wanted to step in
and help people get fit,
nutrition supplements and bring that to
our customers as well.
We just haven't gotten there yet,
but I think it's absolutely something,
I know I want to do it cause I live and
breathe it everyday.
Just haven't done it yet.
Don't you think that's also another
aspect that people don't realize,
like how much physical requirement is
necessary in order to to hunt.
Like especially in mountain hunting,
elk hunting,
you're going in the mountains of
Montana,
you're at fucking 9,000 plus elevation.
It's unbelievably difficult on the body.
And I think most people don't realize
how much physical preparation is
involved.
Especially you two guys,
you wrestler,
you are former football player,
you guys have athletic backgrounds.
You know how physically demanding this
is the hardest things I've ever done.
I've been hunting without a doubt.
And I mean like,
it's hard to say.
There's tough,
that's stuff that's tougher than college
wrestling practices.
Um,
I've definitely,
you know,
I mean you,
you got,
you push it to limit,
especially on some of these long
expedition consonant.
I spent 24 days backpacking in the Bob
Marshall last year to find a sheet to
find one ram.
And it's like,
until you've actually done that,
and I'm talking like it's not just,
you know,
how far or how long,
but it's sustained.
Um,
it's at a sustained high level of focus
also,
which you don't like.
You can,
you can grind away at stuff and you can
just go and go and go.
But I mean,
again,
when we get them,
we don't just go from a to b.
We have to be,
you know,
you have to be on,
on point in the mountains too.
I mean,
you have to be sharp.
You gotta be ready to execute.
The moment comes,
you can't be just sort of trotting along
like a Zombie.
Yeah.
I mean,
when you get up early in the morning,
if you're not glass and every single
time with,
with the same enthusiasm and the same or
that your grid system or whatever,
you have to be as intense on day one as
you do on the last day because you could
miss what you're looking for and you
can't,
you can't let up.
That's the beauty of it.
And I mean,
yeah,
I mean physically fit.
I mean,
there's lots of different stuff.
I've,
you know,
he's got his whole training regimen and
everybody's different,
but,
uh,
you know,
like whether it's yoga or you know,
cardio and you know,
how much you're eating.
And I mean,
it's,
it never ends you,
you,
there is no magic bullet.
The,
the puzzle,
you're always putting it,
you're always breaking it down and doing
a new puzzle.
Yeah,
I do every year.
Yeah.
And,
and everyone has different physical
requirements is some people that are
older and you just trying to kind of
maintain the best possible shape they
get in.
There's some guys that are younger.
We tried to get them into the ultimate
fitness.
When you're training and you're doing
all these backpack things,
what you see you carrying weight it
using weight plates.
Like what do you,
what are you carrying around in a
backpack?
So I use,
we have these sand bags that are set up
for putting over like the booms and our
video root cause now what I use,
you can buy them in 20 pounds,
25 pounds,
30 pound increments.
And that's what I put in my packet train
with.
And so like right now as we're rolling,
we're about 45 days away from are a
sheep hunt in the Yukon.
I'm really stepping up my weight.
So I'm training with a 90 pound pack now
and I'll do a two or three hour hike,
1500 2000 vertical
feet and on.
Now I'm doing it in the middle of the
day with the heat we're having because
it adds another mental toughness factor
to it.
Plus,
as you know,
it adds a whole nother level of fitness
to when you're trained in the heat.
So my goal is to try to train in
situations with weight and conditions
that are harder than what I'll
experience in the hunt.
Just for the mental strength as much as
it as the physical part of it.
Because you get beat down on day three
or day four and you just,
I've seen a lot of guys just fold in the
towel and say I've had it more go home
just physically they don't have anything
left,
nothing left.
Right.
So there's a mental side of it too.
That's a big part of it that gives me
confidence when I'm going on these trips
because it's,
I mean,
they're fricking grinders.
I mean I've had hunts where we walked
for three freaking straight days with 70
pound packs before you even start
hunting.
That's just to get into the area from
the time you wake up until the time you
go to bed.
And that can,
you know,
most people can make the phone sat,
phone call and get picked up and taken
out.
And we hear about it all the time from
clients and customers.
So we try to help them get prepared
lower that way.
So that doesn't happen to them.
When you're doing something like that
and you're preparing for something like
that,
do you start off with like 20 pounds and
like how do you,
how do you do then?
How would you advise someone?
Like say if there's someone listening
right now,
it says,
Hey,
uh,
I'm,
you know,
I'm going to go on a hunt this this
winter or this,
uh,
this fall rather,
and I need to really get physically
prepared but I don't want to blow it all
out in one shot.
Yeah,
you definitely want to build up to it.
And because I don't stop training,
I come out of a hat on and go right back
at my training.
But for a lot of guys are just getting
to ease into it.
Right?
I mean,
you want us,
like you said,
start with 20 pounds and build yourself
up over time because lastly we want to
do is go into hunt hurt,
right?
I've done that before.
I've overtrained or done too much going
into hunt and you have to be careful,
especially as you age I get sent tend to
get tendinitis and joint pain more than
I ever have.
And so it's,
it's managing your body through that
process and having something left when
you leave and,
but being fit enough and having your
feet and in good enough shape and your
boots broken.
I mean there's a lot to it besides just
the cardio part of it that goes into the
hunt.
Yeah,
I think people would benefit from seeing
what,
like if you could make like a blog on
how you do it or get outline,
totally outline how you start off and
how someone would build into it and
maybe consult with someone who's a,
an expert trainer and figure out what's
the best way to uh,
get people prepared to develop an actual
workout for like for pack hunting or for
even hiking.
Any,
any,
any sort of thing where you're walking
uphill in the mountains with weight on
your back.
It's like,
boy,
that is an unbelievably difficult thing
to do all day,
every day for several days.
At a time.
It's just a different biomechanical
movement.
I used to trail run a ton beforehand and
that was enough and I've gotten older.
I've realized that I need to train more
specifically for hunts and that's
carrying a pack with weight and it hits
different muscle groups as you've felt.
It gets more up in your hips and your
glutes and it hits a whole different
muscle group.
Then trail riding does or that weight
training does or training on an
elliptical stairmaster or whatever that
is.
There's no substitute
for spending time in the pack with
weight.
There's just isn't.
No,
there's no sub.
It's so different than anything else.
It just,
it's so exhausting.
It is and it hits a whole different
muscle group and your heart and lungs
may be in shape,
but those muscles aren't and it,
it taxes you.
Yeah.
As much as I lift weights and workout
and kettlebells and all this stuff,
I packed hundred pounds for like three
quarters of a mile in the fall and I was
fucking dead.
I know when it was over I was like,
oh my God,
I can imagine 70 pounds on my back for
three days at a time.
Walking all day just to start hunting.
Yeah.
I'm not in good enough shape for that.
So if someone listening to this,
is there a resource,
is there any like sort of a website they
can go to that give them some good
workouts for,
for something to get prepared for
something like this?
There isn't one specific to what we're
doing and I think it's a great idea that
you have is really laying that out and
we tee,
I mean we talk about all the time,
we take all this for fricking granted.
Yeah,
we've grown up doing it right?
These spreadsheets,
people are like,
oh my God,
that's so amazing.
You do that.
And like I've always done it right on
the house.
You knew what your pack's going away
when that you're not over packing and
then you have exactly what you need and
how much you need of it.
And we break it down to like calories
per ounce and ounces per day.
As far as our food.
We bring,
I mean,
I'd go on a sheet and I don't rely on
the outfit or to the pack for me.
I bring all my own food and it's all
laid out.
It's all,
it's all calculate out to the exact
calorie per day I'm going to eat.
What kind of food do you bring?
A lot of whole foods now.
I used to bring,
you know,
lots of bars and clif bars and power
bars.
Now it's real food and,
and I both gotten to that.
Yeah.
Nuts and whole grains and,
and um,
getting away from the edge.
I did meal so much at the have,
you know,
high sodium,
not a lot of nutritional value and
really trying to focus on,
you know,
bring in breads and peanut butters and
cheeses and things that will stick with
you versus high sugars and you know,
quick burns,
right?
When you have dehydrated food,
how nutritious is that stuff?
I don't just scouring the Trisha,
I think his calories and then if you
really look at their calories are not
that many calories per ounce.
They're light and some of them have
higher calories per ounces than others.
But I,
Brendan's come up with a really good
recipe with your,
with peanut butter and some noodles and
like Stephanie on,
you're really creative with it.
I've been,
I've been kind of building my own,
like my stuff wasn't my id exactly.
If I've modified it a bit and a couple
of things,
ramen and peanut butter and fats and
jerky and stuff,
all that,
the heart weighs about the same and has
double the calories and,
and you don't want,
the one thing I,
this is what I do a lot is advising
people that are going on a big hunt,
you know,
and it's like start today,
don't put it off.
Don't get a plan.
Like get a pack on,
go for a hike,
start working out right now.
You know,
it's going to and,
and,
uh,
get all your gear in order.
And at the end of the day it's going to
be a grind.
You're,
you're not gonna,
you're not going to be full the whole
time.
You're not going to have all the energy
and neat.
Like,
that's the beauty of it.
It's like you can train all you want to
do at the end of the day,
you're going to be working on the
deficit.
You need to be sharp and you're just
going to have to grind through it and
you have to be tough.
You know?
That's the beauty of it.
You can't be a wimp and do this.
So how do you figure out how much peanut
butter to bring?
How does
you can't bring enough,
right?
So you gotta burn what?
I mean,
1,002 thousand calories an hour when you
can heavyweight to altitude.
Is it really that much?
2000 calories an hour.
You'll do a thousand calories on a
treadmill an hour.
But is that,
is that even possible?
2000 calories an hour if you're hiking
for 12 hours at altitude with weight as
possible,
done it.
It's why you lose a pound a day,
two pounds a day on these hunts.
If you,
if you're not in total shape going in,
which is your body's just burning off
one more than you're taking in,
you're going to be a calorie deficit no
matter what.
And that also puts you at a mental
deficit,
makes you mentally exhausted when your
body starts using all its resources to
part of it.
The same feeling.
You get cutting weight,
you get on a huge trip when you're
running out of food,
you're way back in there.
It's just like you just got to dig deep.
Like how do you show up for practice
when you're cutting weight?
You just got to do it and you just got
to dig deep and your body will,
your body responds.
I mean,
the cool thing is your body responding
will eat what it needs to eat and you
just keep going.
You know what I mean?
It's,
it's going to be the,
the,
the beauty of it.
It's never easy.
I mean,
it's going to be,
it's going to be tough.
Well,
that's one of the things that's so
exciting about this is it is
unbelievably difficult.
Pursues test man.
Now if you're going like,
explain to me a hunt,
like say if you're going to go on a like
a,
a mountain goat haunt or a sheep hunt
where you know you're going to go into
very difficult terrain and you have x
amount of days,
how do you pack for that?
Like as far as food?
Yeah,
two pounds a day,
two per day.
And then you want to be range ranging
between 100 to 120 calories per ounce on
your food choices.
So I break it down.
Do you concentrate on,
um,
vitamins?
Do you think about like I do,
yeah,
I'll bring,
I'll bring supplements.
Um,
I'll bring,
uh,
you know,
whether it's um,
electrolyte replacement tax or vitamins
and that type of stuff.
And then the other part of it's just
whole foods,
making sure we max out that Kelly's
frowns high fat content.
And then the other thing I tell you to
tell people is try it when you're not
hunting.
Totally.
You have to,
if you don't like it,
you're going to hate it on the mountain.
Like one year about these new pro bars.
If you tried to pro bar.
Yeah,
I got those to kind of nasty after
awhile.
I mean there's a lot to it.
There's nuts and grains.
Yeah,
they're very filling and they're very
big and dense,
but triton one for 10 days or three of
them a day for 10 days.
At the end of it,
you don't even want to eat it.
And so I've,
I believe now for me at least,
and what I recommend to our customers is
bring food you like now that you love
and focus on that stuff versus trying to
get crazy on something new that you
haven't tried and thinking,
okay,
I'll go to rei and by all these
different types of exotic bars and
that'll be my food source.
Dude,
before I was on a ketogenic diet,
I was eating like 10 of those pro bars a
day.
So I don't know what you're talking
about.
Well,
the peanut butter and chocolate ones.
I fucking love those days when Jamie,
all the time I lived on him for 14 days
in the mountains,
I couldn't,
I,
if I ate another one,
I'd throw,
you know that that expression find me
the best looking woman somewhere.
There's a guy is tired of fucking
a lot of it with the food is a you,
you,
you got to try it out
early.
You got to try it beforehand.
I mean,
I tell people like if you,
if you've never eaten mountain house,
I mean it's,
it is,
it's like second nature to us.
I mean,
so much of that shit that it's like I
got,
I mean I got tell people mountain
houses,
dehydrated,
freeze dried or freeze dried.
Yeah.
Whether it's mountain house or,
I mean there's a million kinds of it,
but I've gotten to where like I can only
eat a certain,
some of them function better for me.
Like I don't like any of the red sauce.
I don't like don't ever eat Chili Mac,
by the way.
Why just try?
It goes right through you.
Yeah.
Your buddy when you're hunting was going
to be bummed you ate it.
But if you,
if you've got somebody you're hunt with,
you don't like feed him Chili Mac.
But if you've never had a hang time,
if you've never done it before and,
and you know,
you all of a sudden you go on this great
big trip and you're stressed,
you know,
and you're traveling and all this stuff
and all of a sudden,
you know,
it's like throwing diesel into an
unleaded car.
I mean if you've never ran on that
before,
you don't really know how you're going
to run on it.
He,
that's what he got to do it,
do it right.
You know,
and,
and a lot of people,
you know in freaks him out.
You know what's the thing leaving the
outfit?
It was cause you on a sheep hunt,
they'll provide the food.
Right.
But you don't know what they're going to
give you.
They don't know what you are going to
like the always over pack.
You mean the food bags?
We'll hand,
you'll be 40 pounds for 10 days when you
really need 20 pounds because they don't
know.
The last thing we want is a client that
doesn't like what they have to eat or
runs out of food and so this is all part
of it.
And then part of it you may not like
what they provide you thing is super
interesting and I'm messing around with
that actually as we as we speak,
because the thought of being able to go
for 10 days with sustained energy while
you're burning your own fat.
I mean that is,
that is like,
I would say that's cutting it.
I'm messing around with that right now.
That's why I got that mct oil and all
that stuff.
I'm going to,
I'm going to try that this fall to see
because I've been in places,
you know,
and,
and it's kind of funny like I've had
times where you run out of food or you
have so little food that I think your
body has switched over to where it's
just strictly absolutely.
And then you feel fine.
Like it's like it just goes away.
So we'll hunger goes away in some sort
of a weird way,
and there's,
there's also a bunch of different people
that are involved in this now that are
coming up with snacks and different
foods that you could take with you when
you're a,
that's one of the reasons why I wanted
to ask you guys what you're carrying
around,
but once your body's into Ketosis,
you know,
then you just need high fat,
high fat content foods,
and you've got to figure out how to keep
them.
Okay.
All right.
Keep them from going bad while you were
out there in the mountain,
but almond butter,
things along those lines and bringing a
lot more of that than powerbars.
Yeah,
and peanut butter,
the probably peanut butters,
most peanut butter you're going to get
is going to be loaded up with sugar and
just you can even get the insulin spikes
are going to get the crashes when,
when you talking about 20 pounds of
food,
that doesn't seem like a lot.
If you tell me 20 pounds of food for how
many days for 10 to two pounds of food
today I talking to is our antiquing
already.
I'm panicking,
I'm starving,
I'm going to start off.
You've got to ration it out.
You got to ration it out.
Yeah.
And I mean,
it's not like you're sitting around
like,
Oh man,
I'm ready to get something to eat.
I mean,
you're right.
You're doing stuff.
You're glassing it.
Like,
I mean,
it's just like,
here's the line as you're hungry to go,
it's like going on a diet.
It's,
it's,
it's basically you're in the mountains,
but your meal prepped.
Like there's your little meal,
you know,
it's like these guys that are slimming
down and be on these competent,
you know what it's like,
that's all you get.
And do you have them broken down into
packets?
We have,
I have broken down per day,
so I have a Ziploc bag with my day.
And how big is,
it was a law clerk and it's about this
big,
maybe it's not very big.
That's so crazy.
Like,
and then you know,
every day is broken down.
Exactly that way.
So what's nice about it as you get back
at night,
you're exhausted.
You take your empty bag out that you ate
all day,
that goes in the garbage,
and then you pull your new one out of
your food bag and dump in your pack.
So there's no guesswork.
None can't be.
And Are you eating this stuff like we
were talking about before you go out
there or are you trying to live off that
for a few days?
I try everything year round,
so if the new,
something new comes out or we learn
about something new,
I'm trying to,
during my training,
I'm trying,
trying to in the off season to make sure
I'm going to like it.
Have you ever,
uh,
there's,
or a new product that's out of this,
a friend of mine has put out,
it's called phat fudge.
Have you heard of this?
Nope.
It's a see pull up.
Um,
I think it's p h a t fudge.com I think
is her,
uh,
the website,
which she sells it,
but she's a,
or it might be Paleo chef.com,
but she's a created this,
um,
it's like a snack.
It's very nutrient date dance.
It's up to fudge that has mct oil in it.
Very low sugar.
I think it's got like a little bit of
honey in it.
Um,
but they're,
they come in these small individual
packets.
Dude,
I fucking live on,
I got to try that.
It's fantastic.
But that's the type of stuff that is so
powerful in the mountains.
Yeah.
Because it's small packet.
You,
you know,
just rip the top off it and shove it in
your mouth and chew it down.
And uh,
you know,
you can see,
you see all the ingredients are,
it's key to genic and uh,
it's called got cow,
it's got Tumeric,
cinnamon,
sea salt,
Maka honey grass fed butter.
It's all like super,
super good stuff.
But it's,
you know,
a lot of calories for like a little tiny
thing,
but very nutrient dense.
And for someone who's trying to burn off
nothing but fats,
it's a good way to go.
It is.
Yeah.
The whole,
the,
the concept of burning fat versus using
sugars was introduced to me.
We're doing some vo,
two Max testing and weight with our
packs on at a UC Davis performance lab.
And that guy trained,
uh,
worked with us cycling team and they
were talking about this movement into
burning fat versus using gel shots and
sugars.
Yeah.
And I've started to,
in our diets and what we bring,
that's been our focus and this made a
really big difference.
It's made a big difference with me.
Uh,
it's made a big difference with a lot of
UFC fighters.
Misha tate switched over to a Kesha,
Jen tita genic die before she won the
title.
Brian Caraway,
her boyfriend,
he's on it too.
He said weight cutting is way easier as
performance levels are higher.
And one of the things that I'm finding
with myself and with a lot of my friends
have gone on as your testosterone goes
up noticeably,
and some guys,
it's going up by double real.
It's because the precursors for
testosterone,
it's all about,
it's all about fats.
It's all about your body turns,
fats,
saturated fats and cholesterol,
all that stuff that you were eating from
healthy fats turns that into hormones.
That's like what it,
and it's one of the,
the,
the big problems with going on high
carb,
low fat diets is that your body has a
difficult time creating hormones through
that.
I didn't know that.
Really interesting and new stuff that's
coming out is if these guys that are
taking it,
they're finding that when they're doing
their blood tests that their
testosterone levels are higher,
their growth hormone levels are higher.
It's really interesting stuff.
Like I think your body is designed to
eat that natural food like plants and
vegetables and meats.
It is,
you watch a bear.
What eats first?
All the fat fish.
Oh yeah.
He needs to meet.
Yup.
I mean that's the number one food
source,
energy sources,
fat first.
I mean it's a wonderful thing.
It's just for,
for whatever reason,
our society society,
that's what makes people fat is really
the sugars.
Yeah.
It's a sugar.
It's 100% of the sugars.
This stuff changes all the time.
And if you go back five years ago and
you read some of the studies that are
done and what people recommend like for
as far as diet now today it's totally
contrary to that.
It is,
it's interesting how this,
the,
the edge is always moving.
It's a cutting edge of this stuff is
always,
it's always changing.
And people were always coming up with a
new studies that show better ways to
eat.
And that's the fun thing about what
we're doing is we're,
you know,
we're always there.
There is no magic bullet.
I got guys call all the time like,
Hey,
what,
what jacket do I need?
It's like dude,
it doesn't look like that.
Clear small,
what is the name?
What does this mean?
Island in southeast Alaska ties density
of black bears in the world.
And I've handed it and it wasn't dot
comed and I just liked the way the name
lays out.
I like the way the balance,
the look and when I was hunting it,
and this is when I had Sitka is hunting
there with my ex business partner and
actually gortex before they had licensed
us and invested in us and woke up the
morning before everybody else is sitting
on the back of the button and I like
thinking about Kuya the name and I was
like,
that's one of the name of the next
company.
And I don't know why that even came to
my mind because we're in the midst of
buildings that could,
but I just liked the name for whatever
reason,
just my gut told me that was it.
Go with the gut.
Totally.
Always.
Every time.
Yeah.
Isn't amazing when you follow it,
how powerful it is.
It's my whole life I've always gone with
my gut.
Totally.
Yeah.
It's,
there's no,
there's no other way.
You know,
so many people are,
are driven or,
or the,
her entire life is about fear and it
dictates everything they do versus
following your gut and putting the fear
of side.
And once you do it makes all the
difference in life.
If fear is good,
it is a motivating factor.
Yeah.
Well it's also the lack of fear can be
very dangerous.
Absolutely.
One of the,
one of the things that I would say like
people that are not scared when they're
fighting,
like those two people are in trouble.
You're in trouble,
man.
You should be fine.
It nobody likes to be scared.
But when I was competing,
the worst tournament's that I ever
fought in,
I was not nervous.
It was too confident and I've,
I just perform poorly.
But when I was fucking terrified and
like completely on edge,
then your body's just,
it's just primal.
It's
just like you get down to that,
that the bare minimum amount of
understanding of what,
what you have to do of the thinking,
the,
the rest of the world fades away.
And all you're thinking about is that
task.
Do you cutting out everything else?
There's no thought about bills.
There's no thought about the future.
There's just what's going on in front of
you right now.
And when,
if you can get down to that,
that's when you perform at your best.
But it's fucking terrifying.
So nobody likes it.
Nobody likes to be like,
when you see guys that are in like the
UFC that are like,
like,
here's a good example now I'm a big fan
of Luke rockhold.
I think he's an awesome guy.
Just talking about on the way down,
he was way too relaxed the time he was
going to kill Michael Bisping.
Michael bisping fought that fight like
he was going in against a fucking silver
back gorilla.
He was terrified or not terrified,
but you know,
jacked up with nerves and like you're
always on the line for him and that's
how you walked.
Knocked him out.
Such a great sport because first knock
out too in the UFC,
it's this first Kale like that.
That's how I sell them on the way to
like Jorge Rivera in Manchester and kind
of get beat down mayhem.
Miller as a Tko.
But the,
the Tkos.
Yeah,
I mean he's also sitting down and his
punches better.
Jason Parillo,
his boxing coach has really been working
with him and d done a fantastic job with
him and with Cris Cyborg and a bunch of
other people that you build up to.
That reminded me of Keith Jardine
talking about Houston Alexander.
It was like,
I kept thinking like,
man,
he's really dismissive.
Like even in my league and all that
stuff and all of a sudden you're done.
You can't,
when a guy's a professional fighter,
if you just stood there and let him
punch you in the face,
would it knock you out?
Yeah,
absolutely.
Okay,
so that it can fucking happen.
They kind of,
yeah,
and the last thing you want to be is the
guy that says,
this guy can't beat me.
I'm going to go in there and fuck them
up.
And then you wake up with a flashlight
and your eyes like,
what?
What's going on?
The Dr. Santiago,
we don't move.
You're like,
oh shit.
What happened motherfucker?
And then you have to deal with that.
That ego that allow the ego tells you
that it's going to protect you from all
this,
you know,
do the baddest motherfucker have,
you don't have to worry about shit.
Ooh,
I don't even have to worry.
And then blam and you're like,
God dammit.
Ego.
Ego leaves you alone.
Like,
where are you now bitch?
He goes,
it's okay to say it.
Just don't believe it.
Yeah.
And even if you say it,
he's got to be real fun.
Yeah.
You gotta be looking at her saying it
too.
These guys are killers.
I mean,
I just,
man,
that sports awesome.
It's a crazy sport is Brendan's got me
into it and I never missed a fight.
Now have you come live yet?
I have.
Where have you been?
To live and to the Thompson Hendrix.
I've been at like 25 of them that he was
at Thompson Hendrix.
Nice.
Lorenzo Fertitta.
His nephew owns go hunt.
Yeah.
So the runs in our buddy.
So he took me,
we got full access.
Oh,
that was beautiful.
That's beautiful.
Yeah.
The big ones coming up next weekend
you'll see 200 is alive.
Oh yeah.
Man on TV.
Yeah.
I was like,
wait,
I need a bill to hear Rogan so I know
what's going on.
Well,
they have these little things,
these little radios that you can get at
the concession stand.
Can you really?
Yeah.
Most of that.
Most arenas have them now.
And you take these little radios and
you,
you turn them on and it actually has a
frequency that picks up the commentary.
Really?
Yeah.
It's excellent.
It's really cool.
I missed that part.
Yeah.
Well there's sometimes something's going
on.
You don't know what happened.
Yeah.
And like,
like they stopped the fight.
Like,
why'd they stop the fight?
You don't realize,
oh,
he's fucking legs broken or,
yeah,
exactly.
You can takes a while.
Yeah.
Commentary.
And it also,
uh,
I believe you can get,
I'm not sure about that.
There might just be fight pass.
One of the cool things about UFC fight
passes,
you can listen into the corners.
Oh,
you can?
Yes.
The corner guys are miked up,
so you can,
you can hear like someone saying,
Oh,
you know,
his hands broke,
or Oh,
you know,
uh,
this is what you gotta do.
Yeah,
yeah.
You just get,
you get insight and you also get a sense
of a building up anticipation.
Like if you know that a guy's got an
injury and then he's trying to gut it
out,
it makes it even more exciting to watch.
You know?
I mean,
yeah,
it's an awesome sport.
Like I said,
I only have a couple of hobbies watching
mma,
hunting.
That's it.
And then they're,
they're very,
it's very,
they're very comparable,
like,
you know,
from going from being a wrestler.
I mean,
he,
it's just,
it's exciting.
It's slow portions of nothing in this
training and grinding and all of a
sudden,
and then every now and again you get to
step in and,
and,
and see where you're at.
I mean,
it's,
you know,
like you always say like two guys.
I mean,
that's,
that's a stripped down to the gets.
You either win or lose at 50 50.
I'm either going to win or I'm not.
And same with hunting.
I mean at at certain point in time in
that hunt,
you either you either get them or you
don't like the percentages work out like
that.
I mean it's,
that's,
that's the cool thing about it.
Well I think also like hunting,
it's very,
it's not perceived correctly by a lot of
people.
It was very misunderstood and a lot of
people think of it as this barbaric,
awful thing involving bullies and
assholes when really they're incredibly
intelligent,
difficult people were pursuing one of
the most,
one of the most difficult things to do
with dire physical consequences.
If you fail those bullies and assholes,
they don't have the dedication to get
there.
Those aren't the real guys.
Well they don't have the understanding
of who they actually are.
The two do in order to face your own
fears,
like a lot of the bullies in the
assholes,
like you can get a certain distance with
that,
with physical power and genetic
attributes.
I mean some guys just hit fucking hard
and they're just good at taking a shot.
And if you stand in front of them,
whale with them,
they might catch you and knock you out
and beat your ass and you just got beat
by a bully.
But the reality is when those guys get
to a steep emile chick or Cain Velasquez
or you know,
the best of the best,
they're going to get fucked up.
Yeah.
Because those guys are just as just as
physically strong just as kate,
but also have their mental shit in
order.
They have their ego in order,
they have their understanding in order.
And those guys are some of the nicest,
most down to earth people you ever going
to meet because they get their ego
checked on a daily basis.
Every one of my met,
we have some guys that are customers of
ours.
Um,
Tj and Mendez and I mean they're really
sharp guys.
Very Sharp and very nice,
very polite,
not assholes.
Very thoughtful.
I mean just great people to be around.
And they also recognize that same thing
in hunting.
They do.
You know,
Tj and Chad are gigantic hunt in chat
libs for it.
He wants to do that.
Like now on most really good athletes
that you would come across that are hot.
I mean like that's,
that's like their second passion.
I love doing tons of baseball players
and football players and I mean cause
like man,
what the intensity.
The same,
you get the same drug out of it.
Yeah.
This DNA,
right?
I mean those guys,
same guys were the hunters of the tribe,
right?
Are the athletes.
Yeah.
And it just,
it's a natural natural deal.
We had a,
Carson Palmer is a customer of ours and
he had never,
it's Kinda like you never been hunting
before.
Carson Palmer is a quarterback for the
cards.
I literally don't follow any other
sports.
That's awesome.
I can tell you everything you want to
know about mma or kickboxing or,
I love a narrow focus now I'm all about
narrow folk apparently.
Yeah.
So Carson won a thing called the heisman
trophy.
I heard about that.
Jamie told me about that.
It's this metal trophy thing that you
get for playing football in college.
And then he's the quarterback for the
now of the cardinals.
But then he was Cincinnati and he had a
guy on the team that took them hunting
during a off during one of their by
weeks,
put it up in a tree stand.
He never been hunting before.
He grew up in Orange County like I did
and he said the first time the deer
walked under a stand,
a buck,
he,
the adrenaline and the DNA of that
process took over and he is just a die
hard hunter now.
And it's all he wants to do.
When he,
when he's done playing football,
he,
he only wants a honey,
he wants to invest in Ku use so it can
be involved with hunting.
I mean,
it's just that happened for him like it
happened for you see,
it happens so much with athletes.
We have Brent Burns plays for the game
called hockey hockey that's on the thing
on ice with ice skates.
He actually,
well it is water.
If they freeze it,
these water.
Right.
Yeah.
And,
and he's the same way.
He just got into hunting and he is just
like,
this is the most amazing thing.
Yeah,
just DNA.
It's intense.
It's,
it's,
it's unbelievably intense and again,
incredibly rewarding.
I mean,
like when I go to the store and buy a
steak,
there's no reward.
It's like,
oh,
this is delicious.
I can't wait to eat it.
That's not like,
you know,
cooking up a deer backstrap that,
you had to get out of the mountains.
Yeah.
I love your instagram posts of your elk
steaks with the Jalapenos.
Yeah.
He'll be the next day.
The next day I went and cooked it up
just like you did.
Oh,
do I sweat like a pig?
I got sweat pouring out of the top of my
head.
Everybody's laughing at me,
but Mike,
it's so good.
Isn't amazing.
Oh Man.
With Jalapenos,
man,
if you tried it that way every way
possible,
you can't.
I've had it raw to burn.
Anything you can put on it.
Love it all.
Yeah.
It's the best meat you can ever eat and
my kids have been eating it for four
years now.
I have a six year old.
It's been eaten bear since she was
three.
So awesome.
Yeah,
it's,
it's the healthiest food.
It's,
it feels better.
It feels better when you eat it.
It really does.
Well.
It's flat out better for you too.
Yeah,
I'm,
and I'm really into pursuing the art of
cooking it in a bunch of different ways
too.
And that's another thing that I learned
from Rinella.
I'm uh,
getting Hank Shaw who I think lives up
your way too.
And he's a wild game famous chef who's
turned to becoming a hunter because he
was interested in trying to prepare this
food and be more connected with food.
So then he started hunting and then
using,
yes.
He uses a lot of local ingredients to a
lot of like ingredients from the area
where the animal actually lives.
It's really interesting too.
Yeah.
Do you cook?
I barbecue.
That's it man.
Style fire in me.
That's all I do.
If I,
if I can't barbecue,
I don't wanna Cook it.
Well that's the best way anyway.
It is.
You know,
especially now,
it really is.
Um,
but yeah,
talking about chefs,
like Guy Fieri,
he's like a client of ours.
You know who he is.
Yeah,
sure.
Yeah.
And so he's,
he's actually become buddies with,
with Brendan because he likes to smoke
meat and cook me like you didn't and
we've got to shave his head.
Yeah.
Right.
Cause it's not the eighties buddy.
He loves us.
Frosted tips.
Got To go down holding down a hack that
stuff off.
We got a three yeah.
Three haircuts for one this morning.
By the way,
if you haven't noticed,
we got damn your haircut looks good.
Thank you very much.
Locks of love.
No hope here.
Yeah.
Cause it gotta have to shave their head
too.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
Um,
like chefs,
like Anthony Bourdain,
he took me hunting in Montana recently.
We went on a pheasant hunt and uh,
you know,
he,
he's a big fan of doing that as well as
cooking the animals.
You know,
that he,
he hunts himself and showing you how to
prepare it properly and he's done that a
bunch of times on his show and involved
in it.
Yeah.
It's fun.
It's actually fun to put different
Marinades,
put different recipes together.
I mean,
I throw it on the barbecue,
but there's a lot that goes into it.
And then also you know,
something that people don't do.
I think enough of with wild game,
they wonder why it doesn't taste right.
It's proper aging.
Your meat.
I don't know if you'd do that with
yours.
I do sometimes,
but most of the time I just cook it.
Yeah,
I mean it's better if you're agent,
you can do a quick age of your fridge.
We put up like on a rack,
like a in like a pan or a plate with
like a wire rack that gets it off the
bottom of it and then put foil over the
top and let that blood drain out.
And how long do you age it for?
I'll age backstrap for 10 days in my
fridge.
Really?
And it is so much better.
What does it smell like?
It doesn't smell like anything really.
Nothing.
How come it doesn't stink after 10 days.
And your friends not rotting,
it's just aging.
They do that with beef.
Right.
But then the outside of it is all black.
But that's what you're supposed to do.
You're,
you're cut off the outside edges and
that's what you do.
It'll trap as well.
What you'd do with any me.
Yeah,
but that outside doesn't stink.
Nope.
It just gets dry and it actually builds
a crust.
You Trim off the crust and cook the
middle million times better.
What is the temperature that it has to
be at when you're doing that?
You can cook it medium to cook a medium
rare.
I mean when you're the giants,
if you're going to quick age,
it goes on your fridge.
Just the normal frigerator temperature,
which is what,
I don't know,
36 38 degrees.
But when they like dry age meat,
when you go to a like one of those
shops,
similar temperatures,
my brother went to culinary school.
He's the one that taught me that real.
It was like you need to age your meat
cause you'll get all the blood out of
it.
The blood is what causes a Gamey or
flavor and also it also tend to rise as
your meat when you agent try it right?
Because you take a piece of back strap,
put it in the fridge with little bit of
soy sauce and some brown sugar or
something on it.
I mean,
you're not eating sugar anymore,
but if you do that,
it'll,
I mean it's phenomenal.
I don't know if it would go bad.
It's never,
I've never left it long enough where you
couldn't eat it.
But,
uh,
I mean I've,
I've left a backstop for weeks,
weeks,
weeks.
It doesn't rot.
That's interesting,
isn't it?
Does more sustainable because it doesn't
have all that fat on it.
Like a beef steak,
the age beef.
Right.
But do you do that?
And it just seems weird because people
don't do it,
but it's like,
like a guy I know that big African Ph,
he'll take a whole hind quarter.
Um,
the guy's name is Steve Colbert and he
told me this,
he'll take a whole hindquarter and put
his fridge in a fridge at his house for
30 days.
And then it's the best.
It is.
So a Ph for people don't know as a
professional hunter,
which in Africa is like a guide.
It is.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Do you know Steve Cabrini?
No.
So he's a bow hunter.
Really cool guy.
Big Guy.
Um,
he's basically killed everything in
Africa with a bow.
I don't know that anybody else has ever
done it.
Like this guy's the real deal.
It goes into the gnarliest places,
but he takes,
takes people hunting over there and
stuff,
but almost,
almost entirely a bow hunter himself
like stud and
you know,
I'll,
I'll introduce you to,
it's really cool.
Like everything and out.
No one's killed more animals in Africa
than him.
Everything.
He's been everywhere to everything.
You know what?
Just think of the sink,
thinking of his meat,
sit in the frigerator for 30 days.
It doesn't go bad.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
I mean it's a cover it in foil,
put a rack so the blood can drain out
and they can sit there for,
it'll be a man.
You'll be amazed at how long you can age
it and how good it is when you do.
Is that the key?
Because I've had me sit in like a,
like a bought a steak at a store and let
sit in my refrigerator for too long.
Then you open up the meeting like,
oh,
it smells terrible.
That's already been age two and sitting
on itself.
Right,
right.
And that is that the key that it has to
drain out of its blood.
And so you don't wrap it up.
Don't put it,
don't,
don't contain it right underneath.
And then you can,
the other way,
if you don't have a rack,
you can take,
I do as a bowl,
right?
Or a pan.
I'll put foil over it and punch holes in
it so it's suspended in that blood and
go through those holes in the flow that
you put foil over the top,
slide it in your fridge.
Did they sell like a rack for aging in
your refrigerator?
Nurses by little,
they make little cooking racks that are
just like screens with that are designed
to go on a pan and get stuff off the off
of a pan.
Know.
That's interesting.
I'm going to,
I'm going to try that.
You've got to try it.
Yeah.
I haven't been doing that.
I just don't make a huge difference.
I marinate sometimes.
You know what I like to do?
I have to take Newman's own Balsama
yeah,
just put it in that for a,
you know,
five or six hours.
He was a great man.
Yeah.
That's excellent.
And then pull it out.
Someone,
um,
served a sheep.
I was at a,
um,
uh,
a camp.
It was absolutely at to hone.
We were,
it was a pig hunting and someone,
um,
brought by,
uh,
some sheep back straps and they had it
marinated in a Italian address.
God's right there.
There's nothing better than dall sheep
or stone sheep back shops.
Yeah.
It's amazing how good they taste so
good.
Civitas is that the best meat of all the
meats is the same as then horn,
big horns,
not near it.
It's,
it's good.
And like the harder you work for it,
the better it is.
But like a sheep tinder line pulled
right out one minute each side as hot as
you can get it.
And I mean,
it's just,
that's it.
Yeah.
Right.
You just want to see her at,
no one will ever know how good it is
because they never make it out.
No critical ever get a bite of that.
Right.
Because they never get it out of the
mountain.
Nope.
Never comes out.
Most of the time you cook it while
you're up there,
right?
Yeah.
A lot of times.
Yeah,
I do.
We have a thing called man Kebabs,
which is you got to hunt down the
animal.
You got to kill it.
You got to bring it,
you got to pack it back to camp.
You got to start a fire that you create.
You got to harvest the willow stick that
you're gonna put the meat on and you
chop it up.
You slide on the meat and at the time we
only had top ramen seasoning,
so we sprinkle the top Rosin Rom
[inaudible],
put it over the fire.
That's a man Kebab top vegetables.
It's kind of kind of funny though.
The top Ramen is the CS,
but top Ramen sees you.
It's fucking good.
It's fucking,
when I used to eat that stuff and I get
some of it,
I'll just a little bit on the table,
put it on my finger.
It's delicious too.
Good season,
good seasoning.
You get really creative.
You don't have much.
It's probably a good idea to like to
bring like in camp,
it's a small package.
It's already sealed up.
It's like a good size for,
it's crazy and you do it as like a rub
and the bobs on that thing.
Granted you're starving to death by the
time you kill this animal and put out
the fire.
But it is off the hook.
Well,
when we,
uh,
when I hunted with Rinella the very
first time and shot a mule deer and then
we ate the liver that night,
we hung up most of the meat and tree
because it was like pretty close to dark
and we went back the next day to pack it
out.
But when,
uh,
we went back to camp and ate liver and
onions,
like from an animal that died two hours
ago,
it was like the most insanely delicious
food I've ever had in my life.
You couldn't,
I couldn't believe how good it tastes.
Yeah.
You were hunting.
Did you guys,
you guys handed down from the ferry up
on the Missouri up there?
Yeah.
On a cheap in there a bunch.
That's it.
Cool.
I saw a lot of sheep up there.
It's probably pretty hard to get a tag
though,
right?
Hardest place in the world.
Is that the brakes?
Yeah.
Hardest place in the world.
Get a tag.
Yep.
That's interesting.
They're just doing a really good job of
making sure the populations go up.
Biggest sheep in the world and a,
yeah,
they had giant balls.
We spent a whole segment of the show
concentrating on the balls of the sheep,
like Rinella.
Made a video.
Put as few as you can find this cause
it's pretty funny.
Um,
we were,
we were there and Rinella like is
obsessed with these big horn sheep and
their balls.
And he's like,
the moment I kill one of these things,
I'm going to,
I'm going to kill it and I'm gonna take
one of those balls and I'm just going to
eat it.
I've eaten an eat like an apple eating
them.
They're great.
They're here.
They're,
they're the,
they're the biggest of anything that I'm
like,
Oh yeah,
that you killed.
Yup.
What does she bought this?
I'm not doing that for Steve.
Just make good like everything else.
You're like Cameron Hanes.
Cameron Hayes won't need heart.
He won't eat liver.
We want to do anything.
I'm like,
you're crazy.
When we shot an elk house cutting the
heart,
I was like,
you're going to eat that?
I'm like,
fuck yeah,
I'm eat this around the hole I put in
it.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
You've got to cut around the hall.
Yeah.
Depending on what's a bow and Arrow,
you don't have to do that.
You know you get that weird funky led in
your mouth.
Yeah,
exactly.
So,
uh,
this is a,
him and I up there and he started,
he started
obsessing about the balls
exactly where you guys are.
I mean exactly where you're at
when you go home and tell people what a
bad spot I took you to.
And you say,
well,
we did see a lot of big orange zone.
What they're going to say is something
like,
what kind of dumb ass once mule deer in
big horn county.
You've never seen a scrolling.
I'd love to show you if you turn right
or house on diapers.
No,
it's perfect.
It's like a,
it's like a church bell.
This is like a church bell hanging down
translate
or they also eat crazy animal.
No,
this isn't one of the real do at church
bell.
Yeah.
That's impressive.
Here it goes.
The first thing I'm going to do when I
kill him one and then punch my tag and
I'm going to eat the contents of that
sac just straight out.
Just raw
apples.
Why?
I don't know.
I feel a calling to do it.
He's another really important factor in
educating people by Connie cause he's a
very well read,
very intelligent guy,
very educated and really very,
very ethical.
I mean is it ethical and as driven as
you can be.
Do you read this book?
American Buffalo?
Yeah.
Well I didn't read that one.
I read the other one in the mediator
one.
Oh,
did you read the American Buffalo?
I heard it,
yeah.
He's got to this to the Max Buffaloes.
Tragic.
Yeah,
it is.
He spells it out so well.
Well he had this guy on his podcast,
Dan Flores,
who is a wildlife biologist who a wild
f.
His story and I should say it's an
amazing podcast where he details the
history of animals and European settlers
coming over here and the wiping out of
the various animals and what's being
done to try to restore that.
They're primed.
They're trying to do something called
the American Serengeti where they're
trying to put together like a,
an area like a protected area,
like as big as yellowstone,
but that's actually good involve
hunting.
Really.
You're buying property right now in
Montana that's going on.
What's it going to be?
I don't know that much about it.
I only just bought a property that's not
very far from where you guys were there
that um,
that,
that there,
it's in block management,
you're allowed to hunt it,
but it's,
you know,
they're,
I think they're pulling
the cattle off it and um,
but you know,
that's,
that's a huge success story right there.
I mean,
those,
those sheep were planted back in there
in 1970s.
It's probably the biggest herd and in
Montana and certainly the best sheep
hunting in the world.
And they were planted in there in the
70s and started hunting in about 1990.
They restarted hunting again.
And I mean they were totally brought
back from money from an auction tag,
but a transplant in there and they've
exploded onto the landscape.
They were shot out by mark and hunting
and,
and domestic sheep interaction,
you know,
years ago and then brought back and now
it's the best place in the world,
you know,
and that wouldn't happen.
A lot of hunters and is an amazing
success story.
And that's,
that's an also an interesting thing.
These auction tags,
which is really weird,
where you let someone,
you give them this opportunity to hunt.
And a lot of times these guys are
spending hundreds of thousands of
dollars.
I got it.
The most expensive tag in history,
$485,000 right there.
Missouri breaks.
Yeah.
What,
2013.
Yeah.
He wanted those balls,
guy paid.
So I mean,
there was a huge ram that,
uh,
a couple of hours,
three of us that,
that guy did it.
And,
uh,
there was,
um,
yeah,
like I paid $485 and the,
the money thing about that is really
weird.
It's this perception of some rich dude
like you're paying for an opportunity to
bypass the system to do something that
you would normally have to draw.
It's as simple as that.
It's not like I'm going to spend this
huge amount of money and you know,
it's this huge head hunt in this ego
thing and he got guys live here.
I mean like there's so many
misconceptions about what goes on with
that type of thing that it's not even
funny.
It's a tax write off.
It's a donation of wildlife if you
really care about wildlife and it gives
the guy an opportunity to take,
you know,
and again,
if you're a billionaire,
if you've made a ton of money and you
care about wildlife and you love to
hunt,
why would you not do that?
It's not that weird.
I mean,
I mean it's all relative.
It's money and said donation.
And yes,
we had,
we had this big sheep,
he spent 18 days hunting and it's the
biggest one ever been killed with an
auction tag in the United States and it
was a phenomenal hunt and the guy you
know was glad to donate the money and
it's,
you know it's,
it's provided new sheep transplants
money for wildlife that would not exist
if they didn't do it.
It's one tag and raise a half a million
dollars.
Well that's the big contradiction when
people talk about hunting and hunting
being for conservation,
how it helps conservation that.
That is one of the biggest examples of
it is how much money goes into helping
these animals and habitat preservation
and reintroducing them to areas like
with the Rocky Mountain Elk Foundation
has done with reintroducing elk to a
bunch of different places is the biggest
success in North America.
I mean they were shot basically into a
few places and they've,
they brought them back through and it's
strongly been through money by guys that
are fortunate enough to be able to do
it.
And it is,
it's a total misconception.
I mean you are paying,
the guy is paying money as a tax
donation and he's giving money to
something he truly cares about that he
loves and has probably grown up doing
is,
you know,
this guy was self made,
started painting boards and West
Virginia and started a bank and made $1
billion.
You know,
like he loves hunting.
That's what loves.
He was not,
it's not some rich guy panda.
You don't put a head on his wall and he,
and,
and he was glad to do it.
And you're paying for the opportunity.
I mean,
the thing that's always lost in it is,
is the dead animal or whatever the guy's
paying for the opportunity.
We had no advantage over anybody else
was the same season everybody else did.
And the guy,
we ended up killing him,
you know,
a great big Ram,
which was,
you know,
obviously the goal,
but I mean,
one sheep raised a half a million
dollars and does incredible and,
and a guy,
he was banned for the opportunity.
He's not paying for it,
you know,
it'd be a hell of lot easier to buy a
great big head to put on your wall.
Then it would to be to spend that much
money and then go out there and maybe
not get them.
But the,
the pursuit is,
is what drives and how does that work?
Look,
there's three guides.
So do you,
did you guys scout in advance and find
those unique?
Those are unique situation.
We had a son in,
in it's,
it's a basically a three year story of
following one ram Ram me called
[inaudible] 52 and in 2010,
a friend of ours was with a guy who
killed around,
um,
up in the breaks,
same deal,
exact same area you ran.
And there was a big ram standing with
it.
There was two big rams together,
killed one of them.
And,
and uh,
the next year when we were up there
scouting,
we came across this ram.
I'm like,
that's the same ram in the photo.
They took a photo right before they
killed it.
And then we tried to hunt them in 2012.
Didn't get him.
And in 2013 it was like this,
this ram.
He was really big.
And then he slipped through two years.
Nobody got him smart old,
smart old sheet.
I mean,
really smart.
And it was all of a sudden,
you know,
we let a few guys know that,
hey,
there's not an unusually big ram up
here,
and if,
if you want a chance to hunt it,
and it's unique in the timeframe and the
fact that there's not always big sheep
around.
I mean,
this is,
this is one year.
This ram is alive right now.
And we told a few guys and five guys
went,
you know,
there was five guys that are willing to
pay half a million dollars.
I went to,
I mean,
there was five guys bid in over $460,000
for the opportunity to hunt this area.
Look at the size of that thing.
Oh my God.
There you go.
The horns on that thing are insane.
Yeah.
Will he edinger Al Mckinney and myself
and,
uh,
I mean,
we spent 18 days like rattlesnakes out
there and it was a,
it was an awesome hunt.
I mean it's,
uh,
it's,
it was a smart old ram.
It was,
uh,
it was just a,
just a really cool deal and the guy and
we ended up getting it.
Um,
how far do you take it from?
He almost killed it with a bow.
We,
I snuck him into 12 yards,
came over the top on it and a resident
hunter,
uh,
being a dick came down the ridge and
spooked the sheet that spotted us,
knew we were hunting as sheep and came
down and spooked the ram.
But he should have killed it with a
bowl.
We,
I mean a hunter with a sheep tag where
the sheep tag.
Yeah.
They do it on purpose.
Yeah,
I think so.
Yeah.
I mean if you saw three guys and you
knew that they had a guy with him that
had paid $485,000 to be there,
new,
all this,
you would probably think I'm probably in
the right area.
Right.
All these guys.
Yeah.
No Shit.
But that's where
it gets weird with public land,
right?
Yes.
Does that Ram bugged out?
We killed him 10 days later.
Nine miles from where there and how far
was the,
the shot when he killed him,
he shot him at four 60 that's a
different,
oh wow.
That's another,
that's a different realm.
God Damn,
that thing's massing.
Tazy so I was fortunate to be on both of
those.
That's two of the top five sheep ever
killed Montana and 10 days.
They are just majestic beasts.
When you look at the,
what nature has given them in their
head,
like what a crazy animal that develop
these gigantic battering rams out of the
top of their skull and the photos really
don't do those things.
Just know you put your hands on those
horns.
I mean,
it's impressive.
Both 11 and a half years old.
I mean that's,
that's the end of his life.
I mean he's,
you know,
he's,
he's running his full course that Ram
actually did not run at all,
that Ram had a broken shoulder and we
had seen him for a couple of years.
He had a really small body and he was
actually a nondominant sheep and it was,
it was just kind of floating around out
there.
He wasn't really,
he was,
he was just physically,
physically past his prime.
Yeah.
So did you like fall or something or
hunting accident?
Hard to say.
It's hard to say.
Yeah.
I mean they have a tough life.
That it's for an animal like that to
live that long.
It's nature is so incredible and it's
diversity that this is something that we
have here in North America,
this incredible animal.
Just a strange looking.
I mean almost [inaudible] we're so used
to them.
We know they exist,
so I don't think we kind of appreciate
them as much as if it were just
introduced to them as an adult.
If you'd never heard of or seen it
before,
probably blow you away.
Totally.
But a crazy animal.
It's kind of a battering ram on its
head.
It does.
I always say like with desert sheep,
you know they had this tiny little neck
and it's like when you see one out in
the desert,
a desert sheep,
a big Ram,
it's like they wouldn't look any
stranger if they were green.
Like if they landed on Mars,
if they landed on Mars and all of a
sudden there was a desert,
she popped his head up.
You'd be like,
it's about what I thought it'd be here.
It's rocky and dry and his next this big
and he's got a 50 pound head.
Like that's about what I thought.
Have you ever seen the video with the
ram and the cow?
Buttheads I haven't.
Gerrymandering does a video,
crazy video where this ram starts moving
towards this cow and the cows calf and
the cow decides it's going to Headbutt
this ram.
Watch this go full screen.
Check this out,
watch the ram comes in in division and
the cows like,
fuck this so it sees it.
Watch this.
The callout Chiodo and he gets up.
I can't tell if that's a bull.
Is it a bull or a cow?
I can't tell them.
That's hard to tell.
It's a blurry ass picture or blurry
video,
but it's just this tiny little thing
that weighs about 150 pounds.
The cows,
not much more than a thousand and chaos,
he said,
but I've seen him.
I mean,
I've seen rams that had their skulls
broken entire horn torn off like that,
that amount of power.
I mean they,
they get up and when they hit and then
just like this state of right after gag
know where after you take a huge upper
cut and they just stand there and kind
of go,
oh,
and then they kind of come back and I'm
like,
all right,
let's do that again.
I didn't get enough of that.
They've got,
they've got cte.
Yeah.
Oh for sure.
I don't do a football study on them.
Yeah,
exactly.
You got to wonder like what?
What did,
what crazy design that nature has
figured out a way to have all these
various different does it,
here we go,
boom.
And they just sit,
stand there.
Look at this collision.
That's when to make your stock right.
Then.
Well,
one of these dummies needs to figure out
how to dive under and get an uppercut
going.
Get some leverage.
Yeah.
Just like don't head bottom to come.
You got to Juco and then slide under.
You're talking about,
you're talking about the balls.
Big Horn sheep have two moves.
So it's this move right here.
And then when they're posturing and
kicking each other around their other
movies,
they get behind each other and smash
each other in the balls.
Oh,
the front kick to the is a big horn
sheep.
Look at the balls,
look at the balls in these things.
Watch this.
Boom.
Look at these nuts.
Look at there's nothing.
And if I had nuts like that,
I'd never wear pants.
I'd be like,
everybody's just deal with what I've got
here.
That you wouldn't be doing a podcast,
maybe doing videos.
That'd be in the poem business son.
And that echoes for like the sheep I
hinted last fall.
That's how I actually found him.
Oh,
you hear here in the middle of the
night,
boom.
It sounds like gunshots going off real
and you'd get up.
I got up and yeah,
it's,
it took me four hours to figure it out
where they were because it echos all
over.
But you can get about every 25 minutes
you'd hear boom.
And it just sounds just like a gunshot
and it's like,
okay,
they're there and you start honing it in
and boom,
there they were.
Wow.
10 Rams and they were butting heads.
Yup.
It's pretty,
pretty cool.
Like little things like that.
It's like he just so cool.
Well,
being out there in the wild,
you get to experience firsthand the
diversity of all these wild.
They're like mule deer with their
incredible racks or elk or or big horn
sheep and there's so many bizarre
creations and there's so much diversity.
Are they hitting each other in the
balls?
Oh yeah.
How rude.
Look at it.
He's just kicking him out balls.
He's like,
fuck you.
I'm going to get behind you and kick you
in the ball.
I was like,
no,
no.
I already know that move
every time he's kicking the other sheep
in the balls.
Get five minutes.
See if you get kicked in the balls.
Oh yeah.
They've got no time.
No time.
It's hilarious.
They know that they have balls,
so they go to attack them.
You know,
what the fuck did they figure that out?
How do they know that?
Balls or I guess they know that they
have balls.
You have balls that big,
you're going to figure that out.
Something's going to hit those things.
But what a bunch of dickheads or magic,
they're fascinating to.
They're like,
I mean,
when they're in the Rut,
they're,
they're a totally different animal than
when they're,
when the early,
you know,
when they're,
when they,
when they get late in the year and start
chasing like there's nothing,
they just go insane.
Isn't that also bizarre that they have a
season where they have to have sex where
you lose your mind?
Yeah.
Once we got that too.
But we get to do it all at all at
college and we can jerk off.
Yeah.
You can alleviate it yourself.
So he could think clearly.
But these poor bastards,
you know,
all the wait all year,
all year,
no one,
they go nuts.
Just getting ready.
No wonder they're balls are so big and
dearborn with weapons.
Yup.
You know,
and,
and as they get older,
the more dominant ones of the bigger
weapons,
which is this what a strange system that
nature's figured out.
It is,
isn't it?
And it's also strange to me like how you
see when it's all over,
they bachelor up like when the ruts
over,
like we,
we went moose hunting and BC last year
and when the Rut was over we found these
like bachelor groups of Moose there
probably were trying to kill each other
just a couple of weeks.
We know how it is though.
He beat up somebody.
Your best friends after,
right?
I guess.
Right?
You don't bang his girlfriend either.
Yeah.
I don't think anybody has a claim on any
of them.
They're all just running around trying
to try to score.
But I think when it's all over there,
they're probably like,
what the fuck was,
what were we doing just a couple of
weeks ago?
Yeah.
What came over us.
I think they knew.
I know,
but it's just strange that it comes over
them so strong here and it's so strong
and the rest of the time,
like a big Ram wants nothing.
Like if you were,
if your sheep hunting the rest of the
year and you see in use,
you're in the wrong spot.
They want nothing to do with them
really.
I don't blame him.
Yeah.
Same,
same with big,
same a big bull elk and serve their
purpose.
Same.
Yeah.
Same with bullets.
I mean,
aside from the Rut and a few times or
they interact the rest of the time.
Like if you're seeing tons of counts,
you're in the wrong spot.
Well,
that's what I told you about,
uh,
when I was in Montana and we saw a
hundred elk together.
All cats this time.
Yeah.
No,
no.
All cows.
Yeah.
We're little spikes or something.
Yeah,
exactly.
I saw like one spike.
It's just,
it's so fascinating that diversity that,
that nature's created so many different
animals.
Like that one hunting gives us the
opportunity to truly see it as it is.
Oh yeah.
There's like a national park or
yellowstone.
Yeah.
To see it as it is up close in its
natural habitat when it's quiet and you
get the sales thing the way it's been
for so long,
does it,
don't you feel like when,
when you sneak up on an animal too and
you,
you lock eyes with that thing,
it almost,
you almost feel like you're in,
it almost feels like a different
dimension.
There's all like that.
He gets your,
you're in this world that they exist in
and there's,
there's no cell phone service.
There's no people anywhere near you.
It's a very strange environment.
It is.
And it's like everything else gets tuned
out too.
It's like this laser focus of,
of what's happening right then all your
senses go way up.
I mean,
at least for me as far as smell and like
you can feel the slightest breeze in
your face and uh,
you know,
you can see that at,
I'm gonna move really,
really close like you'd never would
notice before because of that laser
focus intensity just kind of takes over
your whole system and there's some of us
stock on something.
There's something about tricking an
animal that's whole focus in life is to
not get caught.
That is a great sense of feeling like
you do everything right in the right
place and this thing walks by and like,
oh and an Arrow was already on the way.
It's done deal.
It's like you did it.
I mean you,
you,
you outsmarted something that's 10
million years where the genetics and
you,
you got to fear,
especially with bow hunting,
like you got it in that close and got
them.
You not only that,
we're clumsy.
Our noses sock,
we can't see very good things.
Dog Shit.
They have ears like satellite dishes.
They're spinning around left and right.
Looking all over the place.
Trying to find you a mule deer in
particular.
Yeah,
those giant ears.
Well and their nose.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
The power sent this crazy.
Yeah.
I've seen the craziest stuff at the
farthest distances.
Hundreds of yards.
Fuck this done.
What do you think the wind's blowing at
your back or on your face?
It's actually going around the mountain
and ends up right back at it.
It's just amazing what happens.
People are like,
Oh,
you're out there hunting,
chasing the poor,
defenseless animal eating defenseless.
And it was the offensive side.
Have a way more big ones.
Right.
I always get them if they were
defenseless,
I mean there,
there,
there is smart.
I mean there man,
I've,
I've seen him,
you know I've,
I've,
I've hunted animals where they got one
with you are gone.
Yeah.
Well and like gone for days.
No gone.
Never saw him again.
Gone.
He figured me out.
They're round wolves.
Totally.
You know bears mountain lions.
I've seen,
yeah,
I've seen deer do some crazy things like
lay down on the ground and like hide
from hunters.
Hunters walk right by him like within
yards and just do some really cool
stuff.
Sneak away from people and you go,
those guys never knew their five yards
away from a giant buck and that they
just totally out smarter than him.
It's the coolest thing.
Yeah.
There doesn't Denmat dumb humans walking
by.
He's like,
no problem.
I was laid down.
They'll never see me.
Just imagine if you were a 300 pound
animal that had escaped some them
killing you all the time.
That's your every day is try to get some
grass and your system and get the fuck
away from everything that wants to try
and get laid once a year.
Polygamist yeah,
definitely not.
You know,
you're sleeping outside in Montana in
the winter.
Yeah.
I think it's amazing and we're so lucky
in this country that the people like
Teddy Roosevelt and the people that
founded these,
these areas for public land,
they set them aside and I'll allow these
places to,
to be established with these animals can
live and we never have to worry about
them being taken over and they built
malls there.
I mean,
it's,
it's a really beautiful part of America.
Even if you don't have any desire
whatsoever to hunt.
The fact that you can go up there and
backpack and camp and be in that natural
environment,
it's a really beautiful thing about
America.
Totally.
Yeah.
I mean,
the perception of hunters,
we're just out there to kill something.
That's,
for me,
it's a small part of the whole thing.
It's a good part though.
It is.
But it's be an outfit too and it is
definitely good experience all that.
I mean obviously I wouldn't be there
without a tag.
I get invited to go hiking or go to a
park all the time or you know,
National Party man,
I'm not interested.
But I mean it's uh,
I mean being out in the mountains and
the wilderness and seeing all this stuff
is just awesome.
Yeah.
It's not like if you go hunting and it's
unsuccessful,
it's a zero.
It's like a sentence that's like a six
out of 10.
If you,
if you get a big elk,
it's a 10 but if you,
if you go out there and nothing happens
like us hiking's a four so it's two
points above a hike.
Hiking,
we call it.
Especially if you actually see the
animals.
If you don't see the animals,
it's like a five.
If you don't see anything,
you're like,
what the fuck were we doing in this box?
If you don't see anything,
you need new friends.
Yes.
Somebody somebodies been lying to you or
he just,
something happened,
you know,
you never know.
Now these big horn sheep,
they're very difficult to get a tag for
right in Montana.
Like there's so many of them now though.
Um,
yeah,
it's,
but I mean there's still not enough to
go around.
It's,
it's the most,
it's the most exclusive tag in the
world.
How many do they give out in Montana to
get about 150 a year?
I drew one last year.
Oh Wow.
I mean the odds in the best place at
like one in 500 it's a lottery system.
And then the lodge,
like in the roughest areas that have
better odds are like one in 101 and 500
that's incredible.
So Brennan drew a sheep tag or Montana
to hunt one sheep.
Yup.
You had one unit?
Yeah,
he showed me the picture of it when he
drew the tag goes,
I'm going to kill the sheep.
How did you know that?
About the show?
That he killed it.
The sheeps dead?
Yeah.
You're a savage.
Oh,
was like the,
I'm so glad I'm not that cheap right
now.
When you do that tag,
when they,
when they lose their mind once a year,
they come out to the winter range and a
buddy of mine,
Robbie doctor had found this ram on the
winter range and she sent me a picture
of it and said,
dude,
you know,
this is a huge ram in an unusual area.
And uh,
we applied for it.
I mean,
it's happened before like,
oh,
there's a big sheep.
Nobody knows that.
We didn't tell anybody.
And then he showed up again the next
year.
It didn't draw the tag.
And then last year I drew it and it was
like I drew the tag and I was like,
he's on the outer edge of the life
expectancy of a sheep.
You know,
it's a 500 square mile area.
I'm going in there.
As long as it takes 500 square miles,
the Hud one sheet mindblowing.
That's pretty great.
Think about that.
Well,
that is the ultimate pursuit,
right?
While talking about the most difficult
challenge of hunting with a bow.
Yeah.
How many are you getting from,
uh,
just outside my effective range?
Long shot.
Like I snuck in,
I snuck in at 15 yards for 20 minutes.
It took me 24 days to find him.
I,
I passed up 33 eight year old or better
rams.
Two days you spent scouting to,
oh,
I mean I lost track of time.
I mean I put,
I put on,
I mean,
I'm a crazy amount of job.
Do you have,
we all need one of those.
He said,
he said he's like,
when,
when I was like,
dude,
I,
I drew the tag and like I was emotional.
I drew it like,
I mean people don't understand like,
oh,
you got to tag the hunt.
This thing,
it's like 25 years in a row of knows how
many people put in for the tag.
And there's 150 tags available.
So we just 150 tags in the whole state,
the whole state.
And how many people in this area?
Two tags.
So you got one of two to 220 people
applied for two tags.
And I drew one.
Wow.
It was like amazing.
And you know,
and I,
I had a picture of this ram and like he
had showed up on the winter range and
then disappeared into this abyss called
the Bob Marshall Wilderness.
And it's like,
I'm going to go in there and find them.
And how many total days we hunting?
Oh,
I mean,
24 days,
honey.
I 124 days.
I kind of scouting days you had was like
ridiculous.
Yeah.
So you're going back and getting food
and going back to him soon.
Four or five days at a time.
And like all good things,
you know,
like all the most amazing things.
You know,
timing is kind of a bitch.
We had a baby due
in the middle of my wife.
We're fucking kill him right out there
chasing one if did you see any of the
rams?
Yeah,
but there wasn't quite big enough.
Third,
a third 33 I passed up 33 rounds before
I push.
Hold on a solid.
Yeah.
So,
yeah,
I mean it was after this one cheap and I
thought,
and you know,
like when you talk about really getting
to know animals,
he had showed up on the winter range and
twice we had pictures of him two years
around on the winter range.
And it's just like,
okay,
we got a picture of this big ramp.
Well,
what I started looking at the pictures
and comparing them and all of a sudden I
noticed that in in one picture from 2013
or from 2012 and one in 2013 he had the
same two young rams with them a year
apart,
10 miles apart in distance,
and he had the same two sheep with them.
So all of a sudden I'm like,
you know,
most people would be like,
oh,
it's just a sheep.
And it was a little half curl.
And then there's a young kind of unique
look and ran with them and I'm like,
it's the same room.
So all of a sudden I got a Ram band that
I'm looking for there.
You know,
it's kind of a symbiotic relationship.
Young rams allow old rams or old rams
allow young rams to follow them around.
They show him kind of the hills and they
kind of tolerate them.
It's not like,
Hey,
you're my buddy or anything.
They just kind of like when when the
census start to slip,
you'll see old rams with young rams and
they're keeping an eye on their back for
him.
And I see.
So I figured out this Ram who was 13
years old,
which is the oldest,
so I end up killing him obviously.
And he was 13 years old,
which is the oldest ram killed the whole
state of 150 by two years.
So he's beyond,
he's off the charts old.
So he had these two young rams with him.
So I,
I I,
you know,
basically you have known enough about
she behavior.
I was like,
okay,
I'm looking for this old ram and this
massive area,
but I'm actually looking for three sheet
because if I see either of those two
young rams without him,
I'll know he's dead and it makes a big
difference in 500 square miles.
Look for three sheet versus one.
Apparently.
Huh.
So I still retain.
So I went in there and I was like,
I'm going to go find every sheep and the
entire unit.
And I went in there and I found,
I thoroughly believe that I found every
single sheep in there.
I counted almost 50 more sheep than the
biologist thought was alive in there.
And
do you take photos of these?
Oh yeah.
The bottle to the biologists.
Yeah.
It's,
he's kind of changed his management plan
in the area a little bit.
Like he knows more about it.
I mean it's,
it's like I went in there because,
you know,
for,
since I was a little kid,
it was like,
man,
that's something I always wanted to do
and then you're going to get this
opportunity.
It was like,
I'm not going to go do the easiest
thing.
I mean,
I passed big rams,
a big rams of my bowl,
but I wanted this ram.
I wanted to have like an epic con and
just to see if I could do it,
see if I could find it.
And uh,
and I hadn't found those young rams.
And on the 23rd day,
I said it,
heard him pop and heads started glass
and cutting the timber apart and all of
a sudden,
you know,
another key to the puzzle.
All of a sudden there's that little
young ram that was with
him standing in the timber.
Boom.
I got him go down there,
there's 10 rams in there and my ram
walks out.
That's him.
You know,
it took me two days to kill him,
but I found them.
And you doing all this by yourself?
Um,
I had a,
I had my buddy that originally found the
sheep when I found the rams,
I called him.
He's,
he had a regular job and uh,
it was about a 10 mile,
uh,
is about a 10 hour hike and he hiked in
to help me hand signal and kill it.
That's a good friend,
right?
Who Hiking 10 fucking hours for you.
My friends be like,
dude,
uh,
my wife just told me I gotta go on
hiking.
I call impact it out for you.
But yeah,
it's a good friend.
He found the ram originally and then,
yeah,
and I,
I called him and he disappeared,
you know,
he,
he jumped off of work like,
like his wife was in labor,
you know,
Jesus Christ like I to go,
you guys don't like the same breeding
cycle like rambling or his wife was
like,
he left like that.
Like it was like,
Hey,
my buddy found the ram,
I got to go.
And,
and his word,
you know,
it's a Montana thing.
He's like the guys that he works with
her like,
yeah.
Oh Man.
You got your wife was ready to pop and
no,
she had,
we had had the baby.
Oh,
you'd already high left.
Yeah,
I left.
We had the baby September 11.
So I had left,
uh,
like seven days.
Um,
I,
I went out and we had the baby.
Everything was great.
And then you left right after the baby
was born.
It's even worse.
You sleep at all.
You don't want my wife.
I mean,
she was just like a couple of days like,
you know,
we've got everything settled back in and
she was,
she was basically like,
get the fuck Outta here.
Wow.
His wife's amazing.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
She gets it.
Well that's a good story to end this
with because that sort of embodies what
I appreciate about what you guys do,
that you guys are really like the one
10th of the one percenters of the
outliers of the crazy people that are
pursuing this as a just an incredibly
difficult biological puzzle.
It is,
you know.
Awesome.
I appreciate what you guys,
you're going to get to,
we got to be challenge sheep hunting.
You got to come.
I'll do it.
Come on man.
Let's figure it out.
Let's definitely figure it out.
It's next level.
But listen,
thank you guys for just being you and
thanks for doing what you're doing.
I,
like I said,
I love when people are just fucking
going for it.
So this was a cool podcast for me life,
man.
It's cool to watch you guys geek out and
see all your,
your innovation and,
uh,
I'm a,
I just appreciate it.
Love the coverage.
Love what you do as far as exposing the
world to hunting.
It's awesome,
man.
My pleasure.
So,
uh,
people want to get ahold of you.
Uh,
Kay.
You,
I you on twitter,
right?
Is that what the twitter handle?
I believe so,
yeah.
Then clips on instagram and then our
website,
[inaudible] dot com.
All right.
You can get it.
There it is.
Folks tonight
didn't seem like.