Come on,
let's go.
Boom,
and we're live.
David Goggins,
your book is fucking fantastic,
man.
This has been my running partner.
The audio version of it has been my
running partner for the last week was
fucking amazing man,
but I appreciate that.
Thank you.
When you guys are doing something very
unusual.
The book is Great.
I've read,
I've read it like sat down and read,
read,
but the,
the audio book is really interesting
because you and the gentleman who wrote
a with Adam,
Adam Skolnick Skolnik who reads it,
then you come on and talk about things
in between.
So it's more than just the book is the
book plus is the book plus like a
podcast,
right?
Yeah.
So hold that.
Came to be man as um,
as I was going through this book for
last year,
we would go through change stuff.
I have so many stories,
man.
We went through interviews with people,
so many stories.
He would come back and read it to me,
all my changes and when he read it I'm
like,
man,
this guy has a great reading voice.
I love his reading voice.
And I started getting these different
ideas about doing it,
like,
you know,
what maybe he can read and I can do my
podcast thing on the side and he can
like after each chapter in between
chapters,
make it real interactive type of thing.
And that's kind of how it came to be,
man.
At the beginning I got to be honest,
the beginning I was like,
who is this motherfucker talk and for
David,
Dave like,
take you redo this,
why don't you do it?
Why are you?
But,
but it works.
It really does work.
Like as as it goes on.
And I got also,
it's very,
obviously you and him are good friends.
So when you guys are talking then I
don't mind him reading for you as much
for some strange reason.
I know it doesn't make any sense.
Well,
I wouldn't say we're good friends.
I'm just joking,
Adam,
that you can hear it right now.
He became a pain in my fucking ass
during this process,
man,
because you know,
he's just a,
he's a real anal guy.
You know,
he,
he helped out a lot.
You know,
I'm a,
I'm a real raw,
sadistic type of mindset and he,
uh,
he helped me put that on paper man.
So I give him a lot of credit for that.
Well,
it,
it comes across the book is outstanding
and you know,
it's,
it's more than just sitting,
sitting across from you and you telling
your story is one thing,
but this long detailed history of how
you became to be the person you became.
I think it's very educational for people
because they can realize like,
oh,
he wasn't always this guy.
This is what's fucked up about people.
Like you see a guy who's like you,
who runs,
I mean,
how many ultra marathons did you run in
a row?
You've got some saying,
I ran 808 weekends in a row to stop and
think about that.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Eight hundreds means eight.
One hundred mile races,
eight weekends in a row.
One hundred mile race will put you out
for fucking six months.
You know,
when you ran eight of them,
eight weekends or it's a fuck.
It's fucking insane accomplishment.
It was nuts.
You think about a person like that,
you think of them as a static fully
formed
version,
right?
You don't usually get to see,
and especially someone like you who you
went into so much depth about your rise
and fall and rise and fall.
It wasn't like a straight linear process
between you getting inspired and then
you becoming this bad motherfucker.
No,
it wasn't like,
um,
what's that show called?
Um,
that will smith misplace that,
that black guy who kind of makes it in,
um,
in the financial world,
a pursuit of happiness.
I never saw that.
Yeah,
it's a great movie.
It wasn't like pursuit of happiness,
man.
Like,
like with a guy struggles and he gets
over it and he makes it.
I fell on my ass.
I thought I've got the top of Mount
Everest and Mount Everest,
this fucking slide right underneath me,
man.
I was like,
God dog.
I start from scratch again.
Scratch became my friend.
Literally man.
So you know,
that's,
that's how you're putting the book
match.
Going up,
going down,
going up just to real raw version of how
my life was in.
It was so in depth to go back through
your life with a fine tooth comb that I
almost got embarrassed.
Even put it out there to people.
Yeah.
That's been our stay up man.
Like even me right now to talk to you.
I'm in the car for a fucking hour
getting pumped up because I'm a shy
introverted leave me alone type of guy.
Like I'm still that motherfucker who is
six years old,
you know,
at a play who can't say as line because
I know I'm going to stutter in front of
five people.
So I walk off the stage.
That's still me.
So everyday I'm fighting that dude.
So people think,
oh my God,
man,
you got a podcast?
Looks so crazy,
so evil.
No,
I'm trying to be locked into Joe.
So my mind isn't veer off saying let's
run out the damn door because people are
watching me on the fucking podcast on
open the damn door and get out of here
man.
So that's the real me.
So I'm not sadistic man.
I'm focused on.
We have to do to stay locked into the
game of life.
And that's where.
And that's why I tell people,
man,
I,
I go there,
I go there.
That's one of the reasons why this book
is so good is because you're so honest
about your vulnerabilities and how you
overcome them.
And for people that see someone who's
obese,
who's done great things,
you just assume that they're are
different than you,
but then you hear about your
insecurities and your pitfalls and all
the things that went wrong with you.
And you realize what God dammit,
those the same things to go wrong with
me.
Like maybe I have that inside of me and
I've just never summoned it.
Right?
And I'll tell you this.
I started really realizing that when I
started overcoming myself,
I started getting around these real
alpha males,
these hard,
hard men.
And I always put people way above me
when I was growing up like my God,
they had to have a lot more than me to
get to where they're at.
And a lot of them did.
But once you get around the best of the
best of the best people,
you can kind of start breaking them down
and realize that man,
you,
you're just as fucked up as me like,
like we all have.
But all you did was you hit it better.
Your,
your,
your upbringing,
your mom and dad,
your society,
the way you were raised,
it hit it better than that mind.
You weren't the only black kid or there
was like five in
a school,
you know,
I can't hide going through buds.
I was the only black you can't hide.
But I started realizing just because I
looked different than you allow you my
first can hard either.
So it started giving me courage to
watching people that were all have a
story.
We all have a jacked up life in one way
or another.
Some of us don't have the guts to talk
about it though.
And that's where I found the guts to
talk about mine.
Well,
there's some this purity in physical
pursuits,
right?
Because it doesn't matter what your
social status is.
It doesn't matter how people perceive
you.
When,
uh,
when it comes down to how long can you
stay in that pool,
when it comes down to how far can you
run,
when it comes down to how much can you
push yourself past the part where you
want to quit or how far can you keep
going?
There's a purity in that that it did
dissolve social order,
all that bullshit.
All the what people think about you goes
out the window.
It's what?
Who are you right now?
Right for you right now?
That's a true statement,
man,
and I look at it as psychological
warfare and that's where I started
learning that.
That life is one big psychological
warfare that you play on yourself.
You play on yourself,
man.
The most important conversation ever had
is with myself and that Shit I'll tell
him myself was so fucked up.
It was so wrong.
It was so misguided and other people
start to write that dialogue for you.
Also,
it starts to be what you say to yourself
every single day,
and I started creating a whole nother
warfare.
A whole nother battle started becoming
and I was like,
oh,
hang on a second.
Goggins,
you have these tools,
do you have these tools?
Your life was basically the perfect,
the perfect grounds for training for
where you need to go in your life,
all the beatings,
all the other bullying,
all that you know,
you going through a learning disability,
all the struggles.
It was an absolute perfect training
ground for you to go to where you need
to go,
and that's how I started looking at my
life versus woe is me.
Poopy pants.
Kick a rock down the street mentality.
It was,
no,
God just hooked you right the fuck up.
He hooked you.
Write up man with the perfect place.
You were training for the first 18,
19,
20.
So you were training for this stuff.
Man,
you have the advantage of everybody else
versus my God,
they're so above me.
They came from a great family.
Mom and dad love them.
They didn't have learned.
Then they started.
They didn't struggle.
Nah,
man,
you're struggle is what made you who you
are now.
So I started flipping this into a whole
different.
I started being a master of what I was
scared of.
I was scared of my mind and I became a
literally a master of that mind and
that's what now from now on,
it sets me apart from most people.
I started diving into that,
well,
that is a big part of the stories when
you go over your childhood and you know
your abusive father and then having this
great guy that was going to become your
step dad and then he gets murdered.
It's like right when you're about to get
out of it.
Everything looks good.
Boom.
Then he gets murdered.
It's like these things really did sort
of set you up to start from scratch
again and just go,
okay,
Roger,
that we start from scratch and now
you have that attitude.
You developed it through all of these
horrible personal experiences,
all the trials and tribulations,
all the evil shit that people try to do
to you that sort of set you up to be
able to deal in a way that a lot of
people can't.
Well,
well,
I used to look at my life from a
different vantage point and when you're.
When you're in all the muck and you just
walk in and muck and walk in and muck
and walk in and Muck,
you don't see that.
If you look off to the fucking left of
the muck,
there's a sidewalk,
brother.
Get off,
get off of it.
You have your head down.
Looking at this book,
once I saw the sidewalk,
the sidewalk,
I got a little break and I got different
vantage point and then from the sidewalk
I found a cliff.
Then I found a mountain.
I got way up high on top of my life and
look back down on it and said,
okay,
I gotta figure this out man.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm going to lie.
I'm starting.
So when you have a messed up foundation,
I started lying about everything.
I wanted people to like me.
I wanted to be accepted in some society
of life,
some social society,
and I said,
man,
this isn't the right way.
I messed up here.
I messed up here and messed up
everywhere.
And so I realized the worst thing that
happened to me,
I lost myself.
I never had myself and ever found
myself.
I had no self esteem,
so I knew through working out and
through learning God,
it took a lot for me to learn.
Also,
I started finding self esteem.
Once I found that that's when doors
started opening up.
I started.
I stopped caring about people that what
they thought being judged.
Wow,
if I say this,
if I started right now or you can make
fun of me,
I stopped caring about that and that's
my life started really changing for me.
Slowly but surely that that's such an
important point where you're talking
about the working out because a lot of
people when they think about working
out,
they're thinking of it as being a
physical thing.
Right?
No,
no.
I did it for mental.
Yeah.
People are saying my God like,
no,
don't,
don't look at it like I didn't care
about losing weight.
I didn't care about being the fastest
person.
I came out.
I wasn't making the Olympics.
I won't go into pros.
I could barely read and write.
When I was a junior in high school,
I wasn't going anywhere.
I saw working out as a way for me to
build calluses on my mind.
I had a callous over the victim's
mentality,
so I watched these movies.
I,
you know,
I talked about rocky last time I was
down here.
I always equated training to mental
toughening,
like it was a brutal.
People waking up early and do it.
All these things,
they look,
it looked horrible.
I was like,
wow man,
I got started doing that.
Not to get better,
bigger and stronger,
but that is what's going to build me.
That looks uncomfortable,
that looks brutal and getting up early.
I don't want to do that.
So maybe this long list of things I
don't want to do.
And through that I found myself,
I started like,
I'm like,
you guys aren't doing this shit in high
school,
you guys are getting up at 5:00
in the morning running over here in this
golf course.
So I started seeing myself very
differently than the average human
being.
I was like,
hold on a second.
I have some they don't have.
And that's when I started to develop
these things through working out.
It was this great never ending ethic and
through work ethic are developed self
esteem.
Now,
is this something that you learned?
Is this something you learn yourself
from,
from exercise yourself or is it
something you read or heard about?
Like what made you equate this,
doing this and doing these difficult
things physically to mental toughness to
being this is the discipline that you
need in order to get your life out of
the situation you're in.
So I never read anything.
You know,
I,
I could barely read,
you know,
so I wasn't reading back then.
I just saw,
I watched a lot of movies and I was
really big individualization and I
always equated working out to struggle
and I struggled my whole life,
but I ran from it.
So I started realizing,
man,
I got to start facing the struggle and I
got to be mentally strong for the
struggle.
So that's why I started coming up with
like I'm training for life mentally.
I'm training for life.
I'm not training for like to lift 400
pounds and I found out on my own pretty
much is that through this,
through through discipline,
through self discipline,
through repetition to tons of repetition
of the same thing that you don't want to
do it.
That's the.
That's the key thing.
Through repetition of things you don't
want to do.
You develop mental,
like like an armor for your mind starts
to armor your mind cut,
and I was like,
okay,
we suffer.
We suffer every day for what we do.
We do stuff that sucks every day.
So then when the suck stuff comes,
you're ready for it and that's how it
started coming up.
I just started being very uncomfortable
and now I'm a second.
Just a way of life.
It's a crazy thing to figure out though.
It's like the.
You figured it out and you didn't just
figured it out.
You embraced it.
Like when you were talking about your
senior year of high school,
when you're talking about your mere
being,
your accountability mirror,
like you had a radical shift,
like you just decided to not be a
fucking loser and to start tightening up
and start holding yourself accountable
and,
and get ready for things.
So I had this my whole life.
I don't know if people believe in God or
what.
I don't care what you believe in.
There's been this unrelenting voice in
my head.
We all have this voice is the right or
wrong voice and a lot of times that
voice guides us into comfort and my
voice got it mean to comfort a lot.
But I had this other voice I heard my
whole life saying,
hey motherfucker,
what are you doing?
No Man,
we gotta go over here.
We have go over here to,
to that rockpile over in the fucking
corner where nobody's at that.
That's where victories at.
We're over in that corner.
So this voice was giving me all these
answers.
Not I wasn't real smart kid growing up,
but I had this crazy voice in my head
saying over there is where the fucking
answers are and I will listen to it
because over there was pain over there
with me looking in the mirror over there
was me being accountable for all these
things.
I went through my life even though
people put 'em on me,
it's not mine to own and I didn't want
to go over there by myself,
but I had to in his voice was guiding
me.
There is God,
whatever you want to call it,
but that's what.
That's what it was in me.
It does just what you.
When you separate yourself from your ego
and what you were,
your insecurities and all you like.
If you were giving yourself advice,
you would say that's what the thing is
to do.
So do you think that's what it was like
your subconscious or.
Oh,
you stripped away from all the bullshit
when he couldn't lie to yourself because
it's a voice in your head.
Exactly it.
That's exactly it because it knew.
It knew I was a character.
I was trying to find myself through her
character.
I was making different hairstyles and
sagging my pants and I was off.
I was off,
man.
I was,
I was a clown,
I was a clown and I was like,
this is not,
this is not what you're supposed to be
in life,
man.
And it's ugly when you look in that
dirty mirror and you're trying to do a
new hairstyle to go to school.
You know,
I had the hairstyle one time where I
shaved the top of my head.
Not old men.
Had the hair,
like leaving their.
Yeah.
So I went to school with hair on the
side of my head and in my back and I
shaved the whole top of my head.
I just,
I went to school like that,
you know,
and then I'd had like with what did the
kids say I want that.
I don't remember what it said,
but I was just a funny dude,
you know.
So that was my thing.
I was the funny dude that came into
school like criss cross came out and I
was in high school so my pants are
backwards.
That's my pants backwards,
sag down past my ass,
crack short term backwards with a
toothbrush in my mouth with the reverse
part.
Reverse part is your head is shaved and
you have some hair on top.
Just a little piece of hair versus like
a like a part two here.
The part was on a bald head,
so it was just I,
I,
I was sitting at home instead of
studying,
I would think about what can I do to
impress the motherfucker at school,
why that became my life and that is,
is a long road to hoe to get to the guy
who says now you never smile on any
podcasts.
Look so serious.
I look at that shit.
I'm like,
you mother fuckers have no idea who I
am.
Who,
who,
where I've come from to get here today.
You could have probably been an
entertainer like you probably because
you were doing all that kind of share
some jokes.
Joe,
you do.
So what people read in this book can
hurt me.
It's a sad story.
It's a horrible story.
It's a tragic story.
It's a story that made me who I am day,
but you have to learn to laugh at
yourself too once you,
once you go through that shit I now.
So there's a lot of parts in there was a
of media gets a lot of white people,
you know,
and I have a routine that I won't do,
so people who hire me to speak,
I'm not going to do the routine.
I often do it.
Sometimes I think about it.
I was at 36 black guy to go through seal
training.
Okay.
Out of how many people out of probably
looking at probably 1112 to make it
through probably 13,000
seals.
I'll probably the 36,
36 black.
I'd make it through and over since like
the,
like the 19 forties,
you know,
you're looking at almost 70 years.
Wow.
Yeah.
So you know,
you know,
do the math on that.
So there's not a lot of black guys.
And so I take that and then make a nice
comedy skit out of that Shit.
You know,
like,
like the first time they tied me up and
threw me.
It's called drown proofing.
So I'm negative.
Boring as you know.
Me Too.
Oh,
I related to that big time.
When you talk about White Boys,
man,
there's negative boy you said like a
rock a rock.
And that's hard.
So matching the him getting your hands
and feet.
Tanya asked ass up for throwing the
fucking water.
Say Swim.
Ah,
it was like throwing a cat in the water
with fucking brick on them.
So I was just losing my fucking mind.
So if somebody had to get over,
you know,
and I,
and I found humor.
I found humor in my suffering.
I was like,
motherfucker,
what are you doing out here?
Goggins like this is crazy.
Like you're,
you're literally trying to reinvent the
wheel.
But I was trying to reinvent my mind.
I was trying to reinvent my mind and I
used every single tactic possible to do
that.
I didn't want to live,
you know,
live in this world where I was a fake
human being anymore.
And I was tired of blaming everybody for
where I was at.
My Dad beat me.
This happened.
I mean,
my dad ran prostitutes.
Man.
My Dad literally snatched the soul out
of my mom,
like my mom is still battling.
Like after my mom left my dad and this
one I'll talk about in the book,
she got married three times for a total
of six months,
you know,
I don't go there and I'm going to talk
about the guy she married.
So this woman was,
she's beautiful.
She's,
she's so smart.
All this stuff,
man.
This guy literally stripped her soul
away as a young kid watching it and I
had no soul to begin with in my,
in my brother,
he has a story that,
that he could write eight books,
you know,
my,
my dad just came through in this,
washed this all clean,
so to,
to,
to come around.
He died about four years ago.
Four or five years.
You're not for sure.
I didn't go to the funeral,
but I forgave him.
So I saw my dad through an eight year
old's eyes.
So we left when I was eight and then at
22 I went back to see him through a
grown man's eyes and he was the same
person I remembered,
but I had to.
You can't live with hate,
you cannot move forward.
As much as that guy tried to ruin all of
our lives,
that's where I came from.
I did.
I'd have figured out the origin of where
I started from.
So when I was going back through my life
trying to fix who I am,
the fucked up person,
I was like,
if your knee hurts is usually not your
fucking knee.
That's hurting is something else man.
Like it could be a tight quad,
it could be the right leg,
the left leg.
You got found out the origin of where
all this shit began and it was him.
So I had to go back to where you know,
my,
my roots in,
in the origin of all this happened in
his heart to do that.
Did you make peace with them?
I'm a big piece with.
So we didn't have a peaceful
conversation.
We,
you know,
we,
we left very granual.
He's a,
he's a,
he's a vicious man.
He wasn't vicious man.
I mean mid evil motherfucker.
So I had become a medieval motherfucker
that time.
I was 22 when I was a big boy and so I
was no longer the guy who was afraid it
was now like,
Hey,
I want to kill you type of shit.
And we were sitting at Denny's after an
all night skate or whatever the hell he
owned bars and skating rinks like that.
And so we were sitting down and we kinda
got into it and I was kind of left and.
But I had to make peace with it in
myself.
I,
I could not hold onto that.
Hake is,
hold on to that.
Hate was half the reason why I kept
falling into the same pattern of
failing.
I had to get out and start dumping off
some baggage.
Had to start figuring out me through him
and that's all he was there for.
He was the origin of figure him out,
figure out why he was so evil to my mom,
to me and my brother and I to start
studying him.
Like a lot of people have situations
where someone does something and we all
attack that person,
like,
like on the media,
if someone does something wrong,
everybody now is fucking perfect.
And we now judged this guy.
I don't judge them,
I don't judge anybody.
What I do is I started studying them.
Why did they do that?
Not in a judging way.
I want to learn from you.
And what'd you get out of your dad?
I got to.
He was,
he grew up rough.
He had,
he was very insecure,
had a lot of kids and his insecurities
just trickled over on to us.
So yeah,
he jacked us up real good.
But he never fixed himself.
So if you never fix yourself,
the next person in line is going to get
the wrap and we're next in line,
you know,
his,
his first wife killed herself or
whatever happened and you know,
got burned up in a house with some
craziness and his last stuff that goes
on there that I didn't put in the book
because I don't feel like going to
court,
you know.
But um,
yeah,
this,
uh,
it was,
it was last have,
you know,
one of the great parts about this book
is that you,
you detail exactly what was going
through your mind in terms of like your
weaknesses and how you had failed and
then you,
it's not just one time like you do the
thing in high school where you get your
shit together and then you joined the
military and then you wind up getting
fat again.
And then when you go you and you have to
lose what does 106 pounds in three
months to two to qualify for seal
training.
Seal training.
Yup.
That's insane.
Yeah.
Because we,
I realized at that time,
once again I failed again.
I thought so when you're talking about
is I took this as baptists,
you know,
I didn't know how to read and write
pretty much in high school.
I was like a fourth grade reading level
after that test a few times and I
finally passed it and when I passed it
actually drove my car to the,
to the Dag gone,
um,
airport and watch planes take off
because I was like,
I'm going to be on one of those planes
one day going to air force bootcamp.
So I,
I never,
I always fixed the things on the
surface.
So if I couldn't read and write,
learn to read and write,
I,
I would always fix these things on a
surface level.
And so whenever something hard was like
raised ugly head,
I didn't have any kind of tools to
handle it.
I mean I thought I fixed this already
man.
But no,
I didn't go deep into the dungeon of my
soul to say,
okay,
what is making you a quitter?
What is making you a weak man?
We're just making you afraid.
And so that's why I kept on quitting and
going back to start or not knowing how
to get through hard times.
And that's why I was telling people I'm
not a theorist.
I just studied
like,
you know,
I didn't study a fucking book.
I literally put myself in a fire
repeatedly like a sword.
You put a sword in a fire repeatedly,
repeatedly.
If you keep on doing that,
you're going to get an ice sword and you
keep on beating it.
You've got to beat the shit out of it
and that's what I am.
I became that much.
I said,
okay,
we can't quit.
We got to figure out why you are this
pussy.
Why are you this pussy man?
What is wrong with you?
What's going on here?
So I kept on putting a sore back in the
deck on fire and I just beat it harder
and I beat it harder before I knew I
started realizing hmm,
alright ma'am.
The brain is starting to get hard to
brain is starting to get hard.
I'm no longer a theorist.
I'm now a practitioner.
I put it in here.
We'll add a second while I was sitting
here because you can't dissect anything
in a normal environment.
You can't dissect anything is 72 degree
weather.
You must put it in the fucking freezer
and freeze the fuck out of it,
and then you dissect it.
That sector,
when it's miserable,
dissect the brain.
We're all thinking about,
I need to get outta here,
man.
I want to get out of the fucking
freezer.
Opened the door and he said,
no,
five more seconds,
man.
Five more seconds in the freezer and
nationally you start to pick that brain
apart and that's where all this stuff
did to me.
I kept on putting myself back into the
freezer or the fire in beaten the shit
out of myself mentally and physically
before I knew it.
This is what happened.
Wow.
You said it's an interesting way to self
teach.
Yes,
like most people that you know,
you talk to that a discipline,
they,
you know,
they have something that they read that
inspired them.
They have certain people that they look
up to.
There's certain coaches that taught
them.
There's certain important moments in
their life,
but for you it's a system of failure and
and reflection and then rebooting.
That's it.
Pete.
It failure
and people think a lot of times
department that I'm angry.
Oh my God,
you sound so angry.
You customer much.
I'm a guy.
Why?
Customer much?
Why you still crazy?
If you read my book,
I cannot explain my life by saying,
hey,
it was a merry fucking Christmas man.
No,
it wasn't.
I want you.
I want you to go there with me.
I'm taking you there with me.
I'm a storyteller.
I want to take your ass down.
Paradise.
We are so the house.
I lived in Buffalo,
New York that got my ass beat every day.
Funny.
We lived on Paradise Road and it was
anything but fucking paradise.
So I want you to go there with me.
You want to learn from me?
Let me take your ass home.
Let me take you there.
So that's the whole thing about it,
man.
We were scared to dive into our lives.
What made us who we are to beautiful
people,
that we are.
We all jacked up and so many ways.
That's the beauty of us.
That's the beauty of me.
I'm jacked up,
but I figured
out my own little process and how to get
on jacked up and how to.
I'm not going to get the same,
you know?
I'm not gonna get the same way you're
going to get there.
You may get there by going point a to
point B.
I'm going to get to point c to d to eat
it,
but I want to be there the same way.
You are just a little harder.
That's how I trained my brain,
so it was just different.
It was different.
Different thinker.
When you stop and think about all the
different times that you did have to
reboot and how you found like new goals
and you found new inspiration,
you fired up a new discipline and he
became stronger and harder and you've
got one of the things that people always
look for in life.
They look for a point where they can
rest.
I'm going to retire.
People love.
They love that expression.
The Golden.
I love that expression.
They love the.
They love the idea of a struggle as long
as it ends,
and then when it ends,
you're going to have a nice comfortable
spot.
It must.
It must end.
Relax,
man.
You've done so much.
You've really done so much,
but this.
The idea of reaching this golden year
is,
is it's a very flawed idea because it's
an idea that you're gonna,
you're gonna work hard,
but then you're going to reach the
finish line,
but there's no finish line doesn't
exist.
That's the scary thing about life,
my friend.
That is a scary thing,
right?
And that's what fatigues me.
People go,
man,
why don't you ever smile?
There's no fucking in my friend.
There's no end.
I know that you're,
you're,
you're going to meet campaigns after
this and listen please.
If you guys run,
put a number of the miles that you're
going to run and leave it.
Do not say,
let's see both died because that's a
hard man.
He is a hard man.
When Hans is a hard man,
he will run until you die or he dies.
Man.
Dude,
he doesn't.
He does those two forties.
He does ultra.
He's,
he's a sick fuck.
They see those are the guys I'm looking
for.
Yeah,
that's a scary.
Do you want the two of you guys?
You need to pick a number.
I think you guys are going to run 35
miles.
So we're going to do good.
Five's a good number.
We've been texting back and forth trying
to make it,
you know,
trying to make it sensible so we don't
go off the chain because if one of you
motherfuckers wakes up and has a good
strong espresso knows fuck it.
Let's do 300.
It's going to be on be a long day man.
Oh is it?
Yeah.
You know,
this new race that they're doing where
they're um,
you run for one hour,
you run like as many and then you have
like a bell rings and then you sit down
for a little bit.
You know what I mean?
Like there's like a four point one,
seven mile thing.
Yup.
Is that sick?
Fuck.
What was the guy's name that created
that?
That guided the Barkley Marathon?
Yes.
Yeah,
this crazy fuck.
Last.
So he had people running for days and
days and days.
He invited me out there for this race.
Yeah.
I actually got into the Barkley last
year but couldn't do it because the
book.
So I'm supposed to do it this year.
But now you know,
we'll see you again
how the schedule goes.
But yeah,
that that's a sick,
sick man.
I've done a couple of his races.
Like he has one called strolling.
Jim.
I actually won that one in 2016 but he's
a,
he's a sick man.
Is a stroll.
Strolling Jim race is probably easiest
race.
It's like it's like through the back
country of Tennessee is a 41 mile race
on the road.
It's one of the first ultra marathons
out there ever and my mom lives in
Nashville so it's like an hour drive.
I went up there and it was like when my
first race back after me being off sick
and jacked up for so long and I got
lucky,
had a good race and I happen to want to,
you know,
you were talking about so last muscle
yet,
although we have this thing now that
we've got,
what does that call the pro pro,
so.
Right,
so right.
Have you ever used one,
but also I saw it in there that that
little black contraction,
hard plastic thing,
phenomenal is evil man.
It's good.
It's amazing.
I started getting tightness in that when
I was running a lot,
like I'd never gotten tightness in that
area before.
It seems like that's a running thing,
right?
It's a running thing and also a very
stressed thing,
you know,
if you're a real stressed out man,
like for me,
I can talk about the origin were worth
thing.
Start.
My body was so wrapped tight,
I didn't know where to start.
So I started with the PSOAS muscle,
so that's a real good spot with the
problem with these races is the problem
with people like you.
That's the problem with these races,
like if you get you and another you
right.
And they're in there together.
Like you motherfuckers are going to kill
each other so long day.
It's a long day.
So as long as this a lot.
Because if they're doing a last man
standing type of deal,
right?
Yeah.
Like the first person to quit.
Uh,
it's a,
it's a real long day man.
I mean I've been up,
I got a couple of weeks under my belt,
man.
I know how to feel for her and 30 hours
a move.
Yeah.
And I know how to self motivate a lot of
motherfuckers don't know how to self
motivate man.
Like we'd like to put the headphones on
like before the big game and listen to
the music.
Yeah.
What the fuck did you do when the
headphones come off,
Bro?
It's you and your mind,
right?
I know how to do that.
That's the hard part member.
Listen to music when you run.
Never,
never told you Jamie's cheap as that
video I got.
But I uh,
talks about like running with music and
know what did you say?
I find it,
find the video will play it.
I might not be able to play it.
We get somebody else's content.
I actually,
um,
but I did during my last pull up record.
I listened to that song for rocky one
round 14.
Rocky gets knocked down the corner.
I've listened to that two minutes and 13
seconds long.
Listen to on repeat for 17 hours.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas man.
Seventeen hours man.
I went to assess the dark,
dark evil.
I have a picture of my hand.
The book.
I was in a dark.
I went to.
I went to a place,
man that I'm like,
I can do anything here.
We got to live here for awhile.
Can I kept on feeling that wreck?
I go,
I don't want to see a pull up bar again.
I mean like I did 67,000
plus man.
Like this is my throat.
I'm like,
I can't,
I don't want to see no pull up.
So I was like,
I'm,
I'm doing this.
Come hell or high water,
man.
I broke it out.
It's just a bit.
Let me hear this.
The music's not going to always be
there.
The TV,
those transactions,
total things,
Jim Right now and all this loud music.
People needed to get fired up.
They needed to stay motivated to fight.
Then you can go in the gym,
do whatever they're going to do.
Motivation that keeps you going
and when you're doing this the whole
time you're doing this,
you're doing some of the hardest chin
ups you can do.
You've got a chain around your neck
posted folks that are just listening and
you're pulling down on ropes.
You're doing chin ups on it.
Looks like taped up ropes.
Yes sir.
That's what it is.
Yeah.
Those are grip grip.
That's like Jujitsu guys.
Do a lot of those.
Yes.
I was,
uh,
I,
I spoke to the University of Alabama and
they were in there,
you know,
most,
most of these athletes,
man,
get hype.
So that music is blaring.
Yeah.
I'm like,
man,
what?
That shit comes off and you get popped
in.
Your fucking mouth was on the sidelines.
Brother was going to happen.
We can say to yourself then.
So that's,
that's how I trained my mind,
man.
I,
Trey,
with mark,
I'm going to get popped in my mouth,
man.
I'm going to get popped in the back of
an alley one day.
A man running around doing what I do and
there's gonna be no music.
You better fire,
figured out a pto.
Jamie's cheating.
I was telling you
when I first started running,
people said,
do you run with music as I know,
running,
cheating when you have music on
cheating,
you're cheating.
You listen to music.
But now listen to music all the time,
but more than I listen to music,
I listen to books,
but books on tape or audio books and
yours is,
like I said,
it's been the last two weeks has been my
running partner.
Well I appreciate that man.
Man.
That's phenomenal.
And you're doing this kind of
independently,
right?
Yeah.
So what I did,
man,
is I pissed off a lot of people.
I was um,
I.
So in 2012 I got an offer from my book
for $30,000.
I said,
you can go fuck yourself.
No a hill.
I went through brother.
So then everybody was like,
you know,
we don't see a market for a black guy,
ultra runner,
fat guy who couldn't read like a,
you know,
15 percent of Americans black,
we don't see many know people buying
your book.
They think only black people buy your
book.
There's some ignorant people out there,
man.
Everybody that follows me is white.
I don't have a plan like three black
flowers was always a big fan.
He's black.
Yeah.
He's like,
he's like a unusual species out there
man.
And so I'm sitting or walking around
going,
man,
you don't even know who.
Like everybody I talked to his wife
like,
you know,
it's the ignorance of the world and I'm
in these meetings here in this kind of
stuff.
So now 2018,
I get a $300,000
offer for a first time author.
So I'm sitting back,
you know,
and I'm like,
my God man,
you know,
I used to make like fucking $60,000
a year,
you know,
this is the biggest payday yet.
And I started thinking,
I took that one second.
I talked about the one second decision a
lot about what I went through my life,
what I've done,
and I was like,
you know what?
I struggled so hard in my life.
I went through so much that the biggest
trophy I own now is that book the
biggest trophy?
I don't know.
It's not the book itself,
which what's in the book?
It's what like,
I don't give a fuck if that sells one
copy,
honest to God,
man,
like like my what I did,
and that's what I hope people understand
your life in a journey you put yourself
through.
There's no.
There's nothing more than that and
that's all I want people to do is
realize that you have to struggle.
You have to struggle.
The bigger the struggle,
the bigger the piece,
the bigger the suffering,
the more peace.
I'm not just saying this because you're
here,
but this book is valuable.
This book is very valuable.
It's valuable to people like anybody.
That biography is a very valuable.
When you get to see the mindset of a
person who's done things that you
haven't done,
you get to understand like that.
They're overcoming sort of the same sort
of situations in their mind that you are
same insecurities and pitfalls,
but everybody's going through it.
Man,
everybody that's.
That's one thing I say.
I'm blessed that way,
that my story.
There's no color involved in it.
It's a human story about struggle and I
happened to be in so many different
situations.
There's so many people can relate to
about struggle that I guarantee you mark
my word,
you read that book.
There will be a section of that book
that resonates with is hardcore.
It will make you think if,
if you're not ready to think about your
life and think about,
you know where you can be and think
about what you haven't done,
the book's not for you.
If you're already ready to really self
reflect and hold yourself accountable
for where you're at and where you're
not,
the book is not for you.
It's real.
I've read a lot of self help books and
I've listened to a lot of self help
books on tape too,
and a lot of.
There's some of them that I have to shut
off after to shut off a quarter way and
I feel like someone's lying to me.
I just like,
you're bullshitting me.
You're just saying things.
This doesn't resonate with me.
It doesn't,
it's not working.
Like I'll give it a chance,
I'll give it a chance,
but if I'm,
you know,
half hour in two hours and it's still
the same nonsense.
I don't feel anything.
I'm getting itchy listening to,
you know,
I just want to pull the headphones off
and I'll just kill it.
I'll stop it.
This was the total opposite.
This one man I was,
I was,
I was running extra mile so I could stay
with the headphones on and the.
The thing that I think is gonna Happen
with this book is people going to get
it.
They're going to get a hold of it,
whether it's an audio book,
the or the book book and they're gonna,
they're gonna recommend it and then it's
going to spread like wildfire.
This is a powerful book.
This is a real self help book.
This is like,
this is a real one,
like it's not like someone orchestrates
this whole thing like what I'm gonna do
is I'm going to become a motivator.
I'm going to be a personal influencer.
I'm going to be that guy that goes out
there and tells people you can optimize
your life and there's so many of those
fucking guys out there.
That's not me,
man.
I know this one dude.
I ran into him recently.
I ran into him at this restaurant and
he's fat as fuck.
He's got this big old belly and I know
he does these,
these motivational things and I'm
looking at him like,
what are you talking about man week?
Look at your body,
look at your own temple.
Look at the vehicle you're carrying
around this fucking doughnut around your
waist is just.
He was eating shitty food.
Look soft and like,
wake up bitch.
People are doing that now man.
I mean people are talking to this noise.
Exactly,
and I see him,
I know him.
I'm not gonna say names,
but I know and I'm like,
man,
dude,
do you know why my life is miserable
right now?
Because I can't go on your show right
now,
your podcasts,
if I didn't get after it this morning.
So I cannot talk to people unless you're
authentic.
I'm authentic because I used to be the
most unauthentic motherfucker on the
planet.
Now I had this voicemail saying,
oh no,
I'll call you up if I lie to you about
something.
Even a white lie and Yo,
Joe,
guess what dude?
I fucking live here man.
Like that wasn't real.
It will bother me that badly now.
You know.
So another thing I didn't.
Which funny Bella's book stuff,
man,
I didn't set out to write a book like
literally man,
when I was 24 years old and a couch,
fat spraying for cockroaches eating
donuts and drinking milkshakes.
I did not plan on doing this.
All I wanted to do with chance to
fucking reflection in it.
They're going to mirror this is all this
about.
It's,
it's,
it's a byproduct of,
of that.
And that's,
that's the funny thing about it.
Like it was like,
oh my God,
David Goggins,
but you know what the hell?
I'm like,
what the fuck?
That's why it works though.
It works because you really did do it.
You really did do all those things and
you show how you did it and you're not
using any bullshit theatrical jargon.
You're not.
You're not saying a bunch of buzz words.
Can you live the life of an actual
person?
I can show you how,
and you look into this guy talk and he's
got a neck like a pencil,
and his body's just frail like you don't
even understand adversity.
You don't understand.
Overcoming.
This is not the secret is involved in
the law of fucking attraction attraction
here.
This ain't no attraction here,
man.
This love nonsense.
This is no nonsense,
no nonsense.
This is a real self help book,
man.
This is the real deal.
That's how you self help you self-help
by people who've done it and you learn
what they did and you realize there's no
shortcuts,
and then you learn to embrace that no
shortcut mentality and enjoy.
Enjoy the suffering and the grind of n
what we talked about earlier.
There's no fucking finish line doesn't
exist.
You know what's funny about that is I
have people now,
so when I was in the worst part of my
life,
those people want to bring you back in.
Those people's like you can see who you
hang out with like when you and your
worst and when you try to get better
with what makes it hard to get better is
that you are hanging around people who
like,
let's say you're an alcoholic,
you hanging around people who drink and
I say you want to stop drinking those
people and to bring you back in.
Like I used to be this guy,
this guy who was,
who you know,
who wasn't worth anything.
Now those people who are still there,
they're 16,
17,
18,
30 years ago.
They try and get you back there.
So the hardest part,
you got to see who you're hanging out
with,
man.
You gotta hang out with the people who
you want to be like the most people will
definitely dragged.
You know,
Jackie down and especially if you're
around someone that makes a lot of
excuses and they're always failing.
Oh,
those is like they're,
they're the opposite of inspiration
there,
like a vacuum to suck in it,
out of you.
Why are you doing today,
man?
Why are you getting up against so early?
Why are you doing this?
The people you're hanging around with
me,
it will suck the fucking life out of you
sometimes.
Just got to be alone with man.
Get your shit in,
and then there's also people that are
you going to be around that are always
failing and always fucking up,
and then they're always coming to you to
try to get you to help them become a
giant burden.
Yes.
Never look in the mirror and get their
own shit together and they're always
looking for external help.
That's right.
Always looking for a store.
People don't want to go in deep.
Met All the answer inside of you.
It's a very primitive way how I call
this book is written.
It's primitive.
It's,
it's,
it's very barbarian.
It's how we all think.
It's how it's how a man once walked the
earth and then we'd get all soft and all
these computers and shit.
When we start going away from the most
powerful thing we have is our fucking
brain is our mind and we don't use
anymore.
So you know,
it's like everything has to be so quick.
Yeah.
You use your mind when it comes to
certain things.
Right?
But what you're saying is you don't use
your mind when it comes to.
Exactly.
That is it.
You can't google that shit.
Right?
Hey,
let me google how to suffer.
No,
that ain't gonna be in there.
They ain't gonna be in there.
It could be in there.
It's not in there.
It doesn't exist.
Find some water.
We'll code.
And what's interesting is that that is a
mind thing and people think of mine
things they think of calculating
mathematics literature.
No,
no,
no.
There's many aspects.
That's it.
Don't overthink it.
Put your shoes on.
Lace them up.
So you got to do my friend.
Don't overthink the process,
but see what?
Because you've overcome because you've
accomplished so much now that even when
you talk about that moment of like
embracing that suck,
like you see the biggest smile on your
face,
like you've got a total different
approach to it than the average person.
The average.
You talk to them
about doing chin ups for 24 hours or
anything fucking crazy.
They don't look like there's like a.
A negative of doom feelings.
The thing about it,
man,
I talk about my book openmindedness.
What separates me from a lot of people
is they go into a daunting task in the
task is overwhelming.
Like when I heard the pull up records,
4,020
pull ups.
Not talking about breaking this record.
People are like,
oh my God.
I went right to a pen and paper like,
what are you doing?
I'm doing the math man.
We talking about.
I'm open minded to the fact that okay,
if I do five pull ups on the minute for
so many hours I can get 20 pull ups in.
How much time do you have to rest?
I was breaking the math down.
You have to be open minded to the
possibilities that I can do this.
Once you shut your mind down to the
possibility that it can be achieved is
no way can happen,
so that's my,
my,
my eyes and my body light up about
things because I know that if you're in
a fight,
you have to attack,
you have to keep attacking.
The enemy has to know he is not going to
give up.
You must break the soul.
Whatever the fuck is in front of you.
That's what I realized.
I was never breaking the soul anything
in front of me,
so that's why I came with a thing called
taking solos.
In my book,
I started to devise ways to break a soul
of a human being of a,
of an object,
of,
of whatever's in front of me.
If he keep on attacking something,
nothing wants to stand in front of
anything that is relentless.
Nothing to taking.
Sole part of the book is really
interesting because you talked about
like the the mind shift that you had
when you were in bud's.
Yes sir.
A,
that's an intense part of the book.
Is it is a,
that's when a lot of stuff started
clicking man.
I started watching those instructors on
the side because you know,
there's,
there's three shifts.
There's eight instructors,
three shifts because you know,
the guy's going through through hell
week.
They're up all day and all night for her
and 30 hours.
This is the promise.
Land of mental hardening for me.
I love this place.
And you have the instructors who,
who,
you know,
they've been there,
done that.
Now they're instructing you.
So they do the eight hour shift they had
their park is honest,
usually cold coffee,
drinking their coffee and they're
beating the crap out of us.
And when I started realizing I started
playing mind games and I was like,
you know what?
I bet these fuckers are looking at us
judging themselves about when they were
going through hell week about.
Let me see.
I'm looking at Goggins right now is
better than him.
I was burden that God Burton that fucker
over there.
And I was like,
okay,
you're going to judge me.
Right?
So I'm going to do to you.
So I started doing was I got my boat
crew.
Boat crew too.
It's in the book is a great,
great story.
Say kimber guys,
you can't break boat crew that can't
break broke crew too.
So is Wednesday is Wednesday and
everybody's broken.
Everybody's beat up man and like this.
And then you start moving like a robot.
Everybody's like,
just kind of just trying to get through
hell week now.
And your is at and they know Wednesdays
like that over the hump.
I love that.
You talked about that in the book too,
that they put it in your head Wednesday
you're going to be tired and another
thing they.
They tell you how you're supposed to
feel.
So you are feeling that way.
I was like,
ah,
don't let these motherfuckers tell you
how you're supposed to feel.
No,
it's day one motherfucker.
This is our one.
So I was getting my book who all jacked
up.
I said we're gonna.
Take these motherfuckers souls.
So when they had us doing a simple thing
that God's.
You're struggling with broker tours.
This launched in the fucking bone.
You're yelling.
Yeah,
you can't fucking hurt us.
Get her boat crew too,
and I looked on the instructor's faces
and it looked like someone had just
fucked with their soul and I looked at
my and my broker and I said,
hey,
guess what?
Those motherfuckers aren't fucking
tonight.
Can we own space in their fucking head?
We own space.
They're gonna.
Think about us tonight to think about
how they Kellen boners.
That's right.
How on Wednesday are these guys doing
this?
And screaming out,
you can't hurt.
We were.
We were bringing the fight.
We were tagging.
So.
So when you keep on doing that,
guess what?
People start doing.
I ain't fucking with these guns no more
so boat crew to got a lot more sleep.
Real crew to became that broker.
Like,
Hey,
we can.
We just kept charging and we start
fueling off of that.
We started a few,
not the fact that man,
it takes one second of energy to still
everybody's.
And then you have all the energy you
need.
So you need,
you need to look at someone's eyes.
You know how it is when you fight
somebody and you broke that
motherfucker.
It's like,
Oh God,
man,
I don't want to go back to the next
round and you feel like my gut,
I can fight all day.
I can fight all day long.
That's what taking Solos is,
but you have to have the will to heart
the courage to go that distance when
you're exactly jacked up.
We have nothing left to give and give
more.
That is an interesting thing about the
mind is that you can find inspiration
and when you find inspiration,
when you get charged up,
all the sudden you have energy.
That's right.
It's right.
It's weird.
I talked about in the book also is about
I learned how to control my adrenals.
If you know how you know how you get
that fight or flight response when you
get to move real quick and you know,
I,
I started learning the mind a lot.
How to get myself jacked extremely fast,
like in a horrible environment where
everybody's miserable.
I've learned how to really find strength
in the misery when everybody's
suffering.
Everybody's all poopy pants,
their mentalities down and everything.
I started just like my God,
this is where I shine,
and I started using all that misery for
tons and tons of tons of drive and
motivation to to to then lead people
further because you can get a lot of
power through misery and once people see
that,
my God goggins is fucking going.
Then everybody says,
Roger that let me get my shit and go to.
So I started realizing that if you can
just find strength just a little bit
longer,
you'll have a crew of people following
you along the way and that is another
thing that no one can ever teach you.
There's you.
You're going to have to learn that on
your
own.
You're going to have to figure out how
to pull that energy out of your mind on
your own.
There's not this,
there's no book.
You can read the.
All of a sudden I have it.
I've got the technique.
Now I know how to do it.
Now it's a grind that you have to start
and finish on your own.
You have to take great pleasure in the
fact that no one wants to be with the
fuck you're at right now.
Great pleasure in.
That almost makes it has to bring a
passion.
Nadia has to bring something very,
very weird audio man like you know,
people don't really understand what that
is.
When you're in the worst environment
possible,
the worst situation possible,
and everybody's looking like,
God,
man,
I hope this ends.
And you see that time slows down and you
see that you're,
you're feeling that everybody has that
look on their face like,
God,
this got to go.
I don't want to be anymore.
Have you ever gotten Rhabdo?
Rhabdo my lowest.
So yes sir.
Did you get it?
Yes sir.
When did you get?
I got it all.
My second pull up record attempt and I
talked about it a little bit in the book
there and I have sickle cell trait and a
young kid just died from Rhabdo from
sickle cell is not a good thing
obviously.
Um,
and you grabbed those a bad thing for
having sickle cell.
You have sickle cell trait,
but you don't have the disease will have
the disease.
A buddy of mine died from it when I was
a kid.
Really?
Yeah.
Oh God.
I used to fight with Mr.
train with.
Yeah.
He was always sick.
You'd have to get sick.
Is horrible.
Be Gone.
You'd be out of the gym for months and
come back and he'd just be trying to get
his body back in shape again.
Anyone up dying is a talented guy too.
When you got it,
what did you have to do?
So they put me in hospital for awhile.
That's when my hand got real messed up
and my fluids were extremely low and I
had done like 300 pull ups and they're
like,
man,
your body is wrapped up.
We just not drinking water while you're
doing it.
I was drinking water but not enough.
So I was sipping this carbohydrate drink
and um,
my calories are extremely low.
I didn't know how much I was going to
burn through.
And you burn through an awful lot of
calories,
man.
Doing that.
When you pull up to that many hours and
with the repetition,
with using a single points of just my
hands and my biceps,
my back,
like my body was swollen,
like the Pillsbury doughboy.
I mean it looked horrible and I'm so
they kept me in there for a while.
But how long?
Probably about a eight hours.
I was about eight hours and ivs and
stuff like that.
So they just is basically three.
She had Florida event tons of fluid and
they sent me home though.
So I went home that night.
And how long did you wait before you
jumped back at it?
I think it was back in the pool bar
about a week and a half later.
And then I broke the record of 66 weeks
later when I broke the record.
Jesus Christ.
So when you,
when you did get back on the pull up
bar,
that was how fucked up your body from it
was bad.
But what I do is like I've done through
everything it,
which isn't real smart.
I.
It works for me.
So I'm not saying do this is I've
trained through a lot of my injuries.
I started developing.
I started doing that in butts and still
training because I'm still training
though.
They know you got start from day one or
day is kick you out.
So I started from day one enough so my
third time going through I was really
jacked up when you had pneumonia,
he had pneumonia and I had really bad
stress fractures,
so my stress fractures,
so I was literally,
I would put a sock on and then duct tape
my foot all the way up to the top or to
the minimum ink or tending my calf it
can.
My stress fracture were so bad.
So like the pivot point between my ankle
and my Shin as cast that all the way up.
And so I went through for several months
for a few months with stress fractures,
which was crazy about that is they
healed.
By the time I got the third phase,
my stress fractures are healed.
Wow.
And I don't even know how rhyme or
reason behind it.
I ran on him a few months later they
were here.
Wow,
so I don't know what that means.
Push through the agony and eventually
your body just said this crazy fuck is
not gonna stop.
It's true statement.
Yeah,
it's weird.
A lot of my injuries I've just pushed
through and they've uh,
uh,
duct tape it up.
Have you ever had to have surgery on an
of.
No,
just heartless to couple heart
surgeries,
but um,
none of my actual physical body.
And what was your heart surgery for
again?
You talked about this for asd.
I had a whole no hurt.
Yeah.
So we've talked about more ridiculous.
Yeah,
that's what we talked about that too,
man.
They uh,
they,
they took me off and studied me for
awhile so they realized that my God,
I shouldn't even be in the military.
I wasn't even qualified to be in the
military,
the hole in my heart,
you know,
let alone being special operations were
jumping out planes and stuff like that.
So I was,
I was lucky.
How did they seal that up?
So they went in with a helix patch and
um,
you know,
through my,
for more artery femoral artery and they
went through,
put a patch and they realized,
you know,
I missed like three or four years have
been military career because this heart
surgery.
Wow.
Yeah.
So I was,
I was off of jump status dive status.
I was just a.
So that's what type of recruiting so
much.
I stayed in recruiting for like three or
four years and um,
you know,
I became like a navy recruiter when I
was uh,
you know,
doing this for awhile.
So I got extended there because the
heart surgery.
And uh,
other than that you'd never had to have
any other surgeries.
Um,
no meniscus,
no nothing.
No.
That's crazy.
And I've had some jacked up injuries,
but see how I grew up,
you know,
like I talked about in the book,
my dad and a believer in taking him to
the hospital.
Like this is how it was,
man.
It was,
it was barbarian stuff,
man.
But you know,
you learn to deal with it and you live
it refined,
you get and Mris.
Oh yeah.
Get everything checked out.
Matter of fact,
me,
I was terrified.
Mri machine for a long time.
I was like,
man,
that's.
Yeah,
there's a lot of.
There's a lot behind that man.
But yeah,
I've,
I've been checked out a lot.
I've had a.
So like I said,
like six years ago,
I started stressing out like I thought I
was dying.
I couldn't even get a bed.
So all that stretching out was from
pretty much all these injuries I had.
I had never really fixed in my body.
Get knotted up in more.
Not Up and up.
You mean it's going to heal one way or
another?
It's going to heal and when it heals,
not gonna heal.
Right.
So he'll all jacked up and crooked.
Yeah.
So I'm a.
I'm a cricket jacked up dude man,
but I still get it to.
It's amazing that you haven't had like
knee surgeries or anything like that and
consider all the running.
Moved on.
My left knee right now is in.
It's no joke.
So like I say,
origin of pain.
My right foot is messed up because my
left knee.
So right now I'm,
I'm,
I'm taking care of my left knee is
getting a lot better now,
but don't worry,
Cameron Hanes,
I was still be fucking out there running
with your ass.
I'm not going to get out of it buddy.
So if you listen motherfucker,
I will see you this weekend.
Merry Christmas.
Just so you know,
rather merry Christmas.
I'll say you don't know what's wrong
with the knee.
I have no idea.
It's from stretching.
So basically stretching.
Yeah.
So my whole,
because my body was in such bad
alignment from just what I did to it,
that now I'm in this huge dress routine
in my body's getting back into
alignment.
So your muscles,
like I was a power lifter man,
like I,
I grew these huge muscles.
Now I'm the small guy and I just.
And from the stress in my body going
through hell weeks and also my bias got,
became one not so as things start to
open up,
joints start to hurt,
things start to hurt.
And I'm like God.
So it's been this big long process.
So I'm fashion in better shape than
ever.
My organs work better.
I'm healthier than ever,
but I have these little tweaks here,
little tweaks there from the fact that I
am now.
My bio is locked in position from these
muscles being so tight now.
What do you weight now about one 82 83
and you were like 300 plus pounds.
You at your father's store?
I fattest when I weighed in it for the
military.
I don't know when my fattest was,
but when I weighed in on that scale and
Steven's sounds,
you'll hit that scale on me,
man.
It was two 97 and he was like,
brother,
you got to lose 106 pounds.
I was like,
fuck this.
I can't tell if we're talking about
other.
How's that possible?
So anyway,
it's just not a lot of time.
That's the crazy thing.
They didn't give you three months to
lose that.
Thirty three pounds a month is a lot of
fucking weight,
plus a few.
Almost impossible.
And that's what I thought.
That's what I thought.
But see you see the person I am now.
It was 175 pounds in high school.
So I was.
I was a skinny guy in high school,
so I made myself big.
I'm a small bone person,
so it didn't.
It wasn't it.
Trust me.
It was hard.
It was hardest thing I've ever done in
my life.
But what did people think around you
when they saw you?
Three months later,
you're 100 pounds lighter.
My mom couldn't believe it.
I'm a mom so I was living in
Indianapolis,
Indiana at the time and so I was trying
to study for this as Baptist again,
that you know,
I got to take it again going into the
navy and I'm out here trying to lose
weight and I'm working for this company.
He's spraying for cockroaches and also
are crap and I would lay in her pond in
fucking November in Indiana,
just laying or pond.
I was like,
I'm going to bus.
I got to get hard,
you know,
so I would lay in the pond,
the pond and go for a run.
Just all wet cold.
My Dad got his shirt with,
just frees up from ice and shit and I
was out to run and said,
what is wrong with you?
Man?
I'm like,
you were that kid who just didn't want
to wish ron with you,
so she started seeing the transformation
that can,
you know,
this guy is obsessed,
which I become somebody nestings new
man.
My Guy.
You actually lost that much weight that
fast.
I love the fact that you did it,
but what?
What hurts me is when I hear stories
about people that get like stomach
stapling and surgery and all that shit
that they do,
like you just need to just lose the
weight and if you just did it,
you just did it the right way.
You would have earned it and if you earn
it,
you keep it.
That's the thing about it,
man.
Like we like to take these very quick
fixes in life.
We want the six minute abs approach to
life.
Yeah.
Nah Man,
there's no permanent in that.
There's no permanent in that man.
There's no scarring.
They must be scarring.
Well,
people are terrified of this thing that
you're saying that there's no end,
that there's no finish line that
everyday is a new thing that you have to
earn it still after all the shit you've
done every day you get up and you have
to earn it.
Yes.
You know what's funny about that?
I want you to be scared of it and yeah,
just getting fuel.
It's great motivation in.
See if you look at it that way.
The reason why I speak the way I speak
because I believe in.
I'm saying if I ever shut it down,
that's the end of me and whatever my 100
percent will be.
I don't know what's gonna Happen to me
tomorrow.
Everywhere.
If you can't run,
I will figure what the fuck I can do and
do that.
That will be my new hundred percent.
You must continue to find your new 100
percent.
Whatever life throws at you.
You must find what you can do now and
maybe come to the best you know,
scientists of all time.
Who knows?
Watch out.
You know what I'm saying?
Who knows what that is?
An approach like this,
this approach,
this mental approach.
You can use that for anything.
Once you get past the quitting mechanism
of your mind,
once you get past that thing that this
is applicable,
you can.
You can take these lessons that you
learned from these grueling runs as
losing 106 pounds in three months for
all these different things of struggle.
You can take these lessons of struggle
and you can apply them to anything.
Yes,
I talk about it in my book here about
that race I did that made sill training
look like child's play in ranger school.
That that first 100 miler.
I did write shit on myself and all kinds
of stuff.
That 19 hours it took me with no
training.
I sum it up like this.
You're talking about struggle,
how you.
How you can put so much of life and
death struggle in that 19 hours.
I lived five years,
five years of struggle of happiness,
of of depression,
success,
failure in 19 hours.
That's what's great about some of these
things.
I you get a wide range of life in just
19 hours,
you know,
like when you get to mile 50 in your
mind saying we gotta get Outta here man,
and then you get like 60.
Okay,
we're feeling good.
You have all these highs and lows that
you have to manage within this suck fest
of 19 hours and that's what I get from
lot of these different things that human
growth,
no growth of the mind without friction.
There is no growth without friction.
There's no growth,
there's no growth and there's no
satisfaction.
[inaudible] like there's no real like
people want to sit around and rest,
but you don't really appreciate
restaurants.
You earned it.
That's it.
And people,
they think I'm their craziest person on
the planet.
You are so far removed from that day was
not even funny.
I was 290 pounds twice in my life.
I do not like to do the things I do,
but there's humongous satisfaction for
doing it.
The Schumacher satisfaction.
Lace on your shoes up saying I don't
really want to go for a run today.
And then running and then getting back
and saying,
wow,
I did it,
I did it.
And that's what it's about.
It's about these small steps to doing
things you don't want to do.
You know Jocko,
Jocko willink.
I know him.
Yeah.
Giagos not all great,
but I know him,
I know him pretty well.
He's,
he's awesome.
But every morning you look at that
motherfucker's instagram,
he's got a picture of his watch at 4:30.
He gets up at 4:30
every morning and he earns a sunrise
that's kind of like a motherfucker and
then earns a sunrise.
That's good stuff.
But it's that thing like there's no end
now as an n.
and it's scary.
That is scary.
The scary.
Everybody wants that holding hands while
the sun sets of retirement.
You walk it off into the sunset.
The biggest question I get is,
so when do you rest?
When did you recover?
Yeah,
and I don't want to scare people,
but the truth answer is I don't take any
days off.
No days,
no days,
seven days a week,
seven days a week.
Well,
what does a normal day?
Normal day for me,
a normal day.
So let's say a Light Day,
Light Day,
light day is at least a seven mile run.
I will every,
every for every other day,
so about four days a week.
Calisthenics,
plus gym workout.
So I don't do any gym workout without
hitting pullups pushups.
I called nickels and dimes,
so like five pool of 10 pushups or I'll
go,
you know,
quarters and whatever.
It's like 25 pull ups or in like 50
pushups.
So I have all these different things I
messed up so I will do weights with
calisthenics in every single night.
I stretch for at least every night.
I stretched for these two hours,
two hours every night.
Every night.
So you stretch after you're done working
out?
Yeah.
So at nighttime usually I'll be either
in a quiet room or I'll be watching tv
or I love sports.
We watching the game and I'm on the
floor man.
And that's what I do.
So you just stretch while you're doing
stuff that's stress.
While I do stuff,
two hours,
a long ass time to stretch.
Is this just because you try to correct
or correct years of not doing that?
No years.
Have you ever fuck with yoga a lot?
Yeah.
Yoga is this shit.
What do you do?
Hi Emma.
I have my own yoga,
so I kind of been in my own little yoga
for what my body needs.
I've done hot yoga several times,
yogesh,
huge yoga shoes,
like holding those positions and I'm big
and hold them for a long period of time.
So that's where I stretching that.
Other people said no,
hold stress for a long time.
I hold it for a long period of time.
Come trying to get full range of motion.
A lot of people go in for like,
like,
um,
like my shoulders are messed up.
I get surgery on it now.
If you only have for range of motion in
your body,
don't go in and get cut on man until you
know that your body is actually opened
up.
You know,
we start to get knuckle dragger syndrome
from doing pushups.
He never worked.
You're back,
you know,
like,
uh,
like a,
like your rear delts.
So here you are.
You start hunching over before you know
what your joints are out of whack.
You need to get for range of motion
before you know how fucked up you truly
are.
So I'm.
I'm always working on a full range of
motion like a kid.
They run so effortlessly there.
Always going for range of motion.
As you get older and tireder and sit in
more stressed,
your body starts to get more and more
tight.
Therefore,
your shoulders start to get a balance.
Not a not a joint out of socket there
free.
No,
it's popping.
Popping because you're fucking tight.
Open it up.
First,
open it up.
Can you.
Can you touch your hands behind each
other and raise them up behind you?
You know,
it's all these different ranges of
motion that I get real smart on from a
guy and I took it to another level.
So are you.
Do you work with a trainer or do you
always work out by yourself?
Everything I'd do.
I've never had training in my entire
life.
Really?
Never.
Not one time did he read about
physiology or exercise science or
anything like that?
Nothing.
But what about like when they learn new
shit about new ways to enhance shoulder
stability or new exercises?
You're not interested now?
I don't do for that reason.
Still to this day,
man.
Still this day,
to this day,
it is for me to become better mentally.
How I look has just become a.
like I have thousands,
thousands,
hundreds of thousands of miles on this
body running pullups,
pushups,
swimming,
whatever you wanna call it.
This body is what it is now is from
repetition is not from studying.
You know,
hey,
if you hold your plank for this long,
fuck all that bullshit.
I don't care about it.
I just do it for my mind.
Right?
I want to continue to harden because
that's the only thing that I want.
That's what I want.
I want to have that mind ready for life.
But you also want to increase your range
of motion,
range of motion.
She make sure that you're,
you're,
you know,
you're not causing any additional
injuries to.
Wouldn't you want to like stabilize some
areas that maybe you feel like you might
have weaknesses and find out new
techniques to do that.
Have you seen me with my shirt off?
No.
Stable is fuck.
He had his shirt off when you first came
here.
I walked in it.
Dave got here early and by the time I
got here he was already doing chin ups.
Stable.
It's stable.
Do some pull ups.
Push ups mast and stable shit.
Yeah,
but yeah,
but you're,
you know,
all that stuff is very important.
Honestly.
Just all jokes aside,
man,
full range of motion,
getting your shoulder rotation,
all that stuff is very important.
I,
I learned a lot about that coming up.
I had a lot of people I've worked out
with our smart a bottle of this stuff.
I'm a real old school meat eater,
like Bill Kasman hard type of lifter.
You not look like it.
Back when I was that guy in the back of
the skinny guy,
that's what I did and I got off really
big into human performance about the
body strength,
fitness.
That's what I wanted to be.
I wanted to be a hybrid motherfucker.
I guy that can run 200 miles and then go
to the gym with your meathead who
doesn't even know who's scared of
running it,
lift with him.
So that was my whole thing in life.
I want to be the guy who can run to
miles with the skinny guys and then go
to the gym with the big meat heads and
said,
okay,
loaded up,
let's go.
So that was my whole thing.
Who does a very difficult thing to,
to tie the two of them together.
When you think most people,
when you think ultra marathon runners or
people that run long distances,
they're very thin,
very thin guys.
Like when you were talking about the
first time you ran 100 miles that you
did dead lifts the night before.
Like that is just fucking preposterous.
Nobody does the.
No.
Yeah.
So me and the guy talked about the book
a silverback gorilla is what I call them
in the book.
That's not his real name obviously,
but yeah,
he saw me go into my car the night
before,
my first hundred mile race and it was
like,
he called me out,
said,
hey Goggins Kamir know when a navy seal
cause y'all got to push you through
three hell weeks.
She's like,
you know what?
Fuck I gotta go to the gym and lift
heavy now.
So we're doing squats,
deadlifts,
power cleans,
heavy bench presses.
And I'm thinking I have to run 100 miles
tomorrow.
But I also knew he was coming out there
to watch me.
So I was like,
know what?
You put me through three hell weeks.
You were my instructor.
So now it's my turn to educate you on
what a human can do.
Can I know you can be sitting there
thinking while you're watching me with
your wife and your kid and he's worked
out with the night before we went real
heavy that the heaviest shit were sore.
Your team,
you can sit there while you watched me
run around this one mile track.
How the fuck is he doing that shit right
now?
We lifted heavy as hell and he's running
100 miles and never has been passed 20
miles in his life.
I use that for a lot of fuel,
so that gym workout,
Mr Silver back gorilla.
There was a lot for my mentality that
that brought with me.
I knew I would see you and he came at
mile 50 with a package of six donuts
that I chopped up with the quickness.
So yeah,
so I used that workout for a lot of
motivation.
I knew he'd see me.
I know he'd be thinking advantage and
not get Rhabdo that you know what?
I don't know what I got that day,
but I talk about in the book again that
when I went home that night or that
morning,
that was single handedly nothing even
close.
I'm 43 years old now.
There's nothing even close to that pain.
I knew for a fact I wasn't the guy that
tub.
I knew I.
I knew I was done it.
I was talking about dehydrated,
known nutrition.
I was eating Ritz crackers and mild
plex.
That was the worst pain I've ever
experienced in my tire life.
I was pissing Coca Cola out of me.
It was,
it was bad.
It was bad.
She probably did have rhabdo.
I guarantee it.
I guarantee I will have some bad calls
us Coca Cola,
no Bueno,
no Bueno.
So it was bad and my ex wife was like,
she's,
you know,
she's a nurse and she called my mom up
and mom had a,
her,
her friend there was,
it was,
it was a doctor friend of hers said,
Hey,
you got to give them to doctor
immediately.
And I was like,
okay,
you gotta give me that fucking phone.
I got called up,
Chris Cosmin let him know I did 100
miles so I can get in the badwater it
didn't go as like,
you know,
like I planned but I did get into
badwater after another race,
but I'm putting you do a marathon,
like how later.
So basically I had never run a marathon.
I did the hundred mile race first,
no training,
but I had signed up for the marathon
because it was a first last vegas
marathon running down the strip of Las
Vegas.
So Las Vegas had a marathon.
But it's the first time it's gonna go
through the Strip.
Two thousand five.
I'm like,
Hey,
I'm gonna.
Sign up for it.
I went onto an Iraq.
Did you know did the appointment.
When I come back I'll be training for it
and I go do this race with my family.
Me and my ex wife.
My mom signed up for it.
So in Iraq,
me and my boy sledge in the book,
we're just working out.
We're like,
we're doing crazy workouts in my cardio
was 20 minutes every Sunday on the
elliptical trainer.
That's the only cardio idea.
So I'll call myself training for a
marathon.
Right.
So then,
you know,
my,
my boys got killed in,
in the incident that happened on
survivor,
you know,
the whole operation red wings.
So that's what prompted me to do 100
mile race after the 100 mile race in
November.
It was like two or three weeks later,
that marathon that we all signed up for
that I didn't train for.
I didn't train for 100 mile race and
didn't it off of this like,
Hey,
I'll drive there with you all because I
tried to run the day before,
like I can't even run.
I can't run down the block.
So I didn't do it.
So we were driving to the race.
I said,
hey mom,
my mom's gonna walk it.
I said,
I'm going to walk it with you,
my ex wife.
I said,
you can go and take off,
do your thing,
run your race on walk my mom.
That gun went off in some fucking
happened.
I took.
I was like,
what?
I took up like a Jack Rabbit
gone.
I was like,
what the hell?
So I remember I was thinking,
I was like,
man,
I couldn't.
I just run a hundred miles like three
weeks ago.
Like first time ever I was peeing blood
and Pistons shitting on myself.
I got my body's broken,
my,
my Achilles and my tennis and my feet
are broken.
I go,
what is this?
It?
And every time I started running further
and frog,
okay,
I got to the 10 K,
I'm a Boston marathon time because I
knew the Boston marathon was like three,
10,
59 for my age.
I'm like,
hang on a second.
And then I started using all this
external shit for motivation.
Like okay,
who the fuck can go out here and run a
hundred miles?
No training.
I'm broken most broken.
I've been in my life,
now I'm running a marathon who can do
it?
So I started this feeding myself,
feeding myself.
I get to half a mile,
I'm about 30 seconds off the pace.
I said,
hang on man,
you're goggins.
You can do this shit,
man.
I started this feeding myself,
feeding myself,
feeding myself.
You can do this.
Before I knew it,
man,
I kept talking to like last six miles
and I was off the pace and I just kicked
it and not necessarily new.
I did like a three.
Oh eight and change.
I was like,
and that was what the fuck.
What have I been leaving on the table?
Right.
I've been leaving so much on the fucking
table for pain and that's when I started
like going crazy about the mind like
what the hell am I?
What is up?
Like it opened these different doors of
like possibility.
Then like what is humanly possible?
What are we capable of like,
you know,
people I didn't even know.
I was just amazed by what I was able to
do by a simple fact of just reasoning
and working with pain and pain
management and in my mind is kept on
growing from there and it happened in
hell.
Week it happened.
One hundred mile race happened here.
It started evolving into what it is now
to where now I'm like,
God,
dog,
man,
the mind,
we are leaving so much on the table when
people take me,
he cusses so much.
She sounds crazy.
Don't listen to all that Shit,
man.
Just this cut out the bullshit.
Cut the bullshit.
Just get into the weeds of that.
You are.
You are fucking yourself up by not
examining your brain.
You're not examining your brain
messages.
It that's done.
You examine your fucking brain and that
takes some hard work and suffering.
If you're not going to do that.
I'm sorry.
And it seems like there's no way to do
that as a bystander.
No,
you can't watch it,
man.
You gotta get out there and be like,
oh,
this hurts.
This hurts real fucking bad.
I don't think this is smart.
And then guess what happens?
The body will just,
it will adjust if it goes well.
Then the next question again,
but it's,
you're a time when it doesn't adjust.
I guess some of the stupidest shit man.
Like don't,
don't take it with a grain of salt
people.
Those questions that people that are
wanting to quit.
Yes.
And that's what I say.
When should I quit?
Like a.
Did you ever like,
feel like no,
shut the fuck up.
Stop.
I don't want to like there's always that
next question.
No,
don't take it.
Like go out there and run through a
brick wall as many times as you can.
No,
I'm not saying be me.
Don't run towards it and five miles at
one time.
I'm not saying do that.
I'm saying start to learn.
The mind is powerful.
It's powerful.
Man is unbelievable.
But if people need,
they need a thing to get them going or
they need a thing,
right?
I need a goal they need.
They need A.
I'm like,
it's sometimes the first step is the
hardest.
Like it's hard to take that 1 million,
step two.
But sometimes the first step is the
something about the,
what do I do about it?
They start going over the phone and
start calling people.
They don't get out of the house and
there's something about procrastination.
It's like,
you know,
it's painful.
You know you should be doing things,
but you just keep doing it.
You keep itching.
I procrastinate like a motherfucker,
man.
Every day I want to do this shit.
That's what's so funny,
man.
People looking like on some damn
superhero that came down from the Gods,
from the heavens on earth.
No Man,
I don't want to do this shit.
I'm looking at my shoes for 30 minutes.
Sometimes they can fuck man.
People.
People look up to your Goggins fucked
him.
Am I going to do this shit man.
But guess what,
you do it.
I'm going to do it as long as you do it.
And that's what I know about math.
What I'm saying.
No Man,
you got to fucking sit here and you look
at your shoes for 30,
40 minutes you go,
you got to think about all day long you
go do it anyway.
And sometimes you don't have the time to
look at issues with 30 minutes.
Those are the,
those are the beautiful days.
Yes.
It's,
you'd know,
you just have to go.
That's right.
And so like there's no room for
procrastination.
And that's when I,
when I was in the military,
I love my schedule because I knew it'd
be at work at 7:00.
So you better get your ass up at 4:00,
man.
He had get your shit and brother because
I had to get my shit and before I got my
shit in,
you know.
So that was my mentality back then,
man.
You know,
like I,
I had to get the miles and get
everything in man and,
and get to work.
Man.
I'm a competing with the Alpha males.
Yeah.
But how much does that piss other Alpha
males off that you were imposing?
A very high bar.
I,
I was very misunderstood human being
housed in the military.
The air force guys liked me a lot.
The Rangers liked me a lot.
So much.
Not to seals because they were with you.
They didn't like me so much,
which is fine,
you know,
I respect them.
I think a lot of respect.
I've,
I've a lot of friends in the seal teams.
I got to like,
like minded mentality as,
as me and wants to get me.
I grew up and I got over it.
A lot of guys still have,
you know,
a lot of people can't get over the fact
that whatever.
We're not became a civil recruiter.
A lot of guys thought I wasn't deploying
for a lot of reasons and whatnot.
And they,
I heard a lot.
I was that guy who grinded.
I grind it hard.
I mean I,
I grounded hard.
I was that guy who was up,
like if we went on op or we had a,
a workup,
let's say we had a workup.
We're in Ireland,
were out there shooting guns and,
and dual land warfare and we did it to
like 1:00
in the fucking morning.
Most everybody go to sleep,
go to sleep.
I went to the gym,
I worked out or our goal sleep that's
going to be up at 5:00.
I was up at 4:00
and got my hour in.
I made sure to always do that and I did
it to a point to where I think at
pissing people off because I want a
quiet person about it.
You know,
I,
uh,
I wasn't the most humble person.
I've always,
you know.
So when you're running alpha males,
um,
you're sometimes picking a fight,
you know,
all the time.
And I looked different,
acted different,
I was different.
I am different.
I take a lot of pride in that.
And so,
you know,
if,
if you didn't get after it,
I didn't respect you because I believe
that,
you know,
where I'm at,
I know that human potential is what we
have.
So all we have is what we,
the world sees us a certain way.
And when I saw that people weren't doing
that,
I had a funky ass fucking attitude and I
own it in my book.
I come back from ranger school,
a big time leader.
I was a big time fucking leader.
Get honor man out there.
I lead by example.
And when I realized a lot of times when
you're in these schools,
these schools,
people want to graduate these schools
because they suck.
They don't want to ever go back to these
schools.
Those schools became my fucking life.
People don't want to see a fucking God
that wants to go back to day one,
week one,
a fucking navy seal training every
fucking day of your life.
And that's how I live.
And it's a disgusting human being.
I can be.
It is.
And a lot of people didn't like me a
lot.
A lot of fucking people started some
stupid shit and started saying this and
that.
Bottom line,
man is my fucking resume.
Says it all man.
My resumes out there,
Google is a motherfucker.
You say whatever you want to say about
me,
man,
I,
I miss some deployments,
man,
for having fucking,
you know,
two heart surgeries and people try to
start some rumors.
Shit on me,
man.
You started reimbursing on me man,
because I fucking got the fuck after it
real hard guys like a guy named Hawk I
talked to all time.
Yay.
He's a great friend of mine.
When the horseman first before my heart
surgery,
my second heart surgery,
I'm going to 10 mile ruck run for my
second highest rate.
The day of it,
I'm going to attend mile record and 50
pounds.
I saw that guy.
He's like,
what the fuck are you doing out here?
We get a heart surgeon.
It's Roger that brother I'm getting in
before I'm be out for about six months
after the heart surgery.
That was my mentality because I started
realizing that a young age we'd always
leaving on the table and once I found
out what a human beings capable of,
I didn't know how to control that.
I was,
I was a fucking talking about fucking
savage.
That's what I was.
I was a fucking straight up people's
talking about savage.
Very likely I was fucking from the back
woods motherfucking savage dude,
you know,
and I just,
I was just,
I was,
I told you what I thought I had it.
I ate chips on my shoulder,
I m and a lot of times that wasn't
great.
So is it a situation where like with the
seals were,
once you've gotten through buds and once
you've gotten through all the,
the physically grueling parts of getting
to be accepted once you're in,
then you were imposing standards that
they didn't want to,
didn't want to keep up with.
I will say some people,
you know,
I,
I had uh,
I had one platoon that had a problem
with,
you know,
like I,
I,
I graduated ranger school and I got in
this platoon and I didn't see how the
hockey,
I wasn't charged with pt program and you
put me in charge,
the PT program is fucking your ass.
And the thing about is I didn't like it
either.
I didn't want to do this shit either
man.
But what were you making them do?
Like,
you know,
like I,
it was,
it was some navy,
it was some bullshit,
you know,
we went back to buzz like,
log pts and you're carrying logs,
the berms and shit.
And like I'd had us do like pull ups,
rope climbs,
pull up like flat out fucking hour.
So imagine him doing rope climb,
then go and do like 10 to 15 pull ups
coming back.
And we would do like these if they were
very hard workout.
Like there was no,
like go to the gym,
lifting some weights type of shit.
And I was imposing my own mentality on
everybody.
These are grown ass fucking man.
They ain't no,
you know,
they don't want to be with.
I'm trying to make them to be.
And when they called me off like,
Hey,
you know,
we're not silly.
We were not in buds anymore.
Goggins.
It pissed me off and I uh,
and I get a little fucking attitude.
Got,
got my.
And I got my ball and meet me and sledge
went ahead and started to a workout
together and we developed this like me
and sledge workout,
like fucking random.
And we had this fucking mentality of,
fuck yeah,
ever getting nasty with every day and
everybody's kind of did their own thing,
man.
And I just,
that's when I started looking at people,
you know,
not just people very differently man,
because I've been in to like,
you know,
like to be this special opera.
You got bb,
I have broken legs and these guys,
all those stories.
I was the same guy,
man.
I,
I put people on a pedestal.
I put people like I can never be there.
I could never be that guy,
man.
Never put anybody on a pedestal.
That's what happened to me.
I put them on a pass.
Then once I got out there with them and
I saw him and he wants to get.
Not everybody,
some hard motherfuckers out there do
period dot hard motherfuckers.
I thought every motherfucker was hard.
Yay.
Uncommon amongst uncommon man.
That's all it was about for me,
man.
And I took it to another level and I
pissed a lot of motherfuckers off and
they were trying to find chinks in my
armor.
Then they were there.
They were trying to find chinks in the
armor,
you know,
all he does is run.
All he does is fucking run.
That's why,
you know.
But once again,
that's what I'm talk about the military
too much.
Like I said,
the Air Force love me.
The army guys I work with,
love me,
the ranger school,
all that stuff love me and I wasn't,
you know,
it is what it is,
man.
It's A.
I was part of the navy seals I was at.
I was a team guy but I wasn't part of
the Brotherhood and that's just me,
man.
That's just me.
It ain't say nothing bad about them.
I got a lot of love for a lot of them
rather than I'm ain't got love for me.
Bank talk bad about them.
It's just I'm different and definitely I
figured out I'm different from everybody
in the fucking world and I had to own
that and say,
you know what man?
You made a lot of fucking mistakes being
a being who you are.
And I should've been more of a leader at
times,
but a lot of times a lot of people
should have been a little bit harder to.
So was it that some of those guys just
didn't want to work as hard or was it
just that they were,
they weren't appreciating how
competitive you were,
you were always against them.
Is that what it was that he did it
foster the sense of brotherhood because
you are more like,
come on pussy.
I didn't really call them pussies,
but you can look on my face and I looked
at you and in,
you know,
you can,
you can kind of say this,
you know,
so what happens?
I started developing this,
like the separation in our thing about
me to mass.
I don't go out,
I don't party.
I don't hang out with the guys.
I don't,
you know.
So I was always forming this kind of
separation.
I'm a big time introvert,
you know,
I do my job and I don't want to see your
fucking ass again.
I'm gonna go home refreshed and we'll
see you again.
You know,
you're,
you're in a platoon with these guys for
two years,
sometimes a year and a half and I would,
you know,
we work up,
do our shit and I just,
I was just a different fucking cat.
I'm a different cat man.
Like I,
uh,
you know,
I just,
I think differently,
I believe differently.
Um,
and I believe strongly in what I believe
in,
when some people must appreciate the
fact that you self motivated and that
you were pushing the envelope,
that you were pushing the pace you were
setting a high bar.
Yeah.
I have a lot of guys right now within
the community.
A lot of,
a lot of guys.
Once again,
this is like,
it's like a big soap opera sometimes,
man,
when,
you know,
when we,
when unit fraternity like that,
that's where it's like,
man.
So I had to get different vantage point,
look at it and see that,
you know,
a lot of guys did respect who I was and
what I did.
And um,
I,
I brought it fucking hard a lot in
everyday,
but I also rubbed people the wrong way.
I'm like,
that shit you talking about.
I'm like that if you want to scratch the
fuck out my ass.
And you're like,
fuck this dude,
man.
I love what you talked about when you
ran the marathon.
You realized how much you were leaving
on the table because that is um,
I mean,
I think the,
the unfulfilled potentials,
the story of most people's lives.
It is,
it is.
It could have been the story of mine and
I tell a lot of people who can people
go,
what's your biggest fear in life?
And my biggest fear honestly was let's
say this.
I say,
I don't care if you believe in God or
not.
I don't care.
So this is play game with me.
Let's say,
let's say your God and we have a big
fucking long line of people.
And I made the heaven 75 years old.
I'm 300 pounds.
I made the heavens.
I worked for Ecolab my entire life
spraying for cockroaches.
That's what I did.
But I'm dead.
I'm in heaven now.
And you are at your.
You're judging us all now.
So we're in line raw,
sitting there in line,
you have Adam Brown,
here's a big board up and you're talking
to Adam Brown about his life and you rip
it down and I'm next in line,
David Goggins,
I see my name and I see all this shit.
And God goes,
Hey,
you say read this man now reading this
list and I'm seeing and 82 pounds,
navy seal,
ranger school,
motivational speaker,
changing minds.
Okay,
may I pull up record all this shit?
And I'm like,
that's not me man.
And God looks at me and says that's who
you were supposed to be.
And my biggest fear,
I,
I visualize some crazy shit.
My biggest fear is that one day I'm
going to reach a judgment of my life.
Someone something is going to judge me
for what the fuck I was supposed to be
in life.
And what I want now is that whoever's
judgment,
whatever judged me up there,
I want them to have a board and them up
there right now getting their pin out.
Cause know this person who judges
supposed to know everything.
Supposed to know from the time your dad
at the time you're,
you know,
Tommy boy did.
I want this person to be like this up
there.
Right?
More about me.
St.
Fuck.
I know.
He can do that.
I can do that.
So I want to impress whatever the fuck
is up there.
Whatever's going on in life.
I want to go up there and not have
anything left on the table.
I want to.
I want to drain my soul every fucking
bit of person I am now.
How do you plan on doing that,
but going forward in the future,
do you have a plan?
Yeah.
So where I did not,
I believe in going back to scratch.
So a lot of us,
like right now I've.
I've come a long way in my life.
I've,
I've had to grow up a lot except a lot
of the fucking things I've done in my
life.
I'd accept a lot.
I took all this information,
big database,
took it all.
So what got me to be where I'm at today
is data.
I collect even more data now,
which where I can write this book was I
can tell people,
hey,
you know,
I fucking have a lot of faults.
I have other mentality that can
sometimes rub people the wrong all this
shit.
So how you get better is.
So right now I'm way up here now.
I was way down here,
but what makes you way up here is being
from way down here.
So I love going back.
I call it.
So when I was growing up like three
years,
so from the time I was eight to tell
them I was like 12.
We lived in a $7 a month place in what I
call it is.
I'm always paying rent in that $7 a
month home everyday of my life.
I go back and revisit that place because
that place made me this garanimals.
That place made me this hard man in
there from that place or that place is
hard work.
I places going back to the fundamentals
of life,
the fundamentals.
What made David Goggins,
David Goggins going back in and you're
going back to the,
going back to the library of David
Goggins studying even more than we are.
No.
Taking that out.
Going back to where I'm at now and then
moving forward.
So I believe in always taking steps
backwards to your roots.
We,
we cannot forget the roots and what made
us the grandmother we can ever become
civilized.
Isn't a grandmother like little kids
clothes,
this little kids clothes.
But I love the word I love is closer
drinks.
It was closer drinks members,
something like that.
So when,
when you,
when you live in like right now,
like what kind of goals are you setting
and how,
how are you,
how are you feeding that beast inside of
you?
How you calming all that down.
Stretching helped a lot,
you know,
so when you wire yourself up so much
yoga,
yoga and stretching has really helped me
to like,
you want to be quiet in your mind to see
what you want to go.
Because noise is the ultimate Kryptonite
down.
Too much noise in your mind.
You're not going to be focused on what
the task at hand is.
That's one thing that I've found that
like long cardio,
so the best thing ever for harmon.
That noise?
Yes.
We all talked about that.
All the guys that I did that sober
October thing with a fitness challenge
that like if you work out five hours a
day,
you don't give a fuck.
No,
it's.
It's amazing.
I might give you could take that and put
it in a pill form.
How you feel about life after you work
out five hours.
We don't give a fuck.
Nothing bothers you.
Like nothing.
You nothing because you've struggled.
True.
My fiance right now,
it's like,
hey,
I got x,
Y andZ and like I'll take you.
She's like,
what you want?
Look at shoes.
I'll take you one.
I'm like,
I just worked out for four hours,
man.
I fucking sit down this motherfucker
chair all day long and son.
Yeah,
I'm chill.
It's different.
I get all that shit out.
I ring the rag out in the morning time
and whatever you want to do.
I'm here man.
Most people never get there though.
No,
they always have that chatter.
Always,
always this negative anger.
The guy cut you off yesterday at your
head.
Yep.
All Day Long,
man.
Chatter,
chatter,
chatter.
Maybe I should do this.
Maybe I should've done that.
I should've never let that guy get away
with that exact.
Should have done this.
I should have taken that job.
I should have moved.
I should've stuck with her.
That was me,
man.
People.
Yeah.
People like me.
I was amazing that,
that long cardio.
Just calm that chatter like that.
I'd never until October.
I'd never really done long cardio
everyday it beat that testosterone up
man beats everything on that test.
You're like,
fucking done.
You're cool.
You're cool man.
It's not just that.
It's like it's.
I was talking about people's brains that
I think that the way people's minds work
that you were like a battery.
That's like
leaking out.
Like since we don't use it because we
have all this potential,
we don't use it like oozes off the top
of the battery and it gets messy.
Right?
It's going down the size of the battery.
It's all fucked up,
but when you just drain that bitch like
nature intended,
like give you the potential to run away
from predators,
avoid invading tribes and to fight and
to gather and hunt and all the physical
potential that your body is capable of.
When you do drain it with like a 10 mile
run or long cardio session,
long workout session,
then you can just be you.
It's the great purge man.
The purge,
the purge,
you prayers,
all that fucking demon shit out,
man.
All the evil evil can't stand a 10 mile
run,
bro.
Get leaked.
Right?
The fuck out gets pounded out.
Pounded out.
Yeah,
but you can see things more clearly and
that is only available through effort.
I mean,
maybe it's available through meditation.
I don't know,
but I feel like there's a different
thing that's available through effort
because there's also a satisfaction of
accomplishment.
Oh yeah.
Efforts.
Huge man.
It means everything gets.
You got to feel good about yourself.
Now what do you do?
You plan out your future?
I do,
so I'm very goal,
so I had that Accountability Mirror,
but also plan on all my small,
big time,
you know,
medium goals.
All these things have to do in life.
I'm a big planner.
I'm a big planner,
so you know,
right now I'm going back to scratch so
I'm trying to be wild land firefighter,
you know,
I did that for a couple of seasons.
You're going to do that now.
Yeah.
So I did it for,
I did it for two full seasons,
two half seasons,
so this year was my second year doing
it.
I had to,
I had to stop about two months before it
ended because this book to start
promoting the book and start finishing
the book up,
but I've been doing an opportunity.
That's some fucking work,
man.
Those fucking guys get asked.
What made you decide to do that?
The work,
you know,
like when your hands stopped becoming
really catalyst,
it's doesn't get back to work.
You know,
like I retired from the military.
I did 21 years in the military.
The military wasn't my life.
Loved everything about it,
the discipline of it.
There's some about going back into the
money you make is nil.
It's not about the money at all.
It's just about the hard work.
I've always been looking for those
people like those guys.
Like you're out there digging a three
mile fireline,
literally a three mile fireline.
You're cutting down,
he's fucking shoes as trees dig this
fire line and the fire line is like 20
to 18 inches for for three miles and you
got like fucking 12 people digging this
shit and I'm either thinking about this,
some of the hardest fucking work I've
done in my life and it's that challenge
that you can't find sometimes by going
to the gym or by running 100 mile race
if that,
if that new challenge of like,
Hey,
and you get done digging.
All right,
you've worked 17 hour,
16,
17 hours.
You get your fucking little fucking
sleep mat out shack down,
boom,
right on the floor right there on the
ground.
Get up,
dig some more.
You know,
be out there two,
three weeks.
Sometimes man has doing this shit and
there's great satisfaction in the kind
of work that you do out there.
No one's watching.
No one gives a fuck.
It's hard.
Dangerous work and you know,
you're doing it to help shit out man.
You know,
how did you get drawn into that?
So I got drawn into it because I was
always looking for the next challenge
and I was like,
what is there after the military with
like,
what the fuck is there man?
I'm 43,
I'm getting back in shape,
you know,
I'm fucking getting these health issues
taken care of that I had and I started
once again,
Google's amazing shit.
Hardcore fucking jobs.
No,
pretty much,
you know,
hard,
hard ass.
Fucking found the horse,
you know,
like the first race,
no hardest races in the world.
So basically I started to find this wild
land firefighter and wildland
firefighting.
So our google nest ask Google a smoke
jumpers,
you know,
I'm like,
what the fuck these guys do what?
They jump out of planes and attack small
fires.
Like that's the shit.
So I'm like okay,
okay,
we can put down a list.
And okay,
hot shots,
it was a hot shot dude that go out with
big fires and they dig fire line.
I'm like fuck.
With the video of it,
like that shit looks like it's sucks.
It's hot,
you know,
you're out there on your own.
I mean,
you know,
you're out there on your own man.
Just fire lands.
So that's Kinda how I found it.
I'm always looking for the next
challenge.
I'm never satisfied with,
oh I did that.
Like,
you know,
I became a seal.
I was an air force guy,
became a seal.
I went to ranger school,
I tried out for Delta Force twice,
you know,
like,
um,
I'm always looking for what is next,
looking for those uncommon men and
women,
uncommon people because I'm trying to,
I'm trying to grow,
I'm trying to grow.
And a lot of times you know,
you won't be the one person that's
making yourself grow.
You looking for those.
Cameron Hanes is those Joe Rogan,
those people who are like,
just different people who understand
what the fuck you're saying because a
lot of things I had to say,
I can't save them all.
I can't say the more,
you may not understand them,
so I had to really find a way to
communicate with people.
So the only thing,
oh my God,
what did you just say?
So these Cameron Hanes is these jewelry,
these people get it.
So I go to those little,
those little nucleus spots,
get a little more strength,
a little more knowledge.
Gilbert tools,
take those tools with me,
put in my tool shed and I go off down,
you know,
down the road or on a new journey.
So that's what I do.
Well the proof is in the pudding if you
really do in woodland firefighting
because there's no glory in that.
No Sir.
No.
There's no fame.
There's no.
There's no one taking pictures of,
you know,
and that paycheck is small.
I'm a fucking make you want to eat
today.
Wow.
Yeah.
Is there's nothing involved in that
minute.
They worked their ass off some but you
just doing it as a challenge.
That's it.
Did they freak out when you're there?
You know what I,
I think they're wondering why is a 43
year old retired man,
you know,
all this stuff you've done,
why are you out here?
And I explained it to them.
I'm out here.
I'm not here to,
you know,
to,
to learn from you all to grow.
And also to never forget where I came
from.
You know,
that's where it starts.
If that mentality of I'm going to pick
up that fucking Pulaski and I'm going to
dig this fucking fire alarm for three to
Emmaus,
that's that mentality of never want to
lose.
I never want to get so nice.
Where at,
Oh yeah,
I did it,
man.
I did it.
I'm good at that mentality of I'm going
to pick up that shovel and I'm willing
to dig a three mile line is.
There's some about that mentality that
I'm ready to go to work at any time and
that's what keeps me.
Those are the sparks.
Like,
you know,
I'll look at motivation is just a spark.
It's like,
it's like killing.
You know how a big fire starts.
It starts with a little smoke.
It starts with a little cigarette being
thrown in the woods nicely.
All California's fucking burn up.
That's what I've been doing my whole
life is I find these little sparks and
once that little thing takes off,
that's a.
that's a one hour of fuel,
10 you got 10 our fuel,
then you can move that thing to what?
10,000?
Our fuel,
these big logs and big trees that burned
for days and that's where you want to
bring that motivation.
That's.
You want to bring that drive.
So if you have no kingdom,
the killing is me going out with these
young guys saying,
all right motherfucker,
you're 43.
It's a 20 year old.
Keep up with them.
That kindling.
Now when I leave those young guys,
it has now become that 10 hour fuel and
now that 10,000
hour fuels I used throughout my whole
life.
I use that term or whole life man.
Hey,
this summer at 43,
you went out there and you did that man.
So you know you're not giving up yet.
You're not done yet.
Not Today,
not done today.
That's a crazy choice to make.
The wildland firefighters a very
interesting choice.
It is,
it is a nasty job man.
Because again,
that's the proof of concept.
Like you're really just doing it just
for the struggle.
That's it.
Is there other things you considered
like that?
Um,
so I will,
I apply for smoke jumping this year,
so I'll be a smoke jumper this year,
you know,
God willing.
I'm,
that's where it's at now.
Now's my next military.
That's the next military.
And it's always about human growth.
It's not about money,
not about money.
Human growth.
That's the biggest.
Like I said,
my biggest trophy.
That's why I turned down $300,000.
The biggest trophy in life is what I've
learned.
Like this brain,
if I could put this brand in somebodies
head and said,
here you go,
merry Christmas.
They'd be a happy person.
When I found out is that with no crowds,
no one cheering for,
you know,
racist,
no finish line.
It's an amazing,
amazing thing I've learned in my mind by
no one cheering you on.
Like what that is is every morning I do
what I do.
I don't have a trainer waking me up
there.
No one saying,
David,
you have to do this.
I don't have to do anything anymore.
I've done it.
That's the beauty of all of this.
Knowing that everything I talk about,
no one even knows what the fuck I'm
doing every day and I know that I am
grinding like a motherfucker.
They see a woman that video of me
running or some bullshit.
Hopefully it motivates you.
Merry Christmas.
Dune.
I'm out there for fucking hours every
fucking day and no one sees what the
fuck I'm doing knowing this great,
beautiful thing,
man.
That is a beautiful thing about it,
right?
That you really are just doing it for
the benefits of it.
That's it.
You have to do it that way.
It's not for show like there's a lot of
people like you'll see the little video
they do on instagram like,
bitch,
you are not doing that for very long on
too fast.
I said,
this is not real.
I got my one minute on tape now.
Yeah,
exactly.
If it's so much for show,
I do enjoy those videos that you're
doing on instagram though is a little
motivational things.
I've put some of them up on my page.
I appreciate you posted it.
There's a.
those are,
those are great man.
Like what are you.
Are you just like,
do you just get a thought in your head
while you're out there running and you
just want to get it down?
Yeah,
so what I'll do is I,
my fiance does all these videos man,
so God bless you.
It sometimes be 3:00
in the fucking morning and I'll be
working out and I said,
hey,
wake the fuck up.
I got some shit.
Like hey man,
it came to me man.
I got some shit for these people man.
So that's what happens.
Like usually when I'm working out,
I get this great inspiration.
I some people,
I think it's bullshit but my,
my mind works best under extreme pain
and suffering.
Like when I'm like God wouldn't be out
here and that's when I'm going deep into
the cellar of my mind and that's when
all that gargoyle shit starts to come
up.
Man,
you know what I'm saying?
And so she gets called out all the time
like,
Hey,
I'll run home and say,
get the car,
meet me at 17th street because by that
time I have all my shit together.
So I saw this happens,
man.
It's not like a rehearsed thing.
That's why sometimes I'm a post on
Monday.
Usually it's like every Monday,
but sometimes it's two,
sometimes it's Thursday,
you know,
and that's what I do.
I'm trying to now give back to people in
a way that's real and authentic and just
being me.
What has the response been like,
like after you did the podcast the first
time,
what was the response like and what was
the response like on social media?
Well,
it was crazy.
Man is that you are my usher and I'm
fucking Bieber.
That's the fucking response,
man.
So you're crowd.
Um,
for some reason they,
they resonate with me.
They,
they understand,
they,
they get me and they,
they love the message.
And like,
so if you put some bullshit up on my
site,
I block and delete your ass.
This ain't,
this ain't a playground like,
like,
like my site.
I'm not fucking around with you
motherfuckers.
I want to give you some tools that I
learned.
If you want to take them,
take not merry Christmas.
I go on my merry way.
I don't care.
So if you go on there,
you want to play around and you want to,
you know,
they called those people going to troll.
Fuck,
he ain't showing my shit.
I'm going to block your monkey ass off.
My Shit.
Quit.
I went.
So I've just their friends.
Jamie.
Yeah.
Tell him.
So I've developed like a small community
of people who can go in there and it's
not just me talking so people have now
joined in and there.
I've seen people whose a 150 pounds on
my site,
man.
I'm like in the end they're writing
about and they're starting to break
themselves down.
Like I broke myself down like,
hey,
I went through this.
I went through this divorce and this
happened in it and I tried to kill
myself.
It gets raw and then people are now
going on and commenting on their shit.
Saying hey,
keep it up,
do what you're doing.
It's become like a big fucking like,
hey,
it's a community of people trying to
fucking get better and that's what it's
about.
Man.
This ain't about to David Goggins
fucking show.
No Man.
I'm Mr Kenley.
You motherfuckers take this shit and let
shit burn.
Also.
You probably need all these other people
out there grinding to for fuel.
Oh Man.
Oh No.
That's the thing now like people go,
what motivates you now?
What motivates me now is that there's
over 600 some odd thousand people
looking at me saying motherfucking
goggins is somewhere out there.
He saw her out there fucking getting
after it and I am so you ain't never
fucking loan.
I'm out there somewhere.
Six hundred some thousand people.
There's a chance that when you're
working out,
I don't care if you're fucking
Washington DC and I'm in Nashville.
There's a good chance the same time
we're getting after it and I want people
to know that and it's the real deal we
are getting after together.
Not Know like happy family shit,
but we're getting after it.
No.
Yeah.
Well,
that is,
that's giant for people,
man,
that the sense of community and to know
that there's likeminded folks out there,
they're also trying to improve the
journey to overcome their own demons,
get past their own bullshit,
wash their own weaknesses,
cows up their own mind.
I love that.
It's not time for some soft shit.
It's not top of soft shit,
man.
I know this isn't a fucking playground.
Don't come on my instagram,
facebook or twitter talking to some
bullshit.
Come on if you want to,
if you want to join the community and
get hard and see what you're about.
Don't talk about rest.
You know,
how do you do it now?
That's fucking.
Stop thinking so much and that's put the
shoes on and get grind and you do
without those comments to say,
you know,
this is terrible advice.
Restroom recovery is the most important
thing.
God block all my shit,
son.
You're not gonna last,
not my site here.
That shit.
There's a lot of people looking for
built in.
Excuse her man per.
They're looking for it,
but then there's a lot of people also
that are just really interested in
personal growth.
They're interested in really finding out
what they're made of the re interested
in improving their ability to toughen up
and to discipline themselves and they're
looking.
They're looking for people like you and
other people.
Just add to that momentum.
Once you get going,
it's easier to keep going.
That's it,
man.
Once you get going,
it's easier to do.
Keep showing up.
It is.
You have to get past that hurdle and
once you get past that man,
you're flying
and then you see other people that are
doing it too and you realize like,
this is a.
This is a movement.
There's a lot of other people out there
that it is a movement.
It is a movement.
Well,
that's the thing that resonates with
you.
I think about the audience of this
podcast that I've had quite a few people
on that have that same message and it
resonates with people because we're all
trying to improve ourselves.
No one's perfect.
I hope this is not.
I'm not perfect now.
I never will be.
You're not and you never will be,
but you're better than you were
yesterday and you're going to be better
tomorrow.
That's the truth day right there,
man.
That's what that book says.
I am not fucking perfect,
man.
I had the Boston.
Now finally tell you all I am very
flawed,
but in that saying that you're very
flawed and saying that you're very
perfect.
You exhibit way more strength than
someone who bullshits and pretends
someone who puts up some fake ass
fucking fake facade of perfection,
of moral integrity and growth and
honesty and those people are a real
problem.
It's exhausting.
Fuck you did it for awhile.
I'm like,
I'm fucked up.
I give up.
I quit.
I quit,
I'm fucked up.
I'm going to tell you all.
I can't do this anymore.
This is who I am.
But the confidence
to view of constantly grinding and
constantly putting in that work is what
leads you to be able to express
yourself.
So honestly,
you're right.
I,
for the first time,
believe in David Goggins and I don't
care who else believes in me.
I don't care for the first time I left
and I can tell you all my fucked up shit
and without lying.
That's powerful.
No longer care.
That.
See everybody could get to that.
Then you do.
You don't have any excuses because you
don't need any.
That's right.
None.
You're like me.
Merry Christmas.
Kwanzaa.
Keep moving.
Yes,
it go.
Yeah.
Good luck to you.
Exactly.
Yeah.
We're all in this thing together.
You got your own path.
And so one of us to stare at those shoes
for 30 minutes every day.
That's so true,
man.
So true.
So fire jumping and woodland
firefighting.
That didn't expect that.
I didn't hear that coming.
That's interesting man.
Yup.
And W,
what?
Did you have any other options that you
were looking at before you dived into
those?
You know,
what those are the first two that came
up because I saw how hard it was,
you know,
at 43 and these jobs,
like in the military,
you're a dinosaur trying to retire and
wild land firefighting,
you know,
you start to move into these desk jobs
and that was the challenge of it.
You know,
I'm like a,
I'm like a fucking rookie at 43,
so I'm like being talked to like a
little bitch,
so it takes a lot for me,
you know,
I'm like,
man,
I've done some things man.
Hang on now.
But I have to know humble myself again.
It's hard to humble yourself.
He got some 21 year old little punk ass
bitch say,
Hey,
pick up that shit and come on.
I'm like,
what the fuck to say?
you know,
but I'm like,
okay God,
it's like your rookie man.
Like,
so that's all the training behind the
mindset of it all is that you can't ever
be the point you never learned from
people.
Right.
You know,
you have to always humble yourself and
go back to that.
Yeah.
You know,
like right now there's people listening
to podcasts like,
Oh yeah,
you're great galleries.
Nah,
you ain't Shit Goggins.
And that's the mindset I always want to
have.
No,
like I'm not proud of myself,
but you have to always keep that.
Like I want to keep that dog in me and I
can't always know everything.
Yeah,
we'll be in the beginner at something.
That's fantastic.
It's amazing being learning new things
is fantastic for everything else.
So much growth in that.
Have you?
Do you fuck around with martial arts?
You know what?
I learned a little bit.
I've never gotten crazy in it.
I've never gotten crazy.
I boxed a little bit.
Where do you live?
I live in Nashville,
so out of Jujitsu.
Nashville.
You should get involved in Jujitsu.
You would take to it like a duck to
water.
I'll find your spot,
man.
I'm finding your spot.
You.
You get obsessed with that shit.
Oh God.
Because that's a never ending pile of
fucking tangled bodies and gamble
because it's something that you just get
better at all the time and there's no
hiding.
Right?
Either you get choked or you don't.
Either you survive or you don't know.
I've been in a lot of ground in a lot of
ground gangs,
man,
but I've never really learned the skill
sets.
Yeah,
so it'd be nice to do that.
I'll hook it up.
Please do.
I think you would get obsessed with it
the same way.
Jockos obsessed with it.
Same with a lot of other seals,
get obsessed with martial arts or it
would be nice to do it because it's also
constant competition as well.
I mean,
you can get into competition every
single night of the week real and.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And as a guy who's just starting out,
you're going to be a white belt,
you're going to get strangled a lot.
You want to start from the beginning.
You're going to start from the
beginning.
One hundred percent,
plenty guys your size.
There's plenty of guys that have been
doing it for fucking decades,
like the hands on me and stuff.
Good.
Yeah,
Goggins you coming home,
but it's also a good thing to have the
kind of cardio and endurance you have to
get people.
So I've,
I've,
I've rolled with a lot of guys who have
skills,
but the thing that I really have,
and I'm not gonna Brag on it,
man.
I got fucked up cardio base,
I got fucked up cardio basement and my
mentality is kind of fucked up too.
So I realized that we're fighting.
If you get a big cardio base and your
mindset is fucked up to cardio's almost
everything,
that's what skills,
skills are everything because a lot of
guys with skills also have some cardio.
They have enough to fuck you up,
but to have tremendous cardio with big
skills is everything.
I see him a man dying.
Yeah,
because so many guys started 100
percent,
but three minutes into the fight they're
at 80,
right?
You know,
five minutes into the fight there at 60.
That's right.
Then they for a minute
they come back.
But if you're,
if you're in like a rolling session,
like when you roll your role for nine
minutes straight.
So you and this guy and most of the time
there's multiple taps.
You'll tap him and he'll tap.
You tap each other.
But nine minutes man,
it is exhausting when that bell goes
off,
the last you know the bell for 30
seconds and you got 30 seconds left in
nine minutes and then banging it's over.
It's done.
And then do you take a minute off and
you find a new partner that's good shit
back in there.
You'd love it.
It sounds like a good grind grind right
there.
You love it.
Yeah.
Getting your black belt.
Hey,
some of that take about.
If I went like this hard at it.
It's hard to say because it depends
entirely upon how much emphasis you put
on learning new techniques and broiling
and drilling.
Drilling is gigantic and that's the
thing that people don't like to do.
Cause Jujitsu,
so fun.
People like to just roll because it's
this sparring is where it's at.
Like,
ah,
I don't want to do those practice.
I want to choke people.
Like I knew a few things.
Let's do that.
Okay,
and I do this.
let me get in there and you want a lot
of Jujitsu schools.
They'll start out with like one or two
techniques and then you roll most of the
classes just sparring,
but the right way to do it really is to
drill way more than you spar.
She'd be drilling all the time and live
drilling too,
like you start out where God has your
back ready go,
and then from there you got to try to
escape and do it the right thing to try
to use the right technique to get out of
that position or you'll start out with
an arm bar,
but he's defending and you've got to
figure out how to extend it in those
live drills,
straight drills like technique,
drills,
and then live drills are,
I think even more important in the
beginning to,
uh,
to,
to your personal development and growth
as a Jujitsu player than even sparring.
But a guy like you who's smart and tough
and will go crazy shit.
It shouldn't take that long.
It takes people.
I mean,
it depends on how much you dedicate
yourself to.
Bj Penn got his black belt in three
years.
What?
Yeah,
but it's crazy.
He's Bj Penn.
He,
so like the prodigy for a reason,
right?
I had a conversation with them about
though it was really interesting once
he,
uh,
he goes,
he was talking to some other dude and
the guy said,
uh,
I got my black belt at three years,
just like you did bj.
And He was like,
wow,
man.
He goes,
you must be good.
no,
man.
He goes,
I'm a dick.
Did just like you.
He goes,
you addicted,
you're addicted.
And he's like,
I never thought about it.
That way goes,
yeah.
I'm addicted to jujitsu to get addicted.
Like it takes over your mind.
Everything your days are spent thinking
about.
Some guy would triangled you this
motherfucker.
How do you get me shit?
Like I get that till I got choked out 10
years ago that I think about sometimes
when I'm lifting I'll be tired and I'll
think about a guy caught me 10 years.
I want to like fuck.
Oh,
just about life man.
Yeah.
Because I think about not being choked
out,
but I think about a lot of shit like
that.
Yeah.
Little failures
and just keep pushing.
They grind on me like that
motherfucker man.
And that's what you're talking about
earlier too.
It's like the the mind has these
reserves.
You can trick it and pull them out.
Yes.
Inspirational reserves like you did when
you.
When you guys were going through buds,
we just found that trigger and then all
of sudden you throw in that boat in the
air.
The mind always has the tactical
advantage over you.
Why is it it knows your fear
and nausea securities.
It knows where their height can't hide.
You can't hide that motherfucker,
man.
I forget the tactical banners on your
son.
That's gonna.
Get you man.
It's a beast.
Be your best lesson,
right?
That your mInd.
Your mind knows everything.
You cannot hide from it.
So don't ever try.
Don't try and beat that motherfucker up
gotta.
Keep going at it.
That's also what you did in this book.
You didn't try to like paint yourself in
a glamorous or flattering way at any
point in time.
You were honest at every step of the
way,
which I think is just gigantic for
people too because you can tell when
someone's stroking themselves,
bullshitting themselves is the message
just won't come through.
but this,
your you come through in this book,
you know,
you who you are and what you became and
how you became who you are and who you
used to be and why you were with the way
you used to be.
All that comes through.
it's like there's no filter.
This is just your,
your thoughts like you,
what you remember about your life and
what you think about right now.
Just all comes out onto the pages
harder.
They,
I've done my entire life.
I would imagine.
I have fucking,
I don't know.
People are buying this book.
Then I walk up to people.
People walk up to me.
I'm like,
what are you thinking about mother
fucker?
I think he probably painted in the bed.
Were you thinking about.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
I know,
right?
Like you like thinking about opening it
up all you know,
all bobby.
Hey,
how about you motherfuckers?
Tell me something about you.
That's what people love,
right?
When they know some shit about.
I don't know nothing about them,
but nobody.
That's anonymous.
Trolls,
man.
Get at me.
Oh,
there's a lot of those,
but they're all doing that to
themselves.
They don't even understand.
When you do that,
you're doing it to yourself.
If you are attacking someone
[inaudible],
you know that they have a weakness,
but you're pretending you don't have
one.
You are attacking yourself.
You are chipping away at your own
personal sovereignty,
chipping away your own respect.
So true man.
You can't respect yourself.
You know you're a pussy.
You're ship though,
joe.
To me,
I start looking at people realizing I
know something about you because they
don't want to talk about it.
right?
I already know it.
Yeah,
if you're talking shit about me.
I know you're fucked up.
Yeah.
That's what all these cats that come out
right now who don't like me,
whatever.
I'm like,
really?
Man,
that shit happened 30 fucking years ago.
Fifteen years ago.
You're still.
you're still fucked up about that.
Oh man.
I know something about you brother.
Zach it over everything.
I'm good.
It's water under the bridge grind.
The grind does.
That's it.
You're not grinding hard.
If,
if you're worried about something that
someone did to you years ago,
you're beIng a pussy to yourself may not
getting out there and squeezing that
fucking sold out every day.
If you grind harm,
I've got time to worry about your monkey
ass I to them about you,
man,
because tomorrow I got to go back to the
grind and tomorrow I go back to the
grind again and again and again and
again.
I don't have time to put you into the
hate bank.
There's no hate,
so I'll filter it out,
man,
through the grind.
People don't get it.
There's there's great joy in the grind,
great Jordan,
the suffer.
It's totally cleanses your body out,
man.
If any kind of hate makes you grow up,
it's also the being honest about it.
Every step of the way,
the way you are in this book and the way
you are where you talk about things,
not not trying to paint yourself in a
flattering way,
no it.
It forces you to continue to perform
right by exposing all the shit that used
to do.
By exposing your procrastination,
you've slips your,
you're falling,
you're falling back down and getting fat
again.
All that stuff.
It forces you to be consistent like you
know you did it today.
You know you did it today.
Do you know you're going to be able to
do it tomorrow?
Well,
you have to.
You have to know.
That's good to know.
That's my biggest fear of man,
is that I know I can slip every goes,
man,
you're not permanent shit.
No one's permit almost fucking
permanent.
That's why people that have accomplished
great things and then want to talk about
those great things to the end of time
and not do anything anymore.
They're fucking themselves sit.
Those people that are looking for that
golden age for that holding hands and
walking off into the sunset and credits
role,
that doesn't exist.
If not tattooed man,
it's not real.
I thought it was tattooed.
I'm like,
fuck,
I'm slipping.
I'm like,
what?
I put all this repetition.
I'm still slipping.
Can't take a day off.
Man.
Can't take a day off now.
No days.
Can't take a day off,
seven days a week.
I get anxious,
but see the thing about I do active
recovery,
right?
Okay.
So what's a.
What's a light active recovery day?
You say seven days.
Seven miles is normal and easy.
Six mile run.
That's active recovery and low low heart
rate.
I look like I'm walking a mile to like a
fucking nine.
Thirty,
10 minute mile.
Heart rate's real low.
I'm really big into the heart rate
training,
man.
It's amazing.
So it makes you a machine.
It makes you a machine man.
How so?
It trains your heart in a way that the
way I was able to run these hundred my
race like I was able to do it was awful
heart rate,
so if you go at 80 percent for me for
the longest time it was like 100,
like 1:47
heart rate within 48 to 1:52
right around in there.
If I maintain that man,
I'm in that I'm burning that nice fat
storage and that body wants utilize
that.
It wants to burn that nice and slow.
You're never getting that heart rate up
pro hockey and get your heart rate up or
how it takes a lot to recover from that
and hire ghost.
The longer it takes for it to come down.
We're not staying at 1:45,
1:46
point 47 heart rate for a long time.
When I get done running,
it will go back under 100 within two,
three minutes.
And that's what you want.
You want that quick recovery.
So quick recovery means that your body
is right on point.
And I'll look at my and my heart rate.
The morning time it's using the
thirties.
If it's like 45,
46,
47,
I'm overtrained.
Easy day.
Each day means zone one,
zone one means I'm just going real light
today.
So I train everyday because why?
As far as my mind and as a human,
we're supposed to move everyday is
supposed to move and I'm not saying get
after it every day.
Get after me,
just do something every day or ride a
bike.
If you're real tired from working hard,
right?
An easy Bike spin and as you're
spinning,
take in your fluids,
rehydrate your body as you're active
because that's the best way to rehydrate
your body and like taking a carbohydrate
drink.
It gets all that good carbs.
You start to glycogen,
store your body again for the next day,
so as you do an active stuff that
blood's flowing nice active blood flow,
the blood at the blood flow helps the
recovery process along with drinking
some,
some like uh,
endurance drink or some carbohydrate
drink.
It gets all that glycogen through the
system,
back to the muscles loads and back up
again,
ready to fight another war tomorrow.
What do you use for a heart rate
monitor?
They usually use polar for a long time
and I kind of still use polar now.
Is that a wrist one or chester as a
chest strap?
It's a nice cheap little gesture app.
And now I'm at a point now where I know
I only do my heart rate in the morning
time.
I don't even.
Wherever not run anymore,
do check it with a strap in the morning
or you check the checkers just so you
wake up,
you just put the strap on before you got
to bed,
put the strap on your body.
You don't.
The first thing you do,
put A strap on or do your finger,
whatever one you can do,
even have a strap to your finger.
Know what your average heart rate is,
you know,
your resting heart rate.
And then from there,
if it's a little bit higher,
a little elevated,
you know,
you can't go off into that zone three
zone four training day.
You got to keep it at zillow and tours
on one.
So it's all about the heart rate,
the resting heart rate.
So when you use it,
uh,
the chest strap,
does it register on an application on a
phone?
Like how do,
how do you read it on the watch,
on a watch?
Is it a smartwatch or as a polar was to
polar watch.
So it's a wash that shows you the heart
rate that's reading off his trap.
Exactly.
So does.
And so wHen you say zone ones,
this,
these things that you've created,
zone ones onto the normal,
these are like zones that um,
that's no,
whoever created this,
like,
like the heart rate zone training.
So basically what I did in help me out
so much as my zone two training runs
used to be an 8:30.
okay.
So that was my pace at like a 1:45
mile,
30 mile through stretching and give my
body opened up.
My zone to run now is about a seven
slasH 21,
seven,
18,
19,
kind of minute off just by opening up
your range of motion up my range of
motion.
Wow.
Unbelieve at the same exact heart rate.
So my stride and people look at videos
and be like years ago when I was first
doing my first badwater look,
I was scooting,
I have,
it was so tight.
I looked at was this very rigid runner.
Now actually run,
you know,
everything was so tight.
Everything was contact forming it as I
was like,
kind of like my knees and my joints is
going inward now.
EverytHing's where it needs to be at and
I have a nice long,
nice,
dried.
Do you run on the street?
I run most part and for the most part
I'm always traveling.
So the best thing to do,
get your runnIng shoes.
You'd get your shit and you just go out
and run.
But I,
I try to hit the trails some dirt as
much as possible.
So this is really good for you.
But now my body is like fucking tech,
fucking iron.
I mean it is.
It can take some beatings now when you,
when you run,
if you ever fuck with those barefoot
running shoes.
Oh no,
no,
no.
You know what,
like,
look,
honestly,
I Don't know many people who have been.
I don't believe in it.
I don't believe I've.
I was born with shoes,
wearing shoes my whole fucking life.
I'm not,
you know,
I'm black but I'm not from africa so I,
I'm not down man.
I'm not dear it.
Read the science behind the idea of
using all the muscles in your feet.
I read the science behind it.
I also read,
sounds like motherfuckers have broken
feet and heard that too,
but minimal issues on trails aren't bad.
No they're not.
I'm not doing it now and no man will
break.
Oh my god,
man.
One of those things all the time.
Really?
Associates.
So you liked them?
Yeah,
it would kill me,
man.
I'll tell you what.
Ran in fat tires yesterday under armour
fat tire,
which is like a cushiony ass shoe.
You like it and I was like,
it was so easy.
It's like it's like whatever.
I know under armour has these fat tires.
It's basically like a bmx tire track.
I think it's even made by a tire
company.
Makes the tread.
Yeah man.
It's like it's got a mesh to it and you
run in these things,
man.
You could run over.
See the thing about those five finger
barefoot shoes.
I like running those,
but you've got to look where you're
stepping.
You can't step on any hard rocks game.
You will fuck up your foot quick cause
it's like it's gonna go right into your
foot.
It's a tiny little thin.
So I went from those to vivo in vivo
barefoot shoes.
That's what it looks like.
So when you run on those bitches,
that is a cushiony glorious padding.
Like when you,
when you hit the ground,
it's like smushy,
smushy smush.
I had the other ones,
jamie,
the ones with the boa.
It's cause it's just like got that
little click one that you just pulled
out.
YeaH,
like those.
So it's like you twisted with that.
That's how you tighten it with that
little boa,
a adjuster thing.
It's like a got a thread through it so
you have to lace it or anything like
that.
It just slip them on and pop that sucker
down.
I like to feel the ground a little bit
when I run.
Yeah,
he barely feeling shit with those.
But I like it.
My joints didn't bother me at all
yesterday,
which is crazy.
Like after a good solid run because most
what I'm running is hills pretty steep
and it's great.
My ass and legs never been waiting away
right now.
200.
You think?
Dude man.
Now.
So for me,
the pounding of the,
you know,
the,
the constant pounding the feet to the
ground,
it is a,
it's,
it's rough on the ankles.
It's rough on the joints,
but I don't feel it at all with those
fat tires.
It was like I,
I got done running.
I felt like I cheated.
I felt like wow,
this is so much eAsier.
The cloud shoes.
Yeah.
This just real cushiony and cams always
said that he runs with those a lot.
Oh,
does he?
Yeah,
he's running with a bunch of those.
He's like,
because he runs so many fuckIng miles.
He was running a marathon a day,
like pretty much every day.
I did that for awhile back.
Oh my god,
I got wired in doing that shit man.
What is this right here?
So this is,
this is when I ran,
I ran a hundred and 50 mile trail race.
So the year before I did the same race.
It's 150 mile trail race.
I did it in I think around a 40 hours
and I had to walk the last 60 miles.
got I,
I had pneumonia.
Here we go.
Yeah.
Well,
and then I told the race director,
hey motherfucker,
I'm coming back here next year,
now I'm breaking the course record.
I went back and did like 32 hours.
Same race.
Wow.
No,
no.
When you were Thirty three hours.
So when you run in,
what shoes do you use?
Right now I'm wearing brooks and also
we're a six.
So it just depends on,
you know,
what kind of train I'm in,
where I'm at,
stuff like that.
For trails where you were running for
trails.
I actually,
for the longest time I roar a street
running shoe.
Really?
For trails?
Yeah,
for the longest time.
How come?
Because first of all my body was so
messed up.
The only issue I could ever wear with
this brooks addiction.
It hate even given brooks credit right
now because back in the day they would
help a brother out.
I was running so many miles.
Yeah.
So brooke's.
I'm not trying to.
I'm not promoting brooks right now.
Yeah.
Merry christmas on that one.
I called up the meantimes times.
Hey man,
can I get like a discount or some shit?
Hang up.
Nobody.
Nothing.
So,
but they do have a good shoe and I,
uh,
and I,
and it was not good pr it horrible pr
man,
you know what I'm saying?
Like,
you know,
so,
but um,
yeah,
I love their shoe bonus check or where
was that?
Brooks addiction can.
My,
my biomechanics was so messed up.
I tried so many different shoes and,
and that was a so I can now wear a
neutral shoe.
So how I used to run and very few people
know this,
I used to have heel inserts,
heel wedges and get compression tape
because my body was pushed so far in
from being so tight in my hip flexors
that.
So how I guess that's best dressed
fractures was my bottom mccastle there's
a picture of my toe in there.
Can my,
my toes is Jan in front of my shoes,
can.
My whole body has got this like bent in.
So when you say in benton for people
just listening your.
If your hands are flat on a table,
you're turning the outside of your hands
in so that your thumbs are going down.
Those are my.
So yeah.
So those are my two big toes,
right?
Going down,
going down into the shoe and the outside
of your foot was up.
Was above it.
Right?
So what I had to do to run,
because I was like,
god,
I got stress fractures all time and my
feet were so fucked up.
Sometimes you see that with peopLe's
shoes,
like how they're worn out,
worn out,
worn out on a sideways example.
Like a wedge,
right?
Can we look at it from behind the crazy?
Yeah.
That was my shoe.
So I had to get a heel wedge to keep my
heel from going down.
Guys sit.
Severe tendinitis in the back of my
ankle.
That's actually,
you had to make it thicker on one side
on the inside flat.
Right?
So the insight,
I had a pushup and had to get
compression tape.
So it was compression tape,
heel wedges and an insert.
And that's how I ran every fucking day.
And then did you go to a running coach
or anything digital?
No,
but did you want to know what you were
doing wrong?
You know what,
man,
that was part of that.
Granted more mindset,
man.
Fuck it,
I'm supposEd to be broken.
No,
but then I got smarter as time went and
him and this is painful shit.
Running 100 mile races with this kind of
tendonitis and my feet being fucked up.
It was so painful.
So I was like,
no way.
So then that's what started stretching.
I was like,
my god,
all this was from having a tie.
I got so mad.
Oh my god,
I wasn't.
I wasn't all these different
contraptions and now I just wear a
number of running shoe.
Wow.
yeah.
So I went from being contraption up,
man,
like literally contraption up.
So it's all just the stretching that
opened up the range of motion.
Now when people talk about range of
motion,
they don't understand how tight I was,
like no one understands.
Like when you repeatedly do what I was
doing to myself and you were born with
the stress I was born under,
like I hate.
I can't paint a clear.
It's pretty clear in the book,
man.
My life was bad.
the stress I adored on daily.
I had two people and my body was proof
of literally what my life was doing to
me.
It literally was not at all my muscles
up because I was always under this fight
or flight,
you know,
my,
my dad had made me so fucking scared as
shit,
you know,
to,
to unwind this motherfucker.
Man was like,
it was,
it was a hard task.
You know,
I,
it was hard.
It was a hard task man.
So it's a lot of damage.
It's not just all the hard training,
but it's also the mind,
the mind because think about it,
man,
when you're under stress,
that hip flexor with that,
that's so as most western attached to
your t 12 that that's the only muscle
that attaches your lower body,
upper body and that's the muscle that's,
that's your fight or flight.
Whenever you get nervouS or scared or
something like that.
That motherfucker's business was tighten
up.
your whole body is.
I lived in that like almost fetal
position in my mind for so many years.
So I was always under this tight neck
tension fucking guy.
But I walked around like I'm some cool.
Here's my new hairstyle,
pesticide.
I'm a cool dude man.
But that was not a costume.
The costume where every day get tired of
tighter.
Brenda motherfucker,
man.
Next costume I want you to be in as a
jujitsu guy with a white belt on.
I'm going to send you a picture,
man.
I got a picture because I already
planted that bouncing around your.
It is now.
It is.
I'm going to set it up.
Nashville.
I know there's some places out there.
Nashville,
holler at me.
I'll trust me.
I'm sure they will.
Will find you a spot spot.
I'm listening,
man.
This book is fucking fantastic.
I'm halfway in.
I can't wait to finish it and just thank
you.
Thank you for the inspiration.
THank you for being so honest to
expressing yourself.
I appreciate the fuck.
Yo.
Appreciate you brother.
Thanks again.
Thank you.
Bye everybody.
Thanks a lot,
brother.