Heyi everybody,
this episode of Joe Rogan experience
is brought to you by ting.
Uh,
we have a winner for the Ting,
uh,
podcast contest and the winner
is Holly Mac 23 and Holly Mac 23.
She gets an iPhone five,
right?
Is that what it is?
Yeah.
I'm assuming that Holly Mac is a girl.
I don't even know if it's girl,
whoever.
Holly Martin.
Let's,
let's find out.
Let's do a little Google search on Holly.
Mark 23,
should I probably s she's going
to get swarmed by assholes now.
Wow.
I didn't even think of that.
But they wanted you to announce it online.
Well,
Holly Mac 23 got 19 followers.
Soon there will be more.
She hot.
Um,
listen,
she's a nice person.
That's what's important.
Yeah,
she's very pretty,
but she's got a man in her picture,
bud.
So back off.
Anyway,
Holly Mac 23,
you win the tin contest.
What is Ting?
Ting is a no bullshit mobile service
company that uses a sprint backbone.
What Tim does is they rent time on sprint
but then give you cell phone service
at a in a in a very reasonable
way with no contracts,
no early termination fees,
no add on coverages and you
only pay for what you use.
If you use very little,
you pay very little and if you use more
you don't have to pay some exorbitant
rates that you,
you know,
some fines that you'd get when you go
over your data coverage or over your text
minutes or any of that nonsense that
you get with other cell phone providers.
And I think that what they're doing is
probably most likely going to be the
future for cell phone companies.
I think the more companies like ting
come around and the more they provide you
with excellent service without all the
nonsense and bullshit and contracts and
all the crap that everybody
hates about cell phone coverage.
All that stuff is out the window of Tang
and they have the latest and greatest
android devices.
They have the HTC one
which is a fantastic phone,
and the Samsung Galaxy s well,
the galaxy note three which
is the one that I have,
they have the galaxy s four the
galaxy has fives coming out soon.
The LG flex point is they have all the
latest and greatest android devices and
they have it in a way where you don't
feel like you're getting ripped off.
The whole point of the contest was to go
to tank and to find out how much money
you would save by using Tang,
and 98% of people would
save money with Tang.
That's pretty crazy.
98% those other 2% I don't know
what the fuck they're doing,
but it's probably some weird shit and
that's why they won't say save any money.
Anyway,
go to [inaudible] dot ting.com and
save yourself $25 off of any of the new
devices.
That's rogan.ting.com we're also brought
to you by [inaudible] dot com it's o n
n I t on it is a human
optimization website.
What we sell is everything that
we can find that can benefit you,
whether it's strength and
conditioning equipment,
whether it's a health and nutrition
supplements like hemp force protein powder
made out of the finest hemp force,
whether it's our new warrior bars,
which are these fantastic new buffalo
bars that are made in the ancient native
American way.
They're made with no antibiotics,
no added hormones,
gluten free,
no nitrates,
they're made with cranberries and buffalo
meat and it's really good for you.
Really good for you.
14 grams of protein,
140 calories,
four grams of fat and all in a little
two ounce serving really delicious stuff.
And one of the best snacks you could buy.
A real guilt free snack.
Uh,
and the kind of stuff
that we're selling it on.
It is just the kind of stuff that I use,
whether it's these hemp
force protein bars,
whether it's this earth grown nutrient
supplement that it's a food super food
that we add to,
whether it's protein
drinks or coconut water.
Just to give you,
just make sure you cover your bases.
As far as nutrition goes,
well,
we're trying to sell you it on.
It has all the things that I use,
all the things that my
partner Aubrey uses,
whether it's things like
battle ropes or steel maces,
ab wheels,
just the best strength and
conditioning equipment,
the best supplements,
the best nutritional foods
and snacks that we can find.
Go to [inaudible] dot com that's o,
n N.
I t.
Use the codeword Rogan and save
10% off any and all supplements.
All right,
my pal Bud Brotzmann see
here and Rob Maccachren,
Baja legend is here.
Cue The music.
Young Jamie,
we're going to talk about some crazy shit.
The Joe Rogan experience.
Joe Rogan podcast by night all day.
My Pal Bud Brotzmann was my neighbor.
We've been friends for many years,
many a year.
More than two decades,
right?
We've been friends for a long time,
17 years,
something like that.
Long ass time.
A bud every year.
Leaves family and friends behind and
travels to Mexico to do this fucking crazy
race.
And every year I talked to his wife,
shaking my head,
I talked to other people,
gone that Bud Brotzmann
is a crazy son of a bitch.
Like what the fuck is he doing down in
Mexico doing jumps and flying over hills
while he is brought with him,
Rob Maccachren who is apparently the
man when it comes to this Baja racing
stuff.
And uh,
I mean I'm fascinated by it.
And so,
uh,
I'm,
I'm real excited to get you guys on the
podcast and talk about it and I know
you've got something upcoming
that you're promoting that a,
so people can get a
chance to check it out.
Yeah,
we,
I started racing,
I'm at the TV business,
right?
So I think you think I'm crazy,
but this race as much
like Mount Everest to me,
you just got to go do it.
It starts always starts as
a stupid bucket list thing.
You got to go do,
right?
So I did it one year,
Rob's and doing it for 25 years.
30 I did it one year,
2005 and I'm like,
I've got to go climb Mount Everest.
I got to go do this thing.
So I did it,
um,
through a sponsor.
Might be if Goodrich and I'm like,
oh my God,
and this is actually leans back to you.
This is mixed martial arts of racing.
There's no rules.
There's no classes.
There are there classes,
but there's no rules.
You can do anything you want.
Um,
there's consequences down there.
I mean,
if you don't train,
you don't pay attention.
You don't sleep.
You'd go out and party the night
before you have consequences.
You get hurt,
you get killed.
You could wreck your car,
you could sit in the middle
of the desert for 20 hours.
You know,
I just went to go compete,
Kinda like an iron man.
Like I want to go compete.
I want to finish it all right.
Right.
Just say you did a marathon.
Yeah,
I did a marathon.
I'm a be,
I get a little trophy,
it's fine.
And now I'm hooked.
Right?
So then it's kind of the Lord,
this majestic place.
Rob will talk about a lot
of this majestic place.
So I was like,
I finished,
I'm happy 36 hours in the car.
I finished.
It was great.
Everybody was happy.
I was tired of Shit.
Then the next year I came back
and I want to do it again.
Well,
maybe I'll take second or
third or get on the podium.
And then,
so I started chasing it and started
chasing and it took me eight years every
day,
you know,
I work out all the time just to go race.
I watched race videos.
I give as much seat time as I can
because I only do the one race a year.
I do about two races a year,
just one the practice,
and then I go down and raise the thousand
and I finally went in 2012 but then
there's guys like rob 200 wins.
He's white.
He's won 200 times in off road racing.
He's won five out of all the stats over
at five Baja 100 by by 1005 by one five
hundreds he's,
he's the legend of our sport.
He raises in trophy trucks,
which is not my class.
Don't know what,
what Baja racing is.
Explain that.
What rob,
why don't you explain it?
Since you've done it decades.
Absolutely.
Bob.
One thousands is Baja peninsula basically
starting Ensonata race all the way
down to the pause.
Approximately thousand miles.
All dirt road,
all dirt roads,
some asphalt roads.
Sometimes we can't get through dirt.
So we have to get up on the highway and
actually race down the highway with the
traffic.
As bud was alluding to,
there is no rules.
The highways wide open,
the race is wide open.
There's cattle,
there's horses,
there's a,
are they speed limits on the highway?
Now there are,
there didn't use to be.
Yeah,
they didn't use to be.
Now you know,
we had sanctioning bodies.
The sport is growing a little bit and uh,
you know,
the Mexican government
does want rob doing,
I can't do 130 miles
an hour on the highway.
He can,
they don't want him to do 139 so they've,
they've got us down to 60 but they,
it's sections.
It's really,
it's kind of like in
between rounds in a fight,
you know,
you get jumped on the highway,
you get time to relax a little bit,
get to take a drink of water,
you're crews and 60 miles an hour.
And then I had about five miles you'd
dump off from the dirt again and you're
just hauling ass in the dirt.
How fast do you go on the dirt?
The top speed that close to one 40.
Oh Jesus.
Yeah.
We go cross dry lakes hundred and
3,540 miles an hour through the whoops,
you know,
two and three foot whoops.
Like waves anywhere from 60 all
the way up to 120 across them.
It's an incredible thing.
The,
the wheel travel of these trucks is,
you know,
over 20 inches in the front,
over 30 inches in the rear.
The tires that we have are 39 inches tall.
They cost a lot of money.
Luckily both bud and I or
spa supported by BF Goodrich.
Um,
it's an incredible,
incredible sport.
And like bud was saying,
when he got involved with it,
he fell in love with it.
And I did the same thing back in the
early eighties and I'm addicted to it.
Um,
the ball 1000,
it only comes once a year.
He tried to win it.
If you don't get it done,
you got to wait another 365 days.
You get down there and do it again.
And uh,
it,
it's,
it's an awesome feeling and you can't
wait to get down there and do it.
So these trucks,
they have like some sort of
special suspension on them
where each wheel is kind
of independent and they have a lot of
wheel travel so they can hit these big
crazy bumps and it's still kind of
keeps the thing fairly levels that the,
the idea of mindset.
Absolutely.
Got a great analogy there.
Yeah.
They're,
the front suspension is a arm independent.
The rear is actually straight axle,
but,
uh,
with,
you know,
shocks that are four and
a half inches in diameter,
coil springs that are
five inches in diameter.
Uh,
the trucks,
they work really,
really well over the bumps.
They're amazing.
When you watch them on video,
you see the wheels just flopping around
like they're just just super loose and a
credible thing that
it's absolutely amazing.
Yeah,
they have,
um,
I know dodge makes a
truck that's just like a,
a purpose built off road truck that
they sell for like civilians for it for
instance.
Truck.
Well I know Ford makes the raptor right,
but dodge dodge makes a,
an even more hardcore
version of it for the ram.
You guys are shaking it
not just be for people.
No,
no.
We just know the truck industry and
both rob and I were in an early stage to
develop with the raptor.
I raised her APP to know eight.
Rob was in the early development of,
of the other raptor testing and we just
had that conversation about testing
Borrego we,
we know the truck market pretty well.
Dodge has nothing that they've tried
to duplicate it is what they've done.
There's,
there's some something
called the ram runner.
Yeah,
exactly.
There's a,
Jamie,
pull up the video.
Dodd raptor versus Ram runner,
head to head.
This is what I'm referring to.
I saw a video online that was a,
have you driven one of those yet?
No,
I've driven the raptor a lot and
now they're an incredible vehicle.
Um,
and I know they're pretty
cool that you could buy them.
Like really?
I mean it's,
it's amazing to be able to
go to the Ford dealer and,
and get a truck that is capable
of doing what the Ford Raptor is.
I'm,
I'm blown away.
I've been in the offered
industry for a long time and uh,
it's absolutely incredible with the,
with the raptor can do.
Yeah.
Our neighbor has one of these things.
Use it to go get groceries
and see that's the,
uh,
the difference between
them is that the raptor,
apparently I've watched the video of
the raptor is more comfortable driving
around.
You could actually use
it as a regular car.
Where's the ram runner is much more like,
you know,
one of these things.
Something that you really
wouldn't drive on the street.
Yeah.
The railroad.
I don't know what it is.
I mean,
it's probably aftermarket are purpose
built by a third party or a second stage
manufacturer.
It's not,
I don't,
I mean,
so it's not like as
mainstream as the raptor,
they,
they run,
they run and I've talked to them,
I've been at the plant,
they run like eight fon fifties and
then they throw it wrapped in there,
eight one F-150 he's put a raptor,
I mean it's a,
it's a real production vehicle.
So I high number production vehicle,
that was what my point was going to be.
It's like this is become this,
this type of racing.
It's become so popular that the,
it's sort of bleeding over
into the commercial market.
The,
the,
the regular domesticated human beings
are buying these trucks that they could
just drive out into the desert and go
fucking go crazy and hit bumps with,
yeah,
I used to see,
we call,
you know,
the flat billers,
mimicking the off road
truck by an arranger,
putting fiberglass fenders on it,
raising it up,
lowering it.
And I think,
uh,
you know,
Ford Motor Company saw that.
It's like,
hey,
we should build something that you
can just buy right off the lot.
And,
and they did that I think a
2008 but and I both went to,
got invited to go to the out,
do some testing with the
raptor and blown away by it.
And then they came on the showroom and
you're capable of buying those things for
under $50,000.
So it's an incredible vehicle.
Yeah,
they're fast as shit.
Two right at six to the six is really
fast and motor I loader is incredible.
I'd beat the crap out of it.
And our race,
um,
did 103 hundred five
across the Diablo lake bed.
Um,
it's an amazing thing.
Motor oil,
that's a stock motor t
that's not even pumped up.
My trophy trucks got 900 horsepower.
That's why we can do for one 40 split
900 horsepower.
Yeah,
they're there now they're there.
They probably weigh full of gas.
105 gallons of gas gets
about two miles a gallon.
900 horsepower,
39 still touch five gallons
of gas driving a bomb.
In order to get anywhere.
In order to get anywhere you've
got to have that much gas.
Cause the two miles a gallon
you won't get very far.
It really like it's two miles
to the gallon pretty much.
That's about the average.
That is hilarious.
That's hilarious.
You have a two mile to the gallon car.
Wow.
900 horsepower.
It is a bomb.
It's the bomb.
900 horsepower.
100 and how many gallons?
How many?
Hundred and five gallons.
Wow.
That's crazy.
So um,
how long can that get you?
Like when you,
it's not always two miles,
right?
Like when you're on the
highway going 60 days,
it'll go up to eight.
Yeah,
it'll go up to price six.
Whoa.
Crazy.
We,
we,
we tried to,
we tried to go anywhere from a,
you know,
a hundred 175 miles to
two 25 on a tank of gas.
I'm with 900 horsepower at the tires.
Can't go a whole lot farther
when you out there in the desert,
spinning them and it just starts
tearing the rubber off of him.
And two,
do you have spares in the back or do
you have pitstops do you guys both?
Both.
We carry two spare tires on the back,
but we have to,
yeah,
just to,
but every,
every,
you know,
175,
225 miles,
we have a full on fuel pit.
We pull in there and stop.
They'll put,
you know,
a hundred gallons of gas for get it filled
back up and change the rear tires on
the truck.
And then if we happen to
have a flat in between spots,
you know,
they'll,
they'll rerock another tire.
So we pretty much have that plan to
race up and down the Baja peninsula.
That's about 1100 mile race will stop
every 200 miles if we do the shorter loop
races,
um,
anywhere from 250 to 500 miles
or the other races go halfway,
do tires and fuel and hit it.
So Bud,
when we did,
for folks who don't know bud produced,
he's produced Jesus Christ.
A hundred shows me how
many shows you produced,
produced,
overhauling,
and rides and rides.
When we did that.
Barracuda,
the,
the silver Barracuda that
we mean that was what,
like 2004 or five or since 2005.
Yeah.
So that was like right around
the year that you were,
you were beginning to rate
yep.
Right around the time.
And I loved,
I loved Jujitsu and I love all the
stuff that we used to train together.
And this is Kinda my new,
my next new passion.
I always had to figure out
what something new and crazy.
Yeah.
I'm going to go to Antarctica,
I'm going to climb Mt.
Everest.
I'm going to go do something stupid.
This is my something stupid.
It was really just a,
I had so many TV shows
on the air at the time.
My sponsors like,
hey,
we want to treat you once you go down
and doing the stupid celebrity race.
And then I just haven't returned.
Well Bud was,
so for folks who don't know was one of
the owners of the king of the cage back
in the day and button.
I mad at Jujitsu.
We trained at John Joc Machado's are
both students at John jocks and um,
you are always involved in a
bunch of fucking nutty shit.
You're always off doing something.
Looney tunes.
But this one man,
this one's stuck like glue,
this Baja thing.
Boy,
you would get this look in your eye
like a fucking junkie when you'd start
talking about like a,
like a crazed crackhead.
Just look to get that next fix.
And He came jockey,
I'm sure that 900 horsepower car flying
around and going 140 miles an hour or
bumps.
It is nothing like you've ever seen.
No,
you have to like,
I talked to people like a new,
a good friend of mine.
Um,
Andrew Hendricks,
he raced Fcca for years,
right?
So He's,
he's got,
he's got his Mustang,
he's got an Audi,
he's racing Scca and uh,
the American Le Mans series and
they're fast and he's loving it.
He took one riding a trophy truck,
sold his stuff,
and he's got five trophy trucks
now and he's gonna start racing.
So flat ground got boring.
Flat ground always gets point
going around with a fucking circle.
It's stupid.
It's you going around a circle.
You're going,
I left,
left
bad for your brain,
like bouncing up and down.
I talked to a guy who's an
expert in a lot of shit.
Bad for your brain.
That's what I'm saying.
My whole life I'm looking at my whole law,
my choices and my God,
it's amazing.
I've talked for a living.
What don't,
I'm not sure if there's
anything I don't do.
It is not bad for my brain.
But the bouncing around,
apparently he was telling me that even
just jet skiing like or waterskiing like
getting pulled behind a boat
and bouncing up and down.
He's like,
that's really bad for your brain.
Like you.
There's nowhere in nature where you like,
did he,
did he hit water and have your
head snap up and down like that.
And he's like in nature it's like what?
Running maybe the occasional jump.
You jump over things.
You're avoiding animals
that are trying to eat you.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But you,
you know the human
body's an amazing thing.
Right?
So my very first race,
I
don't think I could feel my neck or my
head for about three days afterwards.
My neck was so sore and I at the time,
and I've actually been a lot
smarter and technologies,
they gave me the heaviest,
oldest,
crappiest helmet.
It must have weighed six pounds and here
put this on and then it was in the car
for 36 hours with this helmet on and I
thought my head was going to come off.
You get a Mike Tyson neck from that.
Yeah.
So your body,
your workout.
I do.
I do for training for thing.
I put a 25 pound plate on my head and
I'm not kidding because I believe you,
you got to you,
your body starts to evolve and could
absorb that and you actually do.
And the thing that helps you the
most is you is you're almost like a,
like a drunk driving.
You just relax.
Do you seat belts?
It just fucking relax.
You know you always put like rob
and I will go take guys for a ride.
We do on occasion,
they're over on this,
on the holy shit bar and their tents and
there are so tense and there were seat
belts or sucked and stop breathing too.
Yeah.
And the,
and they suck.
They're there.
Um,
we actually took a seal team.
Guy was on my team and oh nine but he
put his seat belt so tight it like start
hurting their Clavel your
clavicle start crushing down.
You're stirred and Ms. Turner
starts separating from your chest.
And I'm not kidding.
He's like,
I think my heart hurts.
I'm like,
man,
I swear to God.
Am I joking?
No,
absolutely not.
My heart hurts.
I think it hurt my heart.
I'm like,
no,
you just,
what happens is you really,
you push so much on the clavicle down,
sucking down and your chest
is operating your ribs.
You just separating,
descending your sternum out.
So like the area that they cut up and
when they give you open heart surgery,
it starts separating,
gets carved the dry here.
And I'm like,
you're not having a heart attack.
You just put your things to come on Pussy,
get out of it.
You know,
I took Josh Barnett two years ago.
Yeah.
I know a lot of MMA guys do.
It doesn't apple,
Eric Apple,
he goes down there a lot.
No,
he's been down there a lot.
He does short court racing.
Um,
for,
yeah,
he did short course,
a lot of racing.
He told me he was involved
with some horrible,
horrible wreck.
It was bad.
Yeah,
he did.
He did a nose.
Did you see?
I think it was like Elsinore.
He was in that,
um,
west coast chill and went
over and over and over.
And He,
uh,
yeah,
he uh,
he got blood in his eye
and got all the Funky,
he'd say the same execution or leading,
yeah.
Head bleeding.
And he was,
he's a novice.
He's a great friend of mine and
he's an obvious and race as much.
Um,
but yeah,
that was [inaudible].
He's another fucking nut.
Right.
I mean,
he started out his career
doing motorcycle racing,
a motorcycle racing,
and then got into MMA and now
another crazy adrenaline junkie.
Yup.
The,
the idea behind this is
all based on competition.
And just one of the things
we were talking about,
like there's very little money in this.
Yeah.
For for it.
It's really,
you know,
it,
it's a beautiful sport because you don't
really have to have a lot on lending to
get in certain classes.
And then there's the,
like the upper echelon clash,
like Rob's class and there's not an,
I'll stop talking to him.
There's not a lot of money into it,
but I don't think there's a lot
how much money's in yacht racing.
I mean there's all the really big sports
or things that are on a bucket list.
You know,
there's not a lot of money and
climbing all met at Mount Everest.
It's actually cost you 25
grand if you want to go do it,
you,
it's just one of those
things you have to go do.
Right.
It's passion driven.
I mean,
we get addicted to it.
It's like a drug and we end up spending
everything that we have to do it.
The smaller cars,
the small classes,
the,
the run anywhere from 20
to 50 grand trophy trucks.
Like I drive their $500,000
to go $500,000 truck.
Yup.
Oh my God.
Should pull up a picture.
One of those.
What,
what would he looked for it?
A trophy trucks?
No,
just to Robin [inaudible]
one in your site.
[inaudible] dot com you'll pull it up.
And you know for me too is there's a
mystique around Baja for some reason.
It all based,
you know,
you go,
the essence of cool is that
because you're trying to,
is you're trying to figure yourself out
in your twenties and your thirties and
you look and you look
back at Steve Mcqueen,
guys like Steve McQueen and James Garner
and all these other cool Paul Newman.
They all race the race.
I mean they,
they did this race before and they
went down there and they raised,
they raised,
I mean McQueen almost
one in a couple of times.
Really.
Um,
Paul Newman race day when he was 80,
he was 80 within their race.
I mean these,
these cool guys be what
killed him and yeah,
poor bastard.
These cool guys wanted to
go down there and race.
So there's a cool mystique to it.
I mean the list of celebrities and
people want to go down there and race.
It's just interesting.
Yeah,
I guess it's a very strange
thing that this has become.
So is that the truck?
Yeah,
that's,
that's actually an image.
You're a trophy truck.
That's actually a short core struck there.
That's I,
I do short course racing too.
That's a pro too.
Um,
why is there a naked girl next to you?
Does she raise with you?
That would make racing better?
Absolutely.
That's a rockstar.
The image always have the
ladies in the posters.
Oh,
rockstar energy drink.
Yeah.
Like one of those dudes,
like I'm a rock star.
I'm out there driving around him.
A rock star.
Now he's the most humble driver lab.
There's a lot of guys out there.
I just wanted to let people
know who just listening.
A lot of people watch this.
More people listen and watch it.
So the idea behind it came
when like what year did this,
this,
this race get created?
I don't know,
probably in the,
in the early sixties when
I hear my version of,
yeah,
and then I'll fix it.
I read once now,
uh,
in,
in 62,
I'll tell you exactly the,
the,
the how it happened is 62 of the Honda
Motor Company decided that they were
going to,
they're going to put out to enduro bikes,
right?
1962,
Steve McQueen,
stunt guy.
Um,
his name's Dave Eakins.
Bud Eakins was his stunt
double in a lot of the races,
and I'll make this short.
They said,
how are we going to test these
bike and market to Americans?
These guys are just racers and
idiots and they wanted to go,
okay,
we're going to go,
we're getting swear to God.
This is what happened.
They went in 1962,
they went to Tijuana,
they went to western union,
they timestamp a card and they went down
to La Paz and they timestamp the cart,
no navigation,
no nothing.
And it made the Baja peninsula.
That was the very first run in the 60s.
That happened.
And then all of a sudden,
so they did a time,
it's kind of like,
you know,
you know the gumball rally,
this is like the gumball rally
but on dirt with a huge car.
So they did their rally and
then they post at a time.
It's like we did that in 35 minutes.
So then somebody else
came back or 35 hours,
sorry.
They think somebody
else came back to this.
Okay,
wait,
well we can beat that.
So they didn't 32 hours.
And if you look at the heritage of
people going down there and saying,
I can beat that.
And then truck started
going there and then cars
started going down there.
And then in 67,
there was,
there was a race.
60,
67,
there was a race.
The Nora right was the
first Nora and then,
um,
an icon my world,
right.
Uh,
Mickey Thompson who's an icon of motor
sports for everything that he's done,
a land speed and off road and everything.
He,
the guy that drove the rocket car.
Yeah,
he did.
He,
he drove,
he built land speed records.
Yeah,
he did every,
he's like Mickey,
Mickey Thompson in the motor
sports world is just a,
it's just a genius.
It was like he just to kind of
a pioneer and a lot of ways,
he was always like ahead of the game.
He was always building and pioneering
something before it's time.
Him and Perlman got together
and said let's do a race.
So they,
they started off in Tiawana and there
was a couple hundred guys there.
There is,
I mean Gardner was in there.
Uh,
Steve McQueen wasn't,
there were guys,
I'm not kidding.
We've had shoulder pads,
like football,
shoulder pads on,
on a motorcycle drop the
flag and they all go wow.
Wow.
So that's what started it all off yet.
It's still wild frontier and it's,
I'm telling you there's,
there's no rules.
Someone's in your way.
You Hawk nicely,
nicely.
And if they don't move,
you move them.
Like you pump them and let
you run into them with cars.
Yes.
So humans are cars.
You're running into humans
or you're running into cars,
cars,
cars.
It depends on the day.
But for me it's cars.
Try not to run into humans.
That's not it.
But you told me that
there's a lot of shenanigans
that go on with like the locals,
like the locals know that this
event is going to take place.
A lot of what we talked about,
we talked about before we
went on live on the air,
but besides the fact that
they try to touch the cars,
like if you see the videos like um,
I don't know how much,
how much of this stuff can we show?
We can't play the music.
Is that what it is?
No,
you can play all the other ones.
The other,
the other videos I sent you.
Um,
there's,
here's a video right here.
Yeah.
It's look how wide that fucking thing is.
It's about 92 inches wide,
which is about 15 inches
wider than a normal truck.
And then we are going across
the dry lake about one 30.
And that's your trophy truck?
That's a trophy truck.
That's bog California.
Oh,
that looks fun.
It is fun.
Look how close those people get.
Yeah.
Down there in Baja.
I mean the,
this is the biggest sport that they have.
And,
and they,
they wait year round for us
to come down there and they,
they have uh,
you know,
such a huge passion for it.
Like I do.
They at times they want
to touch the truck.
Well you'll go by and you'll see him
trying to reach out and grab the truck.
Some of the other things they,
the shenanigans they do is a build
jumps booby traps we call them.
And they,
they crashed a lot of cars.
But what they're doing is they
want to see the excitement.
They want to see the truck or the buggy
hit the jump and fly through the air and
get pictures.
One thing it's always funny
about Mexico is you see the,
they have the,
the phone cameras and I think you can
piece together your whole race by them
with their phone cameras.
If they all post that,
you could pretty much put
the whole race together,
styles him.
So I'll put it in perspective.
So if,
um,
first of all,
the Mexican people are amazing,
they're amazing to us and it
sounds like I'm making for them,
but they are innocent
enough or they just
decide like they truly,
and I had to learn this the hard way.
I had a celebrity in my
car and I was driving,
but it's just a random celebrity.
No,
I had actually a chip.
I had chip Foose with me and my car.
Okay.
And we're driving and I'm doing about 90,
just a rate random dirt road.
And I see a bunch of people over here.
Right.
Okay.
I got to make sure to watch them,
make sure they're not
darting out in front of me.
And there's see some random people over
here with a fire and there's a lot of
them and it's,
it's dusk and they both have
fires on the side of this road.
And I'm like,
this is true.
What does his fucking people
doing on the side of the rode?
Boom.
And I hit a telephone pole.
They buried in the middle of the road,
right.
And I went up like this and I'm
coming down like at 90 miles an hour.
I'm like,
Oh fuck,
this is going to be terrible.
Luckily the car absorbed it.
We nerfed in,
bounced off and kept going.
I didn't even see the telephone
pole cause I'm an idiot.
I'm a Newbie and I'm looking
at a bunch of Mexicans over.
There's a bunch of guys that's really
nice to these people coming out to see it.
So they thought it was cute to set up
this booby trap just to watch people try
to jump it and go flying through the air.
Well I think,
you know,
I think the red necks would
do the same thing if you,
if you let,
if you didn't have those fences,
the date the Daytona 500
and they could actually,
you know,
fix the outcome.
Like we're going to,
we're going to see if Dale
junior could jump this car.
Right?
Oh for sure they would do it.
But that's what it is in Mexico.
There's no fences,
there's no fences to keep it back there.
They're able to go wherever they want.
Well and the capabilities of these
trucks are pretty extraordinary.
They're very different than
anything that a NASCAR car could do.
They're not necessary.
I have a belief because some people
throw bottles and shit like that,
but I,
they are not unnecessarily out to kill
us or hurt us because actually after the
wreck us,
they'll help us.
I've had them rec rec before and a booby
trap and they'll roll the car over to
help you fix a car with a welder.
They'll get pimped,
you change a tire and
they'll push you on your way.
They not only throw bottles,
but they throw rocks.
Sometimes they thrown snakes in the cab
of the truck and thrown snakes in the
cab of the truck to,
you know,
it didn't happen to me,
but my partner it with mastercraft racing,
he,
he was coming in and it's an audit coming
to the finish at night and they know,
yeah,
Robbie Pierce from mastercraft,
he got a snake thrown in the
cab of the truck and holy.
Thankfully it's not me cause I
don't really care for snakes.
What kind of snake?
I don't,
I don't know.
I know [inaudible] is so non poisonous,
you're driving 80 miles an hour to snake
kits there and you look down and it
could be,
it might as well be a cobra at
that you're really hardcore.
You put in your teeth and you keep track
at that point you just pull over
and get the fuck out of the car.
So was technology developed specifically
for this race to figure out how to
drive fast and hit those bumps?
Cause this all,
I mean I'm fairly ignorant to,
I mean I've,
I've,
I kind of understand
suspensions a kind of see what,
but it's pretty obvious when
I look at your trophy truck,
there's this,
some extraordinary equipment on that.
Yeah,
absolutely.
It's,
it's developed over the years.
You know,
like when it,
when bud was telling
the story earlier about,
but it started in the 60s they were
taking stock trucks down there,
putting a little bit bigger tires on them,
taking the windshields item,
stuff like that seat,
putting some extra seat belts in them.
And now it's just developed into,
you know,
big tall tires that way.
Tire and wheel probably
weighs 150 pounds a piece.
Wow.
Shocks $15,000 for a set
of shocks for the truck.
Nine horsepower.
Like I said,
uh,
some of us has automatic trainees,
some of the manual trannies,
um,
lights,
like a baseball stadium of KC lights as
a sponsor and run seven of them on the
roof and 7:00 AM on the front bumper
and you can see a mile down the road and
light up the whole desert.
And Wow.
Over the years it's,
you know,
we keep developing,
making things better and
it's the whole ego thing.
You want to be the first one to La Paz
and you're constantly thinking about what
can you do,
what can you make?
What can you build to make it go faster?
Well,
go ahead.
No,
please.
I mean,
and there's an entire industry
that was spawned off of this.
This is a halo,
right?
So trophy trucks and Baja
racing is a halo for any brand.
It doesn't really matter what it is.
We,
we entertain brands like we sit forward,
BF,
Goodrich,
Casey,
they can,
they can go down there and conquer Baja.
Go pro,
you name the company and they want to
go to Baja and they always come to me
cause I'm,
I'm the media guy and they're
like how do we do this?
I'm like I dunno,
I'll hook up with a trophy truck and
we'll go beat the shit out of your product
and see if it works.
It's,
there's a whole entire industry.
If you go to Sema,
which is that big,
you know,
aftermarket parts thing.
There's an entire industry
which has dedicated off road
and the halo of off road
is Baja 1000 racing.
It's the halo.
It doesn't really,
do you know how,
when you say it's the halo,
what do you mean by that?
Yeah,
it's,
it's really the pinnacle.
If you,
if you go to racing like Nascar or f one,
you know the stuff is developed
and then trickles down.
So there is a pass through from
everything that rob is complete because he
complains a lot.
Everything that rob complaint,
cause it's not fast enough,
it's not good enough.
You get a 900 horsepower truck that goes
two miles to the gallon and he'll talk
to his shot covers.
I had a shot,
I hit this bump one time
at 85 miles and I felt it.
I felt it.
I don't want to feel it.
And I drive,
I hit it all due respect.
He drives a fucking pillow.
I mean,
I think it drives,
it drives.
So when you're going over
those crazy bumps and shit,
you're fairly level nothing.
He feels nothing
you,
you feel a little bit.
But it's,
it's incredible.
It's,
it's a analogy we have is just
like riding on a marshmallow.
When you jump and you land,
it's like just falling,
like you're landing on a marshmallow.
Wow.
And that's the development
over all the years.
And,
and,
and thankfully I'm in
the trophy truck class,
which is the elite class.
I've worked my way up from the bottom,
driven through them all and
definitely don't want to go back.
And thanks.
Difference.
The bottom ones,
like what are the,
how many classes are there?
Well,
there's,
there's more than 10 classes.
There's,
there's probably six or eight truck
classes and they're six or eight buggy
classes and there's also
motorcycles and ATVs.
Utvs all these,
there ends up being over
20 classes at the bottom,
1000 and,
and they all compete
against their own class.
They all started their own
time together against a clock.
They don't,
we're not racing.
We were racing all together
the track the same time.
But we're separated by start time.
So you're really racing clock.
You do
have traffic.
You do have to get by the guys,
um,
to,
to get the win.
I'm so used to bud jumping.
So when you're,
when you're driving these things,
it's very different
than the cheaper trucks.
Yeah.
I want to say cheaper cause
none of them are cheap.
But the different clouds,
different classes.
Cause you got an entry level class.
Exactly.
You got to have your entry level
classes and there are a lot more stock.
They don't have as much.
We'll travel.
They got eight or 10 inches of wheel
travel and the truck's smaller tires.
They're just a restricted a lot more
and those cars are a lot more difficult.
They beat you up a lot more.
They take a lot longer to get
down the down the peninsula.
Yeah.
That's what I was going to get at.
So like when you first started out,
you took much more of a beating.
Absolutely.
So now like that's,
that's why you're into
these really cushy rides.
Like you've been there,
done that,
been there,
done that.
I want to work my way up and,
and get to the top of the sport.
I'm doing it for 30 years and I've
been in the elite class since the mid
nineties.
So this is a good vehicle
for the apocalypse except
for the fact that he uses so
much fuel.
If you have gun,
you can get fuel.
Yeah.
We got to make your own fuel
at a certain point in time.
You're not running diesel.
Right.
Yeah.
See that's the problem.
You know,
Neil young makes his own diesel.
I think Daryl Hannah makes her own ds.
A lot of vegetable oil and crap like that.
Yeah.
Well Neil Young,
uh,
apparently has this gigantic farm.
He has like a thousand plus Acre ranch
in northern California and he makes his
own bio diesel and runs all his
vehicles off of his own gasoline.
So he's called politely,
totally off the grid.
They like a conversion
on the old Mercedes.
Yeah.
You can do a conversion
on any kind of old car.
Well,
not even new cars.
Apparently.
You want to do conversions to biodiesel?
Yeah.
We have to.
We have to actually,
I was going to run one year.
I was,
I was working on that show.
That picture of Jamie.
What'd you put up?
Neil Young's 59 Lincoln runs on
bio diesel and give me plugged in.
Wow.
I like that.
That's pretty dope.
I was working on a dealer.
I was going to do a truck and
all electric truck down there.
Oh,
switching out gas.
Is that possible?
Yeah,
it's possible.
I mean the,
the lithium batteries because
I was involved with a truck
company and then they,
you know,
my answer is very stuck.
Like how,
what can we do to market
this thing and read it?
I don't really care what it is.
It can be,
right.
It could be a mini bike.
My answers race it.
We should probably go race it.
Right.
I don't care.
Could you do a,
I mean is it feasible that you could
have enough battery power to do that?
Sure.
Yeah.
In a tour could be amazing.
That's why I want to do it.
Torque on those.
The Electric Motors are amazing.
The problem is I don't think you would go.
Our pits,
my pits,
not his,
my pits are about 120 miles apart
and that'd be hard to get there.
Yeah.
My Buddy Aubrey has one of those Teslas.
Right.
And the pickup is incredible.
Like I was really shocked
at how fast those things go.
Like the zero to 60 in like four seconds.
Right.
It's bananas and it's weird
because there's no gears.
It's just you're just going,
it's not like man,
it's just,
it's very much like a space
ship and then you just,
you hit the grass completely silent.
I mean,
you hear the tires rolling on the rubber,
the rubber rolling on the
concrete and that's it.
You don't,
you don't hear anything.
It's a very strange,
that'd be a little bit scary
in Baja because the spectators,
you're,
they're used to here in the
race vehicle come into electric.
They probably wouldn't hear it coming,
right?
Yeah,
we can play that annoys Erica.
We can play that polka music
or something like that.
Yeah.
There you go.
Um,
how many,
you would have to have
so many batteries though.
What I'm thinking is like a Tesla.
If you go from the beginning
fully charged to the end,
you're getting like 300 miles I think.
Yeah.
But that's all I would need to do.
We planned it out.
It'd be 120 miles who charged.
So we would,
you build a carriage underneath,
which are about seven,
800 pounds of batteries and
then you get to the next pit.
You have a fully charged set of hours.
You drop that carriage,
put the carriage in,
bolted back up.
I'd be in my own class and I can
provide them whatever company was.
Um,
at the time it was a
company called Phoenix.
I can provide them with a
Baja 1000 win as a market
has I'm fully answered or
any of these other country,
any of the other companies have ever
thought about doing something like that.
Forward is amazing at it
because they do use Baja a lot.
Last year,
um,
I raced a brand,
the brand new F-150 the 2015 F-150 which
is a twin tube charged v six in the
stock class.
That stock suspension stock everything
stock on the car it twin Turbo Charge v
six and then we did the raptor together.
I did the wrap to wait,
he was on the testing and I
raced the F-150 last last year.
And when you race in F-150,
how much of it is different than what
you would borrow off the showroom floor?
Nothing.
Roll cage.
We had we a fuel cell roll cage,
spare tire.
That one I had,
I had a radio and we had cup holders.
I remember looking at some of the videos.
It's a cup holder in there.
You can look it up online.
F-150 race,
the Baja 1000 there's me and
you're going to laugh at me.
That's it right there.
Uh,
no,
that seems pretty different.
No,
it's different.
Not,
no.
You'll see my,
it's,
it's the 2012 bond and they pissed me
off because I told them they did this to
make me mad.
But they haven't,
they made me wear a white driving suit.
Folks.
You don't know bug.
Where's bud?
You're,
you're the weirdest
fucking dude I've ever met.
When it comes to clothes,
he'd go over Bud's house.
He's got all black pants,
all black shirts.
His whole fucking wardrobe.
His entire closet is black shirts,
black pants,
black tee shirts,
black underwear,
I'm assuming.
Yeah.
Black socks.
Black sneakers.
Yup.
He just doesn't want
to think about colors.
No.
So when they hit you with some white,
did you wear it or did
you just get a marker?
Sharp?
I was,
I was pretty up.
Luckily I didn't have to get in
the car at the beginning and I am,
the rain was,
uh,
the weather was pretty cold,
so I had a black slicker.
I put them on.
So it rained on you and you rolled around
the dirt and you white drivers seat.
I've been trying to get bud high for so
long to get them to smoke pot and I'm
like,
the first thing you need to do is
throw away those fucking black clothes.
You're going to go,
wow,
look at all these pretty colors.
I could choose.
Just let me get a skill.
Let me get a little
wearing pastels.
You'll start enjoying different colors.
Just start realizing how ridiculous
turned to an Andy Dick and you can wear
pastels and shot Andy Dick.
I'm saying you have an
appreciation for other colors.
No,
no.
I think if I smoked pot,
which I'm not going to,
I'd be more into the dark lord world and
world and I'll have just maybe skulls
in my tee shirts.
Wow.
You would get darker?
Yeah.
Okay.
Now when you drive an F150,
do you use like regular tires of like
you'd take tires that are right off of a
showroom floor?
We had the new BF Goodrich,
k o two is that we raised on this,
on this truck,
normal suspension,
regular F-150 suspension doc dude.
We went hunting at to hone
ranch up in a northern,
like a,
it's near Bakersfield for TV,
right?
You did that,
that team?
No,
this was a recent one.
We went wild pig hunting to hone ranches.
Uh,
this huge ranch.
It's a 1,700,000 acres,
biggest ranch in California.
Huge place.
And uh,
this guy,
Cody,
who was one of the guides there,
one of the hunting guides drove us all
around an F150 and I'm ain't talking
horrific terrain and this fucking
thing is driving over rocks and,
and I,
I was so impressed.
I was like,
this is like one of the best commercials
for an F150 you could ever get.
Just going to,
like,
if you're thinking about
buying one of these things,
what's an F-150 k below go fucking drive
around to hone ranch for a couple of
days and one of these things and
think if you would want to do this.
I don't anything else.
This is,
this is what I,
oh,
that's the wrap to that.
Rob.
Rob and I were involved
with the development of,
so that's a,
that's a custom raptor.
That's not like a,
yeah,
we raised that in class eight and we,
we built it out but it,
it,
that one's still had to stock motor.
Um,
yeah.
Stock,
motor stocked Dash.
We did have,
we did have custom
suspension on it is actually,
that's what caused me to race
the F150 last year is they go,
okay well we built the raptor
a little bit and you know,
people start chatting now online
like oh that wasn't really stock.
So they made us raise a stock car.
Wow.
So just not even a raptor,
just a regular F150 regular F150 regular.
Now did you bottom out at all with that?
Um,
that's probably an understatement.
Yeah.
You don't bottom out with your truck?
Uh,
we do,
but we're going three times as fast
as the stock truck so it bottoms out.
You don't feel quite as bad.
It doesn't do as much damage.
So the bottom of your F-150
was completely stock as well?
No,
no plates or anything.
We,
no,
we did.
We had,
um,
we definitely had a skid plate underneath
the front of them to protect the motor
underneath.
Yeah.
Cause we bought them down a lot.
That's what you see in
the front of the raptor.
That front piece that skipped down.
That's a skid plate.
Yep.
So you just installed
something along those lines.
Yep.
That's it.
Wow.
And then after we raced it and then
the car was in such good shape,
but I can't even believe
cause this year was what?
Last year.
It's to pull up that video.
F150 races Baja.
Yeah,
it's a 2000 it,
you'll see it.
We put it up online.
I'm the FordF one 50 new F-150 races,
concrete ball.
Um,
they,
uh,
this was a tough 2012,
2013.
Sorry.
It was the single toughest
Baja thousand I've ever seen.
I,
I don't know Roger Norman,
who owns score decided to,
it was his first ball.
1000 courses is my opinion.
I'll let rob talk.
It was his first Baja 1000.
He wanted to make a statement
and he's a former racer.
He wanted to make it the
worst fucking course you ever,
ever could drive.
And it was tough.
It was hard and slow and fast and gnarly.
And how did they change it?
He just marks the course.
She goes,
this is the F150.
This is it.
Right.
That's it.
That's amazing.
That's a stock F150 which
is the lights on it.
Yup.
Wow.
That's you driving that thing.
Yep.
I have the blue helmet sitting in my
two great F-150 fucking commercial.
I mean,
Ford's really smart doing this.
I'm,
I'm fucking never thought about racing
in my life and now I'm thinking,
God,
I got to do this.
Goes wrong.
You got do right next time.
Here's the way to go.
Then you go straight to
the top trophy truck.
Next time you're in Vegas,
he lives in Vegas.
Next time you have Vegas,
he'll take you out to
prim and go for a ride.
You'll shit yourself.
I'm there in May.
I'm there in May for the UFC incontinent.
You'll be what?
We'll make a deal.
I'll get you UFC tickets.
You a,
he'd take me for a fucking
beat ride in the desert.
We're in
love that Amber Love
to go to the beautiful,
it's good event to Tj
Dillashaw versus Hanan.
Barao it should be fun.
Um,
now you guys have been involved
in this for a long time.
How much is the popularity
increased over the last few years?
Because it seems like
there's a lot of exposure.
Like I'm hearing about it all the time.
Maybe I'm hearing about it just
because I'm friends with bud,
but I mean,
I'm seeing it online.
I'm seeing like a lot of these crazy
like ram runner type trucks are being
built.
Yeah.
Popularity.
It's,
it's,
you know,
I've known for 32 years and it's,
it's increased.
Um,
Bud's definitely helping out
a lot with score this year,
you know,
with television production,
getting us out there on TV,
putting very good shows together.
I think here at the end
of April and April 20th,
April 20th.
Yeah,
we did it.
We just did a deal with CBS.
You know,
I just,
I told him this great story that I won.
I won my race in 2012 in my class.
And then Roger Norman,
who was a new owner,
came up to me and swear to God,
he's like,
well,
now you're a champion.
You can produce TV.
For me.
It was what he said to me.
It's like great and I get
to happy cause you know,
you know me as I do,
I do TV,
I do all my stuff.
So now I get to kind of merge and I always
see them to this merge my two hobbies
together.
When I was doing Jujitsu,
we had king of the cage.
Right,
right.
Cause I gotta have a reason and I really
a television vehicle to do something
cause then I get to be kind
of be cool in this sport.
Well you're kind of a workaholic and it's,
it helps you when you're doing Jujitsu.
Well you know,
hey I need to know what the fuck's
going on when I'm watching fights.
It's exactly right.
So it's,
so it's a way to sort of make a hobby,
a part of your job.
But you do my immersion style,
like robble,
he's like,
I've raced for 10 years
and now I'm producing a TV.
There's not much,
I haven't done their
experience down there.
Not like rob has,
but he,
I,
I know the racers feel comfortable.
Just like you know when
you're commentating a fight,
it's a fight or you feel
comfortable that you,
you're commentating God,
you know what the fuck they're doing.
The setups,
I know what they're doing in the car.
I'd been on the course and not,
not in,
not in the super trucks,
but I've been down there going,
I know that course.
I know what he's doing.
This is what happens.
That's a booby trap.
Some were editing the show.
I get to bring my experience into it.
Yeah.
That's got to help a lot for,
for the riders,
for the drivers.
Absolutely.
He has as much or more
passionate than I do.
Just just riding around with him today
and listen to him talk about all the
stuff and how jacked up he gets when
he watches the videos and stuff.
He's like a kid in the
candy store and yeah,
buds fucking show rides is what got me to,
I never thought about
buying a classic car,
but I watched his show rides.
I'm like,
God damn,
I want to carry one of those.
That looks fucking cool.
I think the show's coming back.
By the way.
This just coming back.
It should come back to you
have Christ right back there.
You could put two more cars.
I this space.
I got a little garage.
You can put two cars.
I'm thinking of expanding,
thinking,
getting a bigger place that I got to
put an archery range and there's a will.
There's an archery range here.
We,
whether either know it or not,
there's targets in the back and there's
a straight shot 28 yards from the front
door to the back.
You got to tag the Werewolf
cause that what you got to,
I've I've a compound bow sight back there.
Uh,
it's normal.
It compound bow a target back there.
Absolutely normal.
Well my new thing is hunting and I've
been doing that the last couple of years.
I'm fucking bananas about that.
The way your banana,
it's about racing.
So I'm trying to incorporate
that into my life.
And will we do that to them?
Yeah.
They would kill animals on the
race course every once in a while.
Yeah.
But I don't think that's hunting.
Oh,
I think that's just traffic jam.
That's just a livestock getting
on the race course back to uh,
the course getting tougher.
How did they make the course tougher,
rob?
You can enter that.
Roger looks at the maps,
tries to figure out the roughest worse
spots on the whole Baja peninsula and
then tries to mark the course
so it goes through all that.
He wanted to make a statement.
We wanted to make Baja tougher than ever.
And he,
he did it last 2013 it was a loop
race from Ensonata to Ensonata.
It wasn't a peninsula run,
but he went to all the worst parts
of Baja and had us run through it.
So they changed the
actual place you go to.
So there's no real benefit.
Oh,
every year.
Every year.
Every year the course gets different.
Absolutely.
Every year it's different.
Maybe runs the opposite direction,
just different different areas because
that becomes a big issue with like say
like the Nurburgring,
which is the benchmark that they use to
test performance cars there the issue
becomes when guys have raced
in Newburg ring so many times,
they know exactly when to
slow down exactly when you
speed up and that has a big
effect on those Nurburg Ring Times
because you know everyone's chasing that
seven minute time around the Nurburgring
and now sub seven minute in that
portion,
nine 18 they've managed
to go sub seven minutes.
She just fucking insane.
But a lot of that is those
guys knowing that course.
Absolutely.
Then you don't have that.
No.
Our stuff changes every time.
It's different.
Even loop races every time you come around
there's already been a hundred other
cars that had been there since you had,
it's completely different.
Silt beds,
rocks or moved.
So that's part of the thing that's so
interesting about our sport is never the
same.
Well,
it's interesting.
It's also the mayhem
starts with the organizer.
So I want to put in perspective for,
so you know what a tough mudder is,
right?
Um,
I've heard the expression,
so at tough mudder or those,
you know those races they put through
obstacle courses and through mud holes and
you're going to take over year to climb
up a wall and to go through fire and
crawl through Barb wire fence.
This is like a tough mudder.
Our organizer,
which is Roger and some of
the guys who mark the course,
they want,
they,
it start,
the mayhem starts with them because
they'll put us through shit and they know
we're going to get stuck or they'll go,
if he's not paying attention,
he's going to hit that rock.
He was going to go flip it off
the edge and that'll be great.
These guys are sadistic pricks.
So there's saying yes,
you're going to set up a rock there
to make sure we're going to set up the
course by rock.
So if you don't pay attention,
you're going to go flying
off the edge of a cliff.
Yes,
and I've been,
I'm not kidding.
Sometimes there'll be,
it's really weird.
You'll be reading the terrain
and reading the terrain.
You'll come up over this rise
and there's lefthand turn,
and if you don't pay attention,
you're off Jesus Christ.
If it starts with this statistic
pricks that are down there,
mark the course.
Am I wrong?
No,
absolutely right.
Well,
you told me once that you were driving
and you came upon a wreck and a guy had
his bone sticking through his
leg when a guy broke his leg.
Right.
And you if flipped off the side of a
cliff and you had to get down there and
locals are starting to creep
in and it got real sketchy.
No,
no,
that wasn't,
that wasn't a,
you're mixing two stories,
you mean?
I'm like,
yeah,
the Josh Barnett story in our rec.
We had my team in Oh seven the BF
Goodrich Shimo seven had one of the worst
wrecks in the planet.
Everybody thought the two drivers who
were dead and I had to go in and get them.
And this is part of,
again,
this is an adventure race.
It's not car racing.
This is an adventure race.
And what happened in ours.
This is our BC car went off the cliff
into San Javier and to guys like us,
you say he went off the cliff at son
Javier is fucking crazy cause it's far,
uh,
300 feet.
And there are sections on the course where
they're inverted where it's like this
and you just hit the car,
dropped 300 feet,
rolled seven times,
300 feet,
destroyed the car.
And I didn't know cause I went,
we were just talking
about it cause I went,
I was down in Loretto,
we went down to La Paz and I got a call
to go back to Loreto cause our cars in
trouble and we can't find the car
and I didn't know where he's at.
And then the guys in the car call
my wife two o'clock in the morning,
that's not good.
They call my wife on the sat phone
even though I told him how to use a sat
phone.
No like,
and they sound all fucked up.
They're like us bud there.
And nature's like what the fuck?
So she calls me on my sad phone goes
like somebody just called here from the
house and like,
all right,
where would they say the way that thick?
No,
they just hung up.
So now our car is off the course.
We know it's not moving
because we can track it.
We don't know where they're at.
We could kind of tell way they were,
they were the last time.
So I did this again.
This is an adventure race and Rob's
got 7 million of these stories.
I'll tell you one stupid story and then
I'll shut up cause I've been talking too
much.
He keeps saying I'm going to shut up.
You better stop.
Good.
Supposed to shut up.
You're supposed to be here
doing a podcast but not on me.
I self deprecating you.
Fuck,
I'm the dude.
Tried to get my friend
tell you goddamn story.
Alright,
so we exists,
we're racing and I remembered it was
Kenny Barcher might these two guys in the
car.
There was Tracy Jordan was a rock crawler,
king of the hammers guy and Kenny Bartram.
Candy bars was just,
you know,
famous guy who he cowboy Kenny does.
Uh,
he does a new kind of cowboy stuff
and he's an Fmx guys of Mozart,
motocross guy.
So I told him I to get in the car,
San Javier is very dangerous.
Settle yourself down,
get you sign Javier,
and then you can haul ass,
you know,
down to La Paz,
no problem.
13 miles from the pit,
13 miles from the pit.
It's straight down.
And he knows I'm not lying.
There's a twisty road and
there's cliffs on one side,
you're on the side of the mountain for
13 miles and there's clips on the side
road.
Real tight,
twisty stuff.
Don't make a mistake.
And let me tell you why,
because 200 years ago,
some priest,
this is actually true,
200 years ago,
some priest on a donkey,
they used to,
what they used to do with emissions,
they used to be two days.
Missions used to be two days apart.
They'd set a mission here and then him
and a donkey and somebody else would go
up a road.
And when after the second day they'd
land and they build another mission right
there.
And then two days later they do it.
So up this hill,
this donkey trail going up this hill,
this guy and I talked to him,
I had Thanksgiving dinner with him.
He hung the wheel off it
off the corner and said,
Oh shit,
hold on.
Six Times he counted the rev,
the revolutions going over and over
and all of a sudden there was nothing.
And then they hit and the
code drive was knocked out.
He had a compression
brews from his helmet,
um,
compression boots.
His helmet got hit and they put
a bruise on his skull from the,
from the roll cage.
So I ha,
so my story is I get to Loreto and
nobody's there were sold before behind.
There was no pit,
there's no support.
And there's one guy picking up cans.
I'm in my race suit,
I studied Jujitsu.
I'm a bad ass.
Right.
Okay.
So like I go up to this guy and I
look at him and he's an older guy,
he's in his sixties I really
didn't feel like talking.
I just said,
give me your keys.
He looked at me,
excuse me.
I said,
give me your keys.
I have an injured driver.
I need your truck.
So he reaches in his pocket.
I was going to beat his ass.
I didn't care.
I was going to take his
truck and I'd take his truck.
I have an injured driver on the course.
So why wouldn't you just
ask them to help you?
Yeah,
I dunno.
Full with adrenaline and
crazy and I was tired.
And you stay up for three
days and go ask some guy from,
I'm not standing up for three minutes
and you stay up for 36 hours and then go.
He said,
excuse me sir,
can I,
I'm not English.
So he said,
give me your keys.
I said,
gimme your keys.
You lucky you didn't get shot.
Yeah,
that's true.
So he reaches in his pocket
and he hands out and he goes,
can I go with you?
I'm like,
sure,
get in.
So I grab this,
I grab his truck and it was a stock Toyota
truck and we go down this river bed,
did that riverbed,
which is terrible by,
it took me two hours to go 13
miles and the stock Toyota truck,
little tiny itty bit like a mini truck.
We got to San Javier,
went up searching forums,
stopping every time
that there was a crest.
Every time that I thought
momentum could take a driver off,
we'd stop search,
couldn't find them.
So two hours we finally found them.
It was still night.
Well it was it still night I
found them and my co driver got,
had a concussion.
He's vomiting,
he's peeing,
peeing,
pissing himself.
He smelled like shit.
Got picked up.
My two drivers with down there and the
scavengers are already started taking
wheels off the car,
gps,
anything you can get off the car.
You were already doing that while
the guys were inside the car,
guys were already there.
He got off the top of the um,
out of the gully and they were
already down there picking.
So I went back down there to get my
sat phone and get my other stuff.
And I'm like,
get the fuck away.
You gotta I'm shooting the Mexicans the
way that we're already picking this car
apart.
Wow.
And uh,
so I get Tracy back in the car.
Um,
and this is,
these are stories,
these happen every,
that's why it's an adventure race.
I'm not like,
I went to the drag strip
and it did nine seconds.
I got Tracy back in the car two and a
half hours back and we stopped cause he
had to vomit every,
every like every 15 minutes.
Like hold on,
goes well and he's vomiting.
He got a concussion,
bad concussion.
So we get him back.
He's okay.
We get him into Loreto
as I'm gonna get him out.
We were in Lauretta,
we got him down to La Paz and
by that time it was seven,
eight o'clock in the morning
and taken to the emergency room.
Probably not advisable,
but took an emergency room.
I told that like,
yeah,
I told the doctor is Spanish that he or
he heard his dick and he's got to check
his dick.
So the doctor,
so the doctor needs got to
take your pants off.
He starts shaking his pants.
Tracy's Georgia,
swear to God,
he's looking at me.
He's like,
why is he out?
I go,
I told him you hurt your Dick.
God.
Oh,
so how many people have died
doing this race?
Eh,
there's every,
every year.
So there's,
there's probably probably one motorcycle
or the biggest thing is there's
accidents on the highway.
It's not actually that
race cars that happened,
but uh,
because of the race starts and
Ensonata goes all the way to the pause.
We raced all the way through the day,
through the night,
into the next day.
And I usually,
a lot of the accidents happen
there on the highway with,
with the,
the spectator traffic
or the chase traffic,
race,
race cars.
Not Too often.
Motorcycle guys get hurt a lot.
I mean,
Josh Barnett hit him more
to software guy and uh,
in 13 or 12,
in 2012,
he had a motorcycle guy.
But what happened was that,
uh,
you know,
it's funny.
Monster Energy called me and they
said they wanted to do I know any,
um,
any athletes or any athletes
are superstars and want to
come down and race cars.
They were out.
I'm like,
yeah.
So I called Josh.
I know.
He's like,
he's the ultimate gearhead
and two gearheads.
If you say,
hey,
you want to come race,
he two weeks notice never
raced off road in his life.
I had him in a car.
He comes down there to like
the next week I put it in my,
we do some training down,
down to the sterile beach,
show them how to work in the car
and next thing he's in a race.
Poor fucker.
He's like a 19.
He was 19 hours.
He went like,
took him 19 hours.
You'd like the first stent like three,
like 300 miles.
He's going through a silt bed.
There was a motorcycle guy
clips him and breaks his leg.
Now,
Josh did one of the most amazing things.
I'm not saying that rob wouldn't do this.
So Josh Barnett,
do you know who he is?
No.
Youngest ever.
UFC heavyweight champion.
Super Great Guy.
I had him on the podcast.
He's probably one of the best podcasts
guest,
excuse me,
one of the best podcast
guests I've ever had.
He's super intelligent guy.
Yeah,
he's so smart.
Heavyweight fighter.
Amazing,
amazing grappler,
amazing fighter.
And He loves cars.
He has a Shelby,
he's got,
he's got all kinds of
cars and he loves it.
He's a fucking nut.
So he goes down there into a silk,
the silk bed,
um,
and he wanted to get,
he wants to get around it,
but you don't really have control.
And the silt bed,
you can hit it.
Sometimes you hit a Rut and it
throws your ride a little bit.
He hit this guy and broke his leg,
compound fracture in his leg.
So he gets through the silt bed.
And not a lot of guys that do this,
by the way.
I'm just telling you,
it's just like for the
first time being down there.
So he and he feels like shit
and he'll tell you this story,
but he pulls off to the side of the court,
goes in the silt bed,
which is dangerous,
by the way,
pulls the Guy Morton Morton,
the guy's motorcycle out.
So no other cars hit it
and then picks the guy up,
walks him out and puts them
on the hood of his car.
Calls in,
waits for a helicopter to come,
helicopter comes.
Josh carries this guy with a compound
fractured leg into the helicopter,
drops him a helicopter,
then puts his helmet back
on and continuous race.
And then he rolled it.
He rolled his truck after all that.
There's Josh.
Oh yeah,
that's the rest of the
pitcher right there.
That's it.
That's his buggy monster energy truck.
Wow.
So you were talking about the dude who
raced on flat surfaces and then just gave
it up and started doing
only this kind of dirt.
Crazy shit.
There's not a lot of these courses though,
right?
It's like you could go,
there's a lot of race courses around the
country where the average person can go
and do,
you know,
a,
a track day and put on a helmet
and drive fast on a course.
How many courses are there like this
where a guy can just go out and it's
unlimited Baja.
There's,
there's roads everywhere.
Um,
go down there and,
and practice or run or play.
You'd have to go to Mexico to do it.
There's,
there's some stuff in the,
in the states.
Well,
there's a lot of races by the way.
Yeah.
There's,
I mean,
he does short course.
You can,
you can,
you can gear up in a pro of pro four,
pretty easy.
And you go short court,
race and then long there's,
um,
there's two organizations.
There's obviously score and there's a
couple of other organizations that do,
you know,
the mint,
the mint 400 with rob races
in a best in desert robberies.
And I've done some stuff in the,
in Arizona,
Nevada,
you,
there's a lot of race.
So there are a few courses.
Are there courses or is
it just organizations?
We build courses.
They're all,
every off road race is unique.
Uh,
okay.
So now like what if saved,
someone's listening to
this and they're like,
you know what?
I need some goddamn adventure in my life.
Best thing.
Dues look up score,
score schedules,
score,
score on that tubs,
strip club in New York City in Atlanta.
No,
that's wherever it is.
I don't know anything about those places.
Scoring and national.
Yeah.
Score in national.
Looked up on the internet,
look at the schedule,
find out where the race is,
our go check one out.
There's a lot of other races and
organizations that race all over.
Um,
you know the western United States,
there's almost awkward race
just about every weekend,
somewhere,
somewhere in western us
you can,
and for some folks they just
go quote unquote off-roading.
So they just get a truck and find a
spot where they are allowed to drive and
just go nutty.
Yeah,
that's,
those are jeep adventure guys.
The guys go like Moab
and they go real slow.
And that's not what we do,
dad.
I don't get that crawling.
Look,
I made it up the rock dude.
I could walk quicker than that.
You stupid fuck that Rockwell in your
truck that you need to get up to the top
of the rock with it.
You know,
that doesn't make any sense to me.
No.
Yeah,
I don't get the rock crawling.
It's,
it's slow.
Speed is,
it's pretty incredible.
I did a rock crawling
is actually rock race.
So with the Rockies,
well there's different things.
Rock crawling is one thing,
racing slow and then racing slow,
but it's,
it's pretty wild that when they do the,
it's,
I think it's the event's called King of
the hammers and you climb up some rocks
that you can't even climb with your hands,
but you get in this modified unlimited
vehicle that very expensive on top of it.
Same with even bigger tires.
And we have,
and they just go right up at like,
you're like,
you're actually crawling a little,
you can't cry,
you can't climb it now.
You can't climb it with your,
your,
you can't,
it's very hard for you to
climb it as a human being.
But this car will pull up to it
or this truck kind of like a jeep,
but it's highly modified.
It's,
it's difference between like a stock
forward F-150 and a trophy truck.
It's like a stock jeep and an unlimited,
I think they call them
ultra force and they're,
they're incredible.
What they'll do,
they'll go up incredible
rock climbing events,
straight faces.
You'll see some of the
internet stuff is fascinating.
It's crazy.
But it is slow.
It's racing slow.
Well I guarantee you somebody who your
climate theology are those free climber
dude.
Like those Alex Arnold,
guys that go up the,
you know,
they,
they go up things that aren't even flat.
They're leaning towards you.
He said you couldn't climb it.
I could climb it.
Don't fucking test me bud.
I'll fucking climate right now bitch.
The um,
the,
the industry like,
must be like,
it must be a huge thing.
Like building all these
different things and be,
people must be getting involved in this
recreationally and building these like
trucks and taking the regular trucks
and adding all this stuff to it.
And it's just like hot rodding.
I mean you have,
you have a geyser,
right?
Yeah.
There's,
there's,
there's the guys who
brothers built trophy trucks.
Jim Koch builds trophy trucks.
There's probably,
there's probably five or six
builders that do trophy trucks.
And then you have all your,
your guys that work
out of their own shops,
smaller building their own stuff.
So that's,
you know,
but alluded earlier,
there's really no rules.
Trophy trucks.
The rules are it can't fly.
You could have unlimited suspension.
It has to have a body like a truck body,
which is fiberglass and it can't fly.
It has to stay on the ground.
So it's,
it's a unique thing.
You can pretty much brainstorm
with whatever you can to
try to go out there and
beat your competition.
Oh,
that's what's innovative
about the sport with you.
When you give guys a limited horsepower,
limited this,
do anything you want.
Actually,
there is one rule that I'll tell you
that I saw that and you'll remember this
story really well.
There's actually only one
rule that I know of actually.
Um,
but you,
you get to,
you get it.
Especially in competition.
You get to breed the best of the
human mind because he's
trying to beat this other guy.
I'm going to kick his ass.
So here's the one rule.
Oh eight oh seven I
think is oh seven right?
There's a guy named Brian Collins.
Swear to God.
This happened.
They took a fueling system
off an Apache helicopter,
right?
Stuck it off the back of their truck
and they had a fueling truck that would
walk up to it while they're moving and
jam it in the back of it and refuel it.
Why they're moving.
And finally a score.
It was that,
oh seven Oh eight when was that?
I think it was,
I think it was Mark Miller and Ryan,
our cro,
holy man,
they did it on the highway.
They,
they,
they developed a system on a,
on a regular chase truck
that was following the race
truck down the highway and
the fuel was in the bed of the chase
truck and they had a pressurized system.
If they pulled up why they're going
60 miles an hour down the highway.
They pulled up behind the
race truck and it had like a,
like a nozzle out the front of it and
they stabbed it into the nozzle that was
on the race truck and they filled it,
Jesus Christ.
So they could save four minutes.
They could save two or
three minutes in the pin,
not even supposed to smoke
when you were at a gas station.
I think that's a rule.
It's like no more,
no more fueling way.
Goal number highway.
Supposed to use your cell phone while
you're at a gas station because very
rarely a spark and electronic spark
can ignite fumes and you can burst into
flames.
Like that's happened before and
he's talking crazy assholes.
I go at 60 miles an hour filling
in their car up on the highway.
I remember once I was with
a herps team that year.
I forgot what it was and herps.
Yeah.
Herps like herpes.
Uh,
no.
Life's terrible.
Herb's like in Vegas,
the herps gas stations,
the herps hotel,
I don't know what that is.
They're pretty big.
They're,
they're there a day of the herps hotels,
right on paradise.
That's a terrible place to go and stay.
Get sorry for the people who own it,
but just the doping don't
be sorry for the name.
Yeah,
we're going to stay at the Herbst.
Good luck.
I got that.
Got The herps.
Yeah,
I got to the herps shit.
You're going to be okay.
Did you take your medication?
Use some antibacterial soap,
so I didn't know I was with them.
What else?
I won't say their name again.
I was with them and we
saw that and were like,
we're all kind of like,
ah,
that's pretty cool.
And did they win that year?
Yeah,
they did one that year because of that,
while saving time.
There's more to it than just that.
But it helps you think that saved
throughout the thousand mile race.
Probably 10 minutes,
10 minutes at a time instead
of stopping in the pit.
And that matters.
Absolutely.
Now no one's sleeping.
You guys are just driving
everybody in the race truck,
they're driving the whole way.
Some people solo.
They drive the whole thousand mile race
without getting out of the truck drive
the whole way.
I've done that in the past.
Do you have a diaper on cod?
They have these catheters.
Oh cause his kid is a tube in your Dick
and your hobby is way out of control
when you put that bad that's not a tube.
And your texting is a catheter.
Right.
My favorite things,
I like having it.
Like I read Kevin,
it's you live in Dick.
No,
cause it's not what it is,
but it's the best thing that's
ever happened for off road for me.
It is amazing.
It goes over the top like a,
like a,
Oh like a condom.
Right.
And then
a rubber hose connected
to the end of that.
That goes all the way down the inside
of your leg and you taped at the end of
the hose to the side of your shoe so
you can piss in your shoe next to you
shoots.
The best thing I know it's in the
truck and somebody just [inaudible].
Some people have done that though.
They don't get the tube out of their
shoe before they start racing and they're
actually finding out their p
and that's another great story.
Ivan Stewart,
who's a legend in your foot out the
window and then we don't have carpet.
It's all metal.
Aluminum down there as
a hole in the floor.
Yeah,
that there's leaks,
there's little panels and stuff and so
you just pee on the floor and just hope
it goes away somewhere.
Yeah,
it does.
It does.
Well,
the best thing is you pulled in the pits,
you start paying,
you tell your,
your,
your mechanic was like,
I think I've got a leak and
he's down there sniffing it.
That's a great,
that story,
right?
There's happened multiple times and the,
the one I was going to tell you about,
it's Ivan Stewart icon of the sport
was that the start line and warm in his
truck up.
He's just about ready to go off the
start line and all of a sudden underneath
his truck there's,
there's liquid in one of his
mechanics jumps underneath her like,
Holy Shit,
what does that goes?
Touches his finger in it,
comes up,
smells it,
and realizes what it is that
Ivan's actually taken a piss.
It didn't mean to ruin your story,
but for your listeners,
by the way,
get a Catherine,
go online,
get a race catheter.
The best things like,
um,
like in a bar.
I did the race or UFC fight or UFC fight.
I did,
I did this.
I have to miss anything.
Yeah,
but then you get a p on the ground.
Yeah.
You can compete in the bar near drain.
It's fine.
I was,
I would have this blue water.
I was at this blue water
race in Arizona one time.
Uh,
I think it was Greg Fouts
and we got our ass kicked.
We're just putting around.
We got stuck a couple of times.
I'll stock full.
So we actually got to the bar and we were,
it felt like a dick by the way.
And I had my race suit on
because we came in so late.
But the bar is gone and everybody's
there and they're having a celebration.
I just kept my catheter on instead of him.
So I'm just sitting at the bar.
I'm like,
I get next to somebody.
Just start peeing.
Ah,
okay.
Okay,
and you're done.
You don't have to come.
You just pee on the ground of the bar.
You son of a bitch.
I can't believe you think that's funny.
How dare you.
What about the person that owns that par?
You're just peeing in their establishment
right on the floor for a beer.
I don't give a fuck that guy.
Somebody has to buy the beer,
bring it there.
If somebody has to pay to be,
put the refrigerator in and turn it on.
Don't feel sorry.
Eight Bucks,
eight bucks.
Don't buy it.
That's what it looks like.
Black cat.
Yeah.
That's one of the brands right there.
Wow.
That.
That is ridiculous.
When you're in a sport,
when you have to have a
hose taped over your deck.
Maybe there's a problem with that.
Support babies.
You don't bribe.
You don't drink coffee.
No,
never.
Never.
When I was a kid,
my mom,
dad drink coffee.
I couldn't stand the smell.
Probably got to early twenties or so,
realized I'd never had it and said,
you know what I'm going to do without it.
For from my life.
So I'm a soda guy.
So you drink soda?
Yeah,
that's my fix in the morning.
So is that what you
get your caffeine from?
I mean like when you're
doing a 33 hour run,
like you must do some form
of stimulant to stay awake.
No.
Ah,
it,
the adrenaline that gets going in
you when you're winning the race,
you know,
you get,
you get into the night,
typically are bottling thousands starts
at o'clock and you'll finish at two,
three in the morning.
For me,
uh,
if we're doing well,
but about midnight when
you start to get tired,
usually realize you're in shit.
You got a chance to win this race and
the adrenaline kicks in and takes you
right to the finish.
It's when you're having a bad day,
lots of troubles,
and you're pulling a 36 hour event that
and you're not capable of winning the
race,
the adrenaline goes away and then need
to throw some sodas down to keep it going
or,
or some energy drinks.
Yeah,
I would think that that would get really
sketchy when you're dealing with like
these crazy terms where you really have
to be paying attention and you've been
up for 25 hours.
That must be where the real danger lies.
No,
absolutely.
And that's,
you know,
most likely Bud's earlier story
with the candy bars from and,
and Tracy Jordan,
when they went off the cliff,
I mean they just got in the car,
but I believe they were in
the car earlier that same day.
Right?
So they,
the Baja peninsula,
the race course,
a thousand miles,
the highways,
800 miles,
most likely they'd got up in the morning
and Ensonata did a couple stints in the
race car got out,
but they were traveling down the
race course down the highway.
And when they got back in and it
was early hours of the morning and,
and dusty,
maybe foggy.
And
Yeah,
you can remember that every
turn could end your race.
Maybe it may be in your life if you're,
if you're going too fast.
But every turn.
So for,
for me,
because obviously you can tell I
have an issue with paying attention,
I think.
I can't think of anything else.
And that's why I always ate
quite at the cage fighting.
If you get in the cage,
you start thinking about your
bills and your check and you know,
they've got this happen and all the
bullshit you're gonna get your ass kicked.
Same thing down here.
The only thing you have to really worry
about is you're looking at brush or
looking at dust.
You're looking at power lines,
looking at all that.
You're reading the terrain and that's
all the consumes your mind because if you
don't,
you're fuck
yeah.
That's a thing that people need,
right?
Like I find that I gravitate towards
things that require my full completed
tension in the moment,
whether it's,
uh,
going to the rifle range
and shooting a rifle.
You know,
like I,
I took,
um,
my friend Duncan and Chris yesterday,
we went to the rifle range and it's one
of the things that Duncan was saying,
like when you're shooting,
you don't think about anything else.
Like the moment you're
pulling that trigger,
your mind is free of all the other
nonsense you got going on in your life.
Your mind is just concentrating
on keeping the radical,
keeping that crosshair on that target,
calming your nerves and then squeezing
that trigger and not moving anything
else.
What is it about us that we need?
Things like that.
Is it the over complex
society that we live in?
I think so.
I think,
you know there's it with my business,
your business and all elevated.
We're doing,
there's text messages and there's fucking
Facebook and Twitter and you've got to
all this bullshit and there's
so much stuff in there.
And the thing that I think is different,
much different than rifles,
like there's consequences of
what we do because if we don't,
if you miss the shot,
oh Ho hum.
I missed the shot.
I'm not running down rifle.
You don't shoot me.
But yeah,
but in what we do,
if you,
and I've done it before,
I'm like,
I,
you kind of get into a law
like driving in a snowstorm.
You see the snow storm coming
out and you kind of get drive.
You kind of drive yourself,
do a little bit of sleep,
turn comes up,
you're going to go off a cliff,
you're going to wreck your,
someone's going to hit
you from behind you.
You know that the,
the worst it's death need the very easiest
as you broke your car and you gotta
get,
you gotta get out there and fix it
and you just let your team down.
There are teams,
he's got 60 70 people that are on his
team and then they all worked really hard
to get him down there and that
pressure's on him not to fuck up,
but is a weird that we as human beings
have this strange desire to chase danger
like that,
that like that,
that managing danger becomes
sort of like a drug fix.
We're getting,
well,
you're,
you're a lot deeper human being than I am,
but this is,
this goes back to the primal human.
We used to go on hunts,
right as,
as guys,
we used to go and hunt.
We used to like,
you stay here,
I'm going to go on a hunt and I'm going
to chase bear and going to kill the
buffalo.
I'm going to go on the,
I'm going to go to war,
I'm going to do these things and yeah,
I don't,
I don't know what it is.
You get to a certain part of your life
and you've got to start chasing that.
You have to have it.
Like I don't need to raise,
I'd have to race.
Well,
I think there's certain human reward
systems that are set up in our minds and
essentially in our DNA and that we don't
fulfill them at all with the average,
the average everyday cubicle life traffic,
cubicle come home television.
The news bombards you with fucking
nonsense from all around the world.
And then you go to sleep and start all
over again and you're missing a lot of
shit.
And then something comes along
like this race where like,
you know,
if are you fucking jumping
around this crazy fucking truck,
you're going 140 miles an
hour and your body's like,
yeah,
finally,
something's happening.
Yeah.
It's addiction for me.
Absolutely.
I mean,
when I'm not racing,
last year I reached 35 weekends.
I,
it took the green flag
fucking hat most of the year.
I think I took the green flag over 80
times and every time basically I started a
race.
I started race,
they threw a green flag.
So I raced over 80 times
last year in 35 weekends.
Some of these times I
take four green flags.
Actually one weekend last year I took
seven green flags over the weekend racing
in three different trucks.
Um,
discussed her,
there's multiple classes
and the short course races,
there's multiple classes.
So I'm addicted it so much.
I go get in any vehicle I can go race.
So I reached seven times.
But when there's,
when there's,
when I have a weekend off,
I don't know what to do with myself.
So I think I need that adrenaline rush.
I need to race,
I need to get a checkered flag,
I need to win.
That's really what my life is about.
Becoming a part of me.
Absolutely.
And Bud,
you've been,
she'd been chasing stuff like that
all as long as I've known you,
you're always like trying to do
some crazy like charged up thing.
It builds your character.
I think he's the guy you build to
helps you build your character.
And I'm,
I'm,
I'm addicted to drugs.
My drug is a Dorfman's and
adrenaline and I have to have that.
I think it was,
um,
I forgot who said it might've been
Rhys Millen or someone like that,
but they said in,
in,
in normal life you had the guy in
the cubicle sit in New York City,
he may have like one close call
on in his whole entire life
or maybe one a year down in Mexico
you have nine or 10 in a race.
You,
I mean,
you are close to death a few times.
Holy Shit.
Oh fuck.
I'm glad that didn't happen.
And you do that for
over and over and it's,
it's,
it's scary for,
you know.
Definitely.
I've,
you know,
I've tried,
I did a movie in the raptor,
I don't know if you saw it.
No,
I never saw that.
When you do,
you did that,
like you,
you produced a film about the Ford Raptor,
like right when it was coming out.
Is that what it was?
Was the launch,
the launch of that was a launching
oh eight.
And um,
I,
my wife,
there was two movies back to back.
I did.
And there was one time we got stuck
all the guests and I got stuck.
You remember the scene?
And I,
I took a tow a tow strap,
pulled it to the front of the thing,
walked across and hook it
to my friend's truck and uh,
some idiot and the trophy truck wasn't me.
Ran over my strap like right where I was.
Whoa.
I mean,
cause you know,
you're,
you're in this blinding silt bed.
I don't think.
He did not try to kill me.
He's blinding silt bed.
He knows if he slows down,
he just sees a whole,
there's a truck and there's a guy,
I'm going to go right between it.
And I'm like,
oh my God,
talk.
That was very close,
really close.
So I,
that was the scene in our
movie and my wife is like,
ah,
yeah,
you're not doing that anymore.
It's quite often she saw it.
Oh Wow.
My wife,
one last story.
He says,
my wife in 2012 when I won my race,
I called my wife.
I,
it's,
I'm excited.
I won one race.
Rob's run 220 races more
than anybody in the planet.
I won one race.
I called my wife at five o'clock.
I said,
honey,
we want,
I've been chased it for nine years.
She said,
good,
you can quit,
and she hung up on me.
I got no,
I got no play at all.
I'm like,
I'm so excited.
Like I can't,
I want to call my mom.
I went to call my wife.
I wanted to like,
Hey,
guess what?
I did this.
He's like,
yeah,
that's nice.
You can quit now.
Yeah.
It's hard for some people to relate to
that need to be charged up and do nutty
things like that,
right?
Yeah,
I think so.
I mean for me it's all
about winning championships,
winning races and uh,
can't get enough of it.
Well so many people trying to,
they've tried to live their life safe,
you know,
they tried to do just the opposite.
They're like looking for the softest
cushion to sit on there looking for the
easiest job.
They're looking for the longest
amount of time off to looking for the,
this to the cushiest existence.
No that's not living.
You got to get out there
and experience life.
You got to live it.
Yeah I agree.
But I mean there's that,
there's like these two schools of
thought when it comes to people.
There's people that try to seek out
adventure and thrills and have all these
wild experiences in their life and
there's people that have zero desire.
See Joe and I have it.
We have a disease.
We have like a dinner party
or disease or that we share.
Like I,
I can't talk to those people.
Right.
Cause I,
I seek out,
like I,
I do deep sea dives on shipwrecks
and I'll try to go to this.
Not because I think I'm a bad ass shit.
Cause I'm pushing myself,
I always want to push myself.
I have to do something to
train for it.
So when I go talk to people like regular
people or people that are boring as
shit,
I sound like an idiot and I had
nothing to say to them cause you,
you,
you try to do what we just did here
in Rob's got a million of them.
You try to tell them an
adventure story in Baja.
Like I hit a jump at 120 and I jumped
this or accidentally hit this guy on a
bike and the like,
they think you're crazy.
Yeah.
There's certain people that it's just,
it's too,
it's too time consuming trying to
explain your motivations behind certain
things.
Like I try to think of like,
what's the least thrilling thing that I
do that I could sort of tell people that
I do?
Like what do you,
what do you,
what do you do for a living?
Uh,
do a radio show on the Internet.
Like as I say that,
like a leave out the UFC,
I'll leave out standup comedy.
Like,
I don't want this,
just this ain't the,
the bridge between us.
It's too far.
There's no,
there's no room there.
Some folks just,
they don't want any thrills.
They want no thrills.
They want no,
nothing dangerous.
They want to see everything
to be spelled out for them.
They want,
you know,
two weeks paid vacation and they want
to make sure that they could retire when
they're 65 and they're
already ready to die.
Like they've got it all set up.
You betcha.
Yeah.
So,
well,
what's,
what's the best story for Baja?
Cause I told my crazy story,
but you have the,
you have better stories.
You've been well,
you know,
actually I think I'm,
I've been honestly fortunate enough
when I started going to Baja,
I went with Walker Evans and,
and people that have tons of experience
down there and they kind of help
minimize those stories for me.
Um,
you know,
one of the early days racing class,
one single buggy single seat or only
one person in there down there after San
Javier.
Well,
you're talking about earlier,
he had a flat tire and uh,
got out to change that tire and had a,
you know,
the motors running in the buggy and,
and you can't hear anybody around you.
There's typically,
there's no,
I thought it was in the middle of nowhere
and all of a sudden say somebody came
up,
tapped me on the back of the shoulders,
scare this crap out of me.
Um,
things like that.
I,
I don't,
you know,
crashing,
uh,
I've done multiple crashes
all over the place,
Wad and stuff up.
I'm breaking my collarbone.
Um,
the crazy stories I guess,
you know,
I,
I don't have the wild ones.
The reason why is I think that I,
you know,
I go down there prepared,
I'm there to win.
Um,
you know,
I try to really minimize all that stuff
and haven't had a hottest crazy stuff
happened.
Did you get involved in
other motor sports first?
Will you involve regular racing first?
Yeah,
I started racing motorcycles
when I was eight,
nine,
10 years old.
They got this Christ Yak racing
motorcycles is an eight year old.
Got Involved in doing that.
And you know,
my dad was involved in do an off road
racing and the early seventies when I was
on motorcycles.
And then when I got turned 16 years old,
we got an interracial and buggies
doing the mint 400 stuff like that.
And you know,
I quit my senior year of basketball
is the dumbest thing I ever did.
I should've played it through,
but I fell in love with
off road racing and then,
uh,
you know,
just made it,
made it my hobby there
for a few years and then,
and got lucky enough to get picked up by,
uh,
people like Ford Motor Company,
BF Goodrich tires.
And I ended up making a career out of it.
So,
um,
I've been doing,
uh,
doing this for a living
for over 20 years and,
and like Bud said,
we've won over 200 races
on BF Goodrich tires.
I'm actually about 280 total wins
and off road since 80 to over 20
championships.
And if you had to stop and you
had to go and live and office job,
like if someone came along
and BF Goodrich said,
look,
we're taking you out of the fucking heat.
It's just,
it's too crazy.
We're going to give you a nice cushy job.
Stop six figure salary.
Nice House.
Yeah.
At this point,
I can't even imagine that,
you know,
I think about that,
every once in a what a,
what am I going to do when
this is over and I don't know.
I don't even know what I'm going to do,
but,
you know,
hopefully go to work with
somebody like BF Goodrich or,
um,
you know,
my family owns a,
an offer buggy shop in
Vegas doing stuff like that.
But um,
you know,
I don't plan on quitting anytime soon.
It's what I know.
And you know,
it's,
it's almost all I know.
I mean,
I have,
it's my hobby.
It's my job.
It's my life.
Who's the oldest guy that can do it?
You were saying that that
Newman did it when he was 80.
He did.
He do.
He did a race when he was 80.
What a fucking animal he was
and I haven't met Stuart did it.
I mean he did it until in
his sixties Walker Evans,
Larry Ragland some of
the best of the sport,
you know,
had their most success in their,
their 50s which I haven't got there
yet so I'm hoping to calm down.
You calm down.
You did.
There's a thing in our race
racing called red mist.
Read Miss will get you hurt.
Like Jesse James goes down there all
the time and generally wads it up in the
first hundred miles compensated by
Jesse James because he just goes crazy.
No,
because people misunderstand the race.
I mean he knows more about the races.
I bet they misunderstand the race that
they think in the first hundred miles.
I got to beat everybody.
The analogy that I have is
when they put their helmet on,
they throw their brains
out the window and,
and I did that when I was young.
Crash.
A lot of stuff ruined,
ruined cars.
But over time you learn.
That's not how you win the race.
You basically go as slow
as you possibly can to win.
You have to keep an eye
on your competition.
You go through the pitch,
get split times,
find out how you're doing,
but as long as you're,
you know,
you're close to winning the race,
you're doing a good job.
When you get down to the end,
that's typical only you and a couple of
the guys that are racing for the win,
all those other 2030
guys in your class there,
they're broke or they're having problems.
How many people are racing like when,
when they say ready,
set,
go.
How many people fucking
hundred 50 and all the classes?
150 to 350 depends on which
way is like the thousands.
Like 300 to 350 people.
So there was vehicles.
Yeah.
So 350 vehicles all together.
Bob,
how does it,
how does it set,
I mean how many lanes are you're dealing
with here when they start the race,
when the,
when they start the race,
they send one one truck
or one buggy at a time,
usually every 30 seconds apart.
Racing the clock.
We're out racing on the
track at the same time.
You do have to come up
and bump those guys,
move out of your way if they're
slower than in front of you.
But,
um,
you know,
we're racing the clock and
as you get down the course,
the bike start,
usually the bikes,
the quads and Utvs they started
about three hours in front of the,
the first four wheel vehicle.
But we ended up catching those guys.
And that's where it
becomes really sketchy.
And sometimes were these,
you know,
bud story earlier when,
when,
when Josh and Josh at the bike guys,
because the bikes can't do certain things.
Well some of them can do.
Yeah,
some of them can.
Um,
but a lot of the,
especially in Mexico,
a lot of the bike guys are or sportsmen's.
Um,
and when you're doing a long race,
like the Baja 1000,
um,
it becomes more,
uh,
the bike guys.
You know they get used up
quicker and the trucks,
you're sitting in the seat,
you know you don't have air
conditioner but you've got,
you know you can have snacks,
you can have food,
you can have water as you're racing
down the course of the bike guy.
It's just him and a small light.
You know I talked earlier about how the
lights on our trucks are like a stadium.
They have one light,
we have 14 to 20 lights on our trucks.
It's a lot different and
fuck that must be scary.
Driving a motorcycle fast.
They think of baseball stadiums behind
them sometimes I hear at trophy truck
behind him.
Some of the guys,
the smart ones,
oh they freak out.
They look behind them like Ooh Shit.
And they'd get off the road and the
trophic go to blowing by him cause they
don't want to get run over.
I mean there's a lot there.
A lot of accidents with the
bike guys and they're there.
I score is doing a lot of things to
to mitigate that at this point they're
starting them later.
We're going to start it the
night before and stuff like that.
For me,
there's an interesting thing for me.
I was going to tell you,
like I'm known,
you know me for a long,
long time,
I've known kindly like
kind of a crazy jackass.
It doesn't do this when
I'm going down the races.
You,
you talked about the catheters.
There's an interesting to
happens to me and my psyche.
I'm wearing a fire suit.
I have my catheters on,
I have a fireproof underwear.
I put my helmet on,
I got my knife in my pocket so
I can cut my seat belts off.
Anything else happens.
I started doing all this stuff.
I'm like,
Holy Shit,
I'm doing something pretty serious.
And I calmed down.
I have problems with my sponsors who
hang out with me and they're like,
you're,
you're going to fucking wreck.
You're a crazy wacky idiot
who's gonna wreck the car.
So they don't,
they,
they're not managing this craziness.
Well,
what do you mean?
It is?
Like some people just don't,
some people just can't like look
at all the different variables.
Look with all the craziness
and just settle in.
Okay,
this is what we're doing now.
Yeah.
Some people,
and it's hard to read.
Miss comes in like you your son.
And I've get,
I get caught up sometimes too,
cause I had a guy pull behind me one time,
a French guy until he's gonna
kick my ass if I don't move.
I said we'll stop the car.
I'll stop the car,
get out and I don't care.
We'll stop right in the middle of quarter.
You're going to kick my ass.
Fucking French.
French.
They gave us these fries and
now they got at Delta my way.
I'll kick your ass.
That's what he's saying on the radio.
I'm like,
fuck you out of the way.
I'll kick your ass and
I know what he's doing.
He's freaking how out and he's in this
race and you just got to pace yourself.
You get to be calm.
It's hard not to get caught up in the
beginning when guys are banging on you
like they're hitting you.
I don't understand.
You don't,
some people hit hard.
They need Roman to,
you could try to get you out of the way.
Yeah,
it just,
they don't even care.
Then it'll honk.
You just drive also,
boom.
Being rear ended the four
or five at 60 miles an hour.
You're like,
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
The off road trucks or one lane,
it's not like five lanes
on the four oh five
it's one lane.
So to past that guy,
you come up there,
you hope he moves out of the way
typically doesn't really want to.
So you got to come up there and bump
them and sometimes people get out of
control and they hit you really hard.
They try to move you off the track.
Especially if it's a jackass like these
guys who've actually had a bad day.
So this is what I,
the problem I have.
Right?
So they've had a bit,
I'm having a good day.
Right?
So I'm in front of my class.
He's had a bad day and a trophy truck.
He's got 900 horsepower,
105 gallons of fuel.
He's fucking pissed off.
He's tired,
he's not happy anymore.
And he's trying to make up time.
And then there's,
me and my buggy are going to want
to deal with these slow guys.
We want to get to the,
we want to get done,
we want to get to the finish line.
And the dust that he's kicking up makes
the trophy truck guy pissed off and it's
like you don't deserve to be here.
Get Out of my way.
And by the time you get to them,
you give them a little low.
A little low.
That's the bump.
Oh yeah.
And how many guys get
fucked up because of that?
I mean it seems like that would be one
of the reasons why a lot of guys wreck,
well,
a lot of the cars there,
they're built to take that.
It's,
it's in the DNA of off road.
That's,
that's Kinda how we pass.
You come up there,
you bump into each other tagging.
That's your,
you know,
your,
I caught you.
Now you move out of the way.
Let me go buy it.
That's what we do.
So you guys use,
there were chromoly tubing into chromoly
tubing designed to take a good impact,
but you,
you would pull over the side.
Yeah,
exactly.
Like a 1950s dad,
get rid of
you.
If you were in the accident,
if you were on the forum,
if someone hit you that hard,
you pull over and call the cops
and grabbed your neck and go,
whoa.
That was an impact.
Oh yeah.
Part of the game as part of the game.
Wow.
That's crazy.
That's,
it seems so bizarre.
he just seems so crazy that part of it
is just ramming into you while you're
going,
you know,
x amount of miles an hour.
Right?
It's normal.
It's not normal.
It's normal in that world,
in that world,
it's normal.
We were fucking human beings
are so crazy in that way.
We just find normalcy in the fact that,
well,
this is what happens when you do this.
And then all rules,
all decor,
all normal rules of behavior go out the
window when you're racing in a Baja and
you're pissing through your fucking can
shoe.
And well,
I think there's,
there's,
if there's a very weird,
I get some something in the psych.
I can tell you from me once,
once you figured this out and you've
done the organization and you've gone to
your catheter,
to your knife,
you got your chase team,
you've got your feel.
Once you've organized successful
race campaign like he has,
then wreck regular life and business.
It's not that hard,
right?
You actually,
you get out of a race and he's like,
then then actually you sometimes get
a little short with stupid people and
you're like,
really?
You just had to go to the store and pick
up a six pack and come back was that,
that's fucking hard and cause what we do,
there's so many consequences.
He can tell a guy and this
is actually how it goes to.
It's like I need you to go
to the [inaudible] station,
which is the gas station in Mexico.
Be there at one o'clock
with some extra tires.
Got May need when I get out and that's
what you tell the guy and it's 800 miles
away and you don't see
that guy until 800 motel,
you know for 12 hours from there
and that guy is sitting there.
It is logistics crazy and you surround
yourself with the people who know have a
common goal.
Your logistics are all point out.
I mean if you need anything down there,
you know where it's at and you come
back to the states and you can't you and
like you know some of your employees or
someone like that can handle like two
simple instructions or like that
guy would die down in Mexico.
Well it's just the
stakes are higher,
the pressure's higher
and everyone's tuned in.
Everyone's tuned in.
Everyone has a goal.
Yeah.
You want to surround yourself with the
people who've been down there to Mexico.
It's two lane highways.
Very dangerous.
There's not streetlights very rarely.
There's yellow line dividing
the center lane and you got,
you got to have the right people.
It's,
it's a very dangerous things to legit.
It is.
It's a logistics nightmare
to to plan out a race.
I always say to people,
if I,
if I would spend as much effort that I
do off road racing and putting the team
together and the logistics
in a regular business,
I'd have a lot of money.
Instead I race the trophy truck
and I don't have much money.
Oh yeah,
no,
this makes ups look like,
I dunno,
this is look real logistics.
Yeah,
but would it be any more exciting?
I mean,
a lot of money would,
wouldn't be worth it.
And I like this is a lot of people that
have a lot of money that we know they're
just miserable as fuck.
They're all on
antidepressants and they're,
they're always constantly in and out of
relationships in their life is a fucking
holy rack of failure and catastrophe.
But they're financially successful
because they're not challenging
themselves and they're getting,
it has to do with challenging yourself.
Yeah,
I think you're right.
I think there's something about being
uncomfortable that provides you with a
certain sense of wellbeing.
I don't,
I don't know what it is,
but yeah,
I was hunting in Montana last year and,
uh,
we were talking about employees
doing things and this,
uh,
the show mediator has
these guys at work for it.
I mean,
I don't know what they get paid,
but I'm sure they don't get paid much.
And these guys are working
24 hours a day for the six,
seven days that we're there.
They're sleeping on the ground.
It's fucking zero degrees outside
there huddled up and sleeping bag.
They get up before everybody else
because they have to start the coffee,
they have to fire up the,
uh,
the campfire and,
and you know,
have a job where someone doesn't
want to fucking clean the restroom.
Someone does want to take out the
garbage and normal job where you,
you show up at nine and you leave at
five and try getting people to work
throughout the day for what this guy gets
paid to be 24 hours a day in Montana,
sleeping on the ground,
freezing their dick.
But that's what he's doing.
Like that's what he's doing.
And in that world in,
you know,
he becomes a part of that production.
Like this is what I'm doing now and
this guy that you're calling and saying,
hey,
you know,
go 800 miles,
get some fucking tires,
meet us there.
Like that's what that guy's doing.
And he's there and he's there.
Yeah,
and you sit,
I mean production like year,
I have a group and we did the F-150 thing,
they called it my production guys.
Like you've been around
production for awhile.
My guys were up for 54 hours straight
and they call themselves to 54 our crew.
Right.
Because they had the,
we filmed this whole special for ESPN
and then they were filling my whole
special for Ford and they
were up for 54 hours,
not a complaint.
They didn't like hit me for overtime.
They're like,
that was amazing and you've just got to
surround you and I don't care about the
overtime.
You've got to surround
yourself with people.
Like I didn't know my race is
going to be that effing long.
I mean,
we just happened to be,
you know,
we took 42 hours to do it.
These guys do it and 19
or something like that.
But you,
you surround yourself with those people.
And I was going to say something
about our support staff is,
you know,
our chase crews are amazing because we
have volunteers like my brother comes out
every year.
It's something my
brother and I can do now.
They're chase crews are amazing
cause most of them are volunteers.
They're going to come down there.
They'll drive and dangerous roads.
They'll,
they won't sleep at night.
They'll be up for 36 hours and they eat
beef jerky and it's cold as shit and
they are always there.
It's miserable.
They hate it while it's happening.
But in the end you're,
you get home,
you get rested up and you,
all the great stories
come out and you love it.
You want to go back and do it again.
Yup.
It's that,
just that different level of life.
It's like when you're
out there doing the race,
you're out there doing some wild,
crazy shit like that.
It's like everything's elevated.
You're more tuned in,
you're,
you're more aware of your surroundings.
You're not inundated by cell phones
and text messages and emails.
They don't even work.
Actually we,
I have one phone and maybe a sat phone.
I don't even return it.
I'm like,
I'm gone.
Yeah.
Once you go to Mexico,
you call going to Mexico.
Yup.
He down there,
see when I get home.
And that's part of it too,
right?
Part of it too is like the disconnect,
unplug,
unplugging and then,
you know,
recharging your brain and being out
there and the desolate surroundings go on
140 miles an hour over bumps.
Well,
it gives you,
there's another side of it too
that gives you appreciation.
Not,
you know,
I have,
I have a kid now,
but I know my,
my brother sends it to you.
See,
you don't know.
You also see the people,
how they live there.
Our kids,
amazing kids and they live in,
um,
chicken coops,
right?
The blue chicken coop down by a,
um,
a hose.
They live in chicken coops.
And I'm not kidding,
I'm saying it's a blue chicken coop.
That's what it is.
And there's kids and I actually called,
this is my,
my own little story,
but I,
there's,
there's um,
the kids that never grew
up always come out of Ohio.
So there's this little road after
you turned down to blue date,
the Blue Gate on the right hand side,
there's a blue chicken coop and it looks
like every year for 10 years the same
kids come out.
They never get older,
they don't have shoes.
They're smiling.
We hand up stickers.
I stopped him,
give him,
I give him candy,
I talked to him,
he signs autographs,
you take pictures,
you go back the next year they
look the same age and they,
and they live.
Joe,
I'm telling you chicken coop,
I can draw it for you,
right?
It's,
it's a fucking chicken coop
and it looks like it's,
it's a chicken coop,
but it's not funny.
But you appreciate,
you come back and sometimes you
look at your kids and other people,
kids make,
you have no idea how he's your habit.
Yeah.
And then sometimes the kid,
the chicken people go to the dump and
that's where they find metal and they find
scrap and they take the aluminum cans and
they get their money and they're happy
to,
they're happy.
They don't,
they're not negative,
they're not pissed off there.
They have no shoes and,
and you know the Baja racers do a
lot for the community down there.
I mean sometimes they'll,
they'll,
they'll build orphanages.
I mean a lot of the Baja guys get touched
by what happens down there and the
people down there and they go give back
cause it you can't help but you know,
you can't help but go to these.
It's a third world country a lot,
a lot of ways,
not cabo and stuff like that.
But the places where we go and you,
you get affected by it.
You get to see the other world and
you do appreciate what we have.
Our kids will never
appreciate it cause you know,
the 500 shoes,
these kids have no shoes.
Seriously.
No shoes in the live in
chicken coops with a,
a sheet on the front
door.
Yeah.
I've been,
I've driven in New Mexico,
a POW pass Tiawana.
I'm into some really sketchy areas.
And you get to see these people that
are living in these houses that are
essentially like cardboard
boxes with no windows.
And you know,
you see these small villages of places
like that and it really puts it into
perspective.
And even more weird that that's
connected to the United States.
It's just one of the
richest countries on earth.
It's just you just drive.
It's like same landmass.
Yep.
Just keep going.
And he'd go from southern California
with the fucking Kardashians live and you
see a Rolls Royce in your neighborhood
and then a couple hours drive,
and then all of a sudden you're in a
third world country where no one has shoes
and was an advantage.
You'd go through,
you'd go through the gate of Teal on,
you take a right and you go up
this hill and it is a marsh.
So you're in Tijuana and you're right,
you have the cardboard boxes and you
look off to your right and there's a $20
million beach house sitting
there and you can see it.
Imagine waking up every day.
You're up on this hill and
Tiawana no running water.
Everything's happened.
You look up,
there's a $20 million beach house.
Dang boy.
He puts his,
a Mexican,
no states.
Yeah.
So you can see San Diego.
You call up on this hill,
you can see,
say,
look off to the right there.
San Diego in 20 there.
It's right there.
Yeah.
That is fucking bananas.
La Jolla.
Like those houses in La Jolla.
We should do the comedy store.
And we,
you know,
look at La Jolla.
I mean,
they have palaces.
These palaces overlooking the ocean and
the most incredible affluent community.
Everyone's driving around
these expensive European cars.
And you're 20 minutes away from Tijuana.
Yup.
20 minutes.
That's fucking crazy.
That's like from here driving a van eyes,
you know,
and,
but except you're driving
to one of the worst spots,
one of the worst border towns.
Yup.
On Earth.
But the people are amazing.
The people help us.
They do so much for,
so it's pretty fucking bad ass
to Mexican fucking throw down.
Tacos,
shrimp,
everything.
Lobster,
lobster,
tacos.
Where's the lofts?
Tacos at a lots of Tacos.
I forgot what it was at
Mama's Mama's Tom Espinosas.
Mama Espinosa had lofts.
Your tacos are amazing now.
You never get to stop that music a car.
Now do any,
um,
Mexicans race.
Absolutely.
There's a lot of people
that live in Mexico.
The join in on this.
Yup.
Have you ever want it?
Oh yeah,
no,
it actually did a very,
a Taco villa dosa one.
He's a part of the Red Bull
Team on the 50th anniversary.
I'm sorry,
it wasn't,
it was the Mexican independence.
Yep.
That was him and his father.
Um,
Gus wanted,
and they're,
they're,
they,
they're from,
they're from Tijuana.
They're from that area.
Um,
and there's also one,
Carlos Lopez is a lot of Mexican teams.
I mean Lexican teams
get a little resources.
They go race.
And by the way,
they are definitely race trophy trucks,
which they do.
There's a couple of trophy truck teams,
but they'll race Volkswagen's,
they'll race everything
you could possibly get.
So you were talking about the French guy,
they wanted to kick your ass.
Is that a guy from France that
came over just to race in this?
Yeah,
there's about,
there's usually guys from 150 countries.
People from all over the world come.
Japanese guys come down there.
All that means is everybody all
over the world come to Baja.
1000.
It's that much of a spectacle.
You,
you have to be,
I don't live in a cave for 800 years,
not to hear the ball went thousand.
Wow.
And then people from
all over the world come.
Yeah.
Because I've seen like in Europe,
I know they do a lot of rally car races
and they use Porsha's like Porsche has a
lot of rally cars.
They drive on dirt roads.
Yeah.
But did they have this
kind of thing as well?
And other countries?
Yeah.
No rallies pig everywhere.
Like this kind of rally like this
kinda like crazy modified truck.
A Dad Day to dat car,
which is a little,
a little bit different
races as a stage race.
That car used to was um,
really from Paris did a car,
it was Perry to car was the name of it.
And now that's in South America
through Brazil and Argentina and Chile.
Have you raced that car yet?
No.
Yeah,
there's no cars.
Famous race.
I mean it's a very famous race and we
score Raj and I've been talking to Saudis
to try to bring your race over there.
We've met with China.
Roger met with China to try
to bring in race over there.
Um,
we were going to try to expand what score
is going to do and try to bring it to
other countries.
I would think it would be a no brainer
for like Saudi Arabia or any of those
places where I was rich oil people
love to do crazy shit like drift cars.
Yup.
Like you've seen those videos.
So it's drifting videos.
Oh yeah.
From Arab countries.
Dubai's real big right
now on the sand buggies.
You need to get them into off road at
will Rogers talking to me and we can get,
we can get him over there.
They have an f one race,
you know the,
yeah.
Obviously idea is getting all,
you know,
get all the trophy truck
teams come over there.
But I'm on a ship getting
everybody there and go race.
Yeah.
What's the sand buggies like?
Uh,
it's a lot lighter buggy than what we
raced in off road and they basically just
go to the sand dunes there.
Specific built for sand dunes and
they have thousand horsepower.
They do wheelies up the hill,
down the hill and over in Dubai.
I guess that's a big
thing going on right now.
A lot of the recreational,
not racist,
just recreation.
Just having fun.
What is it about people that,
you know,
like the moment someone invented cars,
look at it.
These guys are drifting.
Why is that exciting to go sideways,
by the way?
I have no idea.
The feeling of being out of control
because guiding the most people.
I haven't had a control.
That's an open freeway almost.
Yeah know it looks like it is it
that doesn't seem like a smart move.
Well,
I've seen some fucking
horrific crashes to oh yeah.
I've seen some of those uh,
Arab drifting crashes or cars or
flipping and bodies are flying out.
But the moment like people invented cars,
like how long before the moment of car
was invented before people decided to
fucking race him when
the second car was built,
probably right.
I'll promise you.
When the second car was built,
Henry Ford based the whole
industry that our whole industry,
the first auto race was in in Chicago,
but our whole industry
is based on auto racing.
It's,
it's theirs.
It's even goes past the 60s it's back
when Henry Ford that he raced Henry Ford
raised Duesenberg raced all these guys,
raced it,
prove out Edelbrock
who's a aftermarket guy,
but he raised,
they all,
the thing in our industry is,
you know,
race on Sunday,
sell on Monday,
so I'm going to go out.
Ford built his cars like I'm
going to go out and win this race.
Indianapolis 500 was based
on manufacturers racing.
Who's got the fastest car?
I had a conversation with
someone about that once,
whether we're talking
about planned obsolescence,
like planned like that.
There's certain technology
that's available today that
you're not going to see
in cell phones or televisions because
they want it to be obsolete a year from
now.
And he was trying to make the argument
about automobiles that they do that,
that they can make the best car.
Right?
And I'm like,
you're,
you don't even know what the
fuck you're talking about.
Because what they're doing right now
is they're racing cars and then they
developed that technology
based on those race cars.
And that trickles down into the consumer
aftermarket cars or consumer cars.
The corvette program is
the number one to look at,
right?
So corvette is the longest,
longest running sports car in America,
long as bill isn't everyone out of
production and their race program that the
transfer of technology,
I did a whole documentary series on
corvette launching the c six and the whole
thing was transfer technology.
If they develop a,
you know,
you do the R and d,
which is the hard part,
right?
Which is what rob does for his trucks
and they start looking and poking around.
You do in the Rd and your race and
you make that c six corvette are,
which is called [inaudible] that are
now [inaudible] sweet corvette or they
raced those teens.
Pratt and Miller builds
them and then there is it.
There is a Chevrolet engineer and I know
them on the race team looking at stuff.
Do you know checking Cambra,
checking brakes,
checking aerodynamics,
checking everything and that
technology transfers to your car,
which is why corvette is still one of
the most dominant cars out there for 70
grand.
You can get it just because they,
they invest in that technology and the
new one is incredible and stingers pretty
bad is an incredible car.
It's beautiful looking.
I saw one the other day,
I thought it was a Ferrari.
Same here.
I told my son,
I go,
she got that Ferrari
because that's a corvette.
You're right.
Sorry.
It looks like,
yeah,
it looks like like a European like high
end top end car and the Interior's nice
now to finally they figured out a way
to make a car that doesn't look like a
piece of shit with a fucking
impala steering wheel.
I mean they used to have
these dog shit interiors.
Same thing.
The Viper did we,
I did document and reasonably
I'm rebuilding the Viper
Ralph Shields from uh,
from SRT motors.
He did the same thing.
They race,
they learned stuff from racing.
They put it in there.
But the new new viper is amazing looking.
What's,
what's a better car?
The New Viper or the new corvette?
Depends.
The price points are much
different for the money.
The core of that has to be at the
price point on the viper is 110,000,
115,000 to the core of it.
You could take the roof off too.
That's pretty dope.
The core of that's pretty cool.
Yeah.
Look at that thing.
I mean they fucking nailed it man.
Yeah.
But see all the,
all the hood vents,
all the,
all the break ducks,
all that stuff is all
developed from racing.
It's all functional.
Yeah.
It's not nonsense.
It's not just something to look at,
which,
uh,
you know,
cars have had in the past.
We were at a weird time right now in
automobiles because there's so much power.
Great time.
Great time,
but so much power in the cars you
could buy on the showroom floor,
like when they have a,
the the Shelby gt 500 660 plus horsepower.
Yep.
Right at the walk from the showroom,
pay the guy your money getting a car and
you have a 660 plus horsepower car with
a live rear axle and you're stomping
on the high of Bois and it goes,
it's the same zero to 60 in three seconds
in a fucking car that you could just
drive off the showroom floor.
And in the 60s he used to be,
you know,
280 horsepower,
332 the boss came out as like go,
it's got 320 horsepower.
And I've,
I've actually driven an old 302 and I
actually test drove the new three Oh two
and a test track at Ford.
It's unbelievable.
Parnelli Jones said the same thing.
It's like if we are racing at Laguna
Saker Parnelli and I was like,
if I had that car it'd be easy.
Well,
the new m three Oh two are you talking
about the Laguna Saker one or the one
that hasn't come out yet?
Yeah,
we are.
We are [inaudible] and I were
test driving the Laguna Seca.
That's an incredible car.
If the car got overlooked a lot by people,
it did cause first of all,
the stripes and everything.
We're a little whack like the
way they were painting it,
but everybody wants the bigger engine.
Everybody wants the,
you know,
the 550 horsepower shell,
but now the 668 horsepower Shelby,
but that 440 horsepower,
Laguna Seca was the perfect
balance front end to rear end.
There it is right there.
Yeah,
it was suspension.
That's the boss three o two right?
Yeah.
That's the boss to go to.
Yup.
That's the boss or at two.
And then you're talking about the goodness
sake of with the red and he had the
red lips,
red rims,
the front error.
I'm the front spoiler.
The race spoiler with the
pipes coming off of it,
they just figured out a way to
make cars that have horsepower.
That would be a fucking super exotic car.
Just 20 years ago,
just 20 years ago,
if you wanted to buy a car
that had 400 horsepower,
I mean you're spending a hundred grand,
you're spending 150 grand,
you know,
you're buying,
the top of the line Porsche nine 11
turbo or something like that or crazy
Lamborghini.
Yeah,
that's 300 grand.
Now you're buying a fucking Mustang gt.
Yep.
I mean it's bizarre with bizarre time.
It's
good,
it's very good.
But the amount of power and responsibility
that comes with having one of these,
he just handed off to some
fucking 17 year old kid.
Merry,
merry Christmas.
You little fuck.
Here's your key.
Well they've also improved.
They've also improved.
Um,
breaks,
trash control.
Actually I,
I have also,
I have big issues with tracks,
controls,
stuff like that.
Cause you do hand that guy 700
horsepower car and then he really,
then you just,
you really unfuck everything for him.
Right.
If he gets a little squirrely,
the car fixes it for the car facility
management and just actually breaking for
you.
You don't,
you don't have throttle cables anymore.
He got drive by wire and you
can hit wide open throttle,
but the drive by wire,
the brain tells you no,
no,
no.
You don't want full throttle cause
you're just going to spin the tires.
I was racing at road
Atlanta in a corvette,
c six corvette and they have this
turn 11 that comes off in your car,
gets airborne,
and every time I get airborne
I had to land the card,
shut off like,
okay idiot,
whatever you're doing,
you've got to stop
because that's not good.
We're not supposed to have four.
It would shut off.
It would go into limp mode.
Shut off I go,
bird,
go around the what if you had to
fucking maneuver away from something?
Well,
the Angie would go into limp mode.
It wouldn't.
It would.
It would go.
It would shut down.
I'd nailed the throttle.
There's no throttle.
It would go,
it would go into four cylinder mode,
limp mode,
until I got halfway through the strait
and we're going to go and I couldn't shut
the damn thing off.
That's retarded.
Yeah,
that's terrible.
But now they're,
they're developing them with sport mode
and other modes where you can do it.
You can flip a switch to you
on a lot of these so you can,
well the other problem is,
I don't know if this is true,
but what people are really worried about
is that someone is going to be able to
have kill switches when
they get shut your car off.
Like remotely.
Like say if you're running from
the cops or something like that.
They're doing already.
They have Onstar,
Onstar does that,
you know,
Onstar,
you can shut your car off like that.
Like Joe Rogan just told my Cadillac
and even driving down the road,
can you please shut it off being really?
Yup.
Can you pull that shit out?
It can you unplug all that stuff?
Probably.
That's probably wired in.
It's definitely wired in,
but that's something
you can't retroactively,
you can't take like an old corvette
sting ray like a 1970 sting ray and just
take all those modern components and
have the same sort of experience that you
would have drive and a c seven corvette,
but no Onstar,
no nonsense.
I'm sure you could,
can you,
but you couldn't have
the traction control,
right?
You couldn't,
could you figure that out?
A way to put a computer and have all that,
there's enough,
you know,
tuners are tutored and
builders are amazing.
They can have the traction control on it.
Sure.
Cause that's what a lot
of people want to do now.
Right?
I mean that's another
show that you're doing,
right?
The restaurant mods,
rest of Mod,
rest of mods or the thing where you
take an old car and you put all new
suspension,
new components,
that's very attractive to people.
Tim Allen's going to,
he's got a [inaudible] 69 Camaro and
it's got all new c seven corvette,
um,
suspension wheels,
everything in it,
assemble it.
You can look it up.
It's his new,
it's green.
It's beautiful.
You pop the hood,
you know,
like some stuff are you into cars.
You and I were looking at it.
It's unbelievable.
And he drives it around.
Yeah.
If you could drive it everywhere.
Drive it away.
It starts like a corvette.
You can start it from the [inaudible] six,
nine.
Camille just start it up.
It's a cool car.
What about the interior?
Does it look like a new corvette or is
it like an old school interior as well?
Old School Interior.
Wow.
Pull that up,
man.
Lemme see this?
Yeah.
It's built by Bodie Straub built it.
Okay.
I've heard that name before,
right?
Yes.
Yep.
I've told you about it.
Yeah.
This is a video of it.
Here is,
that's it?
Yup.
Tim Allen and Jay Leno.
Hey.
Wow.
Jay Leno's garage.
Oh Wow.
I mean,
it really is a sleeper.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
That's a corvette.
Turn the volume of,
let me hear what he
says to say about this.
This one here belongs to a real car guy.
Tim Allen.
Tim,
come on in,
buddy.
Shitty wheels,
but introduction,
I stock sucks.
Comedian,
actor,
a bestselling author and cargo car guy.
Yeah,
movie star,
but most of all cargo.
This is a beautiful Camaro.
You know,
I'd been looking at it when
it first pulled anyone,
oh,
it's 68 Camaro,
but then I look and there's all
these subtle little changes.
Just the kinds of things that I like.
The stock wheels are way wider rims.
Tom?
Sure.
We'd used to race one of these
on Woodward when I was a kid.
Green.
This car stock three 27th it's one of
those things that was just a great bullet.
It ran.
It ran circles around any other car.
I loved that car.
Loved race with them.
No console.
It was the low end one,
wasn't the SS,
so I redid that and always like smokey
Yunick the Trans am car that he made and
every time I saw one,
I think one of the elder Brock family
has it now and I'd see it race in these
classic car racing.
Wait,
there's something about that car.
Not the fact that he's trans and lower.
He showed two inches off
the rake up the hood,
took off the drip rails,
which I don't have on
their natural flares,
which they don't have.
They're not all buttoned up.
A lot of my time with the ball pin
hammer j you know what I may think,
think,
think and then I decided in those days
and Woodward days they had Coppos,
which is what is your central
office production order?
You could put it on your order
and if you did the right sequence,
GM would put a truck motor into cars.
We did that time was a four 27 and they
put four 2017 and very few Camaro's and
other wood,
you know,
800 grand or something.
But what that means is that GM did not
want their big engine from the corvette
and the Camaro to fall
from the cell production.
You could,
you could special order a car with
the big engine and that's what these,
and so I changed the name to that.
That's the name of to four 27 Coppo
that shows what we called it didn't,
we did some great little name tags.
All this kind of stuff
is details that I like.
Rally wheels that aren't
wheels at all there.
I mean it's not a wheel like the old days,
he's disc brakes have to fit underneath.
You've got to make them bigger.
And I mean that's what I like.
You know,
I like it when someone does a period car.
I hate it when they,
all of a sudden they
have 22 inch dubs on it.
And it's right.
It just doesn't look right.
You know this town,
you hit a pothole and I'm
standing at the side of the road.
I got to have a cause.
I drive these things right and well,
that's a beautiful looking.
We all,
I mean that's a custom
wheel you cannot buy.
That was made specifically
for this vehicle.
Number one,
I really wanted black wheels with hubcaps.
That's how coppos came.
They didn't come with rally wheels.
So I have a set of black wheels.
I want bumpers.
I put back on it all the trim went back
and I stock mirrors right back on it.
No console,
none of that stuff.
Well,
that's what I love.
It's really a beautiful,
beautiful.
All right.
See if you can get a
video of the inside of it.
I want to see what they did to the
inside of it and she get images,
but that's a,
that's a trend that a lot of people are
doing now because they want to have that
beautiful old school muscle car and look,
but they also want to have a
car that that's the interior.
No Way.
That's a real interior.
That's it.
Recaro seats is the only thing
is to be the interior of the car
play.
Press play.
Let me hear what he has to say.
Low back.
That can be the actual interior,
like a stunt interior
air freshener today.
I was like the brake pedal citizens.
Yes,
cause that's an image
instead of the video.
Why isn't why they did it,
but that does interior.
I've sat in their car.
That's what it looks like he had.
He put like an old stupid looking
steering wheel and everything.
It's a stock steering wheel.
Everything stock interior,
but it's not stock handling like
the pinion and all that shit.
Yeah,
it's all,
it's all c c seven corvette.
Wow.
That's the trend,
right?
That's what everybody wants.
And your new show.
When is that?
Is that an airing already?
Pilot on history channel hasn't aired yet.
There'll be a pilot.
We were shooting the pilot right now.
We'll start doing a bunch of
different cars like that dude,
four of them.
Yeah.
Now how much would Tim Allen have to
spend to make something like that?
Three,
400,000 days.
It's fucking Christ.
You get it.
God Damn brand new corvette for 60 grand.
Talk about defeating the purpose.
You can get a trophy truck.
Why?
Why spend money on that when
you could buy a trophy truck?
Well that's what you're into now.
You'd just,
regular cars on flat ground
is boring as shit to you.
They are boring as shit.
You have wait way to go
wait to go for a ride.
Come bring us back.
When you come back.
I'll bring you back when I
come back and we do Vegas.
Um,
when can people see your show?
Because I know you,
uh,
April 20th on CBS sports.
April 20th.
CBS sports on Sunday.
Yeah.
It's an hour long.
We're doing,
we're doing six one hours this year,
including the Baja 1000.
So all the races that Rob's racing in,
including the San Philippe to 50 fifties,
our first race that he raced in,
we'll tell you what happened,
but he raced in and it's on April
20th and Chris from overhauling,
he is a,
is he one of the hosts?
Chris Jacobs from overhauling
though one of our cameras.
Steele's.
What is another a compadre of his,
that he's one of our hosts and
he's a trophy truck racer also.
Awesome.
Chris Jacobs.
Chris is a cool guy.
Very good dude.
And a crazy car,
not himself.
There you go.
There's Chris.
Yup.
Wow.
Awesome stuff,
man.
Awesome stuff.
So,
um,
uh,
do you have a Twitter account
or anything like that?
Yeah,
Ra at Rob Mac 21.
Rob Back 21?
Yeah.
Okay.
And Bud,
do you have a Twitter account?
No.
No,
no,
no.
He Says No.
I wear all black.
There'll be no Twitter.
No.
Right.
What's a contact?
Me and I have Twitter and Facebook,
but they will now the French
are fucking mad at you.
Yeah.
I've should have kicked her ass.
She didn't that pull over and
now you talk shit about me.
All right.
April 20th,
CBS.
Thank you guys.
This is a lot of fun.
Yeah,
great conversation.
And Rob,
thank you very much for,
uh,
explaining us.
Uh,
you're,
you're insane world.
Oh yeah.
We have one more thing for you right now.
When we raised,
especially when I started racing every,
if you don't win the race,
sometimes you get a little bit of money,
you get a trophy,
right?
So we would only race that.
I have a collection of my house.
You used to get these little pins,
right?
Little hat pins,
like a $2 hat pin.
This is finisher on it,
right?
And that's all you raised for.
You just spent all this money
all this time to kill yourself.
You've got a wall for him.
I got like 10 right?
And it says finisher and sometimes I have,
you know this and I've got
a plaque that says winner,
but um,
they've upgraded a little bit,
but generally you run Robin,
I brought something for you,
which is going to be a finisher's
medal from the Baja 500 oh,
that's what it looks
like.
You can have it.
Why?
Why would I have that Ryan in finish shit,
I don't deserve to have
this because you get,
did you get to remember this?
That's one thing I remember you,
no matter what,
Dude,
you live in my neighborhood.
This is ridiculous.
I can't have this.
I'll leave it here,
but I won't touch it.
Deserve.
I don't deserve to.
All right.
Good Times,
gentlemen.
Rama cat grin.
But Brett's been and a April 20th,
he could watch it on CBS sports.
Watch it.
Tune in.
Uh,
enjoy support.
And the history channel
thing is just a pilot.
Is it airing?
Yeah,
it'll,
it'll be error.
Probably fourth quarter.
December.
All right,
let us know when that's going to air and,
uh,
below we'll tune people into it.
Uh,
thanks to our sponsor.
Thanks to Tim,
go to rogan.ting.com and,
uh,
enjoy yourself some delicious cell
phone service and thanks to uh,
our winner,
Holly,
Matt Callie,
Mac 23 at Twitter.
I'm sure right now if we go there,
she has more Twitter followers.
Let's see.
Let's see what Holly Max got.
Now.
I think we've left her.
She had 19.
She's still got 19 popular girl.
Not really.
Um,
maybe she just,
uh,
maybe she can't,
won't let anybody in.
Maybe nobody gives a fuck.
Uh,
anyway.
Um,
uh,
and on it,
on it.com go to o,
n n I t used the Codeword Rogan save
10% off any and all supplements.
All right.
Uh,
we got several podcasts
going on this week.
Uh,
we will be back tomorrow and,
um,
uh,
we will be back tomorrow with a mark
from a great white is going to be pretty
interesting.
Um,
uh,
well I'll,
I'll tell you all about it,
but,
uh,
he's,
um,
he's actually a really good pool player.
Apparently he's a professional level,
so we're gonna play some pool and um,
then we'll be back Friday with one of
the co founders of Reddit next week.
We've got David towels coming
in and a few other people.
Oh.
And,
uh,
Andreas Antonopoulos is going to come
back to and discuss what the fuck is going
on with bitcoin because it seems
to be the hot topic these days.
Okay.
We'll be back.
We'll see soon.
Much love to everybody.
Thank you very much.