Now we're live,
I,
for one,
want to express outrage at that
Kellyanne Conway woman,
not just putting her feet up on that
couch,
but being the only woman in the room
having a feet up,
or do you think it a sexual posturing
thing?
I don't know if you know.
There's a lot of men in the room.
I'm in a weird position.
It could just be instinct.
Yeah,
look at her.
Look at it dudes.
There's a lot of black dudes.
Is that the Black Caucus?
Black College?
Is this the leaders of the black
historically black colleges and
universities and look at her.
Do you think that that's what's going on
there?
I think that's very sexual.
Yeah.
I mean it looks sexual dude.
She's got the vagina curtain thing going
on.
She's got her legs spread.
Yeah,
she's looking at her phone.
Maybe pictures of decks.
She's actually on tinder,
which is weird.
Yeah.
She's swiping everyone,
right?
Yes.
Come get some.
There's so many great memes about this.
Like I saw one of them that was in
quotes.
What is a train question mark?
Fantastic.
That's fantastic.
We live in a fucking dream and we really
do.
This is so weird to see donald trump's
smiling,
like if you like knocked me over the
head 10 years ago and put me in a coma
and then woke me up today and then.
And then I was like,
well,
what's going on?
Who's the president?
And you're like,
well,
check this out.
I'd be like,
get the fuck out of.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
It's like you remember that scene in
back to the future when he's like,
who's the president in 1985?
Ronald Reagan,
the actor.
That's exactly what it's like.
It's crazy.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
It's great.
Put that picture back up.
So much going on there.
No one's ever done that before.
Like,
before this,
she's like,
we got to do a photo with the blacks,
you know,
like he's just the kind of things he
says we gotta get more images of the
blacks that with me because every time
really important,
really important.
Every time he takes a photo into the
Oval Office,
it's like 12 white guys.
I wish I could do an impression of him.
I mean,
yeah,
there's a lot.
Yeah.
To me it's just talk like A.
I can't though.
I don't like my voice doesn't make that
noise like whatever noises,
voice bank,
very gravelly or something.
I don't know what it is.
Yeah,
very bad things.
Bad debts said.
Very best.
Said that sad thing.
It's hilarious.
The word sad after tweets because
fucking everybody's doing it now.
So funny though.
The Internet is funny man.
The Internet,
the Internet,
you have to like I always look at
comedy,
like music,
you know,
and I always say like,
like I know how to do,
I know how to play Acoustic Guitar,
which is like stand up,
you know what I mean?
And then how to like write I've written
for TV shows that it's like playing the
piano,
instagram,
twitter,
like it's like that's like the saxophone
man and I'm like I'm trying to learn the
music but it's funny man.
It's kind of common.
Yeah.
And people are good at it.
Like some people are just good at it and
like you said,
you see a meme every now and then,
like my girlfriend,
sometimes it'll be in a,
you know,
like whatever is in the bedroom or
something and I'm here hysterically
laughing and I come in and she just
shows me and I'm like,
you know what,
that's pretty funny,
you know,
and it's just a still image with three
words on it and it just works.
Well.
Memes are a new form of comedy,
like these images with text attached to
the end.
That's just so perfect.
Totally.
And there's a way to do it and there's a
way not to do it because you can't be
met at about it.
You can't be like,
oh,
uh,
you know,
you,
you have to embrace it.
You can't think you're above it.
Like you can't go.
Like,
Oh,
here's my me,
my memes about how means you're stupid.
It's like,
Nah,
I'm not kidding you.
Everybody hates you.
Names are awesome.
They're great.
Yeah.
It was like you just have to embrace it
and go like,
no,
that's a funny form of comedy that I
needed to thievery going on with memes
to.
Oh yeah,
you know,
a lot of people like that fat Jewish guy
that just take everybody else's memes
and he doesn't even like put repost.
He just puts their name in it.
Like that's enough.
Like he puts their name somewhere in
the,
in the post.
Yeah.
He's one of those dudes were,
I don't know anything about them,
but it just,
it's hard to like not interested.
And I thought,
Oh man,
I was at a party.
The Fat Jewish was there,
like you should stop this story.
Right?
Because they'll think about this.
That's interesting to me.
It just,
for too long he was doing what he knows
is wrong.
And then he started just adding people's
names to the memes,
but it doesn't like if I've repost so
many stuff,
I write re,
I'd put the repost thing.
I use repost so everybody knows.
It says in the first letters repost.
Right.
So okay,
this is rory is eat.
He put it or this is,
you know,
rory is instagram post.
He's not doing that.
Nope.
Yeah,
it's just,
it's,
there's a funky thing.
But also I got to be honest,
I've been sent some things.
I don't know where the fuck they came
from and I put it up just because I
thought it was hilarious.
Yeah.
I didn't try to say it was mine and I'm
not making a living off of doing that.
I just wanted to share something that's
funny,
but you can do that and go.
I don't know where this came from,
but it's really fun.
It is.
But it's weird because somebody must
have made it.
And how the fuck do you find who made
it?
I don't know.
I mean I,
I've only made one instagram thing that
like did.
Okay.
Which was a,
it was a picture of um,
Ivanka trump and that silver dress.
And I was like,
oh,
right.
When she released it,
I was like,
oh,
I got to do something about this.
And I said to my girlfriend,
but what does this look like?
She's like a chipotle,
a Burrito.
So I found like a chipotle,
a burrito wrapped in tin foil it and I
was like,
who wore it better?
And it did really,
it was like the only time I did
something on instagram because a lot of
times I put a joke on instagram and like
get ready Internet about to break you
and then nobody likes it.
But that one.
But that one I actually saw other people
posting without crediting me.
And I was like,
Hey,
what do you mean you don't really
trust?
This?
Looks like it looks just like she looks
like a Burrito.
He's an odd look and fellow too.
There's something about the man that
named Jared cushner commissioner?
Yeah,
something about him where I'm like wow,
this guy's like,
he's like a character in a Kubrick movie
or something.
And he to me is like,
like,
you know,
I'm a New York Italian Jew but I grew up
with dudes like jared cook.
But he's like the rich version of where
I grew up.
Like he's like,
like a,
a rich Jewish kid from the city,
like went to a private school and then
like got in that world.
And now he's,
now he's like running the country.
I feel like I could have gone to camp
with him.
I mean he really is running the country.
He's one of the guys.
He's one of the main people,
but I don't know that I've read stuff
that like,
you know,
he,
he doesn't have as much say as one might
hope manager would have a little bit
more.
Yeah.
I mean I would imagine the big boss is
the dad.
And then Bannon is trump and then
bannon.
Yeah.
But he's doing trump's bidding.
You mean he's,
it's,
he's the brother in law under the sun
law.
He's got a.
he's got a big part.
He does look at that dark darks.
Got a big part of running the country.
So it does fucking scored though.
Congratulations sir.
You've made out.
Well he,
he stepped in a big pile of shit.
She's hot as fuck too.
I bet she's probably.
I bet she's probably pretty cool.
Reasonable person too.
She seems like she seems like shit.
I think she's probably a little bit like
what's going on.
I feel the same way about Melania.
I think Melania is.
I did not sign up to be the first lady.
Yeah,
well she's not even doing it.
she's not.
Except for that one day she read the
Lord's prayer off of a piece of paper.
Oh,
well how about the one day she
plagiarized Michelle Obama speech?
Yeah.
That was the thing when I started
reading the Lord's prayer.
I'm sure it's out there,
but like my instinct was like,
did she think Michelle Obama wrote the
Lord's for herself?
So she's reading,
but I'm sure that that joke was made a
thousand times,
but let's be honest,
Michelle Obama probably didn't write
that speech either.
It's probably a speech writer.
No,
no,
absolutely not.
But I do think that if you're going to
steal from a first lady,
do it from one,
from like know years ago,
don't do it.
The one who is still first lady.
Well,
do you remember when Joe Biden got
caught for stealing Kennedy's speeches?
That was surprising to me when everyone
started talking about,
oh,
like everyone got so excited.
Biden might run for president.
And I was like,
am I the only one who has been like
paying attention to Joe?
But he's constantly doing those trump
things.
He's the guy who's like,
Hey,
get up,
come on,
stand up.
And the guys that are wheelchair,
he's like such a buffoon,
you know,
he's an odd guy.
And the,
the memes about him were fucking genius.
That Joe Biden means at the end of the
term,
the goodbye means that's what I'm
talking about.
Like that's funny,
you know,
that's what I.
for me it was like,
you know,
the daily show when I used to be at the
daily show was like we were doing stuff
and it always felt like we were the
fastest ones doing it.
Now with memes and stuff,
you're going,
they're instantaneous.
You have a broadcast time.
There's no way you could keep up.
I mean it's,
it's an the speed by which things are
launched and are good,
that they're not crappy.
Like the mockups are funny and the
graphics are funny and like people are
like,
I don't know how fast people are editing
photos on their phone or like photoshop,
but instantaneous.
Well,
they happen during podcast while we're
doing podcasts.
I'm going to make a meme about something
said on the podcast.
It'll be up before the podcast is over.
For me,
the moment for me,
like it was the summer,
I was at the nightly show and I started
to go,
we're in a little bit of trouble here.
It was when that dude was climbing trump
tower when the suction cups and it was
like,
fuck,
it was like 5:00 and we tape it like
six.
We did tape it six and a,
so we were rewriting that night show
when I made a little joke just to one of
the researchers about the Suction Cup
dude,
like what's he climbing?
Michael Phelps back because it was the
Olympics and Phelps was getting such a
stupid joke,
but the kind of thing for a late night
show,
top of show,
hey,
what's up?
Everybody?
Welcome to job.
Before we get started to take a look at
this show the dude and go,
can we why?
Now I'm on that,
and then you see him climbing felts
back.
I said that went back into the rewrite
room.
Open twitter that joe can already been
made.
The graphics were impeccable and they
have been retweeted like 60,000 times
and the dude was already.
It was still on the tower that fast and
that's what I'm like,
we're in,
we're in trouble.
This shows a trouble.
Comedy Writers and Comedians as well,
like to think that they're the only ones
who are funny.
It's almost like you're a neurosurgeon
or a race car.
You have some skill that no one else
has.
People are funny.
There's fucking funny people that are
dentists.
There's funny people.
Like one of the funniest people I've
ever met in my fucking life is my former
boss,
Dave Dolan.
He was a private investigator.
The dude was fucking hilarious and his
cousin was build down to own the comedy
connection in Boston.
And uh,
when I was working for him,
he,
he lost his license from drinking and
driving and he needed a,
uh,
an assistant in quotes who,
who did basically it was a driver.
This guy,
my thought you meant that Pei,
Pei,
Pei lost his license.
And so I started working for them and
we'd get it.
We'd have to get up at like 5:00 in the
morning and like show up at people's
houses to catch them working when they
were supposed to.
You know,
you doing a pie assistant work.
How is that not a TV show?
Joe Rogan,
Pii assistant,
you know,
I don't want to know.
Maybe it could be.
I'm not gonna do it though.
So still the idea anybody's listening to
this guy was fucking hilarious.
He just had a comics mind.
He would just start talking about,
look at this scumbag,
you know the fuck he's doing.
He said he started saying crazy shit
like writing life.
Really?
I mean I would be crying like tears
rolling down my eyes laughing and
thinking like I'm the one that's a
fucking comedian and this,
my boss is way funnier than me.
Yeah.
All the guys that grew up with her.
I mean,
like I grew up in like with funny
people,
like some of my friends are very,
very funny.
Uh,
but they just didn't know who the hell
thinks to do this and do stand up.
That's what people asked me that when
they say,
what's the hardest thing about doing
standup?
I'm like,
it's admitting you're an asshole.
It's like you like if you walked into a
party and it was full of people and they
were all hanging out and we're like,
hey,
quiet down everybody.
I got funny shit to say.
They'd be like,
who brought the.
So they'd be like,
wait,
I'm not done.
Not only do one,
I want you to talk.
I want you to pay me for my thoughts and
ideas and put a light on me,
a letter and if you talk I'm going to be
an asshole about it to you because it's
my.
But it's the whole impulse to do that is
very much like not only do I think I'm
funny,
I think I like,
you know,
and you know,
and then every now and then you meet a
comedian who,
who wasn't funny when they were growing
up.
What were you thinking?
The only reason I did this is because I
always was like,
if I was good at baseball would've been.
I would've been tried baseball,
but some guys are just funny and then
they just become accountants will,
everybody said something funny at one
point in their life and one of the weird
things about being a comedian as it
does,
it's,
it's a special skill that doesn't look
like it's a special skill.
Like if I walked up to somebody who's
like a mma,
you know,
making us,
making a sculpture or something like
that,
I'd be like,
oh wow.
How are you doing that?
Like,
what are you using?
Oh,
well,
what tools?
Like how you,
how you start it.
Like what do you map it out on paper?
Like how you do it.
Like it would be confusing to me.
You know,
I'd want to know,
like what's the process?
If I see a guy go on stage and start
talking,
I go walk and fucking do that.
I guys just standing there like
literally standing.
He's not Cirque du Solei and he's not
juggling.
Yeah.
He doesn't have a Hulu,
but it doesn't have a poodle with no
spitting fire.
Like Gene Simmons.
Yeah.
Everything seems really straightforward.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
And so it's,
one of the things is so deceptive about
it and then you watch someone who's like
really good at it,
he's got like,
it's like,
well that seems so effortless.
Yeah,
this guy's up there,
kill him like this.
But it's like,
it's the year I always feel like the
years of it or,
or,
or being on stage,
it's like,
it's like you have to become as close to
you as you can be in front of a group of
people.
A bunch of strangers.
Yeah.
And,
and you're,
everything I,
you know,
I,
I always found in the beginning of the
hardest stuff about it was you don't
realize like how much super human
hearing and stuff you have when you're
on stage.
It's all these things like,
you know,
it's like a.
I was trying to think of the analogy.
It's like when,
when like,
like you'll never see it like a movie
where someone discovers they have super
powers but they're overwhelming.
Like it's like that.
It's like you start get onstage and you
hear like a fork drop in the back of the
room stuff nobody else is hearing.
And when you're a rookie,
you're like,
Hey,
hold on to your fork.
And people like what we said,
you know what I mean?
Like only you hear it,
you know,
hey,
hey sneezy people like did the guy's
knees,
I'm not,
I'm watching you.
So it's like you learn.
But that for me in the beginning was
like an issue.
Like I remember like emceeing clubs and
like thinking I was like being sharp.
You know,
when people have been like we didn't,
we did not experience that same
sensation you experience because
learning how to relax,
learning how to actually be yourself in
front of all those people.
Like it's fascinating to me.
Like I have a buddy of mine who's
thinking about doing stand up now and
I've known him forever and he's been
working on is his act.
He's to z 39 these journeys for the
first time.
That's not tate tate Fletcher.
He's a successful actor.
He does a lot of movies.
He's in everything in John Wick.
Every time I see him he's in a movie
getting shot.
Yeah,
he's in a ton of movies,
right?
If he's in John Wick,
he's getting shot in the head,
got stabbed to,
I don't know,
he got killed in Jurassic Park if the
killed by dinosaurs,
but he's always getting killed.
But the point is,
he was in Westworld.
He got killed by already killed himself
with a rock,
smashed himself in the head.
I know that guy.
So He's been writing comedy and I'm
like,
well,
you do it.
Like why do this to yourself?
He's like,
I want to do what I want to see.
We could do it like,
I'm like,
Oh God,
I'm totally fascinating because the
process of trying to figure out how to
relax and like ready,
set,
go.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome Tait Fletcher and he gets
up on stage.
Has he done it yet or no,
he hasn't done it yet,
but it's going to be interesting to see
because it's the,
the whole process of like learning,
like becoming so comfortable that you
can relax while you're on stage in front
of all those people.
Just see that's what takes the time.
It's,
it's the,
uh,
being comfortable,
you know,
it's like the Malcolm gladwell thing,
it takes 10,000 hours to master
something that's 10 years.
It's like you've got to be on stage a
lot of hours to be yourself and be
comfortable and not and even eat it,
you know?
And then when you watch yourself back,
you,
especially in the beginning,
you don't realize you're doing stuff.
I remember watching myself back early on
and be like,
am I touching my nose the whole time?
Wait,
why isn't anyone telling me I'm touching
my nose?
You know?
And it's like,
people must think I do coke,
you know?
I'm like,
hey guys,
but I don't probably do to do right back
in the day,
but I never did.
I've never had.
But it's like those are the little
nervous ticks you develop and you have
to learn over time.
Like,
just got to be,
you know,
but it's hard.
How are you,
you,
you've transitioned from doing the daily
show.
Don't take transition,
Joe.
It's 2017.
People are just now going to think that
Oh,
it's coming.
You know?
Yeah.
It's a weird term now.
You can't,
you can't say transition,
right.
In terms medical officer,
he can't say transition,
transition.
Joe,
you're on your journey now to say that
like what kind of journey?
A journey of sexual experimentation.
You can't ask me about it because you're
not supposed to and you can't answer.
You have to accept a lot of um.
Well,
okay.
I was going to say something but on the
transition from going to throw somebody
under the bus,
but it was no need to um,
the,
this whole journey of like going from
like you started off as a comic and then
you worked for the daily show for so
long and you kind of miss comedy.
I did comedy while you were doing it a
little bit,
like a half hour special when I was at
the daily show,
but it was weak because I was putting
working 95 percent of my energy and that
the daily show yet.
But now you're out now you're like,
well,
I left the daily show in like 2013 last
time I did your podcast.
I was,
I was living out here in about to go
back to do the nightly show and the
nightly show was I said yes because I
didn't want to produce anymore.
I wanted to perform,
but the deal for the nightly show was I
got to be on it,
you know.
So that's Larry Wilmore to Larry wilmore
show.
Yeah.
So I went back to,
at the time it was called the minority
report,
but then it became the nightly show
because of fox lawsuits and what's the
loss?
Because remember the minority report,
the Tom Cruise movie,
which is like a Philip k dot dick book
and Fox had just bought.
Oh,
you said Fox.
I automatically think Fox News.
I know.
Well,
associate parent company,
the parent company should change your
fucking name.
Yeah.
You know?
Yeah,
you're right.
Because even when you see it come up,
you're like,
oh,
is this going to be pointless?
I was working for the UFC.
Still do,
but I don't do the Fox things anymore.
And when I was doing the Fox things,
they were like,
oh,
so you're,
you're working on Fox now.
What's that like?
Are they like super right wing?
I'm like,
that's so funny.
No,
it's fucking cage fighting,
dude.
I'm a cage fighting commentator.
Yes,
they are right wing.
But that's not what this now it's still,
it was fox didn't always used to be
right when they're actually not and not
everybody is right wing.
But now there is a place where it's
weird.
I've noticed with the,
uh,
with Fox where it's like if somebody,
they like the right likes,
says something anti-trump,
then they just want them off the
network.
Like,
yeah,
that happened twice.
Shep Smith said something about trump.
He said something recently that was
really good and people we have,
but he went on a rant about it and then
people were like,
that's sort of my favorite thing right
now is there's a group of people calling
another group of people snowflakes for
over sensitivity,
which I love that term.
Yeah.
Which I think is very funny and I agree
there was a lot of snow.
You can get in trouble right now for
saying anything and I'm sure like just
this conversation,
people are mad,
but if some fucking liberal guy on
twitter that was like in all caps,
stop calling people snowflakes and
you're like,
well,
now I want to do it more.
It's,
it's tantamount to psychological torture
for these young children.
Like,
oh,
fucking snowflake.
I got into trouble with,
uh,
when,
when trump won because they kept showing
all this footage on the news.
I'm like,
grown men crying.
So I just said like,
I don't know,
maybe I'm immature,
but to me every time if I see a grown
man crying on the news,
it's not if he's crying because his kid
died.
Just like if you lost the election and
you're a grown man and you're crying.
And so I made a joke about it.
Like,
how?
I think that's funny.
Every time people got so mad,
oh,
men can't cry.
I'm like,
oh no,
men can cry over that pussy.
I don't know.
It's like,
people were like,
Oh,
why?
Why is it funny?
Because it's a man.
I'm like,
yeah,
I guess because he's crying over an
election and he's a man,
like I don't know where I grew up.
That's funny.
It's still funny to me.
It is funny because that's not a guy who
can keep it together.
Okay.
This is not a national disaster.
It might become a national,
wasn't at the time it was just a loss.
Certainly a moment for concern.
Sure.
But,
and I get it.
And then people were like,
well,
what if,
what about,
you know,
gay man?
And I go,
yeah,
I get it.
A lot of people are scared.
They're gonna lose your rights.
They're scared.
I get it.
But man,
I got scolded for grown men crying.
It's funny to me,
not like,
I'm like,
I guess it's not.
I don't know if there's so many people
making a grown man.
Crying is not funny.
What's funny is a grown man crying when
he shouldn't be crying.
Yeah,
that's what's funny.
absolutely.
Yeah.
And it's,
you know,
it's like there's still an instinct.
You still have like a kind of a knee
jerk instinct to things sometimes that
just makes you laugh.
And then if you share that feeling at
the,
at the wrong time,
you're immature.
Yeah.
And then they'll use charts and then the
flip side is,
is the right man,
they're killing everybody.
Snowflakes.
And then you say one thing that they
don't want to hear and they want you on
Fox News talking about snowflakes to
like why chef Smith teaching go with
Meghan Kelly the m and the lame stream.
NBC Indigo.
You.
Doesn't that make you a snowflake?
Now the same thing happened with Chris
Wallace.
Shepherd interview with rents,
Priebus,
and people were like,
get him Outta here.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Chris Wallace,
his,
you know,
his dad was Mike Wallace.
He's actually a journalist.
It's crazy.
Well,
it,
it's a weird time when you see
journalists getting excluded from press
gaggle.
So when you get the New York Times and
uh,
who else was it?
It was never a times la times.
And then there was another big one.
Oh,
CNN,
fuck the fuck man.
What the fuck.
Do you remember when Obama was
considering removing Fox News from
something?
Because Fox News is essentially
propaganda.
If you listen to Sean Hannity,
I've heard Sean Hannity is a wonderful
man.
I've heard he's a really nice guy.
When you meet them with that
motherfucker is spewing straight hot
propaganda.
He was the best point man.
After the grab my pussy shit came up.
He was the best because he just went
fucking straight to Bengazi.
He went straight to the email scandal
and he fucking hammered it constantly to
the point where,
you know,
locker room,
talk aside,
he circled.
We could certainly say that was
inappropriate.
Let's get to the facts.
Your let's get to what's important and
just Bam.
Bam is a big trump ally.
Oh,
but he's good.
He's good at what he does now.
He is very good at what he does,
but I mean when that was going on with
against Obama,
they were like,
look,
why the fuck are we having these people?
Even why we even pretending they're
press.
This is not journalism.
These,
this is a propaganda network.
And it was like,
Whoa,
whoa.
You remember?
It's like 2009 in Obama almost had them
removed,
but people protested.
He's like,
all right,
fine.
Not Trump.
Know he's like,
not only that,
I'm not even going to the press
correspondents' dinner.
That to me is he talked about being a
pussy dude.
Like you're like,
you're scared,
you're scared to get made.
That's him being scared.
And I was thinking the whole time like,
oh,
what comedian gets to do that?
That's a great gig.
Fuck that Gig.
That guy will go after you.
That's the problem is you make fun of
that dude and then like you'll all of a
sudden like you have like,
you're getting all of this more than
audited men more than audited.
They're probably search your emails and
find some incriminating shit that you
might've did when you were in high
school,
but then.
But then part of me is like kind of
worth it to get standup.
Kind of kind of stand up on the stage
next to trump and just be like,
dude,
come on.
Yeah,
you would definitely get mad press for
doing well.
But he,
yeah,
he would.
He would go,
I don't know.
He doesn't handle it well.
Do you remember when Obama was roast him
and he just sat there and stared in his
face?
Yeah,
I know it's,
it's,
it's a weird time,
man.
That was like when Obama said,
we have video of my actual birth for the
first time,
we're going to release this and they go
to the lion king,
lion king cartoon.
Hilarious.
Obama was fucking good at that.
Pretty funny,
funny president.
Yeah.
You mean I,
I just,
I still to this day I think that he's
probably as far as like as a human
being,
not not as like I hate presidential
speeches because I hate,
I hate that whole political talk.
I hate the way people talk right now.
Like they're not a real person and he is
like the king of the pause is a big
fake,
stupid artistic five second pause.
Yeah.
Well I mean he's just good at that kind
of shit and there's a thing too that I
don't particularly like that but I get
it.
But I mean as far as like being like a
representative of the country,
the guy was intelligent.
Well read,
forget his policies aside.
There's something about who the guy who
is in charge is what it says about the
rest of us and what it says about the
rest of us now as it were,
a disorganized mess.
And that's really what it says.
Yeah,
it's,
it's definitely a.
I could tell you this though.
Trump is not wrong about CNN hating him.
Like he's not wrong.
No.
If you watch the election and everything
leading up to the election,
they did not like him.
Even the,
even the images they use of him and they
were pretty openly against him and look,
I was,
like I said,
I worked at the daily show.
I watched a lot of CNN,
I watched a lot of MSNBC.
There's problems.
I have problems with all of those cable
news now.
Good for you because you and,
and I really think that like the cult of
personality media thing.
My,
my biggest issue with cable news is that
there are in the same rating system as
like the Big Bang theory.
You know what I'm saying?
And it's like they're trying to get.
No,
but they're trying to get numbers.
Man,
that's all they're trying to do.
Obviously the goal of Sean Hannity show
or,
or ac three 60,
any of these shows is to get people to
watch so they can sell ad time because
so they can make money.
So that's my issue with it more than,
you know,
they're like,
a lot of them were bad at journalism.
I mean,
you know,
I,
it's hard for me to forget things like
balloon boy when we were at war in
Afghanistan and Iraq and like they think
a kid stuck in a weather balloon and we
have like seven hours of coverage of a
weather balloon floating down the street
with a live chop recovered.
And then it turned out the kid was
hiding,
the dad was a prankster or whatever for
whatever the point is done.
Why?
Why did I have to watch that for four
hours?
You know what I'm saying?
So it's like if a shiny thing happens,
they run towards the shiny thing they
do.
They're immature,
they're looking for ratings,
they're looking to be the first.
They never talked about.
There's like flint,
Michigan,
right.
What,
when was the last time,
like people that don't have water still
and they live in America still,
but the media is not talking about it.
You know,
they're talking right now about Kelly
conway putting their feet,
feet,
shoes on.
It's what I want to know,
but in another words,
God Damn White House,
couch pitch.
So if they get,
they get,
they get.
That's what people are mad about that
like they're like disrespect,
disrespectful.
If the guy was sitting like that.
But you got to imagine this scotch
guarded.
That shit.
If Obama was sitting like that on the
couch,
do you want me to.
Gay rumors would come out about him.
Shell Obama was sitting like that
anywhere.
Oh yeah.
People be so angry.
I would say about the things people say
about Michelle Obama.
She has her shoes on.
Oh boy.
That is just UNAMERICAN shit.
Bubble gum all over the fucking White
House couch.
Dare You lady dog shit.
And bubblegum.
It's a real problem with what the news
is because it's not really the news.
It's an entertainment show featuring
events in the news and it's.
There are 100 percent bias.
There's no real journalism on television
when it comes to TV news.
PBS is they're pretty liberal,
but they're also very boring.
In other words,
they're not trying to Zazi you know,
they'll look,
here's what's happening.
That's what we need though.
You need to be able to formulate your
own opinions and when you're being
steered in one way or another,
whether it's steered by bill o'reilly or
steered by someone on the left,
it's the who the fuck is like a big
reporter for CNN.
I don't even know who.
Anderson Cooper.
That's it.
We'll put it.
We'll put her.
I saw a wolf blitzer the other day in
Vegas.
I ran into him.
I was going to say hi,
but I'm like,
maybe he doesn't like me.
He hit his head for hookers with him.
He's walking into the did and high five
them.
Nobody wants to smoke a joint.
The only thing I will say about Fox is
like their opinion guys,
o'reilly Hannity,
that kind of have them under opinion.
Yes.
Versus like Anderson Cooper is like
news,
you know,
so it's like,
it's like,
why do you think Anderson?
I think Anderson Cooper,
like my take on him is clearly,
he's very left wing.
Right?
He's a gay guy,
you know?
I mean he's a,
he's a,
but he's also a vanderbilt.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
And he also worked for the CIA when he
was in college that I did not.
No,
he didn't.
no,
no.
Yeah,
yeah.
That's the big concern is that Anderson
Cooper is embedded CIA journalist.
Yeah.
That's the big CIA conspiracy theory.
You didn't know that?
No,
I did not know that.
I would imagine that once you work for
the CIA,
you're in the fucking CIA.
Imagine you always have a little
contact.
Yeah.
I have a friend who used to be in the
CIA and I still consider him and the
CIA,
you know,
I mean,
I know,
uh,
another guy whose dad was in the CIA,
fucking dad still in the CIA
essentially.
We'd figure you got to know a couple
people over at this.
Like,
I don't know,
I don't have any CIA context.
You know,
it's like I used to work there,
you probably have a few,
and this is the shitty comparison,
but if I left the UFC I'd still be with
the UFC.
You know what I mean?
Like there's,
there's like,
there's this,
there's a giant bond that you've got to
have with the fucking Central
Intelligence Agency.
You know,
you don't fuck with those guys.
You don't fuck them over and if they
call you,
you answer the Goddamn phone hook.
Yeah.
You,
yeah.
I'm still like,
I,
that's why I really got rid of that when
trump was being so hard on the
intelligence.
I'm like,
dude,
like I don't know man,
like all of those guys that the
intelligence community,
like they're the reasons we're safe.
And when I say we're safe,
I live in New York City.
Okay.
So my attitude on terrorism is if you
live in New York or a city,
you know,
I always take issue with people and I
traveled to stand up and you know,
I make a joke about isis or something
and people go,
Ooh,
in small towns.
But in big cities they laugh and they
go,
it's amazing to me that people in
Kentucky,
I think that there's someone in the cave
like we've got to get Louis,
like it's not right.
But you know what I mean?
Like,
so there's this weird thing that starts
to happen where people are using.
I keep seeing people post nine slash 11.
The World Trade Center is fire go.
This is why the Muslim band makes sense.
I'm going like,
I was their man like you,
you can't just,
you don't get to use that like you.
Like there's something very odd to me
about,
um,
about you.
Like everyone hates New York,
not everyone,
but like real America doesn't consider
New York real,
but the terrorist attacks,
they were,
were like,
it's a very odd thing that's happened in
the country and I know what you're
saying.
It feels like divided in the sense of
like,
we hate everything you guys are about,
but we'll use that thing that impacted
your lives as a way to gain our,
make our point.
That's hilarious what you're saying
because you're saying we hate everything
you're about.
That sounds just like the terrorists,
right?
That's true.
So you're talking about someone from
like,
you know,
a very conservative part of the country
saying we hate New York because New York
is the liberal elite and then you say,
well the terrorists on the side of the
terrorist,
he fucked her.
That's a good point.
I mean it's kind of weird.
It was weird and there was a.
There was a weird thing happening right
now,
but I do.
I do feel like the country is divided to
a point of like it.
I don't know.
We're not going to be honest.
Again,
it's not.
It doesn't see it on the Internet.
It's bad.
I got my.
I got my news a lot from the daily show.
What I would watch the daily show and I
see.
I feel like John Stewart obviously I'm
very left leaning guy,
but he's also a very smart guy and a
very funny guy.
And when he would talk about like events
in the news and mock them and show clips
and mock the clips,
that to me is a way better version of
what I would get.
Like I can discern what's a joke,
I can discern how he's making fun,
but then I will also get the actual
information of these events from him as
well.
That to me is a way better version of
news entertainment than what fucking CNN
is doing because with CNN is doing is
having what are essentially actors like
really boring people that are reading
some stupid shit off a teleprompter.
Like you take fucking Anderson Cooper
away from the news.
What?
Who was Anderson Cooper?
What do you.
Interesting Dude,
you know,
let's have him talk.
Have him give a speech somewhere.
Have him talk to people,
have him,
have him do a standup routine.
He's boring as shit.
I bet you know what I'm saying.
I mean if you're watching an
entertainer,
give you the news,
which is essentially what CNN is doing.
Right?
Fucking John Stewart should be on CNN.
Yeah.
But then he'd have to like go to work
everyday.
Didn't want to do that.
Is that what his deal is?
He doesn't want to work,
you know,
he,
I mean he doesn't want the daily show
after so many years.
I mean,
I was there for a long,
I talked to John a lot.
I think a lot of it is just the feeling
of like,
you know,
doing a talk show four nights a week
every day and calling through all that
news.
Like we were giving people the little
golden nuggets that happened throughout
the day.
But like we have to watch it.
Like,
you know,
we were absorbing a lot of radiation
from all that stuff.
Like you know,
like the closer you are to the
radiation,
the more you know your,
your hair gets great and your soul hurts
after a while.
And I think for John,
I mean I think him leaving when he left
was a good way to do it.
You can just make a bunch of money and
say,
ah,
that's it.
No,
it wasn't even the money.
I think it was just,
he felt like.
And he said it on the last.
I wasn't there for the,
I,
I'd stopped working there before he
retired,
but I think you just got to a point
where he said like,
I'm not doing this at the level I could
do it at anymore,
therefore someone else should do it.
Like,
um,
he was,
he was just kind of,
he did it,
you know,
and I think if you waited through this
election,
which people are like,
I wish he was still on.
It's like,
yeah,
but now trump would be in and then
everyone would be like,
you can't quit now.
You know,
like he'd be,
he'd be stuck in it forever,
you know,
and I think he just wanted to walk away
like on the top,
you know,
like the way,
like retire after a super bowl win kind
of thing.
You know,
people forget that he wasn't the
original hosts.
Isn't that fascinating?
Yeah.
Kilborne was what happened to that guy.
I don't know,
I,
I never worked there with Gilbert and I
started like six months after John
Stewart started and uh,
so I've heard a lot of like funny
kilborne stories.
Like he was a good dude and he was
really funny guy,
but like definitely much more of a read
the teleprompter.
He read what they put in the prompts or
kind of ragging Ron Burgundy style.
Fuck yourself,
San Diego.
Uh,
John,
when John came on and he was like,
really a writer,
producer mind.
That was definitely a sea change that
the show of like the writers wrote.
The original writers go like,
what the hell?
Hey Buddy,
don't ruin our little show.
And he was like,
man,
I don't know if you understand how this
is gonna work,
you know,
there was a little hole,
there was like a clash a little bit,
a little bit.
What was their vision that he was just
going to read whatever they wrote.
Yeah.
Period.
Yeah,
I think so.
But he's a really funny comic.
Why wouldn't they want him to contribute
and make it funnier?
I don't know.
I mean,
it worked out in his favor and his
contributions ended up making the show
pretty obviously.
But Egos are a motherfucker,
man.
It's an odd thing.
Yeah.
Comedy writers are,
like you said,
there's definitely a thing with comedy
writers where it's we have this special
unique skill and it is a skill and it's
hard.
I,
I've done it,
I do it like,
it's hard,
but you know,
a lot of people are funny,
you know,
the Internet to me taught me that,
like the Internet was when it really
became the Internet the last 10 years.
Like,
oh,
yet like there's just some funny dudes
who live in the middle of nowhere and
there's as funny as anyone I've ever met
and they just never had access to this.
They never had access to la or tv or
even knew how to the wildest dreams.
How do you get into this business?
It doesn't seem like we don't have to
anymore.
The whole idea is just to get your
message out or get your comedy out and
you could just do that on instagram now.
Yup.
I was super lucky in that.
Um,
I was on a really unusual sitcom in news
radio and not unusual in that.
It was funny,
but unusual in that Paul Simms,
who is the executive producers,
he has almost zero ego and so if Dave
Foley came up with a funnier line or
Stephen root came up with a funnier
line,
it's like,
oh yeah,
go with that.
Like instantaneously would drop whatever
the old line was and go with their line.
So my whole take on comedy on television
was poisoned like early on by dare,
generosity and lack of ego.
So like when I would,
when we would do that show,
like Dave Foley would rewrite whole
fucking scenes when we do genius genius,
secret producer of that show in a lot of
ways in.
But they wanted him to do it.
They're like,
let's just make the best show we can and
everybody would contribute.
So there was never any.
So I would do other things and when I
would do other things and when someone
would have a better line and the right
it's got.
Yeah,
let's stick with the first one.
I'm like,
that aligns way better.
what the fuck's going on here?
Like they don't,
you don't want to try that line.
I was like,
oh,
there's some weird ego shit going on
here were the writers didn't want to be
replaced by some standup comic who is on
it,
you know that some David spade type
character or whatever they've been had
been rendered irrelevant at that.
Nobody wants somebody else to come in
and do the thing they think that they
need to be doing.
They want to protect their existence.
So yeah,
I mean every show like for me at the
daily show and then the nightly show you
I was running,
I didn't start running the daily show.
I started as a PA,
but like I ultimately ended up being the
executive producer before I left and
same with the nightly show.
My attitude with all of those shows was
all I cared about was the show being as
good as it could be.
I don't care.
I didn't really care where the idea came
from or that the goal was every night,
the best show possible now.
What was your experience doing?
The nightly show?
How long did you do?
Before we did it,
we were.
We were on the air for a year and a
half.
My experience there was awesome.
I loved the people.
What happened to the show?
What?
I mean?
I think it didn't work because,
well there's a lot of reasons.
I think it didn't work,
but mainly it takes a talk show a while
to figure out what it,
what it is now.
And so if you watched the last six
months of the show,
we really like started nailing it.
Like we really had something special and
we figured it out.
Like we got the groove down.
We figured out what the,
what the acts were,
what were the kind of stories we were
tackling and it takes that long.
But in figuring that out,
you know,
Jon Stewart left the daily show.
So our lead in and uh,
you know,
this is another new trevor,
but our leading was now a new host of
the show.
So I think the audience gave us a chance
which any audience would when we first
aired.
And the show wasn't quite there yet as
no show is,
but they gave us a chance.
And then when John Left,
I think they had already given us our
chance.
So by the time we found the show,
like meaning within the show,
but by the time we made it good and
really figured out what it was,
the audience was like,
Guy,
now we already tried that yet we don't
like it.
And to come back now and try it because
it's better now.
You know,
it was a ratings issue.
Yeah.
Ratings,
ratings for both shows.
I mean,
late nights.
Tough right now man.
And also don't forget,
like the nightly show was on 11 slash
30.
It replaced co bear.
But coverity didn't go anywhere.
He just went to a bigger show at 1130.
So now you have an unknown dude,
Larry.
One more who's amazing?
But he wasn't.
He do now.
He's just didn't know.
What does he do?
See a comic.
Larry was a producer,
he was a comic originally and it
producer,
he created the Bernie Mac show.
He created it.
He's been producing and writing
television like every show you've ever
liked.
He's it,
you know.
So how did he get behind the camera?
Because he was on the daily show,
he was our senior black correspondent,
so he would come in like once a month
and do like a thing about racial issues
in America and then really stewart
really wanted to do a show about race
because,
you know,
Ferguson was going on,
all that stuff was happening,
so he wanted to do a show that was more
of a conversation about race minority
report.
And when John called me I was like,
oh,
that sounds fun.
He goes,
and I want you to be the token white
guy.
You know what I mean?
Like meaning I could be the dude on the
panel who's either playing the defensive
role or the aggressive role in talking
about some of this stuff,
but it ended up being a lot more of a
daily show kind of show.
Like we had like much more of an act one
footage news.
Uh,
we did a lot of sketches.
Like for me it was a great experience.
I got like,
I have a real now,
you know,
am I real?
It's on my website.
It's like me,
I was wearing mustaches.
I was doing accents,
like I was playing w we,
we started doing fuse.
What for me was my dream of comedy,
which was the daily show topics with the
Conan O'brien and absurdity.
So we would do stuff like,
um,
like one of my favorites was when that,
uh,
San Bernardino shooting happened and
they were trying to get in that guy's
phone,
Larry notes that everyone in the news
was going,
we've got to get back door access,
backdoor access,
backdoor access.
So we did a bit where I was a backdoor
access expert,
you know,
and it was like just a creepy dude in a
basement with like a mustache and like a
mesh shirt.
And I was like,
yeah baby,
you want to get in the back door,
Larry,
you can't come at it so hard,
you know,
those kinds of things.
So we were talking about real issues and
then playing with like sketch.
So it really got funny and good.
But I think by the time it got funny and
good comedy central was like,
ah,
we got other problems.
Are you happier now just doing standup?
Yeah.
Now when I ran into you in Denver,
which was a fucking fun night,
that was fun,
man.
It was a fun night of Roy was there the
night that Chappelle showed up at my,
uh,
late show on Friday night.
And by the way,
I was watching you so sick because I
knew we were going to go on afterwards
and have some drinks and chat and then
Chappelle came in and at the comedy
cellar in New York,
Chappelle comes in a lot,
but when he comes down with a seller,
it's like,
well,
he'll be on stage for seven hours.
You know what I mean?
Oh yeah.
He'll go on stage sometimes for like
five hours and five hours.
Five hours.
Yeah,
like regularly.
Not regularly,
but it happens to the point where like
some dude in the back of sweeping up,
you know what?
It'd be crazy.
Yeah.
He's just on say smoking butts doing
this stuff.
But uh,
so when he first got on stage,
I'm like,
oh no.
I looked at my girlfriend go,
we're never going out with joe tonight.
I'm like,
we're going to be watching Chappelle's
separate in the morning.
You know,
but he,
you know,
he did this like what,
20 minutes or something.
It was cool.
He didn't do that much time and it was
the end of the show,
you know,
it was late.
I guess maybe you would assume that
Denver people don't have the stamina
that New York City people have to think.
So when he just five hours,
how many people are still there after
five hours of never there.
So I couldn't tell you.
I have to leave after like an hour.
But uh,
he,
uh,
you know,
people will stay through the whole
thing,
but like not everybody,
you know,
it's so weird.
Yeah.
But he's,
I mean he know he's,
I don't know,
I could watch Chapelle for the guys at
such a good dude,
but he definitely,
like,
I've never really hung out with them.
I've talked to a bunch but never hung
out with.
And everyone's like,
dude,
how can I chappelles the best?
And that night I was like,
I don't think he likes me very much.
I don't know.
We were just hanging out,
but we don't think you like to.
I just got this and we all went out.
Yeah.
No,
I didn't,
you know,
it was one of those things where I'm
like,
every time I say like,
he definitely liked my girlfriend,
you know what I mean?
Like what?
He was talking to her when I just meant
like,
he was definitely like,
I was like,
so you ever have that where you can't
get a rhythm with someone?
I was talking to him and be like,
all right,
well that story's not going to fly.
Like I had that,
like I couldn't get like a.
that's weird.
That's your perception.
That's interesting because I don't see
that generally speaking that nobody ever
likes me.
I've seen my perception was it was a fun
night.
We went barhopping,
we went to these.
I've been to Denver.
That's speakeasy was greater times.
Yeah.
We went to these places that you go down
an alleyway,
you pass a dumpster,
you go through an unmarked door and
we're in this weird secret bar and I'm
like,
what is this bar man you remind me of?
It was like that scene in goodfellas
where he's like,
you want some dresses?
Karen?
She's like,
no,
go down a couple more garage doors.
Make a left.
And then she just drives away.
That's what it was.
Everyone was like,
yeah,
there's a bar.
Just keep going to make a left where
like down this alley here,
the hackles on the back of my neck,
the
UFC legend Joe Rogan,
or I'm not going to this bar.
I was going to run.
Dude.
You stuck.
I'm not taking a pike.
I'm thinking of running and leaving you
guys behind it.
So yeah,
it was,
it was cool though.
Was Fun.
We got kicked out of two places for
smoking weed to two different places
that we couldn't smoke.
Weed will just spark up a joint in a
regular.
People just light up a cigarette in a
restaurant like that is,
that's a weird thing that just like a,
he's like missing A.
I don't give a fuck.
He's like,
he's out.
He's got a gene like,
and I don't give a fuck gene.
He's like missing a give a fuck.
I know it's not fair.
And,
and,
uh,
the,
you know,
the best comics to me are the ones who
don't give a fuck and that dude triple
doesn't give a fuck.
So that's why he's so good on stage
because he really doesn't give a shit.
We were out to like,
well,
after 4:00 in the morning and there was
a dj,
we went to some place,
there was a dj and a Dj starts playing
and there's like literally like 10 of us
in this apartment houses place staying
open.
So they were just happy to have
chappelle there.
I think Chappelle even went up to the DJ
and was like,
and then plugged in his music,
he was like,
I got this.
He plugged into the Chapelle was
fucking,
it was such a trip.
Well,
Dave brings these two huge,
uh,
they're like,
um,
you know,
those uh,
Bluetooth speakers,
a JVC,
he's got these big boxes.
He brings two of them.
They're huge.
They're like the size of bigger than
football,
right?
So he brings two of them and their sync
together.
So one's left and one's right and he'll
put them on opposite ends of his Green
Room and blare music.
And I was asking him about like,
well,
why do you carry this fucking things
run?
He goes,
Joe,
my only socializing I do is in green
rooms.
It's like the only socializing.
That's the only time I hang out with
people.
I go,
what do you do?
Others there?
I'm by myself.
I mean,
I live in Dayton,
Ohio.
He lives in the middle of nowhere and
fucking foreign or form.
What a cool dude though.
He's hilarious.
He's a really unique guy and a lot of
ways.
He's also,
he's also just,
um,
it's,
it's very impressive to see somebody
who's that like kind of legendary at
stand up and walk into a place and
people are like,
Oh shit,
you're even whatever level comic is
that?
Oh Shit.
Chappelle's here.
And then him also just be cool.
Like in other words,
he doesn't have to be cool.
Well,
yeah,
when he's not aloof at all,
super friendly.
Yep.
But I think he definitely has like a
little bit of a wall up for guys like
you.
That's why when you came up to me like,
Hey,
what's going on buddy?
He's like,
because I'm like,
I'm wants my phone number.
And I'm like,
yeah,
exactly.
And I'm like,
I definitely don't want your phone
number.
We're just going to be getting hammered
together.
We'll talk a little bit.
Yeah.
Yeah,
we,
uh,
we pulled it out until like I left him
there,
I left there like before I left,
like four or 4:30.
I was like,
I gotta go to Denver is a fun town.
But I know I did,
I did a show before I was there
Thursday.
I did it that show Thursday and then
they did it because I was showcasing my
hour.
So they made,
they created a shell before your show.
So I did my hour at like 6:00 or
something like early,
like they made an early show which they
had never done.
And I was like,
I'm like,
I gotta showcase for somebody at like
6:00.
But man,
that club comedy works,
the room was full.
It was like 6:00.
I like killed.
I couldn't even believe it.
I was like,
this something be like a lunchtime show.
It's going to be brutal.
Nope.
Filled it up.
And everyone came.
It was.
I've never,
I've never been more impressed with a
comedy club in my life than being able
to pull off a show early and good.
And then.
And then you had two shows after but
you,
you got to meet Wendy.
The owner of the common ones.
She's,
she's the reason why there's a scene in
Denver.
I mean she is the scene and she
literally is responsible for that plate.
That's the only one.
That's why I worked that club.
The last time I was there.
I sold out the bell coach,
like 6,000 people.
I still work our club.
It's just like I,
I can't not support that place.
That place is fantastic.
It's,
it's so important too,
because she brings people up from open
miker to hosting to middling,
to headlining.
Like she has like local headlines.
She farmed.
She has like a foreign team,
a real farm team.
Man.
She's really legit and there's.
There's a community in Denver.
Look,
there's legit professional comics that
work in and around Denver.
She'll have local headliners headline
for the week and they'll pack the place.
Yeah,
she's got a great system man.
I mean she's just,
man,
she's just really put it together and
they're all top quality standups.
Like there's no hacks is no,
there's no bullshit.
She doesn't tolerate thieves or any
bullshit club owners who really curate
and pay attention to their club,
always have the best clubs.
It's just,
you know that that's one of the reasons
the comedy cellar so amazing.
Like see who runs it.
Like sure.
Writes it like she's not like,
even if you get past,
they're like,
that doesn't mean your work in there all
the time.
Like she's,
she's always got an eye on.
Everyone is like,
you,
you have to be consistently good there
to stay,
you know?
And I've seen guys come and go at that
place and that place comes up.
She will drive comic crazy.
Like because they're so
excited to be in and then they like
panic,
you know,
I've seen and then they're like moving
and like every time I come in there like
three tables further away and we can get
into further from the tape and then
there are moods that falafel place next
door.
I'm like,
you're not going to be working there
anymore.
That place,
you know,
drives people.
A little con can drive a little crazy
because you want to succeed there and
you want to be a part of it and you want
to be accepted.
You know,
in my first year or so in that place I
was like that for sure.
You know,
before I was like,
okay,
like um.
Well in the 19 eighties there was a
bunch of communities all over the
country.
San Francisco had a community.
Boston had a big community,
New York,
of course,
in La I've always had communities.
Texas had a community.
It's a big community in Houston is huge.
Austin always had a community.
Austin's got a good scene,
but you know,
there's been a few things that have
happened that are good and bad.
The good thing is like these Improv's
have opened up everywhere and so you,
you get that Improv experience
everywhere you go.
You get these big clubs that are packed.
Everyone super professional that shows
are packed.
Everything's great,
the food's great,
the drinks are great services,
great.
But they don't have that sort of xannies
and Nashville feel.
You know what I mean?
I just zany Chicago to a week ago and
I'm going to Nashville like in the same
sort of love.
One of my xannies Chicago is like,
I just it just because it's like a old
gritty club shots everywhere.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well the head shots are like half the
people are dead,
you know,
you look around and like Richard,
Jenny,
oh this guy,
that guy,
you know,
but those clubs they have like,
there's a more,
there's a more organic sort of a,
what's the word?
Craft beer sort of feel to them.
They feel like more authentic in some
sort of a weird way.
Like,
I love working at the Improv,
don't get me wrong,
but there's something about those
Improv's that like,
Houston used to have like a big scene.
They used to have the laptop stop in
river oaks was a huge scene.
Kennison started out there,
Bill Hicks was there,
all those guys were there,
like Hicks did one of his early dvds at
the laptop and then it became,
the Improv was in town,
the laptop went under,
they moved locations and they went under
and then the Improv opened up and then
it was like a headliner club where,
you know,
Tracy Morgan wanted to be there or this
guy would be there,
but it would always be big name
comedians and that was it.
And so like the local scene sort of
dwindled.
I've heard it's sort of started making a
comeback,
but the windled but the,
uh,
I'm trying to think when you're saying
because I feel like I'm doing.
Oh No,
I'm doing laugh out loud in San Antonio.
So.
Oh,
I haven't been there.
Yeah,
that's what you're touring everywhere
now.
Yeah.
Well,
yeah.
I'm hopefully taping an hour in the
spring.
So yeah,
for who?
Um,
I don't.
I don't know if I'm allowed to say or
not can say an official.
I don't know because it's,
I mean it's,
it's.
Well,
here's what you're saying with,
with,
you know,
how this business works.
Like until I see it on the thing,
you tell him like I don't believe I have
anything until I have it until you sign.
Well yet we're even just like,
once it's like taped and I'm sitting at
home and I go everyone turn on Blah Blah
Blah Blah,
you know,
this business always feels like you're
one head of a network getting fired away
from not having the thing you thought
you're going to have.
So I try
to be very,
not only superstitious but just like,
you know,
but it looks like one way or the other.
Ob tape tape in my era in the spring.
But yeah.
So I'm just down the road.
That's what I mean.
When the nightly show ended,
I was bummed.
I obviously,
I wanted the show to be on for 10 years
or 20 for everybody who worked there,
but personally speaking,
my goal with the nightly show was never
to stay there as the executive producer
forever.
My goal was to launch it and get it
going,
sort of teach everyone how to do it
because it was the daily show model that
we were,
you know,
and I know how to do that very well.
And then my hope was I would just be on
the show and like slowly relinquished my
authority of running it to other people
so I could work from like noon to three
and then just do stand up goal a three
hour,
three hour workday and being on time,
you know.
But uh,
but not my,
that wasn't my goal yet.
My goal was to get the show successful
before I did that.
So when it got canceled I was,
I was pretty bummed and I was pretty
disappointed.
I put a lot of time into it,
but,
you know,
for me it was like,
all right,
well I want to go on the road anyway.
And uh,
and I had my whole fall book so I didn't
really know how I was going to manage
both anyway.
So I was like,
all right,
well there you go.
And I got my real and got my own camera
real.
Which to me is just the thing you need
to say,
w when you're pitching something to
somebody,
they go,
what are you going to be in this?
Have you ever been on TV?
You're like,
yeah,
no,
I got it.
Like you just need proof of your ability
to do it.
And I got that,
you know,
that's the fucked up thing about doing
anything on a network because you have
to get someone to agree.
I agree to use you agree to this,
agree with that.
There's all these people that aren't the
creative people but they have the money
yet and they're the ones that you have
to talk to about it,
you know?
Well,
well we've got this idea.
Oh,
let me see your right there.
Yeah,
I give you a money.
Maybe I should give you the covet at
8:00 PM slot.
Maybe not yet.
I don't know.
Kiss my ass.
But that gatekeeper model is dying,
it's over,
it's over.
And what you need now is a room with a
camera.
I mean it's literally all you need is
the space to fail and whatever you're
filming the,
the budget to afford cameras and the
ability to stream and upload things that
you just need to adjust it.
A little venture capital.
I mean I just did this thing even need a
venture capital.
No,
I mean you just need somebody to give
you like 100 grand unless you have it,
you need a 100 grand to do what?
Well,
I'm just saying,
depending on what you're looking to
shoot,
you know.
Okay.
But I'm saying if you want like a sag
aftra level thing with like good camera
guys.
Like you have a bunch of your friends
and you write it and you use a fucking
camera,
like one of these things that you don't
need any of this feel like this is a
strange time when it comes to that
stuff.
Like there's a lot of people that are
still treating it as if it's like you're
filming some movie.
Well,
their television show,
the big budget.
I also find too like the digital spaces
now or being taken over by the old
guard,
so in other words,
all of a sudden like if you,
if you want to pitch something to like
see,
so it's like,
well it's a branch of NBC.
NBC is NBC,
NBC Business Affairs has to get,
you know,
like,
and you're like,
well now I know I'm right back to where
I started when I don't want to just
pitching this to NBC,
but they're doing a lot of standup
specials and standup specials for guys
like Stan hope and ideas and people that
are.
Who else just did one recently who just.
Someone was just on the head of CSOS.
Fuck,
was it?
God Damn it,
Jamie.
Somebody had one.
Jesus Christ.
I can't remember as too fast.
All right.
Whatever.
There's too many people.
Yeah,
there's a lot of governments there.
They're doing a lot of good standup
comedy specials on CCS.
That's great.
It's great that that exists.
Nick Depaulo.
That's right.
I'm glad I remembered that.
Yeah.
Nick's has just,
just came out on CSO and CSO.
You know,
I mean that's,
it is a branch of NBC,
but they're uncentered and they're doing
great stuff.
You know,
I just think that.
Well,
here's a crazy statistic that I just
read yesterday.
Ready for this.
Netflix takes up one third of the
bandwidth of the United States of
America.
One third one.
All of the Internet bandwidth.
One third of the bandwidth it's being
used in the United States of America is
through Netflix.
Wow.
Holy Shit.
That's insane.
It's so crazy.
With the other third,
like Pornhub,
it's all two thirds corn,
one aboves feet as buzzfeed dead.
Is that the one that got killed by Hulk
Hogan?
Gawker.
Gawker killed by.
I forget which one.
Which one of those salacious sites.
So funny.
Yeah,
well that's it.
I mean it's like those sites,
like tmz is probably like one eighth pmc
man juggernauts almost those little news
stations and you know,
youtube is probably a big chunk to
facebook to people love facebook,
man.
Third Man,
a third one that.
Yeah,
that's nuts.
Like if you looked at a pie of the
Internet,
one third is Netflix.
That's what a lot of it's got to be
because you're streaming video,
another word that that takes up a lot of
bandwidth,
so it's not necessarily that that many
people are using Netflix,
it's just that that the stuff that
they're using on Netflix,
is that thick?
For sure.
It's definitely both.
I mean it's definitely a lot of people,
but it is definitely.
I mean it's growing constantly.
Netflix is a goddamn snowball rolling
down.
It has completely revolutionized and re
re invigorated.
This whole entertainment industry.
I went and met with those guys while I
was out here because I've been out here
for like a month and a book.
You want to talk about the difference of
you take a meeting at like like a viacom
type place versus like a Netflix type.
Like netflix.
It's like they just moved into a new
office building.
Like they're like,
you want a water?
You're like,
sure you go in the back.
It's like,
what kind of water do you want?
They've got like snacks everywhere.
Like people like pogo,
stick it around.
Like everyone's so happy,
you know,
like it's just,
it's like the building is new.
There's like a valet in front.
He's like free of charge.
I'll pocket Carla.
Thank you Mr. Netflix,
like everything about it is so nice.
Everybody's so nice.
Everybody's in a good mood.
You gotta think MTV for a meeting.
They were like,
get us.
Help us
what to do.
Yeah.
They have $9 a month is what it costs.
Right?
And how many millions of people do they
have on Netflix now?
Something that did $93.
Million people today is what I heard on
the way in here.
So 93 million people.
What is that?
Right.
But what does that mathematics close to?
$900 million a month.
It's close to a billion dollars a month.
Yeah,
it's in the neighborhood.
It's closing in on a billion dollars a
month.
That's hilarious.
That's so much money.
Printing money.
I did my first comedy special on Netflix
in 2005.
That was my very first special was on
Netflix.
Getting a comedy special on Netflix now
is near impossible because it's
Chappelle and Chris Rock and,
you know,
I just didn't want it.
Yeah,
but I'm saying,
but you're famous.
But I mean,
um,
I mean I think they're doing some.
I mean they,
they,
they buy some to look if you do want and
then you could sell it to them like they
bought Tony Hinchcliffe slash.
I know,
but now it's.
Now that it's harder now,
now it's a bit harder.
Yeah.
And,
and uh,
once again for me,
I mean,
I think you'd probably have to have a
bigger name.
We'll say here's the trailer for the new
will Smith movie.
Netflix reportedly paid 90 million for
run that shit.
Let's to plant A.
No,
we can't play it.
What'll happen?
They'll kick us off.
Okay.
Good stuff.
But you can watch it well to kick us off
youtube.
Yeah,
because it's their trailer.
They just put it up.
Can I call somebody like,
come on guys,
I want to.
You will try to hook you guys up.
But he has a sword.
That's what I'm trying to hook them up.
That's exciting.
It seems like a movie you'd like Joe.
I like all will smith movies except for
the one where he's the homeless guy with
his son.
I couldn't watch that.
What about the one with the scientology
one?
Whereas with his son.
Who was that one?
What's that one word?
A scientology movie?
Yeah.
Ron Hubbard book.
That one.
No,
no,
no.
It's,
it's like a space.
Him and his son are stuck on a planet
that's l Ron Hubbard.
I think that's it.
That's his.
Remember when John Travolta did a pedal
battleship or
battlefield earth.
And he's like,
take human animals.
So that,
that's also an l Ron Hubbard book.
So this is,
uh,
the,
we're watching this right now.
Will Smith.
It plays a cop in La and there's works.
It's like a futurist.
Oh Wow.
Shit.
This looks dope.
There's got a sword in the future.
There's orcs that's an ORC.
Whoa.
This doesn't end well.
David era directed at the guy that did
suicide squad training.
Oh,
this looks good.
Yeah.
Where is that coming out?
December.
Goddammit it.
Why you make me wait til December.
December is a year from now.
You fucks.
It's Goddamn February.
That's not cool.
This is bullshit.
Yeah.
He said,
well,
Smith said he always.
He was always the genre he liked to do
because those were the.
Oh yeah.
The highest grossing movies.
Every time I am legend.
Legend.
So grateful.
So grateful at anytime.
It's a dude and like a German shepherd
alone.
I'm like,
this is good.
I think they should go over.
I am legend though.
And reduce some of those scenes like the
ones with the lions in New York City.
Like,
come on.
Those lines looks so fucking fake.
Well,
you know,
the CGI wasn't where it needed to.
Now redo it,
Redo it,
and don't tell anybody after earth after
earth.
Sure.
After earth is an l,
Ron Hubbard book is that him and his son
is of the deal.
See Jayden.
Okay.
Find out.
Jaden seems completely insane.
Up Famous Willow Smith saying has a new
song that's out then.
I'm not going to lie.
It's a good time.
Well,
that's not good.
How old is
she?
Oh,
oh,
for sure.
Don't release your kid's music until
they're 21 who wrote the shovel on
flickr and it wasn't good.
I said and wrote,
bye.
Oh,
okay.
Same thing.
So it's both the fucking hookers.
This one.
Here's the twist on this one.
It wasn't good
night.
Shop twist,
watchable.
He made one good movie and then fucked
us all repeatedly.
He can't.
They can't stop giving them movies to me
like you.
How many chances do you get?
How is the new one's supposed to split?
Personality one.
This is supposed to be in a good.
Good.
Pretty good.
Did you see it?
Yeah.
Okay.
What did you see the one with mark?
Mark markets chased by the wind.
I think it was plants that were trying
to kill him.
I thought it was the wind might be of.
That's one of the greatest bad movies
I've ever seen in my life.
It's just,
it's just more Walberg running around.
He's like,
he's like,
yeah,
I get in the fucking house.
You know,
it's the second house.
It looks like a branch closes.
I got a second wind.
You know,
there's a guy in that movie who runs
himself over with his own lawnmower,
it's mowed his lawn and then they cut
away and they looked back and he's under
this.
The wind got them tickets.
So the wind's targeting individuals,
but when wants you to kill yourself,
I think is what it is.
It's unbelievably nature wanted you to
kill yourself.
Right.
There was like a smell that it was
putting out or something like that.
I don't know.
All I know is there's a scene where he's
running in a field and he's panicking
and the only thing that's happening is
grasses.
If nature to.
Have you ever seen some of those giant
storm clouds?
They photograph over the Kansas
Cornfield and shit that are as big as
cities and these like,
why wouldn't nature just do that thing
that it already does?
Why does it have to do some targets?
Lawnmowers makes them run over asshole.
Like people are always trying to find
some new hook,
like the village or these people,
they think that it's 16,
12,
but it's really 2015 and they're living
in the middle of a place where they're
not allowed to fly planes.
They can't fly planes over this area.
There's a no fly zone works.
How big is this fucking no fly zone
because I don't know if you know this,
but planes fly everywhere.
You can't.
Even if they're outside the zone,
you probably still here one.
But here's the stupid thing.
They walk in a,
in a short amount of time.
They're at a road and then cars drive
by.
Remember that?
Alright.
I don't think I ever saw the village and
you should say it.
I was fucking terrible.
I was taking a break from [inaudible]
for awhile and it took a little shy,
a little shovel on hiatus.
But he did devil the one about a haunted
elevator.
No,
she did that.
Yeah,
it was him.
Yeah.
He can't stop haunted.
Elevated the health insurance.
I mean,
you know what you should do if,
if,
uh,
Jordan peals horror movies supposed to
be incredible.
I haven't seen it yet.
Yeah.
I feel like I tried doing a comedy,
you know what I mean?
Why not mix it up,
try taking a nap break,
take a break.
He made one good movie that's six slash
movie was good though.
That's good movie.
But often that happens with people like
how
many bands have come out with one great
album and then they follow up is dog
shit most statistically I would say most
bands,
comedians do the same thing.
Some comics have one great special and
then they like,
I always put a nut.
I'm a huge tennis fan,
but I always pointed out to him he's the
best example of a guy who came out of
the gate,
like with the greatest of all time or
one of the greatest of all time.
I think priors the greatest of all time.
But kennison is right up there like
number two.
It's funny because people don't bring
him up in those conversations enough.
Yeah.
I'm saying when you have the WHO's the
best conversation about standup kinisons
name isn't even like,
yeah,
they go with Carlin and all due respect.
I just don't think they're comparable.
Carlin was a great comic and his body of
work is fantastic and he just did a new
hour every year for decades and.
But he had a lot of duds,
you know,
in the later.
The later years were tough.
I'm a big fan of his later specials were
a lot less.
He was a lot less charming and he was
doing a lot more like we're all going to
die.
You are.
Yeah,
we definitely do it.
You,
you're older and have been watching you
for years and it doesn't look up,
but I love but I love to.
I mean it jamming in New York to me is
one of the best hours of.
Oh yeah,
no,
he's got fantastic work.
Don't get me wrong,
but it's not as funny as kinesis.
Best work.
Kinisons best work.
When he was doing like that bit about
the homosexual necrophilia acts are
paying money to spend a few hours of
undisturbed,
but the freshest male corpses
is.
Imagine that you're lying down.
You're like,
wow,
I'm dead now.
I'm gonna.
Go meet cheeses and hey,
what the fuck is it feels like some
guy's got his dick in my ass.
I need life keeps fucking even after
your dad
who is fat and like,
like the whole thing about him was like,
you were an overcoat and he had a baret
with a comb over.
He was just.
The whole thing was chaos.
He was just,
it was.
He was actually think jamming in New
York is dedicated to Sam Kennison.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well he was.
I mean look Carlin's and all time.
Great.
Don't get me wrong.
I mean if he,
if there's a top 10,
he's in there,
but I really think these days,
birds up there to his special.
His,
his,
his recent specialist have been.
He's doing stuff in some of his
specials,
but I'm like,
I can't even believe you can do that.
Like it was all the same way.
He doesn't think about hitting women and
you're like,
how is he going to stick this landing?
It's like 2,500 people pull back.
He goes,
I feel you're pulling away and you're
like,
Holy Shit.
What?
I love the one who does about Arnold
sports that.
Yeah,
that's a nice man.
He's a great man.
Gold digging whores tucked out a great
man.
It's the same.
It's the same hour,
the same hour.
Yeah.
It's,
yeah,
there's a lot of great comedy going on
right now.
For sure.
Yeah,
it's a fun time.
It is a fun time.
Oh,
you live in New York?
Yeah,
I'm living there.
I mean,
I've been out here for a month.
I,
I got cast in this little,
like digital series thing.
What's a digital series like?
What is it like a 10 episode,
little Saifai comedy thing that I got
cast and then I didn't even audition
for.
I think they just saw my nightly show
reel and they're like,
we need someone to play a Douchey guy in
like
a Psi Phi.
It's like a weird Saifai called,
uh,
it's called stellar people.
It's like a dinner,
I mean it's like a dinner.
I've just finished it.
It was really fun though because I've
never done single camera acting before,
which is a different.
A lot of work,
but it's a lot of like there's a dude
five inches from your face and they're
like,
don't look at them and look,
but I want to.
It's right in my face.
I'm not professionally trained.
They'll like,
look over there.
I'm like,
put your right to the Lens.
So close as long as to ours because it
was super low budget,
but it was a sad thing and it was.
Yeah,
we were shooting like 11 pages a day
like it was,
but the dudes shooting it were so sharp.
They were so good and they were young.
They were.
I didn't realize until the wrap party
how young they were.
We were at the wrap party the other
night.
I'm like,
how long you guys been doing this?
They're like,
oh,
we got a feature coming out.
I'm like,
oh,
cool.
How old are you guys?
Twenty six.
I was like,
Shit.
And it kind of made me.
I was inspired.
I was like,
couldn't you guys just be with me all
the time because 26 and you're funny and
you're talented and you know how to
shoot and edit and everything they shoot
looks good.
Well,
and there's still 10 years ago they were
in high school,
so like 10 years ago this whole thing
was kicking off,
you know,
10 years ago you look into 2007.
That was really the launch of the
digital space,
you know,
like I said,
my netflix specials in 2005.
Nobody had netflix in 2005 and it was
looked at as like a joke and that's sort
of where at 2006,
2007 things start ramping up.
And then digital became more and more of
a big deal.
I remember people there was um,
NBC had a different thing before cso
that they were doing.
God dammit.
What was the name of it?
There was another name.
We had actually a deal with them.
Burley bear was what?
That was like a college thing they had
years ago.
No,
no,
it was a crackle,
crackle still around,
isn't it?
Is it.
I will if it's NBC anymore,
sometimes I see crackle come up on
thanks.
Oh,
I dunno.
Maybe,
maybe I'm wrong,
but when we had a deal with them,
but a bunch of shit fell through and
they want to just give me money for
nothing.
That's good.
Nothing.
Yeah,
nothing.
It was one of those weird things where
like nothing happened but.
But you got paid.
He gave me money.
I'm like,
okay,
that's pretty cool.
All right.
I could go for one of those.
Critical if you're.
If you're out there.
Yeah.
It was like an interview show we were
going to do.
It was like similar to like a podcast,
but like in a weird location just
sitting down with people,
which by the way is not the best move.
The best move is have like a place like
this where it's quiet and you just sit
down and talk,
but everybody wants to like how about we
do it in a park when people feel weird
in to park and there's birds chirping
and
fucking drive by in the background.
Sirens,
joggers and shit dog.
I remember I did a show with Neil
Brennan for Sundance a couple of years
ago and uh,
they had never done a show like it was
a,
it was a studio show,
but they wanted to shoot it in a loft,
you know,
and I was like,
well,
we could get a studio and then make it
look like a loft and that way it sound
proof,
you know what I'm saying?
They're like,
well,
we really want it to feel like a lot
firm.
Like,
you know,
the friends,
they weren't really in a loft,
right?
That was like,
no,
no.
I saw it.
They were
so desperate for like it to feel and I
was like,
you're going to have the loudest,
most unsuitable show if you go find a
loft in Soho,
you could just wire it with lights.
So we ended up getting a studio,
but it's like that.
That's a bad instinct doing stuff
outside of a professional area.
Someone said to me,
let's do a podcast at starbucks.
How about you just know and.
No,
but we just get starbucks.
I go to a studio,
why would you want to go to starbucks?
So you want to take the chance and
people next to you having arguments with
their agent on the phone or screaming at
their dog walker or whatever.
If you can't find fluffy like that,
that's all going to be on your podcast.
Is that cool?
Like you don't have the best
conversations in public places like
that.
That's not a good move,
but everybody wants to do something
crafty and creative and different,
you know?
Yeah.
I mean I always think I find that too is
like with standups.
A lot of times younger stand ups will
say like,
I'm really trying to be outside the box.
I'm like,
get a buck first.
Have a fucking box.
You need a box first.
You know,
like,
like Jackson pollock knew how to paint
the bowl of fruit.
You know what I mean?
Like go.
I think he did.
I don't know,
like in other words,
you got to start with some sort of basic
skillset before.
Like now it's like start a podcast.
You hit a sore spot with me,
buddy.
Really?
You're not as Jackson pollock fan?
Nope.
Yeah.
I'm not saying it.
I'm not saying I'm a fan of his.
I'm just saying he was a painter before
he started splattering shit.
Well,
I watched that movie,
the Ed Harris Movie,
and I was like,
okay,
well this,
there's nothing exceptional here going
on.
Like this guy's throwing paint around
and I'm watching a movie about a guy
throwing paint around and it's got some
trials and tribulations.
I,
yeah,
I get it,
but I'm not.
I mean it's not the worst looking art.
It's kind of cool to have like in the
lobby of a hotel or something.
I'm not a fan of it personally.
I like community by like if you bought a
Jackson pollock,
you're spending hundreds of thousands of
dollars,
millions of dollars.
That would be millions,
millions,
millions first.
If I know the artist's name,
it has to be worth millions of dollars.
Okay,
here we go.
Here we go.
I'll fuck you.
Fuck you.
For every one of these,
if you have to pay a million dollars for
every one of these,
click,
click on that one.
Where your cursor is right there at
Jamie.
Fuck you.
This is chaos.
You could go to the Jackson pollock
house.
It's out in east Hampton.
And uh,
my nephews went,
the Jackson pollock house,
the house he painted and it's like,
it's like a museum now,
but for little kids you can paint the
Jackson pollock and my nephew and my
nephew did one and it looks exactly
like,
probably looks better than he was five.
And he did it.
I went to my old agents house.
My old agent had this beautiful house in
Aspen and he had this thing on his wall
and I go,
is this something your kid did?
And someone goes,
no,
that's a world war.
I go,
what?
What are you talking about?
And they're like,
do you know anything about modern art?
I go,
no,
and I go,
what is this?
And the guy explained it to me that that
was probably like a $35,000 painting.
I go,
get the fuck out of here.
I mean it was literally like 12 by 14.
It looks like a little kids first grade
class project.
So I thought like,
oh this is cute.
He puts up his kids artwork.
It's like in a nice frame.
Yeah.
It was like some tissue paper that was
glued to some other paper and some paint
splattered
on it.
Like,
yeah,
moderate.
Let's look more of that.
Just fascinating to me.
And people get so upset if you don't
like what they like.
Like if I've talked about Jackson
pollock before and you get these Jackson
pollock fans and believers and they're
like,
you don't understand this.
The layers of paint and the way his
vision was manifested on to canvas
sounds,
it sounds like the aliens from galaxy
quest,
that's actually kind of cool.
I'll give him 500 bucks for that.
Yeah,
I mean again,
I'm not a fan of it but I try as hard as
I can with stuff too.
Especially now to go like,
you know what that looks like.
But like what they like,
I don't know.
When the dude goes to the hospital and
they find that he has like intestinal
worms and they pull them all out onto
the operating table.
That's what it looks like.
Those are like white intestine warm data
is actually a cool painting.
Now.
I'm trying to change my opinion here
because that one is actually kinda cool.
What about that one up above it?
That green one?
What does that one to the right?
No,
right above it.
Yeah.
That looks like it.
What is that?
That's Jackson pollock to.
I'd be pissed people like what is that?
It's a pollock.
No,
it's not.
So even splattery we've done.
No,
no it is,
but that one looks like he was splatting
something.
Yeah.
That was like that one I liked was on
different pills.
Alien.
Look at him.
Weird looking guy.
He's so weird looking guy to betty.
She will.
She Wolf.
That's what it's called.
Is that a wolf?
I guess there's teeth and the tongue
down the lower left hand corner.
I bet he banged a lot of confused older
ladies with money.
The older.
Yeah.
I feel like.
Yeah,
probably.
I think younger.
Two younger two.
I think there was like a lot of 50 year
old hot ladies that would by his
paintings.
He would fuck them in the.
But that's what I think happened.
He may have done some 50 year old,
but fucking
was that in the movie?
I didn't watch the movie.
No,
but it was like,
I'm not going to do any of the bud
fucking look at that $140,000,000.
I told you the intestinal worms.
One hundred and 40.
How much is she wolf?
How much does she will go for?
He made that in 1948.
Wow.
Holy Shit.
It doesn't say wow.
What year is that?
She will 43.
Jesus Christ.
That is really interesting though,
because back then you know like this,
you're talking about a completely
different time.
This is World War II.
Yet to think about like dudes are like
jumping out of planes in,
in Germany and he's like splatter
painting in the Hamptons,
you know,
making cash and banging war widows.
Now he's banging divorcees of heads of
industry now.
Like the,
the amount of money that you would have
to have to spend $140 million dollars on
some splattery paint.
Yeah.
You have to have netflix money.
A billion a month.
The netflix executive.
The head guys probably putting one up
right now at his house in Brentwood.
I think he's putting it up for him,
for his painting hanger is putting
enough.
Get painting hangers for sure.
Yeah,
definitely.
He's probably
got white maids.
No,
that's money.
It's real money.
Real.
You must.
You must get a lot of you must you say
things.
I feel like why I like you so much is
you are not a partisan person.
You do the thing I tried to do with
politics and everyone thinks because of
the daily show,
I'm very left.
I get accused of being all right lately.
Yeah.
But it's like.
But it's like it's just having an
opinion is like.
So I always try to have an opinion per
issue almost.
I really got confused when this country
went to a place where you have to be all
in,
on either side.
I,
I feel like most people aren't,
you know,
like some people are pro choice and also
okay with guns like well it's just the
people that are pro one way or the other
way or very laughed the loudest.
There's a lot of us that are just
scattered across the board.
Yeah,
just like,
I dunno,
like there's some things that are
reasonable and some things are
unreasonable,
but you are one of those people who sort
of.
I find this on the road a lot now,
like if I'm making fun of like in my
hour and I've really tried to structure
my hour that I,
I hit everybody in and like it's like
it's like hit both sides and then like
some Dick Jokes,
you know what I mean,
like wrap up and Dick Jokes and uh,
but when I hit the left people on the
right and then the minute I'm like,
all right,
now let's talk about you guys
within 12 seconds,
within 12 seconds of love this guy love
this guy,
love this guy.
I hate this guy.
He now.
And it's the same thing that's happened
with,
like I said,
Fox News.
It's like Dave said,
something I disagree with.
I can no longer watch that person.
And it's,
it's a weird time to be doing comedy for
that reason.
It's a great time to be doing.
Comedy is so much chaos because you can
point all that nonsense out.
Yeah.
I think it's going to San Antonio in two
weeks and I'm like,
it's going to be fun,
but there's definitely like a chunk of
my act and I'm like,
there's got to be to cut heads.
Like there's a guy on stage talking
about Jesus,
like I don't like it and I wouldn't be
like,
I gotta go.
I gotta go out the back door.
Your last name?
Yeah,
because I'm A.
I'm half.
I'm a half breed.
Is that a.
is the last name?
Albany's is a town.
Yeah.
My Dad's so Roman Catholic.
Italian.
They should be cool with it.
Yeah,
but I talked about being a Jew.
Put your mom was Jewish so that you were
raised Jewish because you really don't
know the mother.
Yeah.
And therefore it was chosen by God,
you know?
That's how it always is.
Yeah.
It was one of the best people.
He chose us.
Yeah.
Nice.
Yeah,
it was pretty cool.
It's pretty funky.
Converted and his name is Salvatore
Digerlando and he converted to do Judy
Judaism.
Yeah.
Why?
Why did he do that?
Married a woman who was,
as you fell in love with a nice Jewish
lady and he wanted to come in.
You gotta got to go in.
My Dad just converted.
Converted,
converted at 68.
To your mom?
Yeah.
To,
to Judaism.
Well,
your mom's religion with your mom or
with my.
No,
no,
no.
With my mom.
But he'd never.
But he never went in.
No until now.
Until now.
Wow.
He's getting close.
He's like better hedge.
My Bet.
You never know.
Might really be the chosen people.
I got to the fucking big gates papers.
I was living with one for 50 years.
That's exactly what that,
that is.
And you know that they did.
They do a,
I want to talk about it,
but they do like a.
They give you a little poke in the penis
to like they got draw blood from your
penis to Jesus fucking told me that.
I was like,
no,
we're going on with people.
Ticks cutting decks and make digs,
bleeding,
cut and baby dicks and shit.
Circumcisions is weird.
It feels like the kind of thing you
should have a say in,
you know,
like you should go,
you should get on the phone,
you know,
you can't,
you can't.
It's just they just take this thing that
you needed or away and they don't even.
Well,
not only that,
it's being done now for purely aesthetic
reasons and people say something about
aids.
Bowls of [inaudible] crucis was fuck
you.
It does.
It does not.
That's not true.
It's absolutely a lie and that's just
some nonsense that people have said to
make up for the fact that it's still
this horrific fucking practice and by
the way is probably money in it.
Believe it or not,
there's probably a significant business
and cut and baby dicks,
so they're probably trying to protect
that significant business and also
trying to justify the baby.
Dick's,
they've cut in the past,
so if they have three sons and they've
cut all the sons Dicks,
they're like,
well,
it's really important to prevent aids.
Let me tell you something.
If you're going to get aids,
you're not going to get it from having a
dirty for skin.
Okay?
Okay.
We're good.
Yeah.
Fuck you.
There's no,
no one's getting aids from dirty forest.
I don't know anything about the disease
is,
but I do know that uh,
just as a guy who wears button flies,
it would be nice to have one more layer
protecting my penis from just smacking
around my jeans.
Don't wear underwear.
You weirdo.
Yeah.
Well I do wear underwear,
but it doesn't matter about me undies
some time with me undies,
man.
Love them.
Yeah.
Pull up tight to your package suite
place.
I'll take a look at maybe with micromole
doll.
Got this fresh.
I got this pair of boxers from the thing
we were doing because there was a scene
where my dick gets pulled off in this
show,
gets pulled off of a robotic penis.
I don't want to spoil it,
but already put the,
put the.
I don't know if anyone's going to see
it,
so it's okay.
But uh,
but they gave me a pair of underwear so
I didn't have to wreck my own underwear
and it.
And it was the most comfortable
underwear ever wore.
I was like,
this is amazing.
And then my girlfriend came out to visit
me,
she sends me a text and she goes,
why is there a pair of ladies' underwear
in your suitcase?
And I was like,
there is,
and it turns out this underwear that I
thought was the best underwear,
it's like ladies underwear.
And I was like,
I was at belt to buy like 50 pairs of
it.
Who Decides?
I mean,
I don't know,
but I'm on it.
Like it just felt because they were like
this,
like,
um,
I guess they're like a leggings
material,
I don't know,
but it just made my penis like float.
Like it was like in limbo.
Like it was like it was in Jello.
It was very nice.
And are they designed for a vagina and
not for a penis?
I don't know.
All I know is I wore them and I was
like,
I got to get more of these.
And then she was,
she was like my girlfriend.
No,
she didn't get mad first.
Just thought I was cheating on her.
And then she's like,
this is the ladies line at target,
you know,
it was,
oh,
well there you go.
Now I know where to get it.
That's what I said.
I'm like,
cool.
Go pick me up.
Six pairs.
Yeah.
There's certain things that are like,
uh,
they don't have a gender associated like
tube socks.
Yeah,
right.
Unless you have like the little palm
palm and the back of the heel.
Yeah.
That's the only way,
you know,
like little ankle socks for a while.
Ankle socks were only chicks.
Only chicks were ankles.
So you're right.
Doozy and wear ankle socks in the
eighties and nineties.
That was a chick thing.
It was this little tiny socks.
Yeah.
And then,
uh,
yeah.
Now it feels weird to wear shorts with
socks.
Doesn't.
To me it does.
It feels weird.
Line.
I don't know,
I just don't like the way it looks.
It just feels very.
Like I wear socks that they're not
totally ankle socks and people mock my
socks.
Like these socks.
I check these out.
See they go above the ankle.
Like what are you doing?
I see an extra inch,
but will you wear those shorts?
Do you know what?
I don't give a shit.
I'm married and wear a fanny pack.
Yeah,
that's true.
I'm almost 50.
I don't give a fuck.
Yeah,
yeah.
What's going to happen to me?
Nothing's gonna like me less because you
don't like good.
I,
I'm trying to cut people out of my life.
If you have a problem with me because of
my socks.
My socks are an interesting that I have
to talk to fuck off with your shitty
ideas.
There's just too many people with just
like weird,
rigid ideas about what people should and
shouldn't do in this life.
I mean,
and it's,
it's,
it's constant.
You're constantly being told like that.
We don't say that anymore.
I'm like,
when did that happen?
You know,
I can't keep.
That's my biggest problem is I can't
keep up.
What was the latest one people told you
not to say anymore?
Well,
uh,
Eskimo,
but that's not true.
See in certain parts of the country and
the world,
Eskimo is what they prefer.
Okay.
See,
I believe in you.
It is in certain parts of the world they
prefer.
But ask him,
oh,
is what they prefer.
And other parts of the world,
like people that say that Eskimos the
slur,
that is not always true.
You might decide it's true for your
area.
Steve Rinella was explaining this to me.
I believe in Canada.
Eskimo is the correct term,
but in Alaska they prefer to see if
that's correct.
Jamie.
Make sure we get that right.
But that's just people deciding that.
That's what I mean.
Like I didn't,
I've never,
you know,
trying to be disrespectful to you.
It's our Eskimos,
you know,
it's just a problem when you decide all
of a sudden that something's
disrespectful after people have been
using like language is supposed to
always convey intent.
That's it.
That's how it's supposed to be about.
So when you just make these hot button
words,
you know,
we're not talking about like,
like,
like japs,
the japs that was a derogatory term used
in world war two and people throw it
around wildly and they didn't realize
it's pretty offensive and that makes
sense.
Like,
oh,
okay,
I get it.
This is a term from World War II that
was used like geeks.
It was an interim.
It makes sense.
Yes,
yes,
all those things make sense,
but when you get to things that don't
like,
there's certain expressions that don't
make sense.
Like how the fuck is it still the
National Association for the advancement
of colored people.
I know,
yeah.
Come on,
I talk about that.
It's,
it's tough to give a donation to that.
In Canada,
the term Eskimo has largely been
supplanted by the term in Hewitt while
in you it can accurately be applied to
Eskimo peoples in Canada and Greenland
is not true in Alaska and Siberia and
Alaska Determined X.
Eskimo is commonly used because it
includes both.
You pick an inupiat,
so okay.
In Alaska in youit is not accepted as a
collective term and is not used,
especially in Japan,
so.
Okay,
so in Canada you're supposed to use the
term nun.
In Alaska,
you can still use the term Eskimo and
they want you to use it because it does
not refer to a certain type of a native
person that lives up there.
Those are fucking.
Those are the real natives,
man.
I mean,
if you really think about it,
those are the people that not only did
they cross the bering strait but they
fucking stayed in the cold spot.
Yeah,
[inaudible].
They got there and they're like,
yeah,
this is good.
What's interesting is how do you not
keep traveling?
Those people don't have any access to
vegetables and yet they lived almost
entirely free of cancer until we started
importing cigarettes and booze up there
that I did not know.
They had an incredibly low instances of
cancer and what they're basically living
off his fat.
They're living off seal fat and they
would take seals and they would take
frozen fish and they would dip frozen
fish in hot seal oil and eat the frozen
fish.
So they take a frozen fish and they
would slice like,
almost like Carpaccio thin pieces of
this frozen fish.
Then dip it and seal oil.
And that's how they to this day
facilitate.
Well,
it's not a fondue.
It's like a,
you know,
like,
uh,
I don't know.
I could shabu shabu shabu shabu ever.
It's like a Japanese thing where you
take meat and dip it in thinly sliced
meat it on oil or something like that,
something along those lines,
but but somehow or another that diet is
really good for you,
which is really strange.
Like I would think you'd have to have
some fucking vegetables in your life.
Yeah,
but it can't be good for your heart if
you're eating a lot of seal,
seal fat,
so that's where you're wrong.
See,
that's a common misconception and it's
one of the things we've addressed ad
nauseum on the show,
unfortunately,
but I'll get to see the short short
version of fat versus carbohydrates.
In the 19 fifties,
the sugar industry paid scientists to
write about saturated fat and to blame
saturated fat for heart disease and
heart attacks.
That's not the case at all.
It's a lie and it was all created by the
sugar industry to take the blame away
from sugar,
sugar,
processed sugar,
and simple carbohydrates like breads and
pastas and all the things.
Those things are terrible for you and
that's where you get your fat.
That's where you get fat bodies.
That's where people develop like
hardening of the arteries and fucking
clog this and that and all as long with
genetics and a lot of other things but
were saturated fats become dangerous is
when you mix saturated fats with sugars,
saturated fats and sugars together
somehow or another accentuate like you
know,
like fried foods and sugary foods like
sugary drinks like and fried chicken and
fried deep fried fatty things.
That's where things get really dangerous
apparently,
and this is like a a recent study that
connected saturated fat mixed with
simple sugars and processed sugars as
being especially dangerous,
but on their own.
Saturated fats are the precursors for
hormones and in fact a diet high in
saturated fats and cholesterol actually
raises your hormone levels and it's
healthier for your body.
Not only that,
saturated fat and dietary cholesterol in
particular food you eat,
cholesterol from food doesn't raise your
blood cholesterol at all.
It barely moves the needle on blood
lipids.
It's all super confusing because we grew
up with this idea that when you eat
cholesterol,
you get high cholesterol.
It's not the case in factoring.
In fact,
there's a lot of evidence that way where
you're really getting this bad,
uh,
extra fat and your body is from,
from process sugars.
Yeah.
Because your body can't get rid of it.
Everybody's not net.
It's not.
You're not supposed to ever be able to
take a spoonful of sugar and shove it in
your mouth.
It's doesn't exist in a Mary poppins.
Do that dirty bitch,
bitch.
Take the spoon full of sugar.
I'm going to say no.
No,
that's great.
Yeah.
I don't know that much about nutrition
fell,
but it's an here man.
I just say Mexican food.
Well,
that's a good move.
I'll take you to.
I wish we had some time.
I take.
There's a legit Jamie,
I gotta to take you to this place right
down the street.
The most legit Mexican place you'll ever
find.
They're playing Mexican TV with soccer.
They have tongue and uh,
Cabeza.
They have head Tacos.
Shouldn't make it to a dude.
I'm telling you,
this place is the bomb.
I had a,
um,
a tongue case idea,
language,
case,
idea.
It was fucking fantastic.
Really.
I don't know if I'd eat it.
So everyone's speaking Spanish,
they barely understand you when you're
ordering.
If you try to order in English.
God Damn.
It's good though.
It's legit as fuck.
This little strip mall area.
Don't.
Don't give the address.
I don't want trump to take him out.
I know man.
There's not a legal person that joined.
I went down with my family the other day
and I was like,
baby.
Then a legal person that have your
license at the ready.
Bring a passport when you go.
I really do think food is the key to
making people like each other.
I really do.
If that's the case,
why are people kicking out Mexico?
That's what I'm saying.
Like I,
I keep wanting to send like the west
coast.
I was in Arizona doing shows,
food,
Mexican food down there was so good and
I wanted to just send like a little case
of Dhea triangle to trump with a note,
you know like,
are you sure?
You know like take a nibble dude because
it got so hot.
Cold bowls they made.
You ever see that picture of with the
Taco Bowl.
I love Hispanics and I was like,
what?
So weird.
Yeah.
No,
but I feel that's how I feel about.
That's why I think New York,
we've got so many different cultures.
They were at so many different foods
that you like always eating.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I don't get rid of those people that
this is the best falafels in town.
I know there's certain spots where you
can go.
There's the best trucks.
Authentic.
Like it's like you said,
like anytime you go into a place that
has that race of people in it,
eating there,
I'm like,
Oh,
I've chosen wisely.
There's a good Indian food.
Everyone said there's an Indian place
that I go to as well that is in like an
Indian supermarket.
It's an Indian supermarket that has all
these bizarre smells.
You go in as a weird curry,
smells and shit and then in the back
they have like a cafeteria and
everything was an Indian.
Like I didn't know what the fuck they
had.
So the lady was very patient with me and
talked me through all this stuff.
Everything is vegetarian and everything
is all in Indian and it was fucking
fantastic and everybody came in in full
Indian garb like you would think you
were in India,
you know,
it was really weird.
They were all dressed like they lived in
India and just me like looking at me and
he got in one of those big musical
numbers.
No,
but they had the music plan.
They did have Indian,
like legit Indian music plan.
That's awesome.
He ain't gonna find these little spots
and where you can get like real
authentic food from people that you
know,
came from there and say,
look,
this is what we miss.
So we're going to set up shop here and
just make it a little India,
you know?
Yep.
I like that.
That's why I like living in a city.
You.
Oh,
there's some good spots in la too.
There's a great little.
You ever been to little Vietnam.
There's a little,
a little Vietnamese area that has some
fucking awesome little Vietnamese
restaurants and that's.
I always find it fascinating how people
pull pool up in groups.
You know,
they get together and,
and then they all sort of buy property
or rent property in this one,
but is it zone?
I never like to me like China town in
New York.
I always felt like zoned.
I don't think it is because he can
happen organically like that,
but all the Chinese people over here
like a little Italy.
I,
I always assumed so,
I mean I,
I guess I could read about it and the
upper east side is like,
was no,
they're like put some Jews uptown.
Um,
but uh,
yeah,
I mean I think that,
you know,
it's always,
it's always a weird thing to me to like
put that cities have that and it was,
it still feels weird.
It feels antiquated,
but at the same time like Chinatown in
New York,
it was fantastic.
Yeah.
Like you go down there looks great.
Restaurants,
there's like little alleyways,
you can track it down,
you can get different cuts.
The only sort of food resources you
could get in China.
Like you know,
like you said,
soup markets that have.
You've never seen anything in store
before because you're not from China.
Bucket of dried fish heads.
What the fuck is this big barrels of
things and you're like,
what is,
what is that guy scooping out of that
barrel and why is it moving?
You know what I like?
I like those restaurants where they
reluctantly,
right?
The name below the Chinese name,
they reluctantly write something in
English,
you know,
half moon villa above it is.
He's picking it up.
Please let her know we're not gonna.
We're not going for spelling for a half
to right here.
You know,
there's places where you have to um,
like in,
in Quebec and come back.
You have to write in French like you
have,
you have to have laws.
We have to write things in French.
Gotcha.
You can't just do it.
You can't go.
I don't think you can.
I don't think it's allowed.
I think Rebecca is,
they're very,
they're,
they're clinging strong to their French
heritage,
which I completely understand because
they,
they mean they have a long history of
French speaking people living in Quebec.
Yeah.
No,
it's a really unusual part of Canada.
And a lot of people don't understand.
You think of Canadians like,
uh,
you take off a little,
Eh,
what is this about?
You know,
that's not Montreal.
Montreal is very much like a European
city.
It's really interesting in that regard.
Yeah.
Canada,
I like Canada.
I've never had a bad experience in
Canada doing shows or I feel like the
people up there or there,
I,
you know,
it feels like it's like,
I don't want to.
This isn't diminishing Canada,
but there's like a component of it's
like America.
But like people would just seem like
friendlier.
Like I think about that with Chicago.
Like I just did gigs in Chicago and it's
like chicken.
I was like New York,
it's like this big dirty,
smelly city.
But everyone there is nice because
they're from the mid,
like they're just nicer pa.
It's interesting like there they're
friendly and they and they like say hi
to you.
And we went over this on a recent
podcast that Canon has.
So few people.
There's actually 36 million people in
Canada.
Thirty 9 million people in California.
Jesus,
clearly entire country of Canada has
less people than just the state will.
Australia has a but like $25 million
people and it's as big as the
continental United States,
but a lot of it's uninhabitable though.
Was challenged.
Dangerous as fuck my friends go to Adam
Green trees.
Uh,
my friend Adam Green tree on instagram.
Adam.green.
Tree bowhunting.
I think it is a fucking snake to
Australia.
So dangerous.
He lives into Australia there.
Always trying to get me to go there.
A fucking snake literally ate a snake.
It's own size and he had it and couldn't
swallow it and died because of this.
So look,
this is a snake crawling out of a snake.
It's own size.
See that snake's mouth shit?
Yeah.
So a fucking snake ate a snake.
It's own size.
And he filmed the one snake that tried
to eat it dying.
And then the other one wiggles out of
its fucking body.
Whoa.
Like what in the hell,
man?
I mean that is the craziest Shit I've
ever seen in my life.
You want to talk about a hard scrabble
world when he first put it up,
I thought,
oh,
is that a skin thought?
It was.
No.
That's a full ass fucking snake at
eight.
Another snake that is essentially the
same size as it.
That's insane.
If someone pulling it out or how.
I think it's.
I think it's just coming out.
Yeah.
Died.
Trying to eat it.
It's this one.
Is the other one dead though?
No.
The other one's pulling.
I.
I don't.
I can't tell if someone's pulling it
out.
I don't think it is.
It might be.
That's crazy.
I've never been to Australia.
Oh,
there it is.
There's another is another picture of
it.
See,
there it is right there.
The stuff of nightmares.
I killed a snake in the yard gate this
morning and as it died,
a snake came out of it's mouth.
Let me repeat.
A snake came out its mouth.
Holy Shit.
Have you never been to Australia?
Oh yeah.
I've been a few times.
I love it.
There.
Australia is awesome.
It really is.
All the deadliest stuff in the world.
Is there even a way like their shells on
the beach and like,
Eh,
they don't pick up those shells,
you know,
like there's always a little bit you'll
come out there and kill ya if that Sam
gets underneath your skin,
it'll kill you.
My,
yeah,
that's all it is.
All date yet,
you know,
like you did like,
it's crazy.
But they have just.
Schools have these jellyfish.
They'll just murder you instantly just
touching you.
You're dead.
You're dead jellyfish.
It's crazy for like in the springtime,
people open up their barbecues or
whatever.
There's always like black widow spiders,
shit.
And um,
and like,
you know,
spiders that can kill you.
Here's another one.
There's a video.
Look up a spider killing a brown snake
because it's evil snake the brown snake
in Australia.
Again,
by two you're dead.
Dead is fine.
And then the spider kills the fucking
snake.
Like an evil spider snake.
It's like what is going on in that part
of the world?
And what's really fascinating about that
part of the world is they didn't really
have animals there other than like
Kangaroos and wallabies and shit.
There's a lot of the animals that they
have there were important.
Well they are also one of those
countries that did that thing where they
were being overrun by a certain plant
and then they put like rabbits out there
to eat the plant and then the rabbits
went,
went rampant.
Fox is to get the rabbit and the Fox is
fucked them up in different cat cats.
Like the,
they tried to fix shit,
you know,
and they made a disaster out.
Did you hear about the uh,
the thing in the Galapagos Islands with
the goats?
Goats?
Yeah.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
yeah.
It's the same kind of thing.
Exactly.
Try to like manipulate the environment,
the environment.
Like there it is.
So this fucking spider is closing in on
this evil snake and that that's how
crazy or spider webs that you caught it.
You can't even see the web and it's so
strong that it's containing this snake.
I mean I just got him by the head too,
like he knows how to contain it.
Oh yeah.
He's moving in on him.
He's like closer,
closer.
Who I'm trying to eat you.
Alright.
What's that?
I can't show this video on youtube.
Oh,
okay.
Don't worry.
Yeah.
All our nature videos when every time we
try to show a nature video,
we get yanked off youtube.
But for the people want to watch it
because people have rights.
They own it.
They own the video and they want all the
hits and I get it.
So what is the name of the video
people can.
This one actually got one version?
I tried to find it got taken down off
youtube.
It said for breaking youtube guidelines
for a graphic content.
Well,
what does it say?
Redback spider attacks that again?
Yeah.
Redback spider attacks and kills Brown
snake.
I just typed in Brown,
spider kills Brown snakes.
I,
uh,
I had that happen to me with my nightly
show.
Gets canceled.
Like quickly cut my real and my best
stuff.
Stuff.
I put it on Youtube.
I'm like,
Eh,
whatever.
People,
maybe it'll live there.
People will see it.
An hour later,
Viacom flight.
I was like,
you guys are such assholes.
Just cancel the show.
I can't even have it under youtube,
vimeo.
And then through my,
uh,
other than through my website,
like it's,
it's funny how quick they are though,
a new contact Viacom's since you were an
employee and get permission,
I don't know,
I mean you to go through proper
channels.
It just seemed like a lot of,
a lot of work.
I get it though because this is the
wild,
wild west.
I mean we have a lot of websites that
are taking our clips from this podcast
and they put it up and then they put
advertises on it and then they make
money.
They're making money off it.
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
it's really weird right now because
they're trying to figure out what's
legal and what's not legal to do.
Like there's entire channels that are
just dedicated to this podcast and then
they take clips from this podcast and
they make money off of it.
It's real sketchy.
And then there's websites that now are
popping up that have taken clips off the
podcast.
They put them on their website and then
they have pop up ads and Google ads all
over their website.
So the only content that they have is
content that I've created,
but yet they're making money off it so I
get with.
But to me it's like,
well you canceled the show,
so obviously you're not making money on
it,
but they are.
They're going to sell it somewhere.
They'll definitely sell it someone.
But the nightly show.
Yeah.
Well there's nothing to sell it because
they to every episode they have,
they'll sell those episodes 100 percent
and plus if anybody wants to use them in
something,
do you want to use one of those clips?
They'll have it.
It's intellectual property.
I get it.
I mean how much do they spell it?
Here's the other thing,
if you do a show for a year and a half
and it gets canceled,
they lost a fuck load of much.
They sure did 100 percent.
So they were like,
look,
we're going to figure out a way to stop
this bleeding and then to just try to
patch up something.
There's no way around it.
Nelson
just happening.
It's going on.
Actually right now.
Youtube is going to be putting tv shows
on youtube,
like they're going to make some sort of
deal where you're gonna be paying less
than you pay for direct TV or Hulu.
You're gonna be able to get TV shows
just like you're getting now and other
services directly on you
two.
Is that red too though?
Is that going to be a cheaper version
than you?
To Brad?
Because Youtube Red's about nine,
nine,
$9 a month.
It's like the same price as Netflix
and.
Okay,
so you're saying like current television
shows that are out now
is literally happening right now.
Like it says,
that's inevitable.
That's inevitable.
That makes sense.
Jimmy Kimmel and cold bear will be able
to.
Something like that's death.
No,
this is the fucking death bell I'd be
happening right now.
Is the death bell to the networks,
right.
They're climbing
this.
This is going to be historic,
this kind of shit,
because he was going to be no reason to
have television.
Now if once this happens,
they will literally be no reason to have
television if this becomes universal.
Agreed.
Yeah.
Except for sporting events like you want
to watch the basketball game starts at
seven,
you got to watch it.
They're like tv might become the live
sports network.
Yeah,
that's.
I mean that's really all you need and
news maybe news.
I mean it's,
it's,
it's very similar to the model of what
you're doing with the podcast.
It's like you drop the podcast and then
people listen to it when they want to
listen to it.
Look at this.
Youtube reveals viewers watch a billion
hours of video a day as firm prepares to
unveil it's unplugged TV service.
Wow.
Well,
once they make a deal with networks like
that,
man,
fucking hey,
but that's really interesting for all
those people,
like the Poodie pies and the Philip
Defranco's and all these people that
have shows on youtube,
it's going to blow them up even bigger
because they're essentially now on a
network because the network is just is
just as well connected as Jimmy Kimmel
is now.
So in other words,
you're watching Kobe or on youtube and
then the next thing that comes up is the
rory Albany's show.
You're fucking sitting there smoking
weed in your underwear.
Your girl's underwear.
My ladies,
ladies,
ladies boxes.
Yeah.
Your wife's yelling at you in the
background.
I'm on TV.
It says my.
This is my.
This is my show shot up that says this
is how I live.
I'm taking it back.
Yeah.
They got to fix that.
We'd probably New York.
How's New York still not have legal
weed?
I don't know.
It's crazy.
What is going on now and put Batman.
That's one thing I've got to say about
Denver because it's not.
You don't even need.
You don't need to hear anymore.
You don't need to.
You could just get as recreational here.
Now
we can just walk anywhere.
I didn't know that dude.
We have a photo of a photo that I have
to put up on the wall of the moment that
we found out.
Bert Kreischer.
We we're doing a podcast during the no
idea and we did an end of the world
podcast.
It was me,
Bill Byrd Dug Stan hope.
Bert Kreischer,
a bunch of people,
and we were onstage in the comedy store.
The moment that we'd passed recreational
weed pass in California and Bert
Kreischer takes his shirt off and he's
swinging his shirt in front of the crowd
and the whole crowds got their arms up
in the air and they're going crazy.
I had no idea
crush that.
That actually wasn't the exact moment.
That was an exciting moment of the show.
When that actual moment happened,
I was sitting next to Burton.
He didn't have his shirt off yet.
I have a photo of that moment when
everyone is like,
someone told me that,
but I was going to ignore that,
but it's okay.
I mean it's a really.
It looks.
It was pretty close to happen right
afterwards,
but
dammit,
fuck over there and
that is the fact,
but that makes it even.
I really didn't know that.
I thought you still needed a jerk.
No card.
No,
you can totally get it.
I don't think that you can't smoke in
public.
You can't just be smoking.
Is it like Denver?
You walk in,
they can buy edibles.
Because I had that experience I had in
Denver was unreal saying th.
They're called bud tenders and that
alerus it's so jamie.
Tell about that place that you went to
yesterday.
It's like the genius bar.
Is that a place like.
It's actually,
it's on Santa Monica and you're like
crescent heights.
There's most of the stores here and even
like in Denver you can't see anything
you can't see inside from the street.
This is like big glass windows.
You can look right inside and it's like
an apple store tables with ipads on them
with all the different strains on it.
A little jar to like look inside.
You can smell it and you walk up to the
thing and they'd bring it out from the
back like your race or your quarter if
you remember the name of this joint.
It's called Med men,
I believe it was.
What was Med med men
like?
Mad men or something like that.
There's a cool store where they have it
set up in Denver.
It's like you're getting a little line
and then they're like,
next place and then you go up to La.
She's like,
hi,
what are you looking to do?
You know?
You're like,
oh,
I guess get high,
you know,
and then she helps you through your
journey.
I got my first medical marijuana card,
I think it was in like 2000 or something
like that.
I forget what year it was,
but I used to go to a place called
Inglewood wellness center.
It was the only place where you could
get legal weed that I knew about because
of my connections.
I would go down to Inglewood de Hood,
d a h o d do it.
And I was going there for a while until
one of the guys that was working there
got shot.
They got robbed and he got shot in the
stomach while,
um,
while I was a patron there,
I wasn't there the day that it happened,
but it was the place that I was going.
I was like,
okay,
looks like I'm getting my wheat in a
different spot now called doc man,
because they,
you know,
they were getting,
they weren't allowed to buy things with
credit cards.
So you would go there and you would have
to use cash and I guess,
you know,
they had a bunch of cash on hand and
people getting shot.
I'm going to actually,
if they were allowed to use credit cards
back then,
but now you can.
I mean now it's essentially like full
out,
but in Denver,
um,
they're having real issues still because
they won't let them deposit money the
same way.
Like you have to get cash for a lot of
the places.
We're only allowing them to get cash and
then you have to bring this cash to safe
deposit boxes and stuff.
And it was like,
it was like real sketchy.
They were hiring Merck's,
they were hiring mercenaries to carry
the cash around.
So they have these former,
a shit.
Karen [inaudible] walking around with
bags of cash worried about being robbed
and people did get robbed.
That's crazy sketchy stuff.
I mean,
my experience there,
it was like,
because I edibles were something I never
really liked.
I did them once when I was like in
college,
like the end of college and I was in
Amsterdam and I ate space cake.
You know,
and it was great.
I had a great time and then the next day
we were leaving,
I was with my friends and we were
getting on a train to Brussels and I and
I ate two space cakes because I was like
yesterday,
space cake.
Really,
man,
dude.
I was on a train for like four hours in
a tunnel,
like a Gimme.
I'll just look at trade.
Yeah.
I vividly remembered.
I was like,
I will never do this again.
And then when,
but now they're like,
it's portioned out.
You know,
like when you go to Denver,
she's like one gummy bear dry,
like 10 milligrams of marijuana try.
I think they have a rule now.
They sell them to you in these,
in when I was in Denver,
um,
I bought these tubes and the tubes,
10 gummy bears.
Yeah.
And each one was 10 milligrams.
Yep.
And so if you eat the whole one,
you go to space,
the whole tube.
He goes space or you can do it like one
company at a time.
You actually weren't gum gum drops.
They weren't bears.
Yeah.
But that's what it is.
That's exactly what that night I was out
with went chappelle.
I had a pocket full of those.
I gave you one of those,
so in those tubes I had a bunch of them
sitting back there.
I'm like,
I'm not going to take these.
Yeah,
and I also had a.
The little caramels to those things are
good.
You just got to get them from a reliable
source.
You get them from a reliable source and
they're consistent.
Then you're okay,
but you take some big chances when you
take an edible from somebody.
He'll kidding.
I never do it.
I want people like,
oh,
I made brownies.
I'm like,
fuck dude.
Good luck.
Especially as somebody who makes them
themselves,
you anytime anyone makes something
themselves for some reason.
I'm always like,
kitchen look like,
you know,
I went to a Chinese restaurant kitchen
the other day.
It was a really good restaurant.
I'm like,
where's your bathroom?
They go in the back and I walked through
this hallway and past the kitchen.
I was like,
well,
not eating here again ever.
Jesus.
That happens a lot of comedy clubs,
right?
You go through the kitchen to get to the
green room and then they're like,
what do you want it for?
Food?
You're like,
anything deep fried,
something that's been murdered.
All the fucking bugs that possibly could
be torched away by boiling oil.
Yes,
exactly.
Yeah.
And then you're just eating shit.
When you go on the road,
do you bring food?
Like do you bring your healthy shit with
you?
Well,
if the,
if the hotel room has one of them little
mini refrigerators at,
I go to a whole foods and I'll get like
Kombucha and healthy food and snacks and
stuff like that.
But I'm pretty strict with my diet.
I don't know,
just don't eat too much shit.
I will allow.
I do what I call it 80 slash 20 diet
again,
I give myself 80 percent healthy food
and 20 percent of the time I'll fuck off
so I'll fuck off like one day a week.
So one thing you want,
I'll eat cheeseburgers,
fries a,
a milkshake,
but it's only like one day a week and I
just,
it's just not worth it.
I've done it too many times where I've
eaten bad on the road and then by the
time Sunday rolls around and you're
like,
oh,
the road is tough though.
It's hard because you have to like,
do you bring vitamins?
Yeah.
You do?
Yeah,
I do.
I bring vitamins,
I bring probiotics.
My company on it has this thing called
total gut health.
So I bring these packets of probiotics.
I think that's super important and it's
all live stuff that exists off the
substrate that's in the capsule so that
you can actually get real live
probiotics and then I eat probiotics to
all that stuff is really important if
you want to maintain your immune system.
Yeah.
So that stuff.
And then just that's what I've been
struggling with salads.
I get like I get like right now,
like I'm not sick,
but like I always have like I'm always
fighting off,
got a sore throat or you know,
because I'm on planes to work out on the
road.
Uh,
not really.
That's the thing too,
man.
GotTa Force yourself somewhat about
being on the road.
It's like I'm just laying in bed,
eat sandwiches,
like don't you feel a little drained
from the flight itself?
It was like,
oh,
gross.
Yeah.
And then,
uh,
yeah.
And it's like,
by the way,
that's the other thing too,
like with America right now,
like I never posted a picture of food in
my entire life.
I posted a photo of a Jimmy John's
sandwich when I was in Chicago just
because we don't have Jimmy John's in
New York.
So I was like,
oh great.
Jimmy John's,
I lived here.
People were like,
you can't eat Jimmy John's he's at
today.
He's the Guy Jimmy John's into hunter.
And he said,
Nah,
I'm like,
Jimmy,
John's a bad guy.
Apparently.
Apparently John Do,
I guess,
I don't know.
It's find out.
He's like,
goes and hunts like big game,
big.
He's a big game like elephants and shit,
that kind of stuff.
Let's pull it up.
Let's find out what he's doing.
And He,
uh,
and he,
and then people were going and then
somebody goes and he's a Republican.
I go look at the big game hunting thing
I'll give you,
but if I,
if I can't eat food made by a
Republican,
which good luck finding a good steak,
what you're talking about.
Think those ranchers are,
but I love that people think that that's
evil being a Republican.
It's like what?
It's crazy,
Ron.
Paul wasn't evil.
There's a lot of people that are
republicans that would fit into a lot of
people's ideas of what would be a
reasonable politician.
It's just we think of Republican.
We think of the right wrist of the right
wing.
The hardest of the hard sell.
I mean,
to me the biggest issue is,
is the environment,
you know,
that's huge.
Well he just farming and human and
people having rights.
Yeah.
That's my biggest fear about right now
is like gay people.
Like I'm worried that they're gonna be
able to get married,
you know,
like the word gay people aren't gonna be
able to get married,
pull up to that microphone a little bit
closer there.
I'm worried that like that could go
away,
you know,
like.
Yeah,
I think that can happen.
Well,
I mean,
I think gay people would be psyched,
like,
hey,
that bitch,
I'm tired of paying.
I just feel like rights to me are the
one thing that you can't fuck with,
you know,
and that's one.
Right.
I just hope I wish they'd make straight
marriage illegal.
Jimmy John's Gore may sandwiches.
Whoa.
He kills leopards.
Okay.
Well the ram on the upper left hand
corner got no problem with that because
you eat rams and they're delicious.
They're sheep and then also you spend a
lot of money to hunt one of those things
and that money directly goes to
conservation.
The bear.
That's a grizzly bear.
It's a brown bear.
You don't eat those,
but you do have to kill some of those.
There was an issue in North America
where they have too many grizzly bears
in certain areas.
Like in Alaska,
you actually have to kill.
You have to kill a certain amount of
them in order to keep the Moose
population stable because the bears eat
all the moose calves.
What are you assuming that that's the
brown bear?
No,
that's definitely a brown bear and that
looks like Alaska.
I'm assuming that's what that is.
Well,
most places that you killed brown bears,
if it is legal,
if he's killing that bear legally,
which I assume it is because he's taken
a photo of it.
You have to have.
I mean there's.
There's.
You spend so much money to kill those
things and that money directly goes to
conservation.
It's a real catch 22 because the only
reason why those things are alive and
exist in high populations and aren't
decimated and then their wildlife
habitat is protected,
especially protecting habitat and
wetlands for birds,
for migrating birds.
All that stuff comes from conservation
money,
which all comes from hunting.
Hunting is absolutely the number one
biggest source of conservation for
wildlife in the United States of America
by far.
No debate about it,
but then you see them in the upper right
hand corner has got a leopard.
Okay.
That's real tough to defend because he's
not eating that fucking leopard.
And you shooting that liberty to
shooting it for a trophy.
Yeah,
I mean it's just so fucked up to me that
anybody would do okay,
but the deer in the law in the middle,
low bottom zero problem with that food.
Not only that,
$2,
million car accidents in the United
States every year,
excuse me,
one point,
5 million car accidents.
The United States every year from people
hitting deer and 200 people die because
of accidents involving people hitting
deer with cars and unless you want to
bring in wolves and mountain lions and
overpopulate the suburbs with them,
you're going to have a problem with deer
populations unless you have hunters.
That's just a fact.
And in places like the Hamptons,
they're actually hiring snipers to go
out and shoot them.
He killed a fucking rhino that's so
fucked.
They killed it.
Elephant look at it with a double thumbs
up with an elephant will.
Yeah.
So I found out about that and I can't
have sandwiches anymore,
you know?
Oh,
we killed a fucking giraffe and he just
kills everything.
First he killed a rhino.
Is that alliance?
Yup.
Jesus Christ.
It's all real sketchy stuff,
man.
It's real sketchy stuff because in
Africa,
which there's a great documentary that
Louis Theroux did a about African
hunting farms,
these a wildlife sanctuaries that they
have in Africa where they just hunted on
them.
They big high fence operations.
Africa was on the verge.
These animals were on the verge of
extinction just a few decades ago and
now they're thriving and unheard of
populations,
but it's only because people are paying
to go over there and hunt them so they
protect these animals and then what's
even more fucked up.
They use the term poacher all the time.
You know,
these people are poaching.
Most of the time you think of poaching
you think will.
Poachers are bad because poachers are
the people that are killing elephants
for their ivory,
that killing rhinos for their horns.
But a lot of what poaching is poor
people that are just trying to eat
right.
And you know what they do?
Those poachers,
they fucking murderer man.
They shoot them onsite.
So if someone's killing like,
um,
you know,
a black buck or something like that,
one of the,
the game animals that they have the eat,
they're shooting at these people,
they're shooting and killing them left
and right.
And that was crazy.
They're leaving their bodies for the
hyenas to eat.
Did you see the tiger thing that
happened the other day with the,
with the.
I didn't even understand that when I was
reading about it that they were like,
oh,
that's a tiger farm.
I'm like,
well,
those.
That bummed me out,
man.
Well,
people in.
Do you know this?
This is a fact.
We'll,
we'll close on this because from my last
netflix special,
but it's true.
There's more tigers in captivity in
Texas than there are in all of the wild
of the world.
What?
Yeah.
More Tigers in people's backyards.
In private collections in Texas.
Then the rest of the people who own pet
tigers.
Yep.
Texas has no rules.
Texas is a really fucked up place for
people that think that the government
shouldn't own land.
Like there's a lot of people that think
that the state,
federal government shouldn't own land
that should give it to the state.
The problem with that is a state will
then sell it off.
And a good example that is Texas of what
could happen is Texas has very little
public land.
Texas is almost all private land,
so I called a lot of the hunting in
Texas is all on private ranches.
And then these private ranches,
you can kind of do whatever the fuck you
want.
And they bring in all these animals from
all over the world.
Like there's,
um,
there's a,
an animal called a symitar oryx and Orix
in Africa.
I think there are Asian animal,
I forget where they're from,
but wherever they're from,
maybe India or wherever they're from,
they're very endangered.
Not In Texas,
in Texas is fucking thousands of them.
They're all over the place.
And these ranches.
So you can go and hunt what in its
native country you wouldn't hunt because
there's small populations of them,
but in Texas they encourage hunting of
them because they have overpopulation.
That animal right there,
symitar horned oryx.
Wow.
So you can go to these places in Texas
and you can fucking shoot those and
they're delicious.
Where?
What's his name died?
Uh,
a justice.
The Supreme Court with those name.
Oh,
Yay.
Died.
They think they lacked dumb little think
they whacked him.
Well,
he died with a pillow on his face.
It was like,
there was,
it was a little bit of like,
is that what happened?
You know,
in the naked gun when he throws a pillow
out of them?
Yeah.
Tell you what.
It wasn't even really old.
He was like 70.
Wasn't that old?
He was snoring and his wife.
Just you fucking car.
I think it was alone enough.
Yeah.
He probably just had a heart attack.
He was kind of fat.
What was his name?
Justice Scalia.
Scalia.
Yeah.
He was kind of a Dick though.
Wasn't always super right wing Guy,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
but that just right when you look below,
there's the dead with a pillow over his
head.
Ranch over.
Well,
he might've put that pillow over his
head because people are talking the
other room and he wanted to be
quiet and then he.
Yeah,
I've put pillows over my head before
people were talking,
we discovered a judge in bed,
a pillow over his head.
His clothes were unwrinkled,
so then he probably just died.
30,000 Acre luxury ranch.
El Presidente Day.
Sweet.
He's 79.
Yeah,
30,000 acres.
Fuck,
that's huge.
Yeah.
So these people would go to these
ranches and they still do.
They go to these ranches and you can
hunt wild African animals there.
That's nuts man.
I had no idea.
Yeah.
Well there.
I've never daunted anything.
No.
Yeah.
Would you be interested in doing it?
I would be interested in if I ate it,
that's what I'm saying.
I'm the guy I had no interest in killing
something to,
to do it,
but I eat meat so I always felt like,
well you kind of.
When I was in Australia I spent like
five days on a sheep station,
which like a big sheet for him.
It was amazing and I was like herding
sheep on a motorcycle.
It was amazing and cool.
So while I was there,
he slaughtered to sheep and I was there
when he slaughtered them and he like,
Hey,
slow it into my hand.
I like brought them to the thing.
It was like really intense experience.
But he,
that's what he does.
That's how this got slaughtered on the
shoot him in the head or the neck,
cut their Mac and then he like hangs
them upside down.
It was like a really intense thing to
say they just shoot them because if they
shoot them they die instantly.
I don't know why would they cut their.
I don't know what their neck thing seems
so cruel.
Yeah,
it was weird.
It was me and these like for like
Australia and it's like,
alright,
yeah,
I was just standing there drinking a
beer.
Like yeah,
totally.
Just cut a cut a sheep snack man.
That's how we do it on long island
was east Hampton where I grew up.
Uh,
we didn't cut any next,
you know,
but I've thought about doing a show
where I take people hunting that I've
never hunted,
like maybe comics,
but I just don't think it's the right
way to approach hunting.
I just think it's too confusing.
It's too dark and it's also a,
it would take.
It would make content a spectacle to me
versus a what it is now.
Yeah,
I mean I would go like if I went with
you when I went with people knew what
they were doing and I,
you know,
I'm going to do it.
I guess.
I don't know.
My problem is my also my hunting time is
super precious.
I don't get that much of it.
I don't want to be teaching anybody.
I'm trying to figure it out myself.
Course not.
You go out with guys who were,
who were experts.
Experts for us.
Yeah.
Well I got to wrap this up.
All right.
Thanks for having me,
man.
Please my pleasure.
Tell people how to get ahold of you
where they could see you.
What's your website?
What's your twitter websites?
Just my name Rory Albany's Dotcom.
Spell it out.
So the o r y a l b a n e s e Dot Com.
Um,
I'm doing a bunch of shows coming up.
I'm in webster,
New York.
I mean San Antonio,
Texas on the Sixteenth Webster,
New York this weekend.
I'm down at [inaudible] and Tennessee
doing secret show in Philadelphia on
that.
I'm not supposed to talk about that a,
that I got a bunch of dates in May and
you know,
just check out my website and my name,
instagram,
Rory Albany's,
twitter,
all those things.
Check them out folks.
It's a funny motherfucker more often.
Thanks my pleasure.
Bye.