The problem with Brian's fucking
microphone. Listen to that God damn fan.
God that fence socks. Yeah. Until you,
when you turn your mic up and
down when you're going to,
you're going to have to do that when
you talk because that microphone is dog
shit.
Yeah.
Okay.
Be careful you drink there.
The Joe Rogan experience.
Try my day. Joe Rogan
podcast. My name all day.
You're right. I think he's loud as heck
out over here. Yeah, we live. Yeah. Okay.
Yeah, the thing's loud as fuck.
We have a problem here folks.
It's not a major problem.
We have this new tri caster
set up HD Joe Diaz HD now,
but unfortunately the tri caster as
fans on it, it's super noisy where, uh,
Brian's microphone is positioned.
Maybe I could just sit over there until
we fix this because it over there. Yeah.
We'll throw a camera on you. You
don't let Jamie run it. Fuck it. Yeah.
Come on over here bitch. To be one of us.
Come over to the big boys table. Uh, we,
uh, we got this try gas are
set up and it's pretty sweet.
It's because a lot of people watch
this on their televisions. You know,
you take like a chrome cast
or you just use an htmi cable.
There's a bunch of different ways
you could do it and you send,
or you could use that apple thing where
you throw it to apple TV and you could
wash it on apple TV. What does that
called? APPLETV airplay. Airplay. Yeah.
So anything that's on your
computer you could watch on TV.
He just shoot it to that. And if you're
using the uh, air, that's how it works,
right? Yeah. Yeah. Do it from your iPad or
your iPhone or anything like that? Yeah,
it's pretty fucking sweet.
So we're moving into 2015
show does fucking crazy.
But take a chance to the next level.
I've canceled cable. Did she write?
Yeah, she kept some package.
She said that's it. We will
live on Netflix. I love it.
Well, I gotta tell you I love
it. I love it too. I love it.
I ain't go online and you want
to come home at night comedy,
Netflix and I unwind and I could
watch whatever the fuck I want. Yeah.
A buddy of mine worked for Psi
Phi for 20 years and he said,
I got it once he goes,
I would watch how my children are watch
TV and I knew that they were on the some
kids. Yeah. And I kept going to siphon
down them and they were like, fuck,
do you know we've talked with Mike.
He quit and he started his own
youtube channel. Harvest. Shoney's,
fucking killing them.
But it's funny how even my daughter goes
nuts when a commercial comes on when
she's watching bubble guppies
and the commercial comes on.
She do is she looks at me like,
cause she's not used to it on Netflix.
When I put on Dora, whatever, the
Grinch that stole Christmas or whatever,
there's no commercial. So
for her it's fucking it. So
I watched her the other day,
I'm like, look at us. Yeah.
Even a fucking three year old tells
you that commercial suck ass. Yeah.
They're not fun.
It's, it's unnecessary and it
ruins the vibe of the show.
I've watched the walking dead almost
entirely on Netflix or an apple TV rather.
But I, um, uh, decided uh, to,
to record it on my DVR one night
and I tried watching it on,
on regular TV. Oh, it's fucking
awful. Through my watched it. Oh,
that's what it was.
I watched it live without recording it
because you can't watch it on apple TV
until the next day. So it came out
on Sunday, so I watched it live,
so we just paused it and walked away
for 20 minutes and came back so we could
fast forward through all the bullshit.
But it's like every fucking 15 minutes
they have this big break in the show
stops and it's a dumb way
to intrude on television.
It's like for whatever reason,
they started doing it like
that and they stuck with it.
And some guys do it like that with
podcasts. Like I love Adam Carolla,
but Adam Carolla does commercials
like a radio show. He just,
he does them all the time. He doesn't mean
every 15 minutes, you know, he's like,
he's got like breaks like heartbreaks,
just like a radio show, you know,
I guess that's the world he came from.
So you just do it that way.
Will these new marketing
agencies that contact, you know,
they,
they trying to ruin you dangle big money,
but they want you to read 18 times a show.
You can't do that.
It becomes what we went to
get away from. Yeah. You know,
so no I don't interrupt.
I won't interrupt.
I do it before I do it afterwards.
How put Shit on Twitter.
If I think it's a good product
and I enjoy it, I'll do it.
But I'll do it with no contract.
Like if I, if I tweet something,
like if you see me tweet something
about naturebox, cause I like it.
Like I got these Sriracha cashews, they're
the shit and I love him. I love him.
So I tweeted like there's no agreement.
I don't have it.
There's no like you have to
tweet this five times a week.
There's none of that shit.
So I don't interrupt any podcasts
and I don't because I want,
I don't want that when
I'm listening to stuff.
I like stuff to go all the way through
to the end and I'd be more inclined to
support something that supported that.
Then I would beat inclined sport,
something that's that same old system.
That system sucks man,
that every 15 minutes
system you don't do it.
You don't have commercials any year
finding a deal. Any commercial. Yeah.
That's silly. Make some money. Well
I used to just say, hey, go do,
if you want to help out,
just go to shop squad.
And then that just takes
care of everything.
And one little swoop we rock in the
split screen now. Old School, like,
like the old days,
we're going old,
but we're going new again now we have,
I'm sure I wouldn't get between
the apple TV and Netflix.
Well Netflix is incorporated in Apple TV.
So if you have an apple TV,
there's Netflix in there.
You just got to sign up for an account.
But you said that apple comes out the next
day. Netflix? No Netflix doesn't have,
uh, I don't think they have
the walking dead if they do.
It's probably like the earlier seasons
with apple. You buy the whole season,
like your rent the season and you could
watch like all the episodes at once,
which was lose route if you have a
day. Do you watch walking dead? No,
I'm scared of that. You
know, when I was a kid,
that one we would get high and go to go
on to the dead and those type of movies,
you know.
And that was George Miro.
Miro was the fucking crazy
fuck when I was a kid.
That's the guy that made all those
gowns night of the living dead.
And I still remember that one thing with
the black guy's yelling, Mama, Mama.
He stands next to the helicopter
and the helicopter just cuts
the top of his fucking head off. Oh
God. I'm just never, and I, you know,
I don't know. It's not for me. People
walking around like zombies and shit,
I have fucking nightmares and
stuff so I don't watch nothing.
American horror story is probably one
of the scariest motherfucking shows I've
turned down and lasting
for like 13 or 14 minutes.
Is it really that ladies fucking
scary though. What is her name again?
He used to be good looking because fuck
yeah, I was fucking, we were young.
What is her name? God Damn.
It's not Angelica Euston,
something like that. None.
Angelica Houston, the other one she
was in the mailman always rings twice.
The Postman always rings twice.
Got Damn. She was hot back then.
What is her name Ma'am? Just tried
Jessica Lange. Jessica Lange? Yes.
That's what it is. You know, she was a
Fay Wray and the King Kong remake the uh,
Dino de Laurentiis. Is that his name?
King Kong remake with Rick Baker,
which is like what that was
like the second King Kong.
There was like the old school King Kong.
It's a stop motion.
Claymation that looks like shit. But then
Rick Baker did a version of King Kong.
It was super sophisticated for
the time. And uh, she was, uh,
Jessica Lange was the fe ranch.
She was loud as fuck bro.
When Jack Nicholson put her on the
table and fucked in that movie.
Tremendous look. She looked great.
She, yeah, she was smoldering.
But you know what man,
she as an actress like or at an actor
I guess you said it doesn't need to be
gender specific.
She fucking hold her own right now.
She is as good as anybody, man.
She is so creepy on that show.
She's so like powerfully creepy.
You know like there's like there's,
there's just a realism to her.
The crazy that she projects.
It scares the shit out of me man.
He's like judge on that too.
The one that played Tina Turner with the,
with the ISG.
She's in the new season. I haven't
watched it. The fat chick from the cutoff.
Jack [inaudible] legs. James Cons.
Legging. Kathy Bates. Is it the ball?
My God.
Gary as fucking show my wife watches.
Why
do you have to watch the oldest seasons
to be caught up or is it a new season?
A totally new story.
I don't know how it fucking works man.
You just tuned in to freak
out and get out of the room.
And I sit out like eight minutes.
I watched Jessica Lange,
I watched the black chick and
I get the fuck out of there.
That's a Larry of deal with that
shit at all. What pains you a hot,
I couldn't sleep for fucking angel
heart was on a couple of weeks ago and I
stayed up and watched the
fucking scare the shit out of me.
It's really well written because
they set up the first episodes.
Well I don't want to give any spoilers,
but family moves into this House and uh,
Jessica Lange,
he's like the neighbor or she comes
by and she comes by like unannounced.
It's real creepy how she
does it and it may, you know,
he knows she's fucking nuts.
And so the guys there with his wife and
his children and you're like, oh fuck.
Like this is going to end terrible.
Like draws you in.
Like right away you get nervous and
you feel freaked out like right away.
Get Hulu. Joey, did you
ever get Hulu? I think
so,
yeah.
I quit my cable also in Hulu is actually
one of the best ones because you can do
shows usually the day after
or then at the same day.
Like south park is a good one on there.
If you'd like South Park.
What a network.
So they have what?
They have a lot of fox ones,
they have a
lot of NBC like Saturday night live
and stuff like that. It's, it's,
it's a nice blend of all the,
the main networks and also
they also have movies on there,
so it's a nice little change from
also Amazon prime is another thing.
If you have Amazon prime, you get access
to all of Amazon prime stuff. Awesome.
They have their own shows. Uh, and
you can also rent movies through them,
which is nice.
Wow. Yeah. It's the, all the
options that are available today.
You're not the first
person to tell me either.
I have several friends that
have cancer though. Thank you.
Said I don't want to do a buck and a
half no more. I'm not doing it. Yeah,
it seems ridiculous doing it. Netflix
or seven bucks a month. That's really,
I mean it's $7 like that's so insane.
And they go once eight 99 yeah.
So for 20 you got that right.
And I think CBS just announced that they
have something for like five bucks and
you just get all of his cvs,
which is silly because he
can get it for free already.
But I guess the convenience of
downloading whatever you want,
HBO is going right. If you just want to
watch game of Thrones, fuck yeah. Yeah.
You just go HBO online. Right?
Pretty much becoming other cart,
which is something that I've
always wanted in a cable company.
Being able to pick and choose
which channels you want.
Cable companies are screwed. Yeah. And
when you develop a show, like if you were,
when I was doing, they'd Scifi
show, but you've filmed Michelle,
you edit it and once it's edited
then it has to wait for, you know,
whatever night it's on, Tuesday night
at eight o'clock, whatever it is.
And then you wait for it to go on.
And then the show broadcast live Tuesday
night at eight and they sandwich in a
bunch of shit that you don't want to see.
So in between that you're
watching priceless sec
commercials and fucking Toyota
commercials and all this shit
that you don't give a fuck.
You're just being there. They're
literally fucking with your experience.
Come on by me. Come on by this.
Hey, what about this? I feel better.
Look at my wife, looked at my
car, pick it up to the next one.
But what about us? You could buy, I was
told about us. Do you have insurance?
Your insurance run by a lizard and the
evo is fucking goofy shit and you you,
it ruins your experience. They don't
have to do that anymore. Say more.
What are they going to do for commercials?
Product placements.
I think mostly even grosser and I think
that's the reason why we're paying a
monthly subscription fee. If you
like holding up a fucking soda. Yeah,
I know why he killed her.
It's done right though.
South Park is a good example of them
doing it right. Where they actually,
I think have sponsors, but
they just trashed the sponsor
the whole time and real.
Yeah.
I'm nowhere that they're just one episode.
There'll be doing like a Dr Pepper,
but yet the days just talk shit,
mad shit on Dr Pepper the whole time.
You could talk shit on Dr Pepper and Dr
Peppers base. Basically invincible. Yeah,
like as long as you're talking about Dr
Pepper it, unless it's killing anybody.
It's not killing anybody. But if you want
to talk shit about the way pepper taste
and in fact in anybody, you
know, I noticed that one nun,
it was watching Diane Sawyer the
day that Fucko said something.
Who's the guy who's the guy that said
no? Rush Limbaugh? What did he sells?
He took pills. Oh, he
was one of the years ago,
but then a couple of years ago on
his radio show, he said something,
I'm sitting there watching the Diane
Sawyer and she pops up on the screen.
You know what I'm saying?
They pop up the sponsors that left him.
No sponsors were like, fuck or wash,
lemon ball. We just hit the Jackpot.
That's what they don't really realize.
If they sponsored Joey Diaz,
his radio show and he says,
fuck whoever,
whatever John [inaudible]
group and they get rid of them.
Diane Sawyer is when they come up and go,
did you hear what happened?
Joey d is today and the Muslim, they show
American Airlines, Delta, Delta is gone.
We didn't lose we fucking six 30 Diane
Sawyer. That's as good as it fucking gets.
That's it.
They didn't lose.
So either way you don't lose because
they mentioned you, nobody loses.
They don't really fucking lose.
Did you see what happened with, uh,
here's a perfect example. I'm not
trashing out of Kroll. I, like I said,
I love Adam, but Adam had this check, uh,
Alison Rosen who was on her show and he
just decided he wanted to try something
different, which is his prerogative.
But here's what happened.
Her show shot through the fucking ratings.
It was number one out of all
podcasts on iTunes. And you know why?
Because people responded
because she's really nice.
Like Alison Rosen is really nice and
really smart and she's a good podcast her.
So like I think, and I even
sent her an email, I said,
you're going to be fantastic on your own.
Like you don't need anybody.
Like it's probably better for her to be
completely independent because I think
her show could be really profitable.
It can be really good and I think when
you that smart and that opinionated,
you should have your own show. I mean
she's really good but always light there.
Yeah, she always, she had
her own show for a long time.
She knows she still has it.
Alison Rosen is your best friend or
your new best friend. She's really,
she got fired. Show just shot up,
shot through the fucking Raider,
the fucking roof. And I think that
just shows you that like if you're, if,
if,
if it gets out there,
if there's controversy like oh Allison
got five port Raul's and pour hours and
what are you crazy? She's
number one now. She's never won.
She's shot past all of us.
She probably,
because there were so many online
stories about it and you know,
because the timing was really bad for
her. Yeah, yeah, yeah. She does die.
Dog died and she was out of town
and it was done by email. You know,
there was like a lot going on
with it, but you know, hey man,
I know the guy should be able to do
whatever the fuck he wants to do with his
show.
But the bottom line is like she showed
that she was really good on the show and
then the controversy of
him firing her was huge.
It was way better than him like giving
her like some title or a promotion or you
know like if he announced Alison Rosen
been vice president of controversy and
Adam Carolla enterprises, nobody would
give a fuck. But her getting fired for it.
Like if, if you got on the radio
and you will like fuck the police,
fuck gastro, fuck all these cops suck.
Good, suck my Dick. And then you know,
nature box pulled out
and everybody got crazy.
We are no longer sponsoring the joy and
it was a big dog over these websites.
Naturebox pulls out of the,
Jody has podcasts.
You would get hundreds of
thousands more downloads that week.
Hundreds of that office look at, what's
his name? Uh, two and a half bath.
Metalli he got fired drugs,
hookers blow.
Fuck FX was right there with an envelope.
Not only we didn't have an envelope,
they gave him the stupidest deal
anyone's ever given. Anybody ever.
He made all the episodes they had,
they did a hundred episode deal and they
make them over a really short period of
time. So they're just
churning out scripts like you,
I don't have to tell you,
it takes time to write something good.
Sometimes it doesn't.
Sometimes you have the best idea.
Like you'll hear about Quentin Tarantino.
He did blow,
he ran up to his apartment real quick
and he just spent the next six hours
writing a script to, you know,
pulp fiction two or some shit.
Occasionally that does happen.
Like I'm a hunter.
Thompson wrote most of his, uh, Charlie,
the book he wrote about a hell's angels.
He wrote most of it coked up like
in one night. Like most of it,
like you finished up the book like in one
night just rattled off. It is possible,
but most of the time you get it.
Spend time, you got to do revisions.
So they're not doing any of that.
They just fucking slamming them out
there and if it went past x amount of
episodes,
I forget what the deal was.
They had to film all 90 so
he got this huge DLC. He,
he's like $900 million or
something stupid or $90 million.
Here's some in ungodly sum of money
from that deal. Somewhat a nine in it.
Jamie would know. I Bet Jamie knows the
exact number, but he's got a tattoo.
Well he was talking about
it all morning today.
I love gossip, Jamie. The whole idea,
it makes me laugh, but it's the,
the controversy for anything.
It's almost like worth doing.
That's why you know people,
they stir up shit on purpose.
Like anybody that's in like the
reality show business they like,
they're all they're doing is just
controversy, controversy, contrary.
Can we get some controversy
if we have controversies,
we've got to show
controversy tat tat tat ta,
I mean that's all they're trying to sell.
That's all they're trying to sell.
But you can see right through it. You
can, I can like, this is bullshit.
This is the,
the the white chick,
we'll call it the black husband with
a transvestite took them back and the
show's on me and she's like,
what do I do? It's such a tough,
he was going to fucking transvestite. You
get rid of that fucking freak. He says,
now she took him back again and now
they're on season eight and you know,
who even cares about that fucking broad.
I don't give a fuck.
People care if they put him
on the cover of a magazine,
like if you're on the cover of a
magazine and that's what you sell,
like those realities,
Star type people.
It just has to be there on the
cover and then something happens.
She dumped him for this guy.
There's a more handsome guy,
shit that now he's in the dumps.
That's all you need to know and all you
need to do. And then people go, well,
what happens next? What happens
to him? What happens to her? Well,
they'd be reunited. Well, she forgive
him. Will you forgive her? Ah,
they got me hooked.
I mean,
you don't even know what Kim
Kardashians fucking voice sounds like.
Do you understand that?
Like you would not be able to tell that
if Kim Kardashian was doing a commercial
for Delta, you wouldn't
be like, oh, that's Kim
Kardashians. But if like say um,
what's her name? Uh, from
friends? No, the other one.
Phoebe Cates. What's, what's
her? No, not Phoebe. Casey said.
What's her Kudrow Lisa Kudrow.
Thank you. It was gossip. Jamie.
You how funny it is when he turns to
Mike Honda that turn it off for a second.
Just so everybody can hear the fan.
That is so stupid. It's so stupid.
We're working on now. We're working about
the video looks beautiful though. Um,
what is her name again?
According Cox, the general,
basically Sweetser could drink fucking
guys. Thick tip of his fingers of this.
No, I have not. The fucking plastic
surgery. Oh, I've seen her and they put,
they put friends before it. Some nights.
I'm way too young to fuck with her.
Yeah.
They have her on TMT and something on dbs.
They have friends on the TBL and cool.
Good thing.
When you're in a hotel room after doing
this show and you go there, they don't,
you're like, oh my God,
what the fuck happened?
That fucking plastic surgery those chicks
do. It doesn't make them look better.
It just makes them look different.
You know,
until like when you start shooting shit
into your face to freeze it up and puff
your cheeks up to hide wrinkles,
it does not make you look better.
It just makes you look different.
And there's the uncanny valley,
the uncanny valley as they do,
this is a term that used for
video games were with CGI.
They're really close to being able to
completely replicate what it person
normally it looks like. Don't pull
up her face. Don't be rude bitch.
This motherfucker's
gonna. Um, uncanny valley.
Like there's like,
um,
there's some videos that you could see
now like that Nvidia has created where
they are so close to it looking,
what is this, what are you showing?
It shows you all the different steps
they're not seeing. If this is for us. Oh,
I saw the different versions
of the uncanny valley, I'll
pop it up. So like, okay,
well let me just explain the term. Don't
you don't, don't put, don't pull this up.
Um, the, the term that they use in, in
you confusing the shit. I've got no idea.
Shut. This has nothing to do with that.
That's a different uncanny valley.
The uncanny valley that we're talking
about is the difference between CGI,
like high level CGI in a person.
Like it's so close,
but there's something creepy about
it and that's what they call it.
The uncanny valley. There's this
valid that they can't quite cross.
Like did you see him again? I,
yeah. Well did you see the, uh,
the latest Nvidia Shit? Have
you seen that? Uh, not that.
I'm pretty sure we could show that show
Nvidia's latest technology for a CGM.
The guys, the guys face.
We saw it in person,
me and Todd Mesereau from my TV show.
We went to see it in person
in northern California. That's
it.
That's the guy is fucking incredible man.
But it still hasn't bridged that uncanny
valley. We can show this on the podcast.
This is a all Nvidia's
technology and they have pores.
They have sweat.
But what they can't do is tongues.
So when the guys talking they can't quite
do tongues and the teeth look a little
fucking weird but look dead. Yeah,
but God damn, that's pretty close.
That's getting real close.
Ripped.
But there's still something about it
where you're like, man, I don't know.
They got skin down and they,
but they don't have edge down like the
edge detection around the forehead.
You can see it's a little weird and
yeah, like a green screen, right? Yeah.
It's like the difference between the,
the real,
well it's also why is everything in
the background blurry. Yeah. You know,
I guess that's just a sample, but
still it's, but you're pretending what?
This is an old school camera. Is that
what you're doing? Like, why is that?
Why that shit all blurry?
Like
that's ridiculous.
And it's heads floating,
but that's,
that's like real close.
But they still, they can't do
that yet. You know, they can't,
I don't know why we were
bringing up the uncanny valley.
We crude because of fucking people.
Plastic surgery, the bucked, the valley.
But that's what it is.
They all look the same and they're all
standing a little creepy and creepy and
they're not all going to be happy till
they all look like walking dead or
something like that.
They're all going to be,
they're all going to be
hanging out together.
All Yours looks great that
you got it done. No, you
don't have that fucking great.
You look like a fucking something
monstrous. They start looking monstrous.
It's a, it's unfortunate and it
looks, you know, it looks crazy.
Like you're a crazy person
like you're doing, you know,
it's not like some tribal thing where
you're doing like some tribal scarring on
your federal women mob wives.
Have you ever seen those women
know the big ones? Big Edge.
I just saw her last night when I was
scrolling. Yeah. Oh my God, they just,
she's shooting shit like jail summit.
She's just shooting the shit constantly.
All of those women,
those east coast women, the fake tits,
the, the fat taken off that body,
the tightening of the legs,
the, the ass implants.
You can put the implants in your ass.
By the way though,
got been torturing this
hook up for about a month.
We'll hooker Bobby Slayton style,
just torture, torture that,
you know,
who does I want it to sell 11 one night
on Magnolia there and I'd come out and
there's a black girl in the jeep that
is banging when she comes out. She goes,
he was staying there. I'm
like, yeah. She goes, hey,
really length again to stand though.
I'd like to talk more about it. I go,
this is an open mic at the ha ha. Go
down. And she goes, I've been down there,
but the is rude to me and all this shit.
So I go down there like three weeks
later I see it and I'm like, Hey man,
you've been trying. And she goes,
no, I'm still taking notes. I mean,
this chick is gorgeous. She
goes, I'm still taking notes,
but you can tell there's
something not right. You know,
when there's something not
right. So she's like, you know,
I just need somebody to
take me under their wing.
It's doing to me and all this stuff.
Can I get you a digit
and I'll give you a call?
And then she started with the calls,
you know, how are you blah, blah, blah.
I'm like, I'm fine. She goes, when can we,
I can't, you know, I can't teach a cat.
And they got to go out there and
go it, you know, blah, blah, blah.
And then finally I would go,
well, go here, you know, go
over there and go to fly.
I don't know what else to go.
And I wouldn't talk to her for weeks
at a time when she called me like,
where are you going to?
I'm going to the comedy store.
Can you talk to them for me? I can't get
you up at the fucking comedy and stuff.
And then when they should start talking
about her jeep blew up and she needs
$1,000, you know, I right there. I just
started giggling like I just know now,
once they do that,
you're intrigued to see where it goes.
Now you want to talk to them because
she's trying to play it right.
So they finally got
the call when they say,
you're going to be home in the next
10 minutes, can I call you back?
I'm busy right now and I know she's
got to be like a stripper or something,
you know?
Because she disappears like God though,
because she'll call me like at eight and
go, are you doing comments? I'm like,
yeah, I'm doing a spot 11
I'm going to come and see it.
And then I'll never see it. And then
she'll call me like a week later and go,
she always disappears if it's after
like 10 so she does something right.
You know what I'm saying? So finally she
called me one night and I just, I'm like,
I don't even want to talk to this. I
can't even have fun with it. Right.
Because she's trying to
lie to me. Hey, oh yeah.
At least if she was just telling me
she was a hooker, I would torment.
So finally the clouds parted
and she's like, you know,
I really need this thousand dollars I
really need 2,700 but I could take a
thousand to help me.
I said,
you need 2,700 but I get to
take a thousand a thousand
but I get take a thousand
that helped me out. Like you're
like, well I don't know. She's a Dj.
She's a Dj.
Dj is too.
That's why I don't see him late at night
cause Dj, you know. Okay, what do you DJ?
Oh, I just do independent
parties. Really? What do you make?
519 with the fucking thousand for,
well,
you know they want 3000 from my
jeep and shit. So I finally said,
this fucking bitch is crazy.
I'm not going to get any money.
Some of the other night I call up at
seven 11 I'm not going to get no fucking
money. Joe, you're cried.
I pull up the seven 11 I see her at the
counter and I'm sitting with Lee and she
comes down and she's like, how come
you were returned my calls no more.
What's wrong with you? I go, listen, I've
just been busy. You know I ain't got,
I'm doing comedy over the valley, down
over the hill. You're never around.
I can't help you. She's like, you
really got to help me with that money.
Me and Leah Howard, cause I totally
about a lot. Looking at Howard,
she hasn't seen you in
a week and she's really,
really got to help me look it up and run.
You gotta help me with that paper.
So I said, all right, let me drop leave
home and are caught here. So I called him,
I go, listen, how much do you need?
She was 1000 bucks. I go, listen,
I'm not just going to give you 1000 bucks.
She goes, then what do you want to do?
I go, well, if I give you 1000 bucks,
I'm going to put it in every and fencing.
And there was like silence. You know, I'm
not going to fuck this check and I know,
I know you just,
and I'm just pushing like ain't
we're women tried to play like Tommy,
you want to suck Dick and I'll you the
genome. And she still refuses. He's like,
I don't know what your
talking or your listening,
if I give you the thousand I'm
was thinking of your fucking ass.
I mean this ain't here.
And she's like, okay.
And finally she broke. Oh,
where are we going to go? Oh,
I'll take it through a whole dow.
Wherever the fuck you know that.
So Larry and I go meet me on
the corner by the gym. Now.
That bitch is still wait. She's been
calling me since Thursday night.
Every hour. The Hour. Where
are you at, boo. Where you at?
Bu I didn't have the money.
You gotta help me with that paper with
somebody if you ain't got nothing bothers
me. I went to the bottom half
then I got to taste them. Brian.
She's fucking amazing. Yeah.
11 corners. What? Jersey? Yeah,
we'll talk
seminar 11 then given out our spot.
Come on Joey,
hone up her spot. She needs $1,000 a
month. Get to go down there and go.
You know Joey Diaz has been talking
shit about you. I don't give a fuck.
I ain't got to give it to her. Get a
finer putting. Listen, listen to me.
Black chick for months.
That's a fucking 10 with a blonde wig
that I've seen her walk and that studio,
in fact,
she hangs out outside of the Gelson's on
weight too for old Jewish read old man.
Really? I've seen it. I've parked
there. My wife has gone to Gelson's.
I waited outside with the baby
and seen her with a blonde wig.
I had been in that coffee shop when
she walks by and everybody looks at it.
She's young,
she's young.
Cause she came into the coffee shop
once and she started asking us questions
about where this, that like playing,
you know, just in case somebody said,
you look good, right? Why? I'm
busy right now. What are you doing?
You can tell she's right. They get away
with it. Oh yeah, she's a professional.
The young girl does it right.
She doesn't wear the heels.
She has the backpack, you
know, she's the real deal.
I've seen her up and down that fucking
thing for months. So this girl,
if you do it right, they, you know,
they got away with it with the backpack
and no sexy clothes. Blonde wig,
black and blonde wig,
or it makes me think transseptal ginger
black and blonde black. Well, I ran,
went the redheaded wig.
They're good as the Brian tasks.
Her Aaron's Bright Orange Blonde
wig is weird on a black lady.
Oh, okay. It just looks kind of
like it's odd to z. Well it's,
you know, you should be able to wear
whatever the fuck you want to wear.
But when I see like a Chinese check with
blonde hair and Asian chick with blonde
hair or black checkered barn here, I'm
like, you look good with black hair.
Like you don't have to do that. Right.
But what difference does it make sure.
Blonde hair. Who's Eve? Eve, the
chicken that TV show the wrapper.
What TV shows up? I Dunno. Eve. Jamie.
You know what it is? What's the,
should shitty from like the nineties
early 2000 halls. She's tall.
She's in the barber shop.
She has blonde hair.
You got this fucking guy. Don't looks like
the old manager from the comedy store.
Eva's from fell down right then.
Oh, to go with, she's big Joe Rogan.
That's a big model. That's a pretty
girl. Yeah, she's good looking.
I'm like, I look at it.
Yeah, she's in barber shop,
but I think she was a blonde wig.
That's our hair bleached blonde.
Looks like she's banking
guys and she's tall.
So many black checks where weaves,
you know, which is really strange.
Like they were hair, like kind of sewn
into their hair. Have you ever smelled it?
It smells funny.
Fact oils and stuff like
carrot top or funny.
Probably fucked up like
gasoline and fucking oldest.
Like she'll fucking exploded.
I would join it next day. Yeah,
I got to think to be some
fermenting on. Right. And it's hard.
It's not like I had never mind.
I can't say that story. Well,
you feel that the weed, when you
run your fingers through it, yeah.
You can't really, it feels like plastic.
There's a whole bunch of different kinds.
Like Tiffany Haddish had one that was
like plastic where it felt like the pretty
looked like the predators hair.
And have you seen Tiffany
Haddish just hair late late now.
She just has this humongous like seventies
fro nine and every time she's in a
picture with somebody it looks like
in between two ferns. It's great.
Yeah. We know this documentary.
Jamie shut all the shit off.
So we use is like what
the blonde girl had a yes,
that's a weed. I'm talking about
what black girls have like yeah,
that's what we've to, okay, it's a, heroin
was confused. We can't get a weave. Yeah,
guys can get weaves. Yeah. They just,
so your hair on other Nicholas cage and
all his mood, he gets a fucking, we've,
whenever we think well they also have
these, these wigs that have with,
it's like a lace front,
so it looks like your skin,
they glue it to your head and it looks
like the Harris coming right out of your
skin until you get right up in there
and you're like, Whoa, the fuck's gonna.
Hmm. Hmm. Hmm. Yeah. They don't
have that down right either.
Because there's that show undercover boss,
I don't have you ever see that where they
take like a CEO of like Boston market
and then he gets thrown in as a regular
employee at one of their stores and it's
cool because he catches all the things
wrong with his store and people don't
know,
but they always give them like the
dumbest like fake mustache and it looks so
fake and all the employees
have to be like, all right,
what is this undercover boss?
Like there's something all lawyers
are probably all in on it. Yeah,
it's probably a horse shit.
Then there's so much of those
shows they're faking like what?
I'm in trouble what like so many of them
are set up in advance and especially
ones that make people look bad because
you got to think like w how much they're
going to pay these PR,
this purse to ruin their life.
What are they going to
give you 1500 bucks?
Like what scale on one of those shows I
got to ruin your life and you agree to
this. They can't just film
you and put you on television.
Like you have to sign a
waiver. Yeah. What they say,
how they do that is they say stay.
It's a different reality show.
It's like this is a reality
show about a guy that's,
he's a waiter at this table and we're
giving him the opportunity to own his own
restaurant.
So it's like,
it's like another game should,
that's not undercover boss.
That's how they signed the
papers and they, it's also,
it's deception. Deception.
That seems like they could get sued.
Well,
it's deception by its own company that
they work for. So I think it's kind of,
there's like that loophole. What a
fun show them. They don't go back.
This book gives me 10 bucks an hour.
You give him a check for 600 a day.
Once you cast it, they'll go and
back Jack. You know? That's, that's,
there's a lot of those shows now too.
It's amazing how easy it is
to make one of those shows.
There's still hidden camera show.
Did you know that? My friends still,
I executive produced hidden cameras. Well,
how are we meant? Dell has that show,
right?
He has a show where he does hidden camera
things where we can make with money.
The more you get people to do,
like you gotta tell your wife you're
leaving her for a man and you know, like,
and you get like 500 bucks for that and
you get more for more things you do.
It's like,
I did that show for CBS years ago,
like six years ago and it was
called game show in my head.
And I would put like this little earpiece
in these people and then they would go
out and we would make
them do shit on camera.
Like we had this guy put him in the middle
of a Hollywood and told him they gave
him a suit and put some,
a news cameras like,
like you'll like it was a news camera
show and had these people come over and
you had to uh,
tell people that you were there to talk
to someone who was a witness for a Ufo
and uh, they took off and you've
got to ask these other people,
would you pretend it was you? Would you
pretend that you saw this UFO and a,
you got to get them to admit that they
were taken aboard the aircraft and that
they were probed that like did some
medical examinations on them and they got
people to do it. Yeah. That's
how I knew that all that,
that was like a huge eyeopener for me
about how full of shit people are when it
comes to you. LFOS where
everybody's talking about it. Yeah.
It came down the field
and it wasn't from Earth.
I've seen a lot of airplanes on TV,
didn't look nothing like that and it was
spinning around or circle and there was
no doors. And I saw these little,
those people are full of shit.
There's a giant percentage
of those people.
You put a camera in front of their face
and they just start talking and that we
didn't have no problem. We got like
seven people to just right away.
They just start making shit up
right off the top of their head.
All of them did it. No one said
no. It was ridiculous and we all,
everyone that did that show with me,
we all left there and we were like,
what the fuck man?
Like everybody just lied.
Like at least I expected
a few people to be like,
what do you want me to make up a story
about being taken the board of Ufo,
the Fuck Outta here. I mean
that's the reality show. Yeah.
Just to play marshes and got my car and
just go to places like a one of the boys
lake land and way of bitches.
All these mother fuckers that wallet,
the Martians, all these fuckers run down
that street like it's King fucking Kong.
They would start shooting.
Yeah. Today's world,
too many people have guns in
today's world. People. She was fine.
How about in the fucking nineties
they would've shot p Ufos.
They would shoot you if I was any point
in time. Someone's had a gun there.
They're willing to shoot like a Ufo
fit lands like the odds of if you get a
thousand people with guns and
a Ufo lands in front of them,
500 people are pulling that
fucking trigger and let me
and Telligen guy and when
you have a Ufo landing and you
have 10 people that concur,
they show the same thing or they
saw something, what is that? Well,
I go from door to fucking door
and pay people and what the fuck?
It could be a bunch of things. The thing
is, it could be from another planet.
It could be, look, if it's possible
for us to put a rover on Mars,
it's possible for them to send a
ship from another galaxy. Of course,
it's possible. Not only that,
we assume that these aliens,
that everybody keeps seeing these
gray aliens and the big black eyes,
we assume that they're living beings.
They could easily be robots if we're this
close to crossing that uncanny valley
and making some sort of an artificial,
a computer generated image. How,
I mean if the technology continues to
accelerate to the point where you can
actually get a ship to go through
a fucking warm hall, the Real,
the real like impeding factor I
would think would be biological life.
Like why send something living when
you can make something artificial is so
close to being able to make artificial
life. And when I say so close,
within a hundred years, I mean I
think I only anybody disputes that.
They'll have some form of artificial
life than a hundred years robot,
white skin that looks like gun
now go in the future. Let's,
the earth is for something
billion years old.
But we're not the oldest planet.
We're not in the oldest galaxy,
like not even close like the, the universe
is 14 billion years old supposedly.
So that means an extra 10 billion years
for things to form and possibly grow
even out 1 billion years.
Even a million years.
Who the fuck knows we can
do in a million years?
So if these UFO shell up and these
little aliens are inside of it,
they're probably robots.
I would assume that they have,
unless they figured out some incredible
way to bypass space and time and to fold
space and create a
wormhole and punch through.
Like they did an event horizon
and all these, you know,
physics documentaries and they talk
about the possibility of using worm holes
and it's all like crazy theoretical shit.
But until they figured out how to do
that and send like monkeys back and forth
for a few years, they're not, I mean,
why wouldn't they just send robots just
like we're sending a robot to Mars and
it looks like a toaster and it's
got wheels and it's rolling around,
but it's a robot.
If we send a robot that it looked like
Traci lords and it was walking around on
Mars, I mean that wouldn't be
what it looked like. You know,
it just so happens that we set one that
looks like a toaster, but it doesn't,
in a thousand years from now,
we could send wherever the fuck we want.
We can send Bob Costas to the
moon. You know, Bob Costas, robot,
Bob Costas were be reporting from
the surface and the fucking moon.
And I've never been a big marsh and guy
and I always thought that fucking,
you know,
you always think that the high population
of areas area 51 and maybe the south,
right? You know, you just write it off,
but it isn't the high populations of
Washington sightings and a Ufo says why
we're up in northern New Jersey. I
fucking couldn't believe it. Well,
you know why there's this is the cube,
the conspiracy theories,
you know the conspiracy theory y
that's where bell laboratories,
are they the jersey? Yes.
The bill. The big conspiracy.
This is the big conspiracy.
This goes way back,
way back,
there was a company on the Internet and
if you remember it called the American
computer company and they had
this website, they made computers.
There was back in the day where you call
up or you would fill out like specs,
like you know, hey, I want a 300
celeron processor and this and that.
And they would put together
a computer for you.
But they also had this website page that
was dedicated to conspiracies about the
creation of the the,
was it the transistor Dario laboratories?
Yeah.
Yeah, there was, there
was certain aspects of,
of sound and electronics that were
invented in bell laboratories and this
website supposedly polls.
There's the big conspiracy polls,
the cover over the creation of
these things and says this all shit,
all this shit came out of area 51 from
some shit that crashed in Roswell,
New Mexico in 1947 it was all
about the Rosalind Mexico crash.
They took all those,
whatever those parts of those Ufos were
and back engineered them and that's how
they created all this stuff. And this,
this website was totally dedicated to it.
It was talking about how there's a
military base that's outside of bell labs
like that they said was to protect
New York City. They're like,
why would you protect New York City from
way the fuck out there? You wouldn't,
it would take way too long for
everything to coordinate that.
But it's right next to bell labs and
you know, during the military days of,
you know,
I guess this is like bell
labs was probably created
post World War II I think.
So you've got to think,
you know,
there's the Cold War days and the
Russians and there's all this,
there's the technological racist to try
to get to the moon and all that other
shit. I mean we were, we were racing
with the Russians virtually everything.
Nuclear power, nuclear
weapons, space travel.
And so this, this bell labs apparently
played a very vital role in, you know,
United States strategic technology
advancement, like for whatever it was.
But there's American computer company was
convinced that all this shit came from
Ufos from the, the crash saucer in
Roswell and they back engineered it.
There's a lot of people that believe
that northern New Jersey is like the cap.
If you look at Martin, I'm fucking
signings. It's not rational and all that.
The Jersey that's fucking cost that
all the way the fuck you'd like Bergen
County.
Well,
it could also be the air quality in New
Jersey is so fucking bad that people
would just delirious all the time.
But they live in those swamp towns.
But there's one story that came and look,
Bergen,
and this is the part of town
where it's fucking uppity.
They interviewed all these people and I,
I stayed up with that and look to have it.
This
is a tape on Youtube.
Well, Youtube, they have,
they show where the thing landed on
the baseball diamond and all this shit.
But then they went to all those business
owners and whenever you see a last
night, I was watching something
and they showed a view of New York.
It's a circular building that's the
building that complained the most.
If they saw the lights, people landing,
taking samples at dirt out. I mean it was,
it could have been anybody.
Be fucking with them,
but not all these people in conjunction
now. All right. The liquor store,
all that'd be had a couple cocktails,
but all these people in the building
saw the lights, the flashing,
they heard the landing there, heard
the booms, maybe all those broads.
We're just seeing stars
moccasins on line.
Meanwhile you've thought about that
before you said that you're like,
this is the shit saying that they saw
lights and there you're talking about
jerseys, so whatever. You know
what, I don't even explain it.
I know it doesn't work. Um, you know,
I think to the CIA came out with this
report recently about how many of the Ufo
sightings that people saw was actually
experimental aircraft that they're
working on and um, that was
uh, that was real recent.
Like they admitted this kind of stuff.
But then you also have like remote
control drones that they've,
they've had that kind of technology
like radio control technology.
They've had that for a long time and
they've been able to do things not like
quite to the level that
they can do them now,
but they've been able to
do things like they could,
they used to have drone airliners.
They could send an airliner
with no people on it. Just a,
they were going to use that.
That was part of operation Northwoods.
They were going to blow it up.
They can't land them.
They couldn't land them in like
1962 but they could launch them. So,
but then we're going to do is they were
going to have this plane take off and
we're going to say all these people were
in and they were going to blow it up in
the sky and they were
going to blame it on Cuba.
And that was going to be what led us
to go to war with Cuba because that was
when like the Russians were trying to
put military bases there and they were
going to have missiles pointed
at the u s from right over there.
That was the bay of Pigs and all that
shit like that. It got real hot and heavy.
There was this like,
like real showdown between the United
States and Russia over Cuba and over them
having missiles in Cuba. And one of
the things that we're gonna do it,
they're going to arm Cuban friendlies.
They're going to give like
people that they were,
they had good relationships with.
We're going to give them arms and have
them attack Guantanamo Bay cause we have
a military base in Cuba.
And this blowing up,
this airliner was a big
part of their thing.
Like everyone's hair make
up a bunch of fake people.
They're all missing and have actors
play their parents crying on TV,
all that kind of shit.
But they,
they didn't have the capability
in 1962 to shoot a plane up.
They couldn't land it,
like I said,
but they could definitely fly that
fucking thing. It's pretty crazy.
So you gotta think how many like remote
controlled like saucers did they have?
How many remote controlled, I mean the,
some of the drones that they have now,
they look completely alien.
Early seventies
the Martians landed him not taking
county park or mid seventies
when they landed. So, but
since then it's, it's,
there's a ton of fucking spots and
people spot those things of northern New
Jersey CIA admits.
Most of you have seen most of UFC UFC,
most of UFO sightings in the 1950s
and the 60s where our planes,
yeah, they have all these crazy
jets. Apparently they're working on,
it was confirming in a report that the
u two spy planes and a test flights over
the u s coincided with a lot
of, uh, the UFO sightings.
Yeah. I mean, they think
about that fucking,
if you ever seen one of those stealth
bombers and real life ever seen one flying
overhead. No, dude, it looks like
you're in a science fiction movie.
It's like some war of the
worlds star trek type shit.
We were in Palmdale and we were doing
fear factor and we saw several of them
because fear factor started post nine 11.
So it was like right after nine 11.
It was actually one of the
things that people are saying.
One of the dumb ass fucking report or
questions that I got when I was, uh,
doing press for fear factor.
This lady goes,
don't you think that it's in poor taste
to have a show that concentrates on fear
right after nine 11. Wow.
Like you fucking idiot.
They're going to jump off a bridge with
a bungee cord and Eda eyeball like, yeah,
it's like the terrorist one. You're
right. The terrorist one. But, um,
um, my point being that like
we, when those things flew by,
we were out there in Palm Dale and those
things flew by because it was like a
lot of military activity. Like it was
right when the war was about to start.
They looked like they were from another
planet. Man. I know they weren't.
I know there were,
they were going,
they were going to Ed for Edwards
Air Force Base is right out there.
Didn't matter. When you see him you're
like, oh my God, there's are aliens.
Like it feels like they're alien.
Like you see that black
fucking thing shoot sound.
I bet dude,
they're fast as shit and they look,
they don't look like any
plane you've ever seen before.
They look like space ships.
It looks like a scene in star wars where
you have some sort of a star port and
then you know,
in the background all these planes
are landing and taking off into space.
That's what we all thought we would be
seeing by now anyway. Right. We would all,
when you, if you are a
kid and he said, hey Joey,
what do you think it's going to
be like in 2015 you'd be like, oh,
fucking space travel for sure.
Right?
Everybody thought we'd have
bases on the moon by now.
Everybody thought we'd
be flying around in jets.
Everybody would it be going all over
the place and hybrid cars back to the
future. This was the year that
2015 was back to the future too.
When he comes in and ours, all the cards
flying around, we had hung out words,
no flying cars, flying cars they
do have will fucking kill you.
I actually you this one that's
supposed to be pretty good.
There's a couple of different
guys who've made flying cars,
but one of them has like these folding
wings and you drive around like this and
then when you take off
the thing goes Jan clink,
clink and [inaudible] the [inaudible],
the wings come down and you fly like so
you're driving around with the wings up
and you could drive
around town like a normal,
you know as good as like a Prius or
something. And then when you want to,
you lower the wings down
moral drive that traffic.
But this motherfucker up right here,
I would need a large parachute
on that fucking thing. Fuck that.
There's gonna be drunk drivers in the sky
now. That's our all everyone's houses.
We'll have like a car in it at one point.
I think once they figured
out like Google drive,
like Google driving cars and they figured
out how to keep cars in their lanes
and have them avoid each other, like
no matter what, they can't collide.
Once that technology becomes like
standard, then I think you could,
might be able to have some sort of
a flying vehicle. But until they do,
you're going to have people like you
ever watch people and like little private
planes just fly around.
They fall into this fucking fly around.
I went with Phil Hartman. He took me up
to, to look at real estate and we uh,
gotten one of us,
he had a little single engine plane and
we took this plane up into the sky and
we just flew. He went wherever he wanted
to. Like, I'll show you where Malibu.
Ah. He doesn't have to call somebody and
say, Hey, I'm going to fly over by Malibu.
Is that cool? No, he
just does it like they,
and they hit each other sometimes all the
time. Wasn't just crashed on Van Nuys.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. [inaudible]
the only reason why more
don't it's because they're
not more people flying. Yeah.
You know? Did you watch people fucking
spin out like retards in this rain?
Oh yeah. So many people. Yeah.
I saw so many people crash in the rain.
They just forgot how to drive in the rain.
I got some good videos.
I have that dashboard camera now,
so everywhere I go it records HD video
and every night during the rain storms
just pull out,
save it to computer.
There's just tons of clips that people
like running red lights and almost
hitting other cars. They don't know
how to stop. They don't slow down.
It's amazing,
California.
We get rain maybe 10 times
a year and a crazy year.
People don't believe that, but
that is real. Right? I mean,
the last year did we get
rained three times last year.
It wasn't even three times.
It probably wasn't right.
They say we need 11 trillion gallons of
water to to even out what we've lost in
this three year drought. We're still
in a bad drought. Right? Like that.
That rain did anything right.
It's better than no rain,
but we need 11 trillion gallons of north.
That taking the water out of the ground.
Recycling,
usually you're like, I don't know
the vegetation that's up north,
you know Baker's field,
all those little towns live Wolf Cherries
and whatever the fuck they live on.
Strawberries and shit. Yeah, like minutes.
A couple of weeks ago. It was a
new company. They're busy too.
Fucking 2020 are they making wells?
Is that what they're doing?
They come up and pull the fucking water
from who'll the deepest parts of the
earth. They recycle it and use
it again. It's not a, well,
don't go deep. Look it up. It was just
on 60 minutes maybe three weeks ago.
Really interesting shit.
I,
I'm amazed that no one's figured out a
way to take salt out of water. I mean,
they do. Right, but it's
not commercially effective.
It's really cool water.
They have the Lua with sewer water and
they had the people drinking it right
from the fucking sewer
and people drinking water.
It looked like this dog right from
the sewer already was shit. Yeah.
Bill Gates said wrenches spills,
fucking old sneakers and get their drink
and I'm like a fucking mole. Itoh Hey,
you pay for it and you pay for it,
but it's a new machine and tremendous.
Do you think in the future where we're
going to have our own water? It's,
the water is going to be so
bad that we have in our own,
like I don't 20 gallons a supply
of water that we can use to cook,
Wash Herself, then we pee it out, clean
it. But it's our personal water. Like we,
you have to like keep your own water.
That's totally possible.
And actually might not be the worst idea.
I would be happier tricking my piss water.
Right.
Cause then he's someone else's piss water.
He can hack it. Yeah. And would you,
would you use your girlfriend's water?
Like you,
you and your loved one would switch
waters cause it's a little bit,
well here's the deal. All of your
water came out of someone's Dick.
How about that dinosaur fellas?
You think about it.
Some animal most likely pissed away,
some water and it evaporated.
Came down as rain and you know who
I mean? Cal Water. Yeah. Water that.
I think the amount of water we have is
finite. Like, and even though we're like,
oh, we're running out of water, I
think the water's going somewhere.
I mean it's still an earth. It's like
you might not be able to get to it.
It might be pouring in Seattle or I
might be, but it's all just water.
Like somehow or another it gets reused,
it evaporates, it comes down again.
It's all kind of contained in this crazy
ball and they say that a lot of the
water that we drink,
you know it's very likely some of it
pass through an animal's body and was
pissed out and filter down through the,
the like a stream.
Like if you ever like seen a a creek
where you have like crystal clear spring
water that's coming down from a glacier,
like that is a woolly mammoth, mammoth.
Dick pissed out some of this water and
that water like seeped into the earth or
gets sucked up in moisture.
It's very possible that a lot of this
stuff actually came from animals. Dicks.
So if we get to a point where we're so
good at recycling water that you know
when you're getting water,
even though it was poopy water
or piss water or whatever,
there's nothing in there but water,
it's absolutely clear.
Pure water and it's baked and spirits,
spirits,
the spirits and the past that can't get
the spirits like imagine if they drained
the Hudson river and use that
one. How many bodies? Oh my God.
I went over the bridge and threw
a bag of blow over. Oh yeah,
hook whose finger condoms in that river.
They're not a fucking,
eventually you're going to clean
them out with that machine.
They got a bunch of those machines,
the whole thing.
Don't they already do
that with a lot of water?
They'd take sewage treatment and they
treat the water and then they put it right
back into the supply. What they
do right now that's, you know,
our waters are that drainage,
the La River
or whatever. That all gets cleaned
and put back into this. The faucets.
Do you guys even drink
faucet water anymore though?
I was thinking about to see how they,
I won't touch my wife.
Don't you cook with it? That's an
issue. Like we all cook with water.
Yeah, I guess, but I don't, I don't use
my kitchen and I just eat out. Right.
But yeah, I guess I do cook with it. What
if you like make tea or coffee? No, I,
I uh, I have uh, arrowheads.
People like to be Bohemia
and use that city water.
I was watching some new show the
other day, I forget what town I'm in,
but it was showing,
I think it was San Francisco.
They were showing all these different
blocks where you couldn't drink the water
right now.
Like there was this whole
area where they're saying
don't drink the water if you
live on these treats. Like
what? What are you saying?
Like I have to just be on Twitter or I
have to be paying attention to the news
to know this.
What if I'm a guy that likes to read
newspapers and sit at home for a few days
and I'm drinking the water?
You knocking on my door or he,
he telling people you
assuming they have Facebook,
how you're just going to make them
drink this fucking shit water.
They should of storm troopers.
Knock on everybody's door.
Don't drank the water but they don't,
I have hard water. What's that?
Cause I like if I washed my car with my,
my car will be white when it dries
minerals. Yes. Is that really bad for you?
Are really good.
It seems like it'd be good for you too.
I think some trace
minerals are good for you,
but I don't know if like that
quantity of minerals as good for you.
I like hard water.
It's really hard what they say that
that's one of the things that it's bad for
people when you have distilled
water as you drink distilled water,
it doesn't have any minerals in it.
Like you can actually kind of fuck your
body up if you only drink distilled
water,
like distilled water.
Something that wrestlers take
a lot of times before they, uh,
cut weight because when you drink it,
it flushes all your system out of flushes,
all the minerals and your butt.
But a lot of people are saying like,
I don't think dolce fucks with that stuff.
I think a lot of guys are saying
like that, that's not good for you.
Like you need those like that,
those elements of the water with minerals.
It might make it easier to dehydrate
yourself that way because your foot,
but it's not good.
Like I think all that shit in water is
actually probably good for you blessing
because my old code p Lisa
drink distilled water,
really probably guy was as all fuck up
potential health impacts of hard water.
Here it goes.
This is a a a pub med study.
So it says in the past five decades or so,
evidence has been accumulating about an
environmental factor which appears to be
influencing mortality in particular
cardiovascular mortality.
And this is the hardness of the
drinking water. Oh Shit. In addition,
several epidemic epidemiological
investigations have
demonstrated the relation
between risk for cardiovascular disease,
growth retardation,
reproductive failure,
and other health problems,
and the hardest of drinking water,
or it's content of magnesium and calcium,
which is weird because magnesium and
calcium are things that people take as
supplements, right? There's such a fucking
balance to being a person. You know,
like if you have, if you drink
a pound of salt, you're dead,
you know that's fucked.
In addition,
the acidity of the water influences the
reabsorption of calcium and magnesium in
the renal tube tubule. I don't know
what that is, but it's not good.
Not only calcium and magnesium,
but other constituents also affect
different health aspects. Thus,
the present review attempts to explore
the health effects of hard water and
constituents. Wow, that's crazy, man.
Alzheimer's disease is linked
to Alzheimer's disease,
cardiovascular disease,
diabetes, and cancer. Jeez,
it's all terrible.
Hard water is fucking terrible for you.
It's weird, man. Well,
the only thing I use it for is
really just taking a shower,
so hopefully that doesn't.
But is that bad for you?
Because I know that like you
absorb magnesium through your skin.
That's one of the benefits actually
of a like flotation tanks that absorb
magnesium through your skin.
Yeah,
but maybe they need to do studies on
that and maybe it's not good absorbed.
Absorb too much magnesium through
your skin. Man, I don't even fucking,
I know you're taking magnesium
though is like, especially for men,
it's a very beneficial,
there's correlations between
magnesium and testosterone and zinc.
Zinc and testosterone as
well. This is weird. Oh,
so it's a ratio of magnesium and
calcium in the water is a crucial factor
indicating the harness. So I guess it's
just like when shit gets really wacky,
there's concentrations of dissolved
calcium and magnesium and soft and hard
water. Are you dealing with like
hard numbers? I guess? Hard. Yeah.
It's weird because like minerals are
really good for you. It's important.
Like if you don't have minerals, that's
where osteoporosis comes from. You know,
lack of calcium. Your body starts
drawn calcium out of your bones.
Like one of the best ways to prevent it.
You take calcium,
but they also say that a lot of gold,
a lot of our farm lands like the
vegetables that we're getting and the,
the plants that we eat,
a lot of them are nutrient
deficient because a lot of
the farm lands, like they,
there've been like, they've been
grown shit on them for so long.
They kind of like sucked all the good
stuff out of the ground. You're dead.
It's dead girl. Gaza in Cuba.
They said they're not that good.
No one railing to it. Some of the old
time Cubans said the fucking ground,
but it's been, you know, I believe fucking
leaf, it's kind of, you get out of this,
it's like two fucking fully
good job of protecting the dirt.
You got to use um, uh, mulch. You
know, you've got to use compost.
You gotta like your word replenish manure.
Yeah.
And also compost is big to
replenishing the nutrients.
Like that's the thing about dirt
is it's like you look at soil,
you think of it as dirt, but
it's like liquid. It's alive.
There's all sorts of shit in there.
There's not just like minerals.
There's organisms.
And worms and but like you need worms,
like worms are great people add
worms to the garden. You're like,
want them all living in there.
You know you want all that salt,
you want warm shit,
you want worms to shit.
You want them to eat the dirt
and Shit and makes it all nice,
easy to grow in those mushrooms.
I in Vegas guys, those fucking
things with good Jack.
Joey was up till five o'clock
in the morning and never
seen Joey. I didn't sleep.
He didn't sleep.
I went right to the airport.
He got the fuck out and seven or
something. Didn't sleep till late to that.
The visuals, those days are over,
but you got to go deep, deep,
deep to see visual tracking
music. I just giggled. I just giggled
my answer off. It was tremendous.
What is Vegas like on my shirt?
It's like what is the experience
of the craziness event really?
We went and did the show, right walk
off stage and I had a fucking handful,
eight up and that was my Vegas. But
then we went out and we had some dinner,
but we didn't really walk and talk
to fucking crazy people. You know,
Duncan had that fucking meth guy after
the show that was telling them about,
you know,
fucking Satan and all that stuff.
I beside it was giving him
his email address. Yes,
that's the, you know, the mushrooms. When
you go out in public, any of those drugs,
it becomes something else. It
really enhances, you know, there's,
there's a couple of different mushrooms
you could take. I mean, trips, you know,
you could take the mushroom
and home and become very, uh,
whatever that word is
and t itself and writing.
Or you can take mushrooms and leave
and go for a fucking complete different
odyssey.
That's an odyssey when you out with like
four friends and you reach fucked up
and you have to be tight with those four
friends. So I don't have to look at you.
We don't have to communicate.
A lamp to do was look at you and I
can send you the fucking mushroom
telepathically.
We know we'll lose each other in a bar
and every couple of hours we'll just look
at each other. That's
the real dog. You dealt.
What's going on by that look like at
your old body of tell you like you'll be
drinking,
giggling my son,
something wears with Joe and you'll
look at that same time and we'll look at
each other and go, you go
back. That's the fun of it.
It's that certain connection that you're
friends with me. I didn't grow up on, uh,
on mushrooms. I was more of a
microdot acid guy growing up.
All those type of loosen the [inaudible],
which are basically fucking poison.
But I had the same experiences with
my friends. We'd go into large venues,
concerts. We all sit together,
but we'd always find each other.
Duncan told me he took that, um, kind
of acid that has formaldehyde in it.
The pay blotter acid on
paper, you know, he said he,
he had been taking pure stuff for awhile.
They took this stuff and he was like,
it's so disgusting. He was
like, it hurt my bones.
Strychnine strychnine yeah,
that's been around, you know,
why does it have strychnine when I
taught part of the process like when you
smoke crack this fucking the Turpentine
and that you know acid as opposed to
[inaudible] supposedly what we were told
it was to stick it to the payment page.
It really is tricky line.
Is that a Snopes thing?
It might or it might've been a
snips thing. I do know that when he,
when I used to have it in my vials and
like sell it and I've just like you got
to sugar cube and I just drop a little
drop on the sugar cube that never had the
back or
the bone problems,
you know with the liquid acid and the
microdots didn't either because those were
like those little black ones that
pretty much just had a bubble of acid
bubble of so liquid
to me, the liquid and the sugar cube
or in the eye right in the eye ball.
I never did the,
I never thought would fuck me up.
I was very fortunate I got those. I got
to beat these guys when I was growing up.
There were a hallucinogenic expert,
you know, that's what they did.
They made that shit on the weekends
all week long and they pumped it out to
college kids, but they pumped
out, you know, groceries.
They would sell you 144 heads,
you know, and that's all they did.
And they made 10,000 fucking
hits everything a week
and every time you went up
there on Saturday they
had something different.
Yeah,
that's okay.
Anti-Drug educators frequently tell their
students at some variant of the theme
of the inevitable strychnine poisoning
through LSD use. For example,
the strict nine is commonly sold as a
cheaper substitute for Lsd by unscrupulous
drug dealers.
That strict nine is a byproduct of
LSD synthesis that the body produces
strychnine as a result of LSD metabolism
or that strict nine is used as a
preservative to prevent the otherwise
natural rapid decomposition of the LSD
allowing it to be stored or that strict
nine is somehow necessary to bond LSD to
blotter paper. None of this is true. Yeah.
These claims have even been believed to
be propagated by drug users themselves.
In reality,
most hallucinogens cause some degree of
mental or physical discomfort after the
trip is over.
This is an indirect effect of the drug,
not strict nine or any other
adulterant. Okay, here we go.
They used to always also say that the old,
uh, which always seemed fake, like, Ooh,
so much strict nine on that,
that it collects in your back.
And if you ever get in a car accident
and hit that part in your back,
you're going to trip forever.
Yeah.
I'm an LSD stores and your fingernails
and you knew who your fingernails
constantly grow. That means you'll
constantly be tripping. It's amazing.
Fucking hate that guy. I met him,
I met that guy last night. Did you?
It was one of them. Same
Guy. I'm doing a documentary.
I would love to have you involved
to raise consciousness and expand
consciousness sort of in an overall
sense of consciousness. Basically.
Like the vibe I'm on right now is sign.
Didn't even care about money.
I'm just all about spreading
peace and consciousness.
So funny. Those guys that you meet that
follow you, that are fans of you. But,
uh, the other day there
was a few of them and uh,
we would play this game where like one
would come up to us and started talking
to the ghost.
Like Christina [inaudible] Jetski was
there and he starts talking to me and
Christina,
Christina said something to him and the
next thing she knows she looks over and
I'm gone. You know, cause I'm just,
you just kind of like hot potato,
you pass off the crazy person too.
There's one thing I'm not enjoying about
being at the comedy store is how many
people are pitching me ideas. You
can't just hang out there. Right.
For guys pitched me ideas last
night, came up to me, hey man,
I came here to talk to about this project
I'm doing on a really one guy was the
history of the Fart joke.
I'm not joking.
It's doing a documentary on the history of
the Fart joke and um, I will, yeah, I'm,
and this is true, I have no time for
anything. I have no time for other stuff.
I have exactly amount of time for
the stuff that I'm doing right now.
And you know, anyway, that comes
up to me, hey, can you do this?
Can you do my podcast?
I literally don't have the time.
I just not available so I can't do
it. And so the guy goes, well, um,
can I go through proper channels and
talk without watts? What does that mean?
I just said no. Like, I don't want to do
a history of the Fart joke documentary.
We don't have, there's no proper channel.
Like good luck. Maybe it'd be great.
I mean,
look,
they knew that a documentary on corn
would be great and you could have an
awesome documentary on the history of the
Fart joke. I just don't have the time.
What's he like? Whatever did it just
blows apart on you and walks away. Well,
here's a joke.
You pull my finger.
It was, it was a good guy. It
wasn't a bad guy. He wasn't.
He was like really cool about it in
comparison to how many other different
people have come by with ridiculous
ideas where they weren't cool about it.
Where it's just like, you know, I had
to tell a guy last night and like, dude,
you've got to stop pitching me. I'm not
pitching you. I go, yes you are. I go,
I'm trying to have this
conversation with Ari.
You've sandwich yourself in between us
and you're telling me about this movie
you're doing or this thing you're
doing. I'm like, I can't do it.
Like you stop and it's
like you can't hang out.
I don't get those. You know
what I get now? The business
propositions, oh well you,
you,
you need to move to Denver with Rogan and
opened up a weed store and when people
come,
you pick them up at the airport and do
a tour of the city and donate half your
money to the charity. And I told the guy,
listen, I live in La. You do know that.
You know, I've lived in La.
I can't, I'll be not wanting,
even Canada and I can't help it.
Well that means you really don't want
to spray it unless I really don't give a
fuck. What the fuck? I really
don't give a fuck. I really don't.
You want to smoke dope, smoked
dope. You don't want to smoke dope.
Y'All not taking you around. You're
not helping me. Show you a call.
Get the fuck Outta here. What about
believes in the that shit anyway.
I never bought high times in my life.
I just don't.
I don't look at bugs and have
pictures of buds shirt with,
read out my shirt. I just
smoke motherfucking dope. Okay.
I don't know nothing else. I don't know.
Not. I don't know about consciousness.
I don't know about fucking, you
know the Lord. I don't know.
I'm not roll it up or shut your
fucking mouth. That fucking easy.
I don't want to hear about nothing.
Nobody gets that shit.
You go to a town now you get
19 people want to do a podcast.
I don't have the fucking time.
And they want you to jump in that car.
I don't even fucking know.
You fucking know you. Well,
I'll take it 20 minutes away,
20 minutes and you're fucking the world.
That's 40 minutes in my fucking world.
When I go to a town I
don't want to do Dick.
Once I get on that plane to
go to anywhere the fuck I go,
I don't want to do deck.
Yeah.
I wouldn't do the radio that
they have for me and it,
I've already done my podcast for the
week. I've done everything. I go in and,
and fucking got to compute.
I got that little,
what's that new thing that the substance,
I don't even know what the fuck it is
and surface surface trauma that you got
one of those little windows can be
perfect for me. Nobody bothers me.
I go to my room,
I watch all this shit that I can't watch
at home because there's a baby around
and a white fasten your questions about
the hemisphere when you're in the middle
of the right fucking something,
you know,
and you can't say no to the kid
because they don't get, what the fuck?
They don't get a joke. They don't
get nothing. Right. You got to stop.
What the fuck you doing? She runs into
the computer room and jumps on my lap.
That's the end of the computer. It's
youtube and they got to watch fucking, uh,
something about the window of what's
rainy or something about animals.
And I love it, but that's just how
it goes. So when I go to a town,
it's the fucking sit down and write a few
jokes and fucking focus on the act for
tonight and tomorrow night and I don't
want to fucking drive 40 minutes.
You're telling me that they want to stop
and introduce you to their uncle who
was a fan of the his yard. I don't give
a fuck. Alright, let's go. I've delay.
I don't want to do nothing.
Well I guess you just don't care
about spreading the message.
The message is suck my Dick.
That's the fucking message.
Or what about the cause man? Is it
all just about sucking your Dick? Yes.
It's not really what you're bound in
a fucking week yesterday is, yeah,
it's about what?
I didn't want to blow job.
I just want to smoke dope and be fucked.
Him left alone.
I don't know what the fuck are
you talking about? They do what?
They have been coming out to
the comedy store, full force,
full force action lists,
swarms of a choke.
Every show I've done in the past three
weeks I've been hit up for something.
They don't bother me. They just, you
know, I love talking to those people.
I don't mind talking to people.
That's a problem.
It's the people that are pitching shit.
Just regular folks who want to come by and
say what's up? That's cool. That's fun.
That's great mean you have great
conversations and some of those people,
it's the people that like interrupt other
conversations just sandwich themselves
in and gay. I've got to talk to you about
this movie. We're about to jump off.
Seth Rogan's involved. It's
very big. It's going to be huge.
I've got a lot of Bobcat
Goldthwait we're in negotiation.
Looks like shut the fuck up.
I had a guy show up with a camera through
economic storm on camera, like a film,
a film camera, kiss me, took
a picture of cool and it goes,
you mind saying something
about my TV show,
my web series and I'm like,
man, I never watched it.
I don't even know what you're
saying. It doesn't matter. Just,
you know what I'm saying? He's like, and
they fucking jumped the thing at the,
they were in that car on the side
going down a hill and the store,
like they went up the hotel ramp and
turned around and they were waiting for me
outside and they just jumped out with
a camera and they killed was like,
hold on one second. If the kid fucking
jumped and came and the kid had a, a camp,
you didn't even say yes. I didn't even
say yes. He just got and I was like, God,
I don't know. How can you want me to
say something about your web series?
I don't know what the fuck it is. No.
Yeah, no. All the weed people also,
that's another wine. People just like,
Hey got this joint company, you know,
he tastes could take some joints and it's
like shitty weed with oil on it by the
way. So that's another problem. Yeah.
People were to give your shit to smoke
or you have no idea what kind of monkey
business you're doing it that joint.
Did you just give me this,
have cocaine in it? Like what?
Like now I'm going to get pulled over
and I'm, I have some heroin laced. Yeah.
Who knows? Yeah. We'll, the other day
some guy gave me one of those tubes. Yeah.
And I buy those tubes sometimes
when I'm in a rush by my house,
they have the tubes to the joint letter.
It had a little bit of Ash. I bet.
I bet they're like 12 bucks.
You smoke them and I fucking bad.
So I thought it was the same thing.
Well I fucking took him like really
want to get high on the way back to the
store.
We got fucking blast and we have to
stop at seven 11 and get water and shit.
Fuck that. Amazing. We, you know, and I,
I drive leads to the car
and I go home and I'm like,
I'm saving this fucking dude.
And the next day I go to the weed store,
like give it to the guy to go, I want
fucking 10 of those. And he looked at me,
he goes, I don't have these. I gave
it to the girl. That's my friend.
She went in the back and they go, we
can't sell these. These have waxer. Yeah,
that's what it is. Wonder. I was so
fucking I what was going on? He goes, no,
you have to look. CVW Kid went to
give you two of them the other night.
Yeah. Yeah. That was standing next to
you. I told him I couldn't take him like,
I don't know. You did. Sorry. You
know, come on man. Like yo listen,
I don't know you. You could be a cop.
And the girl gave you the buffet. Terror.
Yeah, that was, that was really
ridiculous. She gave me a cake,
a Bundt cake for my
daughter. And I'm like, look,
I'm not giving my daughter a cake
from someone I don't even know.
So I don't want to be rude
to you, but thank you very
much. I don't want the cake.
I don't eat that stuff. And I'm not going
to give it to my kids. She was like,
why not?
And I was like,
I don't know you like I'm not going to
just accept a cake from you to give to my
kid, you know? I mean this is, that's
weird. That's weird. It's weird already.
You know,
if you gave me a cake to give to my kid,
well I know you were still wouldn't.
I probably,
I don't want them eating that much sugar.
I mean I give them dessert every now and
again, but that's not even the point.
The point is like why would I do that?
Why would I give some food to my kid from
some strange lady that the first thing
she says is I have a cake for
your daughter. Like not hello,
not how's your night going? Not
What are you guys up to? Hey,
that was a really funny show, Joey.
You know what are your, where are you?
Where are you at next? Or
You'd go on the road. No,
it's like right away I've
got a cake for your daughter.
Like what the fuck out of here?
God crazy shit is up.
I don't think people understand how
creepy that actually sounds cause they're
from probably from a small
town where it's like,
you know they're bringing an apple pie
over to strangers. Like I'm your neighbor.
Yeah. And Shit like that. In the middle
of talking to someone last night,
this guy comes over, interrupts in the
first words are, it's about, hey man,
can you do me a favor?
And he's got his camera out and he wants
me to make a video for him. I'm like, no,
no, no. I can't do your favor.
Like you didn't even care that we're
talking like it doesn't even bother you.
You're not. Excuse me. Can I
ask you a question real quick?
Is You guys free right now? Can I, can
I ask you something like right away,
can you do me a favor? Oh, well I'm
to make a video and want you to be
like, get outta here. No, I got place.
Needs a green room. It does have one.
Yeah, but nobody uses it there.
Yeah. You use it to the main room,
but in the main room you have the night
a guy came in like I weaseled and he was
already already in the back and me and
Russell were talking about the other
night.
It was ridiculous like talking to people,
but there's a line that I
would live cross with somebody.
I'd love to go up to somebody lean red
band. We breakfast in that Atlanta.
We saw Tommy Heinsohn from the herself
and I had, excuse me, he was tying, said,
yeah, it's an honor to meet
you. I didn't bother him.
I don't want even want to fucking picture.
Stop with your fucking tight.
Just stop with the fucking pictures.
What's the picture you to fucking
dope fucking picture but a bother.
It's fucking guy and breakfast.
Mr Hindsight was a fan. I went,
he's getting the city. I was north Bergen.
Your second cousins with the Holloway.
Yeah. Thank you for your time
and he left. I didn't stop.
I'm not going to stop him and get
a fucking hug. I don't give a fuck.
I really don't. I've never given a
fuck. I've seen people a lot. It's like,
all right, whatever. I'm going
to go bother this fucking
person. You know? I just,
I don't mind talking to
people. I love talking. I'd be,
that's why I became a comic. I love
it. But there's a line that, you know,
when I go out at night, I wanted
to do standup. Nothing else.
I don't know what the
fuck you talking about.
We think I did on the way to the show.
You'd think I smoked 15 joints,
the weight dot Laurel Canyon.
I already got high, you know,
and I already ate a fucking buck cookie.
I'm where I need to be. You know,
if I want to smoke and I this
time because I smoked with people,
but there's other times and I'm already
baked and I got to get back on Laurel
Canyon.
What if I get pulled over when I got your
shitty weed on my fucking breath and I
got to do 90 days because you want to
hit me with that fucking purple fucking
fake weed. You got your shit
together. You know? It's just,
I enjoy it. I just, I don't want to get
pitched. I know where you're coming from,
but I don't want to,
I like talking about people.
It's the weird people before you go
on stage too. That's the only tool.
Sometimes people at the comedy store,
like literally there'll be introducing
you and those people say, hey man,
can I get a picture?
Like do you,
you don't hear that guy like bringing me
up on stage right now. Like you don't,
they don't care.
They just want to get that thing on
their Facebook and that's a real fucking
problem with the access to cameras.
People want to use them.
Even if it doesn't make any sense.
Like people weren't bringing cameras out
and like 2000 when we'd go on the road,
people weren't bringing
that many cameras with them.
We didn't take that
many pictures of people.
Most of the time when you talk to
people off the show, you said hi to him.
It took a few pictures of the folks but
not, and not everybody had a camera.
Now every fucking person you meet
every day has a camera that's up,
mindblowing,
change between days ago.
Yeah. Can you imagine like 20 years ago
everyone just having cam quarters walking
around the street and the worst part
is that you don't know when people are
recording.
So like that,
that people where people are sitting
there texting but they're just recording
you. I was out with my
girlfriend the other day and
it was one of those guys that
just sitting there staring
like, oh, I know this guy,
I know this guy and he's a [inaudible].
He's sitting there with his camera just
up like he's looking and I know he was
just sitting there recording
or doing something. Yeah,
people are fucking weird
air on. It's, it's a weird
time, but people have lost
like their etiquette like,
and because this is such a new world,
like there's no etiquette
as far as like cameras and,
and sticking them in people's
faces are asking for photos.
Like how many times you get to ask while
you're eating mouthful of food. Hey Man,
can I get a picture of like who the fuck
would ever come up to in the middle of
eating your, you've got to
in the middle of, hey man,
can I talk to you about something like,
no,
this is not the time to talk to people.
These are people who are eating food.
They're having a meal and not only that,
they're,
they're sitting at a table looking
at each other having a conversation.
It's one of the most enjoyable things
we do as friends sit around and have a
meal together. You know, it's like, that's
like that expression breaking bread.
You break bread with people
and what are you saying?
I can't do it in public or I'm going
to be interrupted every five seconds by
somebody who wants to take a photograph.
Of course not.
Most people realize that and they don't
interrupt you while you're eating,
but some people do not give a fuck.
You can be eating with a baby on your lap,
mouthful of food, answering the phone
and they tap you. Hey Man, get a picture.
Can I get a picture? Hey Man, can
I get a picture? Hey, excuse me,
can I get a picture? I hate to be
that guy, but can I get a picture?
You hate to be that guy,
but you're being that guy.
I bought a new car. No, not
this. Subaru. The one before it.
Particularly with some of the show. I
bought it off the lot. I was in a rush.
I left the indoor light
on my car was dead.
Koinonia and fucking
Hollywood at rush hour.
Do you go that the guy
that came over and said,
do you need help in the process
goes, hey man, can I pitch you
my mother's grave?
That was the worst thing ever.
When Aba, Hawaiian Guy, the car won't
start. I have fucking groceries. The key,
the key,
the fucking phone was in the car and
my car won't start and I got these
groceries.
I got to put them down,
pop the trunk and wait for
somebody with a fucking,
this motherfucker pulls over. I go, you
got jumper cables? He goes, no, I don't,
but I gotta ask you something.
Can I drop off a script to your agent?
And I looked at him
like, go, you're fucking,
it was like a Jersey boy thing where he
wanted me to dance. I couldn't fucking,
and he had met me one time.
He just happened to see me out of the
street and pulled over in the middle of my
pocket and came up to me. He
goes, hey man, do you think, uh,
you couldn't go anywhere? So you were
trapped. And I looked at him like, go,
you gotta get the fuck out.
Like you're not fucking serious right now.
You have to go through the
proper fucking channels.
I take pictures with everybody.
I did everybody.
I do theaters and after the show,
I don't charge anybody.
I stayed for hours. I'll take
hundreds of pictures. There's lines.
We have videos of it,
of all these theaters where there's
lines around spiral staircases.
And I wait until everybody's done
before I go get something to eat.
I do it all the time. So it's not
like I don't want to meet people,
I want to meet everybody and be friendly.
But there's a certain little line that
people cross that just shows their
socially goofy.
They're just klutzy clumsy and
those are the exact type of people.
They're always trying to pitch
you something. Who the fuck?
Have you ever pitched anything to who the
fuck have you ever pitched anything to?
I've never pitched anybody
in idea of never come up to
someone and said, hey man,
there's this project.
If we had a name attached to it like you,
I really think you could jump off like,
I don't even know you.
Like you're supposed to have an agent.
Like there's a whole system of things
that are in place for a reason.
You have a script, the script is good.
The script get read by reviewers,
a reviewers take it, the agency
represents it. They bring it out.
They'd contact other people.
They say, Hey, we've got
this script. We think that a,
this could be a really good script.
Do you have any actors that would
be interested in doing this?
And then they contact the agents
at the actors. You have meetings.
That's how shit gets done. You
don't just show up. When Joey Diaz,
his car's broken down and took what I'm
trying to break into the business like,
well, you're doing it wrong. It's like
coming up to me and saying, hey man,
can I open for you? Absolutely
not. I don't know you,
but you want to come with me on the road.
What a great idea. A Guy, I don't know,
flying around with me being fucking
weird and who knows how bad you suck.
You know,
you can be terrible.
I've had people that told me
they've never gone on stage before,
but they know that there
would be fucking awesome.
And if they could just
go up during my show,
it would be the right kind of show
to go up for because we have the same
sensibilities. Oh, what a great idea.
You should do. No Open Mike Nights.
You should just go directly to a bunch
of people that paid to see me and I'll
just let you on stage and you do
whatever the fuck you want to do.
I don't even know you a cool
ass that who says, hey man,
I'm the best basically baseball player
of all time. And, uh, just to like,
Dodgers should just let me play one day
and just get out there and showed up and
do, do you want to audition? No,
man. Just let me hit the ball bro.
I'll fucking hit a home run a guarantee.
There's people out there,
there that goofy. There's
a lot of them, man.
And this town is like a magnet for
them because some of them get on TV,
some of them get on a reality show
and they're so retarded that they're
compelling. And then you
listen to him. I mean,
how many fucking look at windy city heat.
How about that fucking movie?
That's exactly what we're talking about.
Wendy city heat is a diary of a madman.
I mean, it's a fucking biography. Don
Barris, Jimmy Kimmel put together,
it took this guy who was
out of his fucking mind and
they had this guy convinced
that he was a movie star and that he was,
uh,
some special and he was a
celebrity and they, they, they,
they hosed him the entire way. I
mean, the guy wasn't in on it at all,
in that fucking guy still around.
Man. And he still thinks he's a,
he gets people coming through his shows.
He's a real headline.
And you have to hear what this shit that
comes out of his mouth. He's all areas.
It's kind of fucked up man, because they,
they've essentially taken advantage.
There's a bobcat Goldthwait that's sick.
Fuck. Look at that. Look at his face.
He loves it. And Dawn Paris is the
master of dealing with retards.
Don Barris has a phd and nuts.
He knows how to deal with it.
Who's was the guy with
the wig? Uh, that's the,
the guy that fucks with
scary period all that time.
Ridiculous.
One of the big three.
But like those type of people with the
people that you get at the comedy store.
I don't mind the picture taking.
I tell you what at all the mice get.
So you've taken 300 pictures.
I've given out hugs.
I've smoked pot.
I'm thinking the heads off six pipes.
We go inside.
I hugged the staff.
I get paid as I'm walking out the door.
There's four fucking people in an alley.
Can we take a picture?
Where the fuck were you?
Where the fuck were you before?
Like once I'm done, I'm done.
I'm done. That's it. Once
it's over, it's over for me.
You guys know it once it's over.
You got a minute to make up your
mind cause I'm gone. It's over.
There's no more nothing. And those
are the ones, the only ones that I go,
I don't get this,
that we've been here for two hours and
you've been standing there like a fucking
bump on a wall.
They get nervous.
They want to be with you at the end is
now at the end as I'm about to go and I
gotta stop what the Fuck I'm doing.
But Vegeta wise and fucking like go head
wasn't living it no more. That's it.
Yeah, I'm done with the fucking
pictures. I'm stumped talking.
I just did two shows.
We just talked to 500 people for fuck,
I be [inaudible] seven fucking 30
that's the only part of the fucking thing
that doesn't, I'm the Sunday nights.
One of the purposes, but I stay in
on Sunday night is to answer emails.
I answer anywhere from 80 to 125 emails.
Good recent that I do it because I
don't have what everybody else has.
That's my little edge. People come to the
shows and they go, I hate your material,
but you answered my,
I ain't give it very often.
I don't think you're funny,
but you answered my email will say
that you and I ain't been on six out of
comics. They didn't answer
me. Well. People are shitty
people. That's rude. Yeah,
don't answer.
They'll come to your show or buy your
shirt just because you answered an email.
You know? That's how far I go. I go the
whole fucking way with these people,
but when I say that's it,
that's it.
Like I get hit obviously for
10 fucking podcasts a week.
I don't even know who these people are.
I don't even know who they are.
I have no idea. They're calling
me. It's and they get angry Joe.
That's what burns me up that they don't
understand what we go through here.
That you know, if I get in a car, it's
45 minutes to go somewhere. That's time.
That's an hour and a half. Then I
have a baby. I got no babysitter.
I got a podcast. I try
to work out, you know,
not to mention whatever wants to talk
to me legitimately about something.
Then I got a wife and then
we got to do stand up. Oh.
Then there's a thing that you have to do.
Call writing.
What the fuck do you want me to, you know
these people that call you up and go,
can you get my podcast? Yeah, we do
five o'clock by the airport. Listen,
you've got no a no dang cause
that's not happening at all.
Five o'clock by the airport.
It's four o'clock in the afternoon.
You're not getting me out
for a fucking podcast.
It's either early or late at night.
Take your pick. I can't do it.
Four o'clock I can't do it. Guy. The
Culver city. That's an hour each way.
You just killed.
If you're lucky,
that's three hours for your
fucking podcasts out of my time.
If you do Culver city,
you literally
have to do 11 in the morning so that
you're out by two at the latest and then
you get on the road cause even
to you're pushing your tool.
It used to be three of this town that
was two to 15 you'll fucking cup boats.
I drove at five once from Venice and I
got, I said, let's see what it's like.
Let's just see what it's like to be
on the four or five at five o'clock.
It was insane. It's insane. It's really,
I feel so bad for those people
that have to do that every day.
My Mexican does that every single day.
You're Mexican, you're girlfriend union.
Jesus Christ. Dude, we'll call
your Mexican because my boy,
but he takes that podcast by the
airport. Oh, it was crazy. Oh,
that's where the Fox studio is.
They do in the same place where Brendan
and I think Fox and five o'clock yeah,
you could suck it. You can stop. I
don't want to. Fox Studios are fine.
That's all good fighter. And the
kid over here. I was like, know,
I'll do your podcast, but we'll, we'll
do it over here. Like, C'mon guys.
That's retarded.
That's too far away.
It takes her an hour and 45 minutes
every single day and it's only 23 miles.
Oh my God.
Where the way from Venice to Burbank.
Did she do a back and forth?
It takes that much or, oh no,
that's just one way home. One way is
an hour and 45 minutes home. Oh good.
She gets off at five and she gets,
she gets home about six 37 Oh my God.
That is fucking insane. And I'm
the way there. It's only an hour.
So three hours. I know. On a
bad day she's in the car. Yeah.
She's pretty much going to Vegas every
day. That's insane. You have to be,
we'd be messed up. Pedal to the
metal. I made it back from Vegas,
wants to three hours,
but uh, I shouldn't have,
I used to make up from San Diego and I
was 35 really nice when that happens.
I have a lot of people
could make my records.
One 20 that's she's the drug
dealer was closing that one.
That drug deal was closed.
That one dog.
I used to get off the stage at the comedy
store in La Jolla. I would have line.
I didn't give a fuck. What a bunch
of, what time you want me to do. Oh,
we want you to do 45 to one hour.
Listen, whenever 1140 years,
that's what I'm doing.
So all these guests sets and all these
people you're putting up at 1140 I get
off the stage and I walked
right through the car.
The cars are already filled up with gas.
There's no need to stop.
It's pointed to the fire from La Jolla.
So what were they trying to do?
Is Sandwich a bunch of people on
him? Yeah, like they would just Tom,
how are you gonna have
to stay til $12 an hour?
20 my drug dealer, closest
one. I gotta hit lows.
Felice by fucking five to one.
This situation going nowhere.
I would do 70 75 from the
La horror comedy store.
They'd be gracious and once
you an immigration Jack,
the Irvine, it's a hundred
certain things that some clubs would like
to do where they want to put on there.
Good local guys in front of a guy like
you because they know a guy like he was
going to have a good audience.
So a bunch of like local guys were like,
Joey deans, do you want to shell? Can I
get on that Shell? Can I get on that show?
Like you know he used to
do that shit all the time.
It's Tom Sawyer in San Francisco.
I remember we used to Tom book the
Gig and then somewhere along the like,
Yo dude done. There's no more this no
more. Because he was like, you know,
I really want to be able
to put the show together.
Like why would you want to put the show
together when it doesn't cost you any
more? If I bring my friends and I
know they're hilarious, like listen,
just trust me.
I've got some great local talent and
these put on this nightmare of an opening
show and be like, Oh fucking Christ. Two
three guys. In a row that you're like,
what am I listening to? Oh God.
And then you'd bring, you know,
I'd bring you or I bring Dunkin or I'd
bring Ari and we'd have a fucking amazing
show. But they were like, wow,
Joey Diaz upsets people. And like,
I don't know if that's the kind of
Kinda Act we want of our club and like,
Oh hey, he's the one that fucking
nobody. He was the worst. Oh.
And I used to go there just to irritate.
I knew he was gay.
I knew he was dying to suck your Dick.
He was,
if there was a guy that was dying
to suck your Dick, it was that guy.
He was
fucking jump though.
The day he showed up with the two seater
to pick you up to do radio in the Pfr.
We came up and I already go to Joey
d is, you might be right. That guy,
I like a small car. He went out and
rented a two seat so he could have,
he was trying to get gigs.
Triggers are like Cosby comedy.
I don't want to hear, it's not
going to like calm. We got out.
When somebody likes comedy,
they stick with it.
That dude was a deck to a lot of
people and with that guy got fired.
I law that people are happy,
Bro.
He fucked over a lot of people
and I don't know about all that.
I liked that guy and he's still like,
um, what's taking good time with him?
Like two or three people.
How he hated when you
brought me fucking hey,
because he knew he
couldn't suck your Dick.
He knew he was dying and suck your
jobs back. Guy was opposed, spoke up.
I fucked the word go.
It's amazing how many guys on the road
look at all the guys when we were touring
that set things. None of them
are around. I know. Yeah.
They never fucking mattered.
When I see a comedy club owner though,
they comes and talks to me.
I look right fucking through and I don't
give a fuck a bed listening to the show.
Fuck you. You're a fucking pimp
and the heat is what you are.
I just looked frigging that warning
makes him a fucking game name.
You know from Mark Babbitt.
I have to go in and listen to
shut the fuck up. Mark Babbitt.
That's your cocaine buddy. Oh, oh,
it was booze bags were the same.
That made believe that was something so
important. And at the end of the week,
we outlasted them. We outlasted
those fucking pee. Those
people are important too,
because look, when Mark Babbitt
was around, I hate to be defended.
Mark down a walked back. It
was a great guy. He was a Greg.
The importance that Houston, look at
Houston County when can put after that.
It did go cup point. That's what I'm
saying. But he wrote notes about the fuck.
But no, but he kept it alive. He was
like the Jim Jones of calming down that
he was doing blow and you know, recruit
young kids. Somebody busted them,
put an ad out for young kids and shit.
You know what you're talking about kids,
you know like fucking how creepy.
He was a guy from Tempe as
much as a bastard. What he,
I would listen to the man
like his whole vocabulary was,
he couldn't wait to say spade. He
loves saying the word the spades. Oh,
like David spade, spade, David's baby.
David's Spain was thinking Phoenix hard
conversation and he couldn't wait to
who? You're not going to believe
[inaudible] pray their family.
They're not coming to your stupid
fucking club and Arizona. Okay?
They're not coming to your dumb fucking
comic club in Tempe that year like that.
All of those columns, you know,
I'll get them out and let them,
and you're friends with the guy that
said that all women wearing funny,
once he got fired,
you'll let them a juice got lost.
That's the only reason why he would
go to New York and go to Letterman.
It's amazing the self-importance they had
armed themselves and at the end of the
day they were worth nothing.
And what they don't know about comics
is that 90% of comics a fucking horse,
they have zero loyalty. So once those
motherfuckers are gone, they're gone.
Like they tried to call people and
say, hey, how you doing comics?
Just hang up on them. We have
nothing to get from, you know, more.
We had nothing in common with you.
I've spoken to 20 club on this,
that the God that I've said that Jesus
had called, tried to call it pilot.
He never returned my call.
You got nothing for him.
Well putting together this a one
night yeah. From Pete to to to him to,
to, to, to uh, Mark Babbitt
or the guy in Phoenix call me.
I've reached out to 20 comics. Not one
of them a hot, but you don't have a club.
No more guy.
I'll be only more than that.
Calls you back cause I feel bad for
you because you were very good to me.
You know Sarah and I was
the biggest con ever.
She bought Chinese check that
work for the Improv guys.
You don't know what the word
coach was the Saturday night.
She was an Asian chick that book Cleveland
and Buffalo in the 90s and she would
abuse you.
She would abuse you.
Like if I ever see and now I will give
you better call domestic violence cause I
will smack her in the
mouth. Whoa. Threatening.
You know what a lot of threatened people
on the Internet. Fuck, this is terrorism.
This is against the Patriot. She would
book Miami, Buffalo and Cleveland.
And what she used to do to comics
was fucking rude statements.
You hear the opinions of Joey Diaz and
Joey Diaz and it's my opinion and my
fucking heart mine. That's Zack. You know,
these people actually picked up this
thing like they were important and they
were no more important than
talent. Well I guess, yeah.
Well I got to tell you though,
the, the, the, the Co argument,
the counter argument to that, is it Mark
Babbitt? I think it's crazy as he was,
was responsible for creating a
scene, like a creative scene. No,
I ain't mad with you.
They had a god Damn Open Mike Night,
that laugh stop that was
packed. I remember it would
start at like eight o'clock.
We'd go once,
it was a lot of warning and next door
and they would be doing another show.
So they'd have a show in the main room,
which was a perfectly shaped,
perfectly sized room that laugh.
Stop in river oaks is one of
the greatest clubs of all time.
And that fucking maniac ran it.
And yeah,
apparently there was some inconsistencies
with the books and there was all sorts
of issues according to blow owners.
Yeah.
There was a lot of [inaudible] off the
back of bill con shit that he had the
basement that I have no knowledge of,
but it was fun.
I had, he broke my book.
Mark Babbitt was one of the,
let me just tell you
the mark Babbitt story.
Mark Babbitt went to Freddy Soto and said,
I'm looking for free tracks.
So Freddy came up to me at the comedy
store one day. He goes, hey man,
mark Babbitt looking for free try. I send
them a tape. I refuse to send the tape,
especially if I'm at the motherfucking
copy store. Okay. I'm glad you said that.
You know fucking the tape. Why is
that? I got busy shores comedy store.
You want to tape you take a ride up here.
You want,
I'll send you a copy of the 10 45 spots
I get. I ain't sending you no tape.
I just, I've never said
don't be a tape. I refused.
Especially people from La that
were calling me up. Again,
we're putting together a TV show. We get
to tape, uh, loving 50th Acom and stuff.
No, really? Yeah. I don't fucking
send the tapes. Mark Babbitt.
I sent him a blank tape.
Okay.
I sent that jerk off finally because
the manager I had Kevin Phillips,
he kept calling me and saying, that guy
come from Houston, keeps calling you.
He wants you to send them a blank tape.
I fucking didn't send
them a tape for a year.
Finally went that went to fucking Ralph's.
Bought a tape but an envelope and sent.
But Joey d standard was done a tape,
you know that motherfucker Columbia
week later and say love my tape.
And he hired me as a feature
at the upper for Bobby slate.
So fuck all you mother fuckers.
That whole tape thing is a power booth.
When you go to a comedy club and
you go to his office to get paid.
He's got a TV and he's got a
thousand tapes with does not them.
You don't watch those fucking things.
That's his fucking power move. Okay, Sam,
be a tape. I sent them the fucking
tape. So the first time he booked me,
he asks, I called him, he goes, I
don't have a feature spot for you,
but I have an embassy spot. I'm
gonna pay you 300 bucks, bitch.
The plane tickets to weighty at
that time was two 20 or something.
So I took the week, but I was
always looking for a better week.
And I got a guy in Toronto, the paint
me like 800 for a feature week, uh,
uh, Bollywood, whatever the fuck it was
called up there. So I did two weeks.
So I call it bad, but like a man,
I told him that you think are bad,
but I got a week up in Toronto.
I got two weeks for 800 fuck you and
your $300 super bowl week with David.
Tell him to fuck trying to pet me
off, but you know, and he goes, okay.
And about a month later I heard he's
never going to hire you again. You can't,
I don't give a fuck. He told me, he told
people I wasn't going to work again,
all this shit and I fucking called him
up. Bro. I fucked can call them up.
And I said,
so that's what you're doing.
You mean to tell me that
you're not going to fuck. Fuck.
You called me back a week later
they gave me through gigs,
opening up a port with a biggest field
and then this is that. We were cool,
but I sent them a blank thing that's
heavily, he said, I'm a blend.
And then he called me. I loved
it. It was amazing. Joey DNA has,
and I did a free show there once
and he lost his fucking mind.
Then we decided it was,
I came down,
it was when my first CD I
recorded a CD in Houston. We,
Pete from Houston. That's how fucking
cool is that. You must be listening.
I don't know. Maybe. So they called him.
Yeah, I bet. I bet that's good. Pete.
Pete was the owner's son and the they all
day they found out some discrepancies.
Babbit came in the middle of the night.
I left with everything.
See Babbitt was uh, do with, uh,
Carlos Garcia concert
with the lap stops money.
Then he will put the check back in
on Monday morning. So nobody knew.
This is an old fucking trick,
but when I was a kid,
I knew a guy that worked at a bank that
would give you cash 30 grand on a Friday.
You better have that cash back by Monday
at 9:00 AM or some people are going to
come knock you the fuck out.
But he did have the bank pro,
so we take the money out and
give him like $35 40 kilos days.
I'm going to give you 30 grand for a kilo,
but you better be back here Monday with
my 45 so he pulled out of the bank,
phone it right out of the fucking bank.
I should give it right back to you.
Back to what? My Monday. I was
friends with that guy for years.
I met him my sophomore year. I was
mailing something and something fell out.
I was working at a lumber yard and never
below fell down and when I went to pick
it up or do you ever going to go? I
didn't say nothing. I ripped that,
put it in my pocket.
That night I went home.
There was two credit cards in two checks,
one for like 20 or one for like 18 and
I was going to use the credit cards.
I was a young kid.
My mom had just died.
I didn't know what the fuck to do and I
went through a buddy of mine who I knew
his brother was a little fucked up and
he knew those people and I said, Doug,
I these two checks, one for 18 months
or 22 he wrote his brother's number.
You just called my brother, he'll take
care of it for him. He called a brother,
brother met me,
the brother had to be like 20 he came
with like three other fucking my field
seats and they go,
what do you want from this?
Like well I want one of the tracks and
you keep the level cause you'll have your
cash tomorrow,
Doug.
Those motherfuckers came be
20 grand is a backup below.
When I was 16 years old the week John
Lennon got shot. Don't you think though,
like we think about like how many guys
that benefited from having Babbitt run
that club or it was a great clubs that,
I'm just saying that I'm not
talking about the job they did.
I was talking to how most people ran
around and thinking they were the end all
bill. Like there's a lot of club owners
that they get to a point that they get so
cocky, they're like, oh, I'll call him
Hollywood. You'll never work again.
And people really trip.
You know when,
when I first started in this
business as a guy, that's the Holly,
the drummer from buddy Holly,
he books in Texas and
he's a real coach bag.
What he does is he calls and he goes,
I'm going to pay your two 50 at
night from Tuesday to Saturday.
And then once the Gig we comes
up, we only have Saturday. Wow.
Why can't drive from Boston to fucking
New Orleans for fucking Saturday night?
No. You know, I'm not doing it.
So I was working with the guy,
I had a great relationship with the guy
and when I moved to Seattle and he gave
me this weekend,
New Mexico and I wanted to go down and
had great clubs in New Mexico at the time.
Sure enough,
the motherfucking calls me cause there's
only one night and Saturday night I go
dog, I'm live in Seattle now. I could've
gotten on there for the other money,
but I can't go for one day
this motherfucking Toby. If
you fucking cancel on me,
you'll never work and Improv,
you'll never work for nobody.
I waited until the night of the GIG
and I call this motherfuck
at a quarter to eight.
He kept calling me page or are
you and I kept calling them back.
I'm 30 miles and miles
south at about correlate.
I call this motherfuck. I said,
don't you ever threaten me again?
It looks like your mothers had line in
that motherfucker hung up the phone.
What? You ever threatened me
again? You thought mother Fucker,
your mother's son. A couple years
later I go to Houston. It's that one.
There's some guy you're looking for
somebody to go to Mississippi the morning
and I feel like 300 bucks and I go out
and do it and they told me the guy, God,
that's the guy I beat.
Well he forgot called him by now.
What did he say?
Equals your name sounds familiar,
but I haven't line up at the store.
I'd done movies.
Just give it a Gig for three
bills. He goes, oh, your
name is Sasha. Really Kwame.
Tomorrow. The next day I called
him because I remember you.
You're the guy that called me
eight told me to protect my mother,
that headline and he still
didn't take any gig. Fuck though.
He wouldn't give it to him.
That's the shit that bothered me.
That's my thing, that
we're young, we're stupid.
We're naive and we believe in
those people take advantage of us.
It's like anybody else taking advantage.
He Babbitt was a great guy,
but the reason why the Houston comedy
scene the way it is because bad fuck with
those kids had at some point he had
them like, bitches don't look at me.
Don't make eye contact the fucking floor.
Look at the kid that bonded the comedy
store. He never did call me again.
Babbitt had them telling them,
you are going to be bigger than Carlos.
You're going to be bigger than this guy.
You know I mean bigger than this,
you know the next Bill Hicks, you know,
but he did have bad tastes. He had,
he had some bank.
You would tell you a guy,
I want this guy to open for you and
you'd go, what are you talking about?
Like what are you fucking crazy,
I'm not going to have people
pay to hear that guy talk.
Like you would have guys that were, they
had nothing, there was nothing there.
It's one guy who would just
memorize these like fake rants.
It was like this long for,
he'd be like,
have these big deep breaths in between
the rants and just ramp this thing out.
Like all these stats and numbers
and we'd say all this shit.
And it was because he had memorized
at all that. It was so impressive.
But there was no funny in it. There was
no comedy in. It was a trick. It was like,
he memorized all this
stuff and it's crazy brand.
We'll send it and then everybody
go, oh, that was great.
He did that thing and that was
his whole act was these rants.
But they weren't like,
it wasn't like a rant where he had a
point where it made like a bill burr rap.
Like you know where it's a rant,
but there's all these jokes in it pointing
shit out and you're laughing and no,
there was nothing until the end and
the end you would clap. He was, well,
he was one of the beginnings
of alternative comedy.
Like people go see him.
My God, that's such a
brilliant, you know, because we,
Jesus Jones wrote that song
and you're like, Jesus,
fuck the fuck you talking about.
He faded away and he cracked
it became a bartender.
There was something and that's
what, you know, a couple my,
my breakthrough in my life really came
when I did analyze that and I met that
the rector,
when I met that dude,
that was that they told him to go
fuck himself on saying that alive.
But dude is that Harold Ramis
here now really changed my life.
That only two hour. I had a great talk
with him about comedy and he goes,
I watched your tape. Why don't you go
to Montreal? And I, oh wait a minute.
You had a tape. I had to stand up tape
at the time. You have a tape to him.
Fuck yeah. That's how Reagan to stay.
That's how rapists I put together.
I can go fucking. So at that time
I went to, I went to see this,
get to know the rules,
don't know.
I went to see this lady
for a movie and she goes,
you're not perfect for this movie,
but my next movie,
you going to be good for her. She goes,
I want you to keep in touch with me.
And it was hell.
And with that bitch is bad.
Like that bitch just
hangs out with Deniro.
She was just doing it because she
didn't, Bronx County, she did Bronx tale,
those types of movies and she really took
a liking to me. So she would tell me,
sent me everything you got.
I want to push you for this morning,
but I need you to send me what you got.
So I only had at that time,
they only had the mezzos. I had that
gay mafia thing. That's all I had.
So I put standup on it.
I had a really good set somewhere and
sent it to him and I have about how rape
is pulling me over and he goes, your
natural, these pricks I see in Montreal.
I ain't got Dick on you. I
mean, this guy said, shit,
this is how fucking my hammock.
And he's the one that look
me the eye and he goes,
don't take shit from these books either
because they're all a bunch of clothes.
Oh my God. He was like, don't
take shit from these books,
the next shift from build these
bushes because once you take it,
it's like the blends Clemenza told
Michael if they should've stopped Hitler
imulitic Munich once you take this shit.
And I remember I shot that
movie in like September. And uh,
that October I did that.
No.
That December Pete from the goodness of
his heart used to headline me in Houston,
the first guy to ever headline me.
It was Pete and Houston.
That's why he still calls me and
I give him the respect as a man.
I still call him the fact
nobody else feels feature me.
He was headlining and he's like,
you're a bad motherfucker.
He saw me with Pablo and
Houston and he's like,
I bet the headline just so he wouldn't
headline being Christmas for two weeks
and pay me job before anybody paid me and
I went down there. Did blow went crazy,
but that wasn't the point.
The point blow. I went crazy. Oh, I
used to go crazy and not for nothing.
I just watched my episode of Coke case
after two weeks in Houston I was like 400
pounds.
My neck was swollen from the sodium and
the fuck and I not so tall and Khloe
line and the cocaine. My back was
swollen. I would go to Houston,
just eat that barbecue everything and do
blow every night and drink shot to yoga.
My style. You know what
happened in state. It is awesome
spot burritos from Houston, your point,
some fucking pounds on it and I haven't
been coming back with Dan and I got a
call from a guy at at the Improv and
this guy is pretty cool guy to an extent.
He goes, hey man, you know
this is a true story Joe.
This is like January 6th of 2003
and I had just done the allies that,
and this is the first time I was in a
test with Harold rape has said to me,
he goes,
both things shift from though these
company guys and tell them all to go fuck
themselves. You're a funny
guy. Don't ever look back. Go.
And I got a call from one of the heads
of the Improv and he goes, hey man, uh,
we just got a call that we
have a club in Houston but you,
you're working in the other
club. And I said, yeah,
that's what they were trying to make.
Bean will not work that use.
This is early on.
This is 2003 before anything and it
was driving on Melrose and he goes,
you know, it's not right that you do
that. We've always taken care of you.
And I go and I snapped Joan.
I go,
taking care of me were in Miami
for six 50 a fucking week.
I do 13 shows and I outsell the
fucking headline because I'm Cuban.
How the fuck do you take cab? He
wasn't, you take care of me. I go,
look at your fucking schedule
right now for the next six months,
go look at Irvine and my in Irvine and
[inaudible] Ontario and my fucking Breyer.
No, no, no, you give it to all your boys.
So don't say you fucking take care of me.
And he goes, well, you don't understand.
All you have to do is ask when I'm
fucking asking, open your book right now.
Oh I can't. I have to know right now
your pocket book. And they're like, no.
And I go listen to
conversation to fucking over.
Well that's anti competitive practices.
I go to the competition and I go to the
conversation's over and he goes, no,
it's not because you just
won't work any of our Improv,
and I could say that again
to me. I go, say that again.
I'm going to go down there.
I'm going to bang your head off that
fucking desk. Joe Rogan just like that.
I wasn't one of those
cocaine morning moves.
He called me at like 10 15 a bad time to
catch me in those cocaine days because
I was probably broke and thinking of
where am I going to get my next fix, rob,
and you're calling me,
threatening me at 10 15 in the morning
telling me I can't work Euston when you
don't do to me, and I said,
say another word. I'm three.
I'm three blocks from your office.
I'm going to go.
Then I'm going to bang your
head off. You know? No, I said,
you're going to say something.
I'm going to say something.
You're going to say something.
I'm going to say something that
I'm three blocks from your office.
I'm going to go down the back of
your head off your fucking best.
And the girl got her to hang up and
I went home. That ain't call nobody.
I thought I was done at the Improv.
And do you know that two days later I
got a motherfucking car with three weeks
from the Improv as a feature
spot in southern California.
So sometimes you've got to put your foot
down with these creepy motherfuckers
dog because they get a pile up to an la.
Nothing happens to you until
they see you on television.
They treat you like shit once
they see you in a commercial,
now they know. You know what? You
may not be that mother Fucker,
but you might become that motherfucker.
So they don't give you everything.
They still break your balls, but they
don't. Now they know that you're real.
This mother fucker could strike.
That's the most important thing with me,
that every year I keep throwing
jabs at him so I could cope all
the shit they won't. But I'm still
alive, mother Fucker, you following me?
So he can say all this shit. They why
behind it. Yeah, but I'm still here.
What the fuck have you done when a company
has too many rooms like that and they
want to big of a piece of the pie and
then they want you to stop doing the other
rooms that are in town that
you've had a relationship forever,
whether it's Atlanta or Denver,
Denver.
They had a big issue in Denver
where you know when you go there,
Wendy will tell you the whole
fucking story about it. She,
she had this meeting with people that
were going to open up another club in town
and they wanted to tell her they were,
you know,
they're going to either
go into business with her,
allow her to buy in or you know, they're
basically going to run out of town.
She was like, oh yeah,
good luck with that.
What are you guys going to
do for open Mike Nights?
One of the things she
asked him and they said,
we're not going to have an
open mic night. She goes, okay,
so let me get this straight. You
sell. It's like if you sold widgets,
why wouldn't you make widgets? You gotta
get your widgets from somewhere else,
like why don't you make your own widgets?
Like you're not going to develop
any widgets and they like you.
They're not thinking in
terms of like long term,
especially like someone like Wendy's.
The best case example, Wendy,
my opinion is the reason why there's a
Denver comedy scene like her supporting
those two clubs, the comedy works, which
two of the best clubs in the country,
she's a reason why there's a scene in
Denver, but she's the best case scenario.
She's a cool person. She loves comedy.
She's fun to be around. She does it right,
but then you got like a
Babbitt that you've got to
deal with his shit or you got
Tom, you got to deal with his shit
when I didn't have to deal with it,
but you had to deal with it. You
know, and these, these people,
they're responsible for the fucking scene.
There are a big part of the scene.
Babbitt was responsible for the scene.
It's obvious once he,
once he left the scene went away. He
was a, he was a key cog in that wheel,
you know. And when you got a person
like Wendy or a person like Babbitt,
that's like a big player
in the whole scene.
Like there are so important
because otherwise all you
have is la in New York and
Chicago barely has a scene.
What's the Chicago scene like?
Chicago's record ripping the rocket. Is
it ripping a rock and milk yet? Where?
Which club?
You got the xannies which is downtown.
They have an open mic night. I don't know.
But the laugh factory is doing great.
Brilliant boy. My buddy, his fucking
kicking ass went with as the manager,
they have it open. Are
they developing dog? He is.
He sells out on Friday and Saturday
with no headline. No, Emma.
That's how good Brian Boards go with
after Brian Boyd walked into that laugh
factors that would it be a county manager?
It Jay was saw the said, well buddy,
who is your favorite comedians?
He said,
Joey Diaz and every motherfucking shit
for you. He said the guy turned pale.
He hired them and the dude's over
there rip it that fucking place apart.
So who does he have local guys helping
you guys? Oh, so he's got a local scene,
but xannies his gray that
wanted rich or the other ones.
And Sandy's has three of them.
Yeah, there's, there's um,
what's the one that's just outside the
airport is tremendous. That's true, man.
I've done the other one that's
just outside. What does it,
what does that all that
I would shoot a special,
then I went off and so who was doing
the open mic nights stuff? This,
the [inaudible]. There's a couple
of clubs now. There's a couple of,
there's one other club in Chicago.
The laugh factory is doing a
lot of open CISM a commies.
You know a lot of places now. You'd be
surprised. You don't might get what?
A club in Miami he did Miami, Huh?
Yeah. Does he live down there?
I'd go, no. I don't know the
particulars. I just heard that.
But there's a lot of comedy going on.
Do you think you would ever
want to own a club? Yeah.
Seems like it would be
a huge fucking headache.
It would be a huge headache
depending on how you did it.
I think that the clubs
that are opening now,
a huge headaches because
a couple of weeks,
a couple of years ago, I was in the
mood for dairy going, I called Terry,
there's no fucking dairy queen. He's,
we're going all the way to North Ridge,
one of the North Ridge.
I did very quick taste of like deck.
The reason why is because these had these
fucking people that never grew up on a
dairy queen.
They bought it as an investment.
They mixed it with Orange Julius and
they don't know that they're from another
country and they went to somebody and
they thought that was the best thing.
When you go, when I go to the
dairy queen and Tennessee,
that motherfucker is only there
for 41 years. When you go in there,
you could tell he knows his ice cream.
Same thing with some of these
comedy clubs now for some people,
their investments and they come and go.
It's the people really love comedy.
And I will tell you one
thing when he was there,
when I walked into that
club in 1991 January,
June 18th, 1991 when I walked into
that club Comedy Club One d was that,
I'm a tell you something else.
When he was doing things at that club
24 years ago and nobody else was doing,
she was putting motherfuckers like Bobby
Collins on a Tuesday and Wednesday.
Nobody was doing that and then having a
different headline and come in Wednesday
and Thursday then have a different
headline and come in Friday and Saturday.
Don't tell me, cause I was there when
the is really good at what she does.
What the is one of the top three comedy
people in this country when you could
make a call and shut your fucking lights
out if she really wants to win the
deals where everybody, everybody likes
when the, when the loves comedy, when,
when the dreams at night she
dreams of an orgy. There's a car,
there's a comedy guy on TV stand
up while she's getting fucked
when the doors,
I respect when the,
I never had a problem when they,
when they asked me to leave and I
wasn't mad that it was business.
It wasn't my comedy or wasn't that she
hated me. It was something that happened.
She's a real, I've never, I never used,
when I'm talking about
50% of these people,
people that they actually become the
end all be all in Cami and we're scared
them and they fuck with us.
They fuck with you Joe.
They fuck with you in a lot of levels.
But do you imagine what it would be like
to fucking deal with comedians? I mean,
they developed this. It's like if
you deal like if you're a woman,
Okay and you're walking down the street
and everywhere you go man are fucking
cat call and yell and yelling shit at
you and freaking you out and you run into
a guy in an elevator, you're automatically
going to be like, what? You know?
You're automatically going be
like Jesus Christ. Another guy.
Like I'm tired of getting hit on by guys.
If you're a fucking owner of a comedy
club and you're dealing with Wacko
comedians all day long,
constantly.
We think about all the people that we
know that are fucking crazy, crazy,
crazy people that we've dealt
with over the years at the store.
I look at areas where the
craziest bunch of the world,
but there's a certain way to deal with,
they used to be a guy in San Francisco
at the punchline that you catch or
whatever his fucking name was another
country that you go up there and there was
no list.
He pointed you to tell you he was next
and you had to sit there and like an ugly
girl at the prom and hope that he would
put ya and after there was 50 people at
the end of the night,
he got everybody gone see you next week.
It was like the waterfront. When those
people went, they would get called on you.
You Ain't getting jobs right the
morning. You're working, you're working,
you're working,
the rest of you go home.
He did it in a way that make you feel bad.
God Sawyer did the same thing
that the people are cops.
They used to do an open Mike on Mondays.
I heard people used to call
them club owners would go,
I'm sending Joe Rogan
enough data to do it. Okay.
And then he'd come up think I
don't have a spot for you bitch.
I came all the way up to
San Francisco and I'm a,
and I'm saying that
was the douchey things.
Well how about Jamie and makes people
waiting in front of the laugh factory that
makes them sign up in the morning
and wait all day in the sun in La,
it's a hundred fucking degrees outside
and there's a line around the side of the
building and people waiting to go on stage
for three minutes and that's actually
waiting in line to go next week.
You don't need you and you have to wait
in that whole entire line just to sign
up for next week show where you have
to wait in line again so that it didn't
used to be like that. It used to
be the week of you can't do you a,
you go someplace and they sign you up
and you come back and I say, listen,
you get as many minutes as people you're
bringing, you're earning your keep.
That's one thing I rather know
where I stand and get fucked with.
That's the leg I'm talking about.
Really? You need a tape of me.
You just saw about the store.
What the fuck do you leave?
If I'm good enough for Mitzi shore.
Why do you want to tape?
Oh the fuck are you and your fucking
Shit town. Don't want to take from me.
I'm not gonna fucking, I'm
fucking comedy. The comedy store.
You caught me.
You want to tape go fuck yourself.
I'm not sending you a fucking day.
It's against my fucking, well,
it's like these people now
and with movies and TV, Joey,
they want you to do a coach store,
but they want you to send the real
don't though sudden Shit Joey.
But they know it's a Costar. They could
offer it to them and if they don't, fine,
I'll do my podcasts and
I'll live another week.
That's the mind and eventually will go,
this motherfucker isn't gonna.
We might as well give it to them.
I'm not doing it for that.
You want me to fucking
be a guest star Rickard.
You want to give me a series regular?
I'll give you a fucking paper and I'll
fucking come down and talk to you.
But for a Costar, we've been doing
this. Look at the IMD. Be What?
Fucking tape you.
You took aside.
Let me see your fucking tape.
I see y'all fucking tape.
How are you sending,
you
know, fucking paid. Even then I
had my fucking pride. Even then,
I wouldn't send the fucking paperwork
I refuse. I finally sent a blank tape.
He gave me that anti. Never. I have
respect for none of them again,
because I found that it was a power play.
It was like, you're on my court. Uh,
you know, you want to give me some
respect? What? Respect? What do you do?
You're a pimp. You take 20% of what
people come to the fucking door.
What the fuck to you? One of you don't.
You can't even play the fucking Ukulele.
The fuck are you doing?
You can't put a fucking Ukulele.
What the fuck have you done? That's
my, that's where I'm coming from.
I didn't want them to sub club owners
are bad, but they did great jobs.
It was the ship.
They bold that I didn't fucking like,
I used to bring Joey on the road.
Me like way back in the day we started
going on the road together. What,
like the late nineties yet.
We started going on the road together
and I would bring him to clubs and they
would go, you know, I just don't think
your friend is a good fit for this club.
I mean it's uh, you know,
he's be like, what do you,
did you not hear the people laughing?
I go there. They're all laughing here.
All those people laughing. Yeah.
It's just not our kind of comedy.
Like what kind of comment is that? I go,
you don't like funny comedy. And like,
I've had guys tell me
that he makes me look bad.
This is like way back in the days before
people knew who he was and they were
like,
you know,
let's just say we just don't think he's
that good and it's just like not what we
want for our club. And I'd be like, I'd
open the door and listen to that here.
Everybody laughing. What's that? You
know? And they didn't have these ideas,
especially in the 90s they had ideas of
like what comedy was and there was a lot
of pressure to be clean.
There was a lot of,
a lot more push now before the Internet,
once the Internet came along,
slowly but surely, it sort of expanded
everybody's idea of what's acceptable.
Like even things on television or salt,
like look at the fucking scene in the
walking dead. I don't want to tell you,
spoiler alert,
when they hit the people over the head
with a bass and they cut their throats,
that was on fucking cable
television. It's not an HBO. I mean,
and they showed it in the
most graphic way possible.
I don't think people would have accepted
that before the Internet had come along.
I don't think people accept that.
But now like our ideas,
I like what you can say
and what you can't say.
They're all so different and you can
get famous from the Internet and because
Joey's become famous from the
Internet, you know, I get to say like,
see I fucking told you,
I told you you were wrong.
You had this idea that everybody had to
fit in your cookie cutter world and they
thought that I was like a sick fuck for
thinking that you were funny. I'm like,
I'm not the only one. Like you're
not hearing the rest of the crowd,
but until someone comes along and puts
you on a television show or puts you in a
movie,
then they don't want to take that chance.
They don't want to take the chance on
this wild man. You know it was you.
It was our Dunkin was the only one
that nobody ever complained about.
Nobody ever complained about me taking
Dunkin. Someone there, you know, like,
cause he's, he's a good joke writer,
but he's also not, well he is now,
he's gotten much more offensive like
lately, over the last like three years.
That's new joke he's got, again,
I don't want to spoiler alert it,
but he's got some great fucking jokes.
But it was this idea that comedy couldn't,
it couldn't be like what goes on at
the store. It had to be like what they
saw on MTV. It had to be what they
saw on comedy central, you know,
it had to be censored. Shit. Joe,
they saw what they want to see.
I saw a fat little ugly Mexican
woman for years, kill it late.
But Maryland Martinez.
Oh yeah.
Then one day and the girl couldn't pay
her rent and then one day a girl by the
name of Lisa Lampanelli came around
with the same act on and she was a white
girl. She fucking killed him. They
went crazy over. Well, Lisa told me,
really good marketing. You don't
know what they're going to go for.
What comes out of my mouth and what I,
I've seen people say worse than me
and they love them and they love them.
You know?
I remember going for a showcase for
two and a half men before the show even
started.
You know that they were looking for
Comedians for side kicks at the laugh
factory 10 years ago. We all went on a
Monday night. They're thinking about me.
That was, they really liked me, but
he's a little too dirty for our show.
I never watched the show until about
five years ago when dad was in the hotel.
They put it up.
The whole show was about sex,
was all about Charlie Sheen being a
purveyor apartment. That was like,
so what were you, what was your
point that night? Embarrassing me.
Taught me I was dirty
and it wasn't for you.
I think I always found
that you got chosen,
picked on and little and
as an exam way magic club.
I remembered he thought
you were too dirty.
Artery was allowed to go on after he
went to a gentleman because he told me to
my face,
that guy from the comedy magic club,
I give them the utmost respect because
he told me on a Saturday night after I
went there and bombed, he
pulled me aside and goes, Joey,
I think this is the last time you
came down. You know, they just use,
you know what the fuck up and him
asking me and I'm not mad at that.
He's got that Jane Lando crowd and he
told me to my face and that's all I want.
Oh Dog,
Joe Rogan and I know that you I been
fucked with a little bit and that's why I
am as defensive as I am.
I don't have time for these people
and I didn't have time for them.
Once I made up my mind that I was working
hard and that I was doing the right
thing, I didn't let people influence. I
didn't want to go to Montreal no more.
They can't then a whole lot since
2004 I haven't wanted to do nothing.
I don't want to be, they were a part of,
you don't see me. I don't bother nobody.
Him In my own circle. Nobody sees me. I
go to the store, I'm not a part of the,
I don't want that. They don't want
me and I don't want to include,
but I'm going to keep doing what the
fuck I do and I'm just gonna keep getting
funny and I'm going to keep getting
funny and I'm going to get a hold of this
and then you're going to be,
what the fuck are you going to be?
You're going to keep saying you
don't like my style economy.
How bad are you going to work?
That's been my life since day one.
I've always been trying to prove
somebody fucking off of something.
They don't like me. I
can't be trusted. Well,
I'm still fucking here 15 years later
and there's been no problems and nobody's
missing a fucking head. So for you, people
couldn't trust me. You're wrong too.
If I wanted to rob you, I would have
run. I'd be a long fucking time ago.
It would be my pleasure to rob
somebody who talk shit about me.
That's how I row. It's, you know,
stuffed up or is there something
it somebody knows, you know,
it's just not working at all. It's like
I forgot what I liked it. I went before,
but do you want some tissue paper
so I, excuse myself. I'm sorry guys.
I just thought there was
something wrong with doing
that weird crackling noise.
I thought it was like it was static
thing out or they do to people.
I see what they do.
I know when I could sit here and cry some,
some amount of energy is,
you know,
it's good to recognize
it and to see what it is,
but you know some amount of energy you
start talking about too much. It becomes
best line that he Griffith ever said was
when he went to see how Mr he saw white
people walking out covering their faces.
I love seeing people now that didn't
like me 10 years ago. I smiled,
waved my thing. Well do you remember
that one time was not mentioning names,
but there was this one agent that would
tell me that you weren't talented and
then one day you and I weren't FirstClass
and he walked past us and the coach
and Joey was laughing at him.
Look at this fucking Mall Mall.
Get back there where you belong.
You know it's, it's the animal.
I think these guys get a little God
complex and they're not God because they
don't know the work and
the effort we put into it.
It hurt my feelings and a lot of it hurt
my feelings. Well, you when Joey man,
as they ever did, because it's like
they made it hard for you. Yeah.
They made it hard for me to know.
They're not around.
Nothing is so many people were not around
anymore who I thought would be around
forever,
including a lot of comics who came to
the store fucking barreling through the
store. Montreal deals, this and that,
and they fucking disappeared.
And then there's guys like me and honoree.
Let me tell you something.
I'm going to tell you something to your
face right down to red band with our we
did in front of me in Vegas and some of
the best material I've heard in the last
two years. I'm going to tell you that
right now. The biggie small stuff.
So when you think about shitting in China,
guys,
maybe that's material I've
heard the last two years,
and for you motherfuckers that had
your complaints about it, I been,
but somebody coming up, a club
owner telling me, I remember hit,
one of his first big jokes is texting
and shitty playing video games.
I'll never forget that oldest
thing. That was the worst. Ben,
he ever heard of this life and me going
another fucking moron that doesn't know
anything about what we're doing.
What was the same thing?
It was like there was no TV credits and
I would bring you guys to open and they
would just decide that you weren't
ready or you weren't good or that I was
picking the wrong horse. You
know? They would tell me that.
They were telling me that like these
guys, they're not that talented. I'm like,
here, you're out of your fucking
mind. Like I know what funny is,
I've been around funny for a long time.
If I was a talent scout, I mean my,
my record for like picking guys
to open for me that are funny,
that turned out to be like big
headliners. It's undisputed. Oh he just,
every one of them, everybody became a
big headliner. You know all of them.
It's like comics know what's good and
you're not going to be good every night.
He's not gonna be good. Every
joke, every time you try new shit,
you run the risk of it not working.
But the guys who try new shit or the
guys who are good and the guys, you know,
sometimes the sets go back,
sometimes things go ride.
But that's because you're taking chances.
It's these,
this cut cookie cutter,
bland, non offensive.
So that's not exciting to me.
What's exciting to me is people
that do wild shit and take chances.
But when you nor have credits, man,
they automatically assume, look, I,
I experienced that. The difference
between and my expertise if I have,
it happened for me really quickly.
But the,
the difference between how people reacted
to me before I was on TV and how they
reacted after I was on television,
like the, the gigs that I could get,
places that I could work at the same act,
but all of a sudden just one or two TV
credits and all of a sudden they let me
in all those like,
uh,
early TV credits that I got
like Caroline's comedy hour
and MTV half hour comedy
hour. As soon as I got that I was in,
it's just like they needed a pass.
They needed to be able to say, Oh,
this guy is approved by a higher power.
You know, whether it's MTV or whatever
it is. And then you're on a sitcom.
Like you could work anywhere.
When I was a kid by watch pri Jamie
Vernon can hold his bladder and I used to
watch prior whatever Kennis
Ryan Red Band got a pee on him.
I always thought that was good
five for copy in our lives.
But I gotta tell you something right
there in the last 100 years and I'm not
talking to this out of my ass.
You could go home and think about what
the fuck I'm done with you right now is
the best time that of has ever been.
Oh yeah, but tell you why. Yeah,
they gave is great. They gave us
Gleason, they gave us this guy,
they gave us that guy and
how good really where they,
you know now today what we have is we
have what you fucking idiots by into the
shit that they shoved down your throat.
But guess what's also happened?
The underground has become
mainstream because of the Internet.
So you the shit that they were
pushing at you 20 years ago,
the shit then pushing that you at
these fucking comedy channels anymore.
It's not the end all be all.
You mother fuckers have figured it out
for yourselves that they've been shoving
shit down on a fucking throats.
Well, we, you know,
and what I know is there was this period
of time for more than 10 years where
they were focusing on what they thought,
what the agents and the managers
thought was clever or inside comedy,
like comedy that the comedians
thought was appropriate there or that,
that like certain groups
thought was appropriate.
Like you got that alternative movement
and they were trying to push that hard.
Like this was the hip guy to be
attached to. This was the hip gotten,
how many of those guys did
we want just fucking die,
die, welcome, die. And they walked around
like they would do something different.
Yeah. Like what they were doing, even
though it wasn't funny, it was better.
It was better because somehow
or another you were, you were,
because you talked about getting your
dick sucked or doing coke like, oh,
he's too, so who wants
to hear that? It's funny.
This is what you're missing.
You're missing. Like,
and that's one of the things that freed
us with podcasts because you don't have
to constantly like express yourself
in a way where people have this,
uh,
you know,
this idea of you on stage and you
don't have to present who you are.
Everybody already knows you,
they know who you are.
So when you're talking about
something on stage, you just,
this is what I think is funny about this.
You don't have to like,
this is what is his philosophy? How
does he feel about the new world order?
What is his thoughts on chem trails?
How does he feel about his e equal rights?
Is he pro choice? You don't have
to say any of that. Like do,
you don't have to establish yourself
as a left wing guy or a right wing guy.
But that was like a big
part of comedy for a while.
It was like people would do stuff
that would establish themselves,
like guys would say things that weren't
funny at all. But like, you know,
if you want to like Bill
Hicks had a fucking bit about,
if you want, you know, a,
if you want people to not have abortions,
you fucking raise those kids. You
fucking raise those kids. Yeah. Okay.
Where's the joke?
There was no joke in it because back
then if you had an important point,
you wanted a sandwich that point in
between jokes. Because in people,
a lot of times to this day, people get
upset at that comedy and rightly so,
and they say it's preachy.
You're using your, your, your,
your time on stage to preach instead
of to be funny and you can do both.
And if you wouldn't,
if you're not doing both,
you're taking a shortcut because
you, you, you, you have an advantage.
You're on stage.
If you're onstage and you start talking
about something and you have a point of
view about Republicans or Democrats and
it's not funny, it's just your opinion.
If I'm in the audience I'm
like, I disagree. You know,
I think this, my opinion,
the differs here. I don't want
to hear your opinion. How come?
I can't talk about my opinion.
But if you go on stays with your
opinion and you make me laugh,
well that's different because then like
you've planted an idea in my head that I
might not ordinarily accept ever. But
you've maybe laugh with it, you know?
And like Ari says fucked up shit all
the time that I don't agree with.
But it's hilarious because he's not
necessarily even saying it cause he agrees
with it. He's saying it because
it's a funnier thing to say,
you know you do that too.
You say shit on stage.
I know you don't really mean but you,
it's fucking funny. And I talk about it.
I talked about in my last special,
it's a very important point that we do.
We say shit, we don't really mean because
it's funnier. That's what comedy is.
And for the longest time there was this
idea the comedy had to adhere to like a
certain rules in order for it to be
high brow or certain rules for it to be
considered alternative or
sophisticated or you know,
this is a, you know, this is
progressive standup comedy like,
but you're missing the funny part.
It's missing a lot of that to become
this other thing to like fit into this
ideology to be accepted. You've,
you've missed in a lot of the funny,
like it's not in there like your
certain things you don't talk about.
Like you won't talk about sex. You don't
ever talk about sex. You're on stage,
you don't talk about sex. That
seems ridiculous to me, but that's,
that seems outrageous. And someone says
like, oh, how could this guy be good?
He's doing jokes about,
I've heard people say that like you're
telling me this guy is doing jokes about
jerking off. Like yeah, that's
really challenging. Um, I don't,
I'm not asking them to climb
Mount Kilimanjaro. All right.
I'm asking him to tell jokes that
are funny, that make me laugh.
I want good stuff. You know, it doesn't
matter what it's about. If it's funny,
it's funny and those people had this
idea and for the longest time they pushed
that idea but now the flood
gates are broken now live.
I fucking the Brody
Stevens or running through,
I mean everybody's running through
and Brody could be mainstream.
He Brody's like squeaky clean but it's
like nobody could figure out what to do
with Brody and then all of a sudden people
realize like we've got to put him on
TV in some way.
Like he's fucking Goddamn hilarious.
Like how can we figure out a way to get
that guy on TV and you're the same thing
and do the same thing.
It's like the Internet has allowed
people to see what you really are.
You know the allowed people to see the
unit and all he had to do is like see the
numbers of the podcast that get
downloaded and then they go,
well I guess we got to get on board here.
And then they all just get on board.
It's 2015 there's a lot of these
comedy clubs I don't even know about.
A podcast is, yeah, it's
amazing cause I'm like,
this is your realm of business and
you have no idea how to, you know. No,
I'm not doing the puck. You have guys have
no, you just want somebody to come in.
No, no. You guys have no idea. No
concept. How can you not have no,
God said you went to the
fucking entertainment business.
They'll know within a year or two.
Within a year or two.
Everyone will know and it'll be the
most important thing that they invest in
every comedy club.
If you have a local scene,
every comedy club should have a podcast.
You should have your own podcast.
How hard is that? You've got a guy
coming in for a week to tell them, hey,
come down.
You're going to do this radio station.
You're going to do that radio station
and you gotta do our podcast for now.
We'll put our podcast up that day.
Everybody is addicted to the podcast.
They know who the guys are that
are going to be on that week. Hey,
nick Dipaolo is in town, he's going to be
doing the blah, Blah Blah club podcasts.
You know,
the fucking ice house chronicles podcasts
or the a fucking flappers finale for
hot fest. Whatever the fuck, you know,
name it up. The comedy store countdown,
you know, whatever the hell every club
should have its own shit. So like you,
you have the guy who's, you know,
maybe not the store because we don't,
it's not like a headline club for the
weekend, but any club that's like the,
like [inaudible] and Nashville,
they should have an hour podcast they
released every week with the headliner.
How hard would that be?
You know,
have a local guy hosted and have them
understand that the idea is to just shoot
the shit with, you know, if
you had a good local guy,
you could do it and you do it
under the name of the comical.
But maybe even switch hosts out.
Like,
maybe you have the middle guy
in the headliner every week,
do a podcast together that you would get
a lot of people addicted first of all,
addicted to that podcast and excited
about going to the club that week. Yeah,
I mean how hard is it to do?
He's been doing that for a
while. Is the Atlanta? Yeah,
I haven't day cause I remember the
punchline interviewing you long time ago,
Jamie. Yeah. Fuck yeah. That was a Jesus.
That was like when we first started doing
podcasts even longer than that maybe.
Did you have a podcast before?
We did, yeah, I think so.
I remember him interviewing,
interviewing you in the office and this
was like when you threw me up on stage
the first time, uh, back from
my break, which was like,
I'm going to say six years ago or so.
You're right.
It was probably before we
even started ours. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. He had a, he had a good
sense of it. Well that's a good club to,
that fosters local talent.
There's a lot of local guys that come
out of Atlanta that they're actually
moving the punchline. You
hear that they're losing
their location? Oh No. Yeah,
they're moving to another spot.
They apparently had,
they had always had an issue with parking
there and apparently just got an open
up a new browser and that green room,
they probably opened up.
Oh did he? They have that laughing
stall too. It's a great fucking spot.
Laughing skulls are great spot and I'm
gonna tell you something else about with
you and her defense in 1994 when the
high two headlines to her help the open
micros developed.
Do you know that?
Hired them like to help
you write the material.
You would be that six at the comedy
works. She buy, she'd cater it,
get like Tacos and you sat around and
your rope material with the headline.
Then you went and did the open Mike
have line. They're grading you. Wow.
A lot of clubs. 1994 back woods was the
guy who gave me the talk who told me,
get your life together and don't
come back here. You're funny,
but you're wasting your time. That's how
I got that. She used to pay Matt Woods.
Why? And she paid a
couple of other guys, man.
So that's how much she had foresight.
Like she really believes developing,
they'd give you three minutes
once a month at the comedy works.
That's what it used to be,
that you had to work around town,
you gotta do Miguel V's with Ted, you
got to do those open mics, you know.
But when they always did try the
home, grown her own comics, you know,
all those holidays, she
puts locals, you know,
and anytime she could
sneak locals in there,
you know the whole lineup is killers.
A lot of people used to bring their own
people because they like working there
because you'd have Rickards,
you know, tie Jordan,
Steve McGrew and some guy had to come in
and follow it and it was hard for them.
It's really,
so they guys would bring in their own
acts because the local guys were too
strong. She always had help.
So if like the comedy store,
so what if I call the comedy
store and say, all right,
I'm coming in for the weekend. Thursday,
Friday, Saturday, I'm working it.
But there's no feature or MC.
It's the comedy store liner,
so I'll go into that. You buried and
Sebastian and I'm going up to that line.
I don't want to file all that
mass. Yeah, see that's worked Jack,
so a lot of people started bringing their
own Wendy's very smart when they had a
club in Tampa with the copy forks first.
When I first got involved
with the comedy works,
they had Tampa and Fort Collins real and
where they used to send me up, Tampa,
Florida, Tampa, Florida and Fort Collins.
I used to go to Fort Collins
when I first started,
when they sent me to Fort
Collins every Tuesday,
every Monday and Wednesday they
did an open Mike for Comics,
did five minutes and then they started
the regular show and then they closed
Fort Collins.
They close to hamper and they kept the
death because that was her bread and
butter when she, wasn't she going to open
in Chicago at one point in time to, yes,
yes,
but Wendy's very smart man.
When do you knows that you're
not going to do the job?
Nobody's going to do the job. You're
doing a lesson. They love comedy as much
as you do when these very hands on.
Yeah.
And to get somebody to run your club
that loves you, go, you know, you,
you've been to a club. When
you walk in, you're like,
these people don't know what the fuck
they're doing. They, this guy was at a,
an olive garden. Fate years pushing
the spaghetti. He's doing calm.
It doesn't fucking translate
the Chicago Improv.
Remember the guy was watching us,
we couldn't smoke dope.
We couldn't drink people up on stage.
And then when we came out to, uh, to,
to, uh, we had some craziness going
on once and they were freaking out.
Got People on stage with them.
We can't have it be the green room.
We came out to Bob Marley exit, thus, oh,
I don't know. We have this dentist music.
Well went to what kind of
world? Like, no, this is, yeah,
they were trying to do some goofy shit.
You know that, you know what's funny?
There's two things that happened.
There was like two shifts and uh,
bringing you guys on the road with me.
The first one was like people didn't
want you guys because you were too dirty,
but the second one was why are you
bringing these guys? They're too good.
This is like there was a,
there was a shift somewhere like in
the two thousands where, you know,
I tell people, you know, Joey
Diaz comes on the road with me.
I like to like you have Joey
Diaz Open for you on purpose.
Like why the fuck would you do that?
But it's what you were talking
about with his Denver thing.
Like people don't want to follow
people that are strong like funny acts,
but it does not make it fun for everybody.
Fun for everybody.
Like why is that? Why is that a
bad thing? You know? I mean that's,
it should be the opposite attitude.
I mean if you've worked on your
comedy and your comedy is good,
he should be excited that the whole show
is really good and you just ride that
wave go on after.
Especially if you are friends with
the guys who are on the show with you.
If you love them,
you want them to have fun.
You want everybody to laugh
at them because you love them.
And then you just like,
we did this show it we just did in
Vegas was that fucking show was amazing.
That was a fun show.
It was Ari Donkin Joey,
me and the Mirage,
that fucking Terry fade or
showroom is so good. They have,
they set it up for that ventriloquist
dude. So the voice has to be perfect.
You know, you have to be able to
hear his voice, his act. So they,
the speaker system is amazing. You're
in the, I was in the back of the room.
I could hear everything like crystal
clear when you were on stage.
I was in the back of the room.
Not this time,
but one of the other times we did it.
You hear everything you say crystal clear.
It's perfect. So amazing room.
But just to emphasize that,
you know, a lot of comics listen
to these shows, these podcasts,
and they walked around like I
did fucking scared. You know,
and then one day I got it,
I'm like, fuck these bitches,
this is my mother fucker playing
field and that they don't like it.
They're going to go down. And my
life changed. My comedy changed,
my outlook changed.
You know,
I let them scam me the same way I let
people scare me about life. You know,
when I was younger they would,
dad said fuck you mother fuckers and
it's the same thing and I'm happy I did
that with copy.
I would have been really scared.
You know this club owners that
are coming to you and go, hey,
next time there's a club
owner that I worked four years
ago, what's he like, man,
you should put something on that joke.
And then after you got off
the second show, he was like,
you got to have my tag bitch.
I don't fucking know you
fucking jerk call. That's still
around. I don't want that. You know,
he would come up to me and say, oh,
this tag would sound better. I get the,
you know, get the fuck out of my,
and then that, none of the way home,
he told me again, you got to really use
my thing until one day I said, Doug,
what was the last time
you will fucking stage?
What can I use your fucking
tag the fuck Outta here.
And then after that he would hire me,
wouldn't talk to me,
the hope we can get the fuck
out of my face. That guy,
you know, we work hard at what we
do and you got to respect that.
It's like a plumber or an electrician
coming to my house and be telling them how
to fucking do his job.
I'm gonna fucking mind you booked me.
Now you're going to tell me how the fuck
the dude get the fuck out of my face.
A lot of them used to be comics. There
was a lot of guys. Those are the works.
Those are the worst.
Those are the worst I to call it
early on.
But he became a good fucking manager.
You know these guys hire you right
now. Big comes Jesus. These guys. Well,
the proof is in the pudding. He had,
Danny had a lot of good people that's had,
it's a good word.
That's my point.
But still he had him and he developed
them and they did something. Well,
he had uh, uh, this people
who are comedy club,
the go comedians that one
day go, Whoa, wait a second,
I'm going to figure out how to
make money on these drug calls.
Then they become comedy club owners.
There's a couple of them were local clubs
around here that tell you what to say.
You can't work clean dog work clean,
but you can't work dirty.
You can't work there. And then I
want to pay you or come to radio.
We're not going to give you a hotel.
When the one woman,
what are you talking about? You're a
comic. So when I worked for a comic,
I let them know right off the bat,
listen, before this goes any further,
you're a comic. So I'm not going to
have to tell you how to act correctly.
What's that mean?
That there's a TV in the green room that
everything's copacetic cause you're a
cop. And that's when I just don't, well,
every time I don't understand
what you're saying. She's a comic.
Does a TV and if you're a fucking cop
be dumping something standings cause
you're a comic and you know the business,
right.
You know how we act and
you know how it works.
I don't want to hit no misunderstandings
about checks or how the green roof
should be of, they should be sold as an
agreement will be. You're a fucking comic.
If you're a comic and I go to your
agreement, it's a size of a closet.
You're not a fucking, you're a
scumbag. Just trying to make money.
I'll fucking comics.
If a comic opens up a room at,
want that room to be that
much better because you're
a calming. If a comic opens,
opens your rule.
Well how many comics open a row?
Yeah,
a lot of Brad Garrett. A lot of
Vegas. You know, just being gay club,
it's supposed to be the shit
and Brad Garrett was the shit.
That's a big difference.
He wasn't a bad stand though.
I'm talking about guys that were
bad standups of what they go.
I'm going to become a standard.
Then they tried to tell you shit,
when you get there you're like,
you'll be a favorite bro.
This is not what you're doing.
You had the line June 4th of July and
Christmas coming back. Then tonight,
Uncle Joey's here get fuck out of my face.
If we were going to buy a club,
it'd be the Ice House.
The ice house would be the car.
Flappers flappers libraries
is a beautiful club.
Just the bullets hard to fucking
get people to go to a club.
You know like think about it.
Everybody that goes to the store,
everybody goes to the Improv is like
there's only so many guys, you know,
there's so many clubs
that we can work out here.
You know like when I was preparing
for the last comedy central special,
I was doing the [inaudible] on Tuesday
nights. I was doing the Improv,
I was doing Irvine occasionally.
I was doing all these different clients
like constantly ice house hopping all
over the place. Like there's a lot of
clubs here. This is like, it's far,
it's like a hot bed of of places to work.
This is one of the best
spots in the country.
If you'd been in the new ice house yet.
What you talking about the nuance?
I mean new Aha. There's a new huh?
Oh, the one across the street.
Supposedly they just had a cold
open on a January 1st and it's,
I heard it's beautiful.
I heard it's like to go.
They were doing shows there now they
had a show that they just didn't happen.
Didn't have there. Were those
the ones on the corner? Sros?
Like an invitation only party.
There was no,
I haven't seen him but I heard it was a,
I heard it's like the ice house.
I heard it's like the ice house main room
stage bigger though. It's bigger. Yeah.
It's like the ice house only
sits like a hundred something.
This was like 200 something
now. Yeah, but still small.
Still like maybe a little bit
bigger than the or you know,
but not as big as the main room.
I did the main room of the night and
then I did the or afterwards. Dlr.
Such a better writer. Such a
better room. It's the best.
That's the way you're supposed
to do comedy jammed in there,
stacked on top of each other.
Low ceiling. It's the most fun.
They'll closest thing for your, it's a San
Francisco bunch of fuck. Yeah. Tell Ya.
They just tried to offer me
the book to do the cops. Cops.
Cops is a great club, but the puck's
line, this show with the band.
I don't care about the money. Yeah,
that have a great fucking give a fuck.
Just let me go up. They go crazy.
What do I give a fuck? Yeah,
it's worth paying or getting
paid less to do that climb.
If I opened up, I think they were opening
up a club with two buddy moving parts.
Now I think they get the head
of themselves and it's like,
I always say you put the all these smart
guys together to do a double is think
of the fucking world. You know.
I still love this. That's what I,
I want to do comedy right there in front
of that wall. Breakfast. Anything else?
You're wasting my time. He wanted to
serve food. Go serve it on your own time.
Just give these motherfuckers
stay fucking drinks, stiff drinks.
Fuck that. Okay. You know really well.
It's 600 seats.
You get 600 people and he really,
Kevin Hart is going to play in your
fucking dreams. You've dumped fuck.
Well they wind up paper and a lot of them,
it's a waste.
You need to 5,202 of the
quarter for a great room. Brick,
a tremendous sound system. So hot dogs
next door would do something special,
but after the show,
if you don't have to fuck with the
wait staff and let them go with this,
the drinks bro, two shows, you know, and
get up. That's what I would do as a comic.
The would be paradise. You know,
there's things that you do.
These people now open it up. Clubs
thinking that 600 people going to show up.
You know, last night I saw
something interesting again.
I was in the room last night and I came
up, my wife was watching the fucking,
that means whatever the fuck was out last
night and who's in the fucking habits
up there standing killing it.
But Margaret Cho dressed as the Korean
guy with white powder on their face
walking across days like Fidel Castro.
And I'm thinking about what they put her
through 20 years ago and how they did
their,
and then when they gave me that ABC show,
because to now rush after
the Tub, Alan Rush. Okay.
They are after the Tim
Allen and Roseanne rush,
something happened and networks that we
got to get a bunch of comics. That's it.
That's the idea.
So they gave Greg Geraldo a show that
gave top row just show on NBC Butler.
Brett Butler, a show on ABC. And
they gave that poor Bogard show.
And are they insulted her?
They told them not to be Chinky.
They were saying all this shit
go, you know, be bored Chinese.
They just didn't salt in her insides.
Then they canceled everybody.
And you know what?
Half of these fucking punks today
would fucking crawler the tree.
I'm looking at Margaret show last time.
Go with,
I bet Margaret Cho's happy that she didn't
fucking quit a bail out or got hooked
on drugs. Margaret Cho said,
fuck you motherfuckers.
I'm just going to get stronger as a comic.
She built up a huge following other row,
whether they're gay or not.
They span the books and she sells out
that bitches tatted from my head to a
fucking towel with fuck you and Korean
letters to all these fucking jet dials
and 20 years later that
chick was killing it.
Last night on stage with
Amy Poehler and Tina Fey,
the two hottest comedy checks in the
fucking world. How you like me now, bitch,
what'd they put that fucking chick who
20 years ago they embarrassed or they
made them feel like shit.
He told her to lose weight.
Do you remember the shit that
she came out with years later?
They told her she was
never going to work again.
You do for going against the network.
Well how'd she go against the
network where so she told them,
but they would tell them to lose weight.
There's no fat Asians. Oh my God.
Cause Shit. They was saying that Margaret
Children, she came out and said later,
then I don't think last night if I
was Margaret Cho that took this Cuban
disgusting Dick Guy with them fucking
forced get on it and said, here you go.
America. Yup. You ups for a
week. This ain't no fucking
malfunction of a wardrobe.
This is just to tell you that you can't
stop comedians, Bro. We just get better.
Don't you know that you dump motherfucking
club owners and you TV dumped fucking
cuts.
We just get while you're giggling and
Auntie and next mindfuck would taking that
joke and breaking it down and
getting on stage and getting better.
These fucking people,
David tell nobody goes to see David
thought he's funniest as he's ever been
because that's all we do.
Unless we're fucking cunts a go away,
but we don't go away. We don't go
away. We'll worst than fucking roaches.
You know how proud I was
last month from Margaret Cho.
Do you have any fucking idea?
Dressed up there with a hat on and white
fucking thing on a phase dog that 20
years later she probably
thought she was done.
What do you think where they can't
see your show up? The three seasons.
What the fuck do you think you're done?
Who's going to hire me?
Look at that bitch.
She then quit and that's what these comedy
club owners and that's what all these
guys and have an opinion on comics
always remember. You fucking go away.
You worthless fucking faggots go away.
You go away.
We keep going.
How long the burns do copy with two
what a fucking cigar in his mouth.
These motherfuckers don't
know nothing about nothing.
They don't know nothing about nothing.
That's why now every morning I
wake up and I go to some of these,
suck my dick today somewhere. One of
these TV guys are going to hear my name.
Last week I had to drive by the Melrose
Improv and see my name. They're all,
we can go that fucking coke, that fat
motherfucker. I didn't do anything.
I just stayed here. Well, you
kept working. I kept working.
I didn't give up and keep working.
Right. I don't, some people get tired.
I never gave a fuck about none of those
cuts with that threats that you're not
going to,
I don't give a fuck dog.
I'm going to get strong and once I got
off the blow now they really got to suck
my ass hole.
Now it's two live crew now.
They got to suck my dick in your ass too.
Right?
Well you knows, but he knows you're
killing me. Fuck this. Don't,
don't crackling Casey.
Motherfuckers don't know how
you're going to breathe like that.
Reminds me of your old knows her one
year before you had your operation. Those
are was very, I was very nasally.
Just throw it on the ground there. No,
there's a garbage
fuck there's a car. Yeah. My old
knows was your awesome show you.
Maybe you should get
your net is carved out.
I'll be had it does your separate mark?
I don't know.
I don't know what the can you usually
breathe out of your nose once I get out I
got a brick spurred me to Jujitsu. You
gotta Bring Watch spray with the Jujitsu.
Really always go into a little closed
guard. I got that pop, go spray my nose,
steroids, something about
leverage with me or something.
Then once I cleaned it out,
it's good.
I ever since I had an ear infection a
couple of years ago, I went swimming.
I had an ear infection. Then
I went in and uh, I flew, I,
I fucked up and I went to the doc and
he's stuck the fuck the probe, my nose.
My nose has been all fucked up
and they sent me that sprays,
but this sprays suck. I live on fucking
Africa. You get addicted to that stuff,
to the real issue with those appraisers.
You're, you're the inside of your nose,
gets addicted to that spray and
won't open up unless you have it.
That's very common. People
get in when you're, you know,
your body's responding and wants that
shit. It swells up and it makes it worse.
It's terrible. There's your
neighbors ever rage, rage,
rage against the dying of the light.
Oh, it's not that kind of steroids.
If they gave me, I have steroids at the
house and it was mostly sprayed two times
to show spray.
It's a shame.
But I'm writing addicted than I was spread
here. And Yeah, nasal spray addiction.
Is it real Mayo Clinic? Yeah. It's that
right or clean it right out though.
Like if you do a bump will that
we'd be able to breathe immediately.
God cocaine's the best fucking
though the spray they gave me.
Now the doctor gave me the prescription.
If I hit my those two times
for like five minutes,
I go into confusion because it feels
like that it has that thing to it.
What they're saying is it's not a true
addiction because a, a true addiction,
what happens is like you,
you get sick if you don't have it.
A true addiction is a compulsive
physiological need for and use of a habit
forming substance known to be physically,
psychologically or socially harmful. Um,
the,
what the nasal spray happens is that you
put that stuff in and after a few days
of using it,
your nose may become less responsive to
the effects of the medication and as a
result you need to use more and more of
the medication to control congestion or
your congestion may worsen if you stop
using the medication that happens to
people. Apparently that happens
to people with Xanax too.
Like they say there's like some sort
of a rubber band effect of Xanax.
Like if you, you know,
Xanax calms your anxiety,
but when you start getting off of it,
like your anxiety like heightens and
worsens to a place where it probably
wouldn't even be if you were on it
if you weren't on in the first place.
And I think that's what happens with
these sprouts sprays to they get you to
come and go and join the Diaz.
They get your income and then go on
these fucks spraying shit up your nose if
you get your nose carved out though, you
know, if you ever want to go and do it.
My guy retired, my guy, Feinberg
and Encino, he was the best he,
he, he had like he was, he was so fucking,
he would so patient meticulous when he
would talk to them and take notes with
them. But he would talk about what people
did wrong and what people did right and
here's a common errors and here's where
they fuck up. And you know he's been,
he had been doing it for fucking years.
He was like in his sixties when he did
my operation, but he made my nose wider.
Like if I look at photos of
my nose before the operation,
after my nose was all sucked good at,
I didn't, I just didn't talk as well.
I couldn't breathe out
of my nose very well.
My voice sounded different and he stuck
these fucking plastic things in there
and cut everything out.
Cut The turbinates down,
remove chunks of meat.
I used to take the,
I felt I took photos of it
and I did some of them online,
but the video won't me blowing
my nose with a waterpik.
I have felt I had photos of the buggers
that I would blow out these bloody giant
honks, their thumbs. I would
blow it. I showed it to Tom.
It's the girl wants in the airport. He
almost threw up. I go, look at that dude.
It just came out of my nose.
It was like he ran away,
but that guy clean my nose out. I have
to Holland tunnels, man. I'm just like,
before that, how was your Jujitsu breathe?
Terrible. My Cardio got 20% better.
They vet you just Regan's guy
go. He goes, I think with you,
it's a deviated septum. Oh, I guarantee
you that's an issue. Do you? He goes,
I get it with you. You'll lose weight
cause war. It goes to that. Well,
that's what Vandelay Silva,
when Vandelay Silva had his nose fixed,
he had all that facial surgery.
They took a piece out of his rib and
reconstructed his nose and made his nose.
I'll give
you look at Vandellia knows it's way
bigger than it was before because he had a
big chunk of their open up his nose
like Vandelay and trying to look better.
He's still trying to fuck
you up. Like when he got his
nose fixed, it wasn't good.
He wanted to look cute but his nose was
completely smashed in and flattened.
It was like no cartilage at all.
It was just smashed and flattened.
And if you look at like what his face
looked like when he started fighting and
like the late nineties as opposed to
what he looks like in the early two
thousands like his nose was just a pancake
and so he had it fixed and stuck way
the fuck out,
like way bigger than it was before and
all just so he could breathe better and
smash your fucking face have.
So it's funny shit man.
We taste right now they should
just go over and legal look truce.
Just true what the FCA
and that she just can't,
it's in Nevada state athletic
commission to do is this.
We don't want you to come
back through the UFC tonight.
We're going to tape you every
week just doing a segment.
That's it because that just talk about
stuff because now he has a remark for
everything that happens. So
he stuck up for Judge Jones
last week. Right. You know,
he stuck stuff for everybody and
it's always at the end of the day.
That's at the end of a bunch
of bag of the UFC. You know,
like what do you think of John Jones?
They just go to the van.
[inaudible] he's like shooting Deca
guys rubbing his back and some
ladies shooting them in the yard.
But then eventually, what do
you think of John Joe? Hey,
I can give him my heart that he had
a blog if then UFC and that's it.
Cause it always has you see, you
ever see did it? Nobody else did it.
Van [inaudible] Goodheart drain very,
very well but then wide. Thank you
for Dana a wide thank you for help.
Thank you for UFC. Yeah, that
guy. Um, he fucked up man.
You can't run from a drug
test and then if you ran,
he ran from a drunk test and then it was
talking about all the UFC doesn't pay
its athletes and all I'm
saying and then the UFC. Okay,
you made nine point $7 million
fighting for us. Here's your record.
The UFC put his record out
like here's your record,
here's how much money we paid you.
You made nine point $7 million.
I don't know what you
think a lot of money is,
but a lot of people think $9
million is a lot of money,
like two years or something.
But he was several years,
probably five years he was fighting.
But the point is he didn't five years,
the only fought six times. It was the
other thing. Like you're saying you,
we work you so hard, you're fighting once
a year essentially. But not only that,
on top of that,
like Vandelay didn't have a winning
record like Vander Lee got beat by Chris
Liebing.
Vandalia got beat by a rampage.
Jackson knocked him out like he
got beat by all. A lot of guys.
He's a great fighter in a fan favorite
and personally like my all time favorite
guy to watch. I think. I think if
I go back to like the pride days,
I love the pride days for two
guys especially. Well, three men,
Tara in his prime for Cro,
cop in his prime fade or for
sure Fado was the motherfucker,
but Vandelay was a destroyer.
He was a,
he was so aggressive and psychotic
and you would watch a Vandelay Phi.
You always knew you were going
to see some fucking crazy shit.
That's when they had stomps and soccer
kicks and he's stomping dudes in the head
holding onto the robe, stomp into
more in the face when he's down.
I mean Vandelay she was amazing man.
His fights were awesome to watch.
But you,
you know that hard,
hard career and then comes over to the
UFC and I always got like really strict
drug testing and all this other shit.
And so when he took off
from that drug test, man,
I mean that was a just a colossal fuck up.
You're better off testing positive.
If you test positive they, they, they
ban you for nine months. That's it.
That's fine. You, they
ban you for nine months.
They tell you can't fight that guy
and you know you have to go through a
suspension. But when you take off they
had to send a message. They're like,
this is for life.
Like you can never fight again.
I personally think that's too much.
But the fear of it and the fact that he's
going to be out for who knows how many
years while he fights it and if he wins,
a lot of people think
you will win in court.
The Nevada state athletic commission
doesn't have the jurisdiction to test him
against his will, you know,
in between contests cause
he wasn't licensed for them.
Like in preparation for a licensing,
the idea of random drug testing,
a lot of people have issues with that
including like van Julie's attorney.
But the bottom line is they're
going to make you go to court.
You're going to have to do
battle and even if you win,
they'll let you fight again.
You still wasted all those years,
your light and no one's going to run
from a drug test again because they're
gonna know that the drug test like
running for it is way worse for you than
taking it and failing it.
That's the message they're trying to send.
They're trying to clean up the
sport and there's only one way.
You got to take your test and if you fail,
well you have to be punished.
It's that simple.
Otherwise you're not playing by the rules.
If you're not playing by the rules,
you can't fight for us.
You can't just run away. You know,
I don't agree with the suspension.
I think a lifetime suspension
is ridiculous, especially since,
look vandelays not gonna fucking he's,
he's not going to become a
composer or he's not going to,
I mean you're taking away
the guy's livelihood.
I mean he can teach and
you can train guys I guess,
but Vandelay still has fighting him.
He still wants to fight.
He had some good fights lined up at Shell.
Son In flight would have made him a fuck
load of money. That shale son and fight,
I dunno. Like what they're
going to pay him for that,
but how much that fight will be worth.
Especially if he could beat Chael
Sonnen and it do it in Brazil.
That would be gigantic. But he fucked
up too man. When he was on that show,
he got embarrassed.
Like the Brazil was upset at him.
There was a lot of people in Brazil
that are upset at his performance and
behavior on the show where
he attack Chael Sonnen. They,
a lot of people thought he made
them look bad and she'll sign it.
Took them down real easy on the show.
You know Vandelay took a swing at
shale and shell duct and took him down.
It's like come are we see and what's
going to happen on the show like you,
you're in and you're
making us look like thugs.
Like you're starting to fight
in the middle of a fucking
a television broadcast.
Talk all the shit you want, but be
there when the actual fight goes down.
So both the guys tested positive for
shit. It wasn't just, I mean Vandelay
might not have tested positive,
but essentially did and Shell son was
10 he was positive for everything.
Everything that existed, everything
other than testosterone, he was on,
it was on all these different
testosterone boosters and the EPO,
which the Lance Armstrong Shit to make
more oxygen, your blood, you know,
they have to clean up the sport.
It's unfortunate they're Vandelay has
to go out like that. Cause the guy was,
you know, so he can't find even
Atlantic city like nope, yard nowhere.
He can't fight anywhere now.
I'm only kidding.
I not finding where Bella tour was going
to hire him to do promotional shit for
them and the UFC is like, Eh,
you're under contract with us.
Like not only can you not work
for, you know, US fighting,
but we won't let you work
for the competition in any
sort of a promotional way.
But that was also because of, Angela
talked a lot of shit. You know,
he was talking to a lot of shit
about the UFC and who the fuck knows?
Man, it's sad. I hope he, I hope
it all gets cleared up. I mean,
I think the guy should've
got suspended for a while,
but I don't know what the number is.
A drug test was the GIA.
The feds came right to my house.
I wouldn't open the fucking door.
I wasn't even hot. I was
high fuck being hot. Fuck.
Last night or two nights ago, I was
fucking high on weed or coke. Everything.
I sent my wife subway, where the
fuck did I go by? Friends came out.
I was on probation, but I did
something. I told my wife,
me and my buddies would go to aspen,
so she left that after to her parents
or something with the baby and I fucking
stay at the house, both plastic
and they called me. They go,
what are you leaving like? Well, I'm
already at the fucking gold right now.
The car is coming. We'll
leave with like, okay,
we thought you said five o'clock no, no,
no. One o'clock I believe in right now.
I've got to go and I don't
know about 10 this way.
The guy knocked out the fucking door.
We were talking in the kitchen.
We got a high and I had to go upstairs.
They kept knocking.
I think I could hit somebody and
then nothing. Are they allowed to,
you're not allowed to break again, just
drug test. You just come to your house.
But if he would have knocked him, I
said, I'm gonna give them a drug test.
She would came back with a share a right,
right, right. They call the sheriff
test, open the fucking door. The,
you know what's the most fucked up his
drug test for companies where they test
you for weed and you're not even like,
it's not even like while
you're on the job, like ups,
something like along those lines,
like they'll test you to make sure
you're not doing drugs while you work for
them is if someone can tell
you what to do with your time.
Like when you leave,
like you could start drinking at Monday
at five o'clock you could ask everybody
at work, Hey, you guys
want to go do drugs.
Let's go down to the bar and do liquid
drugs. And everybody's like, yeah,
we're going to go meet Joey for a
couple of liquid drugs. You know,
and everybody's fine with that because
it's all alcohol. It's all legal. And,
but if you said, hey, you know,
you guys want to smoke some joints
after this silver, everybody be like,
what the fuck man,
you're gonna get fired from ups.
They're going to drug test you. You're
fucked. And they will, they, they could,
they could hit you with a random drug
test him and they can fire you bait.
And you could get drunk as fuck from
5:00 PM to 10:00 PM Sunday night crash,
wake up, head pounding, drive
into work, hungover as fuck,
drinking pedialyte and Gatorade
and water and, and you're fine.
Nobody know where you can say a word.
They'll drug test you.
You pass a flying colors. As long as
you're not actively drunk on the job,
you're fine.
Yeah.
So that's some goofy shit.
A kid hit me up from boulder.
He went together job at fish. Huh? They
take your fucking hand out Jack. Oh God.
Of the please take your
hair and that goal,
that's an invasion of privacy to Vegas
to at those casinos hair. Come on,
give us the answer. You can't
smoke weed, can't do nothing. Dog.
What if you have a medical prescription?
There's a lot of places.
Don't even give a fuck.
Even if you haven't had as big D as well,
because they give a fuck about a
medical prescription fuck about nothing.
I was thinking the same
thing I was thinking about.
Let's say a guy that's in
the California in prison,
not getting the right
medication for whatever it is.
I guess eventually that's going to happen.
Some guy in prison is going to
raise his hand and go the attorney,
I don't know what he's going to win,
but you lose your rights
when you're a felon.
You really lose your rights to
what do you lose your rights?
But I don't think you lose your
rights to proper medical attention.
So if you get that diagnosed
with ADHD or something like that,
a doctor says cannabis as medication.
What do you think? And it's a state law.
It's a state law. This is a federal,
the federal law is the real issue.
The federal.
So somebody in California eventually gone.
I'm not getting the right medication in
prison because they know we're almost
out of time. So I got to ask you
about this because this just came out.
What the whole John Jones thing,
you know,
knowing your past and your
past experiences with coke,
what did you think about
that when that all went down?
Okay.
I had heard rubish not gonna lie to you,
I just didn't say that to you because I
didn't want you drilling me that night
we were in Vegas and we ate the mushrooms.
We came back and John
Jones had done a table.
I told Darra with Jon Jones got up this
room cause he's doing a blog from him.
Ally to people told me, you know, be,
I don't care. I never repeated
it. I'm not that type of person.
I just foot did surprise me.
I'm not mad at him.
It breaks my heart.
People are sitting in adult
do blow and I watch Erin.
How can a champion risk his family and
everything? Cocaine has no nothing.
I had a baby inside the
rule with my wife in there.
I been on federal probation and I'm
snoring blow outside of hide the B as this
though, I would let the dog
out. That's what I would do.
She'd be in the room, read, what
are you doing? I'm letting it go.
Got that dog was the only dog that went
out every 15 fucking minutes go out.
I open the, crack it, drink it
down and put it back in the snowed.
I do two wines and go back in the house
was a hilarious knowing that they were
going to throw me in jail,
knowing,
knowing that we're going to throw me
in jail if I piss test knowing I would
drink vinegar.
I told the story on him before what I
went through that year in the halfway
house,
drinking vinegar and putting food,
cleaning up my deck and a cranberry juice
and vinegar and Gatorade and just let
it get go. When you're addicted, right.
That nothing means anything, you know?
Here's the question.
Is it possible that a guy could just
enjoy a little coke every now and then?
Yeah. You'd say yes, he's, yeah, but
you, you don't have a addiction thing.
You've done coke before.
You've never been a day,
but he's found himself in dark places.
If not, he'd do whatever he like.
He knows how scary it is. I see. You
wear it every night. I can see. Yeah,
I can see where it can for certain people.
Once you get scared with
them that you respect it.
But don't you get scared with alcohol too?
Like if you get really
drunk and fucked up,
I been really drunk and fucked
up before it was like, wow,
you could die from this. You
know, I've thrown up garbage cans.
I mean I've been hammered before where I
really, oh, I think I'm wondering like,
isn't that just as
destructive as cocaine now?
Because you're not spending hundreds
and hundreds of dollars every night on
alcohol usually. You know, here's a drink,
a bottle of Jack and he'd
QCC where cocaine there.
You'd be up til 10 in the morning still
buying it, you know, cause you keep going,
you keep on going because it's, it's
energy. It's pretty much just like, hey,
I'm awake. I feel great. I want
to get shit done and I want to.
So that's the issue is
that you keep going. Yeah.
So like a guy like Jon Jones
who has a lot of money,
like the money's not an issue for him,
but to keep them going.
It's an issue keeping guard and
bitches man, because they just love on.
What was he going?
I feel very bad for Greg Jackson's
camp because somebody had to know that.
Yeah,
well people probably knew but they also
knew he's the baddest motherfucker and
deciding right now nobody just goes
by as a package does it by themselves.
It's going to be doing it with somebody.
And my heart goes out though.
But does it, but do you think he
could be fine with it? I mean, Brian,
do you think he could be fine with it?
Do you think that if you,
if you're a disciplined guy,
you know because you,
you haven't had the problem that,
that maybe Joey's had, you know,
you've never been like full on addicted
like for long periods of time now.
So do you think that a guy like him was
an athlete? Is, was a strong mind to dude,
is very disciplined. I mean,
Jon Jones, when he's training,
like when he trained for this
fight for Daniel Cormier,
he was fucking disciplined.
The word on the street,
the word from Albuquerque was this fucking
guy's training hard twice a day doing
everything he can to beat this model.
He got to pump this up before I'm,
he wasn't trained that hard. He got
popped for weeks before the fight is true.
That's a good point. He wasn't training
that hard. He was still doing the cocaine,
which is by boggling to a guy like me.
But I understand that
because I was addicted. Uh,
it just, it just depends how much he
does. I know people that just do it.
A couple of months I had a friend that
was a tremendous athlete and one night in
front of me, he whipped out a
package, levels died and I go,
what the fuck are you doing? And he
goes, at the of the nine, I always
do two bumps. I could drink
with the rest of these assholes.
And I throw it away or I give it away.
He could do two bumps at Drake like it
was no tomorrow for two or three hours p
at a golf because Drake, boy,
that's children different.
Everybody has a different hardware
and different way of doing coke.
Some people could do a little coke,
but as we take the starch off he is,
he in the drug world. Everything's a
party. I'm happy they caught him down.
I don't know what level of the
addiction he was up to him.
Maybe he just done it the first time.
None of us know until he tells the truth.
And it's also a thing of
John is so fucking good.
That may be while he's doing it and he's
still winning, he's still beating guys.
He's so good. He can do coke
four weeks out. You know,
he could dunk coke three days before Doug
Lawrence Taylor was fucking, you know,
Friday night in New Jersey.
You're playing Sunday. Really?
We think Lara's Taylor went home and
drank Gatorade. Well, how bad is it?
Fuck you up. If he did do it on Friday,
not Schwab Bank, let's say fuck Trump.
Your heart, your breathing, it fucks up
laughing, but once you get back in there,
your fucking back in there.
I know as a comedian,
if I did it two nights in a
row and affected me as a comic,
I couldn't really control by words.
I could control a lot of things and I'm
very good with a lot of things in my
system. The THC in edibles,
what's that? Good coke. Two days.
You could tell it as a cop. You're talking
about raging two days all night long.
All morning. Like I'm grabbing a half
till four in the morning. I Bet I was.
You know, I could do two
grams in the night before the
morning, go back to sleep.
I'm talking to him. The doe drinking
I do on Thursday. That Mike,
I do that by standing up was
falling apart with fighting.
It's something different. You
want to be crazy. But then again,
when I sold sports information, I always
did better with a hangover. Braille.
I was unconscious. I worked off
technique, I worked off technique,
technique. I was unconscious. Everything
had to be so he didn't overthink things.
I didn't know the thing thing. I
closed him. I stuck to the pitch.
I took those beats. So maybe when
you're unconscious you're more,
I'm not saying that this poor kid did
it before he fought. I can't see it.
Listen right here with the route. We've
been 24 years I've been doing standup.
I did cocaine and one on
stage one time March 17th,
1992 was my second year doing comedy.
I feel like I could do coke
like Richard Pryor and talk.
It doesn't work so that Michael
Richards. Yeah, it doesn't work that way.
It doesn't work that way.
You do coke and go on stage.
You might kill one time as Kennison.
If he killed at the end it was a
nightmare and you have no emotion.
You have no abortion.
The cocaine cuts to your heart and the
material so all you are is right back.
Give me your jokes, right? I
hear what you're saying. Pop,
pop, pop, pop, pop, pop, pop,
pop, pop, pop, pop, pop. When I say
a joke, I, man, I let goes on the,
I've seen guys that have cropped
up on stage two and there are,
they are very robotic robotic.
It's over. You're just,
you're working off
technique and with stand up.
You can't work off technique with
Jujitsu and be punching. Yeah. You know,
I could grab all right, but not the whole,
which stand up. There's no technique.
The technique is by emotion. The
technique is my pain. I have to fuel that.
I have to feel that energy
once I have the bridges broken.
Once I do blow, once I do blow
my brother, the bridge breaks,
there's no disconnect.
And I could still yelled at jokes at you.
What are you going to chicken crosses.
You know what I'm saying? Right.
But there's nothing there. So I don't
see it. I just hope he gets better.
You know, I hope that,
uh, it was, uh, you know,
it's just something that he was doing
every couple of weeks just to burn some
energy. It's amazing that he partied
like that and still kick everybody.
We don't know what he did. We
don't know how he party. Well,
we know he was doing coke four weeks out.
We don't get up.
Just haven't been with a girl. They have
like, we could have done a blast. Good.
Listen,
you want a girl?
She got a tremendous piece of
pussy fucking diamond studded.
I'm belly button. Uracil
smell like flowers. You know
what? Maybe even do coke.
Maybe she put a coke rock in a pussy. You
looked at, you know, baby, you touched it.
There's so many fucking things.
But if I came to you and said Joe Rogan,
I didn't do blow. I just put it on
the girl's belly button. She always,
Jesus, I've known you 20
years you got with that one.
What was only metabolites
that tested for it?
So somewhere between two and four
days before that is was, well,
it was a great test because usually
the cocaine's gun, 72 hours.
This test got you till about
eight or nine days. All right?
We're running out of time. We
did our three, uh, when, uh,
when can people see again?
Buffalo helium next week.
Oh Shit.
Had a funny bone and
Columbus Superbowl weekend,
all of it at [inaudible] dot
com all over the Joey done.net
[inaudible] dot net levy to
man, uh, January 30th, uh,
I'm at the Mirage with Ian
Edwards and Tony Hinchcliffe.
That's January 30th in Vegas. Mirage, uh,
everything else is sold out Boston
this weekend. Next weekend rather,
next Saturday nights. Sold out at
that laugh comedy. I'll be back.
I'm going to come back in
the spring probably and I'll
do the Wilbur theater for
a couple nights. Um, I'm sorry.
Everything sold out so quick and it was
only two shows and people didn't get a
chance to get tickets, but I'll be back.
I didn't forget where I came from. Um,
I will be back. Uh, and
uh, helium in Portland.
That shit's all sold out too. So sorry.
90 Shit. Wednesday Joe. Yeah. Naddie show.
Wednesday we're going to
be at the comedy store,
a 9:00 PM in the main room
and is a fuck load of talent.
Jim Jeffries is on the show.
Brian's on the show.
Tripoli's on the show are you should
feel ownership shares Morgan Murphys
fucking hilarious. I need rotten. Yeah.
Okay. Beautiful. Uh, will be there,
so we'll see. You fucks very
soon. All right. Much love.
See you soon. Hey, what size?
Kevin.