I'd get out of Orange County,
the fucking road warrior again when they
killed everybody,
there'll be fucking crazy.
You don't want to be here.
You want to be in the mountains in
Montana,
Colorado anymore.
It's too many fucking momos and fucking
money came into fake fucking money and
bought the hillbillies out the real
motherfuckers that you needed it because
in case she got to go like Woody Creek
to find those people.
Right?
Know Woody Creek.
Is that still fucking amateurs?
Really?
Once you're fucking booze is up there,
you got to go deep,
deep in the mountains of gunnison and
shit like that.
Funny.
Those credits.
Gunnison.
Brian,
you got your volume.
We're echoing garland.
Gunderson.
Where's that?
That's down south.
What do you think about all that shit
about the Denver airport?
Do you know anything about the
conspiracy behind the Denver airport is
the Denver airport.
First of all,
they moved away more dirt than it needed
to and so there's this.
All this thought that there's some sort
of subterranean tunnel tunnel system and
it's all based on the end of the world.
Shelters.
They fucked up Stapleton airport was a
brilliant.
That's what it was like.
Burbank.
You could smuggle a fucking dead fucking
kilos of coke and nobody said nothing
and all of a sudden they came up with a
bright idea.
Let's fucking make an airport 90 miles
farther out by Kansas.
Someone it snows.
We really get fucking buried.
We have no protection.
That's a bunch of cowboys role making
decisions and trust me,
they're too stupid to even know the
conspiracy theory is that people that
built it maybe.
But if the government was really truly
behind it,
like all these people think what it is
that they made an airport there.
But in constructing the airport they
also built some sort of underground
safeguard three stairs.
So there's gotta be some Kinky Shit.
Well you know,
if it's close,
I mean that would be a move,
right?
Nora in airport and then build some
shelters.
That airport is like fucking Kansas,
Kansas during dick out there.
That's what they call it.
The.
If it was easy man,
when I lived in Denver or in Boulder,
there was easy to drive there.
Drive fucking hour.
Nothing.
Never any traffic to be 25 minutes.
Here's the deal though,
bro.
There's no traffic on that.
Don't matter.
Used to be 25 minutes with no traffic.
Tunes crack the window a bit.
They built this monster to spend money.
They built this bond,
this monster to to,
to just,
you know,
like when I went to fucking newark to
see the fights with you did,
we did it.
They built the soccer stadium,
soccer stadium in Newark.
That's spending money left and right,
but they still can't put it on the left
hand turning signal.
So if you got to make a left 29 fucking
miles and people trying to keep up the
reputation as the car jack capital of
the world and if you've got some left
turn signals,
you get some outlet.
People can escape,
can escape the drama.
Fucking amazing.
That's the thing about that.
It's like,
you know,
they think that there's something really
going on inside that Denver airport.
There's all these documentaries.
I'm dedicated to it and one of the
reasons for it is because there's these
crazy murals that were painted up in the
Denver airport and they're really
disturbing man.
Their apocalyptic like one guy's gonna
fucking gas mask on with a giant and
there's pictures of children and coffins
and there's fire in the background.
Have you ever seen that shit?
Yeah,
but yeah.
We've actually talked about on this
podcast before,
but do you think that has anything to do
with,
with that?
I think putting the two together,
I don't think that it does definitely,
but it's interesting,
you know,
I mean,
I don't have opinion one way or another.
I've listened to the people talk about
how it's some great escape base in 2012
there's going to be fucking asteroid's
gonna hit that.
They're tracking.
It's going to kill everybody except the
people that are in this underground
bunker.
I don't know,
man.
I watched the TV show and those dudes,
those dudes that have,
uh,
they've,
they've bought like fucking condos out
in these shelters out in like death
valley and Shit.
Have you seen those people have space in
death valley and so they have like a
condo inside this underground bunker
thing.
It's out in the middle of fucking
nowhere.
You have to drive and you go out there
and they had these shows,
I forget who was the host of the show,
but they.
They took you on a tour of these fucking
but might've been Jesse Ventura.
No,
it wasn't him because they had a sense
of humor,
but whoever it was was like really?
And that they take on his fucking tour
of these underground bunkers that they
have set up where they can survive a
fucking nuclear bomb.
I mean,
these guys are like half a mile deep
into the fucking earth.
So you survived the bump now which you
and eight fucking assholes.
Just listen.
Just live your fucking life.
These people that dig into that Shit and
just live your fucking life.
You will get hit by a bomb.
The best thing you could do is move on
to the fucking next life and pray to
God.
It'll be fucking better doors.
Music.
What the fuck is wrong with me?
I'm going to live in a bucket.
You imagine being living your life
consumer.
What happened was a bomb drops after
1960 of those people.
That Shit wore off in the sixties.
They all moved into buildings but
underground drops with little fucking
sandwiches.
That's how Tang was fucking invent.
The wedding invented Tang for.
So when we go in that fucking tunnel of
doom and after the Russians thought
everybody in the ass,
we can come out and where we got vitamin
C from the [inaudible] Tang,
that's more,
but guess what?
Our fears aren't the Russians anymore.
It's a lot bigger than that and whenever
it's going to hit now,
right now there's a thing going on in
Japan where we don't fucking know.
They align to the people just like
everything else.
They live in a 20 mile radius.
That shit's horrible.
That shit is horrible.
Radiation is fucking horrible and the
best is all these people are raising
their hands up.
We have radiation in key west.
Don't blame it on fucking Japan.
Don't blame it on Japan.
Now.
That's not Japan's for you guys.
Fat Radiation on your own.
You Greasy motherfuckers down there off
the coast of Florida,
you filthy cock suckers,
blame on the pool fucking jobs.
They're walking around with fucking mask
and as radiation West Florida that's
primarily poked up trying guys off and
creating heat sperm that they put in the
fucking beach during CSI Miami.
It's got these chicks Brazilian jumping
up and down with that ass.
That's what that fucking is.
Pussy fucking nasty radiation,
but it's something extra dirty about
porn that you get from Miami.
You ever watched porn from Miami?
Because it's almost like they're a
retarded people fucking,
you know what I mean?
And they're always oiled up to the oil
drop and does something about it.
Like you can't relate.
It's hard to even jerk off Joe Rogan
Mundo Martians and lifting one on one to
fucking trouble trouble.
This thing in Japan is a lot worse than
what they're saying.
You think so?
Fuck yeah.
What makes you say this?
Just I just know our society and they
don't want to scare us.
Which little fucking Japanese started
coming out with six fucking eyes and she
don't know which one's looking at you.
Then they're going to say,
what is that better?
So you can see better.
Maybe.
Maybe that's 2012.
They.
That'll be good.
An adaptive radiation.
This is not.
Was there any animals besides roaches
that are really good with radiation?
Roaches is supposed to be the best at it
right now,
but is that.
Is that even?
Is that even just like a wives' tale?
Someone should do us a favor.
Now we know that the Japan is fucked.
Sandbox.
Cockroaches over there with a Webcam on
it.
Let's see what if you love America.
I go over there and do that stupid
fucking water.
All that soil and they don't know what
the fuck's going on and you know what?
Now besides that,
we're all spread out where we live.
We're in this fucking place.
What the fuck
are you?
Fucking crazy.
These guys are just sitting there
waiting.
It's like a.
it's like a.
you're just waiting for us to wear out
before you fucked us in there.
What's that guy we'd been looking for
for 11 years?
He's just sitting there going,
oh,
we got them.
Now it's spread out like motherfuckers
would just light a fire in Kansas,
CNN,
breaking news.
I get CNN breaking news sent to my
phone,
Hala US intelligence source.
CIA is operating inside Libya to help us
increase military and political
understanding what that means to get
Jack Bitch whore ship quote is that,
oh,
the CIA is there to increase military
and political understanding.
No,
this is what we want you to do.
Do you understand?
Okay,
here's the political understanding.
We got the bombs,
bitch.
Okay,
we got fucking robots that we can
operate from Nevada.
Okay,
and you don't even see them because they
blend in with the sky and they don't
make any noise because they're fucking
solar powered and they can contain how
fire missiles.
Hell fire.
That's what I decided to name him.
Not you know the,
the,
the beautiful flower missile or lick my
ass all muscle.
No.
Hell Fire Hellfire missiles and they're
shooting them from another fucking part
of the world.
Imagine a lag they have.
They must have to really plan in advance
like it's just like playing quake online
when you got lag,
if you have a 56 k connection and if
some asshole you're planning as it's got
a cable modem and you know he gets to
move quicker than you because his
downtime is pink time between connecting
to the server and back as much quicker
so you're fucked.
So these guys must have like Super Wag.
August 1985,
we went to see Rambo to have that
motherfucker took an hour when the
explosive at the end and when he shot at
all of his last time,
nobody liked the black people.
Black people love that.
Will explosives it.
I seen that movie [inaudible] 78 street.
I'd never seen black people in my life.
And Rambo came out of the mother's eyes,
opened up and choked her motherfucking
black people went bananas.
They're like yelling.
We should've thought
of that.
But is it a blonde black dudes that
loved watching martial art?
Love it.
They love special.
Like a dude doing some crazy shit.
Like,
oh,
that motherfucker got a gun,
a nice shoe.
Check that shit out.
Something about a dude pulls his shoe
off and guns down the bad guy.
Like,
Oh shit.
No,
he didn't.
What?
What is that?
What is it?
We're just very vocal.
They're excited.
The best thing about this is,
that was 20 years ago,
the shit we got now as bombs and stuff
is off the charts.
We've got a bomb that comes at you as a
car that follows you to the gas station
or you're pumping gas.
It turns into an Obama guy pops on,
taps on the shoulder and says goodbye.
That's the shit we got.
We got shit that comes to your house
just to look like a cake.
Happy Birthday.
And when you're going to blow out,
the candles are just fucking blows up.
We got some shit now.
You know what I saw?
That was really crazy.
They got this rover,
this,
uh,
this a remote controlled drone rover
that's moving around that can jump in
the air.
It gets up to a fence and I can go like
eight or nine feet in the fucking air.
It moves up to the fence and then it
just goes and flies to the inland the
other side and it looks like basically
it's like,
like some sort of a flat blocks,
you know,
where all the electronics is with two
tractor to rubber tractor things on the
side of it I guess,
and the fucking thing flies through the
air.
I mean,
what's,
what's next?
You know,
that's the other thing that people are
thinking about.
A lot of the shit that's going down in
Afghanistan,
a lot of the shit that's going down in
the Middle East period as that.
The CIA has got all kinds of shit going
on.
All kinds of,
all kinds of little drones and
explosives.
It blowing up in convenient spots.
Spark
anger and you know what they do?
That's so they do spark war and get,
you know,
they've always done that.
But the bottom line of this,
what do,
what do you think is really going on?
They figured out some Libyan doctor
figured out a way how to grow 50 kilos
of heroin in your bathtub in the United
States.
Find out that Jack,
that motherfucker Kadafi has got an army
of motherfuckers around this guy with
missiles and explosives,
but the United States is jacqueline.
This guy's got something to do with age.
It's got something to do with fucking
why we're over there in the fucking
first place.
The whole nucleus of this thing.
People are dying in Detroit from heroin.
It was fucking war and we're still.
Now we're going to take over Libya boxes
or money,
Bro.
Isn't it amazing how many people will
think you're crazy when you start
talking about the fact they're in
Afghanistan for heroin?
People go,
what are you talking about?
They'll look at you like you just
fucking just add dollars,
bowl of shit.
They'll look at you.
Oh,
you're ridiculous person.
Well,
yeah,
we're at war for heroin.
Where do you think that money's going,
man?
Where did you know how much money you
were talking about?
They can ignore that.
You're fucking great.
We want to take over a country so we can
eat better gyros.
That's what you're telling me.
Stuff we've taking over our country so
we can turn it over that fucking loot
dog.
That's the bottom line,
bottom line,
there's all sorts of food over there and
there's all sorts of Luton.
Libya too.
I mean it's,
it's,
is it a fucking
coincidence that for whatever reason we
decide to attack Libya instead of going
to Mexico and straighten out that
bullshit that's right next door,
but I'll.
Mexico's God's Burritos,
Burritos and hookers and donkeys and
Tequila because there's not a lot of
shit to offer.
Mexicans getting ready though.
But listen,
that's some crazy motherfuckers known
and well,
they got to dig in to clean up their
problem.
They've got a big problem and it's
because of the United States.
It's a big part of it.
They wanted to make everything legal.
They wanted to,
you know,
they did.
Do you know that?
Here's a little known fact.
Mexico is decriminalized everything.
Small amounts.
We're not selling it.
Everything's legal now.
You could get acid in Mexico,
you can get mushrooms in Mexico.
They decriminalized everything just
because they had to allocate resources
to fight these fucking drug lords.
I mean,
that's a,
that's a country that country's gone.
The country doesn't have a government
anymore lives right next door,
right next door,
right next door.
The fucking drug army is.
It's like going to war with someone who
lives in your country.
It's like if we were fighting al Qaeda,
but al Qaeda had billions of dollars and
it was way more armed and they were
living here.
That's what it's like.
That's what it's like being a fucking
comedy.
Mexico.
Here's the crazy thing that Mexico is
coming back to get.
What's this bitch?
California and Texas.
You can't take Texas.
It's not going to tell you.
You can't take care of even the Mexicans
will the go around Texas and Jack
Wyoming Go Jack Dallas,
Dallas to Canada.
Shit.
They'll give them a beat Nigga.
You can tell the outskirts of Texas.
They'll come out of their hunting
blinds.
Kill is all here.
He lives there.
Ted nugent lives in Waco now.
Yeah.
You can text.
He does.
He's got a high fence I've always
admired with.
I think he's a retard,
but I think he does a lot of things that
I really agree with and one of the
things that I agree with is when he
lived in Michigan,
he had this bad ass compound.
We'll have 2000 acres or something like
that and it was all fenced in and had
all these animals living inside his
compound and he would just go and Jack.
Um,
and that's where he got all his food
from.
He got all his food from hunting on his
own property and I'm like,
God damn it.
That's fucking brilliant.
That's how I want to live.
I would love to live like that.
Just eat what you hunt.
That's one of the reasons why I was into
moving to Colorado.
One of the reasons why I was up there,
it was like,
look,
if the shit hits the fan living in the
woods,
you know,
there's a lot of animals out here and
it's spring water that comes out to you
and
fucking shooting a pe.
Yeah,
Cook.
I'm gonna fucking cave with your kids.
A cave.
Just given him all fucking silver.
Were living in a tent with fucking
eaters.
If shit ever went down and got Kinky,
can you imagine that Kinky,
Kinky shit gets cranky dog
fuckers.
So I'm excited about Oregon.
Oregon's one of those.
We're going to have a good fucking time.
Oregon's one of those states has been on
the grid for years,
but nobody knew about it.
They kept it hush.
Hush.
I used to get some good weed Oregon 15
fucking years ago.
Past Ashland.
Eugene bend.
Oregon's a hippie and foundation over
there.
Portland is a pretty hippie place too.
It's already hippie girls.
Have dirty feet,
dirty feet.
Make them put socks on.
Fox stops and say don't breathe through
my mouth.
Portland was the place that uh,
I went to last year and we were at
trying to find the most attractive
person in a costco for like a half hour.
I mean the girl is with.
And who would you fuck?
Yeah.
And we couldn't find anyone.
So Costco though,
dude,
go to a costco.
Burbank.
And with a bunch of cripples there too.
I know,
but that's a pack.
Tasco.
I usually find one string.
You need to go to better places,
so it was a smaller amount.
Smaller amount of people you'd want to
fuck.
That's okay dude.
You're going to go.
I'll be okay.
I got to live somewhere with this.
If this place falls apart.
I went to the humans here.
Too many.
We keep on saying that,
but we're not doing anything about it.
Did I fucking moved man?
The only reason why I came back is
because Mrs Reagan got pregnant and
because the dog had eaten by mountain,
might have went to the suburbs.
Then my next move,
we're actually talking about it.
It's not like I'm already talking to
real estate agents.
Oh,
she'll let you talk.
All that nonsense.
The move to move is you'd go and you'd
get a summer place and you try it out
and lived there for a summer.
That's right.
It sounds like you'd be super nice while
you're there,
so it becomes on the side.
Just every time we were there I'll just
bring home flowers and shit and then we
come back to la and then it's all
Jujitsu and loud music and too much pot
smoke.
So Ellie's negative daddy crazy in la.
Daddy just wants to fight and smoke pot
and he's walking around naked.
No,
in Colorado.
Daddy wants to go get ice cream and
daddy's bringing flowers home.
See you just trained them bro.
This is the problem.
You got fluid farts on her.
I love you to death.
Here's the problem.
Joe Rogan's got Joe Rogan's,
got a great wife and Joe Rogan.
I went to his home last week and that
was one of the first times that Mrs
Rogan was home and a couple of times and
I'd been up there like four times.
Mrs Rogan likes to rock the house.
Dot Real qualm was all where you live
now.
All you gotta do is go down the hill and
she can get the party started where you
put it before a motherfucker said
witness relocation plan.
She had to drive 90 miles before she
even seen the dentist who was another 20
miles.
She was from all the weapon boulder.
The first mall that she cares about is
cherry fucking creek.
You know what I'm saying?
So you had a two foods that Denver.
Yeah.
You are too far away from the more you
don't gotta keep a closer to the wall.
You had a 90 fucking miles dog and I
slipped on the love most blew up.
I loved the most living up there and
tell us that there was a
small amount of people,
man,
smaller boulders and only got 100,000
plus people not that much man.
And people are friendly like that.
There's a more relaxed vibe and I think
that shit is healthy.
I think there's something exciting about
living in a big city,
especially if you're,
you know,
you're involved in the hustle and bustle
and you're really trying to make
something happen.
And I don't know.
I
can't believe that New York surrogate,
if you got the voice,
you probably get married and after a
week you dumb fuck you talking a real
estate guy.
Are you talking to a realtor is going to
shut that part of you.
You got to figure out a way to get a
fucking call for her to the mall to go
where the action you can do that.
Don't worry about it.
You've got to move a little closer.
That was
too little close and you just need to
move to Texas.
Texas is.
This is the answer to it.
I like Austin.
I'm a big fan of that.
Austin,
Texas.
I'll tell you that.
I lived there if I was going to live,
but more lane is not legal there.
The thing about Colorado was just like
California.
You could just go rockweed everywhere.
I moved to Austin.
No,
no,
not yet.
Not yet.
The shit hits the fan.
Anything can happen.
You know,
when,
when the shit hits the fan and everybody
gets scared and then you start making,
you know,
survival choices.
You can live in Kansas,
you know,
you'd rather be healthy in Kansas,
you know.
But um,
uh,
the weeds stores in Colorado are just
like out here,
Bro.
It's just how they're everywhere.
There's one place in Denver where
there's a fucking seven of them on the
street
there.
Every way easier to get a license though
the same.
Same deal.
I get headaches.
Okay.
Bang.
Prescription side.
I didn't know it was a headache
20 minutes away from me when I was
shooting at up.
Right in the mountains.
They had a nice like it
Dr. Oh yeah.
There's a place that I used to go to in
the mountains.
It was like a gift shop and they were
doing.
They were struggling,
they were doing terrible and you know
the fucking.
They were about to lose their business
and then they started selling weed in
the back of the gift shop legal.
They've got a legal license now they're
balling now they're.
They're about to open.
Their one place they opened up in
boulder is supposedly,
I don't know if it's open yet,
but they were talking about is going to
be 30,000 square feet.
It was going to be three floors.
I don't know if they went through with
it.
I need to find out if they did because
that's just the most ridiculous shit
I've ever heard.
That's a Goddamn shopping is a Walmart
Walmart of weed,
but they had great spots there,
man.
They had great spots where you can get
weed.
Yeah,
I got some.
No,
and we'd two days ago in Hollywood is 31
percent thc level.
You don't even necessarily.
Again,
it's Matt.
I've been smoking Matt since 2006 and
you got to figure that every year it
gets a little stronger.
It's dead straight week.
They pay this girl.
I forgot to bring a,
but it looks like one of the Martians
from Independence Day.
The growing around it.
It's like a hybrid.
What if I tell you my joint or that
right now?
Are we give it to you now?
I went and.
Got It.
No,
you then go get that shit.
What's it called?
Massive number one.
Oh Gee.
All that shit is fucking strong.
I had to go to the gym.
Bugs fucked up though.
Sounds good.
Dog.
Or are we going?
It's going to be fun.
Last time I went to Eugene,
Oregon with Jody Ferdy and we had a
Saturday night that for a one night if a
trivial,
but it was the same night that there was
a convention for like the American
Association of retarded children.
I don't want to say it wrong,
but it was like the children that
Special Olympics and they had a lot of
little retarded kids running around.
So when I go to check in,
I'm high as a motherfucker and there's
all these kids with balloons and I'm
just freaking.
Because Oregon got some deep weeds,
you know what I'm saying?
Right,
right,
right.
Got Some at the gas station.
Brian,
you're gonna love this shit.
So I got a lighter.
We checked into the hotel in Eugene and
Joe.
This is not 10 or 15 of them.
This is 600 children.
Special Olympics,
200 retarded ones.
And that parents.
Well,
so I go to my room,
you know,
we small,
we do the show.
The show is in the hotel,
but a different part.
They're having a little dance.
You had to see this.
They were all holding hands,
little balloons and the disco and it was
very cute to say,
but if a lot with the story that a lot
of people don't know is retarded,
guys,
boys are the strongest motherfuckers in
the world and that most reverted.
Really.
Y'All have heard that boy,
they go fucking nuts if you see them,
if you show them your pussy,
so listen to me.
We're in the fucking comedy club in
Austin.
They switch it at 10:00.
They switched it and turn it into a
disco
and jody's got a couple of cocktails and
then she started dancing.
She got big titties at the time and this
is little retarded boy who breaks away
from the [inaudible] pile and goes into
the dance and he starts to look at God
and you could see Joe Rogan that he's
losing his fucking mouth now and finally
he goes,
I one to dance was starts dancing with
right.
He started to answer it.
Then he started grinding.
When the judge thinks it's cute and all
of a sudden they come in and they're
like,
Dad,
he is dad's little David,
and they come to grab him and David
fucking snapped like one of those
fucking gorillas in the zoo right now.
They had three black doorman that we're
trying to tackle.
A little timid little timmy was throwing
them around like rock less madrona
around fucking John Fitch.
Just pick the whole offensive line of
the giants.
Couldn't help this little retard down
fucking black gorillas and he just
pushed him on
on De de,
De,
de,
de.
No titties.
He went fucking ape shit.
He's pushing on the counters came.
They had to throw them on the fucking
floor and put his hand up.
No,
no,
no.
And he went fucking ape shit dog.
Those little pods go fucking bananas
when you show them this little one cars
and it was just tidying.
Can you imagine if it was the monkey who
went,
jumped bro.
He's,
he's,
he's a university of Eugene.
These are big black football players.
They couldn't control this 12 year old.
He was banging them,
throwing them around like he was only
12,
12 or 13,
just throwing these fucking black guys
around and never forget that,
that they had to put them on the floor,
handcuffed him,
shoot them,
tranquilize them.
This little fucking poor kids seeing
teddies and he went fucking bananas and
as banana,
that's crazy.
I wonder if they're just doing what
everybody wants to do but just doesn't
have the ball they had.
They don't have the walls that to break
down.
You know what I mean?
What if that's what people like
instinctively want to do it.
Retards can't be like extra more horny
right now.
They probably not extra horny.
It's put that fan on them.
Sweat like Joe Rogan's hospitals,
the electricity.
You know what I'm saying?
You're killing me here,
bro.
This kid went fucking bananas.
He ripped that [inaudible].
You can't even beat them up.
What do you.
What do you do?
Do you.
You can't drop a bomb on.
The funny thing was that they built like
a wall at first make a little mouth
first.
They asked me to leave when he was like,
they're built with black guys.
Got shoulder to shoulder and he was
grabbing at shoulders.
Huh?
I mean it was fucking scary.
You don't know.
They look bad,
you know?
That's one of the weird things about
people that are retarded or down
syndrome or whatever.
You don't seem to know.
You know,
they just kind of are.
They just behave.
They don't go well,
so fucking stupid and
you know,
they're not like that for just
themselves.
You know what I mean?
It's like,
that must be a strange,
strange existence where you know,
that's part of being dumb is that you're
too dumb to realize you're dumb.
You know?
And if he,
I'm not saying dumb,
like there's like they're lazy,
like they have an issue,
there's a mental issues and the mental
imbalance or whatever the fuck it is.
But I mean it's in there.
They're impaired,
but there so impaired,
they don't know they're impaired.
Like they've lost the ability to see
that they're impaired.
You know,
what a strange thing.
What if they all have an inner voice
that that's completely normal,
like,
but they can't take a to be like,
you know,
you know what I mean?
So the whole time that was just like,
I can't believe how much they treat me
so horrible and I wish I,
you know,
but they can't,
when they try to say it,
it's like theater.
There's probably,
there's probably a lot of that.
Yeah.
I think there was a bunch of different
types of,
you know,
being fucked up,
for sure there's that too,
you know,
it's not,
it's not just simple as.
Yeah,
there's some,
there's varying.
Yeah.
There's varying degrees along the way
that are,
you know,
I mean it's fucking crazy thing,
man,
to,
to have your mind impaired,
you know,
and like look,
our minds are impaired in comparison.
I was watching this fucking 12 year old
kid is autistic kid with 170 Iq doing
his take on the theory of relativity and
he's writing out equations on this
fucking window and I'm watching this
kid.
I'm like,
this kid might as well be a fucking
alien.
All right.
I don't know what he's doing.
I have no idea.
He's explaining this like,
this is all simple simple shit.
When this is so far beyond my capacity
to him,
to this autistic kid,
I'm retarded.
Okay.
I am this guy who he has to humor
because I can't understand a fucking
word,
a letter,
a singular part of his equation.
I don't know what's going on up there.
It's chaos to me,
but to him it's so clear.
It's a language.
It's like,
well,
quite simply you have to move this and
this becomes x equals y equals two.
We are the retards to that kid.
You know,
maybe like the,
maybe like,
you know,
people with down syndrome.
They feel bad when people don't have
down syndrome.
Maybe it's just like us.
We feel bad with people who have autism,
like poor kid's got autism and he can't
engage in all the normal emotional
things that we do.
Meanwhile this motherfuckers,
you know,
count counting to a billion in his head
while he,
while he's talking to you about how a
television is conduct constructed,
you know,
maybe we're recharged to them.
Maybe you know,
they look at us and I go this Port Fox,
they can't even do math in their head.
They don't,
they can't see through walls.
They can't read people's minds,
you know,
but some people just had a kid in the
eighth grade,
his name was Michael Alig,
Gretta's assuming kid he had been fresh
off the boat in the fucking sixth grade
by the eighth grade.
This motherfucker spoke three languages,
all that Sicilian shit.
But he picked up Spanish and he picked
up English and I used to just sit and
look at them or do you know what I'm
saying?
Like he was such a cool motherfucker
that I just wanted to hang with and he
was so.
And he was married.
We used to play when you,
when we used to play hockey,
we eliminate the chins with the,
with the hockey stick.
And he goes,
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So I would die.
He was never
drift to the bag with my dog,
but this kid knew nothing when we came
off a boat,
January in the sixth grade,
by the eighth grade knew three fucking
language.
He would talk to me in Spanish,
talk to you in English like nothing and
get a's.
You know,
some people.
Real work ethic to.
It's.
Some people just,
they have this insane work ethic and
people that get a chance to come to
America.
It's so much different than being born
in America.
We don't have any fucking idea.
You live,
you know,
you're living in fucking Guatemala or
some shit.
You know,
your,
your opportunities are few and far
between.
You know,
you live in someplace that's
impoverished.
You're,
you're kind of fucked man.
But when you're in America,
dude,
Holy Shit.
So these guys,
you know,
their family gets them together.
Look,
we're going to move to America.
I have a better life.
And you realize you're leaving
everything behind and you're putting all
your fucking ship and cargo planes and
you're all sitting together crammed in,
coach and you know,
eating fruit out of your mom's purse and
you know,
just hoping that when you get there
things are going to be better and you
don't know anybody there.
And how scary is this?
So when those motherfuckers get to
school,
they come out guns blazing,
you know,
they appreciate the fact that Holy Shit,
I used to live in Italy.
Now here I am in the land of the free,
the home of the brave.
You know,
I'm in America and I'm in school and I'm
learning English and I'm just going to
go fucking crazy over here.
They're just so happy.
And she'll rub.
That's the one 10th of it because I
didn't leave Cuba Cronin.
We moved here.
I woke up on 89th street in riverside
drive.
I had all the fucking things that a rich
kid.
And here I was walking around this
fucking city,
but I didn't know English.
And all you want to do in your heart is
just fit in and you have no idea.
This is not trying to fit in when you
were in grammar school and you should
get a tattoo long hair.
Oh,
you want to know is for them not to know
that you came from somewhere else that I
can't describe it to you.
I can't even stop and start to tell you.
Like sometimes I have this anger at me
and it's because I was so lucky.
We're so lucky.
I need three of us could have been born
one of those black kids and fucking eat
with flies on you.
Any three of us.
And we have so many fucking
opportunities.
And sometimes I wake up in the morning,
this really hits me.
Sometimes I go home and fuck and lucky
that my mother came here and here I am
sitting here smoking though.
But I know what I'm saying.
Like think about what an immigrant was
like.
You know,
I'm telling him for a long time I've
been writing this thing and that's how
it starts with the,
you know,
I don't remember anything.
I don't remember the plane ride from
Cuba.
I remember nothing.
All I remember is crossing the fucking
street on 89th and Broadway up to
[inaudible] 66 and thinking to myself,
fuck,
I'm going to be a fucking American.
What does that mean?
Looking at that flag and you really
believe in something dog.
It's not just a piece of fucking rag
looking at that flag and going,
what the fuck?
Like looking at the wind blowing that
flag and going,
what the fuck?
That flag is the answer to all my
fucking problem.
That's the answer right there.
But even at that age I knew my mother
was fucking crazy,
so I do.
I wasn't a full flight American,
but when you look at that flag and you
just come here,
they have a scene in the beginning of
scarface when they're on the boat and
they finally see land and they showed
the American flag and the director,
whoever the guy is brilliant enough to
show.
He showed it from a different angle.
What that flag looks like.
It's not just we overlooked that flag
every fucking day.
We overlooked that flag.
You don't know what it is to look at
that flag when you first come in and to
know that that's your.
That's your magic carpet.
It's the highest ideal in the world.
It's the highest ideal.
That's why it's so infuriating when
politicians are fucking corrupt.
That's why it's so.
You know,
people say,
why do you criticize what America does
overseas?
Don't you love America?
Yeah.
If you love it,
you want to tell the fucking truth about
what it's doing.
You know,
if you love it,
you're supposed to stand up and go,
what the fuck is going on?
It's like you don't love it by letting
it get away with stupid shit because
there's some corrupt concept.
The wheel that's not.
It doesn't mean you don't love the idea
of America.
I fucking love the idea of America for
sure.
I always remember we only see the one
side of that flag.
We never see both sides together
gentlemen,
and that's a point we never.
We only see that one side of the flag
right now.
You've discussed that the CIA is setting
up things in Libya.
What are they setting up this starting a
war that started in business.
They're getting things going.
That's the other side of that flag that
will never able to see.
We only see once you put a mirror on the
other side of the flag.
You know what I'm saying?
That's the one side of the flag that we
have since we accept this side of the
flag,
we got to accept that.
So the only way that side this side is
possible where it's easy to drive around
is if they're doing all this creepy shit
you gotta bring.
Unless we bring the whole world together
in on everything and that's just not
going to happen and we've done fucking
shit.
Do Creepy Shit to trust them.
You can't trust people to be cool.
You know the look,
the natural instinct,
if someone can get into a position of
power is to be Kadafi.
That's the natural instinct.
The natural instinct is to get botox.
When you're 80,
you have this big stupid liquid rubber
face were goofy clothes and just be
running shit.
Even though you're this old con,
you know,
living in some fucking castle with
billions of dollars doing that job,
can you tell me why is he going with me?
We put billions of dollars from money.
That inside of that flag is money.
Joe Rogan.
That's a lot of people.
Never had comprehend that.
That's the reality of it.
Stand up is a beautiful thing to do.
Some guys are brilliant and some guys
aren't millionaires.
The other fall between the crack,
the other side of the standup up,
it's a business.
It really is a fucking business guys and
it's like anything else.
The other side of that flag is a
business guys and the same way we want
social security.
One was 65.
A country as a dual sell a couple of
kilos every once in a while to replenish
those fucking funds.
You know what I'm saying?
And that's aside of the American public.
Don't want to know that society that
included Kennedy.
That's aside.
The Alex Jones talks about whether it's
true or not.
That's society we not supposed to see
was supposed to be focused on the other
side on what that machine is supposed to
mean to us and for guys like you and I
like looking behind the curtain,
but I don't.
I don't because I grew up in a in a
corrupt hometown.
They seen what politics is at a minute
level.
I can't even dream of what it is at a
national level when I'm taking political
contributions,
but I'm going to pass your fucking bills
so you could pass that law.
That'll make people's hands grow back,
but they're also going to give them
cancer in the eyeballs.
That's part of it.
It grows.
If when I grew up in it,
when it was in the micro process,
I now it's in the national level of
corruption isn't a macro process and it
starts with little things and townships
where if it's a macro smaller than my
micro macro,
a little high.
I'm sorry guys,
but you understand my know exactly what
you're saying.
It's very interesting.
Corruption if not checked,
grows.
It all just keeps getting bigger.
It's not like they go,
hey,
we got to cut the shit.
I know we've been making millions of
dollars on the sneak tip,
but everybody's to stop right now and
I'm not kidding.
Why are you still making money?
These wiki leak things are pretty cool
for the country.
I think in general,
that's why these assholes want to put
that guy in jail.
They want to say it compromises
Americans can.
No,
it doesn't.
He,
he did exactly what the New York Times
was supposed to do.
If they got that information,
they should have done that on twitter
though.
Can you imagine if there was just like
this twitter address that everyone
followed that every tweet,
twitter,
by the way,
JFK,
here's pictures of JFK,
so,
and cocaine to do.
Wikileaks has a twitter and they really,
they really shouldn't have twitter.
They released some,
uh,
an artist article
about how um,
different parts of the American economy
are influenced by genetically modified
foods and how we're trying to force them
on other countries.
And they were like fucking with other
countries.
If they don't go into the genetically
modified food,
if they don't start growing like
Monsanto corn,
shit like that,
you know those that,
that,
those,
these giant companies are way too
embedded into the political system.
They're not doing stuff for the greater
good of people there doing stuff for the
profitability of giant corporations that
moved them into position in the first
place.
The whole thing has been corrupted,
like to sit down and pretend that,
that,
that it's real.
It's insulting.
It's like a,
it's like a stupid argument.
It's like people argue about pro
wrestling,
you know,
it's like,
what are you arguing about?
This is a fake nonsense process.
If you can't notice that from Obama,
Obama's going to pull all the troop out
of,
I can't.
Oh he's not.
Obama won the Nobel Peace Prize and then
he sent 30,000 more troops to
Afghanistan.
I mean,
come on man,
look at all the shit that he's done to
allow these kids to get away with
stealing all that fucking money and that
bailout.
I watched that inside job movie.
Dude.
That shit is disgusting.
It's disgusting how deep the corruption
is.
The financial,
uh,
the whole financial sector,
it's scary,
dude.
They have the people that are regulators
eventually get jobs with the banks,
like how the fuck you're telling me you
work as a guy who's working for the sec
and you're looking into banks and
corruption and shit like that.
And then when you quit,
you get a job with the bank.
How the fuck are you not in jail?
You were the one responsible for looking
over these motherfuckers while they were
doing all sorts of crazy shit betting on
things failing and betting three times
more than that a business is worth and
speculums and,
and,
and bedding.
Fucking forcing clients to buy shit they
knew wasn't good.
Like they did a lot of crazy,
creepy shit and got away with it.
I'm the only one who got popped.
Is that Bernie Madoff?
Those motherfuckers should all be in
jail.
This should be a mass jailing and
they're not.
They're not jailing anybody.
Then it's bullshit.
Then it's all bullshit.
It's all bullshit that they're not you.
You got to like hold them the most
accountable you can and it's barely at
all
people's dreams,
people's dreams.
When you steal people's dreams,
that's the worst thing in the fucking
world.
You 63 years old or so,
somebody calls you and says you're not
going to get you your money at 66 or 67.
All that money you put away.
That happens.
Those guys a lot too.
Tap into a lot of fucking people.
People at 60.
I just watched him about a month ago.
People 71 getting part time,
fucking jobs now this extreme,
this fucking movie showed,
I believe it was Iceland,
how they went in and Jack the Icelandic
economy in like a couple of years these
banks went in and just fucking do is
created bubbles and started making crazy
money and spending an access and then it
all failed and people are fucked.
They had like the most stable,
the most informalized economy.
Like it was a beautiful economy.
Everything was running smooth people.
We're hard workers.
People got shit done.
They lived a life of relative
prosperity.
Now they're fucked.
Everybody lost everything.
Everyone's fucked.
Everyone.
Yeah.
The states,
I think it already has already recast,
what is this be allowed?
What?
What is this?
How do you,
how did these people get money when when
the banks failed,
they,
they will.
They have bonuses in their contract is
how the fuck do you get a bonus when the
bank fails?
Like the idea that you have to respect
them and that they can't lose.
That's just there.
It's so crazy.
Bonuses.
The millions and millions of dollars,
and this is from banks.
When we would take to pay them,
we gave them money and they're giving
out money.
Either way.
If your bank fucking failed,
you can't get a bonus.
You can't get a bonus bank fucking
failed.
Do you take no personal responsibility?
Like who takes responsibility?
Somebody.
And it shouldn't be the guy that stands
to make a bonus.
If the bank does well,
that should be the guy who takes
personal responsibility.
So when the bank fucking fails,
you don't get your bonus con face.
It's it.
It's that simple.
Why?
Why the fuck can't the president say
that?
Is the studies like we're gonna,
you know,
limited to half a million dollars,
half a million fucking dollars for a
bonus when your bank fails,
what do you want?
These motherfuckers are so not living in
reality in most people's reality.
These cons costs so many fucking people.
Their life savings and they have to get
their bonuses and the president is like,
well,
we have to give it to him.
What the fuck are you talking about?
You have to give it to them.
You can't just step into the cut the
shit.
Are you fucking crazy?
No.
You can't get $30,
million dollars after your fucking bank
fails.
No.
In the middle of a crazy.
Down to economy where billions of
dollars from taxpayers.
What?
He'd been funneled to fucking banks to
keep my.
No,
you can't get
a bonus.
Fuckhead you lucky you have a job.
You're lucky you're head is attached to
your fucking shoulder.
Like about getting 90 fucking years.
Yeah.
You're lucky you're not in jail forever
in Haiti.
Have you follow what's going on in the
city of Bell Bell Bell Bell.
California is a city that the fucking
guys just jacked him.
What happened?
Like the fuck you gotta get up early in
the water for this because they talking
about like Gates Ela.
It's a city here of bell off the six.
Oh five or something.
And all the man,
everybody.
It was as corrupt as can be.
They have been Jack and millions.
So if it's at that city of Bell,
if the corruption is that deep,
the cops will have any ticket contests
real everyday on the news.
They come up with more shit.
The guy just got reinvited.
This is all Old Jersey shilling school
clear as Bell Bell,
California.
It's I think like
30 minutes from here,
so 30,
45 minutes,
but they just been having this shit in
there lately.
It's a shitstorm.
They all go.
They will all stealing.
All five guys are stealing.
Big Boys don't understand how they feel
like no one's gonna get caught with good
fucking trail memory,
good fellows and Robert Dinero how to
start killing people because you're
spending too much money.
It's the same goddamn thing.
Man.
That was a great scene,
wasn't it?
When you realized that guy came in,
his wife had a fucking beautiful fur
coat on,
it's like,
what the fuck are you doing?
And then they they know they have to
kill this guy and then there's photos of
him and his wife shot in the car.
What a great goddamn movie that was on
the day and I walked in the part with
her at the mother's house and the
borrowing the knife,
but you gotta think of that whole scene
that borrowed a knife to stab this guy
in the car.
Meanwhile eating the guys in the trunk
of the car like it's the fourth of July
there.
Eat eggs and bread and fucking telling
stories.
Remember the pain thing?
That is such a sick fucking movie right
there.
Great moving.
What do you want from me?
There's not that many of those.
There's very few of those that ever get
that good.
You know,
there's very few movies that ever like
hit that.
That's like a perfect movie.
Goodfellas is like a perfect fucking
movie.
Everything about it,
especially when you see it.
Twenty years later when she was
screaming at Ray Liotta and he run,
he starts laughing and runs away because
gacked out of his fucking mind,
she's screaming at me and he's laughing.
Man.
When they were were packaging up the
coke and his girlfriend was getting
pissed off,
you know,
she's [inaudible],
he's Kinda just fucking making coke for
him now.
He was banging her on the side,
still with his wife and he's got a
packaging coke for them and then you
know,
he,
he leaves laughing and she fucking
throws the coke at the door.
You remember?
That show is the craziest thing ever.
I said,
it's the craziest thing ever.
When he gets to that scene,
and I did coke for 30 years.
When he gets to that scene and he snorts
and he pops his head up and his eyes
dilate right in front of the camera.
That scene is why I turned the movie of
really it bothers me to go.
And you know what bothers me because he
steals it though.
He taps into the coat when he's standing
there with his arms,
watch it again when she's wearing it and
he's standing there with his arms
folded.
I'm telling you,
you're seeing it with my arms.
Felt that
that potential energy,
you're ready to explode.
You can't even take watching that.
Fill that bucket.
I'm below when he sees the fucking that
helicopter,
you know it's behind you.
That chitter chatter they have.
That's paranoid talk.
Why can't we go to your mother's house?
When they dropped the guns off?
Can you imagine joe?
What can we go to your mother's house
and drop off guns.
They had this chitter chatter when he
gets out of jail and he's feeling for
the coke and he comes home and he's
trying to tell her that he wanted for
money.
He wants to get high.
I been there,
Karen.
Karen,
what you do?
It was what we saw.
We had Karen,
that whole chitter chatter looking how
high they are and he just passes out and
just pass out.
Perfect.
Yeah,
they just pass out from the ghetto.
We had $60,000,
dollars,
a fucking thing he had in the ceiling.
What?
Cops wouldn't have found a great fucking
movie though,
but it's amazing when he's looking up at
the helicopters and he's driving so
fucking yes.
When he was in the car and he thought it
was over and he's getting rid of guns,
right?
Wasn't it?
Yeah.
You have no idea what it is to get
caught up in this little room that look
out that window or by the blunt,
and
there'll be a.
What do you call those things?
A fire hydrant,
but in your mind becomes a dog.
Could you imagine if you got Osama bin
Ladin cooked up?
Could you imagine if you got someone,
someone like Gaddafi coked up right now,
how paranoid he would be if they just
go,
does it.
You think he does coke?
Of course you're a fucking terrorist.
You're probably fucking fucking hookers
looked.
The coffee's not a terrorist.
He's a.
he's a dictator.
I mean,
I mean he's.
But I mean,
yeah,
it's the same thing.
That was a bad,
bad person.
Enemy better person.
That was a guy called Carlo something
that was part of the middling cartel
with the eighties bad motherfucker when
that was in charge of bringing it up all
the blow.
He got so crazy and I'm not in a deer
call.
Lowe's.
Yeah.
What's his last name?
He runs and they did call his name.
He was the one that didn't blow up.
I might've made that up.
Blow was the guy on the island that he
went to visit Johnny Depp.
The guy with the blue eyes that had the
machine guns and shit with this guy.
His name is Carlo laid there Les Paul's
Dad got his sentence reduced.
He got like 900 years.
Knocked off his sentence.
He's still got four more to do.
He's the one that went to the government
and said,
doctor,
I gave her adult envelopes face to face.
Wow.
And the laid there,
how they nailed him was he was actually
getting cameras like Ryan does,
sending them around the room.
He got a plate below.
He sit there and make it with a towel on
and just do bumps and every once in a
while he'd go like this,
a chicken coming to suck his dick.
It.
He
just tell poetry all day and finally
they got the cartel got their hands on
this and they were like,
this can't happen.
Get Bullshit on the phone.
Bush.
We've got something for you.
Right.
I'll tell you exactly where he is.
We're going to email to tape the
cartel gave him up real.
Exactly.
Yeah.
They couldn't take that.
This guy was folded.
He's making videos of themselves naked,
sweating with his eyes.
This big blow for 24 hour pop.
Fuck Charlie Sheen.
This guy was naked doing bumps and say
he's talking about La Luna,
you know,
stars in the middle.
Then he would go on on a chicken coming
to suck his dick and he was like,
shoot.
And they will take her on tape and they
just keep you see him pull the buyer
rankles and should he be bleeding?
And then he'd do more bloated.
I wish I was lying to you.
This guy was killing people on tape,
doing blogs,
just not eating for days,
a brilliant shit,
and then they stick one of the Middle
East,
God tell,
got this,
and they're like,
we can't have this.
When they went and got him and brought
him back,
they still have those pictures of him on
the plane next to a marine.
He's just looking around like,
what the fuck do I do?
He lives exactly.
Turn them in.
Holy Shit.
Did you see you saw cocaine cowboys,
right?
Yeah.
No,
that woman,
what's her name was elder elder.
She's out.
She's back in Colombia,
man.
They got pictures of her in Columbia at
the airport hanging out free and this is
the movie,
just detail after detail.
How many people she had killed that
pitch.
The godmother,
I think they call them [inaudible].
She made so much money.
Hundreds and hundreds of millions of
dollars in money,
man.
She was killing people left and right.
They got this guy who's her hitman who's
in jail and they interview him in jail
and he's just telling them all the
different times.
Griselda had made me kill this guy,
so I had to go do some business and I
killed this guy,
how to do some business,
and I said I wouldn't do that because
they wanted me to do a drive by and
there was a baby in the car.
Whoa.
It was fucking Colombian.
They used to shoot anything.
There's a picture of you go on.
Daily News archives.
Nineteen 84.
A Colombian family in Brooklyn got
slaughtered.
Well,
the kid in the room for the wake was 14
bodies and there was 12 kids.
Oh,
Monday.
They sat the kids down to the 12 and
bullets and they're fucking forehead.
Oh my God.
The pictures,
they don't show the bodies,
but they show the funeral parlor and
just the role of fucking bodies,
these Colombians and over nothing.
This isn't the eighties when they were
shooting you over $2 just to make that
point.
You know you're always fucking money was
going to shoot you.
That was the big thing about them,
right?
The Colombians were always taught to be
the most like Colombian neckties fucking
throw out.
Pull your tongue out.
They wanted.
They wanted an intimidation at the
maximum you of fucking savages.
That's right next door to us,
buddy.
That's just like what's going on in
Mexico that's happening right now in a
bigger,
even bigger scale,
you know,
because the Colombians,
even though they had like they were
selling drugs and they were bringing
drugs and they weren't getting that much
resistance from their government.
You know what I mean?
There's was Kinda.
It was,
yeah,
it was kind of cropped.
But in Mexico it's not the same man.
Mexico,
they get a lot of resistance,
but it doesn't matter.
It's those dealing it.
They're still doing it,
so it's scarier because it's more like
it's more militaristic
in Spanish.
Global.
That's the expression,
bro.
That's a silver cash.
That's a finished from the rubber guard
below more or blah blah,
blah.
It's called either bullets or money.
Which one they just show up and which
ones?
Bullets.
A poloma plumber is bullets.
Yeah.
Blocked out as cash.
So they bought a plot that they just
show up at your house,
but a Gundam with an envelope lot more
blocks.
That should be a new rap song.
You want to your call,
that's how they would go around to
Columbia
is a poor fucking girl who was a member.
That girl was trying to be a sheriff and
a some town in a near Juarez.
Remember that Shit.
She was 20 years old.
There's a big story because this is
college girl decides she's going to
fucking get a a job as a sheriff and try
to clean up the town within months.
This poor girl is trying to seek asylum
in America because they're trying to
kill her a little.
Slice your fucking throat.
Look,
you're either in or you're out.
There's no coming back.
There's no,
no,
no.
That's a different society.
This isn't the Sapphire.
This isn't a.
it's terrifying.
Shit is terrifying.
That is terrifying that we're not doing
anything about it,
but yet we're fucking around in Libya.
April one,
1984.
December twelfth,
19,
84.
I was minding my business or 83.
I was minding my business is snowmass
village that was just snorting coke and
going to school at night,
but he just had an electrician's job and
I heard this boom,
but I didn't know what happened.
I just went to bed the next day.
They were telling me a story about this
drug dealer named Steven Gray Book.
He got in the fucking car with the star
that they put a bomb under his fucking
car.
They asked me to Colorado Tam,
some white dude,
and I asked her rather than the papers,
he was about to go on trial for tax
evasion,
Jewish guy that was in with the
Colombian.