Yes,
slow down Twain,
slow down.
You have an orange watch.
You are a fucking,
what is the orange thing?
I've always been attracted to orange.
I grew up in Colorado,
so the broncos orange is always been
around me.
Ah,
so the favorite uninjured hurdle at the
time was Michelangelo with the orange
and then a really no other fighters or
gyms.
We're using orange,
so I wanted to make sure I did my own
thing.
That is your own point.
Yes sir.
Orange.
I mean it's like I absolutely love
orange,
but I see some orange at the store or a
crowd of people.
I see what warrant.
Sure.
I'm,
I just goes boom.
Right.
If there's a fruit bowl,
there's an orange right next to a
banana.
Orange grabbed the orange.
Tj,
what is it like being around this guy?
Oh,
it's intense,
man.
I limit,
you know,
life's full of energy.
You know,
you can't be calm around him because
he's got enough energy for both of us,
you know?
Yeah,
no,
he's,
he's a mad man.
We worked out today and he's in the
middle of like training.
He just gets excited.
So it's hit this past year.
I love it.
I don't ever have to do road work
because of this guy,
you know?
I mean we hit Mitts for so long and so
hard that I'm in too good a shape
already.
You know?
That's interesting.
Like all the footwork drills and
everything.
I never really thought of that.
Like you probably don't have to do road
work.
I it'd be too much.
I have,
I do too much training as it is.
If I'd started doing roadwork,
I think I'd overtrained myself.
That's,
that's fascinating.
What you have to kind of regulate that,
huh?
Like there's,
there's a,
a standard model that like a lot of
fighters fall and roadwork is a big part
of that.
But do you think that with all the stuff
that you do,
if you did that as well,
it might be too much.
It'd be too many,
too many hours put into the day.
I'm just too tired by the time I get
home.
Or I'd have to say,
I mean I could do it on the out of camp,
you know,
just to keep my mind right and kind of
get some zen going.
But during campus too much I,
I train too much to be able to have to
have to run as well.
It's funny because everybody's got a
different sort of way of doing it.
Like Jeremy Stevens was on the podcast
recently and one of the things that he
was saying is that he really ramped up
is running to the point where that,
what he was saying is that having like
this like long endurance base really
helps him and fights because he knows
that he is always going to recover.
You can always push further and harder.
To me,
he seems like it kind of fighter that
does need to build on the cardio
anyways.
You know,
I feel like each person's body is gonna
react differently to training and I'm
someone that has endless cardio.
I feels like when I'm fighting and
training.
So I need to stay more,
a little more fast twitch and I'm always
putting size on instead of losing it.
And I feel like Stevens has been trying
to drop weight and get smaller and it
helped with his weight cut.
I'm sure.
Yeah.
I think it helps with his weight cut her
Bra.
But I think with him it's also like a
mental thing too.
He wants a break guys.
Like he's such an aggressive guy.
Like that's a big part of like it's
training.
It's just being able to like have those
extra gallons and the gas tank.
Absolutely.
I mean I think that's what,
it's kind of hard.
It's hard for me to run because of my
mind.
So crazy though to like,
I'll go,
I'll,
I'm all over the place.
I would rather hit mitts and be
aggressive.
I'm too too aggressive of a person I
guess.
But we were talking before the podcast
about our friend campaigns just ran 200
miles and we're like,
that shit is not good for you to no way.
No Way.
That's not good.
Your body's not supposed to do that.
It might be good for his brain though
cause he's so fucking crazy.
Like,
he needs to know that he can do
something like he ran for 78
hours.
That's why I want to hunt with him.
Cause I,
I just know it's like my dad,
my,
when I grew up hunting,
we'll go hike a hundred miles in a week
to go,
go out the back country and have a
backpack and sleep out in the middle of
the woods.
I just feel like that's how cameron
hanes would do it,
you know,
just as hard as possible just to just to
do it.
Yeah.
My friend Adam Green tree from Australia
came over,
flew over to America last week,
went to Montana and then hiked some
crazy amount of miles into the
mountains,
uh,
camped out when in deeper and deeper
cause he kept encountering wolves and
Grizzly bears camped out there,
shot an elk.
And for the last four days has been
packing out this elk by himself.
Wow.
Four days.
So if you've never shot an elk or you
ever seen an elk before,
folks and elk could weigh,
you know,
somewhere around 800 pounds,
which is probably around 400 pounds of
meat that he's packing out.
So four days of a hundred pounds on his
back.
When we are in your hiking,
you can't carry it all.
You got a quarter it out.
So not only say you hike five miles with
some of your back,
you had to go back and get the rest of
the Elta height that five miles again.
So you're hiking the same trail,
a trail,
you know,
two,
three,
four times depending on how big Dell,
cause you know when you're quartered
out.
Yeah.
And he's pretty sure he said he hiked 12
hours.
So that could easily be,
you know,
who knows how many miles at high
altitude,
I'd imagine a puzzle.
So he's got a hundred pounds on his back
for 10 hours.
12 hours a day for four days in a row.
Yeah.
That's an engine.
That's a workout.
I feel like there's,
I feel like there's nothing better than
that.
It's so primal hunt with a bow out in
the middle of nowhere.
Especially,
I mean by herself.
That's crazy.
Well y'all,
he'll also,
you could get them on instagram.
Adam Green tree bow hunter on instagram.
He documented at all,
you know what the instagram stories.
So he was there.
There is a,
and a dude met him up there,
a friend of his,
a hiked through the night to come and
meet him up there and help him I think
on the third or fourth day.
But uh,
he's got all these videos of him up
there in the mountains.
That's an awesome picture.
Yeah.
It's just,
it's just so cool because I mean,
he's just out there survive.
Look at this.
We're looking right now for folks at
home listening.
We're looking at this tent that's
covered in snow,
the grounds covered in snow and uh,
this is where he's been living for the
past week.
And that is the high country because
when you're a public land,
most countries don't or most,
yeah.
Most countries don't have the same sort
of public land set up that we have in
the United States.
We can just go hike into the mountains
and camp out and these national forests.
And so,
uh,
he,
took advantage of all that and he's up
there.
Oh,
where's it savage Australia.
okay.
Okay.
That's right.
Yeah.
All you have to do is come to Montana.
You buy a tag.
I think attack for an elk is 1000 bucks.
And you know,
he's up there with a,
a pistol because there's bears up there.
So his,
his,
uh,
his kill site,
a bear came in on his kill site when he
came back.
There was a grizzly there and there's a
lot of grizzlies in Montana.
Um,
uh,
Mendez
was just up in Alaska and got an awesome
Mousse and a,
his story's pretty cool too.
What?
He got a real big moose.
And then over the night and camp,
a grizzly bear came in and tried to take
his moose off and took a big chunk out
of its neck.
Yeah.
So it is his whole story of what he's
got going up there.
It's pretty cool.
Yeah.
Went on an awesome hunt and she'll hold
wow.
Look at that thing.
Yeah.
So we're looking at Chad Mendez is it
says a 63 inch do it yourself.
Alaska Moose Hunt is now live on his
youtube channel,
63 inches,
the width of the horns,
which is just insane.
That's insane.
That is an enormous animal.
So if an elk is 800 pounds,
that's probably like 1500,
1600 pounds.
That's an enormous animal.
And he goes through guided hunts,
right?
Yeah.
He just guides.
He guides people.
That's his passion.
Yeah.
That's what he wants to transition to
after he's done fighting.
That's where his passions at and he's
extremely good at it.
So no reason not to.
That's cool.
Well,
here's a question.
He got popped for some supplement thing.
Like one of the in a lot of people were
getting popped for tainted supplements.
If you buy things in the store,
there's a lot of supplements that you
get like at any,
any nutrition store that have all these,
uh,
like if they're not steroids,
they're peptides.
There are all these things that sort of
make your body produce more hormones
that are real legal by Usada.
And,
uh,
he got caught for that stuff apparently.
Is that what he got caught for?
That they proved it.
That it was a supplement.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Oh cool.
I haven't really asked them too much
about it.
It's a bummer.
That's good.
At this level you have to be made.
It would be mindful of what you're
taking into the body.
So especially with the new guidelines.
So it's just part of following the
rules.
Can't go in the Cajun.
I poked some way,
but go.
I didn't know.
Now there's so much going on with the
supplements now you have to make sure
you put it in the research and
investigation.
Speaking in your body.
I poke in.
Did you see that picture of Travis
Brown's finger knuckle deep into
febreeze over dooms eyeball?
He didn't even say anything in the fight
right there for doom.
I don't remember seeing Verdomme Call
Hall.
I don't remember.
I did see that jump,
that jump psychic in the beginning of
the hand on his trainer like crazy.
It was a cool,
without that fight there was cool.
It was a cool fight.
Well,
it was,
it was a bomber to me to see Travis
fight like that,
because I remember travis earlier in his
career was just to look at that picture.
That is fucking insane.
Esther,
Esther Lynn from all elbows on
Instagram,
put this picture up and,
um,
she's an mma,
a photographer.
She takes awesome pictures,
a picture.
And this is insane.
I mean,
it is literally knuckled deep in his
eyeball.
It just,
it's hard to look at,
man.
It's just,
Oh,
my knuckle though too.
Right?
There's middle knuckle.
His finger has disappeared in the
eyeball.
I don't remember him stopping or saying
I poke or anything.
I don't remember either.
Let's focus.
But there was a bad one earlier in the
night with Jimmy Rivera and a Uriah.
Yeah.
That was a bad one.
And Jimmy Rivera after the fights that
he couldn't see,
he still couldn't see.
He's like,
he said,
he couldn't tell what color things were
out of his right eye.
Yeah.
Fucking I blokes,
man.
Pride gloves,
Huh?
On the gloves.
A little bit of a car to turn there.
And that opened all the way.
Sorry.
No,
I think you're right.
Yeah.
Most of the time,
this is what I do.
I obsessed about marshmallows to making
things better.
Someone's got to do something because
the way things are going,
we're just so many guys are getting,
I go so many guys getting damaged
eyeballs.
It's just,
it's not worth it man.
And it seems like we're waiting for
something terrible to happen.
You know?
Like look at Michael Bisping,
I dunno.
Bisping's came from a kick though.
I feel like it might've come from
vittores kick.
What was it that or was it in practice?
I don't know.
Do you think it was in practice?
I think he detached his retina a couple
times,
so I think that's why it is the way it
is.
I think he's heard it multiple times and
it was kind of where it,
because it's not completely fixed.
I think they fixed it enough to where he
can fight and then when he's done
fighting they'll probably fix is I
completed these,
what it seems like what they did is they
stuck oil in his eye.
I don't understand it,
but one of his eyeballs apparently has
oil in it that's protecting the retina.
So that's why one of his eyeballs is
black,
like,
you know.
Yeah.
I was wondering what was going on with
designs.
That's why.
Yeah.
One is black and one is his original
ICO,
which I'm not sure what it is,
but it's very strange looking,
but it's just,
he's a fucking savage.
I mean,
he didn't even consider retiring.
He's like,
Hey,
yeah,
stick some oil in there.
Let's get going.
We didn't reckon do put an eyepatch on.
Let's do this.
Got To get back to the gym mate.
He does push it.
That guy comes to fight.
He said Animal Michael Bisping is the
middleweight champion of the world.
And who saw that coming?
He did.
Yep.
I seen that opening and uh,
and uh,
luke rockhold to instagram videos
leading up to the fight.
I seen the same thing his trainer saw.
Really?
Yeah.
He was leading it back.
He was telling me weeks before the fight
that thinks he was doing,
while he's hitting Mitts,
dropping his right hand all the time
with his left cross and kind of leaning
back and kind of shoulder roll and,
and whatnot.
And Duane called it out a couple of
weeks before the fight that he saw
openings.
You know,
he didn't say he was gonna get knocked
out with it,
but he saw some openings there,
you know,
is there,
I mean that's,
it's pretty simple.
We can see where the openings are on
that one for sure.
And uh,
I remember after bisbing caught him and
his trainer point Adam,
and I'm not quite sure what he said and
left him,
but he was for sure saying like,
see,
I told you,
I told you I like that one.
Yeah.
Yes.
He's a good boxing coach.
He understands the game.
I got respect for that guy.
Um,
but it's cool to see something you've
trained multiple times come out and
actually work.
And then when the fight and then the
title fight.
Ooh,
that's,
that's nice.
That's rewarding.
And along the lines of like what we were
talking about today when we were working
out is there's so much depth to this
sport.
There's so many options and there's so
many possibilities that to the outside
or people look at it,
it looks brutal.
You see that I poke and you're like,
oh my God,
this sports should be illegal as much.
Correct.
But to a person who really understands
and watches it and appreciates it,
it's like there's so,
it's like this crazy language that you
have to learn with all these different
words and all these different ways of
putting together sentences.
And I like to use the language analogy
because I'll give,
you're talking to someone and they only
know a few words and want to yell at
you,
but you're like some Sam Harris type
dude who can just has an incredible
language and you're just so eloquent.
He spin them up like a web and they
don't really don't know what the fuck to
say.
And that also happens in a fight when a
guy has a very simple,
like real obvious game.
He does a couple of things and he does
it well as long as you engage him in
that same sort of simple,
obvious way.
He's got a chance.
But when you over flood,
I'm like,
Dwayne,
this Duane was showing me this switch
series that he works on,
which is really amazing.
Really,
really interesting stuff.
Thank you sir.
But one of the things I noticed is while
you were demonstrated to me,
because it's so unusual if forced my
brain to hiccup for a second ago.
Oh,
okay.
And if that happens in a fight,
you're Foxville oh right.
Oh yeah.
100% those little hiccups.
Right.
Those little moments where your brain is
overloaded because it's got to think
instead of just react because you're
doing something unique
thinking inside the octagon,
you're going to get caught,
you're going to be in trouble.
It's,
you need to have a completely clear mind
and just kind of react to things.
And for me,
it's just been kind of having fun out
there.
You know,
the more fun I have and the more loose I
stay,
the better I'm going to fight.
If I go in there with a game plan and
thinking of what I want to throw in,
what to watch,
watch out for what he's good at,
what he's not good at,
then I'm going to be a little bit
slower.
You know,
we were talking about your fight with
dominick Cruz that you seem so emotional
like you want it to kill that dude like
you were.
So I mean I definitely want to kill him.
You know it was so hot.
I mean it was obvious you were,
you were head hunting as opposed to like
one of the things that I really enjoyed
about what your first and your second
fight with Hanan Barao but your first
fight with Hanan Barao was like,
here you are fighting for the title.
And he was like,
you're on a sparring session.
You were just so loose.
Like right away you can throw every,
there's nothing and attention to what
you were doing.
Everything was like flowing and I was
like,
look how well he's responding to the
pressure.
You were having a great time out.
Yeah,
exactly.
Not,
not thinking about it,
you know.
And like you said with the Cruz thing,
I want,
I wanted to finish him.
I want him to go out there and put a
point on it.
And uh,
you know,
things you learned from those are,
those are the small mistakes you learn
from it and you change them up next time
and you,
uh,
come out there a little more level
headed and uh,
you know,
play his game.
That kind of like you were saying,
you know,
he,
he's a point fighter,
you know,
and if you go out there and let him
point fight you,
then that's what he's going to do,
you know?
Um,
so you've got to be able to react to how
he fights it and change it up a little
bit.
And that's why each training camps a
little bit different.
And you learn those
things,
you know,
when you go and watch a fight after it's
over,
do you see openings and you're like,
shit,
yeah,
that's called regret.
Sorry.
Yeah,
100%.
You'll,
you'll see it in the,
uh,
you'll all get,
I'll start sweating because I'm getting
mad that I didn't do something
correctly.
You know,
like in the end of the first round,
I was watching the fight against Cruz
and I had a double leg locked up so deep
and I just didn't finish it.
And that could have changed an entire,
the entire fight,
just one take down the beat.
In the first shot I was all the way
deep,
hands under his butt perfectly.
I just stand,
pinch my elbows to finish it.
So I went to lift him and he slid right
through my arms.
One difference I had to make was
pinching my elbows and you know,
it
changes it just one of those things in
the moment.
Isn't it fascinating how like you have
to train perfectly and then you have to
just let everything go automatic.
Yeah,
that's exactly it.
You just,
you hit the nail on the head is to train
everything perfectly.
Now it comes down to quality reps,
but then what's a quality rep hitting in
that?
Getting here or getting them to take
down,
not getting taken down,
things like that.
Right.
So now it comes to the,
the point of adapting to the athlete in
the scenario and what's correct.
Again is making sure they have high
success with that technique,
whatever that technique may be.
So just putting in,
putting in the time that reps till it
comes out fluidly and there's no longer
a thought,
but the instant reaction.
Well and also having the right coaches
to give you that information and can
give you that high level technique
because there's so many people out there
that are talented people,
but you see their game just doesn't
evolve.
It just hits this level and it's sort of
like the level that their coaches are
capable of taking them to and then they
don't go any further.
And in that code you have to believe in
trust and that coach will take you to
that level of someone.
I mean,
someone can be telling you the exact
thing you need to do,
but if you don't trust and believe that
guy,
if he doesn't get it through your head
the right ways,
then it's not going to make sense.
You know,
you're not gonna,
you're not gonna do it cause you don't
believe in it.
Well,
I think it's amazing what's going on
right now with MMA that people who are
casual people like,
um,
perfect example,
the other day I was at my daughter's
school and one of the dads came up to me
and this dude was just a new fan.
He'd only been watching mma for the past
year and he was just rapid firing
questions at me and he was obsessed with
it.
He's like,
I was never into martial arts when I was
a kid.
I watched a little bit of boxing and
he's like,
but man that UFC has just got me hooked.
And he's like,
one of the things that I love about it
is how many different ways of fight can
end.
He's like,
it's just,
it's so crazy.
Like you'll,
you'll watch a fight and then all of a
sudden the guy's getting choked.
Just like what happened?
And we were going over this,
uh,
about it.
And this guy was a real smart guy.
I think he's like a hedge fund manager
or something like that.
But he was obsessed with all the
possibilities,
you know?
And I think casual fans are starting to
understand now that this is a very
intellectual pursuit.
If you don't have a strong mind and if
you don't have this full range of
options and possibilities inside the
octagon,
you're most likely limiting yourself.
Agreed.
I see that.
Yeah.
Possibilities are nice when you change
things up.
And again,
like we said earlier,
confused the brain,
get them thinking about something else
and then you do something else.
So that's always nice.
But I think right now we're seeing like,
um,
there's a,
there's a pack,
right?
There's like the standard pack of,
of athletes that are doing things in a
certain way and then there's a few that
are moving away from the pack and
they're expanding the potential of MMA.
I think you're one of those people.
No,
I appreciate that.
And I think you for sure are one of
those coaches and there's a few guys out
there I know you don't like to hear,
but dominick Cruz is one of them.
He's also doing it.
And we were talking about him today that
like his style
is so fucking odd.
You know,
like it's technically not sound
actually,
but you know,
but he uses it the right ways.
He's got awesome timing.
Yeah.
He's got great cardio,
he's got a great Chin and then you can
get away with the bad things he does.
Cause he does them for the right way for
himself.
You know,
I don't necessarily think you can say
it's technically bad because he's so
fucking successful.
Yeah.
And he knows how to do it.
I just think it's not standard.
You know,
like he doesn't like we're using Ramon
dekkers as an example.
He does not throw kicks and punches like
Ramon dekkers.
But what he does do is he throws him
like Dominick Cruz where he's moving
like a pendulum back and forth and it's,
footwork is so weird and he's
overwhelming your mind with
possibilities.
And he doesn't do the same thing twice.
He mixes things up so well that he's a
tough nut to crack.
Did he?
He,
he's tricky.
He is trickier than I expected for sure.
But the,
you know,
a piece of that,
again,
game planning is the talks up to the
fight to get them emotionally invested
and then it becomes a bit trickier to
find the head.
Right.
So that's the goal.
When you were,
when you were leading up to the fight,
he was talking so much yet and you could
tell that you were getting so upset,
but that is a big factor in fights,
right?
Because fights are so emotional because
it's one of the only sports in the world
where your health is on the line.
Like literally like this the option,
it's not like you might get in a car
accident when you're racing cars that
that's a possibility.
But the goal of MMA is for you to fuck
up someone's body.
Yeah,
absolutely man.
Um,
the other thing you had with him too
that makes it pisses you off so much is
that he'll attack anything and just talk
about some of the,
doesn't even make sense just to talk and
talk louder and faster and not,
I'll give you a chance to talk.
It's like a high school girls just
bickering at each other.
I think that's what pisses you off the
most,
you know,
cause he's not even actually making a
great point.
He's just making it and making it
louder.
Voice.
Very articulate.
Yeah.
It a good good analyst because of that,
you know,
greed.
So my technique,
if you get a chance to find him again
for the title,
I bet which you're in line.
Yeah,
right.
Obviously,
well you lost a very close decision to
him and then you beat hot felon,
Sun's out.
Which in my opinion was a,
we were talking about this today was an
excellent example of how far you
progressed because you guys had a really
tough fight the first time you fought.
It was a close fight.
This fight was not closed.
He just ran away from him and he ran
away with the,
uh,
the fight rather,
not run away from him,
but rent.
I mean,
you were just,
it was a clear victory.
It was like you're just were so much
more technical.
There was so many more options you were
presenting to him and he was basically
the same fighter that he was back then.
Maybe slightly better.
But you're all way better fun.
I appreciate him and we,
we've worked hard.
We've long hours where it's really hard.
Um,
you know,
it's crazy how the,
like you said,
the sport works out how quick things can
change.
You know what I mean?
I could be on 11 fight win streak right
now and a split decision loss to have
fail since sal.
You know,
I thought I won that fight.
A very close fight with dominick Cruz
that I felt I want as well.
Those two fights go my way.
I'm on 11 fight win streak.
You still have the belt,
you know,
known as hopefully one of the greatest
comp pound fighters in the world.
You know,
and we have stuff for sure.
What's interesting right now too is this
new rule,
a set that's going to go into place in
January,
you know,
a where they've changed this whole thing
about down fighters like being able to
attach it down.
Yeah,
good call.
You have to have four points down now.
So if you,
yeah,
if you put a hand down on the ground and
someone kicks you,
that's,
that's totally legit now.
Which I think it's long time coming.
I think that's a,
I'm a little bummed out that didn't give
her of the 12 six elbow but you know,
whatever,
which is one of the most ridiculous
rules cause that's really not going to
hurt you anymore than me putting a shin
across your face,
you know,
like crazy or getting neat in the face
and crushing your skull.
Yeah.
That stuff happens all the time and now
you're going to take away an elbow and
you can't even really generate that much
force with,
I don't feel it's not more forest.
Yeah.
I mean I think there's way more forced
than the elbow that comes down the side.
Cause it's more like a punch because
you'll get your whole shoulder torques
into it.
Your shoulder dropping down is a weird
movement.
I mean,
I guess there's some guys like Anderson
Silva or you know,
yachts and Cli or some badass tie
fighters that can generate ridiculous
power with that.
But I don't think it's any more than any
other kind of elbow.
Absolutely not.
No Way.
It's just some of the rules I think are
a little bit archaic I think.
I think we all agree though.
The the,
the,
the gloves.
Yes sir.
Probably like if there's going to be
like one thing that needs to be changed,
I mean it would be really nice.
We could all get together and figure out
a way to make it so there's less high
pokes and here's three experts in the
field right now.
We're all saying no pride style gloves
would be an example or like the shadow
gloves,
but anything that it doesn't allow the
hand to fully open.
Fuck they own pride.
Just use those goddamn gloves.
Those are the sweetest gloves too.
I love the pride gloves.
I collect all kinds of fight
memorabilia.
Yeah.
I'm all over the place now.
They're dope man,
by the way.
Show everybody your,
your wallet.
Oh yeah.
I'm a boxing coach.
Whitman who is by far the most technical
martial arts I've ever come across.
He took a,
an old fight glove and a worth.
The cameras are there.
Made me a wallet out of my glove.
Yeah,
I saw it on.
So dope theft is nice.
He uh,
he makes all my,
uh,
my punch punishments but type has met my
belly,
showed my leg kick paths,
might kick shield.
I'm super impressed.
I was always impressed with trevor as a
cost.
Some get a picture so I'm going to put
that he's just,
he's just an engine.
I mean I'll take that same skill set and
put that into martial arts or to
developing technique or drills.
That's the same things that you did that
same information to running a successful
business or whatever it is you just
said.
Detailed guy.
Yeah.
It's uh,
it's,
it's just fun to see someone do
something that's unique,
Huh?
So colors,
you guys are in Colorado now.
You moved to Colorado full time,
you know,
how much different is it live in there
and what is it like now?
Also your,
your training at altitude all the time.
That actually made a huge difference
that even taken to account when I first
went out there when I was cross training
and I was going back and forth from my
camps going from Sacramento to Colorado
and always going back out there,
it was so tough and,
and somebody will get affected by that
to do differently.
You know some like Joseph Benevidez
doesn't get affected by it at all.
I feel like that Mexicans,
he never gets tired.
Mannequins don't get tired.
I don't know some racist things to say
but in a positive way.
Tell you I'm the Mexicans have a fucking
incredible gas tanks and Joseph will
come up,
he'll be gone in Vegas,
we'll come out and he'll train exactly
the same for me,
when I go to altitude,
it messes with me big time,
but I feel like I get the effects from
it long,
long term.
When I'm done with the camp,
like I felt big differences when I
trained at w train at altitude,
when I'm done with my camp,
after I've been up there for six weeks,
I'm in a camp and you come back down to
sea level.
When we first started hitting mitts that
wherever we go,
it just feels awesome.
You know,
sea level,
you feel like a superman,
right?
Yeah.
It's crazy how much of a difference it
makes.
Have you ever tried one of those
altitude tents,
those things that people sleeping?
I have tried it.
It's so hard to sleep in it,
isn't it?
Yeah.
It gets hot in there and then it,
and then your body doesn't recover as
well.
You know,
if you're sleeping,
that's really high altitude.
He mean anything higher than we're at.
If just even a real high altitude,
it's hard for your body to actually
recover overnight when you're actually
supposed to recover.
You're supposed to,
you know,
have your testosterone built up when
you're sleeping and oxygen getting to
your muscles and recover over the night.
And if you're sleeping at high altitude,
it's really hard to do that.
You wake up more sore,
you wake up more tired and it's hard to
recover.
Interesting.
So what I had heard was that the best
balance was training at sea level,
but sleeping and living at altitude.
I heard that as well.
It seems like it wants to go back and
forth all the time.
That's what I heard when I was in
school.
You know I was a kinesiology major and I
was really into exercise physiology.
They said train low,
sleep high,
you know,
so that your body,
when you're sleeping and hanging out,
you're rebuilding all these red blood
cells,
but then your threshold or working out
at sea level,
you can push it so much harder.
So your body's used to go in that hard,
you know,
but you,
you're training in lack oxygen,
you can't train as hard.
So I mean that makes sense to me.
But then when sleeping in and out to do
10 I feel like you can't recover until
you're acclimated.
Once you're acclimated,
you can recover because you have more
red blood cells in your body.
But until then,
I wonder if anybody does it where like
you live in San Bernardino and then
train up in big bear and just keep going
back and forth
and then sleep Tito's thing for awhile.
He lived up there though,
right?
First Tito,
you still live up there for his camps.
He was one of the first MMA fighters to
incorporate that,
you know,
boss Oh,
Boston,
Boston puffers,
heavyweight title.
Uh,
he came to Colorado for his camp for its
fight against Kevin Randleman.
So I sit there Rutan so,
cause uh,
there was a promoter in town that would
hold shows.
They were called the lone wolf
invitational and uh,
he had a couple shows and then I think
it would be his third show.
Boss was there.
He was just the special guest.
So then the shows after that,
we're now at the boss Rutten
invitationals but when he was there,
he would,
he would be a special guests of the show
and then he would do a seminar the next
day.
Then I'd fight on the show and then do
with seminars.
That's how we,
uh,
came together and,
he noticed the effects of the altitude
and then sweet,
just his next camp there.
I wonder if there's a difference between
like when,
when I think when they're studying how
athletes perform while they sleep at a
high altitude and train at low altitude.
I wonder if there's a difference between
the intensity level that MMA
requires and the amount of like,
I don't think there's a sport in the
world that requires you to train as much
as mma because there's so many different
things you have to work on or as hard.
Like we just share with a lot of nfl
players with Lauren then Dow,
uh,
and,
and Denver,
he trains a lot of denver players and a
lot of guys come for before they do
their combine and come and train with
them.
And you just kind of realize like how
much harder your shrink conditioning is
and how much harder you have to push.
And that's just one workout,
you know?
And then maybe they're going to do some
football drills and whatnot and we're
going to hit meds and do some grappling
and wrestling.
And it's,
it's a very tough sport to get ready
for.
I mean,
I really don't know if there's many that
are as hard or harder.
That's what makes it fun,
Huh?
It's fun to watch.
You know?
It's really kind of crazy when you think
about like the 10 minute rounds a pride
had and how difficult five minute rounds
are.
Well,
he definitely needed,
if you're a grappler,
I mean,
who the fuck is going to beat Damien
Maia if ever rounds,
10 minutes.
Good point.
Yeah,
you're going to be worn out.
That guy's a backpack is such,
he's so on another level right now.
That's one of those guys.
It's so good at one thing,
but he's,
but he's incredible at it that he can
get away with it.
Most guys can't get away with just being
good at one individual aspect of them
and may,
but he's one of those guys that he's
just so dominant at Jujitsu that you can
get away with it.
That's the,
the theory too,
or the concept is he's really good.
They were in,
they could choke while a few submissions
obviously.
Right,
but let's say you're,
you're just Ninja at the in.
They could choke.
Now that's your one technique.
Now everyone's aware of that.
So I got to do was just have different
entries for that rear naked choke.
Right.
So different entries and then obviously
you finished the submission.
But as far as the striking concept,
the same techniques or combination,
just different entries in different
exits.
Right.
Again,
that same technique itself.
Yeah.
There was a few guys who have just
really excelled at one particular
technique to the point where it gets
ridiculous.
Like remember cody Mckenzie was catching
everybody with that.
Mckenzie [inaudible] callback.
Yeah.
Ski Team.
He came and showed it at Alpha male
thing.
It's crazy,
but you got to be built for it though.
He's like perfectly built for his arms
are long,
skinny.
Well,
uh,
then there was Paul Sas.
Remember Paul says like the triangle 12
fights in a row by triangle and
everybody knew it was coming.
He couldn't do shit about it,
but you can get it.
Yeah.
You can use that to your advantage
though as well.
So I was helping Matt Brown train from
Maya and uh,
I didn't like how he was approaching the
fight that he was so worried about what
he was going to do.
He's like,
he's going to do these take downs,
he's going to take her back.
He's going to do this.
Like he was so entrenched in what Damien
Maia was going to do to him in the fight
rather than worrying about what he
should do,
what aspects He should take to the fight
to stay away from his game instead of
really what he's going to do.
So,
you know,
you can use that to your advantage if
you're a fighter that's so strong at one
thing,
confused someone and get them so worried
about what you're going to do,
that they're actually thinking inside
the fight rather than reacting and just
doing what they're good at already.
Cause if Matt,
if Matt would have fought,
I feel like the way he should have in
that fight,
he could've picked Damien Maia apart
maybe.
Yeah,
yeah.
Oh No,
he would've got fucking grapple fucked
again maybe later on.
But yeah,
that's my hope and thought at least.
Yeah.
Well I'm a big map brown fan,
but I'm a be Zoe and Maya fan as well.
For me it's,
it's weird,
you know,
because I'm a fan of a lot of guys and
these guys oftentimes fight each other
and it's just like you just got to
appreciate the event and appreciate the
results.
Sure.
Appreciate the sport.
It was one of the cool things about mma
is that there are these outliers like
this one trick pony,
like Damien Maia.
But what a fucking trick.
I mean he's,
I mean he can strike and Damien striking
has gotten leaps and bounds better.
It's one of the reasons why he's gotten
so better at applying his Jujitsu is
because he's so much more comfortable
with his standup is distance is very
good.
Now we understand striking really well
now,
but that Jujitsu,
it's just so next level making it
happen.
So he runs through a guy like Carlos
condit like that.
Yeah.
Or out graph was Gunnar Nelson grabbed
his gunner Nelson that easy and you know
all them.
Yeah,
just Malden,
like you said,
at another level.
For sure.
And also goes to show you how fucking
good jake shields is.
Oh,
you're right.
People sleep on jake shields.
Jake shields beat him in a,
essentially a grappling match,
you know,
and a lot of people forget,
Jake shields was always a guy who kind
of struggled with a standup because he
wasn't like a explosive guy who's just
sort of like comp awkward.
His standup.
Yeah.
Awkward.
But again,
he beat Tyron Woodley the fucking welter
weight champion.
The world lead them in essentially a
standup file.
So of Nate Marquardt.
Yeah,
she'll just smile with his grappling.
He,
he's coming out the muscle farm,
worked out with us and showed some
technique and his top game is just so
ridiculous and he's strength.
It's just all about is positioning the
weighs on you.
It's,
it's so tough.
I mean it's,
it's a chest mass freshman chess match
for sure.
Yeah.
He gets slept on,
he's fighting Fitch now.
They're going to fight in the world
series of fighting.
That's a very good fight.
Very,
very interesting fight.
That's interesting.
We have bought both ways.
I was wondering about Fitch.
That's good to see him back in there.
Here's a fuck per wall.
Right?
I don't know when the last time he
tested positive after he fought pal
horace.
Oh,
did he?
Yeah,
I thought it was knee got hurt a little
bit of that too,
but he tested positive for elevated
testosterone.
Oh Wow.
Yeah,
I have that.
You got to follow the rules and the
guidelines.
Rules to happen.
Yeah.
But back to like styles.
It just,
is it just so interesting that there are
so many different styles and there's so
many different people like wonder boy,
he's a one trick pony and the other
direction,
you know,
just his fucking striking.
It's just bizarre.
And his style is like really a karate
based,
almost like a sport karate style.
But it's incorporates the movement in
the operating for a longer distance and
he likes to draw people in to get them
extended before he catches himself.
So he's like a Cobra.
Exactly.
Is Movement like his back and forth
pivoting off the waist.
But he also,
he does another thing that fucks with
people is that front leg.
Yeah.
His front leg is so nasty.
I keep when he fought Hendrix,
he hit when a front lake side to the
body and you could see Hendrix got leg
stuck by,
it was a hard shot and you're like kind
of acknowledged it and then he got
roundhouse kicked in the face with the
same foot like right away.
Zohan in her face all the time.
It just never stops.
Funny to me,
a dream fight is Damien Maia versus
wonderboy.
The complete opposite style.
That's a dream fight.
I want to see what the right,
it's like,
I feel like now what we're watching two
with Damien Maia is also,
we're watching this master who's 38 Oh,
you're right.
Good point.
Yeah.
He's still,
well he's,
he's up there for the competitive ages,
but he seems as healthy and it can
happen.
We said 38 me forever.
It's one of those things where you got
to wonder like how much more sand is
left and that hourglass means it pulled
the radica tour trick just fine until
he's 50 yeah.
I mean fuck randy almost came out of
retirement for fade or oh nine he was
thinking about fighting.
What am I saying?
That just as an old fight fan?
Yeah,
for sure.
You got to think about that.
My other two being 38 and be able to
push it that hard still is it his style
of fighting,
you know,
he's not getting hit very much.
He's on your back.
You know,
his training's probably that way as
well,
and so he's able to go a little bit
longer rather than someone that's going
to be in front of you and slug it out.
Yeah.
Good point.
He's definitely taking less damage
striking wise over the years when Judas
stat on him,
when we got hit 13 times over the last
four fights.
No.
Well,
yes.
And like the like it just,
that's in most of them are the Matt
Brown fight.
Yeah.
Oh Wow.
It's just fucking crazy how like
technical he is when it comes to his
Jujitsu.
Yeah.
That's why you don't play Jujitsu.
Right.
So we've got to punch him in the face
while he kicks like nate Marquardt did.
Yeah.
Well nate caught him early in his career
too though.
Still striking up game.
Yeah.
People sleep on nate Marquardt too,
man.
You know,
people forget how God damn good nate,
especially in his prime.
And you watched that tyron Woodley fight
when you fought him in strikeforce.
He looked really good.
Then you have a nation that he hit him
with was like fucking a video game.
Yeah.
Yup.
He was sharp.
That's when he was working with the
Trevor Whitman.
He's back with trevor as well.
But his name again,
trevor is by far the most technical
detailed,
uh,
martial artist instructor that I've come
across in,
in any field.
He really makes it breaks things down.
And I hear Shane Carwyn is making a
comeback
as well.
Yeah,
he's a free agent.
Yup.
So he can go wherever he wants.
Interesting.
Wonder where that's going to go.
Good.
Nice thing.
Is he training with trevor as well?
I'm not sure.
I don't actually spend too much time
with trevor,
but uh,
hopefully if he's smart he should.
He will.
I know he's really close with the
wrestling coach me at least,
or bullying.
And I've been hearing it from the Easter
that you know,
he's a free agent and looking about
getting back into working out and seeing
how his body holds up to see if you know
how he's going to push it and what's
gonna happen.
Yeah.
He has some pretty significant back
injuries.
Right?
Yup.
It was his neck.
Right.
I think is,
you know,
you gotta think that guy played football
at a high level for a long time and all
that crashing big dudes smashing into
each other.
Those guys are freaking nature's man.
I can't,
that's so crazy to be able to be that
big and that fast 230 pounds is run into
somebody who's standing there.
It's not good for you.
Yeah.
I definitely not good for you.
You want to stay healthy,
that's for sure.
Yeah.
Cause it goes back to uh,
keep keeping those same rules in line
when you're training that the goal of
the training is to get better,
right.
Not to hurt each other.
So just making
sure you're taking care of your partner.
And learn to use this time to improve
and get better and better.
I get the better you get and so on.
Yeah.
And if you can get a good camp like that
where everybody has their ego in check
and you all grow together,
that's mass.
Yeah,
no egos there to learn and get better.
Overall,
it's something that I've had to
obviously work on too because I'm so
competitive and I want to be the best
all the time.
You know?
Even in the gym,
no matter what,
I'm like I'm pushing like I want to
train harder than you.
I want to be better than you.
And so that's something that we need
doing.
If I had to work with and I've always
had to work on it,
you know,
I just kinda got to,
stay,
control the fire.
How do you control yourself when it
comes to like the amount of work you do?
Do you monitor your heart rate?
Do you check?
Like do you have any sort of markers
that you checked to make sure that
you're not overtrained?
I know a lot of guys do it off their
heart rate.
It's a good way to do it.
Am I just kind of off the field for the
most?
So how am I waking up in the morning and
how am I feeling?
Am I eager to go train?
Am I eager?
Just still feeling like I'm the best in
the world?
That's kind of like my body lets me know
mentally of what I should be doing,
what I should.
And it's taken a while to learn that I
wish I would've known this during
wrestling cause I,
I,
I believe I messed up my wrestling
career in college by just pushing too
hard for too long and red lining my
body.
So it's all just all feel now and I kind
of lay out my,
my whole camp that way,
you know,
I know what days I'm going to do three
practices,
what day I'm going to do one and just
kind of go off a feel,
you know,
if I need to rest the whole weekend or
just rest Sunday,
it's all if just my energy levels and
how much I'm willing to do.
Do you,
do you have a nutritionist or,
I do.
I'm perfecting athletes.
I'm actually teaming up with them now
tune.
We're doing programs for little kids and
for wrestlers as well.
Cause the wrestling,
the wrestling world does not know
enough.
I mean they've cut weight for the
longest amount of time,
but they just do it the wrong ways.
But yeah,
perfecting athletes has helped me out a
lot with my career and they actually
have been able to boost my hormones with
the way I eat.
You know?
And that's how so,
um,
so my,
my a nutritionist Michelle,
she used to be a fertility doctor and
she's real holistic.
She's into acupuncture and doing all
that.
And the,
the,
the foods that they're feeding you are
the right things for your endocrine
system and boosting your testosterone
and making you just a healthier human
being.
I mean,
if you eat and live healthier,
your body is going to produce more
testosterone and live the right way.
And that's what they'd done with me.
And what I've heard is that more fats
like eating more fats,
good fats.
And I've seen it in a lot of different
athletes,
especially athletes it fall,
start falling ketogenic diets that ramps
up their hormone production because fats
are a precursor for hormones,
so a lot of coconut oil,
a lot of Avocados,
saturated fats from healthy meats,
especially like grass fed meat.
I feel like you can't get enough of it.
I mean,
if you're working out as much as I am
during camp or even just working all the
time,
like you can't get more,
the good fats are one of the best things
for you.
Yeah.
That's the other thing to take into
consideration when people talk about
athletes and people talk about people
that exercise and are fit and want to
follow a healthy diet.
There's such a different caloric
requirement.
For someone like you who's training,
what do you train two or three times a
day?
Yeah,
two or three and just to switch it up,
sometimes I'll do one j one harder line.
Just depends where I'm at.
But yeah,
I'd say on average three times a day,
so your body is just a blast furnace.
It's hard for me to hold on to weight.
You know,
it's,
I had a try,
I got to try as hard as they can to keep
my weight up.
So when I'm out of season,
like right now I'm trying to lift his
lift heavy and stay as big as I can.
And then when I get into camp,
you know,
change it up while I'm doing that.
A lot of hypertrophy right now,
let of hypertrophy training,
I'll get closer to campus or doing more
strength training.
And then when I get in camp like closer
to my fight and do more power training.
So when you say hypertrophy,
like what kind of training?
Like what?
Like like dead lifts?
Like what kind of stuff?
Yeah,
I mean I'll obviously I'll do delis and
stuff,
but it just,
it all depends on the reps you're doing
really and how much weight you're going
to do.
So if I wanted my approach,
if you have find a weight that's hard
for me to do 10 to 12 times,
you know,
that's what's gonna make my muscles
build them like higher reps and start
building size.
And then when I want to get strength,
I'm going to start doing less reps,
you know,
around like six and that's hard to do at
six and then that's when we started
building more strength.
You know,
power is uh,
you know,
three quick hard explosive,
dead lifts and cleans and stuff like
that.
Breaks in between sets.
Yeah,
all depends on the brakes as well too.
Yeah.
So when you're getting down to one 45 or
one 35 rather,
how difficult is that for you?
Like what are you walking around at a
during camp and walk around like one 50
I usually show up five days before my
fight at one 52 I usually train what I'm
going to fight at.
So I walk into the cage one 51 53
probably I'm training like that my whole
entire camp five days before the fight
and Wayne one 15 and then I just lose it
all with waterway.
So that's not that much.
Not at all.
And it seems like a lot to poke people
listening probably,
but we know guys who are losing 25 30
which I think is too much.
I think that's not healthy for your
brain.
That's too hard to recover hydration on
your brain.
You know?
Have you ever thought that if you didn't
do the hypertrophy training and you
didn't do all the power training and you
just did more robotic,
like you might drop down to one 45
naturally and then might be able to cut
to one 25 yeah.
Yeah.
I mean I thought I could make 25 I mean
it's definitely wouldn't be fun and I
don't really,
I don't really want to have to,
but yeah,
it's definitely something that I could
do.
I mean,
you know,
I'm trying,
Heidi mouse needs a supervisor.
He does man.
And I'm a huge fan of the guy too.
You know,
he's so good that I would love to fight
him and I,
I do feel I have a really good style for
mighty mouse too.
So,
cause I know he's talking about doing a
superfight.
He's,
I mean it's,
he's in a interesting position because
he's really essentially cleared out his
weight class.
I mean,
he's fighting Wilson Hayes and Wilson's
a very tough fight.
Fight the winner of the show that the
benefits of just,
it's a bit of me just,
just a wrapped up filming a show with
the,
I think,
uh,
do meet you supposed to fight the winner
of the show.
I think you're right.
But what did I read too?
That way he was supposed to fight,
but he got hurt and pulled out of the
fight and now I think he's supposed to
fight the winter.
The ultimate fighting,
sir.
No,
I think you're right.
But I read something today.
I forgot about that,
but I read something today about him
fighting Wilson.
So maybe it was just a,
an older article or something like that,
or maybe it was confused,
but my point is,
even if you fight is the winner of the
show.
It good luck to those guys.
Yeah,
good
luck.
You're fighting a fucking human buzzsaw
yeah,
yeah.
He's on another level again,
cardio punching from all angles.
Yeah.
He's good man.
And he's,
in my opinion,
one of the best examples or the best
example ever of a guy who has so many
possibilities.
His language,
the language of fighting his language
has the richest vocabulary of any
fighter.
I mean the way he fucked so hutto up in
a clinch with those knees to the body
like that is it.
Who does it better than that?
I've never seen a guy did good break a
guy down better with needs to the body
like that.
You'd have to go to Anderson versus rich
Franklin.
Oh Nice.
Good call.
But that was like almost like a more
brutality oriented thing.
I mean when Anderson did it was just
grab a hold of you and just rag doll you
with with when he was doing it,
when mighty mouse is doing,
it was almost like,
like it was crazy to watch.
It's like Jesus Christ,
like these things are coming there.
They're landing like that.
The vibe,
he's firing them off like with no
hesitation.
There's no wind up,
there's no exertion.
Everything seems effortless and they're
there.
It looks like he could do it all day and
it looks like a real fucking problem
when you're in there with them.
Well,
what are the,
I think I'm assuming make sense is Matt
Hume,
his being his coach who's obviously the
wizard,
right?
Very intelligent in the fight world,
but with the background of pseudo
missing weight,
so much attacking the body,
assuming that maybe he had a hard cut
and maybe ate too much to drink too much
and attacking the body as far as the
game plan.
So it was very smart of him.
Then also,
obviously he did it with the correct
timing and accuracy.
So yeah,
it was good.
So who to really struggles to get done
in 25 that's what I hear you look big on
the show.
I filmed a little,
yeah,
I just did 25 huh?
Yeah,
I,
I find that,
yeah,
he may be,
I mean maybe like the exact example
we're talking about with Tj like that
maybe they were like very similar in
size.
Just decided to go down there and AH,
good call.
Yeah.
It just doesn't have the correct,
maybe not the correct path to actually
make it happen.
If he's actually missing weight,
they needed to get,
I don't know what his deal is.
Lesson a long time.
He did a few struggles in the past but
to,
he missed a couple of the UFC weights,
Huh?
Yup.
Yeah.
And they made him fight at one 35 that's
spotify at one 35 and then the showed
them that he could make 25 again and did
it and then because he's going to be
fighting that,
but it'd beat us now and I'm not sure
when that fight is,
maybe December,
but the at me,
this is coming out to Colorado in about
one week.
He just texted me the other day and he
actually bought a condo in Colorado.
Susan be training with us full time
until the fight and that's nice.
But maybe this is a very creative
martial artists.
We and him,
when we train,
we flow,
we create a whole bunch of new rhythms
and paths and patterns.
It's good.
I do.
I love it as a martial artist finding
the next level of the game.
It happens a lot with him.
Also at Tj,
it's fun to work with that level of
athlete just to play with the game
itself.
Overall,
expanding the level of martial arts.
That's where I'm,
I'm fascinated by what's the next level?
Where are we at?
What can we create?
Yeah.
Benevidez is also one of those guys that
if you saw him like in a silhouette,
if you couldn't see who he was,
if you couldn't see any detail but you
saw him move around,
you would know it was him.
Yeah.
That's good.
The way he holds his hand,
the way he holds his hands,
like
everything cause you've got a very
distinct,
oh,
he's one of my favorite people in the
world,
man.
I love that dude.
He's such a character man.
We're really just spinning kicks and
stuff.
He's got him,
dude.
What do you got here for notes,
dude?
What's going on?
It's made just for me to slow down and
make sure I take my time and uh,
yeah,
that's my main thing.
Let's slow down and think I get so
wrapped up and just getting it.
I put myself into fight mode when I talk
and I just got to make sure I'm being
calm and being collective and making
sure I'm getting the points and the
messages across with with what I'm
doing.
Because now obviously on the podcast,
this podcast has helped change my life
over the years.
And I'm sure you get this all the time,
but you'd literally help change people's
lives for the better.
And I thank you for that and thanks for
having me on.
And for us it's,
it's,
it's bad ass,
but uh,
to use this type of properly to help
influence others and not to try to tear
anybody's name down,
but to help uplift and inspiring and
help people become better human beings.
That's what I felt my messages on this
earth is to help people become better in
my vehicle.
My tool is martial arts,
so I love it.
Whether general fitness or training,
the highest level Ninjas to compete for
the belt.
It's my service back to the world to
help make sure we're all together.
Well,
it's interesting to see you really
flourish as a coach too,
because very few fighters who I'm here
taken to it the way you have,
where you're not only will you a very
good fighter and an excellent fighter,
but you've,
you've surpassed that as a coach.
That's really rare.
I feel that.
I agree with that.
I appreciate that.
Um,
I just put my time,
energy and my,
and my ocd ness in to developing others.
Like that's literally what it is.
I'm obsessed with it and there's only
one way to be great.
It's to be obsessive,
you know,
and then to have,
a fellow ninjas like Tj and Benevidez to
play along with,
with this tool of martial arts to see
what the next layer is.
I love it.
You mean I need this level of dedication
and athleticism in order to do that?
So,
uh,
because of them,
I'm at the level that I'm at.
So it's a win win.
Like every relationship should be,
read the notes slow down,
like every relationship should be,
it should be a willing,
not,
oh,
not a one side of the path.
So,
um,
you know,
not long ago Tj asks me why I'm always
so hyper and excited and loving life.
It's because his goals are my goals.
Like one of my dreams is to see him with
the belt again.
Like that's something that I obsess.
I was to make sure he's wearing the belt
there.
It's in its proper place.
So,
and same thing for benevides.
I would absolutely love to have been a
vsp wearing the belt.
So,
um,
for me to help others become better
brings me a lot of joy in it.
And I loved that.
Isn't it funny that that passion and
that intensity and focus has a negative
connotation?
People call it OCD.
We're weird with obsessed.
Yeah.
It works for me.
But it wouldn't mean,
but why,
why is that like necessarily negative?
It's not,
yeah.
For,
well,
I,
for me,
because I have so many things going on,
there's so many other elements
throughout the world with my wife,
my family,
and my business.
I'm lucky and I'm blessed that
everything in my circle,
my bubble works with each other.
Well,
because I mean I take my kids to go and
train,
my wife goes and trains people asking me
this quite a bit.
Are you going to have your,
your kids fight?
No,
I'm not going to have the fight if they
choose to,
I will support their path,
whatever that is.
Whatever their passion is that it was a
support that where they do have to train
because it look at it as a form of
insurance.
I'm not always going to be around to
protect them and want to make sure that
they can handle potential confrontations
if they,
if they can,
if they need to by either talking about
it,
you know,
turn to diffuse a situation or if it
does come to come to a physical
confrontation,
they can handle themselves properly.
But just being healthy and happy and
confident with your walking your talk
and be able to help other people.
That's what I make it.
Sure.
It's mandatory that my kids do train
martial arts and my wife as well,
El Guapo just texted a sensei car.
Man Carter is definitely going to find
out bossy.
Yeah,
little boss.
So my,
uh,
so I have my daughter Jade,
my little boy Duane Ludwig and then my
third child is Carter boss led but we
all refer to him as possible.
I'm a little boss,
he's the man.
So since uh,
since everyone's my main,
uh,
my most influential martial artist to
make an impact on me and uh,
he's changed my life with what he's done
for me is carrying his passion in my
martial arts journey and then he's the
first guy to take combinations and put
them into one coat.
Great boss.
Ruben is here.
Bas rutten,
ladies,
gentlemen,
former UFC heavyweight champion and of
the baddest man that ever lived.
Thank you for coming.
Have a seat time.
No seizures.
I know Carter is going to fight just
cause how aggressive he is.
I remember like the first time ever go
into Dwayne's house and watching his
little two year old,
two year old pride stomp his dog.
He knows what a pride stop,
isn't it?
Price doubling the dog.
We have big,
big huge pit bulls.
One of them was so a move but two year
old kid stomping a pit bull.
That's what people have a misconception.
Pimples being bad dogs,
but they are known in the past as nanny
dogs.
My kids can actually physically rough up
my pit bulls and they don't care.
They're big enough.
They're strong if they're composed of
and they're females.
So they just,
they're just about it.
The female that does definitely helps
for sure.
Yeah.
Don't tell them this story,
uh,
that uh,
you pretty much went naked then I heard
from your wife yesterday separating the
pedals.
So,
uh,
the two dogs did you have two females?
Two females.
That's all good.
Yeah.
So the story would prove your point.
Crack.
Uh,
I'm about to hop in the shower and my
wife tells me the dogs are fighting out
back.
So I grabbed my towel,
I wrapped around it.
I run outside to separate the dogs cause
they'll fight cause there's the
neighbor's dog barks and they'll bark at
that and the bark at each other.
Then they start arguing and fighting.
Right.
So I anyways,
they went outside with my towel on to
get the dog separate them.
While I'm separate in the dogs,
the towel falls off.
But I still have to separate the dogs
and the neighbors behind me.
Now it's a show boom.
And they have,
they have to get together
back naked.
Just rolling with the dog and separating
them and making sure everything is good.
Uh,
I'm not sure.
I'm not sure what his wife looks at me
now and it's a little bit strange.
[inaudible] she does it.
She doesn't know.
Uh,
it's always nice to
feel wanted.
That's a sad scene.
Separating each are fighting pitfalls.
It's funny now he's flopping around this
shit.
Oh yeah.
That would have been good.
Although it's a joke now is I'll stay at
the dogs fighting to go rip my shirt
off.
Now's a good one.
I had two females.
It fought to the death.
Oh,
that's right.
Yeah.
I heard that mom was a dead dog in my
living room.
Not Good.
Yeah.
How was the other dog was healthy or it
had some fucked up.
She was fucked up.
I put her down after that.
She killed another dog too.
She was crazy.
And then a rescue dog.
I got her a little too late to my
rescue.
I got her when she was about nine,
10 months old and two you'd already been
indoctrinated into the world of
violence.
Oh,
I see it as much as I travel and move
around.
I want the pit bulls there cause no
one's in there breaking in my house and
they pit bulls and my wife happened to
the gun and everything so we're good.
Or if they do it,
they're not going to have a good morning
guys.
Yeah.
Yes sir.
Yeah,
there's and females are like super
protective.
She,
they both the more yep.
Yeah,
yeah.
They genuinely love our kids.
Yeah.
But females together like date just
there like chicks together.
Like try,
try having two wives.
Good luck with that shit.
But to get it to the restroom.
Right.
That's what they do.
Go together and stab each other.
Just,
just something about females.
They just,
two men can,
they get together and one of them will
decide or two male dogs,
one of them will decide like,
okay,
that guy is the king and I'll just
fucking cower when he growls at me.
But females dade fucking,
they never decide who the outfits,
they just go,
Nah,
that bitch got lucky last time.
We're going
right now.
It's women.
It's all the time with women.
If you think about it,
well my wife goes to bank for it.
She went out with the other women.
They all this always stressed like,
oh,
so and so has cancer so and so is this
with us,
with guys that never comes up right here
about him?
He got no,
we are like Barney.
Yeah.
So much sorrow.
That is so true.
Women always want to tell you who's
sick,
who's got a problem.
Oh,
she's got chronic fatigue syndrome.
they read on the Internet.
Oh,
I have a headache.
And they read it and you're like,
oh,
this could be cancer,
right?
Oh yeah,
all the time.
My wife says it's good.
My wife,
she's on point with stuff.
She's good about that.
Good positive stuff and last down and
take care of the family and she,
she's good.
She's programmed herself wisely.
I feel well they say that there's
natural sort of evolutionary path that
women get together and talk a lot.
Like that's one of the reasons why
gossip exists so much with women because
women would be gathering food and
talking and that was one of the ways
they figured out who was full of shit
and who wasn't.
They had where's the men would be out
hunting and he'd be like,
shut the fuck up.
Oh,
interesting.
Interesting.
Yeah.
That's why men value.
We'll also why men,
they value quiet men who know when to be
quiet.
It's important.
And also they,
they don't value men who wear shiny shit
and are really loud and have a lot of
junk on and stuff like that because
those assholes would get in trouble.
They would fuck up hunting parties.
Interesting.
I I agree with that.
That's right.
But it makes,
I read it.
Yeah.
Women are programmed to do more things
simultaneously at the same time.
That's why they can really take care of
the kids.
But he can do anything.
We don't,
we just have one focus and that's it.
That's why I went to military and women.
I always think it's a dangerous thing.
And the reason I'm saying in dangerous
thing is because the natural inclination
for a guy is to protect a woman.
You know?
So if something happens,
everybody wants to automatically,
that's an instinct that's built into the
guy to protect a woman,
which could of course make a big trouble
in the integrate.
Right.
And I said [inaudible] to treating them
as an equal on the battlefield.
That's it.
Yeah.
Protect them.
Well maybe trading wool or take that
away.
You know,
if they train like a guy,
then they go,
okay,
my wife is down.
So see,
I don't want to break it down.
Show fight.
She fought me.
Can't
play too rough with the kids.
I go see her looking at me watching over
across the gym.
I'm like,
Oh shit,
she'll come on,
fuck me up.
And she's,
she's,
she's awesome.
But why was the keeper?
Well,
it's strange times because we're,
we're asking women to take on a lot of
the traits and characteristics of men,
you know,
it's,
uh,
and uh,
some of them want to,
and I understand that,
but some,
for some they feel like they're required
to,
and I don't necessarily know if that's
what they want,
you know,
I just,
but I think society wants a woman to be
a breadwinner.
They want women to contribute and
compete with men in the workplace.
And a lot of ways in a lot of women want
to do that tail.
Lydia?
Yeah.
And then you like,
when you see that and then when it comes
to the military,
it's very difficult to say like,
oh,
women shouldn't be on the battlefield
because then all of a sudden you say,
well,
what are you sexist?
You know,
but,
but it's not traditionally a female open
option.
Yeah.
If you,
if that's a path you want to go ahead
and go ahead.
I want to be made.
You'd be,
you will have fun.
Yeah,
I get that.
I mean,
there's some women that I think would
probably gravitate towards killing
people.
They'd probably think it would be a lot
of fun.
Well,
if you're a feminist then also when you
see a spider,
don't let us get rid of the spider.
They all want to play power.
Power that there's some of them,
you know?
No,
no,
I do everything myself.
I said,
well that's your job right now as well.
Yeah,
I guess so.
Why was the reason,
something about Arachnophobia where they
were thinking that Arachnophobia which
is a fear of spiders and a bunch of
different like snake phobias and much
different phobias might literally be the
memory of your ancestors.
Like someone you know in like someone
your ancestors know,
died in front of them,
got bit by a spider or they almost died
and they got bit by a spider and that
shit is just hardwired into your DNA
that says some people see a fucking
spider and they can't move.
They freak out.
It doesn't make any sense.
My daughter freaks out when a wasp comes
by.
She'll just freeze.
I'm like,
Holy Shit,
I got to go pick her up or swap the for
the wasp away.
We have lost in our area so that Kinda
makes,
she just freezes out,
fly around.
You don't know where they're going or
what.
My daughter's got good foot work.
Did you ever hear him say that?
She does.
That makes a lot of noise.
Like meditating,
flying in front of Michael.
When you meditate
they come and fuck with you.
I look,
I opened my ass.
This guy came back twice.
What's up and he's right in front of me.
Here he goes.
Maybe sends to your ci for sure.
Three Mil.
Is that Sensei?
Sorry,
is meditating in the yard?
We're just talking about [inaudible]
before you arrived.
As far as um,
I went to go back to this,
but again,
he's the first one that I was aware of
that actually did elevation training
when they came to Colorado.
So I already said that.
But also with what he did is he took
combinations and then chunk them
together.
Hence numbers like four.
If you say four in the root and system
is Jab,
cross,
Hook,
cross.
So again,
it's that same idea of taking the
combination and checking it together.
Because if I would say jab,
cross,
Hook,
that's a lot more time than me just sing
for.
And that concept is what it took to
continue the,
to develop the system and just the idea
would be able to communicate with tj on
the paths are in the cage with limited
time,
just calling simple commands or
combinations so we can actually make
sure that the fight,
so taking place,
not getting too sidetracked,
he knows he's got a really interesting
system is a Mark Henry Mark Henry Trains
Edson Barboza and Frankie Edgar.
He is a fantastic trainer.
Like one of the most underrated guys in
the business.
He,
Rashad Evans told me that he will name
combinations after his daughter like
Rashad.
I saw that like certain things and they
changes them with every camp,
with every camp that change,
the names change.
So no one's ever gonna be able to
pattern you then never the other corners
not going to have any fucking idea what
he's calling out
Tyson.
He used to change the numbers all the
time because they would have a number
system,
but then every time he would change the
number.
So nobody could pick up
too much shit.
If you change,
you're going to chase you up or always
having,
oh he's be so lost.
Yeah,
always adding.
He's got a system.
We do an online system.
We do his own academy,
which he teaches,
you know the basic stuff.
I mean boss,
we've got a boss Combo.
We do,
you know,
we got my combo,
stuff like that.
We'll put it online and,
but then we always switch it up.
So each camp,
my combo might be different,
you know,
but if he completely switched all of it
up,
I'd be law.
We already do too much as it is.
I'd be lost.
Yeah,
we did the boss come today.
What I'm trying to like when you're
trying to remember all these different
things and put them all like the Ramon
dekkers,
there's like 50 shot.
Yeah,
the decors like stuff like that.
The Tyson and the deckers.
Those things kind of tie together that
you're doing things you're supposed to
do naturally anyways.
Like you know,
you're returning with the same punch in
slipping and then rolling into the body
and kicking inside than kicking the
head.
Those are supposed to come together no
matter what.
He's just making it a combo.
So once you stop,
stop thinking about the common way,
you just naturally start to do it and
putting in reps with the Tyson,
he's fallen the hooks up with coming to
the body and then the upper cut.
So it's kind of stuff that ties together
and it's a lot easier to remember.
It has to flow,
has to flow natural intuition boss
before you got here,
we were talking about the level of mma
right now.
So fascinating because there's so much
depth and people are getting so much
better and there's so many different
styles and it just seems like such an
exciting time right now for MMA.
It is.
It is really exciting for me.
The first big change that happened in
mma was that everybody knows in shape.
Finally,
you remember we had to all these guys
running out of gas.
I got it,
dude.
That's like being a painter and half a
can of paint to a job or run out of
paint.
I'm sorry.
It's the dumbest thing.
Go run a hill.
One guy one time told me,
I said,
yeah,
but a heavyweight there shut gave
Valasquez and he goes,
yeah,
but he trains really hard
also.
He's Mexican.
I looked at him like,
are you kidding?
You're just giving the answer.
Just train really hard.
And there's a science behind it now to
you know how to train when the train
that hard and which ways to do it.
How do you know how to make your body
bigger if you need to or faster if you
need more endurance that train that way.
So I mean it's just like all these other
sports there is coming up real sport.
You know what to back up my Mexican
theory,
uh,
I talked to crazy Bob Cook and crazy Bob
Cook's said came,
we'll take like a month off or two
months off,
get hurt.
You know,
something like that has to rest up and
injury,
not trained,
come back and now work everybody.
Not Fair man.
That is not how we were talking about
Gilbert Melendez.
Another one.
Fantastic cardio.
A lot of Mexicans have crazy fucking
cardio man.
I always had good cardio.
Just might just be a little hard to,
he has a good cardio cause he doesn't
calm down.
If he shows up here early for the
podcast,
he's out in the parking lot.
Shadow boxing,
you know what I mean?
He's not,
he's going to stay sharp.
Scare the neighbors.
That belt back that got us in his phone
hanging out like little wayne for
whatever he's got to do to happen.
He's always doing something.
Always crazy.
But it goes to up.
But the thing with Duane is when you
hold focus,
which a typist for Dwayne,
you cannot say,
oh you cannot take a break for five
seconds and say listen,
it makes sure that you do it.
He goes,
hey,
he wants to keep,
keep going,
keep going.
Hard to hold time.
I said guys,
step back dude,
this different now.
Okay,
just relax constantly is in my face.
You know he wants to go 100% all the
time.
Hi.
He does that to me.
Holding me like I'll be hitting mitts
will be going for like an hour,
hour and a half.
I'm just like,
you know,
dead tired.
So my faints and my fork have gotten so
good cause how much he's in my face.
He'll come at me at nonstop wanting me
to throw combos and I am so dead tired,
I'll faint and move.
You know what I mean?
Like give me some time,
let me read,
you know,
good cause of uh,
developing your skillset and martial
arts as a whole.
So it's a purpose to it.
We're talking about how interesting it's
been,
how Dwayne has transitioned so well and
to becoming a trainer,
you know?
Was that a challenge for you going from
being a great fighter to being a great
trainer?
No,
no,
it wasn't for me.
It's always been like I'm riding
shotgun,
you know,
each show or for Fritz what it meant to
be.
If we're talking about if a,
if a student fights,
I'm more nervous than the student at
that Modena would be when I would fight
for myself because then I'm in control.
So no,
but sometimes it's difficult if you
don't have the right student.
Right.
If you,
your student's not responding
and they call.
Yeah,
it's very hard.
It's a watch,
you have dose,
you know it's,
but a lot of them don't.
A lot of these fighters don't listen to
their corners still til this day top
fighters.
I mean you hit a corner constantly
screaming.
They don't do what they're doing.
They think they can see it better,
you know.
But once there was a trust,
you know,
and and,
and there was always a good trust
between Dwayne and myself and the same
with him and Tj then he knows what
you're seeing.
That's probably going to work,
you know,
and that,
and he will do it.
Like if I would say four to Dwayne in a
fight,
it will come out less than a second
later.
I really just shout for Papa,
Papa Echo mouth right away if you,
if you could enhance my voice when he's
fighting.
It's a video game.
He does.
We need to get a bull horn listening,
get a bull horn.
The UFC shallot bullhorn.
I did that and UFC,
I brought a mega phone because nobody
was screaming and they actually put it
into contract after that that you could
watch my fight against go suck here.
Short combinations
because I figured in Japan they're quiet
right here.
Everybody's going to scream.
I'm not going to hear them.
So uh,
avi,
Avi Rubin's the old owner of the Beverly
Hills Jujitsu Club says,
I'm going to bring a megaphone.
They go,
yeah,
that's a good idea.
That is a great,
what about just like a tube,
like a roll of toilet paper or something
like that?
Up a piece of paper.
Yeah.
Could that work?
I'll try it.
One of those guards,
cones I always go to when I seen him,
the reason why I brought that up about a
training fighters is because there's a,
there's an interesting parallel between
you two guys,
both great fighters and then both wind
up having great students.
You having Dwayne as a student and
Dwayne now having t j's is getting in a
bunch of,
yeah,
I mean there's,
there's a lot to that.
There is,
you know,
but,
but it's all connection and that's what
everything in life,
you know,
once there is a connection that is,
if people,
you know,
if,
if I don't care for him,
you know,
as he's not a good guy,
and that's what some fighters also,
they come in to just work out,
they're gone again,
you know,
they don't build a relationship.
And once that happens it will,
it hurts.
They're fighting,
I guarantee you that.
Yeah,
I'm sure.
And for fighters it's really a problem
when you build a relationship with the
wrong trainer and then you've got to
leave that guy and you know,
you have this tight bond with someone
who doesn't really know enough.
That's a hard one.
That's,
I've seen that many times.
And when they leave,
people get super butthurt.
It gets,
it gets to be a real problem.
But for,
for the,
if it's real,
it's real.
And it's always say,
you know what I said to my daughters,
he said,
what do I tell the guy said,
just tell the truth.
You know,
can't go wrong with it.
Truth.
It's the guys.
Sorry.
You know,
it says like on inside of him and me,
I would say about a certified all he
that kicks that sucked or this sucked.
And they say,
yeah,
but what if you're going to get him on
the show?
I should,
I'll say the same thing.
And if he tells me that I'm wrong,
he can't say because it did suck.
You know,
you've got to just got to be honest.
There's nothing he can do.
Yeah.
It doesn't mean they suck as a human
being.
Not just means that in that moment that
was the wrong thing to do or they didn't
execute it properly or,
you know.
Yeah.
And then I have to be on point too,
as far as the trainer with the,
with the fighters and coaching,
if I gotta make sure I'm calling the
right commands at right time as well.
And that
goes back to the relationship that you
have and making sure you have that
connection
when you also have to know your fighters
capability.
Exactly.
When you have a great race horse,
you know,
it'd be,
everything becomes so much more
interesting because you have all these
options
[inaudible] you're going to have so much
mental behind it too.
Like Twain knows how to coach me to,
you know,
like not everyone responds to negative
energy.
Not some people will respond to negative
energy,
right.
Like Danny Castillo,
you got to tell Danny could steal,
like you're doing that like an idiot
come on.
Different things that you know,
and he's like,
okay,
yeah,
he'll do a better with me and Dwayne.
Someone where you know,
you know,
I've got to pump the guy up maybe a
little bit,
tell him what he's doing right instead
of what he's doing wrong.
You know,
so you gotta know how to coach each
fighter and once you build that
relationship,
like bosses talking about and you don't
let it go.
Yes sir.
There's very few things that are as
painful as listening to bad corner work.
Yeah.
Oh,
that's fun.
you gotta hear it went down to his live
around the corner,
cross blue cross.
I go,
he just went.
You don't want him to throw a right hand
right now,
you know,
let him keep that here so the liver is
protected and I go,
yeah,
that's an idiot.
Exactly.
Who does that?
Right.
Did you watch the fights this weekend?
Yeah,
I did.
What did you think about steep an hour,
man,
that was crazy.
Crazy,
crazy.
De Three or four large punches you gave
Darwin there on an inch there.
All exact at the same spot.
It's got really good position.
Yeah,
just stopped him and he got hit heart.
He waved it off,
but that's the Tina.
We know.
11 guillotines.
I believe that he had to be dry and
tight once he pulled me in a one time I
said,
I want to feel it.
I go,
Whoa,
this is a really tight guilty,
but he got out.
He's in the,
he's a freak athlete.
He really is and he's a very likable
guy.
He's awesome.
He has deep is a good guy.
When we were talking about his
composure.
Yes sir.
Yes.
So composed like in Brazil when he
fought for Breeshia,
when he's wanting to stare down,
he's just dead faced.
He's got his own dead face.
It's not like a fade or dead face or
cane dead face.
He's got his own dead phase.
But those guys that can just stay
completely calm,
you know,
in that incredible environment of being
there in Brazil,
45,000 plus people screaming for
Fabrizie over doom when he just shuts
his lights out
with our own or main battle.
Right.
It's being able to,
to control ourselves and he's looks to
have mastered that ability to control
his own emotions and make sure he's
directing the energy and the right path.
So Steve Bay,
good job.
Grasshopper,
that motherfucker to see if someone got
into his head the way like you and
dominic were going after each other or
the way connor got into all those head.
Right.
I guess that was a masterclass in
fucking with someone's head.
Absolutely.
Connor took Aldo completely out of his
element or he was just so frazzled by
the time they actually met each other
inside the octagon.
It was just,
I think we had the overeem and a steep,
it is just same as home and,
and a Raji,
you know?
Rousey's intimidating.
Everybody,
Eh,
the way she is.
And she,
when she started at the stare down,
that's when she lost it because she
realized holly didn't care at all.
Right?
She was just there.
I'm going to hurt you.
That was at as the same as everybody's
intimidated by
overeem.
And you should be because he's a
monster.
But I think open could see in his face
already,
he's,
he's not intimidated.
This guy has absolutely no,
and then when you fight a guy like that,
that that little voice starts playing in
your,
in your mind when it gets bad,
you know?
And that's why maybe we saw these crazy
things of running away,
you know,
which I,
I say it's a good thing because I said
the same thing against conor Mcgregor,
but you know,
for a big,
huge heavyweight,
it doesn't look good.
You know,
and now you,
you set yourself up more as a victim
because he's following you in tech.
And that all is an input in your,
in your own brain.
Because now you start telling yourself,
oh,
I know everybody thinks I'm a,
I'm hurt or that I'm afraid of.
Am I afraid?
I'm even know there's the whole doubt
thing that goes on in the mind.
There's always these two voices.
I say the one voice wants to quit that
the other voice wants to go.
Right.
You know,
you're a really bad situation.
And they say,
okay,
call it quits.
Gullah cuisine.
And then some of the other ones,
I don't know.
No,
no,
no.
Wait,
wait,
wait.
We're not going to,
no,
no.
Let's just,
let's just see what happens.
You know,
and then suddenly you come out of the
situation.
I was,
I was about to tap in my second fight
and,
but then the audience started cheering
for him and then my ego took over.
I go,
okay.
I get out of the situation and then 30
seconds later and knocked him out to the
need to deliver,
and I go,
okay,
this is the last time I'm going to think
like that because the bat boy stay away
from the bad voice.
Yeah.
Focus on what you can control and that
yourself.
Right.
Do you ever use any psychological
training?
Did you ever talk to a sports
psychologist or anything like that or is
they're all self taught?
All self taught,
but what I did a lot is talking to
myself and people might laugh about
that,
but I'm very honest to myself.
Like people say,
oh you nervous to fight?
No,
no,
no.
Why not?
What can happen?
What can really happen?
He's got to knock me out.
Matt's going to be hard because it never
happened before,
but if it happens while I'm not going to
feel it,
apparently you know you're going to go
down.
Submission is the submission.
Is that really so bad?
I'm going to tab so what is so really so
bad?
Well,
the really bad thing is listening to all
the crap that older,
the not so good fats are going to tell
you afterwards is social media,
but if you just scare you,
remember the last time I told the story
from in the room,
if you take a fighter and and who's
normally a nerve is final.
This is what I tell my students who are
nervous when they have to compete.
I say,
okay,
imagine now the guys right here.
We put you in the room,
we locked the door.
Nobody can go in there.
You guys fight.
And when you come out,
you're not allowed to say who want to
lose.
Did you?
Do you really care if you,
if you would lose it?
He goes,
no,
because everybody can lose.
I said,
well,
that's the mindset you should have when
you go into a fight.
That's my mindset.
You know,
winning or losing,
I'm gonna win.
I'm gonna do everything in my power to
it.
But if I lose,
so what?
You know,
we're human and we come out of it.
I say,
you make you overcomplicate things,
certain combinations.
When I said it's a four and then I,
I do four punches to the head and then I
say I'm going to,
we stayed with this combination.
The only thing we're going to change
either heights,
so now I'm going to say for you to the
four points,
it's a left,
right straight,
left hook,
right straight.
I'm going to share.
Okay.
Body had had had,
no,
you're the first one has to go to the
body.
Had had,
had body,
body,
had hat head,
head,
body had buddy.
I mean now you can make like 12
combinations from just a four punch,
you know?
And but some people when,
when I tell it to my students sometimes
they overthink it.
They go to,
oh no,
I said no,
just in body hat do the same
combination.
But they start thinking,
oh that's the liver shot that no,
that's not liver shot to the body.
Just,
you know,
keep it simple.
And once you can keep it simple,
it's much easier to,
to do.
Well,
it's one of the things that we were
talking about earlier.
It was the,
the amount of fighting that is mental
and the amount that is your attitude and
how you feel about things and how you go
into things and just your enthusiasm.
Like Travis Brown,
we were talking about Travis Browne,
who earlier in his career was this
fucking stone cold killer.
I mean he had all his crazy footwork.
He throw a lot of kicks and memory.
We knocked out Stephan's true that
Superman Punch,
right?
Yeah.
God Damn.
He was so unpredictable and wild.
I was like,
this motherfucker's can be the
heavyweight champ.
I just give him out,
give him some time.
And then he moved to Jackson's is
training and a great camp,
but he just doesn't seem,
I mean maybe as a few losses in a row,
he doesn't seem to have that fire in
him.
Did he lose when he was at objections?
He chased Kemp's,
yes.
Started losing after you change camps
most of the time.
But that's what I tell people,
like my stretch routine and every time
when I say this they,
they,
they ask me what it's just routine.
I do the same stretch of team as I did
23 years ago when I started.
Same routine.
And the reason is it never got me an
injury.
So if it's a winning combination,
don't break it.
And it's the same with your team.
If it's a winning combination,
do not break it.
Once you bring,
how many fighters do you see changing
camp or firing as a trainer of firing
the manager or somebody who always
helped him and suddenly they started
losing you.
You broke the spell or whatever you want
to call it,
the mystical thing that was going on
that was working.
Don't break it.
Why would you,
yeah,
but it's so rare that you find the
perfect person.
Like if you're with Johnny mcfuck stick
in Columbus,
Ohio,
and he's a shitty coach and you've been
with them forever and you've got this
weird bond with them.
And then for Rasa,
hobby wants to train you.
You're like,
God damn.
Yeah,
but what do you do?
And everybody runs into bus route and
right off the bat,
sorry,
all my students,
I say,
listen,
I teach straight down two times a week.
Go anywhere you want any gym.
I don't mind guys.
You want a spar without a guide to go
anywhere you want.
But the problem is if you have that guy
we were talking about it doesn't know
anything,
he's going to be butthurt.
He's going to be okay.
You cannot no go.
You cannot go.
But a good coach will say,
go just straight everywhere.
If he can find something better.
Perfect examples.
Duke Roufus,
who's a great coach and Pedis Pedis
started training at Jackson.
He just wanted new looks.
You want a different things,
you want to mix things up,
and he had some great times.
That's,
he also cares about Anthony Pettis.
He cares about his career.
He wants him to grow,
and so he's like,
yes,
please go do this new stuff.
Every time I went up and trim,
if Rasa Tristar,
he loved it.
He loved the idea,
go up there,
get some new looks good.
Yeah,
it's a new technique grow,
you know?
Those are real friends.
It was a real people that care about you
and they want you to have the best thing
in your life.
I said,
Dwight [inaudible] cabs,
she got show.
Yup.
Well there's a small handful,
maybe a half a dozen or more of really
truly
elite camps right now.
You know,
there's American top team of course is
is a few that you could go over,
but of places where you're really kind
of can't go wrong,
it's really just a matter of finding the
right combination for you too.
Right?
I mean,
some,
some camps are more grappling heavy and
you might be back a more of a striker.
We've seen that happen to,
you know,
the guys just kind of get the wrong
formula.
It's the thing,
if you're a great striker,
go to a more grappling oriented camp.
That's what I always say.
You got to striking.
That's what I decided.
Okay,
this is it.
Forget about striking three times a day
submissions.
That was it never lost again.
It's just doing what you're not
comfortable at and do that a lot and
make sure you get comfortable at it.
Then that's it.
Wonderboy is great example of that.
You started training with Weidman who
was a great wrestler and it just
completely changed his confidence and
his stand up and now he's so loose
standing up,
you're getting to see the same
wonderboy.
That was,
I think it was like 57 and [inaudible]
was a kickboxer.
Amazing,
crazy like that.
And you see those skills now because
good luck taking that guy down.
Correct.
You know,
he's,
he's getting mauled by Chris Weidman all
time.
Weidman,
who is a big one,
85 yeah.
You know,
there's so many levels to mixed martial
arts,
so many areas.
And we could obviously take the,
the three easy ones with the striking,
the wrestling and the grappling,
right?
So with those now,
what's your style?
What's your skill set?
And now with that being said,
you've got to make sure you're getting
with the best people in those three
areas or something that we could take in
the fourth account,
which since I said earlier,
is the conditioning aspect now.
So there's a lot of pieces of the puzzle
and you can't just go to one guy,
he can't just go to a boxing coach with
the boxing coach isn't really familiar
with mma because things are different as
you point out today with the distances,
right?
And then using the switches because of
the further distance.
So you've got to make sure you have the
correct people that understand the mixed
martial arts game.
Because if you go to an expert,
cried the guy who doesn't understand
where me,
that's not going to work no matter how
much you guys love each other.
It's not gonna work.
You have to have mma in the mix.
Wrestling coach doesn't know how to
strike.
Yep.
He's not going to learn how to close the
distances with punches,
the build time,
time your takedowns,
he's going to want to grab a hold of you
and move you around to shoot on you.
You know?
So yeah,
we might also not understand where
you're in vulnerable positions for
submissions.
Like a lot of wrestlers are still shoot
that double with the neck on the
outside,
you know?
And I mean they just haven't figured the
distance out or the difference in the,
in the technique out.
Yup.
Agreed.
Yeah.
That's why I love this,
this tree on this lineage because I'm
taking what since it has done as much as
I can.
Then what I've done and then adding that
up and I'll pass it and Tj is way,
and this is a direct line of lineage of
martial arts information that's been
expedited and it's,
it's,
it's awesome to have an actual march
start family and just keep passing on
the knowledge.
It's fun for me as a martial art nerd,
it's also interesting because Tj has
that wrestling background as well.
And then I think that's a big factor in
his success because he's incorporating
all of your techniques and your
techniques and then on top of that
you've got that elite athleticism and
then the wrestling base.
So you've got awesome take down defense
and take downs.
And also I really firmly believe there's
something about wrestlers that fucking
grind of dieting and starving yourself
and yourself and
the mental toughness that breed that you
know,
you get from certain wrestlers.
It's like it's off the charts.
I've still to this day,
never done anything harder than
wrestling.
Even with all the aspects of martial
arts and fighting like fighting to me is
it's just a lot,
lot easier than a grind of a wrestling
season.
You know,
I rest of the cal state fullerton where
we started way too.
Or Lik I said,
I overworked myself and push through a
ninth month season.
Being completely strict on everything.
My Diet,
my,
you know,
I can't go,
I'm not going out and having fun with my
friends because I'm wrestling and then
wrestling every weekend and just such a
hard practice.
Like,
still today we do two days a week like
restaurant practices.
Like,
damn,
I don't want to get ready,
love wrestling.
I'm gonna have to go really hard.
Like man wrestling,
I've done it.
You know,
it's tough man.
And it definitely does breed mental
toughness.
And then you're learning how to compete
on your own every weekend.
When you're training a team elevation,
you doing wrestling practice,
are you doing strictly wrestling?
Are you putting wrestling shoes on and
you're doing like full on wrestling?
You like a competition between your,
your teammates.
Are you doing that of we do that as well
as we'll do it even may wrestling as
well.
You know,
there's different forms of it.
But yeah,
I'll go through my wrestling shoes on
and we're doing matches,
you know,
it depends on where we're at.
We'll do situations and yeah,
we're doing full on real wrestling
practices.
Is there a benefit to having wrestling
shoes on though?
Because you're not going to fight with
them on your defense will become way
better if you wear shoes.
So it's so much easier to get out of a
take down without it.
You can't like a single leg,
you should not get taken down in a
single like anyone may.
If you do your,
I mean it's so easy to slide your leg
out on a single leg,
but with a wrestling shoe on,
I can't,
I can't just go to that easy defense.
I have to use my hips,
have to cover his head,
I have to use all these positions that
have a better defense with my shoes on.
So it's a difference between like
grappling with g Nogi is or that kind of
a thing.
Yeah,
I mean I,
so in college I shot high singles,
that's what I shot at shoot a high
single and got tried to turn and kick
out catches shoe and then take us back
and MMA guy turns and kicks out all the
time.
So high single eggs not going to work
anymore.
So yeah,
I mean like with,
with the G on,
you can't get away with certain things.
You can't just slip out of a,
a submission can just slip out of an arm
bar and roll out of it.
You actually have to have the real
technique of getting out of it.
If this guy is so good at it,
you know,
so yeah,
it's,
it's learning you to do the defense the
right way instead of using the cheat
moves.
You know?
That's interesting.
Does it,
um,
was it,
would it be okay if you did it with no
shoes on and your opponent?
I did it with shoes on because that way
you would have the slipperiness of being
careful wrestling against the kid that I
knew it was coming in from like a
college and he's really good.
I am not wearing shoes.
I don't care.
I'm not going to wear it.
She was like Chad Mendez,
like one of the best wrestlers in the
world at practice.
He'll never ever wear shoes.
Now he doesn't,
his defense is ridiculous.
He just pushes you off his leg.
Like the way he'll stand now too is
because he'll only let you shoot a
single day cause he knows how easy it is
to get out of it.
And uh,
he'll,
he'll never ever wear shoes again.
Wrestling ever since grappling though,
don't you think the,
the,
the injuries,
the twisting niece come from shoes
wearing shoes because a lot of guys,
they do it on the wrestling mat and
that's still okay because it might slip
a little bit about as soon as you step
on the judo mat,
which you're planting
your feet and then with upper body
motion rotation,
something's going to twist because a lot
of injuries happened with wrestling,
right?
Yeah.
You've got to get better.
You've got a bit of traction.
So you gotta know.
I mean,
I got to know what you're,
I've wrestled my entire life positioning
with wrestling shoes on and stuff,
but I think it creates better habits to
have your shoes on while wrestling.
You know,
cause you're not going to be able to get
away with the,
we call it a stinky lake where you just
whip your leg out.
You know,
if I have a grip and it's what you want
is to grip above your knee.
But as soon as I get your grip below my
knee just by pushing it down,
I'm out.
I'm just sliding my leg.
It's gotta be a similar situation to
wearing gloves,
right?
Like when trying to limp arm at a
certain positions you have and you kind
of,
it gets,
it's really hard to finish two clubs on
any kind of grappling we do at elevation
is with our gloves on.
You know,
cause I'm catching certain moves and
risks.
I can risk ride differently.
Um,
I could chokes are different.
I can't cite it as easy behind your
head.
You got to learn all those things with,
with gloves on as well.
Some people think that it would be a
safer sport without gloves.
Probably
going to be less whole bloody lot more
blood,
more grown up my bloody,
that's the thing.
The guts and everything and to breaking
hands.
Yeah.
But you would learn a lot more effective
striking look,
you really couldn't just unload on a guy
and just hit anything.
Ross,
I was up training with Tristar.
He's like,
Hey,
I recommend at least once a day,
once every other day hitting them back
with no gloves on,
you know,
get that proper technique of no one had
a hit,
something with no gloves on.
So you don't have that padding and
protecting.
If I've got a 16 or a 10 ounce glove,
I'm able to just go away on my bag and
punching as hard as they want it.
I don't have to punch.
Right.
But if I don't have gloves on and I'm
hitting that as hard as I can,
I have to hit it correct.
They have to have your right knuckle
policemen to put it on that bag.
I mean that's what a lot of karate and
traditional martial arts guys believe.
They believe that those gloves are
actually giving you the soul sort of
false sense of,
of your abilities,
you know,
cause your,
your risks are all wrapped up.
Your hands are all wrapped up.
You know,
you get the question,
how many times did he break his hands in
a street fight?
All the time.
Mitch blood green because they perfectly
tape his hands up and training and then
when he had to it has to hit without on
the other side,
you know,
hitting a bag and but because if you do
it wrong,
like if you're hitting a bag,
bare knuckle,
because I had a guy who told me my,
my coach is really good coach because
she lets us hit the back until our hands
bleed.
I say you'll coach is an idiot.
That's what your coaches,
because if this happens for weeks before
to fly,
I'd guess what's going to happen every
single word,
God,
when you hit,
you're going to reopen the cuts.
It's going to hurt every first.
Oh for your workout,
right?
Yeah.
So yeah,
if you do it perfect and the impact of
spirit,
but as soon as she hit and you slide a
little bit,
then you shave a knuckle love.
Well four weeks before the fight,
that's not going to heal anymore because
you have reopen it every time.
One of the interesting things about MMA
is how we're still kind of learning and
there's no right approach for everybody.
Everybody's approach is definitely the
approach for Damien Maia is going to be
different than the approach for
wonderboy is going to be different than
your approach.
And it's,
it's so difficult to figure out who's
right.
I mean it's really based on the success
of the past.
Well,
if we take away the gloves and turn into
wonder
boys kicking with Damien,
Maia is grappling.
If we take where the gloves,
well there'll be a lot more chill,
a lot more jokes and a lot more kicks.
You got to take away the gloves.
There we go.
Yeah,
I mean it'd be,
it's so much easier to sync.
Chokes in so much harder as defend,
you know,
change up the commands.
And then now when it comes to like if
you look at football or baseball or any
professional sport,
they've pretty much have protocols that
are very similar.
Like most teams have pretty similar
protocols as far as like training and
how they,
how they prepare their athletes.
But with mma it's wildly different.
Like in how,
who,
how,
who decides?
Like for you,
who decides what when you're doing
strength and conditioning,
when you're doing hill sprints,
when you're doing sparring,
like how do you guys work that out?
I find someone that I trust completely
and then uh,
work together with him for my striking
in my mma with Dwayne.
It's something we team up together and
think of like,
what if I do this?
What if I do that?
And it kind of make a perfect plan for
myself,
my strength conditioning coach learning
and Dow,
I believe in him completely of watching
him train athletes and peak in meet the
right way and how I feel personally.
It's all trial and error.
Um,
you know where I'm at right now.
I trust in every single coach that for
different aspects leaser bowling for my
wrestling.
He's been around the game for so long
and knows how fighting works that I'm
going to trust him and my wrestling
techniques and help him pick me apart.
You know,
Elliot Marshall's meant Jujitsu coach.
I really believe in Colorado at
elevation fight team with me and Dwayne,
we really got got a pretty,
pretty good to figure it out.
But someone's going to come in and have
a different mindset of what they want to
do.
And if it doesn't work for you,
it doesn't work for you.
Yeah.
It's just,
it's the trial and error and the
learning as you go along.
It's so interesting because,
you know,
you lose a fight and then you go,
God,
what,
what did we fuck up on?
Where,
what do we need to do better?
Yeah.
And then,
you know,
maybe,
you get that Joe Silva call like,
Hey,
you know,
uh,
we have a fight in eight weeks.
You Ready?
Ready to take it?
So Sylvia called me when I was up on a
ladder doing electrical work in the
mountains to fight in two weeks.
And it was again,
Jonathan Goulay.
So,
uh,
I said,
sure.
I take the fight and then I'd text boss
right away or I call him and say,
all right,
can you train me?
It's like,
sure.
His,
so go out for a week.
So yeah,
going back to the point where I worked
at West,
is Keto in history ever.
You got it.
Well,
you got to fight for that money ever.
We had a fight for that one.
Yes sir.
Mr Rogan,
how many people were hating on him
having the fastest Kaylin history?
There's a lot of fucking debate.
I was like the referee that it's wrong.
It was,
it was a wrong call.
They were saying it was like 11 seconds
or something like that.
Sure.
Like Bull Shit.
That was six.
We played it over and over and over
again.
It was fine.
No,
it's,
we were working on that exact technique
does point down the jab moving overhand
right in the back with Sensei and and
just just ripped it out,
ripped it out and
it was so fun because I'm leaning over
the cage and I'm saying Dwayne is going
to come up straightforward.
I want you to step to the side and just
knock them out.
You will hear me say that,
repeating it over and over.
I say,
I don't know what because every time I
have that I have one time I said he's
opening for the right location and then
the guy over through the right log,
you get out.
How do you know what?
They have no clue.
Every time it works with us or against
boulevard,
we knocked him out.
That combination.
We weren't
get the dressing room before Bomani.
I mean it's all the time we'd Goulay for
some reason I go,
he's got to come straight out.
You just move out and just don't do
anything.
It's Kinda data chunking.
You've seen so many fights,
so many people you have to see things
and you don't even know what you're
seeing.
Just like,
oh like you know how sometimes like
you'll see a guy like I call it all the
time.
I'll see a guy lifted his heel up and
when he said about throw right case.
Yeah,
like you just know for whatever reason
twist a little bit.
Yeah.
Then the funny part is when he does a
backache,
nine out of 10 times,
the other one throws a backache.
So I always thought I'm going to do this
on purpose and hopefully when he makes
them on I'm going to catch it.
Then
I'll go do this too.
It's crazy when people throw back.
Well,
like the,
the probably the most ill advised back
heck of all time was Chris Weidman
versus Luke Rocco.
Maybe the most that called.
It's called at the moment.
What do you mean his corner?
Call it at the moment he called it,
I think maybe it's here's luke had been
knocked out by veto with a wheel kick.
So maybe I'm just guessing that Chris
decided to throw a wheel kick,
but it was like you could see it
comment,
it wasn't fast and if you don't know
100% how to cake,
I said don't kick and he shouldn't have
done that.
It was way too slow and they saw it
coming off.
A memory of that though when,
ah,
be toward Belford did it?
Um,
I think I remember correctly rockhold
was against the cage.
Correct?
Cause he's all circle off.
Yes.
He was aware of the cage.
Now weidman's back was against the
kitsch.
I thought he was close with the cage
then luke was in that fight.
I don't believe so.
No,
I believe he was moving.
It was a belief.
It was the same thing.
He was moving towards rockhold on,
I don't remember that direction,
but I remember the talk them through it
before and it was the first time I'd
ever seen him throw a wheel kick.
He threw it right before against
rockhold and missed and they threw it
again and landed them.
Nice.
Yep.
TRT Tour.
He told me before,
he says,
boss,
my kicks should go to be getting a
really good right now,
somebody out with a spinning back kick
to the head.
I said,
go for it then.
Then he knocked him out.
So Vito has had so many hand surgeries,
I believe he's had a sucker off for
enhanced surgeries.
He's broken his hand so many times that
I think he just started concentrating
more on kicks,
you know,
just see that made a big difference.
This is going back to a patterns and
seeing people that the hill up,
you know,
they're gonna throw something.
Well,
figure out what they're going to do.
But then that same theory is paying
attention to what combinations and what
techniques actually land and then
chucking those together and making
those,
the system.
So just being,
having,
going back to the language and the
vocabulary of high percentage
combinations,
drill them and wrap them out.
So just it's not too bad.
Yeah.
And know how to really deliver a
technique before you attempt it.
Like the first time I ever saw Cain
Velasquez for a wheel kick ever was in
the Travis Brown fight and it looked
fucking perfect.
Cause like what does this guy have been
hiding this forever?
Like he never threw a wheel kick and all
of a sudden it's a perfect,
we'll kick.
But it's probably because he had
practiced them this and drilled it to
the point where he's got it down.
It's like all right,
time to the wheel kick.
You
had a lifeline.
He has a lifelong martial artist in his
corner,
however you're going this.
So I'm sure he's seen a million back
kicks and can correct him on what to do
properly rather than,
than what he's doing wrong.
But it's just,
it was,
it's interesting when you see a guy like
out of nowhere.
Yes sir.
Hold technique that you've never seen
before.
Hi.
Hello athletes.
I can show tj anything.
Right or watch videos and see something.
He could pull it off right away.
It's a great visual learner.
I'm a great visual learner.
So sensei is like,
I can learn by watching papes and
watching somebody do something.
I can just mimic it.
So and Tj,
so consensus.
It's just the way it is.
I wonder what the next technique that
we're going to see that we couldn't
believe someone's pulling off inside the
entre.
Yeah,
it really close line with disclosure and
elbows to the,
to the,
to the collarbone.
I saw some of the Atlanta close line
recently do that.
That's fine.
It's going to be over.
I saw someone do that and I was thinking
of you because you've talked about that
so many times that like oh your bag.
They attached to a US both on to twitter
feed,
right?
It wasn't turned to somebody.
Yes.
Is it close side,
but the coolest nine if you really do
it,
they can cover up with their hands but
you're still going to hit him.
You loop around and your rope around to
the back of the head,
which still outside the Mohawk still
illegal pudge.
Oh yeah.
I know her feed is completed and Eagle,
he moved his head and our didn't move
his head and it's his fault.
Well also,
you know,
Eddie Bravo and I had a conversation
about this,
like when you hit a guy with a head kick
a lot of times is landing on the back of
the hat.
Yeah.
A lot of times the food,
it's coming over the shoulder a lot of
times,
like the,
the foot is impacting the instep is
hitting the back of the head before
anything and nobody's ready for that
impact.
Everybody in fact ready for the sites
and to the front,
uh,
which,
Tyson,
he hits hooks.
He was always the smallest guy,
shortest guy.
But he would hit his hook almost to the
Becca,
a hat.
Here's which was so short at that,
you know,
you,
I always say,
do you know,
just hit yourself really gentle and to
be,
but the palm and the back of your head,
your brain is simply not ready for that.
Yeah.
I'm one of the best head kick Kaos I've
ever seen that came from the back of the
head.
Was there Nesto who's versus Maury
Smith?
I did.
You ever see that?
Yeah.
Jamie find that because it's such a
crazy combination.
The way host gets his leg up there in
the middle of a clinch and Maurice I
believe,
picks his knee up and host comes over
the top and down behind his head.
Sexual judge era style.
Yeah.
He just did a seminar kicking over to
defense.
Yeah,
right there and it's like what you say
before is say you take a punch it and
put it on the head.
You're going to let me just hit the
punishment.
Like if you have your hands up,
it makes no sense.
Yeah.
Having your hands up.
You think the guys protected.
Now don't punch him.
Put your hands up.
Let me punch you.
Let me touch your hands.
Right,
right.
I've always got a kick blocked my kid.
Come on.
It's a misconception of people when they
put their hands up,
but this is what goes on.
If I want to hitch Kikuyu into hat
today,
she put your hand up.
A normal person automatically thinks the
power of the kick because he sees his
defendant,
but if he just would not care and just
kick as hard as she can on the defense,
you will kick them out and it just got
to knock them out.
Let this last weekend we saw a Yancey
Madeiros fraud.
Sean Spencer's Spencer blocked the kick
and he took it right to the,
to the head.
Check this out real quick.
This is a Maury Smith versus Ernesto
who's play it,
play the whole thing so he could see
that the combination seat,
boom,
he does it in the clench with the knee
boone's add edesa rumbled,
deckers kind of style and I like the
push and the cake that ahead.
He started with that at all.
It was able to bring it up in a round
like that too.
It's crazy to realize he was in the
clinch,
a block to shoulder,
almost his hand down for him.
Yeah.
It kind of guides his hand out of the
way.
So was kicks in to come up and lay me in
the head.
That's also where like flexibility is so
critical,
like there's no more important thing
when it comes to kicking technique.
Then flexibility,
because if you don't have the
flexibility,
your body's all stiff and it doesn't
move.
Right and you just can't.
There's no,
no one's going to do that unless it,
you're flexible.
Yeah.
Got a stretch.
Can I do the stretch your routine?
It was such a good guy.
This who is that one Croatian do?
They kept knocking him out.
Yeah.
That fucking guy hits
the animal.
They know his gay was the first gay porn
champion.
He was announced.
That's right.
Yeah.
It's not the k.
He knocked him out yesterday.
Yeah,
his muscles also,
when you see it,
he's like different kind of muscle.
It almost looks like it is very strong.
Know there's some dudes like that.
Yeah.
There's a long time for him to do to
break the ice with me at a,
suddenly he came to me and he goes,
you're a funny guy.
But if took like four times of meeting
him,
he was,
he had no clue what to expect.
That's a hard part of the world.
There is a hard part of the world.
I'll probably talk to relax.
You got to be on guard the whole time.
I think to this day,
the greatest stare down of all time was
cro cop versus vandelay and vandelay
would mean mug everybody and it would
work.
He looked at Cro,
cop and Cro.
Cop looked at him like,
motherfucker,
I'll cut your head off.
It was like,
oh,
he's dead.
The second fight,
that was the second fight.
But in the first fight,
I mean you never saw the eyes of a
killer more than than that,
that one time.
Cause I mean,
I mean he was ahead of an anti terrorist
squadron and Croatia.
I mean,
but you see I go back again.
That was defended late,
always intimidating somebody.
And now you have suddenly a guy who does
not care.
He's not only that,
your strong suit is striking and you're
taking on one of the most explosive
structures to ever compete in MMA.
And a guy who,
you know was a legit k one level
striker.
Yup.
But he would say,
you know,
it's interesting how that,
that style really worked really well.
Like here it is likely the stare down,
look at Cro cop,
they get fuck it stared out.
I mean that's God damn terrifying and
I'm leaving and they're legit as fuck.
He's not believing in vandelay very
much.
But it's interesting because Cro cop was
successful in k one but he was never the
elite of the elite.
But his style,
that explosive one shot style translated
so well to mma.
Whereas maybe like Ernesto style would
not have translated that way because he
was more technical,
set things up more.
What I show,
no single kicks.
I always say,
because they can be countered and I
always say,
are you kick like Mirko Cro Cop?
Because if you then kick really hard on
the defense,
you're buying yourself a little bit more
time because they,
you force them to block it.
But some of these guys with the left
kicks,
if they're the,
they're the orthodox,
they can't kick.
I say take the cake,
whatever it is.
You're going to give you a rashy.
I mean,
he's not going to do anything.
It's they're going to keep muscle.
Just counter the cake.
Well,
when cro complicates of full blast Gig,
you're going to be forced to block and
then you can counter,
which buys him a little bit of time to
get out of the way again,
that tells tj and his last ride of the
sensee.
I'll just wait for the kick in step in
until the cross time him on the way in.
There's levels to everything,
right,
and there's levels to kicking and Edson
Barboza switch kick is yes.
That's one of those things where I
watched that and I go,
what the fuck?
I'm never seen anybody switch kicked
that fast.
Quick,
which is inside leg kick.
He can win a whole fight with all benny.
The jet,
a
spinning back kick to the body.
Oh,
he's back into the body one.
It gets Fujiwara.
I mean I saw it at the of his kings of
the square ring.
When you see him,
you can hear the impact on the bud.
It goes,
you see the guy crumble.
Benny.
The jet was sad motherfucker.
The best American kickbox forever.
Yeah,
he's a bar without a doubt.
One of them told him and then I would
say Rick Rufus,
such a pioneer too.
I mean,
you know shit.
He was doing that back when there was
really no one at that level.
I mean he was at such a high level.
It's such a while due to again Mexican,
native American.
It was dizzy.
Oh is he?
Or maybe a mix,
but I'm pretty soon cause he's a come
out with the headdress.
Blinky Rodriguez,
who was his brother in law was Mexican.
I saw him in Holland coming in.
He was fighting spotting.
He wants Bong.
It was a big bike guy.
Strong,
strong kickboxer and Ben,
he never fought with low kicks and
spying is murdering him.
And the first right,
everybody's for spying spine go wgu
going and he gets loci.
LOCI cause I don't know how he stayed in
the fight,
Benny,
right.
The second five second route,
he starts coming in a little bit and
there was five frauds.
Five to the time because Thai boxing and
a third two out and now better jeff
starts coming back and suddenly spunks
that spitting out his mouthpiece because
he needed an extra break and I need it
again.
And it did it again.
And then it was like rocky versus Ivan
Drago you.
So literally the whole audience changed
from being for the Dutch guy to be for
betty to jet because they realized this
guy is so tough.
But he keeps hanging in there and then
betty jet stopped them into forthright.
It was the craziest thing.
People were going nuts.
If you spit out as a mouthpiece,
he wants spunk.
Everybody.
Whoa.
You know,
he wasn't doing heroin.
It was the coolest thing I've ever seen.
Did you watch glory this weekend?
No,
but I heard it was really good.
Right?
And waste and wilderness knocked out
Simon Marcus.
Oh Wow.
And Marcus was lighten them up early in
the fight.
Light a mosque.
He's like 44 and two right.
Mark has showed that though.
Three of them right now.
Yeah,
he lost to shilling and that crazy
fight where they went that extra round.
And schilling knocked him out with a
right hook,
which is just,
it was an insane fight.
That was the tournament too.
That was the first fight of that
tournament and Schilling for two more
times after that fucking crazy fight.
But the,
uh,
the wilderness fight,
Simon markets was lightened him up,
man with Moy Thai and wellness is more
of a boxer style and he was moving in
and he had some,
some success with combinations,
but then he caught him at the end of the
round a way that with a shot and uh,
Simon mark was kind of playing with them
and lowered his hands,
was smiling and he got hit with a couple
of shots and the referee gave him a real
questionable standing eight count.
And the,
the,
the commentators are screaming,
Joseph Valtellina,
he was screaming like,
that's ridiculous.
They shouldn't do this.
Is that,
that's not a,
the eight counts.
No good.
He wasn't about to go down.
There's no standing eight count and
kickboxing.
Like why did they count them?
Like they're saying that the,
the ropes held them up.
Then the next round wellness just
fucking dropped him legit and hurt him
bad and then dropped him again and then
finish them off
for Uber.
I'm looking forward to him fighting
Butler December 10th right.
God Damn.
That's going to be nuts.
Badr Hari is one of the scariest
motherfuckers ever walked the face of
the planet.
I have no clue how he's still out of
jail.
Out of jail.
I guess he's got money.
It ain't cause they said it was maybe
going to be in Morocco.
I go,
don't do it in Morocco.
Do it because if you beat him,
that's got to be a problem,
I think.
Yeah.
Didn't he rob a bank,
right?
No,
no,
no.
Let him beat up
Morocco,
but okay.
Okay.
Sorry.
Brass knuckles.
I,
my story is better
beat some guy up at a nightclub where he
stomped his shin,
the,
they held a guy down and he's allegedly
stomped on his shin and snapped it in
half.
Yeah.
That's not being a good person,
you know,
and like Tan and I think that's what he
was going forward.
But I don't think so.
Stories like that.
Do you have many of them from him?
That's not good.
Not Good.
Obviously I'm a huge fan of MMA.
I think the Nima Amaze the most exciting
sport in the world.
But there's some things that you see in
kickboxing that you just don't see in
mma because there's no threat of the
tank down.
So you see these wild technical
exchanges and in my opinion,
we need more of that.
You know,
it just is not enough.
There's not enough eyes on it.
Just don't think enough people are
paying attention.
Phenomenal show glory.
It is phenomenal now.
That's why I don't understand the
numbers have a why he's not,
not many more people watching it.
And especially the guys who are
complaining about not understanding
mixed martial arts.
Well,
the punch you can gigging,
everybody can understand that.
And like 85 or 85% knockout ratio.
Yes sir.
Yeah,
it's a great show.
I Love Glory,
but I like lion fight better.
I like traditional ties.
I just feel like glory would be even
better if they just went more Thai.
Because why?
Why take away elbows when widen.
Why no elbows?
Ah,
I'm not a big fan elvis just because of
the cuts cuts too easy.
Um,
but then also limiting the clinch time
cause the crunch time can be boring.
Right.
So I think like the k one rules are
more,
I liked the Cuban roles or Gloria rules
better for that aspect.
For the handpiece fight,
but or just a in the clinch keep abos
but in the clinch,
just a don't allow them to play around,
play around as long.
See,
I understand what you're saying about
elbows,
but part of me is like,
look,
it's a striking contest.
Why would you eliminate one of the best
weapons in striking,
which is elbows and lion fight has
these,
I mean,
look,
they get caught up like for sure.
Like do you see Gaston Balano since on
one of his face Ninja,
he gets cut the fuck up.
His opponents cut the fuck up.
They're blasting each other with
spinning elbows.
But it's fun as hell to watch.
Yeah,
definitely fun to watch.
I'm not trying to be in there anymore at
all.
Much easier just to quit coaching Tj and
coaching the guys and teach them martial
arts and evening what I want and hanging
out.
I totally respect that.
I just think like as a person who
appreciates the purity of the art,
I just feel like there's no reason to
take out those clinch battles and
there's no reason to take out those
elbows because the guys who are good at
those clinch battles,
you know,
they just start fucking blasting each
other with knees to the body and it has
a significant tall and then the elbow
battles that they have inside the
clinch.
It to me it's a,
it's a really important part of the
world.
Stand up striking.
I see that.
Yes sir.
Agreed.
We had a,
we were talking about earlier,
600 euro.
He just did a seminar at my academy and
he showed us really cool clinch elbow
knee techniques.
It was nice to get it from an actual
pure Muay Thai fighter to see his look
and his perspective of what can happen
in the clinch knot.
That was,
that was eye opening.
It was cool.
Yeah.
I think if we didn't have those guys,
we wouldn't know that we will.
We would have only the level of striking
that we see in mma.
And I think,
you know,
when you go and you watch like,
uh,
Ramon dekkers fuck,
you know,
you watch like him in his prime and you
realize,
okay,
this is possible.
Like there's,
there's levels to this fucking thing.
Oh,
Jordan mean,
right.
Yeah.
His elbows.
Oh Man.
Retired hired.
Yeah,
no,
he's coming back.
He is,
I heard,
yeah,
I talked to his father was a,
it was the Boston then this the most so,
yeah.
And uh,
he told me he's going to be back here.
He's a black phone interview,
right?
Yup.
It's Paul as a fucking savage.
There's a picture of him on his
instagram page is like fifties pucker.
Yeah.
Jordan is a very,
very talented guy.
But um,
he had so many fights,
you know,
as a young man.
I mean,
I think there's only 24,
25 and he retired.
Right.
That's what I tell everybody this
because they start competing too young.
He competed when he was 15,
16 years old.
They have to lie about his age.
You know,
you're going to burn out.
You shouldn't do that.
Everybody's asking me.
I'd met this a girl now in a Phi Zalea
12 year old Jenna.
Um,
it started the following year.
I sent us to a whole bunch of gear and
stuff,
you know,
I said,
because she says,
watch me,
I'm going to be the next Ronda Rousey.
So I go,
Hey,
I want to say that,
but it's,
you know,
it's the training.
It's uh,
I,
I told her start sparring maybe when
you're 15 years old,
wait with that,
because your brain is still everything
through your nerves,
you know,
at that age.
And it stops at 14.
Just give it two more years,
you know,
till all the connections are there.
And that may be start sparring by
competing.
I would just wait,
wait for competing.
Don't go in this early,
do Jujitsu,
wrestling,
do all that.
But striking to the head,
I think they should wait with that.
Even even doing those things at a young
age and you make sure they're fun.
You know,
like I almost got burnt out in wrestling
in eighth grade.
I wanted to quit.
I want to be done with the rest of this
too much.
It was just because every weekend I'm
competing in that.
I'm so nervous as a little kid,
I'm putting so much pressure on myself.
They're like,
I got to win this term.
I got to do good.
I like my dad was my coach.
I wanted to impress him.
All this stuff,
you know,
it's like eighth grade.
I was almost just gave it up,
you know?
But you got to learn to learn to have
fun with everything.
As long as everything's fun,
like you can compete,
do all that stuff.
I mean obviously kickboxing's little bit
different because you're going to go in
through some a brain trauma.
But what,
even with the wrestling and Jujitsu,
make sure it's fine if you've got a
little kid that wants to do and a or a
little kid that wants to get involved in
grappling and wrestling.
Make sure it's fun.
You know,
go in and practice playing some games,
news and things as well as learning
technique and cause little kids will get
burned out way too fast
because we hit it as striking a lot,
right?
Aka to let striking to get injuries and
injuries down.
How many times should we spar whispbar
two times a day.
Do we ever get injured
and we go,
if people watch,
they go to go,
oh,
these guys are crazy,
but we know exactly what we hit,
where we kick it.
It's all about sparring partners.
Now if you decide to your great part,
sparring partner doesn't show up and you
get somebody from the club somewhere.
Yeah.
Who has this?
We at you doesn't.
It's not as professional.
Yeah,
you get injured,
but I never been injured.
Inspiring and we
give bus route and settled down.
But same with you.
You'll never get an engine.
We will explore.
What did you think about cowboys?
Serone deciding no more sparring.
He doesn't spar.
He just does drills.
You're talking about that and look
sensational.
In his last fight.
He looks at a station will,
because he's still,
he,
he still was sparring before that,
you know,
it's closer,
but the fruit of your stairway,
it's like a lawler.
He said he never spotted.
Finally he started sparring.
He started sparring.
Any became much better.
See,
I look at that.
I think your reflects his knee.
Reflexes need to be tested all the time.
If you're going to fight,
well then you're going to have to fight
in training because that's what's got to
happen.
Unexpected things,
unexpected techniques.
You know,
you need to be prepared for that.
If you just spar,
you don't know what I'm going to throw
at you.
You get three show lies a counter on my
right straight.
Well what if I set it up as a one,
two instead of just the right straight?
Yes.
With that being said,
sorry.
Um,
is,
is if we're talking about sparring,
but it's not just full on fight
sparring,
but there's a whole level of sparring
drills that you can play with the mimics
scenarios.
Going back to the patterns,
right.
And like what's a typical pattern?
The Jab Cross,
there were low kick learning how to deal
with those things in the motion.
But while you're doing that,
Joel,
yet to had the clear mind like you're in
the fight,
but know that you're going to be here to
be countering the jab.
You're sending somebody up with a jab,
but not just going in finding guys,
I don't want this to be misled where
everyone's just fighting and sparring
hard,
but to do actual sparring drills because
there's a full path between hitting
myths and actual sparring and then
that's the web of the sparring drills.
Yeah.
I think cowboy also had an issue with
cutting the weight too.
Yes sir.
Then he looks cut 70 cutting weight was
just too much for him at one seven he's
a fucking assassin.
I feel like we're so good at the one
seven and there's a lot less pressure on
me at first too.
You know,
you got to go into a fight with just
having fun and not thinking about like,
I'm supposed to win this fight for him
and he's going to a complete different
weight class.
What is there to lose?
You know?
And so I think that's what's helped him
out a lot too.
And I think he's kind of catching his
groove.
He looked awesome that,
yeah,
right.
The body left Duke,
I kick,
I love it.
Anyone all full hits.
If you sought a body shot,
I dug in there.
Right.
And then wrap it up at the high kick.
I love the,
and the technique,
that technical aspect that was so,
there was no wind up.
There's no fucking no muscle behind it.
Everything's just perfect crack head
kick.
It was just God damn
as far as developing somebody a,
I used to help him out when he was first
training in Colorado and he was so
wrapped up into his own style.
I would try to say,
no,
do this and do that.
But then I realized,
look,
he even everyone needs to be their own
athlete.
You know,
you got to do what's,
what's good for you.
It feels natural.
Go ahead.
But um,
and then he's just a prime example of
someone you'd have to allow to be
themselves,
you know,
but just kind of guide a little bit here
and there.
But you know,
he went down to Jackson's and liquid.
He's done.
He's,
he's amazing.
He's such an individual trying to,
we all are.
Yeah.
Cowboy and some other boxes.
He's just,
he's a fucking wild man.
W have yet.
Who's the weirdest guy you've ever
worked with?
Where you like,
Jesus,
I don't even know if I could
and help this guy a
favor.
Favor.
Yeah.
Yeah,
he does.
But he's not going to try to learn new
things.
Yeah.
He sat in the past,
so you know,
I gotta respect that.
And you've been successful.
There you go.
But the game has changed.
Now look at the results.
The game has changed.
You have to change along with it.
Like the definition of insanity is doing
the same thing,
expecting different results.
You have to evolve.
We have to let the ego go and continue
to develop and train and learn.
The has to happen.
Would you guys had personality conflicts
for whatever reason,
you know,
no blame,
but whatever they were,
you guys had.
But what was,
it was a great time when we were
together.
Like,
look what happened.
Look what flourish,
right?
Yeah.
I became much mellor much better as a
martial art instructor,
being able to work with all the
athletes.
Right?
Everyone,
we work together,
everybody rose.
So it was a good time as good wind when
it worked out for me to go home and do
my own thing and uh,
things laid where they were.
Yeah.
You asked you about why you know him as
a good coach and the reason of that is
what I already mentioned with the
training.
He's always there.
He's always there on time.
He always goes full out and that work
ethic he took to be a coach.
He will always be there with the guys
cutting way to doing everything.
I guarantee you they can call you at
three o'clock in the middle of the
night,
the day before to fight.
Don't go,
just give me 30 seconds.
But that's it.
That's it.
If you have that drive and you are so
focused on one thing and he just put
that focus,
that's right.
I'll be training all day long.
I'll get home and want to just like
relax.
Vego may watch some TV,
just do nothing.
Right.
And then maybe be like 12 o'clock at
night.
I'll get a text from duane like on
something on my fight,
what I should be doing,
what should be thinking about.
I'm like,
yeah,
guys,
sorry.
Yeah,
it does not have to think about this all
night,
so he's the reason
why he's so great.
He's like you said,
he's constantly thinking about it and he
cares how well I do.
Before you fought Hanan Barao.
I was eating lunch in Vegas at the
hotel.
I had a bunch of my friends with me.
We're all getting ready for the fights.
Dwayne comes over,
hey man,
come on.
Sit down.
How are you feeling?
How's your boom?
Sits down and just,
we're going to do this,
blah,
blah.
I'm just going to stop.
The whole thing is movement switches to
get to the side,
the whole thing.
A brow browse his style.
It's his style.
He's going to his and he just was
fucking hundred miles an hour and
they're sitting there putting food on.
My Mom's gone and then he and me.
Yeah,
that's right.
Yeah.
That was still got the same.
This is good.
Boom.
That's why you're so fucking good.
You know?
And I don't like the term ocd man.
Obsessed.
I've dedicated my life to the arts.
I'll OCD is those weirdos washed her
hands a hundred times before you leave
the house.
This is a different thing.
This is just,
it's a positive session.
Yes sir.
Yeah.
I've dedicated my life to the arts.
Oh Man.
So it's fun.
I love it.
Yeah.
Pretty much everybody at this table has,
your method though is so uniquely Duane
and I really love your system.
I think that's so critical,
is that you've taken all your stuff and
you've written it out and you put it
into like this system where you can
really learn.
And that's something that I learned from
rob came into the Cayman tapes who's
amazing.
He has a system and it's one of the
things that I learned when I,
when I was training with him,
it's like this guy has this system the
same way a lot of Jujitsu guys have a
system,
you know,
and it's like his,
his system of breaking things down and
movement and strikes that it's all like,
it's,
it's all uh,
it has a pattern to us and you can
follow this pattern as a progression to
it.
And with the way the world is today,
you can learn it all from him online.
You know,
like he's so good at breaking things
down and build a to film it and show it
to people that I can,
you can go on as online academy and
learn exactly what I'm doing.
You know,
all you need is a willing yeah.
Participants.
So I want to train with you is going to
do the same amount of work that you are.
Yep.
Agreed.
Yeah,
it's fun.
I love it.
I definitely love it.
It gives me thrive and passion and a
purpose,
you know,
to put energy in to other humans and to
watch them flourish and grow.
And get better.
And that's a feedback for me.
It's obvious.
It might be just doing it for myself,
but it's a good service back first.
But yeah,
I lived to see people do good.
Well I'm glad you're around dude.
Cause it makes me sad.
It makes it interesting.
And this is such a suck,
a fucking exciting time for MMA.
Match is so much good.
Shit is going on.
Life is you.
You love and doing that show though,
the mma show
last time yet though,
I heard you.
When I'm on a broadcasting,
uh,
you're talking about the different
levels of knocked down.
Right.
And we had herb Dean and big John
McCarthy,
Joe McCarthy was talking about the five
levels of a nug down.
You know,
once you start staggering when she full
back,
when she crawled away,
there's all different sites,
you know,
and I think that,
I love those compensation,
you know,
the round table,
sit down with some professionals and
talk about problems that we have right
now and then figuring it out.
And I
love that.
And the show all,
she was great that she knew talent when
I called them mcgregor in the beginning
we had him on,
you know,
so we see these guys come on the show,
but also once a while we guys are Mark
Coleman or you know,
or don fry.
You know,
I see my old buddies again.
It's,
it's just a fun show pass.
Before you got here,
we were talking about Ipos and we showed
the Fabricio Werdum Travis Brown.
I poked.
Did you see that?
Have you seen it?
Yeah,
I heard about it.
Yeah.
Fucking crazy.
Like knuckle deep into different ratios.
I what do you think could help that?
What do you think could fix that?
I think penalties.
I truly believe so because if you look
at pancreas,
which was open and striking,
we never stabbed each other in the eye.
[inaudible] how is that even possible?
Right.
So now because we are cha hands
backwards because we want to hit with
the palm and,
and it's just a fact when it happens,
it won't happen in training.
Right.
And,
and,
and especially not at that cap.
Oh No,
not anymore.
Of course we've got a,
if they come from Greg Jackson winkle,
John,
I would say,
well my Greg John lost an eye,
you know,
and uh,
w with a neil it wetter as it was a foot
neil.
Okay.
Tonio but,
but still,
you know,
pads for some money holding paths.
That's what happens.
Very dangerous.
Yeah.
No,
but I think once you say,
listen,
if you're known to do that,
uh,
did it happened with you in the past?
Referee should be allowed to go before
there.
He say,
listen,
when I poke I'm going to give you a red
card.
And I think that will,
that will stop it because people are
going to get more,
become more careful.
We Red card,
which in pride with costs you a 10% of
year,
10% perse.
I think the point deduction,
I think one point every time I think,
uh,
you know,
no warnings for an ipod because you
take,
I think the gloves too.
But I think that if you,
even if you take a point away from a
guy,
like if you warn them like that person
you poked in the eye is still damaged by
that.
And so even if he says it's an accident,
like it doesn't matter one point either
way,
even though it's an accident.
What I'm saying,
even if it's obviously an accident,
if your fingers go in someone's eye and
you know it's going to cause a point,
everyone is going to curl their knuckles
back even more accountable for it.
Yeah.
Yes sir.
I see that.
Yes.
The gloves,
gloves and a penalties or a beating.
I hate to believe anybody's doing it on
purpose,
but someone must be doing it on purpose.
Some I feel are kind of aware of that.
There are some tactics for sure.
You know,
does,
I mean how often is that happening in
training?
I don't know,
but uh,
it's,
some of them do look deliberate.
It's that kicks into pills.
Crystal Sisinsky what's one time
fighting and he got kicked six times,
I believe.
It might even be seven.
And it feels,
and he goes back to the colon or the
balls.
Liz and I go kick him back.
Yeah,
that's my answer.
I said he's not getting a warning,
so do it back then.
He knows how it feels and it hopefully
he's going to stop.
But Chris of is too nice of a guy.
He didn't do it.
There's a few fights where you go,
Ooh,
I got to wonder why not.
If that's purpose on purpose rather.
Um,
did you see a check Congo versus Cro
cop?
Oh yeah.
Waylay them in the sack.
Wham.
Like more than once.
I mean it was several,
several good blows.
Most of the time it's bad technique most
of the times with the lead leg and they
don't step open to right foot.
So the angle cannot go,
uh,
like a 90 degree angle into the muscle
and it gets straight up.
It'd be,
she goes,
look,
if everybody who gets kicked to the
pills,
I guarantee you the leg that they're
standing on the toes are pointing
forward.
If they will point to decide,
it will be okay.
Well with check.
I believe it was knees in the clinch.
Oh,
it was,
I think it was just right.
Yeah.
A Thai boxer shoot noted.
I never need anybody to build.
I did once actually,
but that was on purpose.
I guess renee,
Rosie,
I,
if I could fight video from that,
that is the best dealer.
So I fight where they,
Rosie,
you heard about that,
right?
The tall guy from all a total
psychopath,
they say.
And it does always illegal things.
So we're fighting him and I'm the first
ride.
I beat the crap out of him in a second
ride would come out and be a clinching
and he bites in my ear and I'm shouting,
let go,
let go.
And then you see my knee going all the
way back.
Then I need him.
He comes loose from the ground.
That's how I knew him in the bill.
He goes down and I wanted to attack him
on the ground,
but they pulled me off and then a core
habits was in my corner.
Now he brought all his friends who was
like,
he had hell's angels with him.
And,
and I had all,
my boss was friends with me and they all
started fighting.
They throw us,
they threw a chair into the ring.
If bounce off core hammers says beck at
leds behind me.
If you see the video,
man,
it leds behind me.
I looked behind me,
I see the chair,
I sit in the chair while I watched
everybody.
And that later they cleared everybody.
Everybody's throw it down because the
referee took,
he says,
why did you do it?
And I said,
look at my ear.
And it was a hole straight through my
air.
He bit straight through my year,
a holding there.
And then he grabbed a microphone and he
announced to everybody and other,
Whoa,
he's got a hole in his ear.
He bit his ear.
That's why he did it.
And then everybody calm down.
Oh Wow.
And did you continue to fight right?
No.
No,
no.
That wasn't it.
It was a hard knee.
Wow.
The wild,
wild west.
It was a good one.
Eddie Bravo thinks he should be able to
hit a guy in the back of the head.
He thinks that when you take a guy's
back,
when the old days of mma,
when a guy had two hooks in,
you almost didn't go to the rear naked
choke.
He just blasted guy in the back of the
head with the elbows.
Yeah,
that's right.
But here we go again before rules.
Right.
Hands on.
It was and so and yeah.
What's his name
from Holland?
Like a sinker.
Yeah.
Judo Guy told me that guy was fucking
with Enzo.
Could call in his room calling his hotel
room all night.
So hands.
I was like,
oh,
okay.
All right.
And did you see what he stepped on his
face at the end?
Stepped on his face after he smashed
him.
That's what guys would do.
They would take someone's back.
Remember Health Gracie fought somebody,
I forget who it was,
but he got the hooks in and just boom,
boom,
boom.
Right to the base of the skull and like,
it's so affective though.
I know.
I do the same thing and keeps your spine
impact right.
Here it is.
Here's Hanzo.
Oh,
nice.
this is,
this is a actually,
okay,
look at that cage.
Yeah.
Duct tape around it and so he gets his
bags.
He flattens them out and then here it
comes.
Boom,
boom,
boom.
Go to baby.
Yeah.
I mean data is the way to open up that
choke man.
You can't defend once someone starts
raining,
those elbows down and you know you can
cover that shit up all you want.
Now he's tapping.
No,
watch this.
Where did you go to wait,
what he's going to do.
He gets kicked.
It gets up.
It looks steps.
That's right.
That's my head
world combat champion.
That was,
I think the state.
Look at it.
He helps him up.
Hey,
roll over on his head.
We're pals now.
People as well.
Yeah.
He beat the fuck out of that dude was a
good one.
That was I think the same event where
Marillo bustamonte fought Tom Erickson
and they fought.
They fought for like fucking 90 minutes.
It was one of those crazy fight.
It was like a 45 minute fight.
I think it was.
Honestly,
it was a crazy fight because they didn't
have like an ending to those things.
They didn't,
you know,
he just fought 90 minutes for suck up at
Hawaii
drowns.
They did rounds.
I don't think Marillo in Erickson did
rounds.
I think it was just one long er,
I don't remember.
But I remember like Ericsson at the
time,
he's like the forgotten heavyweight.
Like when he was in his prime,
he was fucking terrifying cause he was a
natural 300 pound go real low and
enormous wrestler and he could hit so
fucking hard.
I remember he knocked out Kevin
Randleman,
he hit Kevin random and we're like,
oh left hook and knocked him out.
But it was like Jesus Christ,
he was one of the scariest guys for his
time,
but just like kind of missed the window,
you know,
like he was really scary in the early
days of MMA.
Nobody wanted to fight him a month ago.
Super tough man.
What a great guy.
And we tell him,
Matt Lindland like nothing happened.
I didn't tap.
And they believe that a big John
talked about that on our show.
He said,
yeah,
that,
that was a bad one for me because you
know,
I didn't see it.
And that's what people should understand
at home.
You know,
dee dee,
same as the referees,
especially with Dina and big John just
show invested.
They loved the sports so much.
There's so much,
therefore the foot of fighters,
so when they make a bad call,
it hurts them as well,
you know?
But then to get the avalanche,
avalanche of older people on the
Internet,
you know,
come on,
everybody's human.
And people were talking about I believe
four Colt or three Kohl's that they were
talking about.
Uh,
her with herb dean,
Herb Dean had over seven and a half
thousand matches.
He did.
I go,
I do all sound great.
I like those off cody for mistakes in
seven and a half thousand matches.
You're doing a good job of both of those
guys are the gold standard and John
McCarthy,
that's the gold standard.
Everybody,
I mean,
you know who was really good before he
went away for selling weed.
Josh Rosen,
he did my last fight.
He's very good.
Very good.
Crazy.
Went away for something like that.
So crazy.
Well,
you want to wait for selling weed,
and he had a kind of little bit of an
arsenal,
legal Rahama,
a little only 12 acres of wheat.
They will have nothing wrong with that.
It's just helping the world and the real
problem was I believe guns were involved
and that's a,
that's when things,
but yeah,
look,
you're going to sell weed illegal.
You've got to be their protected.
It's unfortunate.
The whole thing is unfortunate,
but he was a very good referee.
Yup.
Very good referee.
Very good martial artist too.
Yeah.
He always tried and I sat and I respect
that obviously to having people in the
field who if you're going to work in the
field,
he should actually train in the fields.
You should have just gone one day.
I to bring up to you,
what did you think about the Travis
Browne?
Fabrizio Breeshia.
We're doing five where we're travis
called time.
He got his finger jammed for Breeshia,
threw a punch and travis is,
travis has finger apparently broke and
there's some photos of it now online.
It was,
it's fucking nasty.
Like shows you how tough travis is that
he continued with his finger was smashed
and it was a compound fracture with the
bone broke through the skin.
That's one picture,
but there's some even better ones that
he released today.
Well,
you could see it,
uh,
after the fight.
It was a nasty break,
but so it was a weird thing where
[inaudible] through this punch and he
threw like one of those chocolate dell
style over hands that come over the top
and it landed on the fingers of Travis
and snapped one of his finger.
So Travis calls time,
which you really can't do.
He's like,
my fingers fucked up.
He calls time like,
wow,
scroll up though.
And you see it.
The actual opening.
Yeah.
Here comes the boom.
He says timeout.
Right.
Given James said he cannot do that.
I Guess Marie Smith,
did they stop?
Did they go ahead and give me time?
Sorry.
Oh,
that's right.
You did that boss.
You did that in a fight.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But Maurice,
no,
I d I liked that.
Yeah.
I kicked him in the head and then I got
excited and wanted to give him another
kick in the head,
but I slip and a fall and to go out.
Then Maurice wants to jump on top of me
and I put my head up.
I say,
wait,
and he stops and I'm getting up and I
go,
thank you.
That's good closure
trick and another one to help fetty
funny anybody
with the Jason to Lucia.
I dropped it with his liver shot,
right?
And then I walked over to him.
You see what I'm doing as stretch my arm
above me and I wave with my head and you
see him look it up to my head and then I
live or kick him again.
I just put my hand up and say,
yeah,
look at this.
He actually looked there.
That's good composure,
right?
We actually use that stuff all the time.
The bird,
the bird,
so there's mastercard
sutong.
He's my first striking coach.
Had an Alpha male and a.
When dwayne first started coming to
teach at a alpha male,
I was thinking was my second fight.
You were there.
We were in San Jose against a Hugo
vianna and uh,
we're in the hotel room day of the
fight,
just kind of hanging out,
just waiting and mastered tongs just in
the bed.
He sleeps all day long.
And then,
uh,
he's in the bed just hanging out.
My dwayne comes to hang out with us and
he's telling master,
telling the story.
Am I strong as I kind of like looking at
him like he's paying attention but then
it looks at Dwayne.
He goes bird and weren't at a hotel
room.
Right.
And doing like it looks over and look if
there's a bird and as Dwayne back to
start talking to him
again,
he's rolled over on the bed and looking
at the direction night and then
sleeping.
Look over there while I turn over and go
to sleep cause I deal with the barrage
of the,
of the Ludwig I talking fast and doesn't
understand it.
So he turns around the fucking guy.
He was supposed to corner Tj in that
fight.
She said,
what's that?
He was supposed to courtney you on that
fight and we couldn't find the fucking
guy,
uh,
about to walk out for my fight.
And Master town's nowhere to be found.
I'm like,
what the hell?
I'm going out to my fight.
Where's the master Tong and in,
so danny just corners me and after the
fight I get back.
You messed up.
I was like,
oh,
tj.
Uh,
I go smoke way up in the rafters.
So supposedly he says he went up into
the rafters,
this smoke his cigarette and he was too
scared to get down so he couldn't come
down to come corner.
That's a great reason.
I'm in the room like the next day and I
go say,
well,
don't wake,
what the fuck were you ties and
cigarettes or gambling or everything?
I don't know.
It's just so cold.
Good fighters.
Yeah,
that smoked cigarettes.
He was smoking while he's fine.
I mean,
that guy is so talented.
It's crazy.
I wish she,
if he had half the work ethic,
that Dwayne head,
he'd be amazing.
You know,
he,
he's such a good trainer.
He's such a good fighter by justice.
I Dunno man.
He's such a freak though.
Would see him in the corner with a tank
top on and the gold,
bunnings and sunglasses.
Loving light side.
Yeah.
Big smiles on face.
Suns out.
Guns out.
Yeah.
Big Ass belt buckle.
And he would make sure to be in the
camera for the decisions.
He's like position himself so you can
see him like he wants to be a superstar,
you know.
Isn't there like an issue with him
gambling against one of your fighters
against her favor?
Apparently so.
No,
no,
not [inaudible].
This is from the hills
Barao in New Jersey.
It was both.
It was me and Tom and I,
and no one knows if this actually
happened,
right.
But uh,
allegedly
he gambled on borow to beat Faber and
he's cornering faber.
Like what the fuck man.
I go to New Jersey at the corner of my
eye.
I do two seminars.
They,
I get up super early,
do two seminars before his fight,
come back if I do everything I need to
do.
And then after the fights,
uh,
which apparently he gambled against
favor.
I'm leaving the hotel to go,
I got to get up super early and take off
to go back home and,
and I'm,
and I'm walking out down the hall and
he's got a track record of hitting
people up for money all the time,
tongue and uh,
easy an addict.
He legitimately apparently has a problem
gambling and not budgeting his shit.
Right.
So anyway,
I fly to vague or flight to a New
Jersey,
do two seminars,
corner.
Like I'm just,
I'm working my ass off.
I'm leaving the hotel after the fight
now and the next morning and he's
following me down the hotel it,
oh,
Dwayne,
uh,
can I have a little bit of money and I'm
like,
and then I like I gave him the Cro cop
stare.
I was like,
no,
motherfucker.
I got up early,
came out here and work my ass off to
seminars cornered and do what I needed
to do while you were sleeping in.
Don't ask me for money,
motherfucker.
Like I got genuinely mad cause he's just
being lazy ass and asking me for.
So,
um,
I told him no,
it's like that pool when he says you're
the world's worst best friend,
you know,
he put it when you bet against him at
the deadpool,
but on the positive side master,
Tom's a bad ass.
So bad man.
He's such a talented dude.
Yeah,
I know.
It's,
I think he is one of the best guys in
the world.
The holding mitts.
Yeah.
I wouldn't say he's like super
structured and going to like,
maybe it's like his understanding of
English,
you know,
you can't like break something down.
Like this is why you should do it and
tell me like why I'm doing things and
when to do it.
And he just kind of shows you,
he makes you do it on the mits without
even you knowing it.
He makes you do things you're supposed
to do the right way just by holding him
and having a very limited,
limited vocabulary.
TJ A lot.
Oh,
here's my first trainer and I,
I picked up on a stand up very quick
with him and I think he's a great
trainer.
He's just an addict.
I just got nasty Moitai tall dude.
He's so,
yeah,
very good tie.
And He's good.
I love the guy,
man.
It's a problem.
And when people would get that gambling
bug,
that's a scary book.
That's the first Korea.
I never did a good bug.
I mean if you got a trainer,
this betting against you,
I'm as bad as it gets confirmed though.
So master talking was coaching out in
Texas.
He's at a gym in Texas and that's when
this,
when Dwayne first got here,
so masterone was kind of with her.
I'm kind of mad and just kind of laughed
and that's why we needed a new coach,
you know,
that's why I brought Duane in.
And then when favor was going to fight,
Braley brought it back for eight weeks
for his camp and he's out here training
him.
Favorite went in that fight with the
herd.
Hamstring and message.
Chung knew that as well.
Like he tore his hamstring a little bit
and went into the fight,
little injured.
And so when my strong went back to
Texas,
he was bragging that he made $5,000
cause you bet all this money that favor
wasn't going to win the fight and then
it got back to favor because favor new
the the trainer out in Texas.
And so it came back to when we found out
about it and you know,
allegedly who knows if it's really true,
but message was bragging about it,
you know,
that hurts.
Well that's awesome guy.
Yeah,
you love him.
I mean I love the guy,
you know,
and if I would come to find out,
he bet against you.
That's,
that's rough.
You know what if we gave you four
one five and give you four but like
that's what he's supposed to do.
Listen dog,
you know,
and I know that you came into that fight
a little fucked up.
So like here's a taste.
No,
given the majority of it,
right?
Not even half most of it,
but he still won 1000 bucks.
People Gamble,
product problem.
Don't do that.
I know.
Cause he had nothing to show for it
afterwards.
He guarantee went and gambled it
somewhere else.
I mean,
he,
when he was coaching it off from in the
beginning before it ain't got there.
I mean,
he's making good money,
you know?
I know he's,
he supports his family and stuff,
but he should have had been a lot more
well off than he was,
you know?
But he's in a,
it's an addict.
It's a serious problem,
man.
It's like you wouldn't have actually
think that it's probably,
it's,
it's a serious problem.
Goes back what I was telling my guys I'm
doing for myself.
You're going to create habits.
Let them be good habits and I got that
from Sensei.
Pretty good habits,
right?
Yeah.
Your habit is train like a motherfucker
and teach like a motherfucker and get
obsessed with that.
I don't get obsessed with Black Jack.
I invest in other humans.
It's,
it's weird once you gamble because you
need it.
You always lose trust.
I enjoy gambling fights.
I used
to do it all the time.
When I first started working for the
UFC,
I would gamble on fights and then I was
like,
can I get in trouble for this?
I was like,
I wasn't sure.
I'm not,
can't affect the outcome.
You should.
You should mention it before to fight.
You say,
I put my
money,
I'm taking more enticing.
People get mad at me though.
Who the fuck bro?
Right.
Yeah,
but what the fuck bro?
The best is one of the time when Diego
see you dig,
oh Sanchez when a fight and then at the
time here you're going to interview him.
He's like,
Hey,
you told me all this weird before and
you're like,
yeah,
you're weird.
And then he was like,
just got quiet because he tried to call
you out,
but you're like,
yeah,
that's a bad thing.
Fuck.
Have I seen this view before?
He fought Joe Lowe's on and you will see
200 he was doing an interview before Joe
Lozan had like this whole like hadn't
been planned out.
It was almost like a freestyle rap and
put it on his instagram.
It is one of the funniest interviews I,
I wish I remember exactly who did it.
He's so odd but awesome.
Yeah.
Awesome.
And a good thing about him,
a long time ago dish before the ultimate
fighter,
this guy would send me video tapes from
the East Coast and we did a note and he
says,
boss,
I okay,
this one I won,
but I still can you break it down where
I have to work on.
And I would write everything down and
send it back to him.
And then I show him on the ultimate
fighter and the later I met him in an in
an elevator,
I say,
man,
you always used to send me to take.
She said,
yeah,
thank you very much.
But you see,
I really appreciated about a guy like
that.
Yeah,
no,
he's uh,
he's a really,
really dedicated guy.
You know,
Diego Sanchez is a fucking warrior and
he's a guy who's one more third rounds
of fights where he lost the first two,
the Martin Kampmann fight.
I'll never forget his face was hanging
off of his skull and he's chasing
Martin,
Kevin and Mark Hammond,
who fought a one 85 was a big fucking
guy for one 70.
And daigo is just,
I just run it out of a mask of blood
date of the Jake ellenberger fight.
The end of the fight.
He's on Ellen burgers back.
Beaten the shit out of them.
That's right.
Lost the first two rounds.
Comes back in the third like a fucking
savage.
If every fight was a hundred rounds
long,
Diego Sanchez might be undefeated
Mexican.
Fantastic insurance.
He always had a crazy car.
Do Donald Trump.
That's good alone.
I mean think about who had more
endurance and Julio Cesar Chavez,
right?
Well yeah,
you're right.
But then people fail to mention that he
trained a,
it was in Mexico City or it's 7,000 feet
elevation people.
If you don't,
don't take wine and his fights,
a lot of his fights were there as well.
Yeah,
that's a good point because a lot of
people don't realize how high Mexico
City is.
I didn't know until the first time I
went there.
I just did a fucking elliptical machine
there and I was like,
Holy Shit.
I said it.
I said it to convalesce cause it'll know
show are you going to go out like three
weeks ahead because of the elevation?
And he says,
no,
we will.
Uh,
do you think that's a smart idea?
Because you should be training there.
When I trained for the rental and fight
at the Colorado,
Colorado did,
but my first week days,
nine days were
really not nice.
They were not fun.
They,
I mean I got tired so fast.
It took really a while for me to get
into it.
And Colorado is 2000 feet below Mexico
City,
which is correct.
A title fight there.
Do you remember the second shoot?
What's the second shoe of seed there
with everybody?
When everybody ran out of gas?
Yeah,
it was the first two U of c's were in
Colorado.
Oh,
the first one to make nichols.
And then uh,
the uh,
uh,
the,
the other arena downtown.
I forgot what she said with Joe and Mark
Hunt in Colorado.
Yeah.
Yes sir.
Almost died.
They both almost died though.
There's only one way to prepare for
that.
So you have to be in that Lma because
you literally have less red blood cells.
Period.
Does that Taco guy who's an endurance
athlete who lives in boulder and he told
me you have to live there for three
years.
He said to get to reach the full
potential.
He's like for free with those guys.
For you when you were talking about
bikers like or triathletes or something
like that,
like for them,
every last second is in,
because you're doing the same activity
over and over and over again.
It's not like fighting where your
creativity,
your explosiveness,
all these different things come coming
in a factor.
It's just biking.
You're just biking,
you're just running.
You're just,
you're just swimming.
These are the things you're doing and so
every little second,
every little ounce of extra endurance.
So the optimize everything in that
regard.
And he was saying to really hit your
full potential,
we need to live at altitude and train an
altitude for three years.
Okay,
so lifted trains are nice.
Yeah,
I see that three years.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well full potential go from the 99% that
you had at one year at to said that
after three years,
you know,
it could be like that as well.
But I understand what he's spending
threshold.
If you have like only 10 days or two
weeks to train high altitude,
I almost would say don't do it because
she'll first week it's going to be the
worst week.
You can't think straight.
You know,
you,
it's,
it's better to just stay.
But if you have to fight at high
altitude,
always go there beforehand man.
I'm telling you three,
four weeks at least.
There's the,
uh,
the first bank center,
which is right by my academy that a
couple of UFC is there.
When you walk out of the dressing room,
there's a big metal sign on the wall and
it says,
uh,
extreme elevation.
If you,
if you feel light headedness or dizzy,
please rest to drink water.
So that's what like the fighters see as
you're walking out to the cage to that
biggest fucking science.
So it's my fault there.
I was like,
yeah,
yeah.
It's crazy for people who don't live
there to take fights at altitude.
It really is.
Yeah.
Especially with fights.
Fighters can't afford,
like if you're training for a fight in
Mexico City,
you can't afford to go anywhere.
I mean if you,
if you're on the undercard you making,
you know what's like the lowest paid
guys in the UFC males is eight eight.
It's crazy.
It's crazy that I got to,
you got to get on the o two trainer,
they get those lungs
then that will,
that will help them a little strengthen
him.
Yes sir.
For sure.
Yeah.
Because a lot of people say,
oh this part of that,
you know,
it mimics high altitude can't,
you cannot.
It doesn't do you.
Oh you have to wear it like eight hours
a day,
you know,
but otherwise it won't.
But it makes your holy spirit towards
schist system much stronger and it's
easier for you to pull in
when you're talking about your own
personal o two trainer where you put it
in your mouth and you,
you have like different on to write
stronger.
Yup.
The stronger with a guy who was a
trainer,
the scientist behind to Usain Bolt,
three out of gold medalists on track.
I feel to actually,
um,
uh,
dominick Cruz as well as training there.
This guy's a higher Iq and then freaking
Einstein hat he has like over 25 medical
journals that were very,
when it's proven that only inspiratory
training works.
So what,
what,
what happened was he,
he did and um,
uh,
review of,
of,
of my competition and
that was not explained what this thing
is to people that are listening that
don't know
it's an,
it's a device that I invented because I
was,
I was an asthma patient and I realized
that after an asthma attack for like a
weekend better eight days in bed,
I would resume my track and field and I
would,
I would break my running times and it
always bought,
I,
it puzzled me why,
why am I stronger after an attack?
This is crazy.
The medicine medication.
And then I realized when I saw,
I went to the doctor's office and I saw
a poster on the,
on the wall,
but a pair of lungs on there and it
showed where it's inflamed,
uh,
when you have bronchitis and,
and,
and what happens is you think as a kid
that's effected in the lungs,
it's not,
it's in the air pipes that go to the
lungs.
So that was my Aha moment.
I realized,
Oh,
I've been working out in my lungs
unknowingly because I'd been pulling air
through that infected hole.
So unknowingly I made my,
my whole lung system,
my inspiratory system stronger.
So why don't I come up with something
that controls the air intake and that
was it.
And then finally I started though.
You got it.
I started making it.
And it's a very simple device.
It starts with a whole of 15 millimeter
millimeter.
You start training with it and once you
feel that you get the same air as you
did before,
you go to 14 millimeter.
And now with this guy,
what this guy does with it.
Because when my,
my lawyer called me and he said,
listen,
did you read that review about our
competition?
It's horrible.
They,
they,
they slammed this.
I say,
I know because they control the area in
and out.
It's not a good way to do it.
I said,
contact that guy,
I want to send them a note to a trainer.
And when he contacted him,
he said boss would do a he bus route
from the o two trainer.
Yeah,
we already using it.
Conspiratory trains.
I love the product.
So what is the difference?
The differences when you control the air
out as well,
you cannot completely empty your lungs.
You'll,
you'll do it with resistance.
But if you complete an air out is all
with force.
It's all done by your core and your
diaphragm and your intercostal muscles
here and your rips.
But breathing in,
it's also done with that.
It's much harder to breathe in.
But as soon as I start stopping the
airflow out,
I cannot completely exhale anymore
before I take a new breath.
And that's what I started with.
So now when we going to come out with
all these medical journals,
with Usain Bolt,
all these people that he trains all do
inspiratory muscle training.
So they all use that kind of a device
all,
all use.
Wow.
So like those masks that you wear,
that control in and out,
those that,
that,
that was the cause of competition.
That was the competition yet.
So it's just something that just
controls in and then you can breathe out
with your own mouth like so you breathe
in through it and then when you breathe
out,
what do you,
how does it work when you breathe out?
Freely does that work comes out
because it's got two holes,
one site as to where they have the holes
on a and on the other side you have a
flap.
And if,
if I breathe in,
the flap closes.
Brilliant.
Yeah.
And it uh,
and then worked.
And the only thing that this the
scientist said,
he said,
well you could use it like you did boss
with training because a cure me for my
asthma on my website you will read a lot
of people cure for the asthma.
I don't use an inhaler and more and I
used an inhaler my entire life.
Even before world title fights always
had an inhaler with me because if it
would be nice,
for instance,
very aggressively,
three times my lungs would close.
I have to open them up with an inhaler.
I haven't used an inhaler for two and a
half,
three years now anymore.
So it,
it works with everything.
We were actually looking for an FDA
approval.
Everything is going to happen now
because the results are just crazy.
Good.
That's fascinating.
Yeah.
Oh and what he said,
what I wanted to say is what he does,
he lets them in the morning,
do 30 repetitions to,
to take a smaller tiny hole and you lean
over with the o two trainer and once
you,
you breathe out,
you every bit of air goes out of your
lungs and then you,
while you're breathing in,
you're sitting straight up and then
you'll breathe everything out against
you.
Do so many repetitions in the morning.
That's for you,
for your insight.
So that's all you're doing is just 30
repetitions.
That's it.
And that will build you up.
If you go for six weeks,
two times a day,
30 minutes and earth,
30 repetitions.
And after that,
just one time a day to increase,
you're going to have,
you could not to have any elected assets
in your core,
which by the way is the most important
thing if fighting.
That's why everybody gets tired.
I always say because their muscles
stopped pumping,
you know,
just like your,
your biceps are pumping and they start
pushing your lungs backwards.
So now you've launched cannot freely
inhale anymore because you're pushing
them back,
which,
which your core.
And that's the reason when you see guys,
you know,
that's why I used to do,
I actually set that at an a at the
seminar last Saturday.
I said that's why would you before a
fight,
I would do a lot of apps but constant
stretching apps,
apps,
stretches,
stretching and I was for that reason
because you know,
if this gets tight,
your core gets tight.
Oh,
everything goes down hill.
That's why the guys in the beginning
with,
uh,
with the steroid a while at the
beginning,
there's still doing apparently,
but you,
you saw guys,
they,
because if you use steroids,
you pump much harder,
right?
So they're very strong until the core
build software,
elected acid.
Now the lung skin breathe in anymore.
And that's why you see them going
strong,
strong.
And then suddenly they drop and it's
over with them.
That's the reason.
So your protocol for this o two trainer
is you do it 30 times,
like 30 breaths,
30 breaths in the morning,
30 in the evening.
After six weeks,
you increase your Holy Spirit.
They say you got 15 to 20% you will
gain.
It's in.
It's incredible.
You can do in how,
in how long?
How much time does it was six weeks
sweets.
You got to,
yeah.
You'll be amazed what once we are going
to come out with all these journals,
you're going to,
you're going to like 15 to 20% lung
capacity.
Yeah.
Look,
this is in spirit,
Tory,
right?
There's this other devices now they can
date.
There's still
air in there because they can completely
empty their logs.
We're looking at it for folks who are
just listening to this.
Yeah.
We're looking at a video on a Bas rutten
o two trainer,
which is online on Youtube.
Right.
Is it just so that mean or what is the,
you're a trader.com.
The site crashed right now.
Oh,
okay.
What was the site crashed because we
swapped it.
We swamped your site boss guy selling
some ot trainers.
I love the flap though.
That's amazing,
dude.
I'm buying one of these.
It's such a,
I get you on such an easy score.
Yes.
That's an easy thing.
Now,
are you using the buddy exit system
that's want I see it.
Yeah.
No,
come on back.
Come on back.
I'll take you back here.
We got to end this podcast anyway,
but I'll,
I'll show you in the back.
I could,
cause I gotta get the fuck Outta here,
boss.
Ruin your fucking gem of a human being.
Has a pleasure to know you,
an honor to make your acquaintance same.
I can say for both of you gentlemen,
it was a,
an honor to train with you today.
Bang Ludwig.
You're a fucking genius.
And TJ,
you're a bad motherfucker and I can't
wait to see you fight for the title
again.
And I really,
I really hope it is soon.
Yeah.
And uh,
thank you everybody.
That's it.
This fucking podcast is over Jihad.
Awesome.